Speaker 1: It's Tuesday, March 29th, 2016.
Speaker 1: I'm Rim, I'm Scott, and this is Geek Nights Tonight, 6 Nymphs.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: So as you all know, we were at Anime Boston.
Speaker 1: Those of you who might have found us because of Anime Boston, Hey, this is Geek Nights Tuesday.
Speaker 1: We're going to talk about games and stuff, not so much the anime.
Speaker 1: But, on the way home, Scott and I were bored.
Speaker 1: You know, it was going to be a long bus ride and we didn't even go to the con on Sunday.
Speaker 1: So we sat down and I asked the question I always ask whenever me and Scott are alone together.
Speaker 0: You want to play Advance Wars?
Speaker 1: It's either you want to play Advance Wars or you want to play Civ 5.
Speaker 1: And for the first time in my life, that clock rang and Scott said, "You know what?
Speaker 1: Yeah.".
Speaker 0: I figured it would make the bus ride go much faster.
Speaker 1: And it did, actually.
Speaker 1: We played Civ 5 Hot Seat, which I've never done.
Speaker 0: We should have done it with two laptops and played two games.
Speaker 1: Uh, yeah.
Speaker 1: That would have been perfect, except I'm the only one of us who had a laptop that could play Civ 5.
Speaker 0: Why don't they make--my iPad Pro is better than your laptop.
Speaker 0: Why don't they make Civ 5 for it?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: That's actually the one--the only reason I'm leery of the iPad is, as much as I want one, I like to play games like Rocket League and Civ 5 on my laptop when I travel.
Speaker 0: Oh, you can just play different games.
Speaker 1: Like what?
Speaker 1: What game is as good as Civ 5 or Rocket League or Counter Strike that you can play on the iPad?
Speaker 0: Hearthstone.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that sounds pretty good.
Speaker 0: Hearthstone is the best iPad game you can play.
Speaker 1: Yeah, yeah.
Speaker 0: That's the reason--that's the only reason I play it.
Speaker 0: If it were--there was--right?
Speaker 0: It's like--it's literally the best mobile game that exists.
Speaker 1: But when I'm in, like, Hong Kong or something for a week and I got, you know-- There's mad Hearthstone going on there.
Speaker 0: Whoa.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but I would rather be playing Rocket League.
Speaker 0: Well, why don't you just go to, like, a night cafe?
Speaker 1: Because I could.
Speaker 0: And you'd get your ass crushed by some Chinese Rocket League.
Speaker 1: So, I had also never tried the, like, tiny map format, so we just played it dual.
Speaker 1: It was just me and Scott on continent, so we each had a tiny continent.
Speaker 1: And there's four city-states out there.
Speaker 1: And we just started going.
Speaker 1: And at the end of the bus ride when we got to New York, we'd made it about a hundred turns in.
Speaker 1: And we were just getting to the point where things were getting real interesting.
Speaker 0: The main problem was just, like, I think in the dual map, right?
Speaker 0: It's, like, things that normally can be mitigated.
Speaker 0: It's, like, the game is real different, right?
Speaker 0: Because you had the guys that have mad boats.
Speaker 0: Yup.
Speaker 0: And the map was such that I was on an island and you were on an island.
Speaker 0: My starting city was not on the coast.
Speaker 1: Don't you know the automatic, intrinsic start biases of all the different civilizations?
Speaker 0: I didn't know that that was what the map was going to look like.
Speaker 1: I said continents were probably going to be on two different continents because there's only two of us.
Speaker 0: Right, but I didn't realize that your guy was going to have, like, something that gives you a free million boats.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well.
Speaker 0: Like, I figured, like, you know, I didn't, because I don't know all the stupid things in the game.
Speaker 0: There's so many fucking things.
Speaker 0: I didn't even know that was a thing until you used it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I realized that your only problem with Civ V was that you just haven't played it enough, so you don't know stuff.
Speaker 1: Think about how much you know about Civ II.
Speaker 1: Like, you probably remember what almost every wonder does to this day, even though they don't actually, like, they don't have analogs to modern wonders.
Speaker 0: No, I didn't really know.
Speaker 0: I only knew it.
Speaker 1: You knew Leonardo's Workshop, I'll bet, and the pyramids.
Speaker 0: So, I knew Leonardo's Workshop, and you know why I like Leonardo's Workshop so much?
Speaker 1: Because you don't have to deal with the upgrades.
Speaker 0: Also because it had the best music.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it did.
Speaker 1: And everyone knew the pyramids, because nobody wanted to build the stupid granary everywhere.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it gives you free granary everywhere.
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 1: Though, I've noticed when I play, because I've been playing, you know, not to plug giant multiplayer robot, but I actually paid money now, so I can be in a lot more games.
Speaker 1: I use this thing a lot, and the way it actually works, it's five bucks.
Speaker 1: You just give them five bucks, and you can play up to five games instead of just two forever.
Speaker 1: Just five bucks once.
Speaker 1: I think fifteen bucks is unlimited games forever.
Speaker 1: I paid the five bucks, and I got three games going, and I did do my commentary on the big game, but playing the duel against Scott, one thing I realized is that if you have a small empire like that, and you want to rush wonders and rush tradition, you can do like tradition, get some marble early, and just crank out wonders.
Speaker 0: That's another thing I didn't realize is I had some marble right fucking there, and I didn't realize what it did until I finally... Until I finally got my worker to work it, and this message pops up, and I'm like, "Oh, that's what RIM's
Speaker 0: doing.".
Speaker 0: If I would have known that, I would have gotten a worker even earlier and worked it right immediately.
Speaker 0: I did, because I did get the tradition thing immediately, right?
Speaker 0: Yup.
Speaker 0: I just didn't get the worker on it immediately, because I didn't realize what, you know, I'm just like, "Oh, it's a...".
Speaker 0: You know, when I see like rocks, I'm like, "Oh, mine the rocks, get production, all right.
Speaker 0: I want to get the food first.
Speaker 0: I'll go make a farm
Speaker 0: first.".
Speaker 1: I think a lot about those things.
Speaker 0: I don't know all those things.
Speaker 0: There's way too many fucking things.
Speaker 0: There's not that many.
Speaker 0: There's so many things in this game.
Speaker 1: I feel like I know most of them.
Speaker 0: You got culture things, you got sciences, you got buildings, you got wonders, you got units, you got fucking things that you can like get at the councils.
Speaker 0: There's just so many goddamn things, and great people can do like three different things.
Speaker 0: I can't remember all these fucking things.
Speaker 1: But Civ 2 had a similar level of bullshit.
Speaker 0: I just didn't know the things when I played Civ 2.
Speaker 0: I just played.
Speaker 0: I never played Civ 2 multiplayer either.
Speaker 0: I played against the computer.
Speaker 1: I always wanted to.
Speaker 0: I never played against it, and I was never able to beat it on like any kind of hard level.
Speaker 0: I played it normal at the most, and I just sort of played like by feels, just sort of like, "All right, build
Speaker 0: stuff.".
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: You know, "Oh, there's a wonder.
Speaker 0: I can build it in seven turns.
Speaker 0: I'll build it.
Speaker 0: I don't know what it does.
Speaker 0: I'm just going to build
Speaker 0: it.".
Speaker 0: Just building stuff.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I didn't really even understand like the concepts that like, "Oh, you get food, and then you get
Speaker 0: population.".
Speaker 0: I didn't know that.
Speaker 0: I just like, you just build stuff.
Speaker 1: You're like, "What are all those red guys?
Speaker 1: I guess I'll ignore them.
Speaker 1: Hey, why is that guy wearing black?
Speaker 1: Why did my city just revolt?
Speaker 1: What's going
Speaker 1: on?".
Speaker 0: I would just go to cities, and I would click "Produce this next.
Speaker 0: That looks fun," and then click "Next turn," and then move units around, you know.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I didn't really know what stuff did.
Speaker 0: I just like, "Oh," you know.
Speaker 0: But
Speaker 1: I like Civ 5, and I played it a lot because, you know, on long trips, like especially if I'm flying to like East Asia, and I've got like a 12 or 13 hour flight, you can get most of the way through a single player Civ 5 game in a flight like that.
Speaker 1: So I would just play like these long games, but pretty bored playing against the AI, and I'm kind of addicted to playing Civ against humans now.
Speaker 0: I can't even beat the AI in anything like above Prince, and if I do Prince, I can only beat it sometimes.
Speaker 0: Really?
Speaker 0: And only using like the space shuttle.
Speaker 0: Like every time I try something different, it doesn't work.
Speaker 1: So if I ever go for something different, I kind of accidentally get a domination victory along the way, so it doesn't matter.
Speaker 0: That's the thing, is I can't, like I don't war.
Speaker 0: I basically expand with settlers to fill my space, and then I turtle.
Speaker 0: And then I just build stuff.
Speaker 1: See, this is why I think this duel, so we played that game halfway, and we saved it on my laptop.
Speaker 1: We're going to wait until the bust packs and continue the game.
Speaker 0: I think we should play a different game, one where you don't have the entire water covered in boats.
Speaker 0: If you- Well, I mean, what hope do I really have?
Speaker 1: So Scott, that water's covered in boats, but you realize it's just like seven triremes.
Speaker 1: I can't take a city with that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I can't move any boats around.
Speaker 1: Well, you didn't focus on boats.
Speaker 0: But how do I- I need to see the map still and go looking for stuff.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there's one more island that neither one of us got to.
Speaker 1: You know what's on it?
Speaker 1: More barbarians than you can imagine, one city-state, two unexplored huts.
Speaker 0: Right, but it's like, even if you take that island, it's like I can't expand my territories or do anything because any boat- Scott, there's nothing else in the whole world.
Speaker 1: Unless you conquer something, there's literally nowhere else to settle.
Speaker 0: I still need to see what else is in the world.
Speaker 0: Why?
Speaker 0: There's some natural wonders out there.
Speaker 1: I think there's only two natural wonders.
Speaker 0: I haven't seen any of them.
Speaker 0: Really?
Speaker 1: There's one on my continent.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't know what they look like, and then my people would be very happy to see them.
Speaker 1: So here's another thing, because I've noticed this.
Speaker 1: In these games, there are three kinds of civilizations.
Speaker 0: And I can see what your territory looks like and keep an eye on you.
Speaker 1: You can't just build one trireme unless you literally only have that trireme to keep barbarians from taking your one or two work boats that are hanging out there.
Speaker 1: You either build a fuck ton of boats, or you just don't build boats.
Speaker 0: See, but that's the thing.
Speaker 0: My starting city was not in the water.
Speaker 1: Then you gotta be a land civilization.
Speaker 0: Okay, so now I'm trapped in this little island.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so min-max that island.
Speaker 1: Just build a wall that I can't come in with with artillery and nonsense.
Speaker 0: How am I gonna win the game with that?
Speaker 1: I don't know culture.
Speaker 0: I don't think I can win the game with that.
Speaker 1: Alright.
Speaker 0: That's what I'm doing, but I don't think it has a chance of winning.
Speaker 1: Well then build a navy and attack me.
Speaker 0: How can I build a navy if you can just plant your navy outside my one city?
Speaker 0: that can build a navy and kill every boat as soon as I build it?
Speaker 1: Put a bunch of catapults or trebuchets or whatever around that city to clear out of space.
Speaker 1: Because you realize, Scott.
Speaker 1: How can I afford all those?
Speaker 1: Scott, you don't seem to realize how much of a coward I actually am.
Speaker 1: Like, if my boat comes near you and even an archer attacks it, I just fucking run away.
Speaker 0: I mean, I've already shot a bunch of your boats with archers, but I think that's only helping you not pay for those boats.
Speaker 0: That you have extra boats you don't need.
Speaker 1: On the Ottomans, I don't pay for those boats anyway.
Speaker 1: Also, I gifted most of those boats to a city state that's allied with me so that they'll declare war on you when I declare war.
Speaker 0: That's another thing, is I mostly need to travel to make trade routes with some cargo ships, right?
Speaker 0: I have a maximum of three trade routes.
Speaker 0: There's only one city state on my island.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there's only one city state on mine.
Speaker 0: So I can trade with one, but you can build cargo boats and they won't get- And I can trade with two and then I'm done.
Speaker 0: I'm just saying, is if I could try to get some boats out there, I could trade- Scott, you gotta use the internal routes, the internal caravans.
Speaker 0: Yeah, with what?
Speaker 0: Myself?
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: All it does is move food from one city to another.
Speaker 1: No, it creates food in production, Scott.
Speaker 1: It doesn't move it.
Speaker 0: See, this is why I don't know stuff.
Speaker 1: And if you do an internal route, it's not like minus seven production here, plus seven there.
Speaker 1: It's there just gets plus seven.
Speaker 1: So if you have a crappy little city, you can point like three caravans at it and make it a production powerhouse.
Speaker 1: How do you think people finish wonders so quick?
Speaker 0: I don't know, because they know stuff like that.
Speaker 0: that I don't know.
Speaker 1: If you ideology and go communism, right?
Speaker 1: You can do stuff to make those internal routes just be like twice as effective.
Speaker 1: You can just make hammers out of nothing.
Speaker 0: How do I not know this?
Speaker 1: I don't know how you don't know these things.
Speaker 0: It's too much shit in this game.
Speaker 0: But yeah, so- What other game has a civilopedia and it can't even have an encyclopedia.
Speaker 0: It has to have its own media.
Speaker 1: Europa Universalis.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's even worse.
Speaker 1: I can't- Yeah, I'm not playing that.
Speaker 0: I can't even play that.
Speaker 1: That's over the line.
Speaker 0: See, I can only play Netrunner, which has so many fucking cards, because I started when there were very few cards and I learned the cards one at a time.
Speaker 1: But I guess I'll put it this way.
Speaker 0: And see if I'm starting when there's like three expansions and I gotta learn everything at once.
Speaker 1: You just gotta play single player and kind of learn these things.
Speaker 1: Try to win.
Speaker 0: I don't have time for this shit.
Speaker 0: Alright.
Speaker 1: But at least what I don't think I found, because I'm in three Civ V games right now, just on GMR.
Speaker 1: And one of them I'm not doing great, because these guys are like super pro.
Speaker 1: But Civ V is real fun, even when you're not winning.
Speaker 1: Because it's still Civ, except unlike against the AI, the diplomacy with the real humans actually matters a lot.
Speaker 1: And if there is a war, it's just awesome advanced wars.
Speaker 0: The problem is that it isn't way fun when you're losing, because the way I lose is I- Slowly peter out.
Speaker 0: No, I don't have a lot of military units and a giant army of a million guys shows up and I'm like, not only how do they build that so fast, but how are they paying for it?
Speaker 0: And then it destroys me in like a few turns.
Speaker 1: You had the same complaint in advanced wars.
Speaker 1: I remember one time we were doing a pretty big map.
Speaker 1: And I saw you had this one motorcycle guy and he comes over and he comes over and he gets to these cities in the middle of the map that I had long ago completely captured.
Speaker 1: And I think you accused me of cheating because you couldn't believe I'd gotten people there that fast.
Speaker 0: It's the same thing that's been happening to me in games where you build stuff forever.
Speaker 0: When I played Red Alert back in the day, I sent a group of grenade-y guys to go scout out the enemy base.
Speaker 1: And just tanks, tanks, tanks, tanks.
Speaker 0: There's like 30 tanks and meanwhile my war factory is like under construction.
Speaker 0: I'm like, how the fuck did you build that so fast?
Speaker 0: I don't understand, like, what people are doing.
Speaker 0: Because I'm like, build archer.
Speaker 0: Alright, it will take 7 turns.
Speaker 0: And then I look over by you and you get 7 archers and I'm like, there haven't been 49 turns in this game.
Speaker 0: How the fuck did you do that?
Speaker 1: I'm gonna let you in on a tiny secret.
Speaker 0: Everyone cheats but me.
Speaker 0: Yes, I know.
Speaker 1: But I'm having a lot of fun with Civ 5 right now and this is like my game between this and Counter-Strike in the last month or two.
Speaker 1: And I might start up a fourth or fifth Civ 5 game.
Speaker 0: Do whatever you want to do.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So you got any gaming news?
Speaker 0: I do.
Speaker 0: So that Nintendo's iOS mobile game, the Miitomo thing.
Speaker 0: It's basically going to be a Mii-related candy box on your phone, pretty much.
Speaker 0: It's gonna be out for reals in North America on Thursday.
Speaker 0: Yes!
Speaker 0: Candy box!
Speaker 0: And it's Tuesday right now.
Speaker 0: So everybody, get your candy ready and your insulin ready.
Speaker 0: Because it's box time.
Speaker 1: See, I actually did follow through with my threat to not play the 3DS candy box anymore.
Speaker 1: I'm done.
Speaker 1: I just don't even bother.
Speaker 0: I'm only doing the puzzle piece one and I have every puzzle piece.
Speaker 1: Except there will always be more puzzles.
Speaker 0: They've been coming out much less frequently.
Speaker 1: I refuse to.
Speaker 1: I'm just done with that.
Speaker 1: Also, I don't even bring my 3DS anywhere because literally no one will play Smash Brothers or Mario Kart with me.
Speaker 1: So it's kind of pointless.
Speaker 0: I will play a different game with you.
Speaker 1: What game?
Speaker 1: Advance Wars?
Speaker 0: Uh, candy box.
Speaker 1: It is interesting that Nintendo's finally taking these tiny baby steps into mobile.
Speaker 1: But I feel like the long run will be.
Speaker 1: they'll just be a software company on mobile.
Speaker 1: And have some sort of console that maybe also interacts with mobile.
Speaker 0: No, the NX is going to be real.
Speaker 0: I feel it.
Speaker 0: The NX is going to be super legit.
Speaker 1: But what form will it take?
Speaker 0: Not the form of those amazing fakes.
Speaker 0: Bravo amazing fake people.
Speaker 0: Great job.
Speaker 0: You did the best fake.
Speaker 0: I've seen every fake there is to see.
Speaker 0: I've been around as long as the internet.
Speaker 0: And that is the best fake I ever did see.
Speaker 1: The beautiful thing is when the person posted their.
Speaker 0: here's how I faked it.
Speaker 0: If there was internet awards you would get the achievement, the best achievement of the year award.
Speaker 1: But when they posted the here's how I did it, if I'd done it.
Speaker 1: There were replies and comments and discussions about that post claiming that the I faked.
Speaker 1: it post was fake.
Speaker 1: And that's covering up the fact that it's real.
Speaker 1: Which is amazing.
Speaker 0: That's how good that fake was.
Speaker 0: Also, it was so believable because the patent wasn't fake.
Speaker 1: Which is smart.
Speaker 1: You gotta go find a patent like that and base your fake on the patent.
Speaker 0: Now you know what?
Speaker 0: It's not a hunt.
Speaker 0: You know what?
Speaker 0: Those people were saying it's a cover up.
Speaker 0: I'll give them a tiny percent chance that it actually wasn't fake.
Speaker 0: and they were trying to cover up by saying it was fake.
Speaker 1: The ultimate beauty would be if it was a fake.
Speaker 0: Nintendo did it to test the waters.
Speaker 1: Or what if it was a fake?
Speaker 1: but that is actually what the real thing is going to look like mostly.
Speaker 0: So it could be.
Speaker 1: That could happen.
Speaker 1: I mean, if there's a couple of smart choices that could be made.
Speaker 1: There's a lot of smart people in the world so odds are a few smart people would come up with the same solution to a problem.
Speaker 1: In other news, this is actually kind of a big deal.
Speaker 1: So Pax East, I love Pax but it is the worst of the Pax's.
Speaker 1: Now that's like saying this is the worst of the foie gras.
Speaker 1: This is the worst of the king's peas.
Speaker 0: This is the least tasty filet mignon.
Speaker 1: But Pax East is the hardest to go to in terms of local logistics because there's like...
Speaker 0: There's no place to eat.
Speaker 1: There's like three hotels within walking distance that are comfortable.
Speaker 1: The rest are super far away.
Speaker 0: It's more expensive to go there even though we live in New York very close to Pax East than it is to go to Pax South which is very far away.
Speaker 1: And one of the big problems is...
Speaker 0: Pax Australia is cheaper than Pax East if you live in Australia and Pax Prime is cheaper than Pax East if you live near Pax Prime.
Speaker 0: West.
Speaker 0: They changed the name.
Speaker 1: Which is interesting.
Speaker 1: Don't wait for Pax North.
Speaker 1: There's also rumors of all those tabletop events they might start.
Speaker 0: Well they sent out a survey that was like "How would you like if we had Pax branded tabletop events that were as much smaller than Pax in random
Speaker 0: places?".
Speaker 0: And I was like "I will make it my job to run those and travel around the country doing
Speaker 0: that.".
Speaker 1: So with Pax Prime and Pax East, but not so much with Pax South, and actually not at all really at least in the ones I went to with Pax Aus, a lot of people just show up Thursday morning and just game in the hotel lobbies like all day and all night.
Speaker 0: That's every Pax ever.
Speaker 1: Pax South there was not nearly as much.
Speaker 0: but... I think we just weren't going to the hotels that had it.
Speaker 1: Well the thing is the hotels were a lot more spread out.
Speaker 1: In Pax Prime, the Sheraton is the hotel.
Speaker 1: If you can get into the Sheraton...
Speaker 0: Right, but we go to Pax Prime, even if we're not staying in the Sheraton, we go in the Sheraton.
Speaker 0: At Pax South, I think that Marriott across the street from the convention center is the hotel and we've never even walked inside of it.
Speaker 0: I walked in there.
Speaker 0: I never went in it.
Speaker 1: The problem with that hotel is that there's not that much tablespace.
Speaker 0: I haven't been in it.
Speaker 1: There's not a lot of room in there.
Speaker 1: But Pax Prime, the Sheraton, it's a whole convention just going on in that lobby.
Speaker 0: Well, part of the convention is in the Sheraton.
Speaker 0: The real convention is in there.
Speaker 0: There's rooms, panel rooms in there.
Speaker 1: And if you go to Pax East, the Westin lobby is enormous and there's a million people in there playing games.
Speaker 1: Like so crowded.
Speaker 0: It even has that little balcony mezzanine area with extra big round tables that are used for gaming.
Speaker 1: But it's so crowded, like I avoid that place like the plague for the last few years.
Speaker 1: So it's always been a problem because there's nowhere for everyone to game on Thursday except there.
Speaker 1: Like you go over to the Seaport Hotel, despite having a ton of space, there's like no one playing games.
Speaker 0: Well, it's also.
Speaker 0: a lot of these hotel lobbies aren't convenient for gaming.
Speaker 0: Hotel lobby tables are usually tiny weird circle tables or low coffee tables for newspapers and shit.
Speaker 1: But there's multiple factors.
Speaker 0: Yeah, no one has gaming tables set up in there, right?
Speaker 0: I mean, I'm pretty sure like random poker games would break out when it's not a nerd convention.
Speaker 1: But there's also the sort of like consensus critical mass where you need a... Like you have to have a certain critical mass of nerds who want to play games and then the hotel will be rocking.
Speaker 1: If you're below that, it's just really sad unless you have your own small group of friends to just play games with.
Speaker 0: We have that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but then it's just like you're in your hotel room except it's slightly bigger.
Speaker 1: So PAX East for the first time ever is solving this problem in the Westin.
Speaker 0: The big hotel that everyone wants to stay in.
Speaker 1: That no attendees are staying in as far as I can tell.
Speaker 1: It's all exhibitors.
Speaker 1: I mean, we could not even get into the stupid Westin.
Speaker 0: No, because we're so special.
Speaker 1: Well, enforcers and panelists and all the early access gave us no access to that stupid hotel.
Speaker 1: We could have stayed in the Westin if there was one of us and we were only staying Friday and Saturday.
Speaker 1: So there's a big event space, 21,000 square feet in the basement of that hotel that PAX never used.
Speaker 1: Like no one uses it.
Speaker 0: I mean, I thought I was imagining this space because I've been down the stairs in the Westin.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there's a hallway there.
Speaker 0: We played a lot of Wizard down there in the restaurant part, but there's another room down there and stuff.
Speaker 0: And I thought that that was the space.
Speaker 1: Wait, Scott, the restaurant part is like up and around to the right.
Speaker 0: There's a space down the stairs.
Speaker 0: Remember?
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's just a wide hallway.
Speaker 0: No, because there were like lights that were shining on the wall with like graphics and stuff down there.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's just a long hallway.
Speaker 0: Anyway, there's stuff down there.
Speaker 1: That's where we played Vampire Rob Mafia that one day.
Speaker 0: I'm just saying is apparently this space is not a space that is in my brain.
Speaker 0: Because it's some other space I haven't been to.
Speaker 1: It's a ballroom.
Speaker 1: It's an expo hall.
Speaker 1: It's 21,000 square feet.
Speaker 1: And for whatever reason, the hotel said, "Hey, PAX people, you can just use it.
Speaker 1: We're not even going to charge
Speaker 1: you.".
Speaker 0: Are you sure they're not charging anyone for this?
Speaker 1: It appears that they're not charging anyone for this because there's an interesting quote, "Zero gaming will be allowed in the actual hotel lobby anywhere.
Speaker 1: You will be forced to go to this gaming
Speaker 1: area.".
Speaker 1: The hotel is trying to get the thousands of PAX people who crowd their lobby every year out of their hair.
Speaker 0: I mean, usually like other hotels, for example, share it in at PAX West, right?
Speaker 0: It's like, if that bothers them, they haven't done anything about it.
Speaker 0: I don't understand why the hotel cares.
Speaker 0: Like, why is the hotel being nice and helping us out?
Speaker 0: It's sort of like, "Really?
Speaker 0: You're helping us out,
Speaker 0: huh?".
Speaker 1: Well, as far as I can tell, the mezzanine, which is in that area, some other convention has that space rented out on Thursday.
Speaker 0: That's dumb of them.
Speaker 1: And those people, there might have been trouble because that space that they've rented out last year was full of probably seven or eight hundred PAX.
Speaker 1: people like mashed together, sitting on the floor everywhere.
Speaker 1: So the hotel will fucking kick you out if you don't go downstairs to play games in the dungeon, but the dungeon is going to be gigantic.
Speaker 0: It's like, we want the dungeon, but this still is making me very cautious.
Speaker 0: Like, when you go down the street and there's a guy and he's handing out some candy, and you're like, "Really?
Speaker 0: That's not poison candy.
Speaker 0: Is that what you're
Speaker 0: saying?".
Speaker 1: The ones I don't get lately, there's all these people in my office that are just like, "Free massage, free
Speaker 1: massage.".
Speaker 1: And I'm like, "Hell no.
Speaker 1: Hell no, you're not touching me, scary hobo-looking dude with a
Speaker 1: sign.".
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 0: They're trying to convince you to come in for their paid massage or their Chinese...
Speaker 1: And it's a hobo that was hired by the whatever.
Speaker 0: Or their Chinese nonsense or their chiropractors or whatever their evil nonsense is.
Speaker 1: So at least 350 seats with a bunch of tables, also tons of floor space.
Speaker 1: They're setting up JS Joust and you can just game on the floor.
Speaker 1: They're trying to get a bar put down there.
Speaker 0: I'm sure the hotel will be happy with putting a bar down there.
Speaker 1: I'll be happy if they put a bar down there.
Speaker 0: Free money for them.
Speaker 1: So this is going to be amazing and this actually really ups the value of PAX East in relation to the other PAXes.
Speaker 0: Sure, yeah.
Speaker 1: Because Prime's the only other PAX that has...
Speaker 0: If they kept it going every night after the end of PAX, that would be even better.
Speaker 0: If they turned it into... Because this is a Thursday night thing.
Speaker 0: Is it going to be a Friday night thing?
Speaker 1: I think it's just Thursday because...
Speaker 0: When does PAX end on Friday?
Speaker 1: Well, because I'm pretty sure on Friday the mezzanine and everything will be available again.
Speaker 0: Oh, okay.
Speaker 0: But the mezzanine doesn't hold nearly as much as a giant ballroom.
Speaker 1: Thursday is the most important though because the other news, as far as I can tell...
Speaker 0: It is the most important.
Speaker 1: Because, you know, Wizards of the Coast isn't...
Speaker 0: But so is Sunday after the con ends.
Speaker 1: Wizards of the Coast isn't exhibiting and taking up all the space that they always take up, at least in the tabletop areas.
Speaker 0: That is correct, but we don't know if that space will be used for more tabletop or not.
Speaker 1: I suspect there's going to be a lot more tabletop space at this PAX East than there's ever been.
Speaker 0: Maybe, that would be nice.
Speaker 1: Independent of the Westin stuff.
Speaker 0: But they could expand other areas to take that WotC space instead.
Speaker 0: We don't know.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So I got one last news.
Speaker 0: But I think they shouldn't because just because WotC's not there doesn't mean there won't be an equal number of people playing Magic.
Speaker 1: True, but the only reason those Magic people are in our way is because that space is reserved for them.
Speaker 0: Right, but what I'm saying is that if WotC doesn't show up, you're still going to need all those tables to accommodate people playing Magic on their own.
Speaker 1: But as soon as they stand up, my Carcassonne game starts there.
Speaker 0: Sure.
Speaker 1: One last little news because this is kind of hilarious.
Speaker 1: Someone hacked Steam and there was a way to use their API.
Speaker 0: And Steam is like a really bad thing.
Speaker 0: It's really garbage anyway.
Speaker 1: No, but this was an interesting hack.
Speaker 1: They basically were able to list a game in Steam that you could buy.
Speaker 1: that literally no one at Valve knew about or had looked at.
Speaker 0: Whoa, that's pretty crazy.
Speaker 1: So it was a security researcher who did it and he did it as a joke.
Speaker 1: He was going to have the game appear on April Fool's Day and the game is called Watch Paint Dry.
Speaker 1: And it's basically just paint drying.
Speaker 0: I'm telling you, Valve, hire me.
Speaker 0: I'm going to redo all of Steam so that when you click on your inventory, it'll load instantly and won't be like...
Speaker 1: Why would I even want to ever click on my inventory?
Speaker 0: I'm just saying there's so much shit in Steam.
Speaker 0: Because Steam is basically just a website, right?
Speaker 0: Which is what I can make.
Speaker 0: And it's really awful, right?
Speaker 0: The Steam app is mostly just a browser with this website in it.
Speaker 0: And the website's real bad and it's real slow and I think it's all Microsoft-based actually on the back end.
Speaker 0: I could just rewrite that whole fucking thing, especially with a team of great Valve developers.
Speaker 0: Well, maybe their web developers aren't so great, but I get some other ones, redo that whole thing, and it would be amazing.
Speaker 0: And I'm sure that people also, the people who are game developers and publishers, putting their games on Steam have to deal with a lot of web interfaces and stuff that really suck.
Speaker 0: That I could also improve.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean, our friend Conrad has complained every time he's ever had to interact with Steam on the back end, so...
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: Valve is just bad at the back end things.
Speaker 0: It all started...
Speaker 1: Well, are they bad at it?
Speaker 1: Because they do a better job than anyone else.
Speaker 0: Or they just don't care, right?
Speaker 1: Who does a good job on this stuff?
Speaker 0: No one else is doing this stuff.
Speaker 1: No, I'm saying who does a good job on this sort of web front end, back end type stuff anywhere?
Speaker 1: WordPress.
Speaker 0: Alright, we got one.
Speaker 0: Any sort of, you know, thing that you would set up, like, you know, GitHub or, you know...
Speaker 1: No, they're okay.
Speaker 0: Amazon web services is much better than Steam.
Speaker 1: The Amazon console is really, of course, that's more bad UX.
Speaker 0: I'm just saying it's better than Steam.
Speaker 0: Yeah, yeah.
Speaker 0: It's better than Steam.
Speaker 0: It works, right?
Speaker 0: It's not some, you know...
Speaker 1: It does work.
Speaker 1: Of course, I haven't had problems with Steam in a while.
Speaker 0: I'm just saying, it's, you know, it's not like some weird slow-loading pages and shit, right?
Speaker 0: It's way better than Steam.
Speaker 0: Things of the day!
Speaker 0: What was my thing?
Speaker 1: Scott found this independent of me.
Speaker 1: He messaged it to me, like, "Holy
Speaker 1: crap!".
Speaker 1: But I'd already, like, flagged it as my thing of the day.
Speaker 0: I was just using it to sort of make some trash talk.
Speaker 0: that's definitely not going to actually happen.
Speaker 0: Because, as we know already, I suck at civilization.
Speaker 0: But I was like, "It's about a Bronze Age
Speaker 0: battle.".
Speaker 0: And Rym, in the two-player game we're playing, Rym is Egypt and I'm China.
Speaker 0: So I'm like, "See that skull with the spear in it?
Speaker 0: That's gonna be Ramsay's real
Speaker 0: soon.".
Speaker 0: "In his crystal ball, this is what he
Speaker 0: sees.".
Speaker 1: Are you threatening me?
Speaker 0: I'm just being silly threatening you.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna go at the beginning of this.
Speaker 1: In 1996, an amateur archaeologist found a single upper arm bone sticking out of a riverbank.
Speaker 0: Alright.
Speaker 1: Blah, blah, blah.
Speaker 1: A flint arrowhead was firmly embedded in one end of the bone.
Speaker 1: It was a really good picture.
Speaker 0: So that tells you basically immediately, "This isn't some recent murder that I'm worried about.
Speaker 0: This is an old-ass
Speaker 0: bone.".
Speaker 1: Or, maybe someone in 1910 was like, "You know what?
Speaker 1: Flint
Speaker 1: arrowheads.".
Speaker 1: And they thought, "Alright.
Speaker 1: Murder something.
Speaker 1: Maybe a small battle.
Speaker 1: We'll figure it
Speaker 1: out.".
Speaker 1: But they found evidence of a massive organized battle from at least 3,000 years ago.
Speaker 0: So they found this in 1910, so 3,000 years ago.
Speaker 0: No, no.
Speaker 1: They found this in 1996.
Speaker 1: I was saying it was a 100-year-old murder.
Speaker 0: Oh.
Speaker 0: So 1996 minus 3,000 is... 1250 BC.
Speaker 0: BC.
Speaker 0: BCE.
Speaker 1: Way old.
Speaker 0: Yup.
Speaker 0: Mad old.
Speaker 0: Like, not medieval times.
Speaker 0: Sick old.
Speaker 0: Bronze age.
Speaker 1: This is interesting.
Speaker 1: Bronze.
Speaker 1: Because there is literally no recorded evidence, no circumstantial evidence, no references, nothing.
Speaker 1: Indicating that humanity knew anything about a battle, significant civilizations, anything in that region, even remotely close to that era.
Speaker 1: And at first they thought, "Well, maybe there was a bunch of battles here over a long period of
Speaker 1: time.".
Speaker 0: Were they sure it was people?
Speaker 0: They sure it wasn't like a Neanderthal war?
Speaker 1: It's definitely people.
Speaker 0: It wasn't a monkey war?
Speaker 1: Definitely people.
Speaker 0: Elephant war?
Speaker 1: They found a lot of well-constructed bronze weapons, which in that era...
Speaker 0: Alien war?
Speaker 1: The bronze weapons in this time period would have been like the cream of the crop, like experimental weapons effectively.
Speaker 1: And it was definitely armed conflicts.
Speaker 1: Organized armed conflicts.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean this arrowhead stuck in bones.
Speaker 0: That's a pretty sick arrowhead if you can get it all the way down to the bones.
Speaker 1: But there is a big difference between armed conflict, like it could be a bunch of farmers fighting over whatever, and organized armies armed conflicts.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 0: It's not a plowshare that was stuck in a dude's head.
Speaker 0: It was an arrowhead.
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 1: One side definitely won because they found that basically all the bodies that would have been accessible were looted.
Speaker 1: And all the ones that were buried deep in water had a whole bunch of jewelry and stuff on them.
Speaker 1: And this article is just really fascinating because as much as we think we know about history, occasionally we find things like this that kind of blow up our whole perception of the history of the world.
Speaker 0: Also, the photos here are sick.
Speaker 0: Like the dude's skull with the spear stuck in it.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I do not ever want a flint arrowhead to be embedded that deeply into my arm bone.
Speaker 0: Yeah, listen guys.
Speaker 0: Everyone who's currently doing some Civil War reenacting, I'm sure in Europe they do some Bronze Age battle reenacting.
Speaker 0: And then we can find out who the people in Europe are who are the types that would reenact.
Speaker 0: So this gets even crazier.
Speaker 1: They look at this thing and they're like, well maybe there's a bunch of conflicts over a long period of time, but based on the evidence at the site, no, it was one gigantic battle.
Speaker 1: And then in 2013 they found a 120 meter long bridge used to be there.
Speaker 1: So this was a giant battle over a gigantic bridge from a time and a place where we really didn't think there were organized people.
Speaker 0: And we didn't think people knew how to make a bridge.
Speaker 1: I mean, let alone just, there's so much going on in this article.
Speaker 0: This is amazing.
Speaker 0: I'm sure this is real and not one of those people making a fake discovery to be famous with bullshit.
Speaker 1: Nah, this seems pretty legit.
Speaker 0: There's a lot of fraud in archaeology, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, that has happened.
Speaker 1: Here, quote, standardized metal weaponry and the remains of horses, which were found intermingled with human bones at one spot, suggest there are at least some combatants that were well equipped, well trained.
Speaker 1: Quote, these weren't farmer soldiers who went out every few years for a brawl.
Speaker 1: These are professional fighters.
Speaker 1: So I'm really curious to see what we can figure out from this as they start to continue to study this site.
Speaker 1: And it kind of raises interesting questions about how old the civilizations in Europe really are.
Speaker 0: Because, you know, sick old.
Speaker 1: Well, you know, the guns, germs and steel thing, the idea that the animals in Europe and the climate just happened to be more usable by humans, which gave Europe a head start.
Speaker 1: The counter theory to that is that humans were just in Europe a lot longer than we thought and made it that way.
Speaker 0: Well, sorry, guns, germs and steel.
Speaker 0: Evidence is not helping you out.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: So, yeah, this is really cool stuff.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: It's like, oh, why was Europe better?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: They built bridges while everyone else was still like, you know, cave people.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Why did so much military force conversion a narrow river valley in northern Germany?
Speaker 0: It was a bridge there.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: This is a period of significant upheaval in the Mediterranean to the Baltic.
Speaker 1: In Greece, the Mycenaean civilization was collapsing around the time of the battle.
Speaker 1: Mycenaeans, man.
Speaker 0: That's my people.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: In Egypt, pharaohs boasted about having defeated the sea people.
Speaker 1: So it's during all those times.
Speaker 0: Cyclopians.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Unknown horrors of the deep.
Speaker 1: So you got a thing of the day?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I do have a thing.
Speaker 0: So this is sort of like a mainstream thing of the day.
Speaker 0: It was all over like the trash news in, you know, basically the New York Post of the U.K.
Speaker 1: It's like basic story.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: But I think this is something not a lot of nerds have seen because it was all over the mainstream Internet.
Speaker 0: And it's really cool.
Speaker 0: Even if you don't care about sports here.
Speaker 1: I have not seen this.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Here is a dude.
Speaker 0: He's a 50 year old fisherman, which is pretty cool.
Speaker 0: You know, fisherman.
Speaker 0: It's a good thing to be.
Speaker 0: If you're like a professional fisherman, that's cool.
Speaker 0: But he's sort of fat and blobby, you know, but he's not so fat and blobby.
Speaker 0: He can't get around.
Speaker 0: He's just fat and blobby.
Speaker 1: He can really get around.
Speaker 0: And he can fucking get around with the soccer ball.
Speaker 0: Let me tell you what.
Speaker 0: Like, whoa.
Speaker 0: Like, the skills are so high with this dude.
Speaker 0: It's ridiculous.
Speaker 0: It's like, you know, it's sort of like when you see like that, you know, people are always shocked to see like an ugly person sing because usually in the music industry, they only let pretty people sing.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: No, this is like that.
Speaker 0: It's like usually you only see fit people doing athletics because, you know, you think how only fit people can do this like this is probably mad fit underneath all that blubber.
Speaker 0: But he's got the mad coordination and skills and it's awesome to watch him.
Speaker 0: And I hope maybe he could like, you know, get fit and then he could be a soccer player because he obviously likes playing soccer.
Speaker 0: So maybe he could be a soccer player and a fisherman.
Speaker 1: Also, there was that TED talk a while ago and a bunch of research backing it showing that like it's better to be skinnier, like it's better to not be obese.
Speaker 1: Like if you can just don't be fat.
Speaker 1: But if you're already fat, well, it's really, really difficult to unfat.
Speaker 1: And for some people, it might be impossible.
Speaker 1: if you're fit, like if you're physically fit and you exercise, even if you remain fat, you're like 95 percent as healthy as someone who's that fit and skinny.
Speaker 1: Like you're doing pretty well.
Speaker 1: If you can move around, this guy's probably doing all right.
Speaker 0: I mean, you know, this is you can always tell.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: You know, you see like really large, obese type people, the ones that are like a ton of muscle and, you know, that just happens to have fat around it, like the bouncer at the nightclub where it's like fucking with that guy.
Speaker 0: And then the person who's in the rover, whatever thing can walk.
Speaker 1: Well, even though they might weigh the same like NFL, the fat guy in the NFL, he would kill either one of us if he was in the same room and mad at us.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: You know, I think B.J.
Speaker 0: Raji just retired, but it's like, yeah, you're fucking with B.J.
Speaker 0: B.J.,
Speaker 0: what's up?
Speaker 1: In the moment we're going we were just at Anime Boston.
Speaker 1: Stay tuned.
Speaker 1: I'll try to get videos up soon.
Speaker 1: For those of you who care about Kinetic Con, I finally can open panel submissions.
Speaker 1: The secret is the form's already open, but I haven't tested it yet.
Speaker 1: So I'm going to futz around with it and I'm going to announce stuff.
Speaker 1: But go ahead and submit now if you want.
Speaker 1: If you're listening to Geek Nights, you know the drill.
Speaker 1: Next weekend, this coming week, so this weekend, actually, I will be without Scott.
Speaker 1: Well, I'll have a different Scott at Zenkai Con on Saturday.
Speaker 1: I'm doing how to run an anime club, analyzing anime, utenna and practical game theory.
Speaker 0: He's not telling you is that this convention is in Lancaster, Pennsylvania.
Speaker 0: Don't fucking go there.
Speaker 1: Unless you live, only go to Zenkai Con if you live within a couple hours drive.
Speaker 0: If you live mad close, you can go on Saturday only, eat some Amish food, go to the con for a bit and then get the hell out before Sunday when they don't sell any Amish food because they're all Jesus-like.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: This is a town where we went to a bar and I wanted to order beer and I asked the waitress what beers they had and they only had three, but that's fine.
Speaker 1: Small town.
Speaker 1: And she said she didn't want to say the name of the third beer.
Speaker 1: and I was like, "What can you give me a
Speaker 1: hint?".
Speaker 1: And she was like, "It's arrogant
Speaker 1: something.".
Speaker 1: And I'm like, "Oh yeah, I'll have an arrogant
Speaker 1: bastard.".
Speaker 1: She visibly, physically flinched when I said the word bastard and got really uncomfortable around us for the entire evening.
Speaker 0: Welcome to New York.
Speaker 1: Also, fucking nothing is open on Sunday except one bar.
Speaker 1: Last year we just, after we did our last panel, well I did my last panel, those of us who were there just went to this bar and drank all day until we went home playing games.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so don't go there.
Speaker 0: Instead, if you're in New York City, a good place to be, the best place to be, the Mocha Festival is happening.
Speaker 0: Yes, the Mocha Fest.
Speaker 0: It's declined in recent years, I can't lie, but it's still worth a day of your time.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there's awesome stuff there.
Speaker 1: and Emily.
Speaker 0: Emily bought a table so you can give her money if you want.
Speaker 1: Emily's going to be selling a whole bunch of stuff at her table.
Speaker 0: And she'll also be stuck in one place most of the time so she can't run away from you if you're that guy.
Speaker 1: I see her shaking her head right now.
Speaker 1: But yeah, if you want to read her book or buy her book or see a bunch of art or stuff, she'll have a bunch of her friend artist things and she'll have her own stuff.
Speaker 1: And this is the first Mocha Fest in a long time that I'm missing because Scott and I can't both bail on Zenkai Con.
Speaker 0: Why not?
Speaker 1: Professionals, we don't bail on a con.
Speaker 0: I mean, you should have bailed earlier.
Speaker 0: You could have bailed earlier.
Speaker 0: You just waited too long.
Speaker 0: Now you're stuck.
Speaker 1: Remember, one, Zenkai Con is pretty fun.
Speaker 1: And two, that's an audience that we don't reach.
Speaker 0: Like, when I present a Zenkai Con- I don't need- Listen, I'm not going to reach someone who's going to wince when I say, "Fuck
Speaker 0: you.".
Speaker 1: But a lot of the kids who go to the con are coming from Philly anyway.
Speaker 1: But I'm telling you, the kids at this con- Fuck them!
Speaker 1: We'll get like a hundred people in the room.
Speaker 0: None of them- If you live in Philly, you can go fuck yourself.
Speaker 1: I remember last year, one of the panels, I filled the room.
Speaker 1: No one in the room knew who I was or knew about Geek Nights or anything.
Speaker 1: Half of them didn't know what podcasts were and- Yeah, because they're from fucking Philly.
Speaker 0: I don't need these people.
Speaker 0: I don't want to go anywhere near them.
Speaker 1: I got to reach out.
Speaker 1: I got to evangelize the geekery.
Speaker 0: No.
Speaker 0: Why not?
Speaker 1: I thought that was the mission of Geek Nights, to expand horizons.
Speaker 0: Philadelphia people, they just need a little scorched earth policy down there.
Speaker 1: The book, I don't know why you hate Philly so much.
Speaker 1: Philly, I would rather live in than most other cities in the U.S.
Speaker 0: I mean, I guess compared to say like Jacksonville, Florida or something.
Speaker 1: I said cities.
Speaker 1: There's a lot of cities that you don't want to live in.
Speaker 1: Philly at least is cosplaying a city.
Speaker 1: Right after Zeikai Con, like a few weeks, PAX East, as we said- A real convention.
Speaker 1: Well, we'll be there on Sunday doing Atari game design.
Speaker 1: And yeah, then other conventions coming up after that.
Speaker 1: The next Book Club book's going to be Margaret Atwood, Orcs and Crake.
Speaker 1: And I think I'm going to stop reading The Wheel of Time after I finish the 11th one.
Speaker 1: And then I'm going to start reading that.
Speaker 0: Alright, I already got a copy, so I'm good.
Speaker 1: Tell me when you started.
Speaker 0: I also picked- I found a book- you stole my Book Club book.
Speaker 0: So I found another one.
Speaker 0: that's, you know, maybe the most Geek Nights book I've ever seen.
Speaker 0: that isn't Prince of Nothing.
Speaker 0: How?
Speaker 1: Okay, other than Prince of Nothing.
Speaker 1: We'll see.
Speaker 1: I'm vaguely trusting.
Speaker 1: So at PAX South, we needed a short game to play.
Speaker 0: I played this game at Kineticon last year.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and I did not, because I was doing work.
Speaker 1: So you want to introduce the game then?
Speaker 0: Yeah, okay.
Speaker 0: So it's a really tiny game.
Speaker 0: It's published by Mayfair, who I guess used to publish Settlers.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's a Wolfgang Kringemührer game, so.
Speaker 0: And it's a little tiny card game, and it's called Six Nymphs.
Speaker 0: And there's actually a whole lot going on in this tiny card game, and most of the things I have to say about it are positive.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's a- there are a lot of little games like this, like No Thanks, like all those sort of like, "Hey, it's real easy to teach.
Speaker 1: Just start playing it.
Speaker 1: You'll have some
Speaker 1: fun.".
Speaker 1: But usually those games do not hold people's attention.
Speaker 1: Like, if I bust out No Thanks, people really like it once, but no one wants to play it again right then and there.
Speaker 0: Yeah, Six Nymphs you can play quite a few times.
Speaker 1: I mean, I've taught this to people who were drinking, and had been drinking, and were yelling and socializing, and not paying attention too much, and then they are really into the game.
Speaker 0: Well, the fun part of the game, right, so here's the-.
Speaker 0: so you know Nym, Nym is the game that Rym likes, where you have sticks, and on your turn you pick up sticks, and whoever picks up the last stick loses.
Speaker 0: So it's got that unstable, stable state, combinatorial game theory going on, right?
Speaker 0: Six Nymt is basically the same game, that's why it's called Nymt, right?
Speaker 0: It's just more advanced.
Speaker 0: There's a deck of cards numbered from 1 to 104, and there's four rows.
Speaker 0: And on your turn, and everyone simultaneously turns- Two to ten players.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's great, so many players.
Speaker 0: You take a card from your hand of random cards, everyone has the same size hand, and put it face down, and then everyone simultaneously reveals.
Speaker 0: Starting with the lowest card, the cards are added to the appropriate row, the appropriate row being the row in which there is a- the rightmost card is lower than the card the person has played, and then amongst those rows, which of the cards is the highest.
Speaker 0: So if I play a 30, and one of the rows is a 29 in its rightmost spot, my 30 is going there, right?
Speaker 0: If I play a 74, and there's a row with a 94, a 63, and a 52, it's going in the row with the 63, because that's the highest number.
Speaker 0: that's lower than my 70, whatever I just said.
Speaker 0: So you just keep- everyone simultaneously reveals, and plays cards out there.
Speaker 0: Pretty simple, that's the whole rules of how to play the game, but it's Six Nymt.
Speaker 0: If you play the sixth card in a row, meaning there are already five cards in a row, and your card gets forced into that row, you take
Speaker 1: all those cards,
Speaker 0: you take all the five cards that are already there, and your sixth card replaces that row, and is now starting a new row.
Speaker 0: When you take those cards, all the cards have little pictures of bulls on them, some cards have more bullshit than others, whoever has the least bullshit wins.
Speaker 0: So you don't want to play the sixth card in a row.
Speaker 0: Also, the only other rule, if you play a card, and the number on that card is lower than the rightmost cards of every row of all four rows, you pick a row to take, it could be a tiny row with only one card in it, which would be awesome.
Speaker 1: There might not be a tiny row.
Speaker 0: There might not be a tiny row, and then your card makes a new row that is lower than all the other rows, and then everyone else's card comes out according to the rules.
Speaker 1: And then it's basically hearts rules, you keep playing until someone hits 66, because six is a number in this game, and then whoever has the lowest score wins, if there's a tie, joint victory, it's a whole game.
Speaker 0: Right, so here's what makes the game really interesting, right?
Speaker 1: It's got some gobs going on, other than that, not all the cards are out.
Speaker 1: So, nothing changes, you've got ten cards, you've got to play all ten, everyone's got to play ten cards.
Speaker 0: It's just which order you're going to play them in, right?
Speaker 0: So you're looking at the board state, and there's different moves you can try.
Speaker 0: For example, if there's not a lot of cards in the rows, maybe you could just try to get rid of your low cards, and take some low points, and then hope later in the round you'll be safe, and other people end up taking the big cards.
Speaker 1: But, if you have only high cards, the board could get a range, or the table could get a range in such a way, that all the high cards you have are very likely to take some old terrible row that's full of bulls.
Speaker 0: Right, also, let's say you've got the 104 in your hand, the highest card in the game.
Speaker 0: You could try to play it right away, and that would basically go in the final row.
Speaker 0: Like, say the final row has a 54 in it, you could put the 104 right next to it, and now anything less than 104 is going in row three.
Speaker 0: And nothing new is going in row four at all, because nothing's higher than 104.
Speaker 0: And now, someone puts a 90-something in row three, and now every new card is going in rows one and two, and suddenly, the game gets really hairy until somebody plays a super low card, and intentionally takes row three and four, and you can create this lockdown effect, right?
Speaker 0: So you have all these different ways you can play.
Speaker 0: You could intentionally try to take those rows to unlock the game, and maybe you'll get less points now in order to get even, you know, to lower the total points you would've taken if you didn't open the game up, or maybe you can just keep holding out, hoping that someone else bites the bullet, and ends up taking the nymph, and then you can clear your hand and get zero points, and woo!
Speaker 1: And, yeah, like, think about that.
Speaker 1: you've played that strategy of, I play the high number to lock something down, so I play the 104.
Speaker 1: What if all the other players play, like, 55, 58, 60, and then I just take the row and I'm completely screwed?
Speaker 0: Sometimes there'd be only a little bit of space between rows, and, like, you have the card that fits there, and, like, and, like, there'll be a 94 in a row, and the next row has, like, 100 in it, so the only cards that can go in that third row would be, like, 95, 96, 97, 98, 99, so only, like, five or six cards, right?
Speaker 0: And there's four cards in the row.
Speaker 0: Someone else is like, "Ahaha, I'll play my 97,".
Speaker 0: and then it'll go right there in that row, and there's no way I'm taking that row, 'cause no one's gonna play any card, right?
Speaker 0: And someone else is gonna have to take that row, and somebody sneaks in with, like, one of the two cards that could've fucked you, and now you take that row.
Speaker 0: It's like,
Speaker 0: "Ahhh!".
Speaker 1: What is fascinating is how drastically different the game is with every number of players.
Speaker 0: Oh, huge difference.
Speaker 1: The three-player game, the four-player game.
Speaker 0: Tremendous differences.
Speaker 1: Might as well be different games.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 0: When you play, once you get to six players, that makes the biggest gap, because suddenly, you can just, boom, oh, actually, with five players, 'cause every row already has a card in it, right?
Speaker 0: As soon as you get to five players, it changes drastically, 'cause if everyone plays a card for the same row, you can just play something that looked totally safe and end up taking a whole bunch of cards right away.
Speaker 1: Yep, like, in three- and four-player, there'll be rows where everyone is guaranteed to be able to play something safe, and as a result, the game will often get locked up pretty quick, and then it'll come down to, did the person who locked it up have cards to make the game cycle where they will, every round, take no points, and someone else will take a bunch of points, which we saw happen reliably.
Speaker 1: There was always one person who just got wrecked in that situation.
Speaker 0: I mean, I can't say this game has a lot of strategy, but it also has a lot of luck, right?
Speaker 0: At the beginning of the game, you deal with, what, ten cards to every player?
Speaker 1: Yep, and there's 104 cards in the deck.
Speaker 0: So even if you play with the max of ten players, there's four missing cards, right?
Speaker 0: But there is significant luck.
Speaker 0: If you could just get, like, all low cards, it could happen.
Speaker 0: But!
Speaker 0: There's no reason it couldn't happen.
Speaker 0: You can get a really bad mix of cards such that you're just screwed.
Speaker 1: But playing multiple games and all that actually helps a lot.
Speaker 1: The fact that you keep playing games of it.
Speaker 0: Right, yes.
Speaker 0: Because it's not one round doesn't determine the whole thing, right?
Speaker 0: You play until someone gets 66, so even if you get screwed one round, you play enough rounds that theoretically, if you're good at the game, you're gonna win because it evens out over the course, right?
Speaker 1: Yep, yep.
Speaker 0: So what makes the game super fun, even if you don't get to the deep strategies and everything, is just that nymph mechanic is like an exciting hot potato kind of deal.
Speaker 0: The drama of there's this row building up with a bunch of bulls in it, and who's gonna, is someone gonna take it?
Speaker 0: Is somebody forced to take it because they have a bad card and they're just holding out waiting to play it?
Speaker 1: It's a game where everyone's cards go out safely, and then everyone's like, "Oh no!
Speaker 1: Oh
Speaker 1: no!".
Speaker 1: because there's a bunch of full rows and it's super dangerous.
Speaker 0: It's like when someone takes the big row, it's like the hot potato exploded on them.
Speaker 1: Like,
Speaker 1: "Oh!".
Speaker 1: It ends up being a really high drama game.
Speaker 1: Like, people get really intense about it.
Speaker 0: Right, and what really increases the drama even more is that every card doesn't have the same number of bulls on it, right?
Speaker 0: Some cards have just way more bulls on them.
Speaker 0: So it's like, you could have a row and even only with two cards in it, could have more bulls than a row with like five cards that only have one bull each.
Speaker 0: And that could be like, so someone could end up taking that, and it really sucks.
Speaker 0: Really sucks.
Speaker 1: So, I guess what I'm really amazed by even more than that is the mechanical.
Speaker 1: It's a sound game, it's quick to play, but people really like it, even though when you first show it to them, they see these hundred and four, you tell someone, "Alright, this game has cards numbered between one and a hundred and
Speaker 1: four.".
Speaker 0: And the only thing that's fun appearance-wise and aesthetically is the art is a little bit fun, right?
Speaker 0: But it's just outlines of bullheads.
Speaker 0: There's not much going on there.
Speaker 0: Other games have cute graphics or animals or characters.
Speaker 0: It's just bullheads and numbers.
Speaker 1: You kind of get to rope people in and be like, "Hey, I'll teach you the
Speaker 1: game.".
Speaker 1: And you can teach it so fast that they're like,
Speaker 1: "Oh.".
Speaker 0: I just taught it to you.
Speaker 0: Usually when we teach board games, we'll give sort of an explanation on the show, but not go into every detail.
Speaker 0: I literally told you a hundred percent of the rules in this game.
Speaker 1: But what makes the game great, the reason you can play it with people, even if they're distracted, even if they're drunk.
Speaker 0: All you do is play a card.
Speaker 0: There's no other weird decisions to make.
Speaker 0: And then everything after the playing of the card is not decisions, but just execution.
Speaker 0: If one person can do the execution, then it's drunk enough, at least sober enough to do the execution.
Speaker 1: So think about that.
Speaker 1: All you have to do is pick a card from your hand, thinking, and once everyone's ready, it's simultaneous reveal, and then there's no more thinking.
Speaker 1: It's just play out what happens.
Speaker 1: Play out the drama.
Speaker 0: And you do it ten times game over.
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 1: Now with ten players, you've dealt out a hundred cards.
Speaker 0: The four left are the ones that start the rows.
Speaker 1: So you pretty much know that every card's out there.
Speaker 1: So then it becomes multiplayer GOPS, effectively.
Speaker 0: Yeah, because you'll see, like, well, there's a 94 and a 97.
Speaker 0: I could try for the 96, but I know the 95 exists and is in someone's hand because it hasn't been played yet.
Speaker 0: But counting cards becomes a big deal because once a row is taken, you've got to remember what was in there.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but at least unlike GOPS, one person might have the 96 and the 97 and the 98.
Speaker 1: Like, you don't know.
Speaker 1: It's not like everyone has the same hand.
Speaker 0: That's entirely possible, yes.
Speaker 1: Because the thing about GOPS to make it a hundred percent pure is that everyone has the exact same hand as well.
Speaker 1: But if you need to get paid, this replaces No.
Speaker 1: Thanks for Me as the "Hey guys, wanna play a quick
Speaker 1: game?"
Speaker 1: at a con.
Speaker 1: Like, let's just go.
Speaker 1: Play a game.
Speaker 1: Spot it or this.
Speaker 1: They're, like, perfect for this purpose.
Speaker 0: Also, you can get this game way cheap.
Speaker 0: I remember at PAX, they had it at the Mayfair booth, like, stacks of it, and it was, like, mad discounted.
Speaker 1: I think I paid, like, four bucks for my copy.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they're trying to get rid of these.
Speaker 0: You can probably get two of these and give them as a gift.
Speaker 0: Great gift.
Speaker 0: Great gift for someone who plays some games or even the non-gamer type.
Speaker 0: So cheap.
Speaker 1: This has been Geek Nights with Rim and Scott.
Speaker 1: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design, and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at FrontRowCrew.com for show notes, discussion news, and more.
Speaker 1: Remember, Geek Nights is not one, but four different shows.
Speaker 1: Sci-Tech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays, and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 0: Geek Nights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 0: Geek Nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 0: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.
Speaker 1: And the Patreon Patrons for this episode of Geek Nights.
Speaker 1: In order of the amount of money they give us, if they give us at least $5 are... Rebecca Dunn, Nicholas Brandow, Alan Joyce, Heidi McNichol, Amanda Duchette, James David White, Chris Chien, thanks for consistently pronouncing it correctly, Kuntz, Jess, MyStady.com, Mechanical Mind, William Eisenroz, Jeremy Minor, HowMuchMudGoodMudKipKipMudKipKipMud, Tyler Eller, Scott John Harrison, Sean Yeager, Clinton Walton, Ren from New Zealand, Robert Lee, Ryan Perrin, Drew Openlander, Rara Lavelle, Brian Cidroni, Rochelle Montanona, Finn Eric Silverheart, CantmeltSteelBeams, Kinetic Man, Aaron Cerise, Chris Midkiff, Chris Knox, Flame Darkfire, Sam Cordery, Daniel Redman, Chris Hadad, Sean Klein, Chris Reimer, and Thomas Hahn.
Speaker 1: So in the two player game of Civ, because I know Scott won't listen to this that we're playing right now, the one on the bus, he feels like he's doing okay.
Speaker 1: He does not understand the extent of the army that I have hanging out on this island.
Speaker 1: that I won't let him see because he only has one trireme and I just attack him anytime he comes anywhere near it.
Speaker 1: I'm just massing troops over there and when we start the game on the way to PAX, I just have to pick the moment when I'm going to go over the sea and just destroy him.
Speaker 1: So in the game we're playing now, I can see a hut.
Speaker 1: I was lying.
Speaker 1: I can definitely see a hut.
Speaker 1: I want him to feel like he's getting ahead.
Speaker 1: I want him to feel like he's really got things going on and I'm going to try to hide the army that I'm going to build like in a corner of the continent where he's not going to look like up north.
Speaker 1: And I'm pretty confident that I can wait for a hilariously opportune moment and suddenly the forces come over the hill.
Speaker 1: Stay tuned for all our stuff.
Speaker 1: We did record Judge Anime by its cover at Anime Boston.
Speaker 1: We also did record How to Run an Anime Club and Role Playing Anime.
Speaker 1: So I might make those available to at least you patrons, even if they're not necessarily good enough quality to put on the general geek nights, public whatever.
Speaker 1: And now I leave you with something kind of weird and dumb.
Speaker 0: Woman's log number 224 wrapped land isn't wrapping anymore.
Speaker 0: Cooper took their king and the money too.
Speaker 1: We're here to figure out what to do.
Speaker 1: I'll bet Cooper's going to get that gold.
Speaker 0: But how's he making them do what they're told?
Speaker 1: I'm wrapping, Cooper.
Speaker 1: Do what I say.
Speaker 1: Bring me your gold coins right away.
Speaker 1: Yo, King James, you're a dweeb.
Speaker 1: I run wrapped land.
Speaker 1: I'm never going to leave.
Speaker 0: Who be a chump, you ugly fang face?
Speaker 0: My plaid boy is going to bring me from this place.
Speaker 0: Plaid boy, smair boy, hey, hey, hey.