Speaker 1: It's Tuesday March 15th 2016.
Speaker 1: I'm rim, I'm Scott and this is geek night tonight gaming news.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: So many of you might have been wondering what was up with my Twitter the other night between me and Emily.
Speaker 0: I think most people listening are not reading your Twitter.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't know I got more followers than you.
Speaker 0: I don't really care.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I do.
Speaker 0: how many people are actually reading that?
Speaker 0: uh?
Speaker 1: I think a reasonable number.
Speaker 1: a few people reacted to what I true.
Speaker 1: so basically what happened was something happened, and I was typing some tweets like hey guys what's going on?
Speaker 1: and I'd like tweeted one, and then I realized there was a typo.
Speaker 1: so I deleted it And then I retweeted it.
Speaker 1: But because I did that after I'd sent the second tweet it ended up in my timeline sending one tweet before the other one.
Speaker 1: So the first thing that I actually said was basically We're at the ER now Emily's getting her eye checked out.
Speaker 1: the explosion was substantial But we're mostly okay like something like that, but I didn't even have an eyepatch.
Speaker 0: I was disappointed.
Speaker 0: Yeah, though, so what happened was Disappointed because I wanted to get hurt more.
Speaker 0: I want a cool eyepatch.
Speaker 0: I Would know if I was there.
Speaker 0: I would have worn one even if I didn't need it It was.
Speaker 1: luckily it is the part of the eye that Emily got cut on.
Speaker 1: is the part that doesn't make you see well the Part that also apparently heals really really fast?
Speaker 1: yeah, but yeah So we're.
Speaker 0: I've been cut there as well.
Speaker 0: I got I was think we're at the beach when I was a kid me and my friend was throwing sand at each other.
Speaker 1: That's the kind of thing you're doing.
Speaker 1: you're a kid like you.
Speaker 0: don't Balls of wet sand just throwing them at each other real hard like today Scott.
Speaker 1: if I threw sand at you one I'd be worried that I'd hurt your eyes.
Speaker 1: You'd be really worried that I hurt your eyes.
Speaker 1: We wouldn't throw sand at each other like.
Speaker 1: I can imagine what would happen if I threw sand at you and my brain says hey Cut it out Imagining being hit by sand and you're like oh fuck no and that is called empathy But as a kid we're just throwing sand at each other.
Speaker 0: We didn't give a fuck.
Speaker 1: I got my eye scratched once Messing around with the dogs.
Speaker 0: My eye was not as ugly looking as Emily's is but it I had to wear an eyepatch and shit and put like cream in it every day.
Speaker 1: Well, you might have had a puncture an infection or something.
Speaker 0: I had to put cream in there every day.
Speaker 1: Emily just had a four millimeter cut Mm-hmm on the sclera.
Speaker 1: But so basically where I'm sitting exactly where I am now and Emily sitting next to me and we're both working on stuff.
Speaker 1: Yeah I'm working on projects and I have the Red Wings game on and I literally say hey the game started again and Emily turns around Toward me and then there's an explosion Really loud and we are showered in broken glass.
Speaker 1: So it took my brain easily a couple seconds to figure out that it wasn't the window getting blown out By like a bomb or something or the construction.
Speaker 1: Yeah, because I mean there's construction for all I know a crane just like crashed through the window.
Speaker 0: I mean, yeah, I would definitely immediately assume something happened to the construction.
Speaker 1: so we're both sitting there like I have my eyes closed and I kind of look up and Emily's sitting there with her head down and I shake myself and all the broken glass kind of comes off of me out of the Floor like alright and I look and Emily does the same thing and I look up and I see that the tempered glass Shield on top of a light.
Speaker 0: that's in the room really weird light.
Speaker 1: It's a standard torch air like.
Speaker 1: there's nothing special about that.
Speaker 0: It's a weirdo light as a perfectly standard form of light.
Speaker 0: No, there's only one standard form of light.
Speaker 0: That is a light bulb on a stick.
Speaker 1: That is just a light bulb on a stick Scott with it with a shade around.
Speaker 0: There's a shade.
Speaker 0: It's upwards upside down.
Speaker 1: You want the diffuse light to bounce off the ceiling.
Speaker 1: come back down.
Speaker 1: That's like nice modern lighting design.
Speaker 0: No, I want a normal lamp.
Speaker 0: That's like next to you.
Speaker 1: I could also have that.
Speaker 0: I guess Hey lamp, how you doing?
Speaker 0: So or you know fishnet leg lamp.
Speaker 1: So the funny thing is the light was still on and it still works just fine.
Speaker 1: It wasn't the halogen bulb that exploded like you'd expect.
Speaker 0: that would be really weird.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so What actually happened and this is you know, all the news reports to read will say it's uncommon.
Speaker 1: But I've run into this enough times in my life to know it's a thing.
Speaker 1: Tempered glass, you know safety glass the kind of glass you use if you have like a table or a windshield.
Speaker 1: So laminated is one part but also but that's not all of it Tempered glass is also way stronger than regular glass and if it shatters or breaks It'll break into small pieces.
Speaker 1: so it won't cut you because if you break a normal window you get big old chunks.
Speaker 0: Yeah chunks that are dangerous and sharp.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like if you think like oh, I'll just punch through a window You'll probably cut yourself so bad.
Speaker 1: You have to go to the hospital.
Speaker 0: That's why you should wrap a towel around your hand and then punch the window.
Speaker 1: Yes So and safety glass also.
Speaker 0: don't punch one of those a modern window because it's usually two pieces of glass one after the other.
Speaker 1: Well more importantly if you punch a modern window, you'll probably just break yourself and not the window.
Speaker 0: It's also true unless you're really good at punching.
Speaker 1: So tempered glass is amazing.
Speaker 1: It's super strong.
Speaker 1: Like it's pretty much invincible.
Speaker 0: There's a reason they don't use it on phones.
Speaker 1: Uh So actually apparently people buy tempered glass screen protectors and Some phones have used tempered glass in the past.
Speaker 0: Usually they use my gorilla grass or sapphire.
Speaker 1: What probable the gorilla glass might be a form of tempered glass.
Speaker 1: I'm actually not sure.
Speaker 1: I don't know what gorilla glass is made about.
Speaker 0: I haven't been to the glass museum in like ten years.
Speaker 1: So so tempered glass effectively or the ten years has the outside of it Under extreme compressive force all the time.
Speaker 1: by the way They made it and the inside of it has the opposite.
Speaker 1: so it's actually sparse and the effect of this is that the whole thing is Straining at itself all the time.
Speaker 0: Isn't that the same things like a King Rupert's drop?
Speaker 1: Yes It's actually as far as I can tell in my layman's understanding of physics a very similar principle Except it doesn't have Prince Rupert not King Rupert.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it doesn't have the Vulnerable tail at the end.
Speaker 0: It's sort of like wrapped around itself or maybe the vulnerable tail is just you don't know where it is Mixed in.
Speaker 1: so basically if there is a flaw Unless you test it which will cause it to shatter at the time.
Speaker 1: You made it.
Speaker 1: There's no way to know.
Speaker 1: it all looks the same and apparently most tempered glass companies don't test Because it costs the money.
Speaker 1: and why bother?
Speaker 0: well, I mean usually people even like people that make really fancy things.
Speaker 0: It's like I know cameras like they'll test like every tenth camera or something because it's like testing all of them takes too much time And you're making too many of them basically tempered glass if it has a microscopic defect in it at any point.
Speaker 1: Then it may at some point in the next 10 to 30 years for literally no measurable demonstrable or repeatable reason Explode violently.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: And if you go on YouTube You'll find a lot like the very regular news story of some people are home and they hear an explosion.
Speaker 0: No, no one was lucky enough to have the camera rolling just while it happened.
Speaker 1: There are a bunch of videos of it happening on like security cameras and things and it's a thing.
Speaker 1: So we bought a new torsion lamp and I'm gonna try something.
Speaker 1: I bought a halogen.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah So I got.
Speaker 1: I bought.
Speaker 1: I have a halogen one that I might buy another one of the one I'm touching right now in the studio.
Speaker 1: Cuz I like it, but I got an LED one that has a ring of LEDs on the top and I'm gonna see if that's actually bright enough.
Speaker 1: It is very hard to research on the internet to find out how bright lamps are.
Speaker 1: everyone just lies like the manufacturers Make up bullshit about how bright their lamps are.
Speaker 0: I bought an LED light bulb just to put in a regular old lamp.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and it's totally fine.
Speaker 1: Yep, but I don't know if it'll produce enough lumens to illuminate an entire room.
Speaker 1: We're gonna find out.
Speaker 0: you just need more of them maybe but I mean it's as bright as a 60 watt or whatever bulb.
Speaker 0: So it's the same thing.
Speaker 1: So anyway, we shake ourselves off and I'm like, I think I'm okay How about you?
Speaker 1: and Emily says I think I'm fine and then she looks up at me and I see blood Trickling out of her eye and I see blood The worst possible place.
Speaker 1: She's like do I look okay, and I'm like and I'm doing that like yeah But maybe we should go to a clinic just in case you know as I like starting to google for like where the nearest emergency Is.
Speaker 1: So, uh, yeah it ended up being fine and actually the doctor we saw was really funny and really nerdy and I counted for a Lot and we were kind of talking shot up out of hospitals.
Speaker 1: and the final funny that I have is that while we were waiting I was explaining how ICD codes work and I used to work in hospitals a long time ago.
Speaker 1: I've dealt with all this crap.
Speaker 1: So the way you code an injury I was trying to figure out what the code was gonna be for glass in the eyeball.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and I think I figured it out.
Speaker 1: I should go check once I get the insurance thing back, but then I realized in a moment of glory You know the picture of an eyeball and then a picture of a knife and then a picture of a skull.
Speaker 1: So Here's the side.
Speaker 1: do not ever google for different kinds of eye injuries.
Speaker 1: No, do not figure out how bad they are.
Speaker 1: No, you will see the worst things you've ever seen.
Speaker 1: rotten knuckle Good God right there.
Speaker 1: It was like a screw like in an eye.
Speaker 0: Like if there's two boxes and one of them says goatee and the other one says eye injury Let's just open the goatee box.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 1: Hey, but awesome But I Realized what.
Speaker 1: so, you know your clever idea.
Speaker 1: if you want to get like all the New York sports jerseys But have the names like rot to like rotated across all the different sports.
Speaker 1: Sure I want to do a hockey jersey, but I want to have the ice the International ICD code For an injury caused by a pie hockey puck specifically to the striking you in the face.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and that code is like w 220 220 or something like that.
Speaker 1: That's what I'm gonna get on my Rangers Jersey.
Speaker 1: sure It's no good.
Speaker 1: I already have a Red Wings Jersey.
Speaker 1: I'm also gonna get a Red Wings Jersey.
Speaker 1: And so I actually have a conundrum.
Speaker 1: We saw the Isabelle cup Like I saw the cup come out first time I've ever seen and anyone for anyone seen.
Speaker 0: But it's the first time ever seen before cup.
Speaker 1: It's the first time I have ever seen in person a hockey game where an end dot star HL Cup came out.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm, and it was actually kind of exciting.
Speaker 1: So I kind of want a riveters Jersey because they're the New York team But I kind of want a Boston Pride Jersey because they're far and away the best team.
Speaker 0: Well, I mean we went to that footy game, right?
Speaker 0: Would you button?
Speaker 1: but we chose the Jersey based on who had the best logo right and I think stealth jet wins the logo.
Speaker 0: I think they were also the home team and we weren't, you know aware before the game started who was better.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I saw that stealth bomber logo and I was like, that's the one that team.
Speaker 1: Yeah Anyway, yeah, so that was an exciting night But actually the emergency room in Queens at that hospital right by Scott so on this being renovated.
Speaker 1: Yeah Way, okay, like you just went into.
Speaker 0: the good time might have been.
Speaker 1: it was real crowded But everyone's got a chill.
Speaker 1: it was it was the opposite of that time.
Speaker 1: you and Emily took me to get my finger sewn back.
Speaker 0: I mean, it wasn't.
Speaker 0: it wasn't like.
Speaker 0: that was a Newburgh Hospital.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you can.
Speaker 0: you could have gone to a Bronx Hospital, right?
Speaker 0: It's like yeah You were in Astoria Hospital.
Speaker 1: Yeah, also having worked in emergency rooms all over the Bronx in an earlier life Uh Yeah, the emergency room in that hospital in Queens way better.
Speaker 1: if you're in the Bronx and you hurt yourself I would suggest you make your way down to queen promise.
Speaker 0: So the reason that hospital is being redone actually is because the town Councilman who is the Greek guy because they voted for the Greek guy no matter what.
Speaker 1: that's how Queen Astoria does.
Speaker 0: yeah, one of his like campaign promises was redoing that hospital.
Speaker 0: and the reason is because like his dad had a heart attack or a stroke or something and Ambulance took him all the way to Manhattan and he was like what the fuck there's a hospital in Astoria, right?
Speaker 0: My dad would have been better off if you would have gotten the hospital sooner.
Speaker 0: Obviously, that's a big factor, right?
Speaker 0: Why didn't you take him there?
Speaker 0: They're like the hospitals too small.
Speaker 0: So he's like, I'm gonna make it bigger.
Speaker 1: So it's weird that that sort of selfish like personal experience is what drives someone to political action.
Speaker 1: But at the same time if Hitler saves a puppy still saved a puppy.
Speaker 0: Is it necessarily good that the hospitals getting bigger or is that just a corrupt thing?
Speaker 1: Well, I we can see really need that hospital be big.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we do.
Speaker 0: Our hospitals are in really sad state But I mean that specific one in that specific spot.
Speaker 1: I'll take any better hospital.
Speaker 1: Do you really think that if that hospital didn't get better some other hospital was gonna get better?
Speaker 0: Maybe a second hospital a better idea.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think I said the only thing that would happen is some other Representative Monster in that hospital.
Speaker 1: Yeah thing is enlightened self-interest.
Speaker 1: That's the hospital I can get to on the end train.
Speaker 1: That's where you can walk to it.
Speaker 0: It's on crescent.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we actually took the subway to the hospital, but after I determined that the blood was not continuing to gush out of Emily's eye.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you don't pay ambulance fee if you don't have to.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if someone can ask if they're okay, then you probably don't need an ambulance.
Speaker 1: Yeah, usually but what about the situation where the person like in like there's?
Speaker 1: this is a classic scene in horror movies where the person Looks up and you see their face and they look fine and they ask hey, am I okay?
Speaker 1: Okay, and then it pans to the other person's face and they look horrified.
Speaker 1: and then it pans back and you see like the poles Sticking out of their chest.
Speaker 0: that doesn't really happen.
Speaker 1: I'll bet that happens.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I will bet that happens.
Speaker 0: I assume if you have you're impaled you're not talking.
Speaker 1: Anyway, you got any news or any things.
Speaker 1: or should we get into the gaming news roundup?
Speaker 0: Non gaming news.
Speaker 0: this really I think I might have had one, but I forgot it.
Speaker 0: So who gives a shit?
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's a double Super Tuesday.
Speaker 1: Donald Trump's probably gonna get the Republican nomination, which that is my sport to watch.
Speaker 0: It's not a sport.
Speaker 1: It is a sport on it.
Speaker 1: It's a mind sport.
Speaker 0: It's not you know What.
Speaker 1: if so in that panel at magfest we have mind sport and like sports sport and a mind sport.
Speaker 0: You have to win by your own skills.
Speaker 1: So this is a third one.
Speaker 1: It's a money sport.
Speaker 0: It doesn't count.
Speaker 0: see also Money is not Not a sport.
Speaker 1: things of the day.
Speaker 1: So nowadays the computers we don't really think much about random access memory.
Speaker 1: It's just your computers have RAM.
Speaker 1: It's not like the random access is different from the other kinds of access because faster Everything that you interact your hard drives are random access.
Speaker 0: Computers these days have like all.
Speaker 0: it's basically, you know You need lots of memory, right and you want it to all be as fast as possible and have as much of it as possible.
Speaker 0: But the faster it is like l1 cache like the fat or registers the fastest possible memory.
Speaker 0: They just can't be that big because of physical limitations.
Speaker 0: So then we have l1 cache, which is like, okay We can make this a little bigger than registers and it's ridiculously fast.
Speaker 0: We put it like right next to it so he can still only have so much of it We can't have like.
Speaker 0: it would be so awesome if you could have like 500 gigabytes of l1 cache it and not need any other storage whatsoever.
Speaker 0: Yeah, okay, but we can't do that yet.
Speaker 0: So then we have l2 cache l3 and we have basically all the way down to your hard drive Which is multiple terabytes and it's still really really fast.
Speaker 0: It's faster than like Registers used to I don't know as fast and registers used to be in old computers but it's faster than RAM used to be my computers most ways to get data in and out of Processing machines.
Speaker 1: for most like much of the early history of computing as in like this Some of the stuff was still in use when we were born like was sequential access.
Speaker 0: Yeah I mean usually you had a computer and you would input with switches or tape or Cards and then it would output with lights or something like that.
Speaker 0: And then the only storage would be like flip actual flip-flops, right?
Speaker 0: Or maybe made of transistors.
Speaker 0: or maybe you're writing bits out to another tape or something or you have relays that like physical switches.
Speaker 0: They go kachunk kachunk and that's where the memory is stored, right?
Speaker 1: But the idea of addressing a particular part of your storage to get a particular thing right a real to real tape.
Speaker 0: You can't address it Just.
Speaker 0: it just allows you to have a really big output.
Speaker 0: But you have to output everything all at once and then you can read it back all at once just like you can't.
Speaker 0: it's hard Fast-forward and rewind and zoom get to the exact spot on a cassette tape.
Speaker 0: So this you drive yourself insane.
Speaker 1: so the kind of stuff I'm talking about is from the era where it was literally feasible if you had a network device or a way to communicate with another device.
Speaker 1: a Feasible way to get more storage would be to send data to someone knowing that it'll come back to you milliseconds later and By offloading data like that.
Speaker 1: You could use that as a poor man's RAM.
Speaker 0: Well, yeah, I mean if you play any of the Zachtronics games, especially the new one where that's like assembly code What the hell's the name of the stupid thing?
Speaker 0: Oh, uh Space cam no space cam is the old one.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there's the new one the one where you're programming a computer.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you literally have to do that.
Speaker 1: I see something.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they don't give you RAM really.
Speaker 0: so a lot of times we have to do is take another node and all that node will do is basically accept an input and Then send that output out another, you know port on request.
Speaker 0: that way It's basically acting as a space to store like a byte of memory, right, but it's really just another computer.
Speaker 0: So it's like you have to.
Speaker 0: you have two computers.
Speaker 0: They only consist of transistors and flip-flops and whatever, you know.
Speaker 0: But you can say hey listen send these bits over to that computer.
Speaker 0: that computer is program.
Speaker 0: Hey Scott Say take input store and register when and then if you receive this input send your the memory that's in your register to the output.
Speaker 1: Yep, or like hey Scott saved the number eight to me in 12 seconds like that kind of nonsense.
Speaker 1: This is a collection of early random access devices.
Speaker 1: eight like See, I wasn't listening.
Speaker 1: I'm fucked.
Speaker 1: That's gone for that.
Speaker 1: That number is gone forever.
Speaker 0: So we're talking about dektrons Williams tubes, which are literally I've never seen.
Speaker 0: I've never seen most of these things.
Speaker 1: So Williams tube you basically have a monitor and you illuminate a dot on it and Before the dot fades you look back to see what was there.
Speaker 1: so you basically have a monitor that is ran.
Speaker 0: Is it a cathode ray?
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's a cathode ray tube because castle.
Speaker 0: so it's a camera and a TV hooked up back to back.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so think of a mod like a traditional CRT.
Speaker 1: It's scanning right but theoretically it can address any individual point on the CRT.
Speaker 1: It's just.
Speaker 1: that would be stupid and useless unless you were trying to use your monitor as RAM.
Speaker 0: But TV camera is the same thing.
Speaker 0: It's a cathode ray.
Speaker 0: it just goes in reverse and scans the image into the signal and then you send that second runs over to the TV that Mercury back out delay lines.
Speaker 1: I mean some of this stuff is terrifying.
Speaker 1: Core memory, which?
Speaker 0: why didn't you save this for Monday?
Speaker 0: because this is Interesting isn't core memory like the way like I mean a bio?
Speaker 0: Bios is like a circuit breaker right a grid of circuit breakers.
Speaker 0: core memory is a grid of ferrite cores.
Speaker 0: That's similar to a BIOS, I guess they're not Fuses though.
Speaker 0: There's a YouTube.
Speaker 1: now There's a YouTube video on this link that shows you what core memory looks like and how it works.
Speaker 1: And there are people whose hobby is to make core memory the same way that nerds make chain mail.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm It's cool that you do.
Speaker 0: they use their commit their computers, I guess.
Speaker 1: But apparently core memory was almost always made by hand and that's why it was so expensive.
Speaker 1: there.
Speaker 1: You couldn't make a machine to make it efficiently interesting.
Speaker 0: I'm sure we could now if we wanted to but we don't need to.
Speaker 0: yeah, I don't know.
Speaker 0: probably could anyway You know what?
Speaker 1: You could make you.
Speaker 1: so oh my god.
Speaker 1: So, let's see quite a memory.
Speaker 0: Why don't we try to shrink our memory?
Speaker 1: core memory cost about a dollar per bit?
Speaker 0: Yeah her Bit.
Speaker 1: Yeah Bit yeah Ten bits.
Speaker 0: Anyway I do so.
Speaker 0: you ever watch anime or maybe like a sci-fi movie and at the beginning there's always that villain Given his presentation like thinking like the guy in Robocop given a presentation about like the the evil robot, right?
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, or What's another good example?
Speaker 0: rezo and copy rezo like here's my evil plan and all the magical diagrams of how I'm gonna destroy the world Or whatever I imagine like a Steve Jobs presentation only blatantly evil and obviously selling you a bad thing to the evil military.
Speaker 1: You know what like the Steve Jobs parody with the devil and Rick and Morty.
Speaker 0: Sure that I haven't seen okay.
Speaker 1: You should watch Rick and Morty, right?
Speaker 0: I mean this, you know, imagine like say like giving a presentation and like the instrumentality project, right?
Speaker 1: You know that gave me an idea for a fun thing.
Speaker 1: I should make say lays PowerPoints.
Speaker 1: Just make that as like an account.
Speaker 0: I mean, that's a common trope in movies right now.
Speaker 0: You would never think that anywhere on earth would anyone actually give a presentation with that aesthetic.
Speaker 0: That's not a parody or a joke or because they're acting in a movie.
Speaker 0: But in fact that is what happens in this video.
Speaker 0: is a man named Lee Su man, right and he is the CEO Head whatever chairman of SM Entertainment.
Speaker 0: I think yes.
Speaker 1: He's the Scorpio.
Speaker 0: It's SM Entertainment because his name is Su man.
Speaker 0: That's why it's SM Entertainment and the slogan of SM Entertainment has always been like the future of culture technology, right?
Speaker 0: Which is really cool slogan of scariness.
Speaker 0: And he gave this presentation recently right which despite being like a company that makes kpop and shit This presentation is basically evil corporation the stereotypical presentation.
Speaker 0: Wow It's so frightening.
Speaker 0: This is why it's like he's showing off like you'd be.
Speaker 0: think he's about to demonstrate like his new laser weapon to take over the world.
Speaker 0: When he's talking about like first we train people and then we produce really good music and then we market them.
Speaker 1: It's like that board meeting and kill la kill with the evil company.
Speaker 1: I mean these.
Speaker 0: he's actually presenting this plan whereby he's going to make a kpop group called NCT That exists everywhere in the world and has you know a group in everyone's hometown.
Speaker 1: It's kind of shit that he's gonna deploy.
Speaker 0: He's gonna deploy his new culture technology worldwide and at the end of the presentation He has a bunch of people come in wearing masks doing a spooky dance.
Speaker 1: This is the kind of shit you see I'm using on the news in the background at the beginning of an apocalypse movie.
Speaker 0: Yeah or these subtitles would be straight out of anime like that or something you see on like a Commercial for a blatantly evil product.
Speaker 1: in total recall I can explain the concept of SM's culture technology CT very easily through our artists development system.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so you should just watch this because even if it's the most hilarious But also frightening presentation ever.
Speaker 1: What's with this?
Speaker 1: Like say lay look at the graphic read overlay on him.
Speaker 0: The graphics are incredible.
Speaker 0: who Did?
Speaker 1: there's no way they don't realize that this just looks.
Speaker 0: no he definitely did it on purpose.
Speaker 0: There's no question They're too smart to have done this by accident.
Speaker 1: I mean even Hank Scorpio acted like a normal person around other people.
Speaker 0: Yeah This is like not even hiding it.
Speaker 1: in the moment We are going to be at anime Boston not this weekend, but next weekend.
Speaker 1: on Friday We're doing role-playing anime and Jojo anime by its cover.
Speaker 1: on Saturday We're doing how to run an anime club more for an anime openers and still do anime club.
Speaker 0: Why don't we do how to do a panel instead?
Speaker 1: Well, because I got saw Because we did how to do a panel last year.
Speaker 0: I alternate that one.
Speaker 1: That's a gimme because they both fill and people really want to see that kind of content.
Speaker 1: forget everything man I remember pretty well, and I've still been in touch with some people at RIT anime.
Speaker 1: I learned some things.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's interesting You know what?
Speaker 1: Our advice is still correct.
Speaker 0: Sure pretty much.
Speaker 1: There's very little that's changed at least at one place yep, but that one place still seems to have like the culture is pure there still.
Speaker 1: and Motivational anime.
Speaker 1: we don't have any panels on Sunday.
Speaker 1: So you want to see us Friday and Saturday?
Speaker 1: We're also gonna be at Zank icon the following weekend doing a whole bunch of panels.
Speaker 1: Scott might not be but I will be and we're gonna be at PAX East doing.
Speaker 0: I'll be there.
Speaker 1: Atari game design Which actually we've done this panel a couple times now with different Atari games.
Speaker 0: I think it's pretty good and change the games up.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we're definitely gonna change the games up.
Speaker 1: I feel like maze craze does not need to be talked about and I feel like we need a game That's better than slot racers, but not as good as outlaw to fill like a middle ground.
Speaker 1: Sorry circus That need that.
Speaker 1: that's a paddle game.
Speaker 1: Oh fuck unless you want to buy a knob.
Speaker 1: No, if we get two knobs, no.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we could bring the Atari and tell the enforcer like yeah, we need s video Or just going.
Speaker 0: we have plenty of time before PAX East go on eBay and buy some fucking knobs.
Speaker 1: I need to be able to plug them into a USB port on my laptop.
Speaker 0: You can buy converter from Atari to USB because it's the same thing as Sega Genesis to USB.
Speaker 1: I don't think yeah, but Sega Genesis to USB only works because it's still just buttons.
Speaker 1: What'll the?
Speaker 1: what will the rolling analog ish slider do?
Speaker 0: it'll convert it mean?
Speaker 0: Well, you have an analog stick on your steam controller, right?
Speaker 0: I do and that connects by USB By talking to the Windows controller API as an analog input.
Speaker 1: I am not confident that if I buy a Sega to USB Adapter and plug a paddle controller from an Atari into it that it will work without me having to do some major fuckery.
Speaker 0: I think it'll work and I think it will only cost you like five to ten.
Speaker 1: What about money?
Speaker 0: I think you can also find an Atari to jet it - I'm gonna look for it right now.
Speaker 0: Tell you what, I will.
Speaker 1: I'll look if there's gotta be.
Speaker 0: this can't be that hard to buy.
Speaker 0: I know I just haven't actually actually working paddles though because you might have to buy those as well.
Speaker 1: I do have working paddles.
Speaker 1: That's the one thing I have.
Speaker 0: Are they actually good?
Speaker 1: Yeah, they're good enough for kaboom Even though player two is a little bit better than player one, but not that much.
Speaker 1: We're gonna save the best for last.
Speaker 1: so we're gonna talk about the go stuff and the rise of the AI last.
Speaker 1: So if you're waiting for us to talk about that just stay tuned.
Speaker 1: So in other gaming news other than that Xbox Live supposedly now supports cross-platform multiplayer with the ps4.
Speaker 0: Well, it's with everything right.
Speaker 0: supposedly they're adding this and rocket League is gonna be the game that you can play across all three systems.
Speaker 0: You're gonna PC people Xbox people and PlayStation people all playing the same game against each other.
Speaker 1: So currently if I do matchmaking though cats and dogs, it still only matches me with computer people.
Speaker 1: I can only play with ps4 people if I make like a private group and like join with them What you can play with PlayStation people right now automatically.
Speaker 1: Yeah, because before the matchmaking I could play with them anytime I wanted but they never put in the same match as me.
Speaker 0: If I just did the magic you turn it off because by default it's your.
Speaker 0: by default You are playing with PlayStation people unless you flick the switch and the options that says don't do that Please change at some point.
Speaker 0: you had.
Speaker 0: the default is to play with them.
Speaker 0: You would have to check the box to not play with them.
Speaker 0: I feel like if that's true you ever see anyone with a with a avatar.
Speaker 0: This is PSY net.
Speaker 0: No Well, you probably turned it off.
Speaker 1: Well, then I'll keep it off because the times I did play with PlayStation people locally.
Speaker 1: PlayStation culture is bad.
Speaker 0: I don't really notice any difference really between the steam people and the PlayStation people because Rocket League is the pretty much the perfect game for for this cross.
Speaker 1: Hey who plays with keyboard and mouse?
Speaker 0: cuz it's control.
Speaker 0: It's the same thing across every system.
Speaker 0: controller.
Speaker 0: controller controller It's the same options at the same game.
Speaker 0: It doesn't matter which one you're using.
Speaker 0: So it's like perfect, you know you know they tried this a long time ago when they had that shatter run game for the Xbox 360 and you could play against people on the PC and They disabled that shortly after because the place did the PC.
Speaker 0: people kicked everyone's ass.
Speaker 1: Yep, like the other night I was playing Counter-Strike cuz I've been playing a lot of Counter-Strike lately and there was someone on my team Who was just being really bad, but he acted like he played Counter-Strike for a long time.
Speaker 1: So I finally just watched him playing like spectating Definitely using a controller like I saw him be like.
Speaker 1: So I'm like, dude, are you using a controller?
Speaker 1: and he's like What do you mean?
Speaker 1: and I'm like Are you holding in your hand an Xbox controller or a keyboard and a mouse?
Speaker 1: and he was like How would you use a keyboard and a mouse and then someone else on my team voted to kick?
Speaker 1: Yes Yeah, it was one of the funniest things I've ever seen in my life.
Speaker 1: Yeah Okay, like I regret that I was not streaming that game.
Speaker 0: oh my god Yeah, but no this is.
Speaker 1: I'm actually excited for this because rocket league is also one of the best like casual But also serious multiplayer esport games other than video ball in recent history.
Speaker 0: video ball If only you'd come out before rocket league what took you so long?
Speaker 0: video ball where I mean he's at GDC I know right now.
Speaker 0: give it a good talk.
Speaker 0: He's given big hits.
Speaker 0: He's swinging hard and hitting hard.
Speaker 0: I've had three video ball.
Speaker 0: still isn't out.
Speaker 0: So what good are you?
Speaker 1: we're gonna have texted me so far today being like yo dog blah blah blah.
Speaker 1: Where are you at GDC?
Speaker 1: And I'm like, no But I got a GDC.
Speaker 0: you want to pay for me to go to GDC.
Speaker 1: It's like a zillion dollars I think I might come in to pay for next year.
Speaker 0: Your Companies like where are we sending you?
Speaker 1: Technology conference sure Right.
Speaker 1: I mean they sent me to PAX Australia once.
Speaker 1: so do you want?
Speaker 0: I don't know why the game developers keep supporting GDC.
Speaker 0: I wish that they would go to PAX dev or just something else and make it not cost a fortune.
Speaker 0: Yeah, because honestly because someone who whoever runs GDC is the IGDA or somebody is making big profits off that GDC is more of a Spectacle and Pax dev is more of a no world, but the thing is GDC.
Speaker 0: It's like because the game developer It's.
Speaker 0: it's like the conference itself isn't really providing anything other than it's like we rented the space But because all the developers go to it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right there and they make it good.
Speaker 0: It's like the same thing with fucking Gen Con.
Speaker 0: it's like a garbage convention, but because all the tabletop companies go to it.
Speaker 0: It's like well that you have to go there because that's what the tabletop companies are going.
Speaker 0: And if all the tabletop companies would just say fuck you Gen Con.
Speaker 0: We're gonna do something better.
Speaker 0: It would be done and it would be amazing.
Speaker 1: meanwhile e3 basically doesn't exist anymore and all the companies are bailing on the e3 and they're either doing nothing or at least haven't said they're doing anything different or They're running their own events now.
Speaker 0: EA was like we're gonna set up.
Speaker 0: We're not gonna go into e3.
Speaker 0: We're gonna set up something across the street on our own which people do at PAX.
Speaker 0: But they specifically said they're doing it because we don't see value in doing something just for the industry.
Speaker 0: We want the public to come in and it's like oh, that's why we're gonna do our own thing across the street.
Speaker 0: Yeah We can let everyone in.
Speaker 1: it's interesting because what I see at PAX dev is there's a lot of people who are there Who you know are there to work and the people who aren't there who I try to get there.
Speaker 1: like yo You should really give a talk at dev.
Speaker 1: They don't want to because since it's a private serious business industry thing It doesn't get any play elsewhere and they're actually only going to these conferences for spectacle.
Speaker 0: Oh you saying the developers are going to GDC because the press is allowed to GDC and because that's dev doesn't allow press.
Speaker 0: you see Pax dev I think they're thinking was out.
Speaker 0: There's no press.
Speaker 0: developers will come and say all the good shit and they do Opposite.
Speaker 0: the developers are all going to GDC and saying the good shit because there is press.
Speaker 1: I feel it's.
Speaker 1: I feel like there Are people who don't go to things like dev but do go to GDC because they're actually going.
Speaker 1: the reason their company sends them Is to generate press.
Speaker 1: But then there's another kind of person who goes to a thing like dev and wouldn't go to GDC because they want to talk inside baseball.
Speaker 0: Maybe you could have two areas or different days, right?
Speaker 0: You could have secret day and public in public day And media passes would only get you in on public days.
Speaker 1: Whoa.
Speaker 1: Yeah for the public areas And I were GDC I take I mean you.
Speaker 0: you could apply that to like every convention, right?
Speaker 0: I mean even pretty much every convention we go to no matter what it is even like anime Boston or something has like a press junket where like you have all the guests and you Have or the chairs of the convention and the press go to a panel.
Speaker 0: that's not on the schedule.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean like we went to the one at PAX years ago.
Speaker 0: I think that was the first PAX East.
Speaker 0: we went to it because our panel was right after it and we were just sitting there Waiting for it to start.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so it's like gave in taiko and a few press and they're just asking some bullshit questions And then I asked him what he ate for breakfast.
Speaker 1: that was easily the best question that was asked.
Speaker 0: and yeah Don't think you're missing out by being kept out of these things.
Speaker 0: If there is anything good that happens at them the press is there and they'll write an article.
Speaker 0: Notice, they don't write too many articles about what happens at the press junket because nothing happens.
Speaker 1: So I got going.
Speaker 1: you got a list of news over there.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so blizzard, right?
Speaker 0: There's some Hearthstone updates coming out But that's not a real big story.
Speaker 0: The big story is that for the first time in a bajillion years?
Speaker 0: They made a patch to Diablo 2 and then they put a patch for Warcraft 3 and it's like, holy Shit, look at that Passion these old games to make them run.
Speaker 0: on the new windows 16.
Speaker 0: You could run Warcraft 3 on new max now straight up that.
Speaker 1: That's amazing for a lot of reasons because while people like you and me Can get old DOS games to run because we know how to use things like DOS box Or we know that GOG exists.
Speaker 0: normal people cannot write in GOG.
Speaker 0: All they do is they usually take the old game.
Speaker 0: They rarely get the source code to the old game.
Speaker 0: They usually is setting it up and configuring it with DOS box.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so that you can just double-click in you know, GOG galaxy or whatever and game will play.
Speaker 1: They fucks with all the business that if I get there's still dogs, but there's still.
Speaker 0: you're still using DOS box A lot of the time right?
Speaker 0: you're very rarely running the game directly on Windows straight up.
Speaker 0: But Blizzard they have the source code and all the stuff for their old games.
Speaker 0: They can update them and they're doing so I guess to get you to buy them and keep making money off them.
Speaker 0: So someone Warcraft 3 isn't free.
Speaker 1: You got to buy that and someone noticed that several months ago Blizzard had a single job posting quote senior software engineer classic games.
Speaker 1: that was then filled.
Speaker 0: So I guess then this happened who it?
Speaker 0: we should ask who this person is and interview them.
Speaker 0: Yeah, because they probably don't have a lot of secrets that they can't talk about right?
Speaker 0: is you know, they're.
Speaker 0: they've all the Architectures and stories of how these games are made has been well documented in many long-form gaming articles, right?
Speaker 0: You know the the saga of how Starcraft was made and all this shit, right?
Speaker 0: But the question is it's like whoa.
Speaker 0: First of all, let's go play these games that we couldn't play easily because they're way good or at least fun for Diablo's case fun once But Warcraft 3 is always fun Yeah, and I can actually play that RTS because it's not ridiculous
Speaker 1: even though
Speaker 0: I'll still lose But I'll lose less bad than it's Starcraft 2.
Speaker 1: if the fact that this happened the way the timing and the way that it did it bodes well for the sort of continuing maturation of games as a significant force of media because This sort of like archival preservation thing has not really happened that much in gaming except in museums.
Speaker 0: Well, I mean Nintendo's got the Virtual Console right.
Speaker 0: 20th anniversary of Pokemon.
Speaker 0: They put that Pokemon right on the VC on 3ds, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's you know.
Speaker 0: You don't think of it.
Speaker 0: there are a bunch of other think of it the same way because it's not like a patch to make Something up-to-date even though they did patch it to make it up-to-date a patch it to make it work on the 3ds.
Speaker 0: They just don't sell it that way.
Speaker 0: so you don't think of it the same way.
Speaker 1: But think about how many Nintendo games over the years have just disappeared Yep, except in ROM libraries that people run in Nestle or whatever.
Speaker 0: Right?
Speaker 0: Well, I mean those things can be easily emulated, right?
Speaker 0: But PC games are actually rather difficult to emulate for a wide variety of reasons, right?
Speaker 0: Because you know, especially like let's say you get some old, you know a PC game and it's like, oh, yeah This one only has real sound on an ad-lib.
Speaker 0: It doesn't have real sound on a sound blaster.
Speaker 1: Yeah, do you know about DMAs and IRQs?
Speaker 1: Yeah, but you don't And you don't need to like.
Speaker 1: it's stupid to know about this game.
Speaker 0: This game was programmed poorly.
Speaker 0: So it's expecting to run in a 286. if you run it on a 386 or faster, it'll go really fast.
Speaker 1: Whoa dog, 100 megahertz.
Speaker 1: That's that's a bit much.
Speaker 0: I had a 100 I had a 100 megahertz computer and it was a 486 and some games did not work on it.
Speaker 0: And that was Iran.
Speaker 0: who's running PC DOS.
Speaker 0: Oh, but no you gotta run MS-DOS.
Speaker 1: So twitch has done two interesting things.
Speaker 1: one.
Speaker 1: They're streaming Julia Child's cooking show.
Speaker 0: Well, that's sort of after the success of their you know, painting show.
Speaker 0: Right, you know, they're dead.
Speaker 1: I watched a bunch of that.
Speaker 1: That was good business.
Speaker 0: Of course, right after they saw those successful They went out obviously to look for Equivalent things and they stayed in the PBS library.
Speaker 0: I hope they do.
Speaker 0: Mr.
Speaker 0: Rogers.
Speaker 1: So I recall a time.
Speaker 1: Mr Rogers, I recall a time not that get him out here when twitch basically banned all non gaming content.
Speaker 0: It's a beautiful day in the twitch neighborhood.
Speaker 1: I also remember a time not that long ago where if Content that wasn't literally screen capture of a game appeared on Twitch and Anyone started watching it half the chat stream was what is this RL bullshit?
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: Well, unless somebody was like streaming my little pony.
Speaker 1: Yeah But it's interesting that I think the main reason twitch did these two things and why they're doing more things like this Is that being a hundred percent gaming only focused?
Speaker 1: They were set to lose out to YouTube because YouTube was just the same gaming stuff plus Literally any other kind of content in the world.
Speaker 0: YouTube gaming is not doing that.
Speaker 0: Well, people are still on Twitch Really?
Speaker 0: They haven't built the community at YouTube gaming.
Speaker 1: That's interesting because I don't interact with the community and if you don't interact with the community and you just want to use the service To watch YouTube is just technologically superior by a huge margin like watching twitch streams.
Speaker 1: Not that great because for a lot of reasons that don't want to really get into now, but it doesn't work that great.
Speaker 1: yeah, you do.
Speaker 0: only the main problems with the YouTube one is that if Is the there's a limitation that people aren't aware of.
Speaker 0: it can only be so long, right?
Speaker 0: I did a YouTube game stream once and that like it cut off at 12 hours and I did another one and The encoding like never worked and the video is not there, right?
Speaker 0: So it's like it's buggy in that sense.
Speaker 0: But but like the actual way you stream and watching the stream is just better in fact.
Speaker 1: so I've been playing with you.
Speaker 1: guys might have watched me play counter-strike the other day and What's interesting is in the second half of that video?
Speaker 1: I was basically neo god among men walking around as a murder machine.
Speaker 1: But aside from that the Shadowplay, you know the thing where you basically have impact free streaming.
Speaker 1: if you have an Nvidia card One it used to only work with twitch.
Speaker 1: if you install the beta New version like you have to enable the beta and then download the beta and run the beta.
Speaker 1: It can also stream to YouTube.
Speaker 0: Did that force you to update your Nvidia driver?
Speaker 0: Uh, yes, that makes it five crash.
Speaker 1: Yes, actually How I fixed it.
Speaker 1: if you start the game through the Nvidia experience It always works really so and apparently a lot of people have pointed out that if you ever run into a game where one of The Nvidia patches breaks it I mean a later patch will probably obviously fix it.
Speaker 1: but they almost always work fine.
Speaker 1: If you open the Nvidia like game tuning experience and click a launch game from there This has worked a hundred percent for me, which is really interesting.
Speaker 0: But if you'd open up sieve from steam, it just doesn't even start.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: All right Maybe now that I know that maybe I'll update my driver because I've been keeping my driver old.
Speaker 1: I was also a problem, but let me tell you the shadow cast YouTube again way better.
Speaker 1: I can send as many megabits per second as I fucking want as long as I got a pipe for it.
Speaker 1: Not like twitch limiting you to three or six or whatever.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so I tried a 12 megabit per second stream.
Speaker 1: I tried streaming like 10 like giant resolutions.
Speaker 1: It all worked pretty much fine.
Speaker 1: It was kind of cool Mmm, the other thing that it was interesting is it didn't have any options for like setting voice volume Or like any of that fiddly stuff you do in like OBS or like even X split.
Speaker 1: So I was like, I wonder if this will work.
Speaker 1: They just has intelligent defaults.
Speaker 1: It just figures out like, you know We did knows you're gonna have game audio and knows you're gonna have talking audio and it just handles it Mmm and makes it sound great.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I was shocked by how I'm.
Speaker 0: can you get your webcam in the shot or whatever?
Speaker 1: Yes, actually, I didn't try that because I might have not been dressed when I was playing Counter-Strike, but Okay, yeah, but the other news is that another thing twitch is doing is they have announced What do they call it stream first?
Speaker 1: All right, it is an initiative to work with developers designing new games.
Speaker 1: So people are currently making games to integrate streaming into their platforms from day one.
Speaker 0: That's something they tried before right but they sort of backed off on that.
Speaker 0: Like I saw a whole bunch of this especially like around the time the ps4 was coming out.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like games that like included twitch is part of the game like in the game you could push a button and start streaming to twitch.
Speaker 0: and then I thought like eventually every game was just gonna have this and It didn't happen.
Speaker 0: and I'm like, well, why didn't that happen?
Speaker 0: And then I guess now they're gonna try again, but it's twofold.
Speaker 0: It's not just what.
Speaker 0: YouTube should try the same thing.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they should.
Speaker 1: it's not just integrated into the game to make streaming.
Speaker 0: You should also Somebody should make a service to where you can send your RT MPs to one place and have them go to both YouTube and twitch at the same time.
Speaker 1: That's the kind of company that either YouTube or twitch would buy.
Speaker 0: you can do it yourself by starting up a little server and using Something like VLC even or something to go between.
Speaker 1: I think there's even an nginx plug-in that you can use those.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean, but nginx is sort of a weird thing to use.
Speaker 0: Yeah web server Why would you use it to proxy the anyway?
Speaker 1: But so after after a certain unnamed convention where someone wanted to use it for that I've discovered that actually a lot of people use it for that.
Speaker 0: It's a web server It's not.
Speaker 0: it's not a video streaming process.
Speaker 1: You're not gonna believe this but a lot of people are using JavaScript for both front end and back end coding.
Speaker 0: You don't say that you don't say.
Speaker 1: But it's more than that.
Speaker 1: this is also an initiative to allow two-way communication so the game can be dynamic based on events in the Making.
Speaker 1: twitch plays Pokemon something that you can use an API to do easily and officially.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm That is something that I don't think YouTube could move on with any speed.
Speaker 0: YouTube could do that.
Speaker 1: They won't not with any speed.
Speaker 0: YouTube chat should be available by the YouTube API because they're just comments or whatever.
Speaker 1: It's not just chat.
Speaker 1: They want to go further than that.
Speaker 1: They want to make it easy to have real game experiences like deep integrations down the road Like what like maybe even share a controller straight up with someone.
Speaker 0: so I go on YouTube I go on Twitch and there's a game being played and I'm watching it and I take out my controller and I start playing.
Speaker 0: the Game that I'm seeing a stream of is delayed by at least 30 seconds to a few minutes.
Speaker 1: So obviously there are a lot of things they still need to work out and this is just an initiative to work with developers.
Speaker 1: It appears that there's.
Speaker 1: they're starting the focus with simple Interactions that are delay friendly like typing something that in a vote and those kinds of things.
Speaker 0: So it's so a little thing shows up in twitch and I interact with it and then event click to vote he-man or minotaur And then eventually that whatever we happens affects what the person playing the game Yeah deals with.
Speaker 1: So the end game though because there's a feature in the nvd experience shadowcast beta stuff that I didn't look at too closely But it basically let me share an interface where someone on the internet could watch my stream and Connect to my game with a controller to play effectively local co-op with me from the game.
Speaker 1: I'm running Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: I did not investigate that further, but I will at some point for probably for the next Tuesday's show.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: So twitch is definitely trying to do things to stay ahead of the game with YouTube because you're right They're still dominant.
Speaker 0: Well ever since Amazon bought them They have the resources to do stuff like.
Speaker 1: buy TV show like this is right, but they have the benefit of focusing primarily on gaming But they also have the drawback of they don't have the like.
Speaker 1: we literally will appeal to any streaming content of YouTube.
Speaker 1: So we'll see how this all shakes down in the long run.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: So there was a product called the 2600 - daptor and the original version supported both paddles And the joystick.
Speaker 0: the new version the two hundred twenty six hundred daptor two supports paddles joysticks 7800 controllers the calculator thing that sort of joystick with two buttons thing the trackball The star Raider thingy and the because our panel is has a lot going for it.
Speaker 1: if we're standing there with legit Atari 2600 controllers that will add a plus or twenty six hundred daptor two Units on hand two for 57 bucks.
Speaker 0: Well, that's more expensive than I thought but I think you might only need one to do two Paddles.
Speaker 1: Oh, yes, cuz there are two paddles per plug.
Speaker 1: But if we want to do warlords, we need two of them because we need four paddles.
Speaker 0: You know what warlords not actually that good warlords is so good.
Speaker 1: The concept is good.
Speaker 0: if you played it recently on the Atari 2600 the resolution being low is a problem.
Speaker 1: There are other problems with that game.
Speaker 1: that that's another.
Speaker 0: the angles not being highly varied is a problem.
Speaker 1: that game Remade intelligently could be the next video ball.
Speaker 0: It's called video ball.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's just video.
Speaker 0: There's also selling six-foot USB cables for two bucks.
Speaker 1: I don't think I need a six-foot USB cable.
Speaker 0: Also, if you're not interested in using any of those weird like a trackball you get the original 2600 daptor two for 48.
Speaker 0: That's not much cheaper anyway, so 400 bucks.
Speaker 0: Whatever what's I still don't believe any of these VR is gonna succeed because they're all.
Speaker 1: you have a fucked up definition of succeed.
Speaker 1: These are going to succeed in the same way that ultra high-end video cards do same way.
Speaker 1: They call the Kinect succeeded way better than the Kinect.
Speaker 0: then we the wiimote.
Speaker 1: more people buy like Nvidia 980s than by Kinect.
Speaker 1: We moats the original wiimote that succeeded.
Speaker 0: NES power pad.
Speaker 1: The power pad was ahead of its target.
Speaker 1: our globe power glove was ahead of its time Ahead of its time.
Speaker 0: still it was ahead of its time in the 90s and it's still ahead of its time.
Speaker 1: I disagree because if you have that amount of disposable income and you're a hot VR hobbyist this technology is here.
Speaker 1: It's great but for mom and Mainstream and sure.
Speaker 0: so all these hobbyists will buy one just like all the people have 3d printers right now We'll buy one.
Speaker 0: that's I think that's about the level it can get to.
Speaker 0: is where 3d printers are now Which is so widely deployed among hobbyists.
Speaker 0: Yeah, which is not so great.
Speaker 0: That's Scott It's not something that you could economically Scott make a large.
Speaker 1: video games used to be widely deployed only among hobbyists.
Speaker 1: It took a while Sure.
Speaker 0: It's not something that you could.
Speaker 0: it's not at the point.
Speaker 0: See success is when enough people have it.
Speaker 0: It's worthwhile to for a video game hardware device where it's worthwhile to Spend a large budget making a game for it, right?
Speaker 0: So a lot of indie devs are making games of this because it's fun and because it's cool or because you know Demos and whatever.
Speaker 1: that is the only way to incubate the next generation.
Speaker 0: No, like company is gonna make like, you know Madden or anything for this, right?
Speaker 0: Because there just aren't enough people even if everyone who has one buys your game It's like.
Speaker 0: that wasn't enough to justify the cost of making this game and that's fine.
Speaker 1: You need a. this is the first VR platform that is viable to incubate the next generation of VR games.
Speaker 1: We've never had that before.
Speaker 1: the last time VR got big one of the big limitations was that one.
Speaker 1: There was no way to deploy it in homes at all.
Speaker 1: There couldn't be an indie scene.
Speaker 1: It was too expensive too big too horrible.
Speaker 1: Now.
Speaker 1: You can actually deploy it widely and People eat while it is very expensive.
Speaker 1: It is very cheap.
Speaker 0: If you're a hobbyist, it's still a giant thing to stick on your face - it'll always be that no But eventually it'll be just like sunglasses or contact lenses or like a tiny little thing Then replacement eyeballs.
Speaker 0: Yes, eventually when it gets to slightly when it gets to like Ski goggle level instead, you know, it's not it's not that much bigger than my ski goggles It's got to be at least maybe swim goggle.
Speaker 1: Have you worn and used the current generation?
Speaker 0: Oculus it is vastly superior to previous ones.
Speaker 0: Yes technology is getting better, but it's still not good enough.
Speaker 0: It's too big and uncomfortable.
Speaker 0: This is actually for long periods of time.
Speaker 1: The thing is I think it's being.
Speaker 1: it is successful and continue to be successful, but I'm not super confident in the PlayStation VR.
Speaker 0: Because I mean I mean I mean if you're gonna assume right forget about the argument about all the VR being Unsuccessful, right if you're gonna bet on a VR you bet on the oculus one.
Speaker 0: Right all these other ones the valve one and the Sony one.
Speaker 0: It's like get that shit.
Speaker 0: I think it's not going anywhere.
Speaker 1: I think the first good big games like the big ones are gonna come out of valve because they'll understand how to use the Technology.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I think those games are gonna run on the Right.
Speaker 0: and yeah, whatever the vibes and whatever the garbage is out there Samsung nonsense all that shit is gonna be the hollow Basically fake, but that is that stuff is garbage.
Speaker 1: But while I disagree with most of what you were saying before the one thing I do agree with is that fully mainstream Gamer culture.
Speaker 1: It's not quite there yet.
Speaker 1: I Think the PlayStation VR will not be a great experience because people will buy that It costs as much as a game console, but they'll expect the big games you're talking about while the people who buy the oculus on a computer Understand and expect that it's an emergent incubating environment.
Speaker 1: So the oculus person buys an oculus gets exactly what they expected and are amazed by it.
Speaker 1: The kid who buys the PlayStation VR is gonna be real disappointed with it.
Speaker 0: And you want to hear air I'll give you.
Speaker 0: I'll give you a positive right?
Speaker 0: This is unlikely to happen, but it is one for non unrealistic future right in which they do make Badass really amazing games for the VR that everyone needs to play right say counter-strike or whatever, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, and it becomes such that like to play counter-strike E-sport.
Speaker 0: for reals you need to have the VR.
Speaker 0: you can't be counter-striking with a monitor anymore, right?
Speaker 0: It's at that point for certain games Right and obviously not everyone gonna be doing that at home, right?
Speaker 0: You know the people who are eSports champions will be because probably they'll just get one from their sponsors or whatever.
Speaker 0: But most people will still have monitors for a very long time at least five ten Maybe even more than that.
Speaker 0: years right even if monitors become way better.
Speaker 0: it could and I hope this happens Bring back the net cafe or at least make the net cafe exist in the US.
Speaker 1: Oh, I can't afford Arcade.
Speaker 0: it's like if you want to play Street Fighter.
Speaker 0: It's like nowadays You love sticks in their home but like.
Speaker 0: imagine if the only real way to play certain games that were super important was to go and use VR and You can't afford it.
Speaker 0: so everyone starts good.
Speaker 0: we open up net cafes in the US for real.
Speaker 0: Yeah, mostly because we also have the declining prices of commercial retail real estate.
Speaker 1: Also, there is no better way to massively increase the incidence of pink eye among gamers in the United States.
Speaker 0: That is correct.
Speaker 0: So I could see for example in countries that already have net cafes so like a Japan, right It's some net cafe in Japan might be putting an oculus in every one of the little boobs Right, and that's totally realistic And that could be a way that it sees, you know more immediate success, even if it's not in the home.
Speaker 1: Yeah, partly because one of the problems with the more mainstream audience is kind of like with the Nintendo Wii controller.
Speaker 1: There's an article about this.
Speaker 0: In fact, if I was gonna make a VR game I would target it at the person who's in a net cafe in some other country because you want an open space that Is well controlled to do VR.
Speaker 0: and if I was making VR hardware I would get salespeople in those countries to start going around to the companies that run the net cafes and be like look Buy one of these for every booth $400 a booth.
Speaker 0: But that or maybe you know, put them in half your booths and charge more for those booths or something You know as a premium to pay for it something like that.
Speaker 1: So last and not least AlphaGo Defeated the human four to one four out of five times.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the human won one game.
Speaker 0: Okay, so I don't know how much of the fundamental information you want to go over here.
Speaker 1: But they feel like we could do a whole show on this in general.
Speaker 0: But yeah, so it's playing go, right?
Speaker 0: So you already know go is a perfect information game Just like chess.
Speaker 0: the reason that computers can play chess a lot easier before they could play go is because the space of chess The number of possible board positions was much fewer.
Speaker 0: That's not Diminishing the number of possible board positions in chess because there's a fuck ton of them.
Speaker 0: There's just Exponentially orders of magnitude more board positions in go.
Speaker 1: so it's big.
Speaker 1: go is so much more.
Speaker 0: I think the the analogy I gave because we talked about this in some of our lectures the number of board positions in Like in a chess board with I don't know if this is these numbers are close in Actual in actuality but relatively right.
Speaker 0: we'd be like comparing the number of atoms in the Sun.
Speaker 0: We'd be like the number of board business in chess and the number of board positions in go Like the number of atoms in the universe.
Speaker 0: actually maybe more maybe more maybe more Right.
Speaker 0: It's like that's the.
Speaker 0: so computers are able to do well at chess because we could have a database of every of almost every chess board position and The best possible move to do from that position and then just do a lookup and make a move.
Speaker 1: But even so think of it this way.
Speaker 0: checkers was weakly mathematically solved after a decade-long Supercomputer checkers, which would be like the number of atoms in the ocean.
Speaker 1: chess is by no means solved.
Speaker 1: We just have clever a eyes mostly with these lookup tape.
Speaker 0: They have most of the you know, most common positions.
Speaker 0: So you rarely you're gonna confuse the chess pro.
Speaker 1: So the chess programs?
Speaker 1: I've not solved chess, but they will beat any human ever no matter what.
Speaker 0: pretty much I think the days of the days of people beating a chess AI at chess are pretty much over.
Speaker 0: Yeah But when you're the last big the best the best chess players on earth right now Basically are just people who can do what the computer does.
Speaker 1: and there's a lot of cool stuff about how it kind of ruined chess because people are doing things that the computer.
Speaker 0: the last time I watched pro chess the commentators had the computer and it told them this move and they looked at that move and they started talking about how.
Speaker 0: Whoa, that's a crazy move that no one ever think of.
Speaker 0: and I mean It's a lot easier to see chess Even if you're not a pro and I guess chess has at least a few heuristics of right the king.
Speaker 0: and I saw the move.
Speaker 0: It didn't know.
Speaker 0: like whoa, what an amazing move.
Speaker 0: and they're like, yeah, no person would ever think to do this.
Speaker 0: They're like, is he gonna see it?
Speaker 0: and this guy's sitting there thinking for a long time and eventually he does that move.
Speaker 0: and it's like Before that period of time where computers existed no human would have done that move right just thinking about it looking at it.
Speaker 1: So the takeaways are one the computer did not solve go not even.
Speaker 0: I mean we still haven't solved chess.
Speaker 0: We definitely haven't solved go.
Speaker 1: we may never solve go.
Speaker 1: it might not be Solvable in the unit without a quantum computer.
Speaker 0: I don't think it's possible.
Speaker 0: Yeah with one it might not even be possible.
Speaker 1: but the important thing for him from a game perspective is that this AI is So far ahead of what even futurists were predicting that I was kind of taken aback that this happened.
Speaker 1: Like when they announced this I was hoping the I would win but I didn't really think it would.
Speaker 0: well.
Speaker 0: so I mean I. we've been talking about machine learning stuff a lot and we keep seeing it's like it's really hot lately and You know, it's been doing so well It's so many things.
Speaker 0: and when they finally said we you know, we've got a thing using this tech these techniques It's gonna play go it's gonna play again It's ready to play against like the one of the top players ever Right and They were willing to like make a show of it.
Speaker 0: and I'm like they must think it's gonna win.
Speaker 0: and there's been so much machine Learning like positives lately.
Speaker 0: I'm like, I think it's gonna win.
Speaker 0: It's like I almost couldn't believe that it was gonna win but like even before the first match It's like.
Speaker 0: I'm like.
Speaker 0: I felt like.
Speaker 0: I'm like, oh the computer's gonna win.
Speaker 0: and then I'm like what the fuck am I saying?
Speaker 0: Gonna win it go.
Speaker 0: Oh, right.
Speaker 0: It's like ludicrously impossible.
Speaker 0: and then it like destroyed him.
Speaker 0: and I'm like, well, there it is.
Speaker 1: But it was so in terms that advancement it was as recently as January like it was in January In fact that we even as humans were able to figure out how many possible legal positions there are in 19 by 19.
Speaker 0: Go right this like we've shown Figured that an earlier version of this same program played against someone who is not as good but really really good and in matches That weren't you know, highly publicized and it played about as well as like a good amateur player.
Speaker 0: So it played really well, but not as well as it played now.
Speaker 0: They gave it an honorary.
Speaker 0: Right nine rank, right?
Speaker 0: No person has ever honorarily received which is the highest rank and go by the way, which means that you play Divinely, right?
Speaker 0: So they basically without having to go through the rank up system but I mean Right Right without ever having to like rank up and and you know You know start at the bottom and work its way to the top this computer played against someone who had that rank.
Speaker 0: It beat him four out of five times.
Speaker 0: the Korean go organization basically just gave an honorary.
Speaker 0: They're just like, alright Like.
Speaker 1: imagine if I walked into.
Speaker 1: you know the go.
Speaker 0: that's like like if rim walked out onto an ice-skating rink.
Speaker 0: He played some hockey like in one game and he beat, you know the entire, you know Blackhawks all by himself.
Speaker 0: Yeah, even certainly even even defending the goal.
Speaker 0: and they're just like, you know, what rim.
Speaker 0: You just played one game of hockey, you know, or maybe five games of hockey one you won four out of five.
Speaker 0: We're just gonna put your name on the cup.
Speaker 0: I mean, I didn't play in the NHL season You didn't you know, you didn't go do anything else.
Speaker 0: We're just here's the.
Speaker 0: put your name on the cup and you know what?
Speaker 0: Here's an Olympic gold medal.
Speaker 0: It's not even the Olympics.
Speaker 0: Here's the gold man.
Speaker 1: I could probably take on the Leafs.
Speaker 1: I can at least win a couple games.
Speaker 0: Right, that's basically just like here.
Speaker 0: this computer is as good as the highest ranked player.
Speaker 1: There you go And it is the commentary already.
Speaker 1: it did some things in the game that no human Has ever seriously done as far as we can tell.
Speaker 0: and in the one game at loss the human, you know Displayed his magnificence right and did amazing things as well.
Speaker 1: Yeah So it was very interesting watching the computer flail and try increasingly desperate moves.
Speaker 1: It was doing whatever had the best chance of winning.
Speaker 0: see that's the thing.
Speaker 0: So right.
Speaker 0: So that was the most fascinating part for me because it was the part Understood the most right because I don't I can't really tell what to do that in games, right?
Speaker 0: I can't tell what's going on and go really all that much Except because I've only played going very small boards and very poorly.
Speaker 0: so the only things that I know are bad are like really basic moves right and Towards the end.
Speaker 0: when it had lost it started doing moves that even I could just see immediately Like that's dumb that piece is just gonna get taken.
Speaker 0: you just gave points to the other guy.
Speaker 0: that was odd and I'm like Why would the computer do that?
Speaker 0: And then I looked at the board even more closely.
Speaker 0: I like paused the video and I realized wait That's a dumb move because the next move the other guy is gonna make is this move which will just take those pieces.
Speaker 0: But if that other guy doesn't make that move if the other guy is really dumb, right?
Speaker 0: Which he isn't He's like the best there is right close to it then That move would actually be the first in a series of moves
Speaker 1: that would allow
Speaker 0: it to get a whole bunch of points back And be back in the game if the other guy just lets it right.
Speaker 0: So, of course, he didn't let it.
Speaker 0: but the computer is basically like saying Alright, are you he's like he's like I've.
Speaker 0: the computer is like I have lost but I could still win if you're really dumb.
Speaker 0: So I'm just gonna check and make sure you're not really dumb.
Speaker 0: Oh, you're not.
Speaker 0: Alright, let me try again.
Speaker 0: Oh, you're not and it ran out of those and then it gave up.
Speaker 0: So it was almost like in football where you know I talked about this a lot where it's like you're losing in order to come back because you're so far behind.
Speaker 0: You can't just play conservatively which the AlphaGo does very, you know AlphaGo gets ahead and plays conservatively just to keep its winning.
Speaker 0: It doesn't try to like be aggressive and get a whole bunch of points Which is actually why it's worse at playing black than it playing white because black goes first.
Speaker 0: It has to be more aggressive, right?
Speaker 0: It doesn't do that.
Speaker 0: It says I'm winning.
Speaker 0: I'm just gonna do whatever I have to do to keep this points lead Right and win the game.
Speaker 0: It doesn't try to like score a whole bunch of extra points and like run up the score like New England Patriots or whatever Right.
Speaker 0: It just tries to win the game which and the best way to do that is by getting ahead and playing conservatively.
Speaker 0: So when it's behind it has to do a high-risk high-reward Maneuvers in order to get back into the lead because that's the best chance of winning.
Speaker 0: It's like what's my best chance of winning this football game when I'm down by two touchdowns Miracle onside kick Ridiculous trick play right.
Speaker 0: so in go it just so happens that an onside kick is make a really dumb move and hope the other Guy doesn't you know, it's really what an onside kick is.
Speaker 0: It's a really dumb move.
Speaker 0: It's I'm gonna kick it really short and give myself bad field position.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: And hope the other team can't catch this football that's bouncing around and you know Right and hope that I get it instead right.
Speaker 0: and that's in seeing it do that.
Speaker 0: I understood what was going on.
Speaker 0: I'm like, aha What a smart computer.
Speaker 1: a commentator has also pointed out that it Acted like a human and appeared to show the kind of intuition sort of past the go Turing test, right?
Speaker 0: It's like every I was.
Speaker 0: there's two different Commentaries in English and also a Korean one that I can't understand but in all three of them because I did watch you could see The people who are experts at go who are commenting, right?
Speaker 0: They're also at that highest divine rank or commenting and they're like, yeah It'll play this move next and about half the time the computer played that move next Right, so it's like even you know human, I think that is actually less of a statement about how great the computer is, but how great people are and that this ridiculously complicated game.
Speaker 0: You know over the 2,500 years of playing We've figured out a lot of the correct moves to make in various patterns and we're right.
Speaker 1: Oh, well that we or at least as right as as can be known we have developed Heuristics simple enough to hold in a human brain that are almost as good as state-of-the-art 2016 AI.
Speaker 0: that's pretty good.
Speaker 0: Yeah Humans right bad and the human can come up with that answer while the computer is thinking right.
Speaker 0: the computer took like about.
Speaker 0: you know Sometimes it did faster than other times But it always took its turn in about like 30 seconds or so or something like that, right?
Speaker 0: But a lot of times, you know, the person who's commenting doesn't have to like sweat and you know Take their time with their decision.
Speaker 0: They can just be like it could play here and then it plays there, right?
Speaker 0: You know, it's like.
Speaker 0: I almost went, you know, but the guy actually playing is like And I'm sure if the commentator was actually playing they would also be thinking much harder and not just going with their first instinct on Every move right but but often that first instinct was the right instinct, but
Speaker 1: we'll be talking about this You know, there's a lot of consequences of these games Like this is big news and
Speaker 0: even the people who made it who actually, you know, they keep calling it Google's AlphaGo, but actually it's a company Google bought that makes this but anyway But yeah, Google owns it now.
Speaker 0: Sergey Brin was even there like one of the days, you know to make an appearance or whatever.
Speaker 1: But what I've read the next applications of this particular strain of AI learning is going to be medical diagnoses and humans.
Speaker 0: You can use this for all sorts of ridiculous things Like.
Speaker 0: you could use this for spam filtering or you know, you could.
Speaker 0: you can use this for like so many different applications.
Speaker 0: It's just kind of I try to do some tutorials and like how to make it work how to do Google tensorflow stuff and the tutorials are not very helpful for someone of my math knowledge level But I'm gonna keep working on it because there's tons of stuff you can do with this.
Speaker 0: And I just want to point out one more thing is that this is able to work for Go Even though Go is like the most complex game only because is a game of perfect information, right?
Speaker 0: You couldn't get this to even play poker Which is much simpler than Go because it has no idea what the fuck anyone else has in their hand.
Speaker 0: Right and because of you know, if there was some hidden stones and go it wouldn't it wouldn't work.
Speaker 0: It has to know everything that's going on to be able to make these good decisions.
Speaker 1: Now you could make an AI with different kinds of heuristics.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it would have done, right?
Speaker 0: It would have to like be guessing it like what's you know?
Speaker 0: But let's say we had it play poker and we just said well the cards and other people's hands You know the odds of what they could be.
Speaker 0: now make your decision.
Speaker 0: It would still be really good, but it wouldn't be like just so consistently dominant.
Speaker 0: because luck, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, but in the end and there's also no luck in Go even forget about perfect information, right?
Speaker 0: There's no luck in Go right you play something like T&E.
Speaker 0: Not only is there to not knowing what's in other people's hands, right?
Speaker 0: Even though a computer could remember how many points everyone has but not knowing what tiles you're gonna draw That's that would mess it up big time because I imagine I think it would play like in T&E if it was behind by A little bit.
Speaker 0: it would try to dump tiles, right?
Speaker 0: So would I and then sure it would try to dump tiles is like an onside kick and get a fistful of blue tiles.
Speaker 0: Then what would you do?
Speaker 0: dump six more and end the game and when it's losing, I don't know, right?
Speaker 1: Well, the thing is eventually we'll have methods for those sorts of a eyes.
Speaker 1: the the AI, you know The thing that's going to cause the mainstream people to really freak out is gonna be when there is an AI that plays Texas Hold'em Consistently better than humans in the long run all the time No matter what.
Speaker 1: Yep, and it'll be interesting as to if I suspect that's possible Just from looking at cards played and odds and games over time.
Speaker 1: But it'll be real interesting if one of the inputs into that is Cameras looking at the other players Analyzing human emotions and facial regular stuff.
Speaker 0: this can be done.
Speaker 0: Yeah I'm curious how it'll play something like netrunner because like netrunner it's like, okay, we should know she in advance I put down a card with four advancements Running that could either score the computer a bunch of points and win at the game or it could lose immediately.
Speaker 0: What's it gonna do?
Speaker 0: one out of two shot?
Speaker 0: Is it gonna roll a 1d2 in its memory and then decide?
Speaker 0: What's it gonna do?
Speaker 1: It's gonna step back and look at the history of all games Where a situation like that happened and look at how those games went.
Speaker 0: you had to figure out I mean usually I mean most of the time most decks don't play the instant kill card, right?
Speaker 0: So it's you know in most games you would just get points doing that.
Speaker 0: So but if it ran and died it would be game over a no runner AI.
Speaker 0: So that's gonna be using this current method.
Speaker 0: right of the of you know The neural net and the whatever right the same method that AlphaGo uses I think would have a very hard time in games with luck and imperfect information.
Speaker 1: the netrunner I think you need a different mechanism could scrape the internet and tournament information to figure out the ongoing meta and Maybe even figure things out about its opponents and then use that information in its heuristic scouting is against the rules of netrun ever cheating.
Speaker 1: But how could you stop it?
Speaker 0: I know you can't stop.
Speaker 0: Yeah, everyone keeps saying there's no way.
Speaker 1: if I'm gonna lie If I was in a never under tournament, I would look at the Facebook of the people I thought we're gonna be in the tournament.
Speaker 0: Well, I mean you could look at the netrunner DB of those people.
Speaker 0: But yeah, just if you could.
Speaker 0: just you know, bringing rock to the scissors is just how things go.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I mean, you know, what's the compute?
Speaker 0: could if everyone knows the computers gonna be playing everyone could target things.
Speaker 0: They know the computer's weakness is but it's even if the computer knows that it has this weakness It's it's not like you can do anything about it.
Speaker 0: It's like if I know that I'm bad at you know the swimming part of the triathlon I'm still slow at swimming.
Speaker 0: It's like good But I'm gonna do better.
Speaker 1: or you get you build a different body because you're a robot and you can do whatever you want.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's you know I'm really want to see something play games with randomness and imperfect information.
Speaker 1: But I suspect that after this point humans will not significantly contribute to the further understanding of go as a game.
Speaker 0: I think they I think they will in the very short term because They're humans.
Speaker 0: the humans who are into go are gonna learn a ton from these games and other games that happened in chess.
Speaker 1: Humans never beat the AI again.
Speaker 1: The only thing that happened was human games started doing things they did ending in draws more.
Speaker 0: Oh, yes, they're not letting the AlphaGo play so many public games against masters.
Speaker 0: It played five games.
Speaker 0: now They're gonna improve it I guess before letting it play anyone else.
Speaker 0: and in these like very extreme short term They're gonna learn from what it did and learn new things from that on their own.
Speaker 0: But then when AlphaGo comes back another time or another time Right after it's like alpha beta or I guess beta go or gamma go or whatever it is at that point It'll be so advanced that there isn't anything new to learn from it.
Speaker 0: It'll just school everyone and there won't be any human, you know, I don't.
Speaker 0: it'll school everyone more than there is to learn.
Speaker 1: It's gonna play out exactly the same way I did with chess and the end game of that is chess among humans is really boring now And if you played chess against anyone online, they're almost always cheating with AI.
Speaker 0: It'll be kind of sad.
Speaker 0: if if I mean I don't like go I don't like playing it You know, but it'll be kind of sad if it goes the way of chess to where playing it professionally is now dumb.
Speaker 1: Yeah well it wouldn't be dumb except that chess is kind of fundamental end game seems to be that like the gravity like the Attractors in the full space of chess that we haven't explored.
Speaker 1: it appears that most of the attractors are draws So humans can stumble into the draw patterns and do things that the AI is also doing.
Speaker 1: but because the humans aren't perfect like the AI is or at least not near perfect the humans will always be pulled into the Draw black holes and playing for the draw is much more reliable now than playing for the win.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I Wonder if the game of go itself will change in any way, right?
Speaker 0: Will they upgrade to like 20 by 20 or 21 by 21?
Speaker 0: Well, that's gonna be the other.
Speaker 0: are they gonna upgrade it to beyond the capacity of the computer?
Speaker 0: But you know humans will have to change their game dramatically obviously also But at least if they can get out of range of the computer being able to play then they can still have meaningful games Again, there
Speaker 1: might however now and not
Speaker 0: everything from 19 by 19 is irrelevant in 20 by 20 or 21 by 21.
Speaker 1: But I think the AI is now in a similar intuitive position to humans.
Speaker 1: I suspect this AI if thrown against 20 by 20 Would do as well as at least like the Masters.
Speaker 1: It might not be humans all the time.
Speaker 0: The problem is it do.
Speaker 0: well I think the problem is is if you go to like if you go even bigger just if you let's say, you know Let's say we knew for sure the 25 by 25 was out of the computers range.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right, like you would run out of time because Moore's law hasn't caught up right and whatever you we just can't.
Speaker 1: but how good Would humans be at that game?
Speaker 0: Well, I mean so I mean a lot of the things they know already would be okay.
Speaker 0: I think the problem is the game is to be too long.
Speaker 0: It would just take too long to play a 25 by 25.
Speaker 0: You'd be there for like 10 years.
Speaker 1: go Google Google for the 50 move rule or the hundred move rule in chess.
Speaker 1: That is the sad state of chess today.
Speaker 0: Well, I mean go doesn't have that problem because the board only fills up more.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but if the board gets too big, it's like.
Speaker 0: well we had to fill this whole fucking board.
Speaker 1: All right, we don't have time for this shit and I suspect Unlike the NHL or the NFL No one's gonna change the rules of go.
Speaker 0: Mmm, I could see some minor rules being changed.
Speaker 0: Duty things learned from this computer, but it would take a very long time, right?
Speaker 1: But I didn't know there was a disconnect between the two methods of scoring.
Speaker 1: that was actually different.
Speaker 0: There's different methods of scoring There's there's all sorts of thing.
Speaker 0: go you know despite being what seems like a culture of like a conservative old game of like 2500 years old has changed its rules over the course of time pretty significantly Slowly because in the last ten years go go is not afraid.
Speaker 0: I mean, it's it's not.
Speaker 0: it's less afraid to change its rules than baseball is right It's not I mean, it's still conservative, but it's less afraid of changing than other conservative games and sports out there.
Speaker 1: So chess's rules have changed significantly over the years, right?
Speaker 1: I'm Hassan and all that shit and moving pawns twice in the beginning.
Speaker 1: that just happened to speed up the game because the game went too long.
Speaker 0: Yep, so Good for you in that respect.
Speaker 0: go but computers coming for you.
Speaker 1: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Speaker 0: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 1: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows It's actually recorded at night
Speaker 1: and the patrons for this episode of geek nights in order of the amount of money They give us on a continuing basis are Nicholas Brandau Rebecca Dunn Amanda Duchette James David white Christian coons Jess my state e.com mechanical mind.
Speaker 1: William Eisen rose Jeremy minor.
Speaker 1: you expected the next name to be yours But it was me do.
Speaker 1: Sean Yeager Clinton Walton Renee Ren from New Zealand Robert Lee Ryan Perrin drew open lander.
Speaker 1: rare Lavelle Brian's hadroni Rochelle, Monta Nona Finn.
Speaker 1: Eric Silveraude can't melt steel beams.
Speaker 1: Kinetic man Aaron Cerise Chris midkiff Chris Knox is getting hilariously gangbang by the blue man group.
Speaker 1: Sam Corddry Daniel Redmond Chris Haddad Sean Klein Chris Reimer and Thomas Han.
Speaker 1: We just recorded the February Q&A.
Speaker 1: So now I'm gonna open up the March Q&A.
Speaker 1: We also just recorded a Rivoli review of Zootopia.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna get both of those out over the course of this week.
Speaker 1: We're gonna be an anime Boston's like I can.
Speaker 1: all those places.
Speaker 1: Stay tuned for more patreon stuff as fast as I can make it.
Speaker 1: and now Something weird.
Speaker 0: Come on pal.
Speaker 0: We want the names of the other punks You were with.
Speaker 0: we're supposed to be out on the beat keeping the streets safe and clean.
Speaker 1: Pay heed to the words of my brother for it is better to name thy Accomplices and have them with thee in prison than to die by grenade, which is what's gonna happen any minute now Speaking scientifically.
Speaker 1: the bucket falls over when it's hit by a ball.
Speaker 1: The string is pulled tight pulling the pin out of the grenade stuffed in the suspect's mouth, which leads to certain results.
Speaker 1: Try it one more time.
Speaker 1: specs.
Speaker 1: God's too busy to be kept waiting for this sinner hell.
Speaker 0: I've had my turn.
Speaker 1: Wow, come here and see if you can get a hole in one.
Speaker 1: Yep Lieutenant are we supposed to question suspects this way?
Speaker 1: Is this by the book lieutenant?
Speaker 0: Listen kids, there's two things that policeman needs.
Speaker 0: He's got to be smart and he's got to have balls Okay.