Speaker 1: It's Monday August 22nd 2016.
Speaker 1: I'm rim.
Speaker 1: He's Scott and this is geek nights tonight and tells new KP like architecture and adblock Wars and a bunch of meat.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: So I actually was looking at of all things because I've been biking to work again And the weather is like perfect for biking now, and I if I got caught in that rainstorm biking yesterday I dodged that rainstorm not yesterday.
Speaker 1: I didn't get rain on Saturday.
Speaker 1: I was on the west side with Emily.
Speaker 0: Saturday I avoided getting rained on.
Speaker 0: I was biking and I saw there.
Speaker 0: I knew the rain was coming so it was time to go home and then as I was coming home I saw the rain moving around in the distance.
Speaker 0: We saw the rain coming and I went over.
Speaker 0: I was getting towards Queens and things were looking wet.
Speaker 0: All the streets are crazy wet.
Speaker 0: They're big puddles everywhere, but it wasn't raining.
Speaker 0: We just said and I managed to get home without getting wet and we kept biking.
Speaker 1: So we biked through the rain and then the rain lit up.
Speaker 1: We're like, alright, that was fun.
Speaker 1: And then we're like, well, we're wet now.
Speaker 1: So let's just go home and then the crazy rain came out of nowhere.
Speaker 1: So we just we're done.
Speaker 1: We're on our way home.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so we biked over the like went all the way home over the bridge and everything.
Speaker 1: It was raining so hard that on the bridge you didn't slip and fall.
Speaker 1: No, cuz I got a good bike and good tires and I got know what I'm doing.
Speaker 1: But uh, well if I didn't fall it does some slippery shit though, you know Good tires good technique Even even pro people fall down Yeah occasionally But again at the same time my tires are not.
Speaker 1: my tires are sort of designed for Like.
Speaker 1: they're not as efficient as like a pro racer tire would be because I like to be comfortable and I like to not fall over.
Speaker 1: So going up the bridge There's all those downspouts that are inside the bike lane for when it rains because usually they're on people biking over there.
Speaker 1: Water was just spraying out of them like fire hoses all the way up the bridge.
Speaker 1: it's good times, but I Noticed this morning as I was biking to work that my left my front brake cable Has a few.
Speaker 1: a few of the threads have snapped internally.
Speaker 1: I can feel it in there.
Speaker 1: so it's time to get those replaced and I went and updated my bike maintenance log as I keep track of what maintenance I do and I Gathered some slightly interesting statistics while I was at work over lunch.
Speaker 1: Okay, I realized that I replaced my bike brake pads Front and rear.
Speaker 1: I was replacing at the same time every three years tops See my the blood.
Speaker 1: the bike I got in the pads just like the pads.
Speaker 0: the bike I got in 2010. it's now 2016.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: I replaced the pads once ever and they're still fine now.
Speaker 1: my cables I replace a Little over twice a year, but just the brake cables.
Speaker 0: the cables twice a year.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I've replaced the cables never.
Speaker 1: the reason I replace them invariably is I snap them.
Speaker 1: Okay, so I was digging around to my other stuff now my other cables like my shifter cables.
Speaker 0: It sounds like they're probably too tight.
Speaker 1: Uh, no, I think Ones.
Speaker 0: no, I've never.
Speaker 0: I've never broken a shifting or braking cable.
Speaker 1: but I was looking through some note like email emails I had and receipts from older stuff and I pretty much never wear out my brake pads.
Speaker 1: It's just the cables.
Speaker 1: and I was thinking about my biking style, especially in the old days But I think I just carried over from mountain biking.
Speaker 1: I very rarely will shed speed Slow like I'll never shed speed by like bleeding my brakes along the way I'll pretty much be going real fast and then I'll shed my speed all at once if I'm forced to so hard braking Rarely,
Speaker 0: that's pretty much how you drive a car.
Speaker 0: Also a bad way Like that.
Speaker 0: Listen, like racing someone who do something dumb you get rid you go You you hit the brake way too late and way too hard.
Speaker 1: pretty much almost always.
Speaker 1: engine brake in my car.
Speaker 0: Yeah, also bad.
Speaker 0: why when I when I ride a vehicle I break smoothly and well in advance and go You're stopping it's just gliding and Decelerating and then you're stopped.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you stop.
Speaker 1: The only time I don't do that is when I'm driving in New York when everything's stop and go nonsense Even in the stop and go nonsense.
Speaker 0: I will go.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I do.
Speaker 1: I would like to ride in a car with you.
Speaker 1: Then I just let's say you even drove in New York.
Speaker 1: next time we're gonna drive to a con or something you rent the car instead of me and you can drive and I will sit In the back and I will very well just quietly and politely critique how?
Speaker 1: Rapidly you are braking and accelerating.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: We'll see how that goes.
Speaker 1: We all even do a video.
Speaker 1: live stream live stream drive like that video probably just be mad that I'm going slow.
Speaker 1: Thing is it's New York.
Speaker 1: I can't ever complain about someone going slow.
Speaker 1: It's just gonna go slow.
Speaker 0: It's you are even on the highway.
Speaker 0: I'll be going slow and you'll be like, yeah Why would you go slow on the highway?
Speaker 1: you go as fast as you can Because I go smoothly and safely.
Speaker 0: are the top two prior?
Speaker 1: Well, no you go fast as you can when it's a straight line.
Speaker 0: Lastly is the third priority that?
Speaker 1: well, yeah But I'm talking like on the Garden State like down to Wildwood.
Speaker 1: just go like 80 cruise control and that's just it.
Speaker 0: No, why?
Speaker 0: Why not?
Speaker 0: that's not how I do but there's.
Speaker 1: it's not like there's traffic just going 80.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so you don't go 80.
Speaker 1: No, you're gonna be that guy in the right lane.
Speaker 1: Everyone's passing you going slow.
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 0: All right old man I got my two priorities of safely and smoothly.
Speaker 1: I would say that going the speed of traffic is safely.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm In fact, I would say that it's very much less safe to be the person who's going slower than everybody else in the right lane.
Speaker 0: Uh-huh says he who skis.
Speaker 1: Yeah In fact, so also it's time to buy new skis.
Speaker 1: a lot of you might think that you know in the old days There was always this conventional wisdom with specialized equipment time To make excuses to buy things like Scott who just bought a new bike when your old bike is perfectly fine.
Speaker 0: I didn't need an excuse to buy that.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: Well, but so why did you buy a new bike?
Speaker 0: It was $800 off.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know, I'm buying new skis.
Speaker 1: There's $600 off.
Speaker 1: It's the season to buy last year's new stuff that no one bought at like half off.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: So buy new skis because the skis I wanted are literally like 48% off right now and I did a little bit of research and Every all the reviews seem to agree that these skis are what rim wants.
Speaker 1: to get better skis would be to spend Stupid amounts of money and to get shittier skis would be not saving enough money to be worth getting shittier skis.
Speaker 1: So I'm pretty much buying them.
Speaker 1: They're basically just like the modern better version of the skis.
Speaker 1: I got now slightly shorter because I The style of like super long skis is not what I do and not what really anyone needs to do anymore.
Speaker 1: and even better The same kind of skis but like couple steps down right like in Emily's wheelhouse because she's just getting into black diamonds right now.
Speaker 1: Also super discount.
Speaker 1: I think it's time to buy skis.
Speaker 0: No, it's not gonna snow.
Speaker 0: So good luck with that.
Speaker 1: Last year was the El Nino year.
Speaker 1: This year's gonna be like normal snow weather probably Global warming and I can ski anywhere.
Speaker 1: Ah climate change tends to cause more extreme weather not necessarily just warmer rather.
Speaker 1: So in our area, I'm likely to get more snow this year.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: We'll see.
Speaker 0: eventually it's gonna be 80 all year.
Speaker 1: Well, yeah when it gets to that point I'll probably flee because New York is flooded and we're fucked anyway, and I gotta go somewhere way flooded on the third floor by me.
Speaker 1: Yeah, what are you gonna be going to work through the canals in Manhattan like Venice?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I have a bike powered boat.
Speaker 1: Those.
Speaker 1: have you ever ridden one of those things they go So much like for the amount of pedal compared to how fast you go.
Speaker 1: They are the worst possible thing.
Speaker 0: That's because those are right.
Speaker 0: You could make a boat that was powered by pedaling like a bicycle but didn't go slow.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah There they exist.
Speaker 0: those the ones that you happen to rent at like a vacation place or a little lake just happen to be go.
Speaker 1: They exist.
Speaker 1: you ever see him.
Speaker 1: They're a kayak.
Speaker 1: They look like a kayak, but once you get going they rise up out of the water And they're on just like one little wing-a-ling.
Speaker 0: I mean, I'm sure you could even just do a thing where there's like a flywheel and you use you pedal to just get You know energy into it and then put it into a normal motor like the kind of powerboat has with a little propeller.
Speaker 1: I'll show you a video or I'll link to a video.
Speaker 1: I'll find a video one of those things I'm just saying.
Speaker 1: there are many mechanisms that can be done But it's basically a kayak with a little wing-a-ling and you fly out of the water and it's cool and that's what you want.
Speaker 1: But even then I think a bicycle on asphalt is gonna be way more efficient.
Speaker 1: It's just my guess.
Speaker 0: Nothing is nothing.
Speaker 0: No mode of transportation that's ever been invented is better than a bicycle in terms of efficiency.
Speaker 1: That's probably true, but I don't.
Speaker 1: I'm not sure and I can't back that up But I could see that being plausible.
Speaker 0: the bicycle is the most efficient form of transportation ever actually created by human beings.
Speaker 1: Ah Say it depends.
Speaker 1: What do you?
Speaker 0: and it's also more efficient than any animal.
Speaker 1: What do you mean by more efficient?
Speaker 0: Energy you put in to make it go versus how much you go.
Speaker 1: But what do you mean about how much you go?
Speaker 1: What if I make something?
Speaker 0: how fast and how far?
Speaker 1: what if I make something?
Speaker 1: That weighs an ounce has a payload of another ounce and is super efficient.
Speaker 1: Does that win?
Speaker 0: How it has to go.
Speaker 0: as to carry, you know carry a lot.
Speaker 1: That's what I'm saying.
Speaker 1: What's your metric for going?
Speaker 0: has to go.
Speaker 0: You're one.
Speaker 0: you're one like I have a grain of salt.
Speaker 0: It gets carried in the wind.
Speaker 0: It's like.
Speaker 1: that's super efficient.
Speaker 0: It's like It's not a. it's not a transportation mechanisms.
Speaker 1: You got any news here on this Monday gig nights.
Speaker 0: I mean we talked about this all the time, but I guess you know It's a. it's a battle that we've always been involved in and it's raging yet again.
Speaker 0: So we might as well continue to rage.
Speaker 0: I don't think we talked about it last time at two weeks ago.
Speaker 0: So Facebook has decided to start the next battle in the war on ad blocking.
Speaker 1: Well, there was a there.
Speaker 1: there were multiple salvos in rapid succession on this one, right?
Speaker 0: It seems like we're winning.
Speaker 0: But anyway, so what Facebook was basically like, alright, here's what we're gonna do?
Speaker 0: We are going to stop ad blockers from blocking ads in your Facebook feed.
Speaker 0: So what they tried to do is Make ads in the Facebook feed look a lot like posts in the Facebook feed to confuse the ad blockers.
Speaker 0: So the ad blockers updated their shit like real quick Yep, and then Facebook shifted again, and I think the ad blockers shifted again.
Speaker 0: and the main reason that Facebook cannot win this battle is because at least in the United States, there's actually a law that's actually Surprisingly well enforced really?
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: What's this law?
Speaker 1: This is a twist on this.
Speaker 1: I didn't know about.
Speaker 0: I forgot.
Speaker 0: I forgot the name of it, but I'll get it for you.
Speaker 1: Sure.
Speaker 1: It's real.
Speaker 0: Yes I read about it in like three places.
Speaker 0: when I because I it was like a week ago that I read because I got nothing On this.
Speaker 1: this is all you.
Speaker 1: I got nothing.
Speaker 0: You can't just like have ads in the feed that don't say their ads.
Speaker 0: you can't just like put a post in there.
Speaker 0: So if there's like like it has to have the word like like.
Speaker 0: they're putting the word Sponsored there or like, you know, Google separates the ads from the listings.
Speaker 0: Yep It's like they can't not do that because at least the United States you'll get in trouble if you don't.
Speaker 0: if you do that Ah, it's so beautiful.
Speaker 0: Basically, it's like yeah as long as they have to make the ads not exactly a hundred percent identical to the not ads and as long We can find it's like you can write code just like if you see the word sponsored.
Speaker 1: block the whole thing Ah, but there's a second component to this.
Speaker 1: because Facebook has to work in a web browser as a web page and not a proprietary Application we can render it over the fuck we want.
Speaker 0: Well, yeah, we know that's that's the original news But the two things together.
Speaker 0: the other thing is that Facebook right the way that they tried to you know Make mix the ads in with the content.
Speaker 0: They didn't count on this.
Speaker 0: They did not count that the ad blocking people Would be willing to block content along with the ads.
Speaker 0: now See, it's like the like the way they blocked some of the Facebook ads.
Speaker 0: They also ended up eliminating legit things from the feed with this blocking mechanism.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna back up and go to a completely different place in case and Facebook was like Facebook was like.
Speaker 0: Hey you ad blockers are ruining the people's feeds with their ad blocking and they're pretty much like we don't give a shit.
Speaker 0: We'd rather not see as low Who sells ads.
Speaker 1: look upon my field of fucks and see that it is barren.
Speaker 0: It's like I'd rather have.
Speaker 0: no I'd like if you if there was a way All right, like.
Speaker 0: it's like if I had to block half the tweets in my Twitter feeds in order to get rid of the ads.
Speaker 1: But I would good luck.
Speaker 1: Have fun.
Speaker 1: Awesome.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 1: Well to back up a bit remember the early in the earliest days of email spam wasn't a thing Like.
Speaker 1: I remember when I got spam.
Speaker 1: like a spam email came into my account at our IT Delete button and I saw it in Elm.
Speaker 1: I didn't push the delete button.
Speaker 1: I forward it to the abuse at our IT dot edu and they would look into like blocking it.
Speaker 1: for me That is how different the internet was not that long ago.
Speaker 0: I was telnet it into a server.
Speaker 0: You don't know.
Speaker 0: that was really long ago, by the way, uh 16 14 14 years ago.
Speaker 1: That's a long time ago Yeah, but it's also not that long ago.
Speaker 0: a kid who was born then be 14 right now.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so In the when Gmail added spam blocking the earliest problem that was noticed was that a lot of you know A lot of spam blockers would block.
Speaker 1: you had two ways to go either Never get false positives But as a result a lot of spam got through or you'd tune it more and more and you'd risk missing an email you wanted To see but in return you block a higher percentage of the spam and what everyone realized very early in the email spam blocking wars Was that pretty much everyone would be willing to miss like 90% of their emails rather than see a single spam
Speaker 0: pretty much
Speaker 1: and adds it the same way.
Speaker 1: I remember when I used to use host files.
Speaker 1: There was an anime site I used to go to and one day they had this giant horrible animated banner ad over the whole site and I was like well and I added it to my host file and Then the entire site didn't render anymore.
Speaker 1: It was basically like just text on a white screen and I was like actually this is better I think.
Speaker 0: imagine this you got a TV show.
Speaker 0: The TV show is 20 minutes long.
Speaker 0: Yeah It's an episode of adventure time.
Speaker 0: you can either watch this episode of adventure time and one commercial that is 60 seconds long or You can watch this episode of adventure time and miss one minute of the episode of adventure time.
Speaker 0: at that point I would choose the third option of I just pirate the adventure time entire saying if those are your only two choices You're probably missing the one minute of adventure time.
Speaker 0: You don't have to watch some like ad for something about the old VHS days.
Speaker 1: Remember as a kid my one of the chores of my family was someone had to be the manual ad block for the family.
Speaker 1: so Simpsons Cosby show all the stuff that we watch.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we watch The Cosby Show.
Speaker 0: We did not watch The Cosby Show.
Speaker 1: I watched a lot.
Speaker 1: We like we were like with.
Speaker 1: there were certain shows that we would watch as a family.
Speaker 0: We watched The nanny.
Speaker 0: Whoa, and we watched.
Speaker 1: well, we didn't watch the nanny and we watched.
Speaker 1: I watched mr.
Speaker 1: Belvedere The Fresh Prince of Bel Air.
Speaker 1: We watched both elf and we fucking watched small wonder.
Speaker 1: we did not watch small wonder small wonder But one of the chores the family was someone had to sit there and record the shows that we're all gonna watch.
Speaker 1: we never watched him live and they would pause the recording whenever the commercials came on and Unpause it.
Speaker 1: and because you know the person doing it It was like taking off the garbage like ah, I gotta block the ads this week mom.
Speaker 1: I don't wanna.
Speaker 1: So sometimes I'd miss like I wouldn't notice.
Speaker 1: the show came on and I'd miss like the first five minutes of the episode.
Speaker 1: No one complained about that.
Speaker 1: No one was sad about that.
Speaker 1: We just missed part of the Simpsons because that's fine because no one wanted to see the ads.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: so in a tiny kind of side news the The newest Android 7.0 is coming out.
Speaker 1: You know what they're calling it.
Speaker 0: What letter are we on?
Speaker 0: and and Nutella?
Speaker 0: Nugget, okay, that's the second choice.
Speaker 1: I think Nutella is a trademark.
Speaker 0: that was that was actually my second guess cuz that was the only other end candy other than neko wafer.
Speaker 1: Yeah, neko wafer could have been good I think.
Speaker 0: but I realized after I said what was the first thing.
Speaker 0: I said Nutella that is trademark as a trademark.
Speaker 0: But now it was also trademark and nougat is the only non trademark You know, yep, and there's the old.
Speaker 1: the news is pretty good.
Speaker 1: Like it's gonna go out to most Nexus devices.
Speaker 1: The only Sad thing about this update is that they're not pushing it to the Nexus 4 or 5. now You might say baram those show those phones are old as fuck and I would say yes, that is true.
Speaker 0: What about that?
Speaker 0: What was the tablet?
Speaker 0: the Nexus?
Speaker 1: 7 like the first Nexus tablet It's not listed here is getting it but I don't know if it's not getting it because I have one.
Speaker 0: I actually got one super cheap.
Speaker 0: It was like 10 bucks.
Speaker 0: Oh, I use it just for the live wedge app.
Speaker 1: I was thinking about getting the smallest cheapest Android tablet at some point because I have that teleprompter.
Speaker 1: so I have the teleprompter and It works with a phone like you stick the phone in the bottom and it's teleprompter is tiny.
Speaker 1: When I got my tiny phone My tiny phone barely fits in there.
Speaker 0: Like it's a little too small actually because size it is And I'll tell you if the little tab little so.
Speaker 1: I kick-started a while ago and I even think about it the newer version of The teleprompter and it's way bigger.
Speaker 1: It literally my phone is literally too small to put in this teleprompter.
Speaker 1: So I need a tiny tablet.
Speaker 1: I was last time you use the teleprompter I've practiced with it a bunch, but I haven't made any videos with it since the five nights of Fred because video.
Speaker 0: And now you're gonna buy a second teleprompter and you haven't used the first one
Speaker 1: because I use it once For one video and actually actually I've got a bunch of work work queued up and I'm probably gonna use it for that because it's Way easier to use a teleprompter for that kind of stuff.
Speaker 1: Like me looking into a screen talking about with method to and you're gonna time stamps NTP.
Speaker 1: so The Nexus 5 is not getting it.
Speaker 1: but many people have pointed out that the Nexus 5 is 100% capable of running it like.
Speaker 1: there's literally no reason not to push it out there.
Speaker 0: I'm sure you can.
Speaker 0: I'm sure you can just do it.
Speaker 1: I don't know, but you're not gonna get it automatically.
Speaker 1: you're gonna have to like fuck with it to make it happen.
Speaker 1: It's not just gonna come over the air.
Speaker 0: I mean, even though it's capable It's probably just a matter of.
Speaker 0: they could only have so much time to test on so many devices.
Speaker 0: They didn't go that far back and it's not worth it for them.
Speaker 1: You get is the turning point because I think it's gonna sell Nexus fives if they do it, right my phone The Sony Xperia z5c comp like compact is the best Android hardware in the world.
Speaker 1: bar None for a phone right now just for all those reasons.
Speaker 1: It is so powerful.
Speaker 1: Everything's great about it.
Speaker 1: The question will be will it get nougat or not?
Speaker 1: because if it gets It's worth it.
Speaker 0: So the joys of an iPhone.
Speaker 0: you're gonna get it.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah the joys of this.
Speaker 1: It's waterproof and the battery lasts like 50 hours.
Speaker 0: legit iPhone battery last a fucking long time.
Speaker 1: your iPhone battery ran out.
Speaker 0: when we were at Sandy Hooks I was running Strava like non.
Speaker 1: I was running Strava to Scott.
Speaker 1: When we got home at the end of the day, I still had like 60% battery.
Speaker 0: I think I ran it on the boat though as my mistake.
Speaker 1: But you know as I said, I got this z5c partly because it's like androids.
Speaker 1: last gas.
Speaker 1: and If this phone gets seven then androids still a good Still in the running.
Speaker 1: or if they release a z6c that is just a better phone then in a two-year cycle I'll just upgrade my Android phone to the newest Sony every two years.
Speaker 1: if neither of those happens iPhone 7 SE but you bottles Android apps.
Speaker 0: We're gonna do an iPhone.
Speaker 1: Yeah Android that let's see.
Speaker 1: I bought dogcatcher.
Speaker 1: It's a podcatcher.
Speaker 1: I cost like a dollar or two.
Speaker 0: The iPhone has one built-in you don't need.
Speaker 1: I bought a Carcassonne.
Speaker 1: Oh, no, I gotta buy that again.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I guess you do.
Speaker 1: I bought a super hexagon.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't need to buy that again.
Speaker 1: I play that game out.
Speaker 1: I bought settlers not gonna re-buy that now, uh I Think I bought anything else.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Oh though.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah I didn't get the YubiKey or NFC.
Speaker 1: so I don't have to worry about that because Security keys with NFC do not work with iPhone because Apple just go fuck yourself.
Speaker 1: Apple doesn't care.
Speaker 0: Well, maybe one knows they got a new updates coming right away.
Speaker 0: Say they like to do everything after everyone else already does it?
Speaker 1: And the other news is interesting or at least vaguely interesting is that Skylake processors like it is still a golden age of if you have a bad old shitty or broken computer or like you're about To go to college.
Speaker 1: It is like the time to buy a computer.
Speaker 1: Holy crap Like even if you don't need like the 1080 videos mostly Nvidia's fault yeah, but not just like processors have been plateaued for so long that you can get like the Fastest Intel i7 Skylake bullshit computer for like way under two grand.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I mean, that's what happens.
Speaker 0: like for example You know whenever a new thing comes out, not only is that new thing out, but the thing that is great But just now.
Speaker 0: one model old is now cheap for a thousand.
Speaker 0: nine eighties are going like all everyone's.
Speaker 0: getting nine eighties like 1080 is the loading up of nine eighties.
Speaker 1: a thousand dollars including a video card.
Speaker 1: You can buy a fucking supercomputer.
Speaker 1: if you're willing to spend two grand.
Speaker 1: you can buy a god.
Speaker 1: but What's interesting is that the next generation was originally I think it was gonna be like a 10 nanometer process like they were gonna go like fucking crazy, but instead Kaby Lake, which is the next chip is It's still 14 nanometers far as I can tell.
Speaker 1: like it's not it's not going.
Speaker 0: I was reading about the five nanometer process.
Speaker 0: Oh, so Here's the problem and they're discussing like what kind of gate they need to make to get this to work.
Speaker 0: So like they're like we're gonna use the all-around gate or we're gonna use like the like the F whatever it's called.
Speaker 1: So I'm gonna tell you kids a secret if you buy computers ever like you know about computers And you know enough about processors to go to Wikipedia and click on like Kaby Lake to see like what's coming next The problem is you're always gonna see the next one.
Speaker 1: so I can see Kaby Lake Which isn't coming out really till like next year, but I can click on Canon Lake.
Speaker 1: And if I look at Canon Lake, I'm like, ooh, yes, I can wait for Canon Lake But then I can see that ice lake is the successor to that.
Speaker 1: and if I click on ice lake I can be like Oh, that's some 10 nanometer bullshit.
Speaker 1: Ooh, but then I see that Tiger Lake is the success.
Speaker 1: You'll never buy a computer.
Speaker 1: You will never buy a computer if you get on that road.
Speaker 1: Hmm.
Speaker 1: You got to just buy a computer.
Speaker 0: or Is the thing that some people do?
Speaker 0: Yeah, they buy everything.
Speaker 1: true That happens.
Speaker 1: But in the very least you can look ahead and see.
Speaker 1: is the next Architecture going to do something that I care about like?
Speaker 1: is it worth waiting like kind of?
Speaker 1: could I use the computer?
Speaker 1: I've got for another year because if I can I can get the next-gen architecture.
Speaker 0: I just use a thing until it's dead and then I get a new one.
Speaker 0: I don't really pay too much attention like what's.
Speaker 0: you know the timing is well I care about the only adjust my timing slightly.
Speaker 0: You know it's like if my shit's broke.
Speaker 0: I need a new one and if I see something new is coming out in like two months like all right.
Speaker 0: I wait two months, but if you get past that point where it's not broken yet.
Speaker 1: But it's like you have a choice.
Speaker 1: if you could upgrade now and get Significant benefits of grading or wait and get better benefits, right?
Speaker 0: Just how much am I gonna wait?
Speaker 0: We're gonna wait a whole year.
Speaker 0: It's like how broken is my shit?
Speaker 1: Like?
Speaker 1: I don't think I can wait for KP Lake cuz my computer.
Speaker 1: I need a new computer.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna buy the baddest ass guy.
Speaker 0: Peter looks like it's working to me.
Speaker 1: Uh Yeah, it is working But it's not fast enough anymore.
Speaker 0: Is there anything you did where it didn't?
Speaker 0: didn't get the job?
Speaker 1: editing 4k video playing some modern games?
Speaker 1: copying large files from flashcards to the computer?
Speaker 1: Because I've used v2.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah USB 3 is computers so old.
Speaker 0: there isn't a USB 3 PCI Express card You can get.
Speaker 1: I could but all my PCI slots are filled with shit and one of them doesn't work.
Speaker 0: How many devices do you have?
Speaker 1: his computer's all knife?
Speaker 0: I don't have.
Speaker 0: like any PCI Express things.
Speaker 1: I have one that's broken and There's.
Speaker 1: there's a bunch of problems my computer.
Speaker 0: But anyway, the news another thing that rim broke on purpose to excuse buying a new No peed on his computer.
Speaker 0: I saw him.
Speaker 1: Yeah But anyway, the news is that Kaby Lake Intel's going big on.
Speaker 1: the thing that it does is that the built-in Intel video stuff like if you don't have a video card Can play overwatch on like pretty big settings like straight up and play 4k video like it's nothing.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't really believe this because I'm sure I saw videos of like, you know, the old Intel You know video chips that they come in laptops and stuff and they would be like, oh, yeah These are totally great.
Speaker 1: You can totally game with these and once you totally game with the Intel 7 stuff in my laptop and once you finally get one, they're garbage my laptop I think my my Lenovo 230 with a core i7 can place at 5. it can play overwatch Just with the settings down like it works.
Speaker 1: fine.
Speaker 1: Place rocket League Like a champ.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it does.
Speaker 1: It's garbage.
Speaker 1: Okay, but it totally does.
Speaker 1: but this this chipset Now would be that like I would before we were talking about how now might be the time to like upgrade your HTPC because it'll Last forever, especially as you can get the tiny 1080s and make a tiny computer.
Speaker 1: You might be able to go even tinier if you can hold out till Kaby Lake.
Speaker 1: cuz if Kaby Lake holds up you can make A flat computer.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you can make a computer.
Speaker 1: That's just a tiny motherboard with a CPU in it Like an m.2 hard drive stuck into it and one RAM stick stuck into it.
Speaker 1: That's the whole computer.
Speaker 0: It'll play games it the sideways Laptop RAM basically a laptop without a screen with a bunch of USBs and HDMI.
Speaker 1: That's probably about the size of the 95 watt power supply from my laptop, right?
Speaker 0: And just put that under your TV.
Speaker 1: Yeah get less furniture If you're a computer like PC gaming enthusiast.
Speaker 1: now is the time to be alive.
Speaker 1: But anyway things of the day.
Speaker 1: so our friends Phil and Jay.
Speaker 1: Phil sent me a link and he was like I have a thing of the day for you.
Speaker 0: Well, in other words rim is so bad at finding things the day He can only get a good one when someone else better than him.
Speaker 1: of everyone who'd expressed an opinion and the old man chopping garlic versus funny overwatch video thing of the day 100% of those opinions said that my thing of the day about overwatch was funnier.
Speaker 0: I asked I asked all the people in a small town in Wyoming Who is gonna be president and all of them said it would be Donald Trump.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's that's.
Speaker 0: that is the equivalent of what you just said.
Speaker 1: All right, does anyone think that Scott's old man chopping garlic was better than funny overwatch video?
Speaker 0: Yeah, anyone who isn't a 13 year old kid?
Speaker 1: anyway Whenever someone because a lot of people, you know, you know like Luke Crane with this thing where people like, you know You should do and he's like, you know you should do.
Speaker 1: So people always are like, you know What would be a good thing at the day and they send me stuff and it's usually stuff that either already was the thing of the day or that is like five to ten years old and they just found it recently, but this is Something special.
Speaker 1: so I get to set the stage.
Speaker 1: There's a YouTube channel and this YouTube channel is called.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna zoom in on this.
Speaker 1: What is the YouTube channel actually called?
Speaker 1: so I think it's just called sitting and smiling and the guy live streams like every day or two a video.
Speaker 1: There's hundreds of them and Every one of these live streams is called sitting and smiling and then the number of the episode and it's him for about two hours Just sitting cross-legged with lighting smiling at the camera.
Speaker 0: So he's just like a meditating dude, but he videos himself meditating and that's it on you.
Speaker 1: There's a tiny chance like there's ways you could fake the live stream.
Speaker 0: Sure.
Speaker 0: I'm sure you could but these videos exist.
Speaker 0: But I mean plenty of people meditate two hours a day.
Speaker 0: So making a stream of it is not unrealistic Yeah, but he does it like he sits down.
Speaker 1: He just does it with a goofy smile sitting there two hours every day or so.
Speaker 0: in one of these videos Somebody post a comment that says like in one of the videos he stops smiley frowns for a second.
Speaker 0: Can you find it?
Speaker 0: and you have.
Speaker 0: you have like?
Speaker 0: 200 hours of video to look through and you're never gonna find it.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna quote this thing that I'm looking at right here.
Speaker 1: The episode of sitting and smiling features a very special guest about 2.5 hours in the webcast.
Speaker 0: At least they tell you when it is.
Speaker 0: That's nice.
Speaker 1: This is the guy.
Speaker 1: I hear someone come into the house Which is odd because only my housemate is at work and we aren't expecting anyone.
Speaker 1: I realized I didn't check to see if the doors are locked before starting the webcast.
Speaker 1: I hear the person stealthily moving around the house Mm-hmm, and then I hear them stealthily climbing the stairs toward my room the door opens and then I hear an unfamiliar male voice Say hello.
Speaker 1: Then after presumably seeing me sitting still and smiling in front of a camera lit from beneath by a fluorescent bulb He promptly descends the stairs and exits the house.
Speaker 1: Okay, you can see this happen at two thirty six thirty.
Speaker 1: So that is my thing of the day that the best guess is that a robber broke into this house And later on like yes Like the guy who's in for that robbery came in.
Speaker 1: because think about this you break into a house You think it's empty you're going around getting to rob stuff and then you come into a room and you see a dude Just sitting there smiling at a camera and not moving Silently with weird lighting.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think I would abscond.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean the guy saw your face.
Speaker 0: So even if you steal stuff, oh, he doesn't see.
Speaker 1: I don't know if he cuz the guy just saw like the shadow.
Speaker 1: I think cuz.
Speaker 1: in the video the guys like his eyes kind of like look to the side, but he doesn't turn his head He doesn't interrupt the smiling.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm Also props to the guy for like not interrupting the smiling.
Speaker 0: I mean like that's pro dude I mean, he's mad Zen.
Speaker 0: That's his deal.
Speaker 0: Oh my god.
Speaker 1: These videos have like 20,000 views each.
Speaker 0: Well, you know you can be.
Speaker 0: you can you can transfer his energies to you and shit.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna do a red super and I'm gonna watch one of his videos and live stream myself watching it at some point After packs, can you sit and smile for two hours?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: You know what?
Speaker 0: I don't think you could even shut up for two hours unless you're sleeping.
Speaker 1: Why don't we do a smile off let alone like keeping your body still Got one to a live stream smile off.
Speaker 1: you and me both smile at the camera.
Speaker 1: first one to go away loses.
Speaker 0: Oh, you want a Zen Zen battle then off?
Speaker 1: I feel like I would bet money to the purposes of Zen.
Speaker 0: I would bet money's real pictures of presidents that are dead that I could beat you.
Speaker 0: Why don't we?
Speaker 1: Why don't we both bet on ourselves, but let me bet on me, but let the listener.
Speaker 1: Oh, I'm gonna bet on me But let the listeners bet.
Speaker 0: no, so it's basically you can't sleep.
Speaker 0: You have to stay awake.
Speaker 0: You can blink.
Speaker 1: I guess You can retain a calm smile.
Speaker 0: you cannot go you have to smile not move a lot.
Speaker 1: you can fidget.
Speaker 1: fidget.
Speaker 1: He's okay Scott.
Speaker 1: if we had to know it was not don't fidget off.
Speaker 0: I mean does he not fidget?
Speaker 0: I can't fidget.
Speaker 0: I mean I didn't watch a lot of these meditate without sleeping and smile.
Speaker 0: Oh shit These are four hours long not to know and see how long you can go and the first person to know It's live stream.
Speaker 0: So everyone's watching and they can tell who's the winner.
Speaker 1: now I'm just thinking that Simpsons episode.
Speaker 1: eat your broccoli.
Speaker 0: We can actually have the listeners like vote who they think the winner is like because they'll be like.
Speaker 0: rim moved it You know one hour in.
Speaker 0: and then if only like five people say that rim moved an hour in but everyone else votes for.
Speaker 0: Scott moved it, you know 45 minutes.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah, son.
Speaker 1: You're definitely eating this broccoli now.
Speaker 0: So my thing today once it gets a really good thing today, but it's not your thing of the day It's my thing of the day Phil's thing of the day, dude You're going by my thing I think of the days are farks or something.
Speaker 0: Awfuls or Better than rims.
Speaker 0: thing of the day.
Speaker 0: cuz rims thing of the day was nothing because it was Phil's thing of the day he used And mine is actually great.
Speaker 0: Nonetheless.
Speaker 1: This is real great as I'm scrolling through this.
Speaker 0: So if you go to Disney World, didn't he world?
Speaker 0: There's Epcot where the big dome ball thing is.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I fuck.
Speaker 1: I love Epcot way more than like every other part.
Speaker 0: It is an inside the ball thing.
Speaker 0: I'm pretty sure it's.
Speaker 0: inside the ball is the thing called horizons, which is basically a remake of Tomorrowland from the World's Fair which is basically a ride where you get on a little car and it goes around real slow and you look at stuff and the things you look at our little animatronic life-size dioramas of like futuristic kitchens and you know futuristic farms and sort of like.
Speaker 0: You know totally kitsch what they thought the future is gonna be like in the 60s kind of stuff.
Speaker 0: Right, and it's totally awesome.
Speaker 0: these people Way back in the 90s, which is probably around the time that I went there They figured out how to get into this ride Not just into the ride like you wait in line and you ride it cuz you know what.
Speaker 0: there's no line for this fucking thing.
Speaker 0: You could just yeah, you can just get on whenever you want.
Speaker 0: You could ride it like five times in a row.
Speaker 0: They figured out how to get behind the scenes.
Speaker 0: They figured out there were hidden rooms.
Speaker 0: There's like they were.
Speaker 0: they would know like when the cars are coming so they could go chill in the diorama and then be Out before the next car came.
Speaker 0: people these photos are so great.
Speaker 0: They knew how to not get killed because it's very easy to die when there's this sort of Carousel machine going around.
Speaker 0: it could easily crush you right like a subway.
Speaker 0: They learn how to not get killed.
Speaker 0: they were.
Speaker 0: they got partied back there.
Speaker 0: They got drunk back there They quote.
Speaker 1: of course that kind of confidence can only give it away to a higher risk of danger.
Speaker 1: one evening who'd haphazardly Stepped on a rotten piece of plywood and fractured his right foot.
Speaker 1: another night chief cut his head wide open.
Speaker 1: The danger they put themselves into was actually far higher than either of them realized at the time.
Speaker 0: It's very dangerous.
Speaker 0: It's like this big machine basically and you're going to easily have their arm or leg completely severed by the heavy machinery.
Speaker 0: Yes easily But I guess that didn't happen.
Speaker 1: they risked life and limb.
Speaker 1: to make sure horizons were you remembered and now it has been.
Speaker 0: so yeah, um The thing I wonder about this is how did they get into Disney World so often?
Speaker 0: were they buying tickets?
Speaker 0: They have like year-round passes or something like.
Speaker 1: maybe I guess season pass.
Speaker 1: I mean when I was a kid Cedar Point like they went to town.
Speaker 0: well I mean you get Disney World doesn't close so you can go there year-round.
Speaker 0: It's in Florida, but they it's like they worked in Florida somewhere and after work every day They went to Disney World with their annual pass.
Speaker 0: It's like how often did they go there?
Speaker 0: like what?
Speaker 0: What kind of life?
Speaker 1: an annual pass?
Speaker 1: I'm looking up right now For fuck.
Speaker 1: so wow it's way cheaper than I realized You got to live in Disney World.
Speaker 1: an annual pass to go to fucking anything anytime you want forever with no blackout dates Except for it doesn't get you into special event things that need like their own.
Speaker 0: Like you can't go to like a character breakfast with that shit.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you have to make a reservation for that separately, but you can just ride Space Mountain all day every day.
Speaker 0: $829 that's it.
Speaker 0: That's about right dude.
Speaker 1: a season pass to Cedar Point when I was a kid was like 200.
Speaker 0: Yeah, all right cool Cuz no one can fucking use that.
Speaker 1: in the moment We're gonna be live at PAX West which is coming up real soon soon Saturday September 3rd 5 p.m.. Chicken theater the grind.
Speaker 1: It's very funny that I tweeted about it And then literally the next tweet in my feed immediately was this article that was like now's the time to love to power Level up all your wow characters.
Speaker 1: It was like a Kotaku article.
Speaker 0: I think another wow expansion is coming.
Speaker 0: yeah I don't know why.
Speaker 0: and then independently
Speaker 1: because of that a whole bunch of people in my feed We're all tweeting about like enjoying grinding someone who I won't name in our forum and someone else I won't name on Twitter both today express their love of going like back into old content and MMOs and Grinding the shit out of it and someone else the third person was complaining that a lot of modern MMOs don't have as much grind as the old one, so I feel like our panel aptly timed.
Speaker 1: So you got anything?
Speaker 1: What other meta stuff do we got?
Speaker 1: The book club book is Rebecca.
Speaker 1: There is another book club book Orcs and Crake that we already did a show on.
Speaker 1: there is a third book club.
Speaker 1: It's a new book club.
Speaker 1: Scott's not involved because he hates this stuff, and he doesn't want to learn anything, but me Kremlian, Andrew, Ro, Kate, a few other people.
Speaker 1: We're starting a separate book club.
Speaker 1: That's basically an international politics Salon we're gonna do is we're gonna pick a nonfiction book every month or two or an article like a long-form article.
Speaker 1: We're all gonna read it, and then we're gonna argue about the topic that was discussed by the article.
Speaker 1: We're all gonna do our own independent research beyond because you know the article might be wrong the book might be biased whatever.
Speaker 1: But the point is we're going to learn about and research a very narrow and specific Like real-world topic and then argue about it on the show for an hour.
Speaker 1: And then I have a forum thread just like the book club.
Speaker 0: Don't waste your time with this kid.
Speaker 1: so the first book We're doing is a relatively recent history book by Richard Evans called the coming of the Third Reich.
Speaker 0: Yeah, just so you need to know about.
Speaker 1: but this one is not the typical History channel cries rise of the Nazi Party.
Speaker 1: This is more a history of the Weimar Republic and like the situation in the pan-german areas that led to all this.
Speaker 1: and I've read about two-thirds of it.
Speaker 1: and this is Fascinating because while I know a lot about the era before World War one, and I know a lot about like 1939 through 1945 I didn't know a lot about the Weimar Republic and this shit is Fascinating mm-hmm and this book is one of the few that is Popping off to where like I can read it without like having to do a lot of research.
Speaker 1: Also Scott who's complaining so much about everyone wasting their time and not bettering themselves.
Speaker 1: Why are you reading all this fiction?
Speaker 1: Why do you care about this Rebecca book?
Speaker 1: All right, all right anti intellectual Scott What else we got?
Speaker 1: our video Atari game design is up on YouTube for your enjoyment If you're a backer of the patreon, there is one more slot in the eight player play by mail Civ 5 Extreme game that I'm gonna be playing with you guys.
Speaker 0: No one's filling that slot.
Speaker 1: one spot remains.
Speaker 1: well, I just opened it up to the regular patrons like Yesterday and most of the people in the game are these super patrons give a dollar take the slot and then stop giving the dollar.
Speaker 0: Go join the game.
Speaker 0: the game will be locked in sure and then rim won't even get your $1.
Speaker 1: I'm totally happy for that cuz frankly a lot of people are giving away more money than they need to.
Speaker 1: to be honest I was kind of hoping that every listener would just give a dollar but instead there's like a few hundred of you Some of you are giving way more than a dollar Has lots of money.
Speaker 0: you probably don't what the fuck is wrong with you.
Speaker 1: that money has not been spent.
Speaker 1: all that money and Believe me you will know about every penny that I spend and that money is only gonna be yeah I'm gonna flaunt it in pictures of like selfies of me with expensive shit luxury brands.
Speaker 0: This is why I am.
Speaker 1: none of that money is going to Scott.
Speaker 0: if the money goes to see me in my bed It'll be because I bought equipment that Scott will use.
Speaker 1: and Scott has already tried to convince me to buy a like a camera for him yeah, and He could not convince me.
Speaker 1: that would be used for a geek night's patron or listener project photos of all the patrons everyone.
Speaker 1: actually That would be a cool project.
Speaker 0: if we traveled to All the pen and I'll write dumb dumb head on the photo and put it on the internet where everyone can see.
Speaker 1: if we use The money to over the course of a year like I've all the plays Live take like one good portrait of every one of them and then make a collection.
Speaker 1: that would actually be a cool thing.
Speaker 1: I'd be willing to spend the money on that.
Speaker 1: that would cost way more than the money.
Speaker 1: We've collected so far.
Speaker 0: Give more money.
Speaker 0: What's wrong?
Speaker 0: The reason it
Speaker 1: would cost so much is that a not small number of the patrons are Australians who really wants to come back to Paxos and I don't know if it's gonna happen this year because I have a work conference In Australia,
Speaker 0: we'll go to Monaco for the Grand Prix.
Speaker 0: That's halfway to Australia.
Speaker 1: I go to Singapore every year for f1.
Speaker 0: I'm not saying go to Monaco though.
Speaker 1: You want to come with me next year to Singapore and see f1?
Speaker 0: No, I got Monica.
Speaker 1: Singapore is way cheaper to get into f1 the Monaco.
Speaker 0: But why would I want to go to Singapore?
Speaker 1: Singapore is cool.
Speaker 1: We can spend like a week in Singapore doing the f1 shit.
Speaker 1: Monaco has a prince and then we can just go to Hong Kong and those principality.
Speaker 0: What's Singapore?
Speaker 0: a city-state?
Speaker 0: Yeah Yeah, it's got city states.
Speaker 1: give you all this happiness.
Speaker 1: you get luxury goods out of them.
Speaker 0: The Principality is a luxury good.
Speaker 1: Also, Scott is doing a YouTube show.
Speaker 0: I'm doing a lot of YouTube shows, but only one of them requires no effort.
Speaker 0: So if you go to my youtube channel, you'll get stuff that doesn't cost you any money.
Speaker 1: It's a pretty good show all the time.
Speaker 1: It's basically lunch with Scott.
Speaker 0: I watch it.
Speaker 0: Well, everything's gonna be with Scott because I started with netrunner with Scott.
Speaker 0: So it's gonna be asterisk with Scott.
Speaker 0: So everything else I do is also gonna be something with Scott.
Speaker 0: but lunch is almost every day.
Speaker 1: Well, you guys saw to remember we were doing rim versus Scott.
Speaker 1: That's the one where Scott and I were playing these duels of said five.
Speaker 1: It's not gonna just be said five.
Speaker 1: We're gonna do like everything.
Speaker 1: that's just us fighting with each other.
Speaker 0: You decided that I didn't.
Speaker 1: I did just decide that.
Speaker 1: Yeah Yeah, and I'm gonna try to keep doing it Resist doing it.
Speaker 1: All right, take that not a patreon thing.
Speaker 1: It's just on YouTube.
Speaker 0: Well, that's your video right there.
Speaker 0: rim for Scott gets Scott to do a video Scott wins.
Speaker 1: Do you want an argument?
Speaker 0: This is an argument.
Speaker 1: All right, so, uh, we got tickets to a thing.
Speaker 1: Well Scott saw this thing.
Speaker 1: we got tickets to it.
Speaker 1: But I'm gonna read you the title of what the thing is and that's the reason why we're not gonna do a main bit.
Speaker 1: We are going to right now the Queen's Dinner Club colon Mothership meat company, right?
Speaker 0: Well the There's a barbecue place.
Speaker 0: It's pretty good.
Speaker 0: That's near here and the guy who owns that opened up a new barbecue place that is an even bigger cooker.
Speaker 0: So he doesn't run out of food like he does the other place.
Speaker 0: But it's a different style of barbecue.
Speaker 0: It's Texas style, which I actually prefer and it's not open yet.
Speaker 0: But how are we eating there?
Speaker 0: Because if you buy tickets, there's like a preview night.
Speaker 0: I guess he wants to fit, you know, see if his foods any good and it's like four blocks away from this apartment.
Speaker 0: So we're gonna walk over there and eat barbecue all that cornbread and it's gonna have the same amazing cornbread from the other place.
Speaker 0: So all right, I just want to eat.
Speaker 0: I'll just get back dude.
Speaker 0: Keep your meats.
Speaker 0: I want three cornbreads.
Speaker 1: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening.
Speaker 1: music can't leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at front row crew comm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 1: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows It's actually recorded at night
Speaker 1: and the patreon patrons for the show at this episode in order of the amount of money that they give us on a continuing basis as long as that amount of money is at least five dollars are Alan Joyce Rebecca Dunn Nicholas Brando Logan Stafford Heidi McNichol Amanda Duchette James David white Christian coons construction noises.
Speaker 1: my stately.com.
Speaker 1: Sean Hayworth William Eisendrass Jeremy minor Chris Freimer and Thomas on.
Speaker 1: Oh Scott your beard tickles when we kiss Aaron Cerise Brian Fisher sailor Vista Sigourney Weaver's finest hour Iggy kid Matthew Smith Don Schleich jar Tovish and Joe Shiro Joe star Tyler Eller Sean Yeager Sam Cordray Clinton Walton run from New Zealand Ryan parent drew openlander rare Laval Brian says Roni Rochelle, Montanona Finn Eric Silverado the rural juror Chris midkiff Chris Knox Daniel Redman Sean Klein Chris Reimer and Thomas Han.
Speaker 1: and now I leave you since Patreon contents coming.
Speaker 1: I got nothing special to add here right now the typical stinger of the episode and I got something Not that weird and actually pretty relevant and probably too old of a reference for most of you.
Speaker 1: So glad you tuned in to dinner in a movie tonight because we're watching the creepy and rocks the cradles.
Speaker 1: That's right.
Speaker 1: This movie stars the sexy the devilish Rebecca de Mornay.
Speaker 1: It also stars Annabelle Shiora.
Speaker 0: Julianne Moore has a nice part in it.
Speaker 1: She's lovely even though she doesn't get naked.
Speaker 0: No, she doesn't.
Speaker 1: but you know, it does get naked.
Speaker 1: what our rock-a-bye baby back ribs.
Speaker 1: But then we're gonna cover them up with some delicious barbecue sauce.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, so watch a little movie.
Speaker 1: when we come back We'll show you what you need to make your.