Speaker 0: It's Wednesday November 30th 2016.
Speaker 0: I'm rim.
Speaker 1: I'm Scott and this is geek nights tonight.
Speaker 0: It's a trivia battle.
Speaker 1: It's gonna be bad.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: I went to the doctor today.
Speaker 1: Cut me.
Speaker 1: he cut me so bad.
Speaker 1: I wish you know cut me so bad.
Speaker 0: was this like an accident like you tripped with the scalpel Or did you get something cut off?
Speaker 0: No, so I had this cuz I got stabbed with a needle by a nurse who tripped once.
Speaker 1: whoa smell practice anyway.
Speaker 1: No, so my in my family the Rubens we get I guess these things called I don't know if it's lumb poma or limb poma.
Speaker 0: Basically, I don't think it's lymphoma not lymphoma.
Speaker 1: It's a poma.
Speaker 1: know the lipoma I know what those are something like if I don't know how exactly it's pronounced.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like lipoma lipoma.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's what it is.
Speaker 1: Li poma, I guess.
Speaker 0: anyway, so basically the poma dangerous.
Speaker 1: No, it's not really annoying It's not dangerous anyway.
Speaker 1: Normally when you get fat on you the fat spreads out and like a layer, right?
Speaker 1: but sometimes you get a blob of fat in one spot and it's like you got a blob in your body and it's just Annoying and it can grow.
Speaker 1: and like my remember my grandpa had one on the back of his neck.
Speaker 1: That was like enormous Right.
Speaker 1: It was like it looked like a like a big fat snake around half of his neck in the bag Yeah, and he couldn't lean his head backwards or anything.
Speaker 0: So I understand people who don't have access to health care but I've known a lot of people in my life who have Excellent access to health care who have things like this and just never get them dealt with.
Speaker 1: dude There are like I'll be watching.
Speaker 1: I forget who it was but like I was watching a immense game and one of the players had this huge mole type thing like near his ear like a big Like really crazy kind of thing that could easily almost definitely be removed Doctor.
Speaker 1: so maybe it couldn't be but it looked like it could be and he's a baseball player Which means it minimum he's making hundreds of K's a year.
Speaker 0: Hey, that might be a load-bearing mole probably millions, right?
Speaker 1: So it's like he could have had any.
Speaker 1: you know There's no reason for someone who's like a wealthy professional athlete to like, you know not remove.
Speaker 1: So I could understand like maybe you have a scar from getting hit with a hockey puck in the face and you don't want to Get plastic surgery like fix it up.
Speaker 1: But if you've got like really, you know.
Speaker 1: or like if you've lost some teeth and you don't want fake ones All right, you know, but like if your teeth are all janky, it's like you can afford orthodontia.
Speaker 0: Well when you're an adult, that's a lot more invasive.
Speaker 1: I'm just saying but like if you got something growing on you You could get it removed.
Speaker 1: Yep, and it's not hard.
Speaker 1: So it's like You know, I can't look at any guts or anything cuz I'll get nauseous.
Speaker 1: So I haven't looked at it.
Speaker 1: It's under this bandage.
Speaker 1: There's some stitches.
Speaker 0: I guess I'll look at it.
Speaker 1: I can't.
Speaker 1: I can take it off tomorrow shower or whatever.
Speaker 1: I should be.
Speaker 1: I hope I should be able to look at it by Tomorrow morning.
Speaker 0: I'm just shockingly on the squeamish when it comes to that kind of stuff.
Speaker 1: I'm not like.
Speaker 1: I'm just sitting there and I'm not looking and dude just cutting my arm open And yeah I can feel like my skin being tugged and I can feel him try to squeeze it out.
Speaker 1: And I looked at it once.
Speaker 1: it was in this little plastic jar.
Speaker 1: That wasn't a problem because it was just like a little blob of fat.
Speaker 1: It looked like someone cut it off a steak You know and but not a problem I just can't look at like a hole in my arm cuz.
Speaker 0: then I'll be like, whoa I mean I was literally in the woods like with a bicycle spoke through my leg and I was just laying there like well, fuck me.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if I saw that pull that out like bike home, there was no pain whatsoever No, and in fact, he also liquid nitrogen.
Speaker 1: this war on my finger.
Speaker 1: So I was trying to remove how you got the twofer Right.
Speaker 1: Yeah That's why I did it too for it.
Speaker 1: Right because I didn't.
Speaker 1: I wanted.
Speaker 1: I was going in for the wart primarily because I've been trying to.
Speaker 1: I tried to remove the war Three different ways you go.
Speaker 1: said the duct tape method was gonna work and I don't disbelieve her because I guess she removed one with duct Tape.
Speaker 0: I have removed them with duct tape in the past - it didn't work for me the duct tape.
Speaker 1: I also before I tried the duct tape I was trying compound W from the drugstore.
Speaker 1: that didn't work either.
Speaker 1: so this time I went for the liquid nitrogen method from the doctor and That hurt way more than getting.
Speaker 0: Yeah No as a kid, I got a planter's ward and one of my feet like in the middle of it on the bottom and It took two years to get rid of that motherfucker.
Speaker 0: I went back like the first.
Speaker 0: they did the like the norm the UV burn then the UV burn again.
Speaker 1: It's gonna work.
Speaker 0: and then they cut it out and it grew back again.
Speaker 0: and then the liquid nitrogen did and took like a Centimeter chunk out of my foot and I have a scar and a hole and pain to this day.
Speaker 1: I'm pretty sure that the liquid nitrogen in the finger is just gonna permanently work here.
Speaker 1: But it's like he sprayed it on there for like 15 seconds Right and it stung while he was doing it and now it's kind of sore.
Speaker 1: and he says what's gonna happen is eventually just keep band-aiding it and Eventually, it's gonna just fall off on its own and underneath will just be skin and it'll be totally cool Yeah, and they'll be like a scab or whatever.
Speaker 1: Just you know, just keep band-aiding it and ignoring it until it falls off.
Speaker 1: So I'm like, okay, that's what I'll do But I gotta go back and get the stitches removed from the armhole on the other side.
Speaker 0: There I have an annoying vein in my body that could be remain.
Speaker 0: yeah, it's like internal But why would you remove a vein?
Speaker 1: because it's something I'd.
Speaker 0: it's an annoying vein.
Speaker 0: that does nothing.
Speaker 1: What's I found out about?
Speaker 1: is it a hemorrhoid?
Speaker 0: No, it's not.
Speaker 1: I am right is a vein.
Speaker 0: Maybe I'll tell the story in a separate time, but I have a vein in a place.
Speaker 0: That is annoying.
Speaker 0: Doctor was like that junk, baby.
Speaker 1: And he was it's it's it on the sack.
Speaker 1: You gotta get a sack.
Speaker 1: It's in there.
Speaker 0: It's in the left sack.
Speaker 0: It's like a bunch of extra vein in there.
Speaker 0: Uh-huh, and the doctor was like I went when I was a kid.
Speaker 0: I was like is this fun?
Speaker 0: is this cancer?
Speaker 0: and I go to the doctor and he's like no it actually isn't it's.
Speaker 1: I mean, I got a vein on my sack and my junk and it pumps blood to fill up my junk.
Speaker 0: This is like an extra vein and they were like you can get it cut out But it involves not surgery.
Speaker 0: and I was like, yeah, I'll let it be.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: This is just on my forearm.
Speaker 1: It was.
Speaker 1: It was not like a giant.
Speaker 1: if there's a lump of fat on my nuts that should have been removed when it was tiny.
Speaker 1: No, it was like.
Speaker 1: I mean, it was still tiny but I just want.
Speaker 1: you know It got a little tiny bit bigger since like last year.
Speaker 1: I've had it for years and I'm like Let's remove this before the grandpa sighs.
Speaker 0: Well, I got on my left wrist - I got a Gideon's lump and that thing comes and goes.
Speaker 0: it's actually kind of big now compared to normal and Surgery seems to be ineffective.
Speaker 0: So I decided to never bother.
Speaker 1: It's a book thing.
Speaker 1: Yeah, let me hit it with the book.
Speaker 0: No, I smashed it once and I made it go away for like four years, but then it came back.
Speaker 1: I'll smash it.
Speaker 1: It'll be I'll smash it hard enough for eight years.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: No, I don't want to break my wrist.
Speaker 0: I'll put up with the Gideon's lump instead of the risk of breaking my wrist.
Speaker 1: I'm really precise.
Speaker 1: It's smashing.
Speaker 1: So anyway, he's my ball peen hammer.
Speaker 1: So super precise.
Speaker 0: I am always Oddly afraid of any use of a ball peen hammer.
Speaker 1: I'll use my regular hammer Precise.
Speaker 0: you remember what a ball peen hammer is for cuz we leave it up.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you remember a peening is I guess Shaping metal somehow.
Speaker 1: that's all in vaguely.
Speaker 1: Yeah Yeah, so the biggest news this is actually pretty big news Even though it only affects a subset of this is big enough that my co-workers brought it up Right like rim message it to me and then I saw it was in my slack at work.
Speaker 1: I'm like well like this.
Speaker 0: cut through cuz if you're in the stage like, you know that even like Pure normal like joyous like Sonic the Hedgehog of OC fanfiction knockoff parody account Will remind you that shits bad politically in the u.s.
Speaker 0: Like you can't get away from it.
Speaker 0: Like that is like the undercurrent of everything.
Speaker 0: and yet this cut through all of that and filled my feet.
Speaker 0: See
Speaker 1: that kind of makes me happy because usually that's the kind of thing that I really pay attention to are like Really specific features that have been added to or removed from software that is I use or is used You know by many yep, and that's like important news because even though
Speaker 0: in tabs appeared in web browser
Speaker 1: Right, like some small feature added to a software, especially if it's a frequently used popular software It could actually be like completely changing the everyday lives of the people who use that software
Speaker 0: or more importantly They're a bellwether of a huge iceberg of change that you don't know about
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 0: It's like it's a feature that everyone wanted but couldn't happen because of some complicated reason.
Speaker 1: These features that when they're released seem just sort of like like people might make fun of them or scoff or who just ignore them And up can change the world even like when cameras are in phones.
Speaker 1: room was like man.
Speaker 1: But meanwhile cameras and phones has changed the whole world.
Speaker 0: I was not mad on the concept.
Speaker 0: I was mad about the fact that in that era any phone that had a camera in it Ram was like.
Speaker 1: I don't need that.
Speaker 1: any browser with tabs is stupid.
Speaker 1: I was open to more windows.
Speaker 0: I went to tabs right away.
Speaker 0: I know you didn't but in that era Cameras and phones were Garbage.
Speaker 1: you get like nothing.
Speaker 1: you'd know Many a video.
Speaker 1: that is garbage quality because the content outweighed the fact that the quality was garbage.
Speaker 0: But it wasn't just that.
Speaker 0: in that era most phones unless you bought an expensive Weird dongle or did a bunch of hacking you could not get the pictures off your phone without paying money.
Speaker 1: My foot I got the dongle on my phone.
Speaker 0: Yeah, my dog with a dongle for my phone was $70 and it was not worth it.
Speaker 1: I think I bought it for like five bucks My phone.
Speaker 0: it was $70 and there was a hack way you could do it and I tried the hack way And it did not work, and then I gave up.
Speaker 0: hmm, but anyway.
Speaker 0: This is one of those features.
Speaker 0: This is it's a big deal.
Speaker 0: that is a big deal, and we don't even know the details of it yet.
Speaker 1: We don't need to know details.
Speaker 1: Netflix
Speaker 0: announced kind of out of nowhere that they're gonna have basically airplane mode
Speaker 1: right so that means Instead of having to be connected to the internet while you're watching your Netflix you can while you're home Download an episode or season or whatever of some amount of Netflix content And then watch it when you don't have an internet connection like if you're somewhere where there can't be internet like the middle of the woods Or in the subway.
Speaker 1: or you know it's basically the same thing that Spotify just sort of does automatically only Netflix.
Speaker 0: now first Here's a big deal for the UX like you don't understand like you unless you really think about it the wide range of Applications for this that will really make things good for people.
Speaker 0: for one people with metered bandwidth you can pre-download a bunch of shit when the bandwidth is cheaper if you're in one of those places or You download a bunch of shit at the end of the month and then watch it the next month
Speaker 1: right people using their wireless data Right.
Speaker 1: right now Verizon and whatnot is charging them a fortune because they're watching videos like in the car using LTE.
Speaker 1: Instead right now they can be at home with their free or much cheaper Wi-Fi use that data And then when they're in the car basically you know this is gonna cost Verizon AT&T T-Mobile Sprint a lot of money.
Speaker 1: People actually use this feature enough and wisely.
Speaker 1: They're gonna be selling a lot less data's and making less money's.
Speaker 0: or even if say your internet is Unreliable or slow so that streaming is low-quality like even like here with my.
Speaker 1: You can't get HD's because you have crappy internet, and you live in the woods.
Speaker 1: well now when you go to bed You can just say hey Netflix download this and the next day is done And then you can watch it in full HD's even though you have a shitty internet with like satellite internet or some garbage.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like in my life right now a big part of why I don't watch a lot of anime in particular Is that what I would like to do?
Speaker 0: because I have like a half-hour commute each way.
Speaker 0: It's just watch it on my commute cuz I got nothing else to do.
Speaker 0: like it's read watch something listen to something sleep.
Speaker 0: I'm not gonna do nothing.
Speaker 1: I used to watch like whole seasons of anime on the train.
Speaker 0: That was a laptop, and I'd even sometimes that was mine.
Speaker 1: I was my iPhone 3g.
Speaker 1: what I would do is I'd rip DVDs or download stuff convert it with handbrake And then put it on to the storage of the iPhone and watch it in the default iPhone video player.
Speaker 0: But the crunchyroll doesn't have this and it's not like I want to download stuff to keep forever or like pirate or whatever.
Speaker 0: I literally just want to watch the like one punch man on my way to work instead of having to be at home or Above-ground to watch it like let me time shift for an hour, and I'm good yep.
Speaker 0: So on the back end what makes this really important is that the only reason this feature did not exist Everywhere immediately in the streaming world is because of licensing.
Speaker 0: the people who made content were by and large Adamant against any possibility of downloading anything ever mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: That's why YouTube does not have a download button even though people who work at Google have in many times Told me these specific downloader services to use yep, because they know yeah There's there are YouTube extensions for Chrome like that.
Speaker 1: let you download YouTube videos And they're not officially approved by Google or either not Google made.
Speaker 0: But but the winks is good as a nod to a blind bag.
Speaker 1: You can totally trust the good ones.
Speaker 0: so Netflix has rolling this out for their own content, and it'll be very interesting to see what other Content that is licensed from other people gets.
Speaker 0: this treatment versus doesn't right because you'll be able to infer a lot about the state Of the licensing industry by seeing what gets that little download widget And what doesn't right.
Speaker 1: and YouTube actually if you pay for YouTube red you can do this Onto.
Speaker 1: you're like I. if your iPad or your iPhone or whatever you just can't do it to a computer It's like in my I I pay for YouTube red.
Speaker 1: so in my YouTube official app on my iPad I could download something and keep it in there to watch it in the subway, but YouTube doesn't have like entire series of things I want to watch.
Speaker 1: it's not how I use YouTube so it's not a feature I end up using.
Speaker 1: unless like there's a rare case I'll use it which is if I start watching something long in the morning, and I see something when I wake up That's kind of long, and I don't want to watch it right away.
Speaker 1: No, you know and I think if I'm I usually just add it to watch later.
Speaker 1: But if I plan to watch it later on the train I'll also push the download button.
Speaker 0: But it also serves a sort of quasi area between like.
Speaker 0: I don't really care that much about owning media anymore.
Speaker 0: like I'm fine with Ephemeral nature of the streaming world.
Speaker 1: I don't want to own any physical objects I don't and I don't care about the.
Speaker 1: you know semantic.
Speaker 1: You know like Ideological difference between owning a license to what you know.
Speaker 0: there is a practical difference though as I think someone pointed out.
Speaker 0: I saw much of screenshots.
Speaker 0: It's actually really hard to legally watch the old Evangelion again.
Speaker 1: I got it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I have DVDs that I ripped.
Speaker 1: yeah who don't got it?
Speaker 0: anyone who didn't buy the DVDs when it was out?
Speaker 1: I'm sure you can just buy DVDs.
Speaker 0: No out of print hard to get expensive.
Speaker 1: You can just buy DVDs on eBay.
Speaker 1: I'm sure this bootleg ones, but that are exact rips of the real ones.
Speaker 0: Let's see that's three dot 33. you cannot redo.
Speaker 1: They're working on the final one for 44 whatever.
Speaker 0: so once four Dot four dot four dot four four four final rebirth.
Speaker 1: There's volume one.
Speaker 1: Oh, there's a box set.
Speaker 0: Here's the old pre remastered box.
Speaker 0: That's a perfect collection.
Speaker 1: What's not perfect about that.
Speaker 0: That's not the platinum edition.
Speaker 0: It says perfect.
Speaker 0: That's the old box.
Speaker 1: then I Mean you can get it if you want to easily.
Speaker 1: Oh, there's a platinum one.
Speaker 0: Yeah, one hundred and seventy two dollars.
Speaker 0: Well.
Speaker 1: I mean that's what someone's trying to charge for it.
Speaker 0: You can 14 offers 172 hundred and it's all in the hundred and seventy.
Speaker 1: you should sell yours because it's already been ripped.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think I threw away the case though.
Speaker 0: I just have the DVDs.
Speaker 1: sell it for 150 Yeah, or a hundred.
Speaker 0: I feel like worthless plastic Like a human being who would buy a season of anime for $200 or even $100 on Amazon.
Speaker 1: doesn't exist Which is why they're all still for sale and not sold.
Speaker 0: is the kind of person who?
Speaker 0: Needs the collector aspect of it as opposed to just watching it?
Speaker 1: Listen anytime.
Speaker 1: I want to watch Evangelion.
Speaker 1: I'm confident that it will be available for me to watch in the form I desire to see it It's not.
Speaker 0: there are things that are hard to get and watch though They're slightly rare and I just kind of collect those and I even have the video file for stupid.
Speaker 1: nothing lasts forever.
Speaker 1: So if I can get that from that Australian TV rip, I know anything.
Speaker 0: So pay attention to this.
Speaker 0: the fact that this happened is Kind of a big deal and you're gonna see a lot of real life either.
Speaker 0: you're going to see Doesn't have this.
Speaker 1: I wish they did.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm probably gonna because of this feature.
Speaker 1: I'm probably gonna.
Speaker 1: you know one South Park season is done.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna end my Hulu and get a Netflix for a while.
Speaker 0: Oh more importantly I want crunchyroll to do this because anime is like my go-to Watch long series that I like.
Speaker 1: it would be real convenient cuz one anime episode is like one subway ride.
Speaker 0: Yeah I could basically watch two to three episodes of some rando show a day every day.
Speaker 0: And the only reason I don't do that now is that as soon as I get home like oh now I'm home now I can watch anime.
Speaker 0: I got overwatch to play mmm, and I got geek nights to record I guess
Speaker 1: Mmm, so actually Something I've noticed a lot lately is there's you know You know There's certain things that like come up and it's like wow people have been talking that about that a lot lately.
Speaker 1: or man people have Been using that new word a lot lately, right?
Speaker 1: The thing I've that's lately has come up more often is like theme parks for some reason.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, cuz the other night we were all talking about like Thanksgiving.
Speaker 1: we're talking about Universal and Disney cuz like they were watching on ABC like the Disney Thanksgiving Whatever thing at the right.
Speaker 1: and then yeah, you know, my sister lives in LA So she has like a season pass to Universal cuz it'll close to her house.
Speaker 0: for a couple months I've been rumbling with Emily and Jason some other people that next summer.
Speaker 0: We're going to fucking cedar point.
Speaker 0: Clock is ring.
Speaker 1: I'm just saying so there's a news that happened that makes me want to hold off going to any of those places because Nintendo has made a deal to make Nintendo theme park shit at the universals.
Speaker 1: So I'm gonna wait until that shit is done and then I'm going and going hard.
Speaker 0: Yeah, because I'm gonna ride the Mario ride.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna be all up in that curvy ride Where I turn into a ball.
Speaker 1: if this Of that Harry Potter stuff that shit will be lit and it's like man It's like yeah that hurt Harry Potter.
Speaker 1: shit is like they go so deep, right?
Speaker 1: You can buy.
Speaker 1: they have like multiple flavors of like butter beers and I don't read any Harry Potter's but I know what that is Right and you could drink that shit there and I probably won't like it cuz I don't drink
Speaker 0: that I mean granted It's interesting because like the Harry Potter land is super.
Speaker 1: That's what I'm saying.
Speaker 1: If that's what they got at the Harry Potter land, right?
Speaker 1: What's the Nintendo land gonna have?
Speaker 1: like every different Yoshi's cookie to eat right?
Speaker 0: It's like oh, man Yoshi's cookies kind of bad though.
Speaker 1: Listen, if they cookies at the theme park will taste good.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and also Yoshi's cookie is good and you're a bad person.
Speaker 1: What I mean?
Speaker 1: and can you imagine the Pokemons that are gonna be in there?
Speaker 0: Pokemon land will be its own thing.
Speaker 1: I mean, it's like There's so much Nintendo shit.
Speaker 1: You could make the greatest theme park ever Like you could just make a whole theme park Nintendo only.
Speaker 0: well like already, right?
Speaker 0: So the Harry Potter thing like you buy one of their stupid wands.
Speaker 0: then all over Harry Potter land You can do certain motions and cast spells like make it happen and I mean like, you know, the link dragon themed roller coaster.
Speaker 0: You buy the special you buy the master ball and then you can do AR games and fight trainers like in the fall man.
Speaker 1: You go down the pipes and you come out and like it's a slide Takes you to underground Mushroom Kingdom.
Speaker 1: Yep, and you go down there and there's music playing like doo-doo-doo-doo-doo-doo Really?
Speaker 0: The only problem the only rule is you have to eat a bunch of food before you go into that park and do not eat Until you leave.
Speaker 0: that is like the only problem.
Speaker 1: I want to eat the delicious Nintendo food like magic mushrooms.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah eat the snacks, but don't eat real food, but the sandwich.
Speaker 0: Things of the day.
Speaker 0: I found this a while ago and I just thought it's really cute and funny.
Speaker 1: And this is a good thing of the day because it's simultaneously internet II like the shit rim likes.
Speaker 1: that sucks But not so internet II like a homestuck that a normal person or a normal nerdy person At least is gonna be like.
Speaker 1: what the fuck is this crazy nonsense for 12 year old?
Speaker 0: So I am glad you brought this up Scott because I just on the patreon Remastered an old beta episode of geek nights.
Speaker 0: All right, and we started doing our things of the day.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm I my thing of the day.
Speaker 0: you were like, oh, this is amazing.
Speaker 0: Like you're really into my thing of the day.
Speaker 1: What was your thing today?
Speaker 0: Well, that's that's not relevant right now.
Speaker 0: It was the holographic augmented reality gorillas concert.
Speaker 0: Not bad your thing of the day Mm-hmm was the most horrific internet shit.
Speaker 0: It was so painful.
Speaker 0: And you so you in this episode.
Speaker 0: I play some of it in the episode because we want like.
Speaker 0: we listen to it and watch It and I am the whole time being like Scott.
Speaker 0: Oh my god.
Speaker 0: This is painful.
Speaker 0: Oh, how could you and meanwhile you're like shut up.
Speaker 1: This is awesome.
Speaker 1: What is it?
Speaker 0: It is the all your base Mm-hmm, like that story Sung filk style to the tune of Bohemian Rhapsody.
Speaker 1: Oh, that's good.
Speaker 0: It is So bad and painful I could have internet.
Speaker 1: It's not as bad as your time.
Speaker 0: We will not know.
Speaker 0: make your time.
Speaker 1: It's not potato conditions.
Speaker 1: If I may at least it makes sense.
Speaker 0: if I had used this without telling you that this was your thing of the day from 2005 as my thing of the day today You would probably have said it's terrible internet shit garbage.
Speaker 1: It's not as terrible as potato conditions.
Speaker 1: It's not just nonsense, I mean it might be poor.
Speaker 1: I haven't listened to it right.
Speaker 1: I could I concede it may be poorly sung Cringe-worthy filkness, right?
Speaker 1: It's filky and in that sense it is bad, but conceptually, right?
Speaker 1: It's not just in unintelligible nonsense or an internet shouty guy or a 12 year old garbage, right?
Speaker 1: It's actually the.
Speaker 1: conceptually it's you know a remix which is just fine.
Speaker 0: Just saying that's my bar.
Speaker 0: now.
Speaker 0: that thing of the day from 2005, you know also, you know 11 year ago Scott was what 20.
Speaker 1: what for?
Speaker 1: right 24 and 25 year olds like bad days.
Speaker 1: You can't trust them.
Speaker 0: So anyway my thing of the day today, this is just a cute series of shorts.
Speaker 0: It is the fantastic adventures of Bellsprout.
Speaker 1: go bells as Pokemon season.
Speaker 1: Yeah Pokemon in the house go Bellsprout.
Speaker 1: So yeah, you're not the worst Pokemon.
Speaker 0: No, I like Bellsprout.
Speaker 0: He's okay.
Speaker 0: I was perhaps like what are the key?
Speaker 1: I wouldn't put him in my party, but I wouldn't hate on him, but he turns into ugly Pokemon.
Speaker 1: But not it's like.
Speaker 0: no you never upgrade those guys.
Speaker 0: I like my time Bellsprout Oddish.
Speaker 1: Oddish starts out cuter than Bellsprout but gets uglier.
Speaker 1: Yeah, Bellsprout starts out just fine but gets not as ugly as Oddish gets but still ugly that you wouldn't want it.
Speaker 0: I want my team to be all cute little guys.
Speaker 0: So Bellsprout Stupid game.
Speaker 1: I'm walking around and you know this Pokemon that people just have standing next to them.
Speaker 1: But they're just like you talk to those Pokemon and they go squirt or whatever you want.
Speaker 0: those Pokemon There's.
Speaker 1: no there's all.
Speaker 1: they got fucking core solas everywhere and I'm like, man, I need a rods I can catch me a core Sola, that's like the ultimate cute Pokemon.
Speaker 1: It's a little pink coral guy.
Speaker 1: He's like the cutest.
Speaker 1: Anyway, anyway, nothing beats combi and I don't even have a water.
Speaker 1: Pokemon combi is way cute Thing of the day, right?
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: What the hell was my thing of the day?
Speaker 0: All right, it was a test.
Speaker 1: It is a test.
Speaker 1: This is a good test.
Speaker 1: I'm a little short on things of the day lately because the people are so upset on the internet They're not producing good stuff.
Speaker 1: So get back to work internet.
Speaker 0: But all right, this is the one with the cute Guma girl.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so There's many many paper Mario games And Mario RPG type games and the best of all of them if you don't know is thousand year door for the game of cube.
Speaker 1: People make fun of that game cube, but I had like this thing ridiculously incredible game for it.
Speaker 1: This was like a normal old RPG that kept my attention like in the college days.
Speaker 1: I played it like crazy Until I beat it and then even played it some more cuz it's just so damn good.
Speaker 1: now I'm actually thinking about playing it again, especially because every sequel has been not as good.
Speaker 1: It's just it's like it's just.
Speaker 1: there are other good Ones right the Mario and Luigi games for the you know, GBA DS many of which are excellent or you know varying in quality But many of which are excellent, especially the first one, right?
Speaker 1: But this is the best of all the best Mario themed RPG type video games and here's a task of it.
Speaker 0: and tool assisted.
Speaker 1: right tool assisted.
Speaker 1: in what time?
Speaker 0: To 2930 let's.
Speaker 1: that's less than three hours for a game that probably took me Weeks playing every day because it was so good.
Speaker 1: I played it every day.
Speaker 0: So quote from the video It's actually faster to say no because it skips an animation of Mario nodding his head Jesus XD.
Speaker 0: I love speedruns.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: But yeah If you want to see this game without putting in all those hours You can watch this test.
Speaker 1: or my recommendation is play the game because it's so incredible Beat it and then come back and watch this.
Speaker 0: I've never seen anyone cosplay as that cute Goomba girl.
Speaker 1: go for it ever.
Speaker 1: That's like one of the best side characters that might be the best side character.
Speaker 1: It's actually some of the best things about all of the Mario RPG type games is that they're not afraid in those games to bring in a whole bunch of characters and make new characters.
Speaker 1: I know like Koopas and Goombas that are like individualized and you know Like that's specific really bad about killing all those generic ones right like a specific new toad guy.
Speaker 0: Does she know that Mario has killed probably millions of her brothers and sisters, right?
Speaker 1: But it's like they just make up tons and tons of characters for these things and a lot of those characters are really cool And cute and never get used again in any game ever.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: I mean Super Mario RPG kind of like kick that off Yeah, so I can play that again, maybe plenty of materials.
Speaker 0: So in the meta moment book the book is Rebecca.
Speaker 1: I finished playing doom.
Speaker 1: So now I can read Rebecca.
Speaker 0: I'm almost done with the third Oryx and Craig book.
Speaker 0: It all came together.
Speaker 0: Everybody fucking knew Jimmy like.
Speaker 0: That seems to be what the story is like.
Speaker 0: everybody knew him.
Speaker 0: I was like, oh, yeah that guy what's his deal?
Speaker 1: What is it?
Speaker 1: Oh, he's got to tell them all the truth.
Speaker 1: They don't know.
Speaker 0: they all actually do know it's interesting.
Speaker 0: Yes, it's it's.
Speaker 0: it does not go the way I expected it all to go.
Speaker 1: It's actually interesting makes you want to read it.
Speaker 0: then Yeah, like what?
Speaker 1: so the best second and third books just as short as the first one.
Speaker 0: They're a little longer, but I'll say this so they keep telling the crackers stories like Jimmy did And you know the crackers like that.
Speaker 0: if they say oh Jimmy like they say oh when they're talking about a person like Oh Toby Oh you yep.
Speaker 0: So at one point a character says oh fuck.
Speaker 0: and then they like get obsessed with who fuck is and they want to meet fuck.
Speaker 0: And then people start having tell stories about who fuck is.
Speaker 0: so they won't keep bothering them.
Speaker 0: and fuck is now part of the mythology Trickster spirit who helps people out and you summon him by saying oh fuck.
Speaker 0: because if someone says oh fuck it means that they need Some help and fuck will come and save the day.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's gonna be a check-offs fuck.
Speaker 0: I think it might be If you subscribe to the guys.
Speaker 0: patreon one of the things is in.
Speaker 0: there is the remastered beta episodes of geek nights from before October 31st 2005.
Speaker 1: that's a good reason not to pay for that patreon.
Speaker 1: No one's listening that shit.
Speaker 1: There's a reason.
Speaker 1: there's a reason it was hidden from the world.
Speaker 1: Yeah, don't dig too deep.
Speaker 1: We learned that lesson.
Speaker 1: How come people never learn lessons except guys?
Speaker 1: I'm the only person who learns lessons and actually abides by what we learned.
Speaker 1: This is where everyone else learns a lesson and this is and forget what we learned.
Speaker 0: you guys listen to Daryl Surratt.
Speaker 0: How many times do you tell you not to watch an anime because it's bad and then one of you decides to watch it?
Speaker 0: Cuz you'll have like oh watch the bad anime and then you realize that there's a reason.
Speaker 1: he told you not to watch the person Who says okay and doesn't watch it.
Speaker 1: cuz I'm the smart person.
Speaker 1: You don't be like me the smart person and not like rim the dumb person.
Speaker 0: But You will get to hear Scott defending that old thing of the day.
Speaker 0: He's really invested in it.
Speaker 0: He's also really invested in Alan Greenspan and Elliot Spitzer.
Speaker 1: Elliot Spitzer.
Speaker 1: he was so good before he was so bad.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and Fitzgerald you talk a lot about him, too.
Speaker 1: I forget who that is.
Speaker 0: I know you knew a lot back then.
Speaker 1: I was paying attention But I knew I didn't realize it was a waste of time to pay attention.
Speaker 0: Also, we talked a lot about how someday they'll be murdered by drone.
Speaker 1: That hasn't changed.
Speaker 1: yeah Talk about that recently as well.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I've also talked about committing murder by drone, but only jokingly.
Speaker 0: It was quite a bit more theoretical maybe not so jokingly in early October 2005.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean you know murder by drones a real deal.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it happens Otherwise.
Speaker 0: we're going to be at Pac South where you're going to be at mag fest.
Speaker 1: Magfest is way soon.
Speaker 1: Yeah, also my magfest friend who volunteers at magfest swore to me there was a rampart there last year and the year before.
Speaker 1: How did we not see it there?
Speaker 1: I think he's lying.
Speaker 0: He has to be lying.
Speaker 1: I'm like there's no way that none of us would have seen it if it was there.
Speaker 1: He's like.
Speaker 1: no I swear I played it there, and I'm like I don't know because you realize if there's a rampart machine We're just gonna hog it and ignore all arcade etiquette.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know the Azans who play the initially machine and don't let us play.
Speaker 0: We're gonna be bad for rampart.
Speaker 1: Yeah, no one's playing rampart, but us.
Speaker 0: unless you're coming into our rampart tournament It'll be you me and randos you keep getting kicked out of the game.
Speaker 1: Scott Johnson and chase could take turns.
Speaker 1: Yeah, Alex or Pete can get in a game.
Speaker 1: Maybe yeah, that's it well after.
Speaker 1: well I don't know.
Speaker 1: be there he can play.
Speaker 0: well man.
Speaker 0: We'll have to do some serious like friend-only ladder tournaments.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I guess other people feel che we could teach them to play rampart.
Speaker 1: I don't think they played.
Speaker 0: yeah.
Speaker 0: Also, it doesn't count unless it's got the eight balls in there.
Speaker 0: Yep, it's got to be the full-on Experience three-track ball.
Speaker 1: good to joystick garbage.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but might as well not even have the machine there.
Speaker 0: Yeah, just just leave some poop in the car.
Speaker 1: That is what might as well.
Speaker 1: Just be like a mr.
Speaker 1: Do machine if you're gonna bring me that stick ramp.
Speaker 0: Man.
Speaker 0: magfest.
Speaker 0: I'm really excited about this like I remember remembering what magfest is like as it gets closer.
Speaker 1: It's like oh, I hear the distance Again louder.
Speaker 0: So we'll have shows in the future.
Speaker 0: but we're in the situation yet again where Scott and I have independently consumed a lot of different Wednesday media and There has been no overlap at all.
Speaker 1: Well, so you just you can you consumed Wednesday media and used it all on your stupid patreon.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that is true I consumed Wednesday media that you just haven't consumed.
Speaker 1: like I want to see miss Hokusai when you're in Australia.
Speaker 0: I've done a patreon episode about miss Hokusai.
Speaker 1: No Do anything.
Speaker 1: and then you know, I read a bunch of comics that you didn't read.
Speaker 0: I just watched Doctor Strange last night But that's not an anime.
Speaker 0: It's a comic.
Speaker 1: It's a movie.
Speaker 0: arguably It is a movie that is more animated than live-action.
Speaker 1: I mean do you I mean if you want to do something like that?
Speaker 1: We could talk about like, you know spider-man his amazing friends.
Speaker 0: All right, so Emily had an idea and we expanded upon it.
Speaker 0: I don't know if this will work, but I'm kind of feeling it partly because I just I just think we're lacking material is the problem.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think now if we had the questions pre-prepared This could totally be awesome.
Speaker 0: So this is more like the pilot.
Speaker 0: This is a lot like those early beta episodes of geek nights because we would we tried all these like bullshit concepts.
Speaker 0: We had this idea in early geek nights.
Speaker 0: It was actually Scott's idea and we did it for a while.
Speaker 0: It was real bad.
Speaker 0: then we agreed it was bad and stopped it.
Speaker 0: But we did a sig at the end of every episode like a catchphrase Like wubba lubba dub dub, I don't remember this.
Speaker 0: It was your idea to had to sign each podcast like it was a post in a bulletin board.
Speaker 0: Okay, now people had their cigs.
Speaker 0: No, you don't remember that like an email signature But before I do.
Speaker 1: but I don't remember this idea for the.
Speaker 0: not only was it your idea But you insisted we do it and we did it for a while and we both agreed It was lame and bad and killed it.
Speaker 0: Okay, and it was good.
Speaker 1: That means that we we learned.
Speaker 0: now We were a little bit self-aware.
Speaker 0: We had some bits that did not make it to the final format.
Speaker 0: I feel like this is workshopping toward not a. I wouldn't run this as a real like actual game show like.
Speaker 0: remember we used to do Challenger on fire at anime cons and it turned out that fucking nobody Even people who claim to know stuff could actually answer any questions or compete in any sort of game show Unless it was 100% rigged and faked.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: So I feel like this is the kind of thing that if we needed like a sixth anime Boston panel someday We could just sort of fake it.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm like because we're one of the ideas we have for anime Boston this year You know, we do the judge anime by its cover.
Speaker 0: I think the theme is like old-school like old-school anime.
Speaker 0: So maybe we should do a judge anime by its cover, but literally do it for like 70s and 80s anime Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: We could do that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I guess it's just not enough anime per season back then.
Speaker 0: Well, you know you just do like generic old.
Speaker 0: basically It's just an excuse to expose the audience to like 20 old anime They should probably watch but doing it in a contrived format that allows us to play ignorant, you know Not really, you know that kind of thing.
Speaker 1: But anyway, so there's two ways to make trivia interesting.
Speaker 1: All right The first way to make trivia interesting is to have questions that are hard to answer but people who are so knowledgeable That it's like actually like a good competition like.
Speaker 0: oh then it has to be two people who are do claim Express that they have knowledge in a very narrow and similar and you need to have really good prepared questions Which we don't have.
Speaker 1: we didn't prepare shit.
Speaker 1: Nope.
Speaker 1: So what I think the format we got to go for here, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, basically you have to think of a very small topic you want to discuss.
Speaker 1: that's really specific to one comic or anime And then just ask a contrived trivia question that will allow you to tell this story.
Speaker 1: So for example, I might ask you What's a good question?
Speaker 1: So, you know how spider-man right?
Speaker 0: I don't shit about spider-man, but okay He had that black costume.
Speaker 0: Oh boy venom.
Speaker 1: No poison, right?
Speaker 1: Where did he get that black costume from?
Speaker 0: Didn't he fly to the moon and sew it?
Speaker 1: it's pretty close to the truth, right?
Speaker 1: So see now I can tell the funny story about where this comes from because you will not believe it and if you haven't read Comics, you won't know.
Speaker 0: actually this works because if you look at the audience of a typical panel at a con, right?
Speaker 1: It's like I can't do a geek nights episode about.
Speaker 1: where did spider-man get his ridiculous costume.
Speaker 1: Well awesome costume but the ridiculous story of how.
Speaker 0: nor can I even come up with a good like.
Speaker 0: I guess the panel would be Ten crazy fucked up things.
Speaker 0: You didn't realize from comics, right?
Speaker 1: So check this.
Speaker 1: right back in the nowadays There's all all these superhero comics have events for all the heroes get together, right?
Speaker 1: But back in the day, it wasn't like that.
Speaker 1: Every hero is in their own separate deal.
Speaker 1: way back except Wolverine putting them all together.
Speaker 1: That was later right.
Speaker 1: putting them all together in one comic like the fact that Superman and Batman would be in the same comic Was a crazy idea until like the 80s even and seven like way later, right?
Speaker 1: You know things like the Avengers did like the Fantastic Four was like one of the first team Comics there ever was in terms of superheroes, right?
Speaker 1: So Marvel their first major major major event They ever had was the secret war and the story of the secret war is so ludicrous and stupid.
Speaker 1: It was like basically the most contrived way to just get superheroes together.
Speaker 1: and what they did is they're basically like There's someone there's a bad guy and the bad guys in another dimension and the bad guy opened these portals and dragged all the heroes Into his other dimension where he could make them fight the and then they fought
Speaker 0: Plot to a fighting game like that's
Speaker 1: a mortal counter.
Speaker 1: It basically is right and it was so contrived like at the end They tossed them all back and they're like look this won't affect any of the individual stories because at the end We'll just toss them all back where they came from like they all go in a portal and they fight.
Speaker 1: now I'll go back out of the portal.
Speaker 1: Alright, so in this other dimension that they were in They stumble upon like some room that's got all this technology shit in it and there's something that's basically a fucking sewing machine.
Speaker 1: yeah, effectively and Spider-man uses it with this goop to make a new costume But it's out of annual.
Speaker 1: and then afterwards right like after the secret war was over He brought this costume with him because it was black and a white spider on it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and it turned out to be this living evil thing.
Speaker 1: You know, they they like turned it into a plot point.
Speaker 1: where is this living evil thing?
Speaker 1: And you know, they kept using that thing for a long at his time.
Speaker 1: It stuck around for super forever.
Speaker 1: But yeah, it's just way way interesting that like yeah It was just a sewing machine.
Speaker 1: and if they ever tried to do that in a movie I think they did but I didn't see that movie You probably have to turn it instead into like it's a nano.
Speaker 1: whatever People complain nerds complain at least when the movies or adaptations don't stick to the original story.
Speaker 1: But it's like.
Speaker 1: how can you stick to that?
Speaker 1: How could you possibly make a movie where spider-man goes up to a space sewing machine?
Speaker 1: Yeah and makes a new costume out of it.
Speaker 1: How do you shoot that Adam West Batman?
Speaker 0: imagine sitting in the theater Adam West Batman.
Speaker 1: you sit into the theater 15 bucks to see this on opening night and you see in Peter Parker at a sewing machine.
Speaker 1: go like digga-digga.
Speaker 1: Hey, it's like what the fuck.
Speaker 1: you can't do that.
Speaker 0: All right, so You you've read the old Doctor Strange.
Speaker 1: I read some old many dot various.
Speaker 1: I've never read like.
Speaker 0: specifically like doctors I've been many things because I'm curious how well it lines up with the movie I just saw.
Speaker 0: cuz I actually finally saw the movie Doctor Strange, which is actually way better than I expected Is a way cool character, but he is a character I actually have not read any of his comics.
Speaker 1: I don't know a lot about the best.
Speaker 0: I know more about dr.
Speaker 0: Orpheus who is a parody of dr.
Speaker 0: Strange.
Speaker 1: So the best dr.
Speaker 1: Strange comics are two kinds.
Speaker 1: number one the old psychedelic kind because they were psychedelic.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right.
Speaker 1: and secondly, dr Strange he's basically like the side character for everything because if you're say spider-man or Captain America or any superhero whatsoever Can't punch a ghost right and you got some problems with something spiritual.
Speaker 1: you basically call dr.
Speaker 1: Strange.
Speaker 1: He's not hard to call cuz.
Speaker 1: he lives in a mansion in Manhattan and it's like dude who has a mansion in Manhattan.
Speaker 1: Are you fucking kidding me?
Speaker 1: Yeah, how rich is this dude?
Speaker 1: It doesn't even have to go to work.
Speaker 0: Don't pay him Doesn't doesn't the that organization?
Speaker 0: cuz aren't there two other sanctums?
Speaker 1: He was originally like a surgeon so that makes a bunch of money, but not enough for a Manhattan mansion.
Speaker 0: So he had a Manhattan man.
Speaker 0: So in the movie at least he had a Manhattan mansion just from his surgery money.
Speaker 1: But that's not enough money for a Manhattan mansion.
Speaker 1: He he was inherited that shit.
Speaker 0: He is so you know the the doctor in Nothing monster.
Speaker 0: yes He was.
Speaker 0: he's like a hundred times better than that doc.
Speaker 1: It's a similar story.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 0: I'm aware Yeah But in the movie in the most time basically I'll ask you some questions That I would answer based on the movie and we can see.
Speaker 1: if the comic answer is different I might get the comic answer wrong.
Speaker 0: That's fine.
Speaker 1: I'm just curious because I don't remember that much.
Speaker 0: So what magic items is dr.
Speaker 0: Strange typically use or carry about him?
Speaker 1: He's got he's got a cloak all right.
Speaker 1: What's the magic cloak?
Speaker 0: What is it called something?
Speaker 1: I don't do anything.
Speaker 1: I don't remember.
Speaker 1: I think he can hide inside of it or transport with it or something.
Speaker 0: in the movie.
Speaker 0: It's just the levitation cloak.
Speaker 1: Yeah I think that's it and it literally hasn't like that.
Speaker 0: basically it literally has a mind of its own and they use it for some Somewhat slapstick comedy.
Speaker 1: He also has the amulet of agamotto.
Speaker 0: Yeah, which he in the movie.
Speaker 0: How does he get that amulet from?
Speaker 1: I think he doesn't.
Speaker 1: he like kill some evil demon like agamotto and take it from him.
Speaker 0: In the movie, he literally remember.
Speaker 0: he goes to the library to sit in there and no one's paying attention.
Speaker 0: So he steals it and cast spells with it and they're about like a moto is basically a god, right?
Speaker 1: So it's.
Speaker 1: I think he took it in a battle or so.
Speaker 1: He stole.
Speaker 1: I don't remember I could be wrong.
Speaker 1: Maybe he did steal it from a library.
Speaker 0: What about his ring?
Speaker 1: Isn't the I?
Speaker 1: I think there's a guy.
Speaker 1: Mandarin was Mandarin in the movie.
Speaker 1: No, so Mandarin is basically this dude whose power is.
Speaker 1: I have a bunch of magic rings.
Speaker 1: Yeah, he's a villain and the only time I ever remember anything about dr Strange having a ring it was like I think I read some comic where he fought the Mandarin or took it from him where Mandarin Took it from dr.
Speaker 1: Strange or something like that.
Speaker 1: I don't remember.
Speaker 0: Okay in this movie He's got they like.
Speaker 0: it's a big Chekhov gun everywhere, but every one of these monks cuz there's a lot of them He's just like one of many has a sling ring and it's the only way to teleport.
Speaker 0: and if you don't have the ring You can't teleport.
Speaker 1: That's like a Green Lantern thing.
Speaker 0: And that means also that you can't get out of the mirror dimension Okay, which is where you can have a Mortal Kombat battle and not hurt anything outside of it.
Speaker 1: Yep I think he also in he had some magic items that he couldn't carry around with him.
Speaker 1: I don't remember.
Speaker 1: it was like I could just be totally misremembering cuz my memory is garbage.
Speaker 1: But I remember maybe like an hourglass or a sundial or some or a mirror or some kind of you know Object like that.
Speaker 1: that was like in his mansion that he couldn't bring with him.
Speaker 0: All right, so in the mansion that he ends up taking there's windows that each go to like a different dimension And oh, yeah, he has the big stained glass window.
Speaker 1: That's all crazy.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there's like a dial.
Speaker 0: You can just change like what dimension it's all.
Speaker 0: that was the dial.
Speaker 1: It wasn't a sundial.
Speaker 1: It was a yeah.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: Yep Yeah, Dr.
Speaker 1: Strange the other Dr.
Speaker 1: Strange comic yeah, he's cool whatever.
Speaker 0: yeah, I'm more a fan of dr.
Speaker 0: Orvis.
Speaker 1: Alright, let me think of a different trivia, right?
Speaker 1: So You know, there's a lot of Leiji Matsumoto animes.
Speaker 1: Oh, right gun frontiers.
Speaker 0: my answer.
Speaker 1: Yeah now There are many characters in them But those characters they have their same story told many different ways many different times.
Speaker 1: You notice you if you read if you watch Captain Harlock, you know, you'll see Captain Harlock.
Speaker 1: But then you watch Galaxy Express and Captain Harlock will appear.
Speaker 1: but it won't make any sense.
Speaker 1: You won't be able to combine that with like the real Captain Harlock TV show cuz it doesn't line up, right?
Speaker 1: so my favorite guy is You know tochiro right now not Tetsuro.
Speaker 1: Tetsuro is the kid in Galaxy Express.
Speaker 1: Tochiro is the guy doesn't become the ship.
Speaker 1: Yeah, he becomes the ship.
Speaker 0: right spoilers.
Speaker 0: I guess yeah.
Speaker 1: But You don't see tochiro a lot and most things.
Speaker 1: you only see the ship like in Captain Harlock the TV series.
Speaker 1: He's already in the ship like, you know, you don't know much about right?
Speaker 1: So, I guess I got to think of a trivia question related to tochiro.
Speaker 1: yeah sure in Galaxy Express.
Speaker 1: the second I think is the second Galaxy Express movie.
Speaker 1: I do Galaxy Express or maybe it was the first movie But basically he's on this planet and he's somehow still alive even though Tetsuro already has his hat and gun.
Speaker 1: I Forgot it.
Speaker 1: Oh, it's hard to think of a trivia question.
Speaker 1: Yeah, he's just awesome.
Speaker 0: No, I'm racking my brain cuz a lot of the ones I can come up.
Speaker 0: one I you can see my monitor so I can't try not looking at your monitor.
Speaker 1: Nah, my eyes are closed.
Speaker 0: I heard.
Speaker 0: oh, actually the other problem is I came over.
Speaker 1: Okay, fine.
Speaker 1: Who is a tochiro married to Tochiro?
Speaker 1: Yeah, do you even know?
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: I can't believe you don't know this easy question.
Speaker 0: I probably don't know.
Speaker 0: I don't know I'm our eldest That's right.
Speaker 0: Yeah, okay Don't trick me I Mean, I guess I could be like met you do know.
Speaker 1: But that's also.
Speaker 1: it's like a huge plot point because like on all these things You'll see like if you're watching something and he's not alive in it or he's not already in the ship in it Like they're always alluding to like emeraldus is looking for someone or oh he's or he's remembering someone you're supposed to know.
Speaker 1: it's him.
Speaker 1: and the craziest thing is like you'll be watching something the emeraldus is in and There'll be allusions to him without ever saying his name without mentioning him, right?
Speaker 1: And if you haven't seen all this other stuff, they'll never let you know Who the hell she's worried about whatever.
Speaker 1: It's just like oh, she's worried about someone and that's it.
Speaker 1: But if you know from watching other things like oh shit son Alright in Trigon.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Oh, this is a good idea going for things that are more like that.
Speaker 0: How Many people did vashta stampede directly kill Mert like dead?
Speaker 1: Yeah one.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I was right.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 0: Do you remember that guy's name?
Speaker 1: is the guy never 13, right?
Speaker 0: Or is it he killed that guy?
Speaker 0: Did he actually?
Speaker 1: was that the guy he killed or was it the guy?
Speaker 0: All right, fine.
Speaker 0: It's spoilers I guess but it doesn't spoil the real purpose of the show.
Speaker 0: Who did vashta stampede kill?
Speaker 1: I'm pretty sure it was like the final.
Speaker 0: I know who you're thinking.
Speaker 0: It was like the most evil gung-ho gun guy of all because the guy you're thinking about is the guy who kills all the people In the town and there's that.
Speaker 0: that's like one of the past episodes because is funny up to that point and then he has to Get evil, but no he Bremer He breaks the guy's mask and the guys laying there.
Speaker 0: He's got his gun in his face and he's just like you killed those people.
Speaker 0: They're dead.
Speaker 0: Give me one reason why I shouldn't kill you that episode, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, it doesn't kill that guy I must.
Speaker 1: it's the most evil gung-ho gun guy like at the end.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Is it the most evil the second most?
Speaker 0: Well, I guess it depends.
Speaker 1: It's not the final boss.
Speaker 1: It's the you know, the final gung-ho gun guy.
Speaker 0: You don't remember that guy's name at all.
Speaker 0: No, they all have great names.
Speaker 0: They do like the saxophone guy.
Speaker 1: It wasn't the saxophone, you know us.
Speaker 0: that was the guy before the saxophone guy killed himself.
Speaker 0: the guy after the saxophone Yeah, the gato blue summers.
Speaker 1: All right that guy.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's right.
Speaker 1: Yeah is in the comic.
Speaker 1: He's a way bigger deal.
Speaker 0: Yeah, cuz the comic is so fine.
Speaker 0: I I read the comic and I can not line it up with the anime at all.
Speaker 0: Nor am I really sure what happened in the comic?
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm night.
Speaker 0: Oh just Panels just kind of happen and there's gunfights.
Speaker 0: I guess that's it.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm Let's do some.
Speaker 1: Let's do some.
Speaker 1: Evangelion tribute Evangelion.
Speaker 1: that's the trickiest.
Speaker 0: Yeah Evangelion I haven't seen in a long time, but I've seen it a lot of times.
Speaker 1: All right, so listen Tell me you know, there's all these kids in his class, right, but the most of them go away.
Speaker 1: Yep, right Can you tell me you know, gee, I can't remember all their names.
Speaker 1: Oh gee, right just Yeah, he's the right.
Speaker 1: but just Describe all of the kids.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I was right.
Speaker 0: told you he's the one I thought you're gay cuz he's the gruff one Who then is gonna be a pilot and then he breaks himself.
Speaker 1: So that's one.
Speaker 1: Describe all the students in the class that have like speaking named role.
Speaker 0: Okay, there's the spunky girl who's resentful of people all the time with the black hair and it's kind of friends with Asuka Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: There's I guess the main kids.
Speaker 0: So there's Asuka who is Asuka right.
Speaker 0: and There's The fanboy military kid.
Speaker 0: Yeah who wants to be all hardcore about this really wishes He was the robot pilot.
Speaker 0: toji doesn't want to be the robot pilot.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: Ray is Ray.
Speaker 0: all the different rays are out there.
Speaker 0: Yeah, uh Shinji obviously, I think there's only one more that I remember and there's the kid who's actually an angel.
Speaker 1: Oh, I guess he gets in the class.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and in the manga.
Speaker 0: he's in the class forever like Character?
Speaker 1: no, but there's one other that I remember.
Speaker 1: who else is the student council president girl?
Speaker 1: He comes.
Speaker 0: I thought she was the black haired girl.
Speaker 1: I thought she had brown hair, but she comes to like deliver homework or something at some point.
Speaker 0: She's not the character.
Speaker 0: I was thinking of.
Speaker 1: Oh, I think that's someone different or did I make a mistake?
Speaker 0: Well, we are the best at trivia.
Speaker 0: Let's see.
Speaker 0: I'm looking up just pictures of these characters.
Speaker 0: Okay, uh Oh, that's like, you know The question I was gonna ask you was name anyone who ever sits at a control panel in nerve HQ.
Speaker 1: Miss Otto sits at one of these once.
Speaker 0: does she or does she just stand there?
Speaker 0: She usually stands there, but does she ever sit at one and touch a button?
Speaker 1: I'm sure she'd purchase some buttons.
Speaker 1: That's a point.
Speaker 1: She actually does right now, but there's the three people this nerdy guy.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there's the girl G and the girl and then there's the other dude.
Speaker 0: think we're talking about the same girl.
Speaker 1: They're all basically the assistants of You know yellow hair person.
Speaker 1: What's her name?
Speaker 0: Oh Reads go.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the one voiced by Bar Who is Luke Morgan's favorite character in that show, I don't know but I'm gonna go with Old guy.
Speaker 0: no reads go.
Speaker 1: Okay, who's the who's?
Speaker 1: there was the old guy?
Speaker 1: No, no doctor, whatever.
Speaker 0: Oh, oh the Grand Moff effectively.
Speaker 0: Yes, go zu Futski, yeah, if you'd see that guy he has murdered.
Speaker 0: Do you remember the name of the head of?
Speaker 1: Sele Zero one keel.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: Yeah, sure.
Speaker 0: Uh man, you know These aren't good trivia questions, but good questions for the like.
Speaker 0: the conceit of that panel would be like Alright, what the fuck was kaji up to with that briefcase like those?
Speaker 1: I know exactly what he was up to.
Speaker 0: I think everyone who watch Ava like super closely knows what was up, right?
Speaker 1: So here's the deal.
Speaker 1: if you don't know the story even Joe and I'm just gonna spill it out for you.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so in the first well the first impact right way back in the day way back in ancient history, right?
Speaker 1: There were these aliens and aliens were like yo We have like swear we know everything and also we're super powerful and that's too dangerous.
Speaker 1: So we're gonna do is we're gonna send out into space like Superman.
Speaker 1: Right these pods and some of the pods are gonna have beings of like unlimited You know like health and life or whatever like the s2 engines and all that nice and right and some of them are gonna have Knowledge, right?
Speaker 1: Like and then.
Speaker 1: so it's just like Adam and Eve right, you know Lilith the tree of knowledge Which you can't eat from and Adam the tree of life, right?
Speaker 1: So and never the twain shall mix.
Speaker 1: so they send these aliens out in these ships to land on planets.
Speaker 1: so of course Adam smashes into the earth and You know, so does by accident Lilith and it's like oh shit - you know one of each side landed on earth at the same time and We have so we can't in case this happens, right?
Speaker 1: we don't want these two things to be combined ever.
Speaker 1: we built in a system to where they'll self-destruct and Everything will be totally chill because we won't have ever to mixing again anywhere on the universe.
Speaker 1: so Of course what happens is the Lilith one lands on earth and a bunch of life spawns from Lilith, which is humans, right?
Speaker 1: but then the second impact was when The Adam one wakes up and that's what killed, you know, miss Otto's dad and everybody a second impact, right?
Speaker 0: The second impact so that's Adam woke up basically and it was like oh shit They woke Adam up right and it might not have woken up if they didn't go poke him.
Speaker 1: The point is is that there were two on the same planet and you know Adam and basically turned off or whatever because you know what.
Speaker 1: not so Because they were you know, the mixing of the knowledge and the power Boom impact dope to prevent this from happening.
Speaker 1: So Akaji had in the briefcase was actually Adam left over.
Speaker 1: Oh, look, he's still here.
Speaker 1: Yeah, he got his leftovers here, right?
Speaker 1: It's all the angels that are coming right to fight.
Speaker 1: are The spawns of Adam right which is why they're fighting against, you know, they're trying to basically get to.
Speaker 1: you know That's like the fail-safe system, right?
Speaker 1: They're trying to get to the remains of Lilith down underneath the nerve headquarters yeah, and destroy it to prevent the combining of the two.
Speaker 1: and when there's the episode where able towards the end where Ava one goes nuts and it beats the totally awesome angel and takes the engine out of it and absorbs it into itself and they say something like We're trying to protect the earth not make a god oops Right, cuz that's Ava one does what's not supposed to be done and combines the two and becomes.
Speaker 0: That would have been a good trivia question.
Speaker 0: Who's whose mom is in each one of those Ava's your mom.
Speaker 1: Yeah Let's go to a different Ina.
Speaker 0: All right, you want to ask me one.
Speaker 0: cuz I got.
Speaker 0: I got one here again.
Speaker 1: What else can I?
Speaker 1: the problem is thinking of one that has like an interesting discussion topic or anime want to talk about?
Speaker 1: All right, so Let's talk about cuz.
Speaker 0: I got chaos entry beast up here.
Speaker 1: You got chaos entry beast and I'll talk about El Hazzard.
Speaker 0: Oh shit, El Hazzard, right?
Speaker 1: So now Hazzard, right?
Speaker 1: There's all these princesses.
Speaker 1: Yep, right Can you name all those princesses?
Speaker 1: Cuz I only remember like.
Speaker 0: I don't remember any of their names There's there's red haired girl who wanted she was like younger and wanted to prove herself.
Speaker 0: There was the old one who married.
Speaker 1: Professor you remember way more than me Fujimoto.
Speaker 0: What's the Fujimoto?
Speaker 1: Cuz he actually married one of the princesses.
Speaker 1: Yeah, what I was at the TV series cuz I only remember any.
Speaker 0: there's more away V2.
Speaker 1: I never watched anything but the original Ava Fujisawa not Fujimoto.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but you saw a kick.
Speaker 0: cuz remember he would get more powerful if he didn't have alcohol or cigarettes in his system.
Speaker 0: mmm, I remember all that crap and The third one.
Speaker 0: I don't actually remember the third one.
Speaker 0: There was the old one who was retiring.
Speaker 0: there was the young hot-headed one and there was another one that I can't.
Speaker 0: Oh, no, it's cool.
Speaker 0: The green one with the black hair who is just chill and smart.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm Don't remember any of their names though.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's a show I forgot a lot of but it had like.
Speaker 1: that was the show of hubba.
Speaker 0: hubba zoot suit has a lube is outside.
Speaker 0: No, right.
Speaker 1: It's like those bug room with janae.
Speaker 1: It's like that's funny parts.
Speaker 0: It was also kind of the reason why.
Speaker 1: and janae sister.
Speaker 1: It's like.
Speaker 1: this is like a very generic Anime TV series from the generic 90s era of anime like that.
Speaker 1: But you know, it doesn't have even though it has like these anime tropes and whatnot.
Speaker 1: It executes them, but it doesn't have bad anime things like, you know, moe's.
Speaker 1: It's like it's just completely normal and totally funny and Points has fantasy adventure.
Speaker 0: It's got everything cat armor, but Jedi Like.
Speaker 0: I Cannot help but fucking laugh out loud at Jedi.
Speaker 0: He's funny stuff.
Speaker 1: He is a funny, dude.
Speaker 0: However, remember we were qualifying this only the first OAV.
Speaker 0: Yeah now watch the TV show cuz it's terrible.
Speaker 0: No, and the second OAV is just perverted.
Speaker 0: So in chaos entry beasts, tell me anything about the three main characters this bird guy.
Speaker 0: Yeah, do you remember his name?
Speaker 1: bird guy?
Speaker 0: You're close Robin bud mint.
Speaker 1: Oh bud mint.
Speaker 1: That's right, bud.
Speaker 0: And then at one point there's a nickname that a character has for him.
Speaker 0: I think it's his father or his mentor.
Speaker 0: Do you remember what his nickname is?
Speaker 0: No, Teva.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 0: There's also means like chicken wing.
Speaker 1: There's also a mermaid girl.
Speaker 0: Yeah, do you remember her name?
Speaker 1: Mer something you're real close.
Speaker 0: That's your last name mamer.
Speaker 1: mamer may mirrors her name and then this main tiger guy.
Speaker 0: What's his name's?
Speaker 0: the best name?
Speaker 1: I'll remember it if you give me any of the theme song.
Speaker 1: One dava dava.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's his name on dava dava.
Speaker 1: That's the worst name And they each have a robot and then the robots combined.
Speaker 0: Who are they fighting against this?
Speaker 1: isn't it like an evil lady who's got like a Like a demon kind of thing.
Speaker 0: No, you're thinking of a kamako.
Speaker 0: She's their sidekick.
Speaker 1: that's from a different.
Speaker 0: No, she's in that show.
Speaker 0: She's just a sidekick.
Speaker 1: a kamako was from that other show.
Speaker 0: No, what other show?
Speaker 1: a kamako is the sidekick of the bad guy?
Speaker 0: Yeah, they're basically just low rent.
Speaker 0: Team Rocket.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but like anime Team Rocket not real Giovanni Team Rocket.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm Yeah, what?
Speaker 0: what is the most interesting aspect of the world that they live in like cut in half?
Speaker 0: Yep, literally cut in two two separate pieces of earth.
Speaker 0: There's animals on one side and technology on the other side And it was made by guy next.
Speaker 1: Oh, really?
Speaker 1: Yeah, I didn't know that and animate.
Speaker 1: Oh As news to me.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I learned a lot about this cuz I was gonna do a panel on it years ago And I never made the panel.
Speaker 0: I have like a half the slides done cuz I was like this show.
Speaker 0: anyone know about this show.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm All right, so I'm gonna go and do some.
Speaker 1: right we were talking about this before the show cuz it's ending soon.
Speaker 1: You know some dr.
Speaker 1: McNinja, right?
Speaker 1: Oh, can you tell me?
Speaker 1: Everyone in the McNinja family.
Speaker 0: There's Dan McNinja dad.
Speaker 1: That's right.
Speaker 0: I forget the mom's name.
Speaker 1: I Don't know your name either.
Speaker 1: There's a mom McNinja McNinja.
Speaker 0: There's old McNinja the clone.
Speaker 1: Oh, you remember it old McNinja the old McNinja the trick question Had a farm.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah ninja came back in the like final bat.
Speaker 1: I think I got somewhere near that part.
Speaker 0: So it's not as basically dr McNinja is important right now because like the the boss fight hack, you know, the dude has other work to do.
Speaker 1: You know, he's ending dr.
Speaker 0: McNinja because it's time to end that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and he wanted to give it a proper ending.
Speaker 0: So we just had this like giant epic arc tying up every end and bring everything together into the final battle.
Speaker 0: We're basically it's like at our JRPG like they went in like there's a part where they went into like the final dungeon Mm-hmm, and then there's the final battle which just happened pretty epically.
Speaker 0: and now the square boss is happening and I think the panel that is up as of the taping of this episode is like The P like right after like.
Speaker 0: the next panel is going to be the climax square boss fights.
Speaker 0: Hmm so there's Gordito who's adopted Yeah, who I think the parents kind of love more than they like doctor doesn't everybody.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think so.
Speaker 0: Ah There's grandpa McNinja who is the reason?
Speaker 0: yeah the old plot like the whole plot of the the.
Speaker 0: What's the the Rick?
Speaker 0: What's the name of the product from Home Alone 2?
Speaker 0: That they use as the magic item that the ghosts want?
Speaker 0: It's a little recording device that the kid uses to trick the bottle.
Speaker 1: Oh the microphone.
Speaker 0: Yeah, what was that called?
Speaker 0: I forget I owned one.
Speaker 1: I did not.
Speaker 0: it had it like a clever marketing style name.
Speaker 0: Anyway, something saw.
Speaker 0: Oh my god, I'm gonna look it up now.
Speaker 1: There's a microphone that broadcast on AM or FM radio in a very short radius.
Speaker 1: So if you're standing your radio, no, that is not what it was.
Speaker 0: No, it's the talk boy.
Speaker 0: Okay, the talk boy was just a cassette recorder and playback system that had a microphone and you can also speed up or slow Down the playback.
Speaker 1: I had a fisher-price recorder, which did that but couldn't speed up or slow down the playback.
Speaker 0: No, the the artifact in that old thing in dr.
Speaker 0: Mangia is literally the talk boy.
Speaker 0: Mmm, like literally, okay Uh, I think that's all of them.
Speaker 0: I can't think of anyone.
Speaker 1: I forgot Dark Smoke Puncher.
Speaker 0: god, damn it.
Speaker 0: I forgot about him.
Speaker 0: indeed Who's also a fan of our?
Speaker 1: also, dr.
Speaker 0: McNichol, well, yeah Real one.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I guess all the other clones and I don't know if they're in the family only old wing ninja is really.
Speaker 1: yeah.
Speaker 0: I guess a good interesting question would actually be who are in order?
Speaker 0: all of the primary villains That's like name all all the primary Batman villains King radical.
Speaker 1: Yeah Everyone else is just such a chump.
Speaker 0: It doesn't use like the cyborg.
Speaker 0: I was pretty good.
Speaker 1: is the fat mayor crab guy?
Speaker 0: Yeah, he comes back is Ronald whatever.
Speaker 1: Yeah ghost wizard.
Speaker 1: Yep literal Dracula All right, literal Dracula then Franklin.
Speaker 0: No, he's sort of there's a bunch of ghost wizards.
Speaker 1: That's just one Yeah, but the ghost wizards in general, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah super dangerous.
Speaker 1: Oh Unicorn motorcycle dude.
Speaker 1: Yeah Sort of a villain I guess mostly.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we'll see if he will see what happens.
Speaker 1: that I already mentioned Ronald.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you mentioned Ronald.
Speaker 1: Okay Oh, there's the muscle guy.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, the bodybuilder guy for his name.
Speaker 1: Yeah, whatever his name is.
Speaker 0: He's still around.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's most of the major ones.
Speaker 0: I think we killed enough time.
Speaker 0: we just hit the hour mark.
Speaker 0: give or take.
Speaker 1: oh good Cuz I'm hungry.
Speaker 0: I'm also hungry and you know Bad show.
Speaker 0: We're getting good feedback from Emily, maybe we'll do this as a panel at like a low tier con.
Speaker 1: No, let's actually watch and or read something next time.
Speaker 0: Alright, let's watch cuz this is like the lowest hanging fruit We because the show we did on the Sailor Moon super s movie was actually pretty good.
Speaker 0: Okay, cuz they're short Let's watch.
Speaker 0: So here's your choice Scott.
Speaker 0: You get to pick from one of two Sailor Moon movies.
Speaker 0: I'll summarize the Sailor Moon movie because they're short and I have them.
Speaker 0: Okay, one of them is Luna the cat falls in love and there's a whole story about her Sounds good.
Speaker 0: And the other one is a gay flower from space kidnaps.
Speaker 0: Cuz tuxedo mask to Be his lover forever in space.
Speaker 1: Let's do the cat one.
Speaker 0: Okay, we'll do the cat one.
Speaker 0: That is the s move.
Speaker 1: This is a. this is a.
Speaker 0: it's also a Christmas movie.
Speaker 1: This is a trick question where you're like rim.
Speaker 1: Let's choose between two things to eat for dinner.
Speaker 1: We go to fat or we can eat poop.
Speaker 1: choose one I'll let you choose.
Speaker 1: we can eat where you want the salt and fat or poop.
Speaker 0: Well, cuz I remember when I gave you the choice way back.
Speaker 0: The third option was the candy dimension invades the earth and steals children.
Speaker 1: Didn't we already see that one?
Speaker 1: We did.
Speaker 0: we did a whole show on it cuz that's the one you picked.
Speaker 0: Okay candy dimension invades earth And it's also the second boy that Chibi Uso falls in love with if you don't count her dad.
Speaker 0: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott.
Speaker 0: special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 1: be sure to visit our website at front row.
Speaker 1: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 0: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 1: But unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night.
Speaker 0: And this episode of eat nice is brought to you partially by the consideration of all of our patreon patreon.
Speaker 0: So I'm now going to read their names in order of the amount of money.
Speaker 0: They give us on a continuing basis as fast as I possibly can Alan Joyce Rebecca done Nicholas Brando Heidi McNichol Amanda Duchette construction noise as I've you say my state e.com believe my listeners Jeremy minor Chris Reimer and Thomas Hahn Christian coons and Chris Reimer with and Chris Hahn Reimer and Thomas and You can use that And I continuing sure of it.
Speaker 0: on Harley Iggy Kidra Lavelle James David, why are you sure on, Montana?
Speaker 0: Superboy a playground with no kids.
Speaker 0: Aaron Cerise Brian Fisher sailor vista so long space cowboy Matthew Smith Don Schleich Kajar topics and Jojo Joestar Tyler elder Shawn Yeager Sam quarter Clinton Walton read from New Zealand.
Speaker 0: Ryan parent Drew up and Leonard Brian Sidroni.
Speaker 0: Finn Eric silver out redacted Chris midkiff Chris Knox Daniel Redmond Sean Klein Chris Reimer and Thomas Hahn.
Speaker 0: Yeah, those old episode of geek nights that are in the patreon the most recent remastered one will be up soon.
Speaker 0: it is Fascinating to listen to these old things.
Speaker 0: I cannot stress it enough.
Speaker 0: They're not necessarily good, but they're getting better.
Speaker 0: But they get like plus two to the roll.
Speaker 0: for goodness just because of how weird is to hear me talking about gen 2 on The desktop downstairs and Scott being really excited about the nuances of the special prosecutor's office.
Speaker 0: But anyway now I leave you with what happened.
Speaker 0: What happened?
Speaker 1: Somebody set up us the ball.
Speaker 1: somebody set up us the ball.
Speaker 0: We get signal.
Speaker 1: what Main screen.
Speaker 1: turn on.
Speaker 1: main screen.
Speaker 1: Main-screen.
Speaker 0: Turn on.
Speaker 0: Signal.
Speaker 0: main-screen.
Speaker 0: turn on.
Speaker 0: Main-screen.
Speaker 0: main-screen.
Speaker 1: main-screen.
Speaker 1: turn on.
Speaker 0: It's you it's you it's you it's you it's you.
Speaker 1: how are you gentlemen?
Speaker 1: all your base are belong to us.
Speaker 1: you are on the way to Destructions.
Speaker 0: what you say all your base what you say all your base your base are belong to us.
Speaker 1: what you say Signal.
Speaker 1: what you say hey you are on the way to Destructions.
Speaker 1: you have no chance to survive.
Speaker 1: make your time Somebody set up us.