Speaker 1: It's Thursday, June 23rd.
Speaker 1: I'm rim.
Speaker 1: I'm Scott and this is geek night tonight.
Speaker 1: How to not suck.
Speaker 1: we're bringing it back at hosting a party.
Speaker 1: Let's do this Man.
Speaker 1: that's the kind of topic we did them back in like 2006 2007. we used to host a lot of parties and stuff back then like actually kind of way more than we do now Mmm, but also it's interesting that we we were trying to think I would do the show today And we have forgot that we had that ongoing series how to not suck at something that
Speaker 0: seemed
Speaker 1: pretty popular back Then like and we just kind of stopped doing it.
Speaker 1: I don't know why.
Speaker 1: I don't think we ran out of ideas I don't know why we stopped.
Speaker 1: so I think we're gonna start.
Speaker 1: how to not suck at doing episodes on how to not suck at things.
Speaker 1: Mmm Got any any meta any things to talk about in the beginning of the show.
Speaker 1: Thursday the lounge.
Speaker 0: Now that you're done talking about nothing I got some somethings.
Speaker 1: You want a thing.
Speaker 1: so my pebble broke and I'm getting a replacement.
Speaker 0: You have had that happen.
Speaker 1: so the pebble.
Speaker 0: I had the very first pebble ever and the screen just like flip the fuck out and Then they sent me a new one eventually.
Speaker 1: I have the pebbles.
Speaker 0: They didn't want the old one back.
Speaker 1: I have the pebble time steal series.
Speaker 1: they're making me send it back, but I Have had it for a long time, and it's waterproof, and they make a big deal on the website.
Speaker 1: They're like wear it at the beach wear it in the pool Wear it.
Speaker 1: it is a hundred percent waterproof.
Speaker 1: thirty meters down go nuts.
Speaker 1: So we're at the beach And I had it on and I jump into the water and the screen immediately goes apeshit and it dies.
Speaker 1: So like Literally like.
Speaker 1: it starts buzzing constantly, and I look and the buzzer is like squirting water out the top of it.
Speaker 1: I'm just like really like didn't even pretend to be waterproof.
Speaker 1: So I do the warranty thing and they respond back and they're like so before we're gonna accept the warranty you need to take a video of you attempting to charge it and Trying to turn it on and proving that it won't turn on.
Speaker 1: and I was like Okay, I made this video of like it not turning on and I sent it to them, and then they're like okay I'll give you a new one
Speaker 0: okay, but then
Speaker 1: they asked me something interesting Mmm, and this is actually I don't know if you're aware of this Extreme design flaw of the pebble which is not relevant to what happened to me because I can see the top seal here.
Speaker 1: I'm just not sealed.
Speaker 1: like you can see it's not sealed.
Speaker 1: But if the pebbles in water and you push any of the buttons immediate ruin.
Speaker 1: The buttons are not waterproof.
Speaker 1: if you press them That's something that they bury and hide.
Speaker 1: But that is a an explicit little design flaw of all the pebble.
Speaker 0: so if you push the button in the water Fucked just ruins it and they won't give you.
Speaker 1: if you do I don't know if they will or not but in my case I can clearly see that that is not what happened.
Speaker 1: So I don't have to worry about that like if I push on it Yeah, I'm not planning to go swimming anyway.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but that was an interesting thing that happened to me at the beach.
Speaker 1: Cuz it starts buzzing.
Speaker 1: I'm like who's calling me while I'm in the water.
Speaker 1: I'm like oh pebble warranty is calling me.
Speaker 0: I guess Okay News time.
Speaker 0: I guess a big news happened.
Speaker 1: Well.
Speaker 1: You were the one who was bitching for like ten minutes, Bob There's no news at all in the world right now.
Speaker 0: I found a news Super important news.
Speaker 1: how important could this be?
Speaker 0: the National Hockey League is going to officially and definitely create Yet another hockey team in the city of Las Vegas, Nevada.
Speaker 0: This is a done deal.
Speaker 1: Now what sucks is that this team should be called the Stars, but that name is already taken.
Speaker 0: Okay, so first of all right issue.
Speaker 0: the first we need less hockey teams not more hockey team.
Speaker 0: Yes issue the second they could have just moved the Arizona team to Las Vegas.
Speaker 0: Yep Number three we just need less hockey teams.
Speaker 0: They should.
Speaker 0: what they really should do is get rid of Arizona team and probably a few others.
Speaker 1: now I'm actually like I. while I kind of want to do less hockey teams I feel like we're at a pretty good level like if we didn't expand.
Speaker 1: I feel like this is sustained anyway.
Speaker 0: Another issue that requires the some amount of discussion.
Speaker 1: right no one lives in Vegas who cares about hockey.
Speaker 0: No, there is going to be an expansion draft which basically means each team.
Speaker 0: I'm not going to go over the specific rules.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah I've never I've never paid.
Speaker 1: it's like expansion drafts are not common.
Speaker 0: you can it.
Speaker 0: you can read these specific rules for the expansion draft Online, but basically the deal is each team can protect a certain number of players from its team.
Speaker 0: So basically you're like if you're you know the Rangers you saying you can't have our loan quest.
Speaker 0: he's ours.
Speaker 0: Don't touch this right.
Speaker 0: and then there are certain players that have like no move clauses or no trade clauses in their contracts And those players you have to protect like you can't decide.
Speaker 0: you have to spend one of your protections on them because you're forced to Because you made that contract.
Speaker 0: so what if?
Speaker 0: and then what if you had?
Speaker 1: All your contracts had no move somehow, and you've only got in protection.
Speaker 0: There's all kinds of rules.
Speaker 0: The expansion team can go around and they just take players for everyone to make their own team.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and that's how that works, and then you have to fill in your slots with a shell people.
Speaker 1: so imagine this You're gonna have a team now.
Speaker 1: That is a whole bunch of people who have fought with each other in the past.
Speaker 1: some of them probably hate each other.
Speaker 0: I mean that's no different than any other trade deal.
Speaker 1: Uh the difference is in a trade you get like one player in exchange for a player.
Speaker 0: This is a team composed of nothing, but those people anyway, so then All these people have to go to Las Vegas to play hockey right.
Speaker 0: so the deal that the big deal is The gambling situation right.
Speaker 0: so that's the whole reason you choose Vegas because Vegas is actually.
Speaker 1: I don't think that's the reason you choose Vegas.
Speaker 1: I've learned a lot about this.
Speaker 0: so Vegas It's a big city with no sports teams.
Speaker 1: No, professional sports team gambling in Vegas has been on a steep decline for a decade.
Speaker 0: that is true but Sports gambling in general is on the rise.
Speaker 0: that is also true.
Speaker 0: It is the only kind of gambling that freakin matters anymore than anyone cares about now.
Speaker 1: There is a side angle here Vegas.
Speaker 1: the way they make money now is hospitality and spectacles and Hockey in Vegas is actually perfect for a spectacle.
Speaker 1: There's a whole bunch of games there.
Speaker 0: So if you're suddenly all these real hockey teams have to go there yep like they're gonna have away games and fucking.
Speaker 0: so think it is.
Speaker 0: If the Rangers are in Vegas for a game I guarantee there's once a year at most because this is the West vs The East.
Speaker 1: is it once or twice it might be?
Speaker 1: I mean, I think twice.
Speaker 0: yeah Vegas will come to the garden.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, no one will go to see you get cheap tickets.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah You can't get cheap.
Speaker 1: It doesn't be.
Speaker 1: I don't care if it's the Sabres.
Speaker 1: you still can't get a cheap Rangers ticket.
Speaker 1: The Sabres are better than Vegas but so if the Rangers are in Vegas for their game there I Guarantee there's at least a couple thousand Rangers fans.
Speaker 1: I happen to be in Vegas at the time.
Speaker 0: It's a. Vegas will be way cheap Yeah, but they'll be like, oh you can go to Vegas in the winter Which is a place you want to go in the winter and see cheap hockey I also think.
Speaker 0: and then you can sell the high kids to have gambling machines at the hockey arena Just like they did in Australia at the footy field.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but anytime there's a game in Vegas They're just gonna be gonna score a goal first.
Speaker 0: Who's gonna score the most goals?
Speaker 1: which players gonna score first, but hey tourists you want to see Penn and Teller?
Speaker 0: You want to see who's gonna serve the most penalty minutes?
Speaker 1: I think that the audience of the Vegas stars is gonna be like any given game is gonna be Vegas not stars.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm just calling the Vegas stars for now.
Speaker 1: Emily thinks they should be called the aces.
Speaker 1: That's not bad.
Speaker 1: I want to call them the Mavericks.
Speaker 0: There's already a Dallas man basketball.
Speaker 1: Well basketball not the same.
Speaker 0: What?
Speaker 0: what?
Speaker 0: The only team that there I know of that I can think of right now where the same name is in two different leagues Not counting minor league the Cardinals.
Speaker 0: They're the st.
Speaker 0: Louis Cardinals of the house ball in the Arizona Cardinals of Football.
Speaker 1: that is true.
Speaker 1: I can't think of any more unless you count minor leagues.
Speaker 0: And that doesn't count because there's a million stupid giants the San Francisco Giants and the New York football giant.
Speaker 0: I did not know there was a San Francisco Giants the baseball team and then they used the World Series recently I guess I guess I pay attention to baseball is also used to be the New York Giants of baseball.
Speaker 0: that no longer exists.
Speaker 0: Let's bring them back Mm-hmm, I think instead of expanding in Vegas someone's gonna tell me that there's another one that I forgot There should be.
Speaker 1: we should just expand into Bronx or Queens.
Speaker 1: Have a third hockey team here.
Speaker 0: No, the Islanders are already garbage.
Speaker 1: You don't need yeah But at least there's more.
Speaker 1: it spreads a little bit of hockey out because the Rangers you just can't see unless you got an inside Line, but there's rain the Texas Rangers and the New York Rangers.
Speaker 1: But this audience is gonna be like a third the people in Vegas who decide they like they care about hockey and that's gonna be Their team.
Speaker 1: it's gonna be a third tourist who've never seen ice hockey before who are like, yeah, I'll see an ice hockey game.
Speaker 1: It's part of my Vegas thing.
Speaker 1: Whatever cool.
Speaker 1: It's a spectacle.
Speaker 1: I'll go watch this thing.
Speaker 1: and the last third will be fans of whatever the other team is who happen to be in Vegas And we'll see how this all goes.
Speaker 1: I don't predict they'll win a Stanley Cup in my lifetime.
Speaker 0: You know, that's the main.
Speaker 0: that's the last point.
Speaker 0: right is like there.
Speaker 0: now We really can't have Vegas with the name on the Stanley Cup.
Speaker 0: that can't happen Like.
Speaker 0: it cannot be allowed but it's possible.
Speaker 0: and what are you gonna do if it happens?
Speaker 1: No, like I feel like old enemies like the Rangers and Islanders will somehow collaborate to prevent Vegas from getting right.
Speaker 0: And but you know, hey if I go to Vegas in the winter, which is a most likely to go in the winter I'll go see a hockey game for cheap.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I would see it's readily available.
Speaker 1: You know what?
Speaker 1: Even if it was like Sabres and the Vegas Mavericks I would probably go see it cuz it's Vegas.
Speaker 1: What else are gonna do?
Speaker 1: gonna see Ben and Teller You're gonna eat a bunch of fancy food.
Speaker 1: You're gonna wander around watch a fountain.
Speaker 1: do a thing.
Speaker 1: Have you been to Vegas in your adult life?
Speaker 0: Nope.
Speaker 1: Have you been to Vegas ever?
Speaker 1: Oh it Talked to us a long time ago, but the way it's way more fun and nicer than I expected But also like 80% exactly what I expected.
Speaker 0: Like there's the Florida Panthers of hockey and the Carolina Panthers of the NFL.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah I didn't even think of them.
Speaker 1: So other minor news is This is more video game news but it's kind of relevant to Real life because if even if you're not like someone who would self-describe as a video gamer And I'm not I don't even know if this game is good because I haven't actually played it except a demo.
Speaker 1: but this game the NFL New York Jets and the Winnipeg Jets Playing the Harford Whalers down in hell.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so VA - one one HALL - a. it's this video game that
Speaker 0: we've been waiting for for years
Speaker 1: based solely on having played a like two-minute demo of it and being told what it is and it's basically a Papers-pleased style game coupled with a visual novel set in a cyber dystopia That is so close to the Idoro world that I'm kind of like a shot.
Speaker 0: It's pixel anime style But as far as I can tell from the you know information I have gathered these part where you make the drinks Papers-pleased acts as like a skill like clicking fast almost right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, this doesn't have that.
Speaker 0: It's you know, it's basically.
Speaker 0: it's more like Phoenix, right?
Speaker 0: Like.
Speaker 1: it's just a visual novel mostly Yeah but based on the drinks you make for people and how you interact with them like stuff will go differently and I can't say the game's good.
Speaker 0: We haven't played it, but I've been waiting for this game for a long time Installed it the day it came out because I pre-ordered it But I just haven't had time to play it because it's summer and I'm outside all the time.
Speaker 1: It looks like the kind of game that I'm gonna really really really really like.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna try to.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna stream it with my new equips and it's weird and different enough to where.
Speaker 1: even if you don't think You like video games This is the kind of thing that you should try.
Speaker 1: it might broaden your horizons on what it means to say This is a video game.
Speaker 1: Hmm Even if the game is bad at least be interesting and I suspect it's not gonna be bad.
Speaker 1: No Other interesting stuff that's been going on.
Speaker 1: So Scott said there's no news, but literally right now Britain is having a referendum on whether or not they're going to leave the European Union.
Speaker 0: don't care You don't care at all.
Speaker 0: next next news.
Speaker 1: You need you even know like what that entails or what that means.
Speaker 1: What is the European Union?
Speaker 0: Scott don't care next?
Speaker 1: Okay, really?
Speaker 1: So you have no this.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: This is why Scott doesn't ever think there's any news.
Speaker 0: There's nothing to say about this.
Speaker 1: There's a lot to say about that.
Speaker 0: Nothing to need to say that hasn't already been said.
Speaker 1: Continue by that logic.
Speaker 1: No one should ever make any more media cuz.
Speaker 1: every concept has ever ever been expressed.
Speaker 1: at some point in some Form.
Speaker 1: you're just rewriting.
Speaker 0: I don't watch a lot of our media old man Scott.
Speaker 1: But anyway things of the day.
Speaker 1: I stumbled onto these videos and they're actually pretty pleasant.
Speaker 1: They're called like oddly satisfying and it's just a serious kind of like gifts with sound but longer form.
Speaker 1: But it'll show like just a machine making cakes in close-up detail or like this one right here a guy has set up like 40 balls all over snow pool table and then he throws one ball with his hand and it bounces around like crazy.
Speaker 1: It doesn't hit any of them.
Speaker 1: and all these just like really Satisfying videos to watch like a master chef has been around for a while.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's just a thing.
Speaker 1: It's one of those YouTube ghettos.
Speaker 1: It's good stuff.
Speaker 0: I mean this has been a thing like this is even older than YouTube right?
Speaker 0: this kind of stuff like I remember like even in high school seeing like JPEGs or like animated gifs of like stuff that was like, whoa.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it was animated gifs I think we call.
Speaker 1: I used to see it was gear porn cuz it was just complex gear.
Speaker 1: Yeah, awesome thing.
Speaker 0: Okay, and it was all it was called.
Speaker 0: even back then it was called oddly satisfied But that's not my thing of the day.
Speaker 1: This is oh my thing of the day.
Speaker 1: Is that someone did something brilliant and this is the cut?
Speaker 1: This is like.
Speaker 1: this is the most beautiful troll in the world because it's creative and interesting.
Speaker 1: They call it the most Unsatisfying.
Speaker 0: those things like an OCD person goes it's things that just don't work out.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I've seen these two.
Speaker 1: like he starts to go and then it just falls.
Speaker 0: I've seen this exact one.
Speaker 1: I think I guys about to catch his finger in a mousetrap in slow motion and just before it snaps the gif ends.
Speaker 1: Someone slowly failing at Tetris to tourists throwing a frisbee the wrong way over and over and over again.
Speaker 0: clearly not Understand the museum exhibit.
Speaker 0: I wanted to make the guy place sitting there playing Mario badly.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and you can't stop him He's just doing it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, just keeps touching that first Goomba or whatever.
Speaker 0: over and over it's falling a hole.
Speaker 0: You know, I guess he can get to the first hole and fall in.
Speaker 1: occasionally He has to get to the first hole and then fall in like he gets a little bit further.
Speaker 1: You're like maybe he's got it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so he's not improving right?
Speaker 0: It's some some performer some performance art, right?
Speaker 0: They're not improving.
Speaker 0: They just keep sucking and not getting anywhere significant.
Speaker 1: one of these is just Mario like trying to jump up onto a thing You're just failing forever.
Speaker 1: It's it's beautiful.
Speaker 0: That's what I'm talking about.
Speaker 0: So yeah so I Felt like I used this thing of the day, but I guess I didn't so I couldn't find it in a search.
Speaker 1: So this is a duplicate.
Speaker 0: is here's a bunch of old awesome.
Speaker 0: Yes rooms fault.
Speaker 0: It's a bunch of awesome old woodblock prints, which are my favorite You know old Japanese artworks and all these artworks of something in common.
Speaker 0: They depict people Flipping over go boards as in like.
Speaker 0: when you flip the table because you're pissed you lost risk and shit.
Speaker 0: Let's go with the game they played.
Speaker 0: So that's the thing.
Speaker 0: They're flipping.
Speaker 0: I'm sure they would be flipping other might be a shogi board in here somewhere.
Speaker 0: No, it looks like I'll go boards, but it tells you Flipping the table is not something new.
Speaker 0: It is a century-old multi-century old behavior.
Speaker 0: right and It's kind of cool to see you know, someone in ancient times exhibiting a behavior of the modern times.
Speaker 1: Yep, because humans have not changed substantially in terms of our brains for like 40,000 years.
Speaker 1: So even though society is advancing all that time We haven't so much physically.
Speaker 1: so the same but I virtually bullshit that we do now.
Speaker 1: You know some go master would do and troll the other guy.
Speaker 1: a hundred or a thousand You might not a thousand.
Speaker 0: what I wonder though is like how come there aren't like depictions of like, you know Dudes flipping over chess tables of like, you know, some like European arts.
Speaker 0: I've never seen that.
Speaker 1: maybe they less really less angry one Maybe there are but to wood blocks were kind of a pop art thing.
Speaker 0: That's true.
Speaker 0: That's not the kind of thing you would paint you would you know, if you're someone's paid, you know patron by somebody.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well you saw that thing.
Speaker 1: I was gonna use the thing today later.
Speaker 1: It's an explanation of why in medieval art babies look like frumpy old men and then suddenly in the Renaissance babies look good.
Speaker 1: It's not because people couldn't draw babies.
Speaker 1: They drew them ugly on purpose.
Speaker 1: because of all these stupid societal reasons.
Speaker 1: I'll use that as my thing of the night.
Speaker 0: I'm curious of those societal reasons.
Speaker 1: It's a real good video.
Speaker 0: I can just go to the museum and find out.
Speaker 1: yeah In the meta moment Connecticut is July 7th 8th.
Speaker 1: Well, it's 8th 9th and 10th.
Speaker 1: You can pick up your badge on the 7th.
Speaker 1: I don't know if there's anything on the 7th.
Speaker 0: We're not responsible like to advertise that it's on the 7th and they'll put like.
Speaker 0: I mean last year They had like the meager amount of late Programming or something on the so just able to say that it was for day.
Speaker 1: What was interesting?
Speaker 1: like we were shocked.
Speaker 1: we scheduled like four panels like Thursday afternoon and evening.
Speaker 1: There was a surprising number of people who showed up by surprising.
Speaker 1: We mean five Like 40 or 50.
Speaker 0: I didn't see that many.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you did.
Speaker 1: you were there.
Speaker 1: we counted them together.
Speaker 1: We remarked on how crazy it was that there were so many people.
Speaker 1: I even have the spreadsheet with the numbers and our notes.
Speaker 0: some sad people.
Speaker 1: You were off by a full order of magnitude.
Speaker 0: Also a lot of those people weren't people.
Speaker 0: they're so sad Alright.
Speaker 1: Alright goalpost mover.
Speaker 1: We did one of those panels.
Speaker 0: I Thought we bailed on it.
Speaker 0: No, we did it.
Speaker 0: I don't remember this weed now.
Speaker 0: I remember being in this room and there are a few people and I was like, holy fuck.
Speaker 0: Why is anyone here?
Speaker 0: Did everyone leave Jesus people?
Speaker 1: there were like 40 people whatever.
Speaker 0: anyway Don't go to convention on Thursday.
Speaker 0: It's not like it's pegs.
Speaker 1: Can I count is pretty fun.
Speaker 1: The schedules must be up mostly up online.
Speaker 1: the font for the schedule I got nothing to do with.
Speaker 1: do not come to me with that.
Speaker 1: that is Outside of my control on this convention.
Speaker 1: All I do is schedule all the panels.
Speaker 1: I do not do anything else.
Speaker 1: So if you have any complaint about anything you can add account.
Speaker 1: that is not.
Speaker 1: why didn't you schedule a panel on X?
Speaker 0: Go to someone.
Speaker 0: answer to that is cuz it sucked.
Speaker 1: No, the answer to that is because no one submitted anything.
Speaker 1: also like kind of interesting.
Speaker 1: No one submitted anything related to ponies like at all.
Speaker 0: like that's gone I think I haven't even watched the news season to ponies at all.
Speaker 1: I watched a couple episodes.
Speaker 1: It's going.
Speaker 1: it's steady-state entertaining but Not as good as continuing adventure time.
Speaker 0: I also got when what's the newest adventure time?
Speaker 1: There's been a bunch shits gonna.
Speaker 1: do you know what happened to Finn sword?
Speaker 1: the Finn sword?
Speaker 1: Maybe the one that is Finn?
Speaker 0: I Remember seeing something happened to it.
Speaker 1: something happened to it.
Speaker 0: I don't know how new that is though.
Speaker 0: Did something else happen?
Speaker 1: Alright, uh, did anything happen with the crown?
Speaker 1: Did anyone go inside the crown?
Speaker 0: Inside of it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, your name stole it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you're way behind on adventure time.
Speaker 1: Adventure time, you know I like Steven Universe but adventure time has gone on so much longer and is still like the freshest show Like it just never gets stale and I'm curious if they're gonna keep that up.
Speaker 1: Hmm But yeah pony stuff not represented.
Speaker 1: old people only submitted undertale because I asked him to.
Speaker 1: There was like two people submitted.
Speaker 1: Dr.
Speaker 1: Who things There was still a Hetalia.
Speaker 1: ask a nation, but only one.
Speaker 1: Like the Hetalia stuff mostly disappeared.
Speaker 1: there was a ton of homestuck submission still but they were all ask a homestuck.
Speaker 1: Literally not one of them looked like it was actually a panel.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm and otherwise Most of the submissions that I got cuz remember while it's a pretty big con It's a generic con like it's one of the few cons.
Speaker 1: That is all the stuff and is pretty big.
Speaker 1: I'd say it was about a third anime submissions and Almost everything else was gaming related.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm like gaming is the primary thing.
Speaker 1: anyone submits panels for now other than cosplay and I suspect that's because gaming cons traditionally didn't have a lot of panels and Pack sort of changed that and now there's a lot of gaming panels.
Speaker 0: I mean people also.
Speaker 0: everyone plays games, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah It's like the universal nerdery But like for whatever reason gaming culture has a big panel making component.
Speaker 1: That is second only to the anime culture.
Speaker 1: But the anime fans.
Speaker 1: I have a lot more anime cons that are Less professional or lower level enough to accept their like.
Speaker 1: I I'm a punk kid wanting to a panel.
Speaker 1: There aren't as many gaming cons that will accept the punk kid who wants to do a panel.
Speaker 1: So as a result all those gaming panels that are like mid-tier are ending up at conventions like kinetic on which is interesting.
Speaker 1: A lot of them look pretty good actually.
Speaker 1: But I think more panels were submitted about gaming than any other topic and of those I think it was a 50/50 split between tabletop and video.
Speaker 1: Otherwise, the book load book will be Margaret Atwood's Oryx and Crake gonna read it soon.
Speaker 1: I am in the last hundred pages of the Wheel of Time.
Speaker 1: Andral busted out.
Speaker 1: He did the thing and it was pretty good.
Speaker 1: I know you don't know who that is.
Speaker 1: Do you remember anyone from the Wheel of Time?
Speaker 0: Ran.
Speaker 1: Rand Altor.
Speaker 1: anyone else?
Speaker 0: Luz Theron.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: All right, that's still only one person.
Speaker 0: Dark one.
Speaker 1: Who is the dark one?
Speaker 1: What is the dark one?
Speaker 1: What's the dark one's name?
Speaker 0: Dark one?
Speaker 0: Nah Shaitan.
Speaker 0: Oh, right.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that was the girl who is basically the ridiculously powerful and trying to hit on Ran and Land.
Speaker 0: fear?
Speaker 0: Yeah, that one.
Speaker 1: Wow, skipped a lot.
Speaker 1: there didn't even bring up like Perrin or Tam Althor or Tom Marilyn.
Speaker 0: Well, I'm just talking about the cool characters.
Speaker 1: Tom's not cool.
Speaker 0: He's alright.
Speaker 0: He's like the best.
Speaker 0: Well, I mean you love the spoony bard.
Speaker 1: He's an angry old spoony bard Retired spoony bard.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm not.
Speaker 0: I'm more into the you know, the Luz Theron types.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, the Luz Theron stuff's pretty good later on.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, I'm done with that crap real soon.
Speaker 1: and then we're gonna read Oryx and Crake.
Speaker 0: Oh, actually, my favorite my favorite dude was the the ancient king of Man of Theron.
Speaker 0: That's my guy.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, I think part of his brain is inside of Matt.
Speaker 1: Yeah, yeah shit went down.
Speaker 1: Yeah, um, otherwise the patreon is going strong.
Speaker 1: people are like people seem to really dig it and put stuff in there.
Speaker 0: Make it weaker we can.
Speaker 1: uh, I'm working on the chicken surprise shirts sometime this by the end of the summer.
Speaker 1: That's gonna happen.
Speaker 1: It's looking pretty good.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah Well, I'm gonna get him for the people who want them first And then I'm gonna try to get a license a legit licensing agreement with the game designer.
Speaker 1: be like look Do you remember this game you made?
Speaker 1: I sell chicken surprise shirts officially Because I think I think I could sell dozens of them maybe total.
Speaker 1: So yeah bringing it back how to not suck.
Speaker 1: We used to give a lot more advice on geek nights and we kind of stopped over the years.
Speaker 0: and you know what our advice Then is probably bad advice compared to now because we're older and smarter now.
Speaker 0: So what I would actually get smarter when you're older, right?
Speaker 0: That's not.
Speaker 0: I mean.
Speaker 0: when I was younger I said old people were dumb and I still say that.
Speaker 0: but whatever age I am is the age when people are the smartest.
Speaker 1: You know what is.
Speaker 1: you don't get smarter.
Speaker 1: In fact, you kind of objectively get dumber But you get a wiser or at least you should get wiser.
Speaker 1: A lot of people don't get wiser.
Speaker 1: you can tell those people when once they hit their 30s Suddenly they stop upgrading all their shit like whatever phone they used when they hit 30.
Speaker 1: They just use that kind of phone forever.
Speaker 1: Like they're why should I upgrade?
Speaker 1: Why would I care?
Speaker 1: Like if a new website comes out like a new social media thing after they turn 30, they will never use it.
Speaker 0: No I'm not using the snapchats.
Speaker 1: I'm not using the snapchats either.
Speaker 1: The I've already used the snapchat some dumbass kid who doesn't know better.
Speaker 1: But what I'd kind of like to do is we should take one of those old how to not suck episodes do that topic again now and then just post both episodes side by side and there will be objective evidence of Whether or not we were dumber back then or dumb now.
Speaker 0: I mean, we're gonna agree more with whatever we say now no matter what.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but other people will see the two.
Speaker 1: like if we give completely different advice on like how to get a job ten years ago Versus now that would be very interesting.
Speaker 1: Mmm, but we have to make sure we don't ever go back and listen to those episodes.
Speaker 1: Are we tainting?
Speaker 0: That's definitely not a concern.
Speaker 1: Hey, I gotta listen to those beta episodes.
Speaker 1: I'm remastering the third one right now.
Speaker 0: Holy my concern.
Speaker 1: Holy hell Guys, at least we're gonna get the radio Shaq microphone soon.
Speaker 1: It'll get a little easier.
Speaker 0: So how to not suck at what?
Speaker 1: Throw in a party hosting guests all that nonsense we See like.
Speaker 1: I don't go to as many parties or gatherings as I used to because college like very different situation.
Speaker 1: But I see time and time again the same mistakes the same problems.
Speaker 1: A lot of people really suck at inviting groups of people into their house To have a party let alone suck at like.
Speaker 1: hey, let's have a holiday party Let's have like a holiday a party around a specific event.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so many.
Speaker 0: I mean there's so much differences that go on based on the level of party and what kind of party.
Speaker 0: but I Guess started the beginning with that invite part, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So how do you invite people, right?
Speaker 0: So obviously if it's a fancier party you got to mail the invitations And if it's less than that, you can just email people or whatever or call them individually or something.
Speaker 1: So something interesting.
Speaker 1: ask them individually in person for an invite party like a wedding in particular Culture says you have to send like I'll save the date and then you have to like mail people.
Speaker 1: these RSVP things.
Speaker 1: Practice shows that nobody under the age of like 35 will ever Send that envelope back and you just call them all.
Speaker 1: anyway be like you're coming to my wedding right in the envelope bag.
Speaker 1: I don't think I've ever sent one of those envelopes back.
Speaker 0: You're the bad person then.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I am.
Speaker 0: I always said in the envelope back.
Speaker 0: Here's your asshole.
Speaker 0: if you don't I think most everyone sends it back except you.
Speaker 0: You're not You're the one you you think I got.
Speaker 0: no one sends these back.
Speaker 0: No, you're the fucking hassle.
Speaker 0: who doesn't?
Speaker 1: certain unnamed people who had weddings in the last ten years Confided in me that something like a third or more of people did not send the envelope back.
Speaker 1: Like it's not just me who doesn't send the envelope back still send the fucking envelope back.
Speaker 0: But also the main thing with the invitation right is you?
Speaker 0: there's two concerns no matter what party it is Right.
Speaker 0: concern number one who to invite you need to prioritize the people not you know, don't invite people who don't mix.
Speaker 0: Well, yeah all that kind of stuff right?
Speaker 0: don't invite the people you don't like.
Speaker 0: Make sure they don't find out the party's happening.
Speaker 0: Wait, wait hot.
Speaker 1: take any any party any gathering that has any invitation process more formal than hey You want to come to my place on this date?
Speaker 1: You're almost definitely doing it that way because you are inviting people.
Speaker 1: You don't actually want to be there.
Speaker 1: Yeah, because it's always a wedding right funeral.
Speaker 0: Don't send out invitations for a funeral.
Speaker 1: You tell people when the funeral is the day after they die.
Speaker 1: Uh, you're Jewish.
Speaker 1: most people don't do it that way.
Speaker 0: All right, right, right.
Speaker 0: Yeah Right, so the other concern with the invitations is the main purpose of the invitation is not what you think it is.
Speaker 0: It just let the person know you want them to come.
Speaker 0: it's to remind them of when it fucking is because they're gonna be like.
Speaker 0: Oh, right.
Speaker 0: There was that party today and everyone's partying and the person's not there.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you need to.
Speaker 1: somehow you're getting married today.
Speaker 0: Right, you need to get if you you want this person to come they want to come but they will fail to come even if they're usually have their shit together unless you make sure that the thing is on their calendar and on their schedule and they Remember to come.
Speaker 0: like I'm like I have like my whole calendar and all shit in order all the time.
Speaker 0: Like I'm super good about that.
Speaker 0: But if you don't if you invite me to a thing and like I don't remember if it's not on my calendar Like there have been times where it's like oh shit that's this weekend.
Speaker 1: Oh snap now, this is more of.
Speaker 1: this is separate advice.
Speaker 1: This is more advice of how to live your life.
Speaker 1: You probably have a gmail account.
Speaker 1: use the fucking calendar.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like know when stuff is but if you're hosting a party like this might sound dumb You might feel like isn't that like a?
Speaker 1: no if you are going to do something literally send your friends a calendar invite.
Speaker 0: Yeah, do something.
Speaker 0: make sure you know.
Speaker 0: Basically your goal is to make sure that the people mark it off on their schedule and remember to come.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you got to give them the date the location the time all that stuff now.
Speaker 1: Actually, I think the other.
Speaker 1: Well, there's another one more thing Which the other is if you're sent if you're formally inviting people to a thing Then it's sort of like saying this is my thing.
Speaker 1: I am responsible.
Speaker 1: It is a party as opposed to people are coming over which means you've got to feed them.
Speaker 0: Well, no, I mean one other aspect of the invitation Which is sort of like the addendum to the invitation is you have to let people know what to expect, right?
Speaker 0: It's like, you know, you are going to have to get a hotel, you know You are going to have to wear black tie Bring food.
Speaker 0: You will not have to bring food.
Speaker 0: You'll have to bring fucking money.
Speaker 0: Bring a gun You know, whatever you need.
Speaker 0: let the people know what they're gonna need.
Speaker 0: Otherwise people show up and like I didn't bring any board games.
Speaker 0: No one has a spot it here.
Speaker 0: What the fuck?
Speaker 1: Yep, it implies that there is structure to your event.
Speaker 1: now unstructured events are possible But that's a whole separate kind of party.
Speaker 1: We'll talk about that later.
Speaker 1: I'm about structured parties here.
Speaker 0: So please moderate amount of structure.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like if you if you send someone an invitation That's probably a party where they expect.
Speaker 1: when they show up There's gonna be like snacks and drinks and stuff and at some point dinner will appear.
Speaker 1: if you invite people semi-formally to a thing like you're the kind of person who doesn't normally do big social things and You don't even make it very clear.
Speaker 1: Like I'm not feeding you I guarantee your friends might not complain to your face.
Speaker 1: Why didn't you feed me?
Speaker 1: but they're pissed.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they're mad that you didn't feed him.
Speaker 1: They expected you to feed them.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they traveled right there in your house or whatever or at your venue and they're there during dinnertime and they're partying.
Speaker 0: They're not expecting to leave the party and get food or call for their own delivery.
Speaker 0: And then so if there's no dinner It's how we're all hungry.
Speaker 0: and now because we're hungry.
Speaker 0: We're hangry.
Speaker 1: Yep, and Even worse if you like if you're a hose like you're hosting the party You're gonna have less fun than everyone else because you got to do all that sort of host stuff.
Speaker 1: So like it sounds like kind of minor advice But for real when people come over in this sort of thing after they've been in your house for a couple minutes You should ask them.
Speaker 1: Would you like anything to drink?
Speaker 1: Would you?
Speaker 1: would you like a snack?
Speaker 1: Would you like some food or have it all out somewhere where it's very obvious that hey take one of these things if you're hungry You're thirsty.
Speaker 1: Well, otherwise your friends are sitting around in your house thinking to themselves man.
Speaker 1: I'm really thirsty.
Speaker 1: Should I ask him for a drink?
Speaker 1: Can I just open his fridge?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I just open people's fridges.
Speaker 0: I don't have that feeling like I see other people do have that.
Speaker 0: and But like I'll.
Speaker 0: you know, sometimes I remember to ask them but you about half the time I don't.
Speaker 0: because if I'm in someone's house, I'll just go and I'll just if I need water I just go and start looking for cups and getting water, you know It's like I don't.
Speaker 1: well that brings up a very important point because there's there are two very very different kinds of parties because what we've been talking about to this point is how a typical person throws a party who doesn't Run a regular basis have their friends staying at their house.
Speaker 1: the kinds of parties we throw almost exclusively are Hey all our friends come to our house this weekend.
Speaker 1: Everyone's gonna sleep on the floor in like sleeping bags and pajamas.
Speaker 1: and Just you're just in my house.
Speaker 1: Like take every tip.
Speaker 1: everyone assume take whatever you want for the fridge Like we're all real close friends and family like.
Speaker 1: no there is no Formality to it in that degree.
Speaker 1: like if I show up at one of our friends houses I probably just go straight into their kitchen and take something out of their fridge And I think someone goes in my fridge is I don't care as long as they don't mess it up.
Speaker 1: And if you don't throw parties like that at a regular basis or at least a semi regular basis or at least go to parties Like that I think you need to make closer friends before you hit your 30s or you're gonna be in for a Rude awakening of not having a lot to do and going to very boring Stilted parties among a bunch of adults who aren't really close friends anymore Sitting around a table that has a bunch of like bags of chips open the picking at
Speaker 0: and then everyone has to go home late Because you know and sleeping there.
Speaker 1: Yeah Uh, so yeah Really just.
Speaker 1: I guess this all comes down to.
Speaker 1: you have to set the expectations for what the party is.
Speaker 1: If you have a close friend group, that's probably implicit.
Speaker 1: If you don't have a close friend group You've got to give a fucking timeline of like at four o'clock.
Speaker 1: The catering is going to arrive.
Speaker 1: Bring like you bring beer you bring snacks.
Speaker 1: You don't bring anything.
Speaker 1: You always bring garbage And very specifically tell your friends unless you told them to bring something Do not bring anything.
Speaker 1: your friends are gonna bring the worst snacks the cheapest crappiest bags of chips that they literally bought at a bodega On their way to your house.
Speaker 1: They're gonna bring a six-pack of beer that you will never drink Mm-hmm that you do not want.
Speaker 1: the only bottles of awful liquor I have that I either threw away or gave away to someone because Someone unnamed literally just brought it to our house and put it on the table.
Speaker 0: people always bring some nasty chip.
Speaker 0: That's the kind that I don't eat.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: It's like Tostitos covered in schmutz Some kind like nope.
Speaker 0: I don't eat that and then no one eats it and then it's there.
Speaker 0: Yeah and then everyone leaves and it's still there.
Speaker 0: cuz they don't want to take that shit home.
Speaker 1: like we had a big party at that Waterfall house upstate and even though our friends were very organized like we had a spreadsheet and again guys That's I mean, there's a such thing as going too far.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Well, I'm gonna get to that If you have a gathering that's more than a few days or is more than like ten people.
Speaker 1: You actually should plan it like literally I'm not joking make a spreadsheet and Organize shit like who's responsible for bringing stuff if anyone is or pay money and just make all that go away?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'm usually a fan of the paying money just sort of spontaneous.
Speaker 0: Like what are we gonna do for dinner tonight?
Speaker 0: All right money.
Speaker 1: it happens Yeah you see you are a fan of that.
Speaker 1: but at the same time the only reason most of our big gatherings have gone smoothly is because Someone else actually did plan all that.
Speaker 1: because if you have 20 people and someone says hey, let's order food You know your friends especially if this is a party where people who aren't close friends are you know like that guy you kind of know from work is gonna be like I don't want any pepperoni and someone else is gonna be like I only eat pepperoni, right?
Speaker 0: So, you know what I say?
Speaker 0: All right us for getting pizza.
Speaker 0: the rest of you just do whatever you do.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's party goer.
Speaker 1: advice of bail on whatever the party is doing and fend for yourself.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if I show up to a stranger party, I have a plan.
Speaker 1: This is the Scott party.
Speaker 0: It's everyone.
Speaker 0: fend for yourself the party and you know that in advance I got.
Speaker 1: I got bailout plans.
Speaker 1: Like if the party sucks, how do I make an excuse to get the fuck out of here?
Speaker 1: If the party is boring do I have a plan to make it not boring?
Speaker 1: if I don't I have a plan to get the Fuck out of there.
Speaker 1: I have a plan to get food in case food is not at the party.
Speaker 1: I have a plan to call the police in case it's that kind of party.
Speaker 0: Don't need a plan to call the police just do it.
Speaker 1: Like if you show up and Oh party.
Speaker 0: No, I meant posse Rims driving up to your house and he's like, okay Let me make a list of things that I'll do and I'll call the cops.
Speaker 0: for if I see There's not much on that list, but there are things on that list The same things that are on the list all the time.
Speaker 1: but this was a big party that involved like multiple friend groups mashing together and Because we were staying in a remote place ordering food was not an option.
Speaker 1: So we had to plan who was gonna cook in what we planned it real well The problem is your friends are all morons.
Speaker 1: So even though there is a spreadsheet that was shared with everyone and everyone has Google.
Speaker 1: you can log in.
Speaker 1: you can look at the Spreadsheet.
Speaker 1: it says you bring this thing and that is what you were supposed to bring.
Speaker 1: do not bring more.
Speaker 1: You need to remind your stupid friends who are coming to your party on a daily basis not to bring shit or they're gonna bring Shit, I think we had you already talked about brings four times the amount of food we needed despite having the spreadsheet.
Speaker 0: Hmm All right.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Hmm.
Speaker 0: So now once you're at the party and everyone's brought their shit You got to do stuff at the party up.
Speaker 1: if you run a party you are Responsible for everyone's fun.
Speaker 1: Like if you don't want to be responsible for that You should not host a party.
Speaker 0: people will just default to sit around play video game watch YouTube play board game Poke their phone do their own thing unless somebody you know organizes and says, all right We are doing this thing it is happening.
Speaker 0: So, you know based on the scenario, you know, that might be someone else But usually it's your party.
Speaker 0: You're running it it.
Speaker 0: that's your Responsibility for at least the major thing to be.
Speaker 0: you know, like maybe you're all gonna go to a nearby.
Speaker 0: fair, you know It's like okay, we're gonna go at this time.
Speaker 0: Here's how to get there.
Speaker 0: This is when we're going.
Speaker 0: we're gonna be you know Yep, and it's if you're gonna.
Speaker 0: if you have any you got to be like, okay You have to actually get up and be like, okay people let's go Get out.
Speaker 1: if you're gonna have a party that involves events or like significant activities You can have one of those per day and one optional less complicated thing.
Speaker 1: That is the absolute maximum.
Speaker 1: Yep If you try to do more than that in a given day on a party or a weekend or anything It is going to be disaster.
Speaker 1: unless your job is literally make all this happen and you yourself have no fun.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm I cannot stress that enough.
Speaker 1: That is like the mistake everyone makes up.
Speaker 1: Yeah in the morning Let's all go get brunch together, which already nope You can't get a restaurant for 20 people and now it's one o'clock.
Speaker 1: then we're all gonna go to the haunted house at 7.
Speaker 1: So before we do that, let's go downtown and like wander around through all the shops.
Speaker 0: you get out of town.
Speaker 0: You're not gonna make it to the haunted house by 7.
Speaker 1: Yep, half your party's gonna say fuck it on the shops go straight to the haunted house The other half your party's gonna get lost downtown.
Speaker 1: You won't see him again until that night.
Speaker 1: Some people are gonna say wow, this is too complicated bail on everything.
Speaker 0: It would be theoretically possible for one person to go to the shops get in their car go to the haunted house.
Speaker 0: All right, you know, but when you're with these basically when you're with more people Everything slows down and takes longer.
Speaker 1: for every four people you have in addition to yourself and your close fast walking fast friends.
Speaker 1: Assume that it'll take like 20% more time to do Literally Anything right like even it.
Speaker 0: let's say it's me and rim right and we're gonna go see a movie.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right.
Speaker 0: So we separately take the subway arrive at the movie on time watch the movie and then separately leave.
Speaker 0: That's basically instant speed.
Speaker 1: Yep So now we're now.
Speaker 0: but now we got a different situation me and Rimmer at a party and me and rim together with no one Else are gonna go to the movie.
Speaker 0: right.
Speaker 0: both of us together is slower than both of us separate.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's just how it is.
Speaker 0: It won't be that much slower to be so really fast because we're both really high speeds.
Speaker 0: But it'll still be slower.
Speaker 1: But like alright now we've got 12 people and we're gonna go to the shops before go to the haunted house.
Speaker 1: Well one half the people don't actually want to go to the shops.
Speaker 0: That's also true.
Speaker 1: They're only going along to socialize and that's all they want.
Speaker 1: Yeah of the half who want to be at the shops a few of them are gonna spend way too much time in the shops and A few of them are gonna want to go to different shops and split off.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm getting the party back together Will take like a half hour And also it does.
Speaker 1: it's not even just in the city It's anywhere.
Speaker 1: the the every two or three or four people you add means another car in the suburbs Which means now there's six cars all driving to the place.
Speaker 0: But now you had to spend.
Speaker 0: even if you're gonna go somewhere you lose ten minutes just discussing who's going in what car and which?
Speaker 0: Car is going where and then oh this these people need to go to the ATM.
Speaker 0: So that car is making a little you know detour.
Speaker 1: Oh car four is not a gas that sucks.
Speaker 0: This car needs to go to a walla to get some snacks and this car needs to do this and you know who's going in That one.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you keep you're not you're losing time constantly with every.
Speaker 1: I mean hell.
Speaker 1: remember way back We all a bunch of us all plan to go to an Otacon and we had like four cars.
Speaker 1: One of the cars refused to speed on the freeway.
Speaker 1: So they we lost them forever.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm, cuz they would only go 55 never else.
Speaker 0: They got their hours after us.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like three hours later.
Speaker 1: Yep so I This is you might think.
Speaker 1: Oh, don't worry.
Speaker 1: I made some buffer time.
Speaker 1: No, you didn't know you didn't.
Speaker 1: almost everyone I know is terrible at this.
Speaker 1: It's just a human nature is to underestimate the pain in the ass of dealing with a few more people in your group.
Speaker 1: So like for every four people assume an extra half-hour buffer time maybe for everything Which means if you have any number of people you cannot do more than one thing in a day.
Speaker 1: and that's it Like.
Speaker 1: that's the golden rule.
Speaker 0: never deviate from that unless you are a professional All right, so now you know your party's winding down.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I've got to get people to go home.
Speaker 0: you should offer them tea.
Speaker 1: Would you like me to roll out the beds?
Speaker 1: Yeah, should I?
Speaker 1: shall I arrange a hotel room for the night?
Speaker 1: Shall I call into work for you.
Speaker 1: Would you like to hand them a lease?
Speaker 0: But little Airbnb.
Speaker 1: It's real easy If this is a formal party where there's people there who aren't close friends well in advance say this is when the party ends and Wrap it up.
Speaker 1: Like don't try to be passive-aggressive about it.
Speaker 1: No one's smart enough to pick up on the social cues and more importantly the people are overstaying.
Speaker 1: They're welcome They see the cues.
Speaker 1: They're actively resisting because they're lonely.
Speaker 1: Like not even joking that guy.
Speaker 1: you kind of know at work who's at your house and it's 11 And you really want the party to end.
Speaker 1: he's hanging out because they got nothing to do back home.
Speaker 0: There needs to be some sort of clear ending time, even if it's like a big fancy party with like a band and shit Right.
Speaker 0: It's like they have like.
Speaker 0: okay guys, you know you play let's dance.
Speaker 0: Yeah last dance That's actually the last dance.
Speaker 0: That's why they have that song.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's why it exists.
Speaker 1: Like you might think you can be clever and sort of socially finagulate.
Speaker 1: You're probably not clever enough to do that.
Speaker 1: So make sure there's a defined end and if it's your actual friends just be blunt.
Speaker 1: Just be like guys.
Speaker 1: I gotta go to bed.
Speaker 1: get the fuck out of my house.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and if you're the real if they're real friends, they're totally okay with that.
Speaker 1: That is how I end almost every party guys.
Speaker 1: I'm going to fucking bed.
Speaker 1: It's like 4 a.m.
Speaker 1: Jesus.
Speaker 1: Fuck go away.
Speaker 0: You guys do whatever.
Speaker 0: I'm going to bed.
Speaker 1: Yep, either get out of my house or if they're actually close friends I'm going to bed.
Speaker 1: Just don't leave the door unlocked If you're.
Speaker 1: if your close friends are not that close you need closer friends In terms of food and catering and all that.
Speaker 1: If you're going to pay for catering I Kind of recommend you pay for catering.
Speaker 1: don't think you can cook food for everybody.
Speaker 1: you probably can.
Speaker 1: there's a big difference between cooking a Dinner for four or five people cooking a dinner for your family where dinners an hour late And that's just what happens and cooking dinner for a bunch of people or someone's been cooking at dinner all day for your family and Thanksgiving.
Speaker 1: Yep, you might have some friends who are like we'll take care of dinner which in our group is often the case.
Speaker 0: like there are Certain of our don't expect to play a board game with any of those people on that whole day Yep, but they'll have fun.
Speaker 1: Like they'll be in the kitchen like doing.
Speaker 1: they're like.
Speaker 0: I hope if someone offers to cook that they like doing it.
Speaker 0: That would be weird If you said I'll cook dinner, I hate fucking cooking These assholes, they're all having fun and I'm cooking.
Speaker 0: it's like I offered to cook.
Speaker 0: Why did I do that?
Speaker 1: Yep, like so pro tip I'm complaining.
Speaker 0: I'm doing a thing that I volunteered to do.
Speaker 1: Here's the pro tip.
Speaker 1: if you're having a party where there's a grill and someone's gonna be cooking meat That's actually gonna be a job all night Usually be constantly cooking meat
Speaker 0: because the meat you basically can't if you have any significant number of people unless you have a monstrous grill Or
Speaker 1: you can lower safety.
Speaker 0: You cannot grill faster than people can eat what you were grilling.
Speaker 1: Yep All right.
Speaker 1: So this is where you cheat.
Speaker 1: This is like pro tip.
Speaker 0: You need to get like you ever go to like one of those public barbecues and they have like tons of grills lined up and then You're still waiting for food.
Speaker 0: Yeah It's like people can eat a burger way way faster than it takes to cook one and they want a second like in a Lauren Scojo party.
Speaker 1: like someone right now someone will come out and be like, hey the burgers are done and by the burgers They mean literally as many burgers as could fit on that grill.
Speaker 1: They're gone before you can get upstairs to the grill.
Speaker 0: It's actually what I suggest doing and Some people might not like this is you know You let you have your grill.
Speaker 0: you grill some meats.
Speaker 0: people eat them.
Speaker 0: you girls some meats people eat them.
Speaker 0: if you're eating like these Waves and actually takes long to eat Grill and even though your grill is small just put those meats to the side and don't let anyone fucking eat them.
Speaker 0: Right and then wait until you've grilled everything and then let people eat and you say won't those first burgers be cold?
Speaker 0: Maybe but maybe you can heat them up to keep them in a warm place like near the grill or in a warm oven.
Speaker 0: That's like, you know, right.
Speaker 0: I think there's strategies you can use to serve everyone at once and then Because once you start serving food everyone enters food mode, right and there's their hangry because you didn't give enough snack, right?
Speaker 0: So they can't really be enjoying themselves like playing a board game once food mode is activated But only some of the people are eating and now food mode is on for hours until the grill is finally empty.
Speaker 0: what you can do is You can let people keep enjoying themselves playing games and whatnot because they're not in food mode yet.
Speaker 0: and then you activate food But everyone eats simultaneously and finished eating something.
Speaker 1: you ring a bell soups on every pony.
Speaker 1: Let's go.
Speaker 0: they finish eating and then they go cleaning and then back to enjoying.
Speaker 1: and if you provide enough snacks People won't be so hangry that they start freaking out about when's the burger gonna be ready?
Speaker 1: They'll be like, oh cool food and they won't rush it, right?
Speaker 0: So the final thing I just mentioned.
Speaker 1: so I got the cleaning everything you said there.
Speaker 1: There's a more pro move.
Speaker 1: I've seen Laura and scojo like at their parties do this to a tee and some of you go to those parties and listen.
Speaker 1: You're gonna see what's happening.
Speaker 1: And if one of you was fooled by this now You'll see through the gnosis.
Speaker 1: a lot of people who don't go to a lot of parties or who just you know For various reasons they kind of want to like have something to do with the party.
Speaker 1: They want to be like the grill master because that feels like when you were a kid Like.
Speaker 1: you see the dad cooking the grill and you're like, man, I want to be that someday.
Speaker 0: No, you don't get to have any fun doing that.
Speaker 1: you want to go do something else so you provide snacks and all that.
Speaker 1: But then you'd be like, hey who wants to man the grill?
Speaker 1: who wants to run the grill?
Speaker 1: not some other schmuck to run the grill and do the waves and leave them there for the rest of the night and there'll Rotation of schmucks who will be making all the food at the grill and you can just leave the grill alone.
Speaker 1: It'll take care of it.
Speaker 0: if you invited schmucks sure?
Speaker 1: Yeah, well, he's cleaning is?
Speaker 1: it is there.
Speaker 1: they're they're they're they're marks.
Speaker 1: That's what they are.
Speaker 0: No matter how close the first person is a friend to you No matter how neat and tidy like their houses, right?
Speaker 0: They're gonna goth the fuck up out of your house.
Speaker 1: They're gonna break at least two glasses.
Speaker 1: No matter they're gonna break your shit.
Speaker 0: They're gonna mess your shit up.
Speaker 0: So here's how to prevent them from messing up your shit.
Speaker 0: You know maximally you can actually get things a little bit cleaner, right?
Speaker 1: So as an aside make sure you cannot resent them.
Speaker 1: That's how parties go right.
Speaker 0: rule number one.
Speaker 0: Fuck the environment.
Speaker 0: disposable everything Yeah, but you just don't want to fuck the environment completely.
Speaker 0: what we do and it seems to work pretty well Is you?
Speaker 0: it works at packs.
Speaker 0: also you have a plastic cup and you write your name on it with a sharpie.
Speaker 0: You put the sharpies near the cups more than one of them and everyone writes their name on a cup with a sharpie.
Speaker 0: And now sure someone might go for a second cup if they change beverages or something.
Speaker 0: But they're gonna write their name on that too.
Speaker 0: And if you see cups around the house with names on them that haven't been reused or clean or disposed of properly You know, you can call that fucking person out like, you know rim you got this half-drunken.
Speaker 0: Dr.
Speaker 0: Pepper over here.
Speaker 0: What the fuck.
Speaker 0: how long has this been here?
Speaker 0: an hour and you actually get you know.
Speaker 0: And as you call one person out and everyone else will get their shit in line.
Speaker 1: Except I don't think they will because I Take inventory.
Speaker 1: because we because one thing if you have a dishwasher That helps enormously.
Speaker 1: if you have a dishwasher use real stuff for glasses and drinking.
Speaker 1: maybe use plastic disposable for plates and things because you can wash a lot of Glasses in a hurry in a dishwasher.
Speaker 1: as long as you turn on that mode You never turn on depends on the number of people you got.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the heated dry.
Speaker 1: You got to turn that on.
Speaker 0: That's I don't like the heated room was worried about like my plastic.
Speaker 1: Well, yeah, you only use the heated dry if you're doing a party situation and you're just filling with glassware constantly.
Speaker 1: Maybe that's like the number one use case for heated dry.
Speaker 1: Anyway, but your friends are going to leave so many half-drunk beverages around your apartment.
Speaker 1: like you I don't know why this happens.
Speaker 1: I don't know how but forever.
Speaker 0: I mean if I pour beverage I usually drink the whole thing immediately and then it's an empty cup.
Speaker 0: I have to carry around and like fuck.
Speaker 1: I don't know why you even use cups.
Speaker 0: Cuz.
Speaker 0: I was like you drink right ahead of the pitcher.
Speaker 1: Yeah, just drain it you're done.
Speaker 1: But if you're gonna serve alcohol my advice to you is very specific either have bottles of beer and just leave it at that or if there's gonna be cocktails do Not let people make their own cocktails from your liquor cabinet.
Speaker 1: They're going to one.
Speaker 1: They're gonna ruin all your expensive liquor Waste it and not drink it.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: They're gonna make cocktails, but most people suck at making cocktails.
Speaker 1: They're gonna make cocktails that aren't that good and then they're gonna leave them out and not drink them and then they make another cocktail.
Speaker 1: That sucks.
Speaker 1: if you're going to have booze at your party either pick a few trusted friends or yourself and they make everyone's drinks or Leave out the things to make a few drinks like a very limited set like a limited set of tools and put a piece of Paper that's laminated next to it that says here are the exact recipes to make these two cocktails.
Speaker 0: Another thing you can do is in you know, you can basically lock or hide the cabinet of you know equipment.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and you make.
Speaker 0: you know get like your 10 martini glasses and make 10 whatevers.
Speaker 0: Yep Right and then it's like or like you do a champagne, right?
Speaker 0: You don't give someone the champagne valve that go nuts, right?
Speaker 0: You pour a bunch of champagnes.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you give everyone a glass.
Speaker 1: now those same rules can apply to regular non-alcoholic beverages Like if you've got fancy juices, you're gonna make stuff be like, alright Who wants a glass of like ice cranberry something?
Speaker 1: and then everyone who says that you just make like 10 of them all in a Row.
Speaker 1: don't let people make their own stuff.
Speaker 1: It's okay if it's in cans or bottles But as soon as they're pouring They're gonna leave half-drunk garbage all over the place and they're gonna mix monstrosities that they themselves won't drink.
Speaker 0: I think this is at least part of the reason why like, you know Japanese people they always pour the sake for the other person can't pour your own.
Speaker 1: Yep Well, that also means that if you're getting drunk, it's harder to pour your own.
Speaker 0: At least that's the number one reason I'm saying this is a one of the reasons.
Speaker 1: Yeah you if you if you want to get drunk in that situation like if you're that kind of person you at least need to find Someone else who themselves wants to get drunk and is willing to enable you.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it raises the bar of getting drunk in terms of drinking and drunk people.
Speaker 1: There's gonna be some of your friends.
Speaker 1: They're gonna drink too much alcohol and be dumb.
Speaker 0: Don't be friends with them.
Speaker 0: Yep Pretty much like they have a problem.
Speaker 0: Let them know.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like don't let your friends get stupid drunk at parties reliable and definitely don't let them drive you.
Speaker 1: No But like if there's a friend of yours who gets way too drunk at parties on a regular basis They're gonna bargo like.
Speaker 1: they obviously get too drunk to where they can't really interact like every party.
Speaker 0: Yeah, yeah talk to them like.
Speaker 1: that's.
Speaker 1: that's intervention time.
Speaker 1: It's one thing if someone gets too drunk at one party but if they're too drunk at three parties in a row, like I'm not even joking like Figure out a way to deal with that's just.
Speaker 0: that's life problems not party problems.
Speaker 1: Yeah But parties are the best way for you to see that happening because if you are hosting a party You cannot get that drunk because you're responsible for the party.
Speaker 1: So you will have that like even if like in our group luckily a lot of people don't drink.
Speaker 1: So we have a good mix of.
Speaker 1: you know Scott who has no alcohol in him you as a little all the way out to certain unnamed people who have a lot of alcohol.
Speaker 1: But at typical parties everyone's pretty drunk which kind of sucks.
Speaker 1: that's bad.
Speaker 0: Does they know?
Speaker 0: if there's trouble no one can do anything about it.
Speaker 1: But if you're hosting a party you need to be not drunk so that one you can you know.
Speaker 1: Make the party happen.
Speaker 0: man if the cops show up and every single person is drunk Who's gonna be the reasonable person to talk to them?
Speaker 0: Nobody?
Speaker 0: Yeah, you're all just gonna go to the slammer.
Speaker 1: You can't arrest us all.
Speaker 1: you can't arrest us all
Speaker 0: and you're not gonna remember you're gonna wake up in the slammer like fuck
Speaker 1: Yep, but even if you're like our group if you're hosting the party you're responsible for everyone's happiness And you're sort of like going around like donating it like making sure things go like you you go over to like the group Of people who are just poking at their phones and like hey, what are you guys up to?
Speaker 1: Why don't you go play a board game with Scott over there?
Speaker 1: He's setting up a seven wonders right now Like facilitate all that but as a result you're very well placed to spot People who might be having problems like someone who's got some anxiety Someone who is obviously like not having a good time Obviously because of other issues going on in their life,
Speaker 0: and you know why did they come to this party?
Speaker 1: well It's probably good that they at least came to the party But maybe depending the host is in a unique situation to see that shit.
Speaker 1: The problem is I could give way better advice about that.
Speaker 0: host also is the only person who hopefully knows everyone at the party.
Speaker 0: Yeah someone who's a guest might not know.
Speaker 0: all the other guests would not be looking at those guests that they don't know like they're only Hanging with the people that are in their crew and open invite friends of friends parties.
Speaker 1: That's a whole different ballgame that we're not talking about tonight.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's a whole nother world Mmm.
Speaker 0: What else you guys say?
Speaker 0: nothing.
Speaker 0: I want to go eat pretty much.
Speaker 1: One of the most important things other than everything we talked about is just that just make sure that everyone's having a good time Or at least had the opportunity.
Speaker 0: why even having a party if people aren't having a good time?
Speaker 1: yep except most parties.
Speaker 1: Just Peter out into Everyone sitting around poking at the phones.
Speaker 1: a few people rim and Scott are in the corner with a few other people playing a board ignoring everyone.
Speaker 1: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 0: be sure to visit our website at front row crew comm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 1: Remember geek nights is not one But four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 0: geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience But unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 0: it's actually recorded at night.
Speaker 1: The patrons for this episode of geek nights in order of the amount of money.
Speaker 1: They give us on a continuing basis are Alan Joyce Rebecca Dunn Nicholas Brando Heidi McNichol Amanda Duchette James David White Christian coon's my stady calm.
Speaker 1: Sean Hayworth William Eisen Rose Jeremy minor Chris Reimer and Thomas.
Speaker 1: on Iggy kid Matthew Smith Kajar tavish and Joshua Joe star Tyler Eller Don Schleich Sean Yeager Clinton Walton run from New Zealand Robert Lee Ryan parent or open later rare Laval Brian said Roni Rochelle, Montanota Finn Eric silver rod Chris Reimer and Thomas.
Speaker 1: on Aaron Cerise Chris mid give Chris Knox flame dark fire.
Speaker 1: Sam Cordray Daniel Redmond Chris had odd Sean Klein Chris Reimer and Thomas, huh?
Speaker 1: I Just I cannot.
Speaker 1: I clap to you those of you who coordinated that nonsense.
Speaker 1: Yeah kinetic arms coming up.
Speaker 1: I'm almost done remastering the third beta episode of geek nights.
Speaker 1: We'll catch up on the Q&A soon and by the end of the weekend I should have utana episode 15 up as well.
Speaker 1: I know that's been a long time coming but stuff keeps getting in the way.
Speaker 1: Stay tuned.
Speaker 1: after kinetic on hopefully we'll announce our packs prime panel schedule and I'll at least be a packs dev I don't know if Scott will and Vague thoughts we might be able to make it to PAX Australia.
Speaker 1: We're not sure yet.
Speaker 1: If you really want us to be at PAX Australia Contact packs Australia and be like hey are the geek nights guys coming back?
Speaker 1: like really are they?
Speaker 1: can you ask them but get them?
Speaker 1: to come back.
Speaker 1: that'll really help us come back, but Looking into coming back and now I leave you with something.