Speaker 0: It's Thursday August 18th 2016.
Speaker 0: I'm rim I'm scared and this is geek nights tonight.
Speaker 0: I guess umbrellas and rain.
Speaker 1: That's all you rain gear.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: Well, you got a better idea for Thursday show.
Speaker 1: I go home and eat.
Speaker 0: I've seen a whole bunch of movies, but you're not watching movies anymore.
Speaker 0: I've seen a whole bunch of these to see.
Speaker 0: No, none at all Not even like movies that are already on Netflix.
Speaker 1: nothing Netflix right now.
Speaker 0: Oh, see I dropped the Hulu.
Speaker 0: I did that too because there's nothing on Hulu that I want to watch it.
Speaker 1: I dropped everything.
Speaker 1: right now There's nothing to watch.
Speaker 0: I still got the c-roll because I'm watching anime and I still got the Netflix.
Speaker 0: cuz I'm watching.
Speaker 1: I watched all the animes in the c-roll.
Speaker 1: I'm waiting for more to show up.
Speaker 0: Uh, so you didn't watch any hero academia, whatever.
Speaker 0: No, no, cuz that's the show.
Speaker 0: I was gonna watch.
Speaker 0: talk about it.
Speaker 0: All right, it's not watching stuff not doing stuff.
Speaker 0: so what's your Thursday show on Nothing, I haven't seen anything.
Speaker 1: Let's not do.
Speaker 0: I just saw Kubo.
Speaker 0: I just saw Ghostbusters not that long ago.
Speaker 0: It was actually really good.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like real funny real legit.
Speaker 0: I'd say Three times funnier than Ghostbusters - maybe four times funnier.
Speaker 0: and like.
Speaker 1: that's like saying I got four pennies four times more money.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but 90% as funny as the first Ghostbusters like it's right under there.
Speaker 1: You're saying that the second Ghostbusters is only 25% of the second one.
Speaker 0: There's the second Ghostbusters movie.
Speaker 0: Not that good.
Speaker 1: No, I'm saying is you're?
Speaker 1: you're saying you're you're you're.
Speaker 1: basically the numbers you just used rate the second Ghostbusters movie much too Highly.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: So let's take comedy movies as a whole.
Speaker 0: What was the last good comedy movie?
Speaker 0: That you can think of name a good comedy movie Ever?
Speaker 0: young Frankenstein young Frankenstein.
Speaker 0: Where's the last time you saw young Frankenstein?
Speaker 1: a year ago.
Speaker 0: Did it hold up?
Speaker 0: Yes All right, cuz I got a. I watch like 20 minutes of space balls about a month ago does not hold up that movie.
Speaker 0: Not even at all funny.
Speaker 0: I'm sorry.
Speaker 0: That movie is funny.
Speaker 0: I guess if the internet didn't exist.
Speaker 1: Mel Brooks always had the lowbrow but his Cleverness decreased over the time.
Speaker 0: it's you know what it is because even I'm gonna be honest I think blazing saddles holds up a little better, but not that much better.
Speaker 1: cuz aging saddles holds up significantly better.
Speaker 0: Yeah but the one I have not seen in my adult life to be able to say the score on his men in tights and I have This worry that it doesn't hold up at all.
Speaker 1: There's only a few jokes in it that hold up and the rest do not.
Speaker 0: yeah But I think of it a lot like I think of the far side where the far side Was some of the funniest shit I'd ever read in a day before the internet existed and all these modern comedy things existed.
Speaker 0: the far side was relatively avant-garde compared to anything else you see in a newspaper and Nowadays, like if far side had never existed and it started today.
Speaker 0: And let's even assume that nothing that was inspired by the far side existed.
Speaker 0: It wouldn't even get a read like.
Speaker 0: it wouldn't even just be there It was.
Speaker 0: there was a time and a place that comic could exist and it's long gone.
Speaker 0: I feel like a lot of Mel Brooks stuff is like that.
Speaker 0: Like it just cannot compete with modern comedy and it's notable only for the relative Pioneering that it did in its era.
Speaker 1: I think if you look at history as a whole right history of modern media Those things are like that going back to the 20th century.
Speaker 1: The comedy sort of has these, you know big sine wave right whereas like there are time periods Where a comedy was like at its peak and all the comedy from that era at least the top tier stuff holds up forever.
Speaker 0: Like, you know if you go I wouldn't say all the comedy.
Speaker 0: I think it's partly the anime import syndrome of like not like early 90s stand-up.
Speaker 0: There was a lot of really good stand-up like.
Speaker 0: I remember this era of like amazing stand-up in late 80s, too.
Speaker 1: but that's just because everyone forgot about All the other stand-up comics that weren't on HBO specials bones, okay, so if you go back right go back to Marx Brothers, right that shit lasts forever.
Speaker 1: Uh, so
Speaker 0: a lot of their like their movies not actually great to a modern sensibility unless you have some nostalgia toward them or are particularly looking forward to that particular kind of mostly set piece prop style comedy
Speaker 1: anyway, so Then after that, there's like a time period where shit ain't funny Until like Jerry Lewis like a bit later, right then shits funny again.
Speaker 0: Is it if you what's the last time you watch the Jerry Lewis movie?
Speaker 1: Long time ago.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Anyway, I just worry watching Jerry Lewis movie right now.
Speaker 0: We're both gonna be like.
Speaker 1: I won't say it's impossible.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I won't say it's a hundred percent though I don't have right.
Speaker 0: it's very for kid brain to not remember stuff right.
Speaker 1: then shit goes downhill again.
Speaker 1: But then it comes back.
Speaker 1: it comes back in the 80s.
Speaker 1: you get some Eddie Murphy.
Speaker 1: you get you know This is our SNL golden age kind of action going on.
Speaker 0: Right, you know, yeah, but at the same time So SNL.
Speaker 0: when I was younger, I had this like.
Speaker 0: I remembered SNL being the most Ridiculously funny, but it was partly because I was only ever watching the best of that's what I'm saying.
Speaker 0: But then II.
Speaker 0: but the problem is it's just that I think the best of of almost any era is gonna be pretty great.
Speaker 1: No, it's like the best of in like, you know An era that sucks is like not even close to what's an era that sucks Like what's a year that sucks anything between the year?
Speaker 1: 2000 and today?
Speaker 0: all right comedy movies 2000 I don't know.
Speaker 0: five Hair comedy movies in 2000.
Speaker 1: I mean the funniest movie probably in that era.
Speaker 1: It might be hot fuzz, which is okay.
Speaker 0: Alright, let's see comedy movies from 2005.
Speaker 0: I just found a website that seems to have a pretty good list Charlie and the Chocolate Factory The longest yard.
Speaker 1: I don't even know what that is.
Speaker 0: I saw it.
Speaker 0: It was moderately funny.
Speaker 0: Okay, 40 year old virgin in the worst movie.
Speaker 0: Uh Insulting to all nerds I Would say that it is not even a tenth as insulting to nerds as Big Bang Theory.
Speaker 1: It's hanging out in the same swimming pool.
Speaker 1: It's the same shit.
Speaker 0: The thing is that movie was moderately funny.
Speaker 0: I would say that was moderately funny not saying it's a movie for all time.
Speaker 0: It was not really funny.
Speaker 0: It's trash.
Speaker 0: Uh, I guess they made that hitchhiker's movie again.
Speaker 0: Yeah, uh waiting don't know what.
Speaker 0: definitely didn't see Wedding crashers.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's not funny.
Speaker 1: might as well be hot tub time.
Speaker 0: the sisterhood of traveling pants never heard of it.
Speaker 1: Rumor has never heard of it.
Speaker 0: Jennifer Aniston.
Speaker 0: Okay, whatever the Brothers Grimm.
Speaker 0: I didn't see it and The internet says it was terrible.
Speaker 0: Okay, kiss kiss bang bang.
Speaker 1: I heard that that's actually good.
Speaker 1: I haven't seen it though.
Speaker 0: Oh 83% on Rotten Tomatoes heard that that's actually decent.
Speaker 0: Have not seen mr.
Speaker 1: And mrs.
Speaker 1: Smith Don't know what that is.
Speaker 0: spy movie.
Speaker 0: Okay sky-high.
Speaker 1: I don't know what that is.
Speaker 0: Madagascar.
Speaker 0: Just friends yours and mine curse.
Speaker 0: Dukes of Hazzard remake.
Speaker 0: Nope.
Speaker 0: Nope getting lower and lower here.
Speaker 0: So hot right.
Speaker 1: no, so one may be good comedy.
Speaker 1: kung fu hustle 2005. it's not American kung fu hustle.
Speaker 1: It's pretty good, but it's not like.
Speaker 0: well, you know what kung fu hustle.
Speaker 0: Not nearly as good as I expected it to be to be honest Yeah, like I saw a trailer for it and I thought it was gonna be the best movie and ever.
Speaker 1: and it's okay.
Speaker 0: It's actually way too long and isn't anything like the trailer.
Speaker 0: Chicken little be cool.
Speaker 0: Okay, let's try Looking for a sampling here finding Nemo not a comedy.
Speaker 0: It had comedic moments.
Speaker 1: Love actually supposed to be the fantastic movie.
Speaker 0: actually, uh Wait, you haven't seen it.
Speaker 0: No, it's super fucking good.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like Just you should just watch it.
Speaker 0: Is it really look 99% fresh?
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's real good.
Speaker 0: I said it was but I wouldn't call it a genre comedy movie.
Speaker 1: Probably not You know, what?
Speaker 0: Is it partly that good comedy is within other broader works now?
Speaker 0: I mean just a genre of a movie that is in genre comedy with a capital C that that has disappeared.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean, yeah you there every movie City of God is listed here right anything any work has comedy in it, right?
Speaker 1: You can get the most serious horror movie, right and Like super serious not trying to be campy horror movie like super serious horror movie and there's gonna be funny bits, right?
Speaker 1: That's how it works.
Speaker 1: But we're talking about the pure.
Speaker 1: This is a Comedy made to be a comedy.
Speaker 1: I think that genre unto a Blues Brothers or a Marx Brothers or some others was a Musical Smothers Brothers or some other kind of brothers.
Speaker 1: Yeah They're brothers involved.
Speaker 0: Just two brothers two brothers.
Speaker 1: All right, you didn't get that joke, you know or like you know coming to America or I've not seen coming to America as an adult any kind of Kind of Richard Pryor action.
Speaker 1: Yeah That is this is a comedy that does anything it made anymore.
Speaker 1: That's why I said the only kind of example is like the Edgar Wright kind of action and that's okay sometimes.
Speaker 0: Actually, you know not on the same is real funny was what we do in the shadows.
Speaker 0: never really.
Speaker 0: it's a recent movie.
Speaker 1: What are you doing in the shadows?
Speaker 0: It's a mockumentary.
Speaker 0: It's the same format as like best in show or that kind of thing.
Speaker 0: Oh, that's an okay, but it's about Vampires and they just kind of suck.
Speaker 1: That's the one where the the guys got like a messed up leg and he walks the dog At the end, right?
Speaker 0: Oh Yeah, but I'm talking about the vampire movie.
Speaker 0: that's in that same format.
Speaker 0: Okay, like say a similar style movie Finding Dory which I guess is the sequel to Finding Nemo.
Speaker 0: That's apparently almost as good.
Speaker 1: It has comedy but it's not a comedy.
Speaker 0: I'm looking for a movie.
Speaker 0: That was genre comedy, I guess Bad Moms Probably not good.
Speaker 0: Whiskey Tango Foxtrot Swiss Army Man sing the Hollas hail Caesar.
Speaker 0: All right, hail Caesar I kind of wanted to see the Coen brothers movie.
Speaker 0: That's it.
Speaker 0: That's a genre comedy.
Speaker 1: I think I heard not good things.
Speaker 0: 83% fresh.
Speaker 0: That's better than the vast majority movies ever made.
Speaker 0: But yeah I would.
Speaker 0: I would suspect that movies that primarily say I am a comedy are fewer number than they used to be and I think That's an evolution of comedy.
Speaker 1: I think I think it's because The people who are currently the comedians right the top-level comedians are not really making movies, right?
Speaker 0: So think about what constitutes a top-level comedian though All right.
Speaker 1: so if you
Speaker 0: know it's not like in the 90s people would say like they'd list stand-up comic artists or like SNL writers or like Simpsons writers, but now like who's gonna who you talk to you to be in a comedy
Speaker 1: I'm saying like if you go back to the 90s, right like Fargo You have pre garbage.
Speaker 1: Adam Sandler was at least making movies that were pretty garbage.
Speaker 0: Adam Sandler constitutes at most four movies.
Speaker 1: That's what I'm saying.
Speaker 1: Oh, that's what I'm saying.
Speaker 1: And then in the 80s, right?
Speaker 1: You had all kinds of people right?
Speaker 1: But now it's like you don't see Louis ck really making movies miss TV show or something, right?
Speaker 1: You don't see key and peel aren't really making movies.
Speaker 0: So you should watch the Fargo TV show because one it's actually legit critically amazing like it's fantastic.
Speaker 0: But to key and peel are in it.
Speaker 0: Sure and they're real good.
Speaker 1: It's not a movie.
Speaker 1: He's what I'm saying, right?
Speaker 1: They're not making movies that are primarily comedies where they're the main characters and so forth right like used to happen.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I guess if I'm thinking if I have to think about sausage party, I guess that's the current genre comedy.
Speaker 1: Well, that's the lowbrow that movie.
Speaker 0: But I guess when I imagine genre comedy I guess the the end of that era that I keep that just I think of like the movie the kind of movie that comes to Mind is still better off dead Like that.
Speaker 0: and I just I don't think that format works any.
Speaker 1: you know, we have Monty Python really anymore.
Speaker 0: Yeah, Chris funny Python.
Speaker 0: They made two and a half funny movies.
Speaker 1: that shit holds up forever though.
Speaker 0: Yeah, yeah actually kind of does.
Speaker 0: To be fair I have not seen Monty Python and the Holy Grail in the previous decade.
Speaker 1: You Laughed there you go.
Speaker 1: I just I just proved that it holds up.
Speaker 1: I'm wondering one word.
Speaker 1: I don't got it.
Speaker 0: You don't got to see it again, but in my brain, I didn't laugh right away my brain.
Speaker 1: You literally laughed out loud uncontrollably and not faking it.
Speaker 0: All I had to do is say my brain thought pang And that is what I laughed at the new.
Speaker 1: ah, that doesn't matter I Got my shrubbery.
Speaker 1: Therefore the movie holds up man.
Speaker 0: How did Monty Python go from being?
Speaker 0: Obscure nerd bullshit to every nerd quotes it all the time to mostly forgotten except by people like us again Because the generation after us didn't watch it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, pretty much.
Speaker 0: So will the next generation be like we were?
Speaker 1: pass it down.
Speaker 0: Well our generation when we're older go to kids who are like, you know The young age that I first saw money Python like when my dad one day was like son.
Speaker 0: I think you're ready.
Speaker 0: Here's a movie and I want you to just go in your room and watch it and tell me what you think.
Speaker 0: and he gave Me Monty Python and the Holy Grail and I remember laughing so hard.
Speaker 0: I literally couldn't fucking breathe.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm And I had to rewind.
Speaker 0: yeah Yeah, and I feel like because the VCR one or two generations of kids from now that same cycle will repeat.
Speaker 1: I hope we can always go with meaning of life on the kids, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, because it's boobies in it and then they will agree to watch it.
Speaker 0: Yeah life of Brian's a little more cerebral.
Speaker 1: That's only for the smart kids, yeah But it's better.
Speaker 0: So you got any news on gig nights Thursday the lounge.
Speaker 1: It's not it's not a big news but it's the only news I could find.
Speaker 1: I had something to say about.
Speaker 1: so Basically t-mobile and sprint and now it's new unlimited plans.
Speaker 0: Right, and I was actually thinking cuz the iPhone 7 is coming real soon I don't use more than like I have like 10 gigs a month between me and Emily and I don't I use like a game.
Speaker 0: You got the combo plan, yeah, it's way cheaper to get a combo plan.
Speaker 0: Holy shit.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so yeah If you wanted to be a mobile we could do a three-way plan.
Speaker 1: No, I have a variety.
Speaker 1: like a hundred gigs have Verizon iPhone 7s coming soon.
Speaker 1: so based on what the iPhone 7 has.
Speaker 1: I'm either gonna get it or because my contracts over in October or I'll get the iPhone 7s in January February, which Hopefully would exist.
Speaker 1: Hopefully they'll keep that going right and update their success and I'll get a small iPhone 7. should be great if that happens.
Speaker 1: But anyway, so I'm thinking oh, you know what?
Speaker 1: Maybe it when I get the new phone, which is either now or then I'll get me switch over from Verizon to t-mobile.
Speaker 1: save some money's right because I'm paying like a hundred something a month For you know more gigs than I need.
Speaker 0: I mean we're Scott.
Speaker 0: I'm paying a hundred bucks a month for tons of gigs for two people, right?
Speaker 1: You know, I have as many gigs as I need.
Speaker 1: I never really hit the limit and I only come close convention month.
Speaker 0: if you go Skiing in northern New Hampshire, you won't get service.
Speaker 1: That's fine.
Speaker 1: I mean, I don't get service of horizon there either.
Speaker 0: Yeah, actually Verizon had plenty of service there.
Speaker 1: Oh, maybe anyway, but you know, so I'm looking at this new plan They announced and it's like yeah, there's catches on this unlimited plan.
Speaker 1: I'm like, what's there are I don't need the unlimited plan, but then I kept reading and it's like, you know And it goes worse.
Speaker 1: so the catch they have with the unlimited plan is that all video playback is limited to 480 PS and To unlock to get real video playback.
Speaker 1: It's 25 bucks a month and Sprint doesn't even let you do it at all.
Speaker 1: It's like they're just screwing you.
Speaker 1: but t-mobile will let you pay 25 bucks extra to get real video playback if you want.
Speaker 0: I wasn't that.
Speaker 0: only if you have the unlimited plan, I think otherwise, I think whatever resolution you want, but you're Right, and then don't watch a 4k video by accident.
Speaker 1: I kept reading and it says oh, yeah, by the way with t-mobile You know if you tether it's only gonna be 2g.
Speaker 0: What Scott?
Speaker 0: with t-mobile one I can tether my 4g But remember there's unlimited global roaming everywhere in the world.
Speaker 0: I can tether overseas, but I only get 2g.
Speaker 0: That's the free global roaming nonsense.
Speaker 0: 2g tethering.
Speaker 1: in America I might as well have a dial-up modem and they'll charge you 15 a month to get LTE tethering.
Speaker 1: but you pay 15 a month not unlimited LTE tethering but only for 5 gigs of LTE tethering.
Speaker 1: and if you do More even more tethering you got to pay another 15.
Speaker 0: This plan is the worst.
Speaker 0: It literally just makes your cell service worse.
Speaker 1: So I went to t-mobile and I realized you know If you look at the plans just straight up like the one that has the same number of gigs that I have not the unlimited One it looks like a great like.
Speaker 1: I would just save like 30 40 bucks a month.
Speaker 1: Right and I'm like, oh well, I guess I should still switch and just not get this garbage unlimited plan.
Speaker 1: But then I looked into it and to actually get all the stuff that I have on Verizon like unlimited LTE tethering and you know not messing with my video playback and all that it actually ends up costing the same.
Speaker 0: Well, I don't use much bandwidth for whatever reason.
Speaker 0: I don't know why you use so much bad I don't?
Speaker 1: I only use like six gigs.
Speaker 1: I mean I have a 60 plan and I hardly use it except for months where there's like a Conventions or two conventions and then I sort of push the limit.
Speaker 0: That's what I'm saying.
Speaker 1: most months I'm like under two gigs whatever.
Speaker 0: a hundred bucks a month for two phones tethering and everything is just fine.
Speaker 0: None of those weird restrictions.
Speaker 1: I'm just saying I did the maths and it actually doesn't turn out to be better.
Speaker 0: So, yeah Hmm.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's it was interesting right?
Speaker 1: It's like it looks better, but it's not better.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well, you know what.
Speaker 0: American cell phones are just kind of the worst and nothing we can do about that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I just want you know people before you get a phone plan or the next time you redo your phone plan look carefully At all the carriers and do the maths and see which you know.
Speaker 1: I think I might actually be able to switch a t-mobile and maybe save ten bucks or something in which case I might do that But it's not.
Speaker 1: I thought I was gonna be saving 40 bucks a month.
Speaker 0: It's definitely worth it to switch if you travel at all because of the unlimited global roaming like the fact that in Canada Like you just say you go to your phone and that's the one thing you can do at T Mobile.
Speaker 0: that at least if you're an American you can't do it If you live anywhere else is when I went in for the first time and you know deep on your menus There's the roaming options and I was like, you know what?
Speaker 0: Let's just turn on data roaming everywhere Unlimited and it just totally works like you'll net.
Speaker 1: don't charge you monies.
Speaker 0: No, it's a hundred percent free.
Speaker 1: How fast is it?
Speaker 0: Uh, so by default.
Speaker 0: outside of North America you get 2g except most of Asia You'll end up getting 3g because that's the slowest the network can go.
Speaker 0: So you get 3g and like most of Asia you get 2g.
Speaker 0: in most of Europe But a few places you get 3g just randomly and you get LTE in Canada and Mexico Mmm, so that alone makes it worth it because I looked into what it would cost to have data roaming Overseas if I was on any other provider.
Speaker 1: and you basically don't write for eyes.
Speaker 1: if you call Verizon and say I'm going to Germany Can you please let me use Verizon in Germany?
Speaker 0: They're like how much money is in your wallet?
Speaker 1: Yeah, they'll be like, oh give us a Zillion dollars you're like no actually what I'm gonna do is when I get to Germany is buy an SD card from some SIM card From someone else.
Speaker 1: cuz fuck you.
Speaker 0: Yep Now you can't do that in Turkey, but Turkey's basically.
Speaker 0: But I did use my unlimited data a lot while I was there.
Speaker 1: also in places like that You can just get a temporary phone when you get there.
Speaker 0: Yeah, uh, you got to show passports and weird shit.
Speaker 0: It's kind of a pain.
Speaker 1: I mean it takes you 20 minutes at the airport when you land.
Speaker 0: Yeah But there's something magic about landing in some rando country and literally just turning airplane mode off and checking my email immediately.
Speaker 0: Like that feels real good.
Speaker 0: Okay, yeah.
Speaker 0: Also, honestly, I've done the SIM card thing.
Speaker 0: It usually takes more than 20 minutes.
Speaker 1: the other thing is there's rumors, I mean, you know that The new iPhones will have more than one SIM slot.
Speaker 0: Yeah Cuz that's the thing.
Speaker 0: actually in a lot of other countries like especially in Asia to dual SIM card is The way you go this phones like with triple SIM cards, but it's not iPhones But you do it to arbitrage or if you travel between like China and another place regularly.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: so Uh interesting news kind of an aside because we were talking about this earlier.
Speaker 0: It's official.
Speaker 0: the data shows that this July was the hottest July as far as we can tell in human history.
Speaker 0: Definitely since 1880.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but I mean not since all of history.
Speaker 1: There was like a volcano era.
Speaker 0: Well, yeah, there was the Big Bang.
Speaker 1: It was real hot during that sure But I mean I'm talking my earth right since you know earth is sure the dinosaurs had a hotter July Probably 40,000 or so years billions of years old though.
Speaker 0: Uh, yeah kind of irrelevant our current.
Speaker 1: I'm saying we survived this heat before billions of years ago.
Speaker 0: No problem Unless it just keeps going up.
Speaker 1: That's fine.
Speaker 1: I'd like it to keep going up.
Speaker 1: We need to get to the point where there is a palm tree growing in the city, New York City followed quickly by malaria And the fact that downtown is gone.
Speaker 1: That's fine and I can bike in January February and every month of the day.
Speaker 0: in January you can buy because it's 100 degrees and then in June You literally can't go outside or you'll die like in a hydro bed.
Speaker 1: No, no, we need I can.
Speaker 1: I just need 100 degrees 24/7 way to make it perfect once a year.
Speaker 0: So how's this June through September?
Speaker 0: It's between 95 and 100 degrees outside sounds good during the day all the time.
Speaker 1: Sounds good.
Speaker 0: September through November it gets to like 80. so you have like a nice like that's autumn.
Speaker 0: It's like 80 degrees out.
Speaker 0: Take it then from January to March.
Speaker 0: it is Negative one and covered in snow all the time.
Speaker 0: No, and then as soon as you hit April It's back to 70 degrees and then back to 100.
Speaker 1: No, that's the January.
Speaker 1: March part needs some fixing.
Speaker 1: How about like, you know, nice nice 70 degrees?
Speaker 0: I'm gonna give you a nice skiing weather then you're gonna give me a nice or I'm gonna do nice biking weather.
Speaker 0: You're gonna be some nice skiing weather.
Speaker 1: Why don't we just contain all the snow?
Speaker 1: It's like somewhere no one wants to ever go and you can just go there and ski and not get snow on everyone.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if it could see I'd like it to be.
Speaker 0: I'd compromise.
Speaker 1: go to the Alps.
Speaker 1: I'm never going there.
Speaker 0: I compromised on.
Speaker 0: it's 85 degrees year-round in New York City, but north of Poughkeepsie Across the entire country.
Speaker 0: It is always under freezing and snows every day.
Speaker 1: How about this?
Speaker 1: we keep all the snow in some other country that you can go to and then once all the skiers are in One place on earth we make an avalanche and then skings done forever.
Speaker 1: We're good.
Speaker 0: In fact, you just bought a new bike because it's bike buying season.
Speaker 1: It is but I didn't realize it was bike buying season.
Speaker 0: I was.
Speaker 0: this time of year every year is the time when you buy all the seasonal shit, right?
Speaker 1: It's like.
Speaker 0: well, so no, what's weird is Scott?
Speaker 0: It's not just like though.
Speaker 0: you buy the summer stuff at the end of the summer.
Speaker 0: No, you buy the skiing stuff at the end of the summer - wouldn't you buy the skiing stuff at the end of the winter?
Speaker 0: No, actually, it's not cheaper then that's weird.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it is weird because right now is when the 2017 models all come out 2017 skis - and yeah, all the 2017 skis are coming out so you can get the 2016 skis real cheap real.
Speaker 0: So I'm looking at the skis.
Speaker 0: I'm looking at buying or about a thousand dollars retail.
Speaker 0: What's wrong with the skis you got?
Speaker 0: Actually, they're way old and I'm a way better skier than when I bought them and I know why they're shitty now Like I need better skis For real.
Speaker 0: so you want to know why.
Speaker 1: at least the thing with a bike, right?
Speaker 1: It's like I keep my old bike, but with skis you can sell those skis.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna keep the old skis because there is a use for them.
Speaker 1: someone else goes in.
Speaker 0: Nah, maybe but it'd have to be someone who's about as tall as me.
Speaker 0: But the use for those skis is that they're old and shitty, right?
Speaker 0: So if I do spring skiing a problem with skiing like in the early or late season Is that there's not a lot of snow like you're skiing But there's like a rock there or some grass there or like little shrubbery.
Speaker 1: Good idea.
Speaker 1: even it's like you're already not going skiing in the perfect ski weather.
Speaker 1: Definitely not going skiing when there's a rock sticking out of the snow Yeah, but it's like 50 degrees and you can wear like shorts.
Speaker 0: It's real fun.
Speaker 0: But you wear that.
Speaker 0: use the shitty skis when the snow covers thin so you bang up the bottoms of your shitty skis.
Speaker 0: It's like having a shitty bike that you take to work because if someone steals it Same deal having the beater car in the real car.
Speaker 0: So you have the beater skis and the real skis.
Speaker 1: Yeah, people own a Porsche and a Toyota.
Speaker 1: You don't see them driving the Porsche frequently.
Speaker 0: Yep Great.
Speaker 0: I had that guy who worked with an IBM who had the Porsche that he raced and then he had the RX7 that he commuted in.
Speaker 1: Right, but he didn't take the Porsche to work that often.
Speaker 0: No, we brought the RX7 to work all the time Mostly because I was obsessed with it.
Speaker 0: So we always wanted to take me out and show me stuff.
Speaker 0: That car was real cool, but I would never own one in my life.
Speaker 0: Yep, also interesting in the news today because it came and went so fast a Horrifying naked Donald Trump statue appeared in Union Square and apparently they appeared in cities all over America today And it was some sort of art project.
Speaker 0: All right as this funny little dick coming out multiple people asked me if I saw it.
Speaker 0: New York Park Service actually took it down real quick So I couldn't have gone to see it even if I wanted to and it's like you would have to take the subway to get There.
Speaker 1: it's not like they put it up outside rims office.
Speaker 0: Yep, but granted I could have taken the express train one stop from my office.
Speaker 0: Sure, no two stops.
Speaker 0: two stops because it also stops at does any Hall, but that's not like my news.
Speaker 0: My news is that the New York City Parks Department is now my favorite department in New York other than the MTA.
Speaker 0: It's a good department because they had to take the statue down because that's their job.
Speaker 0: Right, they issued a statement and their statement was we oppose quote any Unpermitted erection no matter how small That is the side I a plus shade.
Speaker 0: that is like pro level shade.
Speaker 0: That is the kind of shade that you can get away with Officially making a statement as a government agency and yet no one can actually fault you for it.
Speaker 1: I do have to say like I've maybe talked to Parks Department employees like a few times and Every time I've ever talked to one it was usually to ask something about whatever city park I was in and they always know a lot.
Speaker 1: They know way more than they should know.
Speaker 1: They're like, you know museum curator level knowledge of whatever Park you're in.
Speaker 0: Well, like when Emily's ago we went to Sandy Hook and saw the nuclear stuff but the time before when Emily and I went we this part guy was like standing outside of this old ruin and we're like What's the deal with the ruin?
Speaker 0: and that guy was a museum encyclopedia of information about that ruin?
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm real cool, dude You didn't know anything about anything else.
Speaker 0: He might have we didn't ask about anything else but anyway things of the day You got anything got a thing of the day?
Speaker 1: Yeah, so I occasionally argue with some people about kitchen gadgets, right?
Speaker 1: Cuz in the kitchen, there's like two philosophies.
Speaker 1: The one philosophy is you can get these specialized gadgets that do like one thing really efficiently Sometimes or you can just use a knife for fucking everything because a knife does everything in the kitchen.
Speaker 1: on my phone pop my popcorn No, but here I. it's like you could buy for example an air popper to pop your popcorn Yeah, or you could pop it in a pan with like a lid on it.
Speaker 1: Yep And it's like is it okay to buy the air popper?
Speaker 0: I would say yes because popping it in a pan fucking sucks is a pain in the ass, right?
Speaker 1: So there are certain cases where the answer is.
Speaker 1: Yes, and there are certain cases where the answer is.
Speaker 1: No, right.
Speaker 1: So a good example of a yes would be.
Speaker 1: I have this thing That peels and cores and slices apples into a spiral.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, I know that thing.
Speaker 1: it takes the peel off and now normally I would say no you should not get this thing.
Speaker 1: However, if you ever plan on making an apple cake Yeah, you're gonna need to like.
Speaker 1: do this to like 20 fucking apples and then suddenly it becomes Okay, you can have that because doing that to 20 apples with a paring knife You know and once is gonna take you all fucking day hungry for apples, right?
Speaker 1: But if you just have to do it to one apple because you're making like a baked apple or an apple pie which needs Significantly less apples than a cake.
Speaker 1: You should not own this thing.
Speaker 1: You're just being lazy and buying extra garbage.
Speaker 1: You don't need Yeah, so the number one offender is the garlic press because the garlic press is basically Like it doesn't?
Speaker 1: it's not any faster.
Speaker 1: You could just smash a garlic clove with a knife like BAM and that takes a fraction of a second and then you just take Your knife.
Speaker 1: and if you really need to go at it, you know, take it take it take it take it take it take it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so there's a counterpoint.
Speaker 0: I'm pretty sure if I Google around and I'm not gonna cuz I don't want to see it pretty sure that there are instances of people who take the side Of the knife and try to smash it and end up just really kind.
Speaker 1: You're buying a device to make up for your lack of skills, right?
Speaker 1: It's basically what you're doing.
Speaker 1: It's not faster.
Speaker 1: It's not more efficient.
Speaker 1: It's not something that you know.
Speaker 1: If you're someone who you know cooks with garlic often and you should have a knife Obviously and you should learn to use the knife to smash peel Mince mush the garlic and if you don't know how to do this here is one of the best chefs to ever live John Pappin, holy
Speaker 0: shit is this guy fast at that
Speaker 1: and he will show you he's a really old man now But you know, he's been chefing his whole life.
Speaker 1: So he will show you the proper way to garlic.
Speaker 1: He's way better at it than me, but I'm good enough.
Speaker 1: So if you can watch him, I'm using the same technique he uses and I have been forever, but obviously I'm not at that level.
Speaker 1: So it's basically I'm casting lit one.
Speaker 1: He's casting lit three.
Speaker 1: Right, so just copy what he's doing.
Speaker 1: You'll be slower, but you won't need to buy a stupid garlic press like a baby.
Speaker 0: now I will admit cuz you know I had this old shitty garlic press that we just had and it just was awful and I didn't really use it.
Speaker 0: But one day that I saw a different garlic press just in our thing and I used it and it was actually real good.
Speaker 1: Obviously better things are better right if you try to do this to the garlic but like a blunt not sharp shitty knife Yeah, it's not gonna go.
Speaker 1: Well, you need a sharp proper knife.
Speaker 1: actually the best thing for smashing garlics is a cleaver because it's nice and heavy.
Speaker 1: It's like BAM.
Speaker 0: You can just smash the fuck out of them You know, however does not work very well is I've seen people attempt.
Speaker 0: This is a meat tenderizer hammer.
Speaker 1: No, don't do that.
Speaker 0: Cuz you think oh, I'll just smash it.
Speaker 1: No, you will send garlic all over the place.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the garlic will explode.
Speaker 1: don't do that.
Speaker 0: But this garlic press was like, but it would be like it was fast.
Speaker 0: It worked great.
Speaker 0: I loved the shout out of this thing.
Speaker 0: I didn't even know where it came from.
Speaker 0: I assumed it was Emily's one day.
Speaker 0: Judith is over and she was like, how the fuck do you have my garlic press?
Speaker 0: I've been looking for that shit for like a year and I still don't know how I got here.
Speaker 0: I guess they cooked.
Speaker 0: they probably came over and cooked some and left it and brought and she took it back and Not don't have a garlic press and that's all.
Speaker 1: you don't need a garlic press.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: in a race, right?
Speaker 1: But you know, there's lots of kitchen gadgets out there and some of them are okay and some of them are not okay.
Speaker 0: So I'm playing a lot of overwatch.
Speaker 0: still.
Speaker 0: the new patch is coming out looking pretty good.
Speaker 0: cuz two patches in a row.
Speaker 0: They're buffing a character that I think is already overpowered that I'm really good at and they're nerfing a character who gives me trouble.
Speaker 0: The game is twice.
Speaker 1: I mean they make their decisions based on the statistics.
Speaker 1: They see a win rates in such and such.
Speaker 0: So the game is twice said.
Speaker 1: your perception of what is Opie is incorrect.
Speaker 0: Oh, no, I'm not.
Speaker 0: I very specifically feels Opie to me not actually Opie god.
Speaker 0: No, but Twice the game has looked at me and said rim the thing you're doing the thing that you do every time you play we're gonna make that stronger and we're gonna make the thing that counters that weaker and I'm feeling real good about that for now until eventually I'm sure that pendulum will turn.
Speaker 0: but this is a short Animated video of someone explaining the plot of overwatch as far as I can tell.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so I came into the room and I didn't really watch this video closely, but it's real funny.
Speaker 1: I could tell it was about overwatch and I could tell that it was a YouTube video and I could tell it was like One of those internet shouty man's the annoying voice except it's not a man at all.
Speaker 0: It's literally just like a guy voice acting this overwatch.
Speaker 1: and this is the kind of thing that's funny to 12 year olds.
Speaker 0: So I think it's legit funny.
Speaker 0: I think I think Scott is just an angry old killed.
Speaker 1: I think this is the kind of thing that's funny for 12 year olds and is garbage.
Speaker 0: and like alright listener I'm asking you which which thing today do you think was funnier?
Speaker 0: the old man chopping garlic?
Speaker 1: It's not This.
Speaker 1: you I didn't bring a funny thing of the day.
Speaker 1: I brought a regular thing in.
Speaker 0: Alright old man chopping garlic is Scott's aesthetic.
Speaker 0: Meanwhile, mine is this really funny video explaining the plot of who do you respect more?
Speaker 1: the old man?
Speaker 1: Who is one of the best chefs to ever live?
Speaker 1: or some garbage YouTube shithead making a crappy video?
Speaker 0: I don't know why you say this guy's a YouTube shithead.
Speaker 0: It's just a funny.
Speaker 1: first of all, his voice makes me want to murder him.
Speaker 0: I don't see why.
Speaker 0: I really don't see why.
Speaker 1: and second of all the aesthetic of the video Makes me want to murder anyone who likes this sort of thing.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's real funny.
Speaker 1: Yeah, rim likes the ten-year-old kind of aesthetic.
Speaker 0: Scott's just salty cuz he doesn't play.
Speaker 1: overwatch Which is the tribe has nothing to do with the subject matter.
Speaker 1: This could have been.
Speaker 0: I think it does.
Speaker 1: This is about Mega Man.
Speaker 1: I would have said the same thing.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you couldn't be funny about Mega Man like you can't about overwatch though In the moment the book club book coming up is Rebecca.
Speaker 0: The previous book club book was Oryx and Crake.
Speaker 0: There is a new thing that Scott doesn't want to be a part of but a bunch of the rest of us are.
Speaker 0: We're gonna do a geek night salon.
Speaker 0: It's a separate book club.
Speaker 1: That's just can't do one book club.
Speaker 1: You're gonna do two book clubs.
Speaker 0: Well, cuz you won't do nonfiction.
Speaker 0: So We're all gonna read either a long-form article or a nonfiction historical book of some kind.
Speaker 0: Then we're gonna have a short podcast and a forum thread where we all having the common ground having read all the same Treatise.
Speaker 1: if you want to read nonfiction read devil in the white city, so we're gonna read like fiction.
Speaker 1: But it actually is totally true.
Speaker 0: So we're all reading this.
Speaker 0: Basically, it's a history of the Weimar Republic.
Speaker 1: Oh my god leading through World War one Peter the great book yet in the bathroom.
Speaker 0: I think the great book was actually really good.
Speaker 0: Oh my god I read almost that whole thing.
Speaker 0: I'll just take a fucking nap But I did not know a lot about Actually the Weimar Republic's politics and you don't need to know what I've learned so far from this book.
Speaker 0: That's real interest.
Speaker 1: take a nap and pretend you read it.
Speaker 0: All the people are trying to compare Trump and the alt-right's rise to like 30s Germany.
Speaker 0: That is not true at all.
Speaker 1: Read the Wikipedia page High level and wait and you read the book.
Speaker 0: No, but it's actually more like early 1920s.
Speaker 1: you're only gonna live.
Speaker 1: for how many more years of your life you're gonna waste that much time reading this old man Who's sharing videos of old men chopping up garlic.
Speaker 1: That's right.
Speaker 0: Simultaneously a lot of good at people reading nonfiction and trying to make better than listen the rest of your life.
Speaker 1: You're gonna eat a lot of food that's gonna be delicious with delicious garlic in it is an important life skill.
Speaker 0: You want to read some book about Rebecca?
Speaker 1: Why my republic will not enrich you?
Speaker 0: Do you know what?
Speaker 0: do you know about the Weimar Republic?
Speaker 1: as much as I need to know what about Bismarckian politics?
Speaker 1: I know Bismarck was Bismarck.
Speaker 0: What did Bismarck do?
Speaker 1: The guy with the pointy head.
Speaker 0: That is yes.
Speaker 0: That is so that aesthetic is as much as I need to know What about Brandenburg and Prussia and I know the Brandenburg has a gate And if you build it your units get I think 15 X.
Speaker 1: That's right.
Speaker 1: It's all you need to know.
Speaker 0: we're gonna be at PAX West.
Speaker 1: This is the year 2016.
Speaker 1: That's just long gone.
Speaker 0: Saturday September 3rd 5 p.m Chicken theater the grind.
Speaker 0: I started making graphics and stuff for our slides for the panel.
Speaker 0: I think the panels gonna be real good and be editing those slides and add this up to it over the course of the week.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna at work.
Speaker 1: I had to do work today, but starting tomorrow I'm gonna be putting in the JPEGs.
Speaker 0: if any of you remember our older lecture on Competitive tests of skill in games.
Speaker 0: We had all these charts.
Speaker 0: I'm working on similar charts for this panel.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna delete rims charts.
Speaker 1: the charts were good.
Speaker 1: stick with my funny JPEGs.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you're I think you forget my charts.
Speaker 0: They culminated in that moment where he showed the Counter-Strike chart and you can see that head clicking is the 80% Skill of that game.
Speaker 1: It's true.
Speaker 0: But PAX is gonna be super fucking awesome this year.
Speaker 0: We're gonna be there doing a panel also, uh Atari game design.
Speaker 0: I finally uploaded the most complex video of a geek knives panel I've ever uploaded and it's a real good panel and it's in glorious 4k and I have no complaints about it.
Speaker 0: And you should all watch it because I think it's one of our better recent lectures.
Speaker 1: I don't think it's that great I think it's pretty good.
Speaker 0: What's a better one?
Speaker 1: All the other ones like what?
Speaker 0: Which one all which one every single one?
Speaker 0: Okay so umbrellas This rims idea.
Speaker 0: I had many more ideas that you were not into.
Speaker 1: all I did was confirm that we had not done this idea By searching our database.
Speaker 0: I even proposed that it's actually possible.
Speaker 1: We have done this idea.
Speaker 0: in my search failed I just I also.
Speaker 0: I searched for umbrella umbrellas Raining.
Speaker 1: I said I searched for weather.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: I think we've talked about whether.
Speaker 0: a bunch of time.
Speaker 1: Yeah warm today.
Speaker 1: We talked about whether every fucking episode.
Speaker 0: But I also proposed that we just continue that kind of unexpected thing at the beginning where we talked about comedy.
Speaker 0: Just keep talking about comedy.
Speaker 1: Yeah Scott I'm out of stuff to say.
Speaker 0: rather than comedy Scott is much more invested in that old man in his garlic.
Speaker 1: The garlic is most delicious.
Speaker 1: Garlic is more delicious than the comedy is funny.
Speaker 0: You're lucky It was not an old man chopping onions because I think that would have been even more comedically apt.
Speaker 1: onion Cutting is actually even more important because you can avoid crying if you'd have proper technique.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah the whole thing.
Speaker 1: Here's the problem the the when I watch use a fresh onion if he's an old onion.
Speaker 0: That's why I could be crying when I watch chef's videos of how they cut and prepare onions.
Speaker 0: primarily The thing I learned about restaurants is that they throw away like half the fucking onion.
Speaker 1: also Throw away a ton of fucking food also core the shit out of onions Like also.
Speaker 0: I don't need to core it that much.
Speaker 1: also they do it so fast They don't have time to cry.
Speaker 1: It's like.
Speaker 0: But no they throw away like half the onion when they restaurants waste tons of fucking food.
Speaker 1: not news.
Speaker 1: Yeah, because you know You can't make like the same thing look beautiful if like you're using like the middle of the onion where the Rings are time.
Speaker 1: You know when I worked at the Bella's like you go to you go to the section where there's like the onion rings and they're All full size.
Speaker 1: Yeah, cuz they threw away all the middle of the onion where the Rings are smaller.
Speaker 0: You gotta chop that up put it in the soup.
Speaker 1: Sure, maybe they did.
Speaker 1: maybe they didn't.
Speaker 0: I was there one of my jobs way back when I worked at the Bella's back RIT that job that I famously quit by just one day deciding not to go in anymore.
Speaker 1: I should do that tomorrow.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, I can live a little while on my savings But I was in charge of actually prepping all the onions and tomatoes in the morning.
Speaker 0: I get there like 6 a.m.
Speaker 0: And I peel a bunch of onions and I wouldn't call him at all.
Speaker 0: I just throw them all in a giant onion grinder.
Speaker 1: Yeah, just grind them out because you know onion bits basically No rings.
Speaker 0: just needed onion shavings effectively and it worked real well.
Speaker 0: and My eyes would.
Speaker 0: they would turn like deep Satan-esque red.
Speaker 1: Why did you wear the goggles?
Speaker 1: They do nothing.
Speaker 0: the goggles did fucking nothing.
Speaker 0: Okay, I guess if I'd worn swim goggles and nose clips, I might have been okay.
Speaker 0: But now I had safety goggles on with a little vents on the side.
Speaker 0: No, that was just an onion greenhouse for the eyes.
Speaker 0: Nope Yeah, in fact the day I quit but I was trying like why did you try like the the Horace Grant sports goggles?
Speaker 0: Uh, I don't think I owned any.
Speaker 1: you could get some with your.
Speaker 0: uh, if I had money back then I would not have been working at the Bellas in the first place, right?
Speaker 1: I Repo man.
Speaker 0: that whole era of my life can be summed up by all the jobs I had during that era.
Speaker 0: I regret having and I should adjust done without money Because those jobs were horrible.
Speaker 0: working for minimum wage is the worst thing.
Speaker 1: So umbrellas umbrellas.
Speaker 0: It's two philosophies with umbrellas much like same as sunglasses.
Speaker 0: yep, either buy the best like the perfect umbrella and take very good care of it and use forever or by a Neverending parade of shit Brella's see with sunglasses.
Speaker 1: I originally was doing $20 sunglasses from the rest stop and Losing them breaking them and getting new ones not caring.
Speaker 1: but then I realized hey I've already spent like hundreds of dollars in stupid sunglasses and I bought multi hundred dollar sunglasses.
Speaker 1: and Because they're multi hundred dollars there.
Speaker 1: I guess more durablos and not breaking and since there's so much money I'm not forgetting them anywhere and I haven't lost them.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so they've lasted me longer than clearly longer than ten pairs of $20 sunglasses.
Speaker 1: So umbrellas though You know, I was doing the $5 umbrellas and then one day our umbrellas last 1.5 rainstorms.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they break way fast.
Speaker 1: So I bought a more expensive umbrella.
Speaker 1: It was really big though, and then if I can lost it.
Speaker 0: So then I was like how big are we talking Scott?
Speaker 0: Are we talking golf umbrella?
Speaker 0: Cuz I hate you if that's true.
Speaker 1: No, well, it was just.
Speaker 1: it was normal size in terms of its diameter, but it was a full stick.
Speaker 0: Ah, oh, so that's the biggest debate is do you get a stick or a collapsible?
Speaker 1: It was it was super durable Like it was totes.
Speaker 1: is that had like a super crazy rubberized handle and like oh, I've seen those It was never gonna break.
Speaker 0: They got nothing on those sends sticks.
Speaker 1: No, but it was.
Speaker 1: it was a full-size stick but a normal, you know radius umbrella.
Speaker 1: Anyway, that umbrella was great, but I lost it.
Speaker 1: I left it somewhere cuz it's like I wasn't.
Speaker 1: you know, it's So big you're more likely like put it down.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: Stick umbrellas are obsolete in the modern era.
Speaker 0: They're just worse in every way and you're gonna lose them, right?
Speaker 1: So anyway So now I can't went back to the cheap ones.
Speaker 1: and then I want an Amazon and bought the highest rated umbrella like some Gusbuster thing.
Speaker 1: they had like a crazy warranty.
Speaker 1: Busters have always been shit and it showed like videos in a wind tunnel and stuffs and it was 40 bucks.
Speaker 1: I'm like, alright fine.
Speaker 1: That's eight umbrellas.
Speaker 0: so I bought it and True to its word.
Speaker 1: It was more Durable than the cheapo umbrella, right and but the problem was the umbrella mechanism did not break Like all the other parts broke like the little strap came off and the velcro strap.
Speaker 1: It's like all these other parts of the umbrella broke but not the actual umbrella mechanism itself.
Speaker 1: Until eventually it broke and there is a lifetime warranty, but it was such a pain in the ass I was just like fuck it.
Speaker 1: I went back to the cheap umbrellas.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and now I've been subsisting on free umbrellas.
Speaker 1: They get at work.
Speaker 1: They gave out umbrellas with the company logo.
Speaker 1: Whoa, I've been using that and it broke because it's cheap.
Speaker 1: but only one of the metal sticks broke so you can still use it.
Speaker 1: So but I'm in the market.
Speaker 1: I kick-started this umbrella called the saw umbrella and they had.
Speaker 0: I feel like kick-starting.
Speaker 0: an umbrella is Real like that.
Speaker 0: shit's not gonna come out or be worthwhile.
Speaker 1: They haven't delivered it yet, but they keep posting updates.
Speaker 1: So they are working on it.
Speaker 1: and this umbrella is fancy in that it's sort of like an ultra modern kind of umbrella Where it doesn't have like all these mechanisms.
Speaker 1: It works more like a Japanese umbrella, but it it's like a solid color.
Speaker 1: You know, it's it's interesting.
Speaker 0: So yeah The only advancement that was needed an umbrella technology is the sense ones that are asymmetric.
Speaker 1: I feel like that you and that you and the weird a cement.
Speaker 1: It's like, you know, that's like toe shoes of umbrellas.
Speaker 1: But you wear toe shoes and you tell a kilt.
Speaker 1: so why not get the weird umbrella just set?
Speaker 1: hear me out Let's get the full set.
Speaker 0: So hear me out.
Speaker 0: if you live in like bullshit suburbia where you're never walking on this might as well.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you got to take all three of those things in your recumbent bicycle.
Speaker 0: So actually I saw someone legit a couple years ago biking and they had one of these sends umbrellas Like mounted on the front of their bike.
Speaker 1: Uh-huh, and they were going like wearing toe shoes.
Speaker 1: No, but they were going like and you tell a kill because that's you.
Speaker 0: they were going easily 15 me I'll make pushing 20 miles an hour on their bike and those umbrellas working fine.
Speaker 0: It looked real stupid.
Speaker 1: Listen I do agree with function over form, but there's a limit.
Speaker 1: At some point you can no longer sacrifice form you must maintain form.
Speaker 1: No, you're getting more functionality.
Speaker 0: But so hear me out on this.
Speaker 0: if you live on umbrellas There are two cases for umbrellas.
Speaker 0: in terms of normal use cases It's raining.
Speaker 1: I don't want to get wet use case one.
Speaker 0: You live outside of a real city.
Speaker 0: use case to.
Speaker 0: you live in a real city Because if you're outside of a city just get a gigantic fucking golf umbrella.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you're only using the umbrella to get to your car.
Speaker 0: Yep to and from car.
Speaker 0: That's it.
Speaker 0: So just get a giant umbrella so your legs don't get way you don't have to carry it so you can get a huge ass stick and toss it in the backseat and You're never in anyone's way.
Speaker 0: So it's fine and your umbrella is gonna be.
Speaker 1: you can get one that's super durable and you're not gonna lose it.
Speaker 1: So, you know who gives a shit, right?
Speaker 1: Yep
Speaker 0: But if you're
Speaker 1: gonna say actually you need more than one because you need one to leave in the car And you need one to be in the house Yep And then you just have to remember that if you ever use the one from in the house to get to the car
Speaker 0: Oh god, send cells an umbrella mount for their bikes.
Speaker 1: Wow If you ever use the house umbrella to get to the car make sure when you get back to the house you bring one of The two umbrellas back into the house.
Speaker 0: I don't think this is what I saw.
Speaker 0: I think this dude a jury-rigged it but they make this thing rims ordering it.
Speaker 1: I see him click it.
Speaker 1: I'm by nice typing his credit card number.
Speaker 0: You know what this mount is?
Speaker 0: It's literally just a tube.
Speaker 0: Uh-huh It's a tube that you just take the bottom of the umbrella and that's he's buying it.
Speaker 0: I see this is not getting bought by rim.
Speaker 1: He could buy now just now.
Speaker 0: So in a city if you use a large umbrella.
Speaker 0: But you are the worst form of vile humanity.
Speaker 1: Now, maybe you're in some city like Hartford, Connecticut.
Speaker 0: You're not a city.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 1: There's no people on the sidewalk and you can use the large umbrella without touch.
Speaker 0: if you're in New York and your umbrella is wider Than a standard small bodega umbrella.
Speaker 0: Like I hope you fall into a manhole and die.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean I have like if my if my umbrella accidentally popes poke someone with a large umbrella in the eyeball fuck them.
Speaker 0: Now I worked with the guy who made an argument that because he was he was shall we say a large gentleman a Wide knit wide a gentleman.
Speaker 0: Uh-huh And his argument was a small umbrella does not cover him.
Speaker 0: and my response was I don't care.
Speaker 1: My response was That's correct.
Speaker 1: You have Justin saw.
Speaker 1: you said it not me.
Speaker 1: I believe the comedic sponsor would be a small umbrella doesn't cover my large body.
Speaker 0: go on.
Speaker 1: Yes Your body is quite large large person.
Speaker 0: but The problem with the standard bodega size umbrella is that shit you get what you pay for five bucks.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it just falls apart.
Speaker 0: But also because the small umbrella that is acceptable to use in a place like New York.
Speaker 0: The problem with it is if it's raining hard your legs are probably gonna get wet.
Speaker 0: That's true pretty wet.
Speaker 1: No, that's not a big deal though.
Speaker 1: But I mostly just keep my bag close to none of my electronic bits.
Speaker 0: Oh, I also.
Speaker 1: I don't care if I get wet.
Speaker 1: I just like my kick in my iPad way But it's really my phone's waterproof.
Speaker 0: I don't care.
Speaker 0: But if you're walking in New York if you walk slower Scott Like if we walk like normal terrible people do and you don't have a long stride your legs get less way.
Speaker 0: That's true, but it's real painful to walk.
Speaker 0: that shallow like it just hurts.
Speaker 0: I feel bad.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so the asymmetric umbrella is real long like it's as big as a golf umbrella front to back.
Speaker 0: But it's normal umbrella size on the sides.
Speaker 0: So I don't get in anyone's way It's acceptable to use in New York City.
Speaker 0: and yet my legs don't get wet because I basically have a golf umbrella in one direction.
Speaker 1: I didn't say that it wasn't functional.
Speaker 1: I said you sacrificed the form for that function just like So.
Speaker 0: in the old days the first sense umbrella was a stick only and I bought it.
Speaker 0: It was like 70 bucks.
Speaker 0: And of course, I lost it within a year because it was a stupid stick.
Speaker 0: So I bought another one and I said rim if you lose this one, you don't deserve good umbrellas.
Speaker 0: and sure enough I lost that one.
Speaker 1: You're back to the $5.00.
Speaker 0: No, so then a few years ago.
Speaker 0: I saw that they made a folding asymmetric umbrella.
Speaker 1: You still have it.
Speaker 1: Uh, so I bought it.
Speaker 1: You think you lost it or it broke?
Speaker 0: Uh, it broke Oh, but I caught the company and I was like, oh you got a lifetime war.
Speaker 0: Oh, you actually did the warranty.
Speaker 1: I could have done that on the guy.
Speaker 0: Not only that but they responded they had improved it because they knew it had flaws and the one the one they gave me in return Is basically perfect.
Speaker 1: well see I would buy a fancier umbrella right now because my like I said my company branded cheapo umbrella has one broken metal stick and it's rain soon, but That Kickstarter umbrella will arrive at some point.
Speaker 0: So I don't want to buy about your hex light on it.
Speaker 1: I don't want to buy a fancy umbrella and then immediately get this Kickstarter umbrella and have two fancy umbrellas.
Speaker 1: That would be stupid.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's true.
Speaker 0: It's also you gotta wait to see if it's good.
Speaker 0: Like it might be great.
Speaker 0: It's like wait for a new iPhone.
Speaker 1: I'll stick with the cheap ones until the kick-started one shows up and then that will be the the point of.
Speaker 1: well as The game of life puts it the day of reckoning.
Speaker 0: Oh here.
Speaker 0: I found a thing that shows the progression of those umbrellas.
Speaker 0: That's the stick one that I kept losing.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: And that's the one that broke on me the folding one and that's the modern one Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: So I really like that umbrella.
Speaker 0: Uh, I think because it's a folding umbrella.
Speaker 0: So it's really tiny.
Speaker 0: I'll never lose it because I just literally put it in my bag and it's fine Mm-hmm, and I brought it on not a stick.
Speaker 0: We'll lose it.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm We've tapped the well of umbrellas.
Speaker 1: They keep you from getting wet.
Speaker 1: Well, oh, no We forgot about the part rim believes that people in Michigan don't use umbrellas in the south in Bose.
Speaker 0: the kids in southeast Michigan like.
Speaker 0: I don't.
Speaker 1: but I don't believe this story.
Speaker 0: I think it's just I'm just saying in high school in particular No one ever took an umbrella to school.
Speaker 0: Like I don't think I ever saw an umbrella in my high school ever.
Speaker 1: I don't believe this.
Speaker 0: you would drive to school and it was raining.
Speaker 0: People just like trying to park real close to the building and just run in Because it's not like you went back outside during the day.
Speaker 1: It sounds a bit far-fetched.
Speaker 0: No one ever used umbrellas in high school Especially to my high school.
Speaker 0: my middle school kids were not allowed to bring umbrellas.
Speaker 0: Remember that I think because people were hitting each other with them and it was one of those things You know a school will like will be like listen you shits no more gum ever.
Speaker 0: someone ruined it for you.
Speaker 0: I think someone ruined umbrellas for us in middle school.
Speaker 0: That's a separate thing.
Speaker 0: That was that school, but I'm telling you in high school.
Speaker 0: I was a Michigan.
Speaker 0: No one ever ever ever took a stupid umbrella to high school.
Speaker 0: Like just you.
Speaker 0: just walk through the rain because you were only ever outside if it was raining between your car and the high school.
Speaker 1: It sounds a bit ridiculous.
Speaker 0: Well, how so like if you're not a single person your high school had a room, bro I mean, I'm sure there were a few also.
Speaker 1: that's not what you told me before.
Speaker 1: you told me before is that people in the whole?
Speaker 1: Midwest didn't use umbrellas.
Speaker 0: So generally I suspect that in southeast Michigan people tend not to have umbrellas like they do in cities.
Speaker 1: You're modifying the words used before the podcast.
Speaker 0: cuz I was a kid I remember pretty clearly that like when people like we go to the mall like with anyone even I went with like other people's families Or whatever there'd always be the car umbrella and there'd only be one and no one else had an umbrella.
Speaker 0: so Whoever drove would drop everyone off at the front of the mall or wherever we went like the restaurant and they'd go park wherever And then they'd walk in with the only umbrella that that family owned.
Speaker 0: and I remember that pretty much always being the case Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: I don't I very rare I can't remember a time in my life Where I got out of a car with multiple people and multiple of the people getting out of that car had umbrellas.
Speaker 0: We're there ran for the door or got whoever drove us to drop us off and assume that it's anyone in the Midwest.
Speaker 1: I need you to basically say the rim is wrong.
Speaker 0: in southeast Commonly see umbrellas.
Speaker 0: or do you not commonly see umbrellas?
Speaker 0: because I did not commonly see umbrellas.
Speaker 0: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott.
Speaker 0: special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and brand.
Speaker 1: Okay For the logos be sure to visit our website at front row.
Speaker 1: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 0: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays and a comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 1: But unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night.
Speaker 0: And the patrons for this episode of geek nights the amount of money they give us on a continuing basis Regardless of the fact that many of them are trying to undermine me or causing me to stutter over their names.
Speaker 0: are Alan Joyce Rebecca done Nicholas Brando Logan Stafford hiding McNichol Amanda Juchette James David white Christian coons construction noise.
Speaker 0: This is my city.
Speaker 0: comm Sean Hayworth William ice and Rose Jeremy minor Chris Reimer and Thomas on.
Speaker 0: Oh Scott your beard tickles when we kiss Aaron Cerise Brian Fisher sailor vista Rick Moran is versus the universe.
Speaker 0: Iggy kid Matthew smish Smith Don Schleich shark tovish and Joseph Joe star.
Speaker 0: Tyler Eller Sean Yeager Sam Cordery Clinton Walton Renford, New Zealand Ryan parent drew open letter.
Speaker 0: Rila Val Brian said Roni Michelle, Monta, Nona Veneric Silveraude the rural juror Chris midkiff Chris Knox Daniel Redmond Sean Klein Chris Reimer and Thomas Hahn.
Speaker 0: You'll see our content continue to accelerate on the page around.
Speaker 0: as you might have noticed more and more stuff will come out faster and Faster and I'm real hungry.
Speaker 0: So I'm gonna cut this short.
Speaker 0: I leave you with something odd.
Speaker 0: Who are you?
Speaker 0: we are the Knights who say No, not the night to say me.
Speaker 0: Who are they?
Speaker 0: we are the keepers of the sacred words.
Speaker 0: Those who hear them seldom live to tell the tale.
Speaker 0: the Knights who say me demand a sacrifice.
Speaker 1: Knights of me we are but simple travelers who seek the enchanter who lives beyond these woods.
Speaker 0: We Shall say again to you if you do not appease us.
Speaker 0: Well, what is it you want?
Speaker 0: We want a shrubbery a What?
Speaker 0: Please please no more.
Speaker 0: We will find you a shrubbery.
Speaker 0: You must return here with a shrubbery Or else you will never pass through this word alive Knights of me.
Speaker 1: you are just and fair and we will return with a shrubbery one that looks nice.
Speaker 0: Of course, I'm not too expensive.
Speaker 1: Yes now Go All this will be yours.
Speaker 1: No, but the curtains lad.
Speaker 1: Oh as you can see stretched out over the hills and valleys of this land Little be your kingdom.
Speaker 0: Listen I've got this kingdom up from nothing.
Speaker 0: Well, I started here.
Speaker 0: all of us were swamp.
Speaker 0: Well, the king said I was daft to build a castle on the swamp, but I built it all the same.
Speaker 1: Just to show him.
Speaker 1: they sank into the swamp.
Speaker 1: So I built a second one That's like into the swamp.
Speaker 0: So I built a third one that burned down fell over then sank into the swamp.
Speaker 0: But the fourth one stayed up.
Speaker 0: and that's what you're gonna get lad The strongest castle in these eyes, but I don't want any of that.
Speaker 0: I'd rather rather what I'd rather just see.
Speaker 0: Stop that.
Speaker 1: Stop that.
Speaker 1: You're not going into a song while I'm here.