Speaker 0: It's Wednesday August 24th 2016.
Speaker 0: I'm rim.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott and this is geek night tonight.
Speaker 0: Legie Matsumoto's Queen emeraldus Did you actually read it the manga?
Speaker 0: Let's do this Previously on geek nights Alright, so uh we got tickets to a thing.
Speaker 0: well Scott saw this thing.
Speaker 0: We got tickets to it But I'm gonna read you the title of what the thing is and that's the reason why we're not gonna do a main bit.
Speaker 0: We're going to right now the Queen's dinner club colon Mothership meat company.
Speaker 1: right well the there's a barbecue place.
Speaker 1: It's pretty good this near here and the guy who owns that opened up a new barbecue place.
Speaker 1: that is an even bigger cooker.
Speaker 1: So he doesn't run out of food like he does the other place, but it's a different style of barbecue.
Speaker 1: It's Texas style which I actually prefer and it's not open yet.
Speaker 1: But how are we eating there?
Speaker 1: because if you buy tickets, there's like a preview night.
Speaker 1: I guess he wants to fit You know see if his foods any good, and it's like four blocks away from this apartment.
Speaker 1: So we're gonna walk over there and eat barbecue all that cornbread And it's gonna have the same amazing cornbread from the other place.
Speaker 1: cornbread I just want to eat.
Speaker 1: I'll just got back.
Speaker 1: dude keep your meats.
Speaker 1: I want three cornbreads.
Speaker 0: So what was all that about?
Speaker 0: Because that was basically Scott was the one who was like hey should we go to this thing?
Speaker 1: well There's a barbecue place nearby.
Speaker 1: that's pretty good, but I've had some issues going there like they ran out of food.
Speaker 1: But their cornbread is like the best cornbread.
Speaker 1: I've ever had.
Speaker 0: it's like.
Speaker 0: we've said it's basically more like cornbread pudding Than just cornbread, and it's just big chunks of corn and real dangerous.
Speaker 1: But it's.
Speaker 1: you know the food is good there.
Speaker 1: So I heard that the guy who owned that restaurant was opening up another one near even closer to rims apartment where we are right now and I was keeping an eye waiting for that to actually happen.
Speaker 1: so we could eat there.
Speaker 1: And then I heard even more rumors like he bought smokers that were so big so he wouldn't run out of food.
Speaker 1: He'd have so much food.
Speaker 0: and now that I've seen them.
Speaker 0: They are pretty big.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they're enormous.
Speaker 1: so then I heard aha He's not open yet, but they're doing a special thing there.
Speaker 1: You can go eat there.
Speaker 1: There's gonna be like a one-time dinner for 60 bucks whatever.
Speaker 1: so we bought three tickets And we left stop podcasting and went on over there now I was into a partly because we've done this before.
Speaker 0: I mean there's that ramen joint that opened up as a pop-up like in the One night pop-up.
Speaker 1: This is a permanent restaurant.
Speaker 0: One night early open the ramen place became a permanent restaurant in a different building.
Speaker 1: That was like the test and then we discovered that actually this is like a dinner club thing the Queen's dinner club Which is basically a bunch of cool people just do like mostly old fat people except at our table.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well we I don't either at the table of cool people People mixed in.
Speaker 0: I would not say that it was all that people.
Speaker 0: It was definitely people who might be described as yuppies in their 30s to 40s.
Speaker 0: Yeah, which does not not describe us.
Speaker 0: But the point is we were we won table roulette because our table was basically just awesome nerds and people who got stuff going on.
Speaker 1: yeah Anyway, so we had some delicious barbecue including the cornbread.
Speaker 1: He made the same cornbread as the other.
Speaker 0: all that smoked pastrami though pastrami was like.
Speaker 0: at first I was sad because they didn't announce like the like the many many courses.
Speaker 0: so people just like we missed out on the duck But I found out later that a lot of the people who got the duck.
Speaker 0: They missed out on the pastrami that we got because we jumped right into line, so I feel like it was a wash.
Speaker 1: Yeah, no, I'm gonna get.
Speaker 1: I gotta give me some pastrami anyway, and then it worked.
Speaker 1: today I had some free shnippers coming in and there's no limits.
Speaker 1: like we got honey milkshakes, and we just full.
Speaker 1: we went full out.
Speaker 0: So you know what?
Speaker 1: I've eaten too much food in the past.
Speaker 1: I probably might not even eat dinner.
Speaker 1: I haven't eaten since the shnippers.
Speaker 1: I'm probably not gonna eat until tomorrow.
Speaker 0: I've been trying to go mostly veg after Monday.
Speaker 0: Just because That was too much.
Speaker 1: I would have if there wasn't free shnippers.
Speaker 1: I didn't plan that.
Speaker 0: It's gonna be real bad though because the shnippers is like it's not a chain.
Speaker 0: There's just as one of them.
Speaker 1: There's four of them.
Speaker 0: Well.
Speaker 0: Where's the other ones?
Speaker 0: There's only the one originally.
Speaker 1: There's four.
Speaker 1: There's one mayor Madison Square Park.
Speaker 1: There's one downtown and there's another one.
Speaker 0: cuz I'd only ever been to the one like the main one the mothership the flagship.
Speaker 0: But then a few weeks ago as I tweeted I was walking a different way from my office like I went somewhere weird where I don't normally go And there's all these buildings that are always like under scaffold as the downtown one, and it's not open yet.
Speaker 0: The new ones are new.
Speaker 1: is that if you go to their website It says where the four of them are but the Madison Square Park one has been there for quite a while.
Speaker 0: So I walk by a building that normally has a scaffold up in the scaffolds gone And I see the shnippers sign and for a tiny second my brain says there's no way.
Speaker 0: And then I walked over and sure enough there was a tiny sign that said yes shnippers is coming.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so Basically, you know people come to New York And if they're you know the Shake Shack is like the place to line up for which is great because you know Shake Shack is Not bad.
Speaker 1: no it's not bad.
Speaker 1: I will eat it a Shake Shack, and it is a delicious food I'll put it this way.
Speaker 0: I would not eat it a Shake Shack in New York because there's better options, but if I were like Anywhere else in America dude if you put a Shake Shack like in a suburb That's the best restaurant in the summer.
Speaker 1: yep if there was a Shake Shack within walking distance of any convention We go to right, but the point is you know Shake Shack is not worth waiting in line for but it's good.
Speaker 1: It's like ten times better than five guys, but shnippers is like way better than Shake Shack.
Speaker 0: It's way more choices of food, and it's not cheating.
Speaker 0: It's not like tourists.
Speaker 1: tourists are not lining up for it.
Speaker 1: although at certain times Different locations may be crowded you don't have to wait in a very very very long line like you do.
Speaker 1: a Shake Shack.
Speaker 0: But like you know downstairs from the geek night studio in our apartment There's a place called the Baroness that has like the best burgers.
Speaker 0: But there's sort of like high quality expensive meat fancy burgers, and there's a time and place for that, but Shake Shack burgers are kind of like cheap crap.
Speaker 0: Oh burgers.
Speaker 0: They're good, but they're like that genre of burger that is cheap.
Speaker 0: Oh Snippers is the same level.
Speaker 0: so what you're definitely comparing apples to apples comparing the Shake Shack to the snippers the shippers is just better in Every possible regard.
Speaker 0: yeah, also the milkshakes Yeah, so one thing the place downstairs doesn't have.
Speaker 1: I mean you think like Shake Shack actually sort of has average milkshakes.
Speaker 1: like it tastes great It's a milkshake.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, just aren't that many places that I went to shnippers, and I just had Honey vanilla milkshake.
Speaker 0: that is the one to get.
Speaker 1: I could have gotten honey salted caramel, but I was keeping it you know.
Speaker 0: Yeah, honey was really doing you any favors.
Speaker 0: Honey is just high fructose corn syrup from bees.
Speaker 0: No, it's pretty much as fructose.
Speaker 1: I'm pretty sure I think it is not fructose.
Speaker 0: I in fact am confident that I mean I'm pulling up a Wikipedia right here that the only reason honey is special Is that there's laws saying that even though you can make synthetic honey?
Speaker 0: You're not allowed to call it honey, even though.
Speaker 0: It's basically the same.
Speaker 1: No, I thought it was special because the sugar is mixed in with the honey goop.
Speaker 1: No, you don't get honey honey honey.
Speaker 1: You don't get honey.
Speaker 1: Goop if you just have sugar Honey gives it that extra.
Speaker 0: What is the composition of honey?
Speaker 0: I'm scrolling down here.
Speaker 0: all will be known.
Speaker 0: China Apparently makes all the honey in the world.
Speaker 1: I'm pretty sure there's a lot of beekeepers around here.
Speaker 0: China makes more than like every other country at the top of this list combined their mad bees in China.
Speaker 0: So, let's see top five honey countries.
Speaker 0: China makes 0.47. it doesn't tell me what.
Speaker 1: that is a measure of half a percent of the honey.
Speaker 0: I don't know Turkey is 0.09 That's number two.
Speaker 0: Oh World is 1.7.
Speaker 0: So whatever the millions of tons.
Speaker 0: So China the top five are China Turkey, Argentina, Ukraine, Russia.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we can.
Speaker 1: even our bees died.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Well, I think it's that you know what you think.
Speaker 0: we make a lot of honey We don't?
Speaker 0: we make a lot of like artisanal craft honey.
Speaker 1: All right physical composition as China's making the China's making the shitty honey that comes in the bear.
Speaker 1: That's not the honey.
Speaker 1: I use.
Speaker 0: Oh my god.
Speaker 0: Just tell me what's in honey.
Speaker 0: All right, honey is primarily fructose 38% fructose 31% glucose.
Speaker 1: that's kind of equal Scott.
Speaker 0: That's more fructose than is in high fructose corn syrup.
Speaker 0: I think one.
Speaker 1: it's like 1/3 fructose 1/3 glucose 1/3 honey.
Speaker 1: Goop of 7%.
Speaker 0: maltose 1% sucrose 17% water 1% other sugars 2% 0.2% ash.
Speaker 1: Emily adds up to a hundred percent.
Speaker 1: Where's the honey goop and 3% unknown?
Speaker 1: unknown.
Speaker 0: well like just garbage that gets in there.
Speaker 0: cuz bees, you know bees make it.
Speaker 0: you know, You don't have an FDA going into the bees and be like the legs Our petals.
Speaker 0: yeah beep boop, but look how much of it is ash.
Speaker 0: Alright, I fructose corn syrup.
Speaker 1: What part of it makes the honey goop.
Speaker 0: Hi for just corn syrup is 24% water.
Speaker 0: So more water by default.
Speaker 0: Uh Okay, so high for just for corn syrup has 10 to 20 percent more fructose than honey.
Speaker 1: Okay, that's good.
Speaker 0: But it's not that much more.
Speaker 1: I mean, I'm no one's trying to say honey isn't just sugar It is mostly fructose.
Speaker 1: I'm just saying honey also has honey goop Which gives it a flavor that is very very different from just fucking sugar.
Speaker 0: I'm confident you can make synthetic honey, and you wouldn't be able to tell the difference.
Speaker 1: It's corn syrup.
Speaker 1: If you drink it, it tastes like sugar water.
Speaker 0: Have you ever drunk corn syrup?
Speaker 0: or if you just drunk beverages sweetened by it?
Speaker 1: I've had a you know bottle of corn syrup for cooking and then I took some out and I just ate it.
Speaker 1: I didn't like drink it like Chuck.
Speaker 1: Well go go go.
Speaker 1: I like, you know had some and I had on my finger and I licked it and it tasted like sugar water only thick.
Speaker 1: It's the same as if you like you're making simple syrup.
Speaker 1: you put sugar and water and boil it And then I use it to make lemonade.
Speaker 1: It tastes like that only thicker.
Speaker 0: Yep, man I should start making the lemonade again.
Speaker 1: Don't make lemonade.
Speaker 1: Why not?
Speaker 1: I made lemonade recently.
Speaker 1: You know what is what happens first you got to buy lemons.
Speaker 1: lemons ain't cheap for the amount I needed like eight lemons.
Speaker 0: Just buy lemon juice man.
Speaker 1: Hold on see let.
Speaker 1: if you just buy lemons, right?
Speaker 1: The lemons end up being more expensive than just buying simply lemonade.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right not even counting the cost of the sugar water and your effort.
Speaker 0: So I'm saying buy just lemon juice.
Speaker 1: It's hard to find lemon juice.
Speaker 0: That's not full of sodium benzoate or whatever.
Speaker 1: No, that's not actually fucking lemon juice.
Speaker 1: It's always like from concentrate high fructose corn syrup.
Speaker 1: It's not easy to find lemon juice.
Speaker 1: That's actually just already squeezed lemons.
Speaker 0: Well, what's wrong with from concentrate if it still doesn't have any fructose stuff in it?
Speaker 1: it all had fructose stuff.
Speaker 1: I could not find a lemon juice.
Speaker 1: That was just lemon juice.
Speaker 0: I'm confident I can get that from the yuppie grocery near here.
Speaker 1: But if I'm going to buy just lemon juice, I could buy just lemon.
Speaker 0: Hey, yeah But the reason to make your own lemonade is one fuck it you make limeade instead.
Speaker 1: But - you can just buy limeade from simply but - and limes are even more expensive.
Speaker 1: And the lime and finding lime juice that is that is a hundred percent lime juice is even harder.
Speaker 0: Oh god I know that the lime George is not a joke.
Speaker 0: I've noticed over the last several years that the limes we get are getting smaller and smaller.
Speaker 1: I could not find any lime juice at all.
Speaker 1: That was actually lime juice.
Speaker 1: It was just like lime flavor.
Speaker 0: the problem simply or the whatever is that it's too sweet and not acid enough.
Speaker 1: I never had that problem.
Speaker 0: I like.
Speaker 0: I like my lemonade and my limeade to be more like just biting into a lemon.
Speaker 1: So here's what you do.
Speaker 1: you go to the street fair that's there every weekend in a different part of the city Bike on up and say hey I got.
Speaker 1: I was there recently because It was on Steinway and I was on a netrunner tournament a few blocks away And I needed a drink and the game store only sells poison.
Speaker 1: I don't drink.
Speaker 1: so I walked over there and there's a lady with a little lemonade stand and you know I was like hey Give me a mango lemonade and she just she's like do you want sugar?
Speaker 1: and I'm like There's made the sugar in the mango juice.
Speaker 1: She just took lemon and she took ice and she not too much ice had plenty of beverage and she squirted mango into it And she didn't add sugar.
Speaker 1: So it was you know, so I wasn't.
Speaker 0: when I was in Wildwood last something happened.
Speaker 0: There's actually kind of bad, you know, Curly's has the giant The delicious but 90% ice.
Speaker 0: Yeah, also like 10% just granulated sugar, but you can get refills.
Speaker 0: So it's okay, but they have the lemonade in the orangeade and I remember in the past I would see them squeezing the lemons.
Speaker 1: They didn't squeeze they were it wasn't actually.
Speaker 0: so I don't know if it's true with the lemons But when I ordered the orangeade and in the past I recall that never seen them having oranges I did see them having oranges.
Speaker 0: I remember specifically seeing that.
Speaker 0: all right They may and I remember that the problem with that place was that you're so thirsty and you buy it and you drink it.
Speaker 0: then You realize that there's like a centimeter of sugar just like piled at the bottom of your glass.
Speaker 1: good It didn't you didn't drink it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I When I got it I watched them make it and they literally just went into the spigot and got fructose orange juice shit Into the cup until it was like mostly full so syrup.
Speaker 0: and then no Well, it was like basically like orange soda but not carbonated.
Speaker 0: Mmm, and then they dumped the sugar in it and handed it to me.
Speaker 0: So they gave me sugar water with sugar in it.
Speaker 0: So, yeah end of an era a dream has died.
Speaker 1: why not take traffic an orange juice and add Sure, you know added sugars, right?
Speaker 1: It's like it doesn't.
Speaker 0: actually you know what I should do.
Speaker 0: I should just buy the simply but then dump it into a decanter in the fridge and then just squeeze like two more lemons into it.
Speaker 0: Good, that might do it.
Speaker 0: I gotta experiment like when you were trying to recreate that perfect blend from Adult pineapple.
Speaker 1: orange juice used to be pineapple juice orange juice and lemon and then at some point they changed the recipe to where the number One juice in there was Apple.
Speaker 0: pretty much every juice these days is actually apple juice.
Speaker 1: I was originally pineapple orange and lemon.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well, you know what soda pop was originally cane sugar sugar sugar.
Speaker 0: So I saw some people that were vague one.
Speaker 0: I feel like almost no one in America knew who captain Tsubasa was except for Anna Twitter.
Speaker 1: Yeah, people in America don't know who captain Tsubasa is.
Speaker 1: cuz a we don't care about soccer B. It's not an anime that was even shown here to any of the anime fans haven't seen it only the most hardcore of anime fans and Japanese people living in America and that sort of person knows what that is in the United States.
Speaker 0: but a lot of people were kind of assuming and expecting especially with Pokemon go that the thing Japan would do at the Olympics would Be Pokemon.
Speaker 1: Well, Pokemon is one of Japanese Japan's biggest cultural things, but Pokemon hasn't spread to the entire world, right?
Speaker 1: It's like all of Asia and the United States and Canada and you know Europe certain, you know certain places in the world.
Speaker 1: pokemania has taken over.
Speaker 1: But if you go to like, I don't know like Africa or you know Brazil say where the Olympics were like Pokemania hasn't taken over there as much.
Speaker 0: so I'm gonna quote the anime news network article that itself sourced BuzzFeed Japan which talked about this and this article link to is just kind of interesting because it talks a lot about Recognition and like why Japan chose what it did for the closing ceremony and all that stuff.
Speaker 0: but quotes.
Speaker 0: according to BuzzFeed Japan There are distinct reasons why we did not catch a glimpse of our unique monster commandments and unidentified Tokyo Olympic Paralympic Committee member said that the team behind the ceremony show began preparations in January
Speaker 1: before
Speaker 0: Pokemon go hit a big and additionally Mario games have consistently outsold Pokemon games Worldwide and Pokemon is not as well known.
Speaker 1: Comparatively that's true.
Speaker 1: My Mario is such a recognized character.
Speaker 1: He's had like the Mickey Mouse level.
Speaker 1: In fact, Mickey Mouse has declined because Disney doesn't use Mickey Mouse at all.
Speaker 0: Now while they're relatively recent like Mickey Mouse cartoons that are really good as far as I can tell they're only on YouTube.
Speaker 0: Like they're not.
Speaker 1: they're on in Times Square.
Speaker 1: You can see one like on the giant sign on the side of a building.
Speaker 0: Oh But anyway, but yeah, like Mickey Mouse is not like any face every day.
Speaker 1: Yeah, kids do not, you know might know who Mickey Mouse is cuz he's like the face it but it's like, you know when It's like Mickey Mouse cartoons were big a hundred years ago.
Speaker 1: You know, what's the last time you saw Mickey Fantasia?
Speaker 1: kids haven't seen that shit.
Speaker 0: I was in Disney recently.
Speaker 0: Didn't see a lot of Mickey?
Speaker 0: actually you see him on the logo Welcome to Disney like the only character actor that I saw a lot of just because we were sitting somewhere and then he was doing His thing was Rafiki.
Speaker 1: Really?
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 0: He was doing a good job though.
Speaker 1: I mean all those people are like super professionals.
Speaker 1: Yeah You don't get that job if you suck like.
Speaker 0: you don't realize how a pro that is like even if you think you know it Until you're there again cuz you're used to seeing people in costumes kind of like, you know mugging for the cat.
Speaker 1: Those are people all those people who do jobs like that like tour guide on the duck bus and right.
Speaker 1: Those are all people have acting skills, but didn't get into TV and movies The per and the people.
Speaker 1: and in terms of that level like in at Disney World in a costume is like the highest level you Can get like.
Speaker 1: a lot of those people probably have been in TV and movies or will be Even in a fancy costume.
Speaker 0: who is not trained versus someone at Disney?
Speaker 1: and if you're and if you're someone who's like in a costume Where your face is seen as opposed to got a big head on?
Speaker 1: Yeah It's like you got to have even more skills to qualify for that job.
Speaker 0: You got any news?
Speaker 1: yeah, so What was my news?
Speaker 1: again, all right, so Astro boy, you know, it's a big deal, you know in Japan and whatnot, right and actually Dark Horse is republishing.
Speaker 1: You know Astro boy the manga came out in the US and there's little tiny volumes.
Speaker 1: Dark Horse has been republishing them in an omnibus edition.
Speaker 1: So it's only it's not gonna be that many volumes because they're huge and they're a bargain.
Speaker 1: so you'll be able to easily read all the asteroid manga if you want.
Speaker 1: and You know, a lot of Tezuka manga has been reprinted over recently and whatnot.
Speaker 1: so on Kickstarter I was surprised to see a Tezuka related Kickstarter.
Speaker 1: That wasn't more manga.
Speaker 1: In fact, I don't think DMP has done any more Tezuka mangas recently on Kickstarter.
Speaker 1: They were doing a whole bunch of them and then they sort of dried up that.
Speaker 1: well.
Speaker 1: anyway This Kickstarter for a Tezuka thing is for a digital collectible card game.
Speaker 0: How was this even officially license because Tezuka is dead and can't stop them?
Speaker 1: No, but like the Tezuka company Tezuka productions is like actually not stupid and they're not like a lot of.
Speaker 1: You know, what's it called?
Speaker 1: Things that hold on to your stuff when you're dead.
Speaker 1: Trust yeah, whatever You know, they like.
Speaker 1: they do a good job protecting the house, right?
Speaker 0: They're not like the token estate, right?
Speaker 1: They're not.
Speaker 1: I was about to say.
Speaker 1: they're not like the token estate or the Martin Luther King estate where they protect the house Too well, and they're not like some other estates that don't protect the house enough Like I think if I if you have to have an estate, yeah state was the word I was looking for not trust.
Speaker 1: I feel like that's how you want to go the Tezuka level of protecting the house.
Speaker 0: My only my only wish now is that when we are both dead if you we have enough property worth.
Speaker 0: No, if you revive geek nights in some fashion My only stipulation is that you do not revive it as a collectible card game, right?
Speaker 0: That is so this Kickstarter.
Speaker 0: just looking at it just looking at this first page not even clicking on anything One there's only one sentence here at the top under the campaign like before it goes into the details but that sentence is a Digital CCG based on the work of the godfather of manga Osamu Tezuka's universe featuring world-famous creatives.
Speaker 1: right, so the art, you know is definitely his characters, but not in his art style at all.
Speaker 0: and Oh Kickstarter flagged it as a project.
Speaker 1: They love to yet the product mean this is gonna be a real bad game.
Speaker 1: Maybe not as bad as boys guys.
Speaker 0: I mean, it's possible.
Speaker 0: It could be good.
Speaker 0: Technically it is possible.
Speaker 1: anything is possible But this is going.
Speaker 1: I guarantee this will be a bad game.
Speaker 0: much You know much like in our judge anime.
Speaker 0: by its cover and you will feature in anime Boston.
Speaker 0: There are warning signs that don't necessarily.
Speaker 0: Everything about this is a warning sign warnings on number one.
Speaker 0: It is based on an intellectual property.
Speaker 0: That is not already a game.
Speaker 0: that is that's already death for a game, especially a CCG.
Speaker 0: I Mean remember the Star Wars CCG the first one.
Speaker 0: Remember the Sim City CCG.
Speaker 0: This is gonna be like that.
Speaker 0: This game is gonna be bad and the fact that it's digital Actually gives me even less faith in it because it means that they'll be able to make the kinds of mistakes that were hitherto Impossible to people making CCGs because they were limited by the physicality of the cards.
Speaker 0: No one involved in this is gonna be as skilled as Blizzard and I guarantee this game is going to be garbage and I also pretty much guarantee that it's not going to be popular right now.
Speaker 1: if you want to invest on Kickstarter not in technically not invest but purchase a Comics related game on Kickstarter there is right now for the next 47 hours Hurry up the Prince Valiant storytelling game by Greg Stafford who has also made games such as King Arthur Pendragon and whatnot.
Speaker 1: This is actually a reprint of an old game that's been out of print for a super long time.
Speaker 1: But Prince Valiant the is the tabletop RPG has been out of print for a super long time.
Speaker 1: Like I just said, I just
Speaker 0: backed it
Speaker 1: right, but this game is A game which is like a really simple RPG so you can play it with like Kids and you can read it real quick and it's like super convenient and it also hopefully if you play it with kids They'll be interested in Prince Valiant Because nobody knows about Prince Valiant anymore cares.
Speaker 0: So for $7,000 you can.
Speaker 0: you too can be the executive producer of that Astro Boy game.
Speaker 1: They don't have an executive producer.
Speaker 1: That's a problem.
Speaker 0: So that's something I've noticed lately is that kick-started games will pretty much always make the top tier.
Speaker 0: You get an executive producer credit so you can back a bunch of projects Which it seems like a lot of people do and then on your LinkedIn profile You can be like I was the executive producer for these 11 video games.
Speaker 1: Huh?
Speaker 1: I'm rich.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't need a job.
Speaker 1: Why do I need to put things on my LinkedIn?
Speaker 1: I can afford to spend seventy five hundred dollars on a crappy CCG that'll last.
Speaker 0: five minutes Would buy us like four packs Australia's.
Speaker 1: So, yeah, that's a lot of monies But there's so many I like four bicycles.
Speaker 0: Oh the reward and things like every.
Speaker 0: get every common card.
Speaker 0: x4.
Speaker 0: get every uncommon card.
Speaker 0: Get one of every rare card get one.
Speaker 0: So basically people who back the Kickstarter for this CCG are gonna already have all the black lotuses Yes, and also unlike say magic the gathering.
Speaker 0: This is why I play an LCG and not a CCG or the Pokemon game Which have or like Hearthstone which have experts continuing to weed that garden and maintain those cards over time.
Speaker 0: This game is not going to get maintained.
Speaker 1: This is a CCG being made by artists and not being made by game people.
Speaker 1: It also looks Go play a Japanese CCG.
Speaker 1: They're bad.
Speaker 1: They're not good games, but almost all of them All of them.
Speaker 0: this does not look good.
Speaker 0: I Feel bad that this exists.
Speaker 0: I'm kind of sad now.
Speaker 1: I mean like Yu-Gi-Oh is a jet right card fight Vanguard.
Speaker 1: That's the kind of game they make.
Speaker 0: so speaking of ice crease fucking Vanguard God seven flashbacks to old kinetic arms, right.
Speaker 0: so Speaking of sad it's not news that people on tumblr who are artists and fans of shows Harass other people who are fans of shows and or are artists about stupid shit.
Speaker 1: Yeah If you're gonna be on tumblr don't follow and join those people in those kinds of communities because they're just bad people.
Speaker 0: Now what happened relatively recently and this specific thing seems to happen primarily With Steven Universe and not other shows what I mean aren't all the shows like this like the.
Speaker 1: you know The supernatural people and the.
Speaker 1: what are the other ones that have drawn?
Speaker 0: I feel like just because there's been multiple instances lately that I've run afoul of And this isn't just the current show that has drama.
Speaker 1: You sure really gonna say that?
Speaker 1: none of the?
Speaker 1: I'm pretty sure everybody.
Speaker 0: Yeah, super natural.
Speaker 1: There wasn't drama in the Harry Potter communities.
Speaker 0: So this is not drama within the community.
Speaker 0: This is drama where the fan community Harassed someone actually working on the show so much that they had to delete their Twitter account.
Speaker 1: How did they reach this person?
Speaker 0: So basically now she's off Twitter to not have to deal with this stuff.
Speaker 0: I assume she has like some secret locked account somewhere.
Speaker 1: Now is this person like an animator?
Speaker 0: So Lauren Zook deleted her Twitter account on Friday.
Speaker 0: blah blah blah.
Speaker 0: She's a storyboard artist and basically just a storyboard artist.
Speaker 0: Yeah, what the fans were mad about?
Speaker 1: Okay, that there was a bad storyboard and otherwise you got the wrong person.
Speaker 0: Steven Universe fans are fucking nuts.
Speaker 0: So and I say that as someone who loves the show they were mad That she drew a sketch that showed two characters Possibly being romantic with each other.
Speaker 0: and because that was the wrong pairing those characters should be dating different people They decided to harass her in person as much as they could until they drove her off Twitter.
Speaker 0: Okay, their complaints seemed to be that she was undermining the integrity of the show by Advocating for a particular relationship.
Speaker 0: That wasn't the one they wanted.
Speaker 0: they wanted to other characters to date.
Speaker 0: So it's kind of like what happened.
Speaker 0: only luckily the No Man's Sky team doesn't have to deal with this like level of Specific directed harassment where the fans made some shit up about your thing.
Speaker 1: What I would do if I was her right if I drawing skills I would draw every how many characters are in the show, right at this point you there's like.
Speaker 0: There's a lot more gems now since when you stopped watching.
Speaker 1: I'm just saying you could conceivably draw every single pairing And just post of one after another.
Speaker 0: you know what I would post.
Speaker 1: I'd only post one and threesomes.
Speaker 1: just start going right.
Speaker 0: It's just like I would post one's guaranteed.
Speaker 0: It would be Lars and everyone one by one Every day.
Speaker 0: eight Lars Once.
Speaker 1: that would take a long time right?
Speaker 1: just every day.
Speaker 1: just quick sketch Maybe like a five-minute sketch of a new pairing you haven't done.
Speaker 1: and keep track on a little sheet little spreadsheet.
Speaker 1: Yeah, just keep posting more.
Speaker 0: But this is like a confluence of two trends that I just block.
Speaker 0: everyone on Twitter are getting kind of worrying And we just have to figure out how to deal with it in that one fans of things both.
Speaker 1: These are all 13 year olds right?
Speaker 1: so actually technically legally aren't they even not allowed on Twitter.
Speaker 1: Child protection online protection pretty sure there is some guy right.
Speaker 0: it's like the child online protection act.
Speaker 1: I can't imagine there that you know.
Speaker 1: as age increases I'm sure the likelihood of being in that group of people who are harassing her decreases.
Speaker 0: however I worry that it's not like Gomer gate But I still feel like the upper age on these people is in the mid 20s.
Speaker 1: I mean, I'm sure there are older people, but I'm sure the bulk of it is younger kids.
Speaker 0: But it's this conflict.
Speaker 0: two factors.
Speaker 0: on one hand these fans who watch a show and like just get really like Scarily deeply into it and identified too much with it simultaneously have access Via social media to a lot of the people who make that thing and Tied with that much like with no man's sky.
Speaker 0: They make shit up about the thing you made and then they get mad at you when the thing you made isn't the thing that They made up.
Speaker 1: Yeah, cuz they're crazy little teenagers.
Speaker 1: Yep, so just fucking ignore them,
Speaker 0: but I just I don't understand Why it seems like either
Speaker 1: ignore them or give them the smackdown Above
Speaker 0: and beyond all the others like the pony people like sure the bronies are annoying But they never quite got to the level that the Steven Universe people did.
Speaker 0: Mmm, no, I don't think so.
Speaker 0: They're more I guess.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I guess that's true.
Speaker 0: Is that you know the very annoying from a washing them from afar and going guys really?
Speaker 1: Oh pony people never did go and attack or harass as far as I know any of the people working.
Speaker 0: I mean, they probably say they probably lost in the voice actors, right?
Speaker 1: They probably yeah They were stalking and or you know going, you know wanting to see and speak with People do and they're fans of a person, but I didn't like Why did you give Scootaloo parents?
Speaker 0: She was supposed to be an orphan in my head Can and you fucking ruin the show you piece of garbage.
Speaker 1: Did they give Scootaloo parents?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I gotta catch up on the current season.
Speaker 0: I've been too busy watching Steven Universe.
Speaker 1: I don't even know how much there's been since I stopped by.
Speaker 0: so the danger warning.
Speaker 0: one of the episodes of the season I saw a clip from.
Speaker 0: it is The ponies are all at a comic convention about daring do.
Speaker 1: Oh bad cosplay.
Speaker 1: That's gonna be the.
Speaker 1: what was the fan service episode from the last?
Speaker 0: Oh, yep.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: Same deal.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's danger sign cuz I like.
Speaker 1: that's disappointing though, cuz I like daring do.
Speaker 0: yeah Well, it was weird when they made daring do a literal character.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that was weird.
Speaker 0: But - there was an episode that I saw another clip for where spike gets trapped enemy mind style.
Speaker 0: It looks like with one of the changelings from the failed war.
Speaker 0: So that could be good that could be good Yeah.
Speaker 0: So I feel like the show is gonna continue to be.
Speaker 0: what last season was that sort of like?
Speaker 0: it either hits or it misses And it's about a 50/50 shot.
Speaker 0: I'm sure but I haven't watched it yet, so I can't say but Seriously, Steven Universe fans.
Speaker 0: Just call me shit.
Speaker 0: Just settle little a things of the day.
Speaker 0: This was posted to me like a little while ago By our friend Chris was a. Chris O'Rourke posted it in our in our secret hangout, I don't know one of them.
Speaker 0: But anyway.
Speaker 0: So I was joking a while ago about how you know, I can't get my competitive rank in overwatch too high.
Speaker 0: I'm peaked out at 51.
Speaker 0: That's like the best I could do in season one.
Speaker 1: 50 like average.
Speaker 0: No, the way it the way it actually skews it's above average.
Speaker 0: It was a slightly above average because 51 Cluster everyone so tightly in the middle because the ranks only go up to 100. that was kind of dumb the neck.
Speaker 0: in season 2.
Speaker 0: The ranks are way way way way way way bigger.
Speaker 0: So there's a lot more room to really place you in the rankings.
Speaker 0: They like completely changed the system.
Speaker 0: It's definitely for the better.
Speaker 0: but this Because what I was joking with we're playing a game and I was like, why don't we all go for the bottom rank?
Speaker 0: Like how bad would you have to be?
Speaker 0: do I have to like actively sabotage my team?
Speaker 0: or is just being bad enough?
Speaker 0: What would it take to hit rank one?
Speaker 1: I mean just.
Speaker 1: I mean it's based on winning and losing.
Speaker 1: so you could actually be really good and get lots of kills as long As you don't complete objectives and you lose the game.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but You have to actually lose the games to rank down.
Speaker 0: Correct and you have to lose games against people who are relatively in your ranks.
Speaker 1: So if they're really bad, you got to find a way to get them to win.
Speaker 1: So now in this is the way it gets harder as things go on because your opponents are shittier.
Speaker 0: the guy With the lowest possible rank in overwatch.
Speaker 0: There is a hero among us.
Speaker 0: this hero actually went and worked hard to be the worst ranked player in the entire world at Overwatch and this article tells his hero and then he got down ranked and hit one.
Speaker 1: He got down ranked and it put him back at one because you can't go lower than one.
Speaker 0: So, I think the best part of this when he was talking about like what it's like when you get to like different levels and When he hit the 30s, he was like in the 30s.
Speaker 0: I met the angriest people in the world.
Speaker 0: Like those are the people who think that they are way better than they are Right because I'm furious right?
Speaker 0: I mean that their rank is so low.
Speaker 1: They're not at the 50s where rim is So they're not even average right there below average, but they they're not in the zeros.
Speaker 1: like they know how to play They're just not any good at playing so they're stuck in these 30s.
Speaker 1: But they feel like they should be better.
Speaker 1: because like they know what they're they don't have the rules of the game They know what to do.
Speaker 1: They're just not winning games.
Speaker 1: So they're not ranking up beyond the 30s.
Speaker 0: So they're mad salty quote in the mid 30s I met the angriest people in the world.
Speaker 0: It's somewhere in that mid 30s number 20s area.
Speaker 0: These are just the angriest people in the world.
Speaker 0: They think they should be doing better.
Speaker 0: They're really not good enough or these are just people stuck on really bad streaks.
Speaker 1: I guess I agree.
Speaker 1: but if you have just a bad streak like let's say you play the game for like a whole night and you're drunk or Something or you're really tired, but you play anyway, and you just lose a bunch of games your arm hurts You know, you know for some reason even like pro baseball players like a it'll have a slump where they don't you know.
Speaker 1: But if so, if that's the case you will eventually maybe like a. even if you have a bad month You can come back the next month and whoop right back up as soon as you you know, because you'll be fighting against chumps.
Speaker 1: You'll beat them all.
Speaker 0: I bottomed out around 18 where I could still pick Hanzo and my team would just legitimately lose Either by me being a bad character or everyone else being self-devouring because they were so and so like.
Speaker 1: I'm just a bad character like that's under power.
Speaker 0: so Hanzo is a Japanese honorable man who has a bow and arrow so it's a sniper.
Speaker 1: So it's a stereotype.
Speaker 0: So yeah, all the characters are stereotypes But there are two Japanese characters and they are both literally.
Speaker 0: I am honor like it's kind of Blizzard.
Speaker 1: get to work on that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like the other characters are not that bad, but both Japanese characters are like that.
Speaker 0: But he's basically the shit.
Speaker 0: lord 13 year olds I'll pick a reaper because he's skull guy.
Speaker 0: the ones who are I know that well.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the people who are bad at the game the kind of people who Deadpool is their favorite character.
Speaker 0: Yep, if you're if you like Deadpool you're playing Reaper in this game.
Speaker 0: But Hanzo is the one that people think they're good and they play Hanzo to snipe and they just ineffectually Ineffectually die in the corner.
Speaker 1: a sword guy is a sniper.
Speaker 0: I know so that there's one of the Japanese characters is sword guy and the other one is bow and arrow guy.
Speaker 0: Oh an arrow guy is Hanzo.
Speaker 1: shouldn't Hanzo be the sword guy.
Speaker 0: Uh, that's Genji.
Speaker 0: Okay, so he was so bad and there was one game where the guy some someone on the team Just could not deal with this and is freaking out at him like Hanzo fucking change.
Speaker 0: God Hanzo use your alt kill no one.
Speaker 0: God Hanzo switch characters and Where is it?
Speaker 0: So every time this guy was yelling at me, he'd reply with a simple phrase all lowercase I Hanjo Spelled wrong.
Speaker 0: I Hanjo I Hanjo That is my new favorite thing.
Speaker 0: read this article.
Speaker 0: This is amazing.
Speaker 1: is a hero I don't even know.
Speaker 1: you don't need to play this game or know anything about it.
Speaker 1: You just need to know about gaming in general to understand that this man is a hero.
Speaker 0: In fact, I want to add a slide to talk about this in our panel because this guy had to grind Technically to get down to town to the bottom.
Speaker 0: He worked way harder than a lot of people trying to rank up.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so you got a thing of the day.
Speaker 1: I do so, you know one aspect of netrunner the game I played the most and I'm starting to play again because the weather's starting to get a little colder and Cards are coming out that are pretty hot.
Speaker 1: Is the arts right?
Speaker 1: the arts and netrunner are like maybe the best arts on a Customizable card game that there is.
Speaker 0: Well, it helps that.
Speaker 1: it helps that it's cyberpunk arts and not fantasy arts.
Speaker 0: The other day someone in the forum was like, all right.
Speaker 0: I've already seen goes to gel stand alone complex.
Speaker 0: What is the mother?
Speaker 0: cyberpunk anime.
Speaker 0: and I ran out after like five.
Speaker 1: right just play netrunner anyway.
Speaker 1: So one of the guys who does a lot of the art there, you know You read every time I get new cards I look through and see the artists are and there's one guy.
Speaker 1: Think his name is Mike Zellinger.
Speaker 1: I think is his name Hmm.
Speaker 1: All right Matt Zellinger, that's his name.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so he does almost pretty much all of the characters like the.
Speaker 1: whenever you get a runner There's always the.
Speaker 1: you know a character right the human being or you know Something close to a human being maybe a robot or a cyborg who knows what.
Speaker 1: but if it's a character He's usually the guy that draws it.
Speaker 1: So they're all in the same artistic style and he's got this great article going on.
Speaker 1: It might even be a series and this is part one.
Speaker 1: I'm not sure.
Speaker 1: on Creative block calm where he talks about his like drawing and Photoshop process which you know If you're an artist, you don't really need to know how to draw you.
Speaker 1: It's like you know how to draw already or you don't and you're not gonna draw as well as him.
Speaker 1: reading this and you're not Gonna, you know if you already know how to draw this isn't gonna help you learn how to you know draw better.
Speaker 1: But what this will help you is learn about all the peculiarities of shit He has to put up with to draw a card game specific.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah Like make sure it works like a tiny part of this car that someone it's like.
Speaker 1: it's going to be on a tiny piece of Card, but they might want to put it on like a play mat.
Speaker 1: It has to be you know, like this resolution and these are the kind of colors you got to deal with it.
Speaker 1: the printer.
Speaker 1: Here's where they're gonna put like the stat thing how to make the it visit like it visible and easily Recognizable when the person like looks at it and you know It's like they can just look at the card and glance and know what card it.
Speaker 0: I don't want the skull shirt that this guy's wearing that noise.
Speaker 1: I think it's noise.
Speaker 1: I like this skull shirt but yeah, um, there's some good article going on here for Card making art type stuffs good stuff in the minute moment.
Speaker 0: We're going to be at PAX next week.
Speaker 0: This is probably the last show until we get back from PAX because I'm flying out on Tuesday to start packs dev and pregame And warm the hotel bed up for when Scott arrives on Thursday.
Speaker 0: So on Saturday, we're doing the grind Saturday September 3rd 5 p.m.
Speaker 0: In the chicken theater.
Speaker 0: That's one of the theaters actually in the convention center because it starts with C. There's only two left in the convention center as far as I can tell so I guess that's good or bad.
Speaker 0: I think the ones in the hotel might be bigger But I've noticed that the crowds for those have been lower as time has gone on.
Speaker 0: unless it's a big event Yeah, but it I don't know I could.
Speaker 0: we could do a whole separate thing in like the ebb and flow of panels.
Speaker 0: over the years They moved around a lot.
Speaker 0: Like it wasn't that long ago packs 2008 the first time we did beyond D and D. the first time we went to a PAX.
Speaker 0: The panel rooms were like these tiny rooms that seated like a couple hundred people tops.
Speaker 0: Like there was no stage.
Speaker 0: We're just on the floor and packs come a long way since then, but we will be there doing this panel.
Speaker 0: I think it's looking pretty good.
Speaker 0: And as always I can't promise will you?
Speaker 0: I mean we're gonna video it.
Speaker 0: I can't promise it'll go on YouTube.
Speaker 0: I mean it took three takes for me to get a good Atari game design to put up.
Speaker 0: just because Just because you do a panel doesn't mean you have good video of it.
Speaker 0: Like I had one where the video was fine except after through the panel Scott and I kind of shifted four feet to the left and now Scott's just out of the frame for the whole rest of the panel.
Speaker 0: well, but So, yeah If you're gonna be a pecs and you like us, you should probably go to that panel and see it.
Speaker 0: It's also not opposite anything.
Speaker 0: You probably care about for once.
Speaker 0: It's not like choose that or the omega-thon finale.
Speaker 0: It's just like on Saturday in the middle of packs at a good time.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm The book club book was oryx and crake.
Speaker 0: you can read about it.
Speaker 0: the next book I don't have to keep mentioning that is well, you haven't put the new book club yet.
Speaker 0: Okay, it's your book.
Speaker 0: You gotta make the post great.
Speaker 0: the next book club book, which Scott has not made a post for yet is Rebecca.
Speaker 0: And the third book which Scott is not involved in for the geek nights politics salon is I think moon.
Speaker 0: the rise of the Third Reich puts you to sleep.
Speaker 0: We're reading about their Weimar Republic and it's some fascinating stuff and we're gonna have an argument about it at the end of September.
Speaker 1: Yeah arguing about that.
Speaker 1: Goodnight moon was to say goodnight to first.
Speaker 0: All satellites matter.
Speaker 0: Otherwise Scott's doing a YouTube show where he eats lunch with you every day.
Speaker 1: I'm doing a lot of YouTube shows But that's the only one that I'm producing Consistently because I just record on my phone and push the button.
Speaker 1: the other ones are being edited and filmed.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna try to pick up with more and more sieve videos and just all that other sort of stuff.
Speaker 0: soon I'm gonna start trying to live stream overwatch, but I got to tweak my setup because shadowplay cannot be on or Civ 5 won't work.
Speaker 0: OBS it's live streaming overwatch on my ancient computer.
Speaker 0: not quite an optimal situation.
Speaker 0: So we'll see.
Speaker 1: use a live wedge.
Speaker 1: it's a separate device, it's great.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I guess I could buy a second live wedge.
Speaker 1: You could also buy that, you know the live.
Speaker 1: What's the other one?
Speaker 0: Or I could just finally buy my new computer.
Speaker 0: I think that might just have to happen.
Speaker 0: Excuses to buy computers excuses to buy bikes.
Speaker 0: So of all the leji Matsumoto verse characters out there I actually knew the least about emeraldus because I never really like watched or read any of the stuff about her.
Speaker 1: Well, cuz Queen emeraldus has like the least amount of media, right?
Speaker 1: It's like you'll be watching Galaxy Express this humongous TV show.
Speaker 1: You'll be watching Captain Harlock or something and it's like emeraldus shows up and goes away.
Speaker 1: You watch a movie.
Speaker 1: They'll be like a few emeraldus scenes But like, you know the actual store complete story of emeraldus Isn't like in a lot like TV shows and movie like.
Speaker 1: there aren't a lot of them.
Speaker 1: There's like.
Speaker 1: I think there's a couple movies maybe something like that.
Speaker 1: I'm sure I could look it up But as far as I know there isn't some like super long clean emeraldus TV show.
Speaker 1: I will go verify that.
Speaker 1: and if there is I've never seen it and I've never seen in English.
Speaker 0: I mean, I'd never even like seen really the manga until you handed me this hardcover, right?
Speaker 1: So leji Matsumoto manga in general.
Speaker 1: There's a lot of it.
Speaker 1: Actually.
Speaker 1: There's a Galaxy Express manga.
Speaker 1: There's all this stuff but It Hasn't been published in English extensively, right?
Speaker 1: It's like the Galaxy Express manga.
Speaker 1: part of it was in English but not the whole thing and even those volumes are super old and out of print and hard to get.
Speaker 1: and You know, oh, so there was a queen emeraldus OAV.
Speaker 0: Yep, and a manga and And 78 that's that's what we're reading now.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think that's it.
Speaker 1: So finally someone says huh?
Speaker 1: You know what?
Speaker 1: There's probably people, you know All these other mangas that no one ever never heard of are getting sold in English at a profit.
Speaker 1: Maybe there's someone who cares about lady about some hotom on So kodancha who is also publishing like attack on Titan and Akira and stuff.
Speaker 1: You know, they're publishing for the first time queen emeraldus manga in English in the United States.
Speaker 1: The first volume came out in a fancy hardcover.
Speaker 1: I got it right away and I read it and then it made rim read it Yep, and I got to say I like it a lot.
Speaker 1: It's the same as watching a lady Matsumoto, you know anime only in manga form
Speaker 0: Yep But you can emeraldus yourself because her character at least insofar as we've read this volume one of the manga is Just this stone-cold mysterious person who likes to murder people and give children guns.
Speaker 1: She's the same characters.
Speaker 1: He is in all them, you know, yep That's the thing.
Speaker 1: the lady Matsumoto universe is this weird thing where it's so consistent yet It's so unconsistent like it's thematically consistent.
Speaker 1: if you try to put its character consistent It's just not temporarily consistent right?
Speaker 1: if you try to put like events in order you can't.
Speaker 1: because as soon as you try to line up like any two separate things Even if you try to line up like Galaxy Express TV, you know movie one and movie two like I think are the only things that might line up kind of well with Each other but not even perfectly right?
Speaker 1: It's like trying to line up the Harlock TV show and You know Galaxy Express TV show.
Speaker 1: it's like What.
Speaker 1: or try to line up like Arcadia of my youth and any other Harlock thing ever?
Speaker 1: It's like it's like two jigsaw puzzles.
Speaker 1: It's don't fit together Right, but there are certain things that are like facts and the facts of like don't change, right?
Speaker 1: So it's like, you know, captain Harlock's deal is this and his deal is always the same general deal, right?
Speaker 0: It's like if someone made a new like blessed Semicanonical lady Matsumoto universe thing someday like even in the distant future.
Speaker 0: as long as they maintain all those facts It'll still kind of work right?
Speaker 1: It's like this is who emeraldus is.
Speaker 1: This is her general deal.
Speaker 1: It's like the timeline of things doesn't make sense.
Speaker 1: They'll even tell like the same stories multiple times in different ways, right?
Speaker 1: It's like, you know, you'll see I think there was a you know, Tochiro Is it?
Speaker 1: does I forget what there's like two different movies where he becomes sort of one with the Arcadia and it's like well Which one of those is the?
Speaker 1: you know, the fact is that he is it.
Speaker 1: he is the ship basically, right?
Speaker 1: So that fact remains the same But how at what point did that happen?
Speaker 1: is totally different because that same story is told multiple times much like The Bible where you're gonna tell the same story ten times in ten different ways.
Speaker 0: Yeah, now we know the reason for that is the documentary hypothesis where right but regardless, right?
Speaker 1: That's how lady Matsumoto things are.
Speaker 1: so here, you know We read about Queen emeraldus and there's some usual as it is with Matsumoto.
Speaker 1: There's some kid who we never heard of before and she takes a specific.
Speaker 0: He's basically the Tetsuro of this of this manga Except this one's a little more like she literally just comes out of the sky.
Speaker 0: It's like hey kid.
Speaker 0: Here's a gun.
Speaker 1: She gives a lot of guns to a lot of kids.
Speaker 0: Not just her though, like Everybody.
Speaker 0: just if a kid is like like.
Speaker 0: they help a kid like hey kid.
Speaker 0: I got your back.
Speaker 1: It's also interesting.
Speaker 1: She gives tochiro's gun to someone but it's like didn't test as a perfect example of the timeline not being correct, right in this manga she gives tochiro's gun to some kid and But meanwhile didn't Tetsuro end up with tochiro's gun and got it?
Speaker 1: got it from tochiro's mom.
Speaker 1: well It doesn't line up.
Speaker 0: emeraldus is immortal.
Speaker 1: I don't know about that.
Speaker 0: I'm pretty sure she's immortal.
Speaker 0: She's immortal for now.
Speaker 0: She hasn't finished her whatever yet whatever she's doing how whatever reason that she's a.
Speaker 1: You're saying that this happens.
Speaker 1: Well after the events of Galaxy Express and she got the gun back from Tetsuro after he died or way before.
Speaker 1: she already knows How did the if it's way before.
Speaker 1: how did the gun get back to tochiro's mom?
Speaker 1: cuz it's all a loop right now.
Speaker 1: That's bullshit.
Speaker 0: Why was the ship called emeraldus?
Speaker 0: Because it was yeah, even she's like.
Speaker 0: that seems like a crazy coincidence But it does make sense at least that you know they portray her as being immortal in that you know Everyone's afraid of her.
Speaker 0: everyone knows her legend wouldn't you be?
Speaker 0: She only kills you if you deserve it.
Speaker 1: The one thing that no Matsumoto work focuses on is that you have a lot that focuses on these characters like Harlock and emeraldus.
Speaker 1: and what?
Speaker 1: or and who?
Speaker 1: Are infamous throughout the galaxy or multiple galaxies?
Speaker 1: right the Galaxy Express goes to Andromeda, so it's at least two galaxies And these people are infamous everywhere like everyone who travels in space knows who they are.
Speaker 1: even people who don't travel in space know who?
Speaker 0: They are find some random speechless dinosaur and be like blah blah blah Harlock, and it'll be like Harlock.
Speaker 1: no, but space is big.
Speaker 1: You got to be really dangerous and really famous to be known throughout all of fucking space, right?
Speaker 1: It's like it's a big deal to be famous on Earth or even just part of it to be famous and infamous across space Whoa?
Speaker 1: It's like.
Speaker 1: they don't focus on how big a deal.
Speaker 1: that is enough.
Speaker 0: But I do appreciate like the way this one starts in the very beginning is.
Speaker 0: you know she appears and there's that hot guy Who's like a bounty hunter?
Speaker 0: Who's like?
Speaker 0: I'm max something max the wall And she shoots him immediately.
Speaker 0: But do that's?
Speaker 1: I mean that's another common theme in all Matsumoto things that in space if you want to survive just fucking shoot first.
Speaker 0: Yep, never wound an enemy.
Speaker 0: always kill anyone you fight with otherwise.
Speaker 1: They'll seek revenge right when they give Tetsuro a gun.
Speaker 1: It's like Tetsuro listen you want to survive in space and make it to Andromeda.
Speaker 0: She gives him a gun to fucking shoot people.
Speaker 0: the kid the the bartender gives him a gun.
Speaker 0: someone else gives this other kid a gun.
Speaker 0: I think he gives a kid a gun at one point.
Speaker 0: Everyone gives kids guns in this book never adults as always.
Speaker 0: I'm an adult.
Speaker 0: You're a kid.
Speaker 0: Here's your gun.
Speaker 1: That's right Kid I feel bad for you.
Speaker 1: I want you to succeed in space.
Speaker 1: You're gonna need a gun.
Speaker 1: Yeah, because you're a little kid and otherwise you're just gonna be also the guy.
Speaker 0: in the beginning I feel like the rules of space are a lot like the rule of the playground.
Speaker 0: Well, you gotta remember.
Speaker 0: There's also the space.
Speaker 0: is that good blah blah and kids like.
Speaker 0: so why don't we throw the captain out?
Speaker 0: Well, the rule of space is also that you can't throw the captain out So I'm gonna kill you and like that.
Speaker 0: the rule of space really is just kill anybody who's in your way no matter what?
Speaker 0: What was the guide like midway through who just murders everyone in that bar and the bartender's like man?
Speaker 0: That guy's so annoying.
Speaker 0: I wish someone would do something about him.
Speaker 1: I also got you know, you got to remember.
Speaker 1: part of this shooting thing right is because Matsumoto is like a military gun.
Speaker 1: You know otaku right, but you know one of the first things he did like in 1972 He did gun frontier Right, which is the guns which is.
Speaker 1: captain Harlock is a in a Western, right?
Speaker 1: So it's basically, you know, that's what Matsumoto does.
Speaker 1: he portrays space as a Western which is why you're just shooting people.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well, it's a Western with a trackless.
Speaker 0: It's just a right.
Speaker 1: It's just instead of instead of how to survive in the Old West kid.
Speaker 1: You're gonna need to shoot people survive in space.
Speaker 1: They just replace Old West with space and in gun frontier is.
Speaker 1: it is literally just a planet in space.
Speaker 1: That is like the Old West, you know, so.
Speaker 1: But actually I think that in gun frontier, it's like.
Speaker 1: actually Totoro is like the main character and Harlock is a sidekick.
Speaker 1: It's kind of it's.
Speaker 1: you should check it out.
Speaker 1: That's like.
Speaker 1: I think it's one of the only things like focuses on Totoro more and everything else.
Speaker 1: Totoro is like this mysterious, you know already dead soon-to-be-dead hiding and someone's looking for like in this one Emerald is like looking for him obviously, right?
Speaker 1: But he's like I'm looking for someone and I can't say and I'm like.
Speaker 1: I've seen other Matsumoto things.
Speaker 1: I know it's Totoro that you're looking.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it can't be anyone else.
Speaker 1: Who else would you look for?
Speaker 1: Nobody?
Speaker 1: There's no one else you even know.
Speaker 0: Yep, but she's mysterious.
Speaker 0: She won't tell anyone her deal except this kid and once she tells him she's gonna kill it.
Speaker 1: That's the part.
Speaker 1: I don't.
Speaker 1: that's actually I don't know is like why does she have to kill?
Speaker 1: Why is she helping him if she knows she's gonna have to kill him someday?
Speaker 0: Well, there are at least now two and why will she have to kill him?
Speaker 0: There are now two Leiji Matsumoto stories where Wayfish blonde woman with power comes from the sky leads a kid on an epic journey Only to then betray and/or kill him or at least That's what they're going to do.
Speaker 1: It's Queen millennia, which is also that story.
Speaker 1: Okay, so three That's that's the story he tells.
Speaker 1: That's what you get.
Speaker 0: it's not a bad story though, right?
Speaker 1: I mean space battleship Yamato is only different and that there's no kid.
Speaker 1: It's all of them go in her ship together.
Speaker 1: It's like everyone together let's go and all the other ones are.
Speaker 0: a little kid has to go and a woman takes it All right The captain who's about to kill him and then he reaches for his gun and it's not like he dropped it.
Speaker 0: He's like, oh wait My gun fell out of my holster.
Speaker 0: I'm unarmed.
Speaker 0: that violates the law of space BAM and he just shoots him in the gut.
Speaker 1: That's the law of space.
Speaker 1: Yeah shoot him first.
Speaker 0: I Like how the kids kind of like a little bit of a shithead, right?
Speaker 1: It's like, you know, Tetsuro is sort of like, you know brave.
Speaker 1: he's like he like he want, you know He wants to avenge, you know, his murdered mother, right?
Speaker 1: I guess he has a like a noble purpose.
Speaker 0: almost right story is also known from the beginning Like.
Speaker 0: we know why he's mad like we know his back.
Speaker 1: He's so small at the beginning to his little potato Yeah, but this kid was his name Ushio.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right, whatever his name is I care about him a lot less than Tetsuro and I like him less than Tetsuro because he's just sort of angry Like he just wants to build a spaceship to go into space and you don't know why.
Speaker 1: and maybe if we find out why maybe He probably has a Tetsuro similar tragic story.
Speaker 1: That'll make you like he.
Speaker 0: obviously there's a flashback where he was reliving his memories And his mom was just hoping he'd die.
Speaker 0: and there was all that nonsense with the money, right?
Speaker 1: But you know Tetsuro like, you know, so he liked his parents.
Speaker 1: They got killed horribly.
Speaker 0: This is depending on what year this is.
Speaker 0: in the Legio Matsumoto verse.
Speaker 0: I mean how many humans are there versus immortals?
Speaker 0: I mean he says he's from earth.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I Mean there was.
Speaker 1: you could be on earth in you know, all of them pretty much, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, earth is a very different place though.
Speaker 0: Maybe depending which part of you might be a real bad place.
Speaker 1: I think earth was the worst place like the beginning of the second Galaxy Express movie where there's like a it's like a Cyberdystopia and there's an act of rebellion everywhere.
Speaker 1: Yeah Humans versus robot people just shooting in the streets all the time, you know, we can fix that problem with the dirty humes.
Speaker 0: Yeah But the killer I don't know if you if you haven't read any lazy Matsumoto stuff at all or watched any yeah Maybe just start with this.
Speaker 1: you can start with anything.
Speaker 1: It doesn't matter It's the same story crook slightly.
Speaker 0: So I would say if you want a long show to watch just start watching Galaxy Express.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean, I actually think the first thing to watch is space battleship, right?
Speaker 1: Cuz if you if you watch that you're starting like that doesn't connect as much with other things.
Speaker 1: And I think it's the earliest thing not necessarily in terms of timeline But in terms of period.
Speaker 0: but I feel like the average like anime manga fan in America At least if you know who even know who Matsumoto is.
Speaker 1: you vaguely imagine all the things that look like this Yep, there's a tall blonde girl and if it looks like if it looks like interstellar 555, that's who it is.
Speaker 0: Everyone's got a scar and everyone's brooding.
Speaker 0: I Don't know I just I really like lazy Matsumoto nonsense, but it's kind of Disposable in that it's all just this sort of cycling vague stories about men standing and being.
Speaker 1: it's like once you've seen enough You've seen them all right.
Speaker 1: So you just have to see enough.
Speaker 1: But enough is quite a bit right because there is a significant variation that goes on.
Speaker 0: Yep well, this volume at least in this manga has a good bit of the Really silly nonsense and they're ridiculous melodrama as well.
Speaker 0: Like that's all there everyone This kid meets.
Speaker 0: it's like go on I will die or whatever.
Speaker 0: But I see that you will go on to do the thing that you want to do and I want you to do that Right.
Speaker 1: I mean in Galaxy Express Tetsuro goes from planet to planet on the train.
Speaker 0: have?
Speaker 0: those planets are like fuck you.
Speaker 1: Each planet is like some moral dilemma and conflict and they have to run back to the train on time Existential crisis at that moment and each planet is like a totally different episodic deal in this.
Speaker 1: Instead of going for planets a planet on the train He's trying to build a ship and his ship crashes into every planet, right?
Speaker 1: He just he builds he fixes his ship and then manages to get to another plan.
Speaker 1: Then he crashes where he finds another problem and that until he can manage to take off and get back into space again.
Speaker 0: but in Galaxy Express them landing sort of Catalyzes the transformation of the planet for good or bad, right?
Speaker 1: I mean if you're on a planet and the Galaxy Express alert arrives fuck just like the robot carnival show.
Speaker 1: It's like.
Speaker 1: it's like the the you know, the news of the century like oh my god the trains here Holy shit.
Speaker 1: If it's an express, why did it stop at our backwater planet which is like a movie?
Speaker 0: what's happening?
Speaker 1: Is that why the movie makes more sense?
Speaker 1: Cuz in the movie they get to Andromeda real fast like a real Express.
Speaker 0: Well, it's an Express.
Speaker 0: It's only stopping at the big planets.
Speaker 0: The local probably takes like a thousand years to get to the end.
Speaker 1: Every planet along the way.
Speaker 1: TV show.
Speaker 1: it stops all the local planets.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: Maybe there's more planets I don't know.
Speaker 0: the TV show the galaxy local.
Speaker 0: nine nine.
Speaker 0: Anyway, yeah, this is good stuff.
Speaker 1: I'm just happy there's some you know, we'll get to read some Matsumoto manga's in English easily.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I hope that they go and get all the other ones.
Speaker 1: if we enough of us buy this one I like a hardcover and put in the extra bits.
Speaker 0: this is it's following the sort of back and forth where it's like 50% the kid doing his stuff and Everyone like pat him on the back giving him a gun and then dying to push him forward even though they just met him Except that one girl who doesn't murder him, but then she gets what's coming to her.
Speaker 0: But meanwhile, you've got 50% emerald is being mysterious and push.
Speaker 1: if it was a hundred percent emerald issue wouldn't be mysterious, right?
Speaker 1: That's how it has to be right.
Speaker 1: you Keep the secretive may tell or the secret of Harlock if like you're focusing on them all the time You got to focus on all the other people and then the mysterious awesome Powerful character has to almost be like this force of nature that comes through.
Speaker 0: but I feel like she is more Powerful than some of those other people at least in terms of she doesn't resolve situations with even a modicum of danger.
Speaker 0: She's like D and vampire hunter D. Yeah, which nothing wrong with that.
Speaker 0: I love the hell out of vampire hunter D Even though the plot is literally.
Speaker 0: D wins a fight because he's stronger and then he wins another fight because he's stronger and then up He's gonna lose a fight.
Speaker 0: Nope turned out.
Speaker 0: He was stronger.
Speaker 1: the end If you're infamous throughout space that's about as strong as you have to be yup and To not be dead where everyone's just shooting everybody.
Speaker 0: So yeah, if you're looking for a Matsumoto fix just pick up these hardcovers.
Speaker 0: Good art good typical like it's just it's monster.
Speaker 0: It's more lazy Matsumoto.
Speaker 0: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott.
Speaker 0: special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leaf for web design and brand Ok for the logos.
Speaker 1: be sure to visit our website at front row crew comm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 0: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 1: But unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night.
Speaker 0: the patreon patrons for this episode of geek nights in order of the amount of money that gives them continuing basis lungs that amounts over $5 are Alan Joyce Rebecca Dunn Nicholas, Brenda Logan Stafford, Heidi McNichol Amanda to shed James David White Christian coons construction noises.
Speaker 0: my state I'm Sean Hayworth Willie my summers Jeremy minor Chris Reimer and Thomas on.
Speaker 0: Oh Scott your beard tickles when we kiss Erin Cerise Brian Fisher sailor Vista Sigourney Weaver's finest hour Iggy kid Matthew Smith Don Schleich jar Tovish and Joshua Joe star.
Speaker 0: Tyler Eller Sean Yeager Sam Cordery Clinton Walton.
Speaker 0: written from New Zealand.
Speaker 0: Ryan parent drew open letter.
Speaker 0: rare Laval Brian's at Roni Rochelle, Montana.
Speaker 0: Finn Eric silver on the rural juror.
Speaker 0: Chris midkiff Chris Knox Daniel Redmond Sean Klein Chris Reimer and Thomas Hahn.
Speaker 0: the civilization game appears to be full.
Speaker 0: I'm going to Hopefully by the weekend set up the game and send people invites and get that going and I'll be recording all my turn But like I said can't necessarily share those turns with you guys till the game progresses a bit.
Speaker 0: Otherwise, there probably won't be episodes next week because of packs But we'll be generating a lot of other content along the way.
Speaker 0: those of you who are on patreon Don't forget that Emily and I both reviewed and did some final thoughts on Kubo and the two strings and we'll be doing a lot More roomly reviews as time goes on.
Speaker 0: so stay tuned.
Speaker 0: and now I leave you with something Puppies and socks filled with cream and candy rocks.
Speaker 0: Oh potatoes and molasses.
Speaker 0: If your stomach is crumbling and your mouth starts mumbling There's only one thing to keep your brain from crumbling.
Speaker 1: Oh potatoes and molasses.
Speaker 1: If you can't see and put on your glasses, they're shiny and large like a fisherman's barge.
Speaker 1: You know you eat enough when you start seeing stuff.
Speaker 1: Oh potatoes and molasses.
Speaker 0: It's the only thing left on your tusk list.
Speaker 0: They're short and stout to make everyone shout for potatoes Molasses For potatoes.