Speaker 0: It's Wednesday, April 19th, 2017.
Speaker 0: I'm Rym.
Speaker 1: I'm Scott.
Speaker 0: And this is Geek Nights.
Speaker 0: Tonight, your name.
Speaker 0: Pretty much the biggest anime movie ever.
Speaker 1: What's the Japanese title?
Speaker 0: Kimi no Noah.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: So a notable feature of my life in this apartment building.
Speaker 0: We've lived here since like 2009.
Speaker 0: And the building has a bike room.
Speaker 0: And a couple years ago I think we got a better bike room.
Speaker 1: We've talked about this bike room in the past years.
Speaker 0: When we moved in, the building was all like less than a year old.
Speaker 0: It was a brand new building.
Speaker 0: And there was a bike that I noticed in the bike room because it was like in the way of a good spot.
Speaker 0: And both tires were flat.
Speaker 0: Like completely flat.
Speaker 0: Like hanging off the rims.
Speaker 0: And after like a year of that bike never moving and always being there, one day I moved it and I put my bike in the much better place.
Speaker 0: Literally the next time I went to use my bike, that bike was back in that spot.
Speaker 0: But let's fast forward to today.
Speaker 0: So the number of years between 2009 and 2017 and whoever owns that bike moved it on the first day.
Speaker 0: the new bike room was open into the new bike room.
Speaker 0: Because you had to move your bike yourself.
Speaker 1: And the tires have never been not flat.
Speaker 0: The tires are not only completely flat but now the cabling for the brakes is like loose.
Speaker 0: And it looks like everything, like stuff is rotted and just broken.
Speaker 0: The bike is literally unusable.
Speaker 0: And a couple days ago I moved it off of the peg because it happens to be hung on the peg next to our bikes.
Speaker 0: And it's always in the way because since the tires are flat it like leans in over our bikes.
Speaker 0: So I just took it off because it's not locked up or anything.
Speaker 0: And I put it on the floor.
Speaker 0: And I have not yet checked today to see if the person has moved it back.
Speaker 1: If you haven't checked, then why are you telling the story now?
Speaker 1: You gotta tell the story after the final checking.
Speaker 0: No, because I'm never gonna reveal what the answer is.
Speaker 1: Oh, that's good too.
Speaker 0: I'm just gonna leave it open forever.
Speaker 1: That's also fine.
Speaker 0: The moral is, why does this person own a bike?
Speaker 1: It's not really a moral.
Speaker 1: No, the real question here is not like, I can understand.
Speaker 1: Okay, the person has a really shitty bike.
Speaker 1: They're planning to fix it someday.
Speaker 1: They just haven't.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know, like if you live in the suburbs, you got busted shit in your garage that you don't throw away.
Speaker 1: Exactly, but that part makes perfect sense.
Speaker 1: It's not crazy.
Speaker 1: But they're moving it so reliably.
Speaker 1: The crazy part is that the person is going in to check on it so frequently.
Speaker 1: They're not using it.
Speaker 1: What the fuck are they doing with it?
Speaker 1: Why are they going to look at it?
Speaker 1: If you have a busted bike in your garage, you're gonna fix one day.
Speaker 1: You basically never, ever, ever look at it.
Speaker 0: Or if you see it, you feel ashamed.
Speaker 0: You either hide it or you fix it.
Speaker 0: If it's like right out in the center, someone might be like...
Speaker 1: Maybe they're doing some sort of time lapse thing, where every day they take a photo of it getting more busted.
Speaker 0: Or maybe there's an alternate podcast out there where this dude is like, "So I got this shitty bike and I'm just fucking with these people who seem to take a weird interest in
Speaker 0: it.".
Speaker 1: I'm using it to hold a spot in the bike room for when I get a good bike.
Speaker 1: And I check every day to make sure.
Speaker 0: But I haven't gotten that new bike yet because I'm saving up my pennies.
Speaker 0: Bike's on layaway.
Speaker 0: That's my story.
Speaker 0: Because I promised I wouldn't tell any fixie stories.
Speaker 0: This bike is not a fixie.
Speaker 0: It's just a heavy-ass steel tube... I don't know, bike?
Speaker 1: Piece of rust?
Speaker 1: Does it even count as a bike?
Speaker 0: There's only rust.
Speaker 0: The only rust on it is on the brake cables.
Speaker 0: Alright.
Speaker 1: Not bad.
Speaker 1: Not the worst I've seen.
Speaker 1: Far from the worst I've seen.
Speaker 0: It's been a couple days.
Speaker 0: I really want to see if they have put it back on its pay.
Speaker 1: Why didn't you see on your way into the building?
Speaker 0: I gotta go down there.
Speaker 0: I just didn't bother.
Speaker 1: You were just down there on your way up.
Speaker 0: No, it's one floor down.
Speaker 0: It's in the basement.
Speaker 0: There's a giant-ass room down there.
Speaker 0: In fact, the room's so big, I'm doing bike maintenance down there now.
Speaker 0: It's basically like my personal workshop.
Speaker 0: I even hid tools because there's a bunch of tool chests of contractors and things.
Speaker 0: I just got some tools down there.
Speaker 1: Whatever.
Speaker 1: So, I don't have any real news action going on, but I want to talk about this anime called Kimono Friends.
Speaker 1: Not Kimono that you wear.
Speaker 0: Well, that would be Kimono.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right.
Speaker 1: This is Kimono.
Speaker 1: K-E-M-O-N-O.
Speaker 1: And this is a show that I heard lots of buzz about on the interwebs.
Speaker 1: And I saw a lot of tweets, you know, with pictures from the show.
Speaker 1: And so, I was thinking, "Huh.
Speaker 1: I don't know anything about
Speaker 1: this.".
Speaker 1: But the internet is giving me that sort of Madoka feel.
Speaker 1: Everyone's talking about a thing that I ignored.
Speaker 1: There must be something up with it.
Speaker 0: And I remember very clearly because Dragon Maid kind of had like this initial, like everyone's talking about it.
Speaker 0: And then everybody shut up about that show.
Speaker 0: And it was nothing but Kimono Friends on Twitter.
Speaker 0: Like, within the span of a couple weeks.
Speaker 1: So, there was a time where I was sitting down with a Crunchyroll, and I'm like, "Huh.
Speaker 1: Let's watch something.
Speaker 1: Oh, I know.
Speaker 1: I'll watch that thing that everyone talked about.
Speaker 1: Let's pull up episode
Speaker 1: one.".
Speaker 1: And I've watched only episode one.
Speaker 0: I watched a couple of random, not whole episode, basically I went to later episodes and kind of did the skim through and see if anything's going on.
Speaker 1: So, what I had to say about this show is it is not good.
Speaker 1: Why are all you people-- I can sort of see why people are obsessed with it, right?
Speaker 0: Dude, it's got better ratings than like half the anime on Animator's Network.
Speaker 1: I can see in the plot, there's definitely some sort of mystery.
Speaker 1: Like,
Speaker 1: "Ooh."
Speaker 1: I'm going to spoil the whole first episode.
Speaker 1: You know, deal with it, right?
Speaker 0: Humans are the unknown animal, the end.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 1: There's clearly this Safari Zone, right?
Speaker 1: But the Safari Zone is dilapidated.
Speaker 1: It's clearly some sort of post-apocalyptic world where all the animals have become furry animals, right?
Speaker 0: People animals, but-- They're not really furries.
Speaker 0: They're more like Nekomimi types.
Speaker 1: Whatever, but this actual person, or at least as far as we can tell, actual person, they could have animal parts that are covered up by their clothes.
Speaker 0: I feel like if they explore, there already is a show that explores if there's animal parts covered up by their clothes, and that's that Monster Musume show.
Speaker 1: But anyway, this actual person who's not an animal person appears in this place with no memories and befriends some animal person.
Speaker 0: The serval girl, I guess.
Speaker 0: And they're all like, "What the fuck are
Speaker 0: you?".
Speaker 1: And they start exploring and meeting animal friends and learning about the world, and there's also these weird jelly monsters that are something mystical or some connection, obviously, with the post-apocalypse stuff, and there's a mystery there.
Speaker 1: So people are into it because they want to know what the mystery is.
Speaker 1: I don't give a shit.
Speaker 1: I've seen enough post-apocalyptic shows with terrible secrets of space.
Speaker 0: The thing is, if you want a weird show that has some of those vibes, I can name a lot of better shows.
Speaker 1: Every good anime ever.
Speaker 0: And if you want cute, funny animals, guys, Damaka Dobutsu exists.
Speaker 0: Just watch that over and over again.
Speaker 1: So this show, the animation is not the worst, but it's awful.
Speaker 0: Well, it's not low budget.
Speaker 1: 2 out of 10.
Speaker 0: It is low budget.
Speaker 1: Lowest budget, crap CG, garbajo.
Speaker 0: You might think it looks good in stills.
Speaker 1: The character designs aren't bad, right?
Speaker 1: It's just the animation, the movement and the quality is not good.
Speaker 1: The acting is just...
Speaker 0: The show is slow and repetitive.
Speaker 0: You know what it reminds me of?
Speaker 0: Binchotan.
Speaker 1: Yeah, this is just some... Remember that?
Speaker 1: Yeah, this is just some garbajo anime.
Speaker 1: I don't know why it became a big deal.
Speaker 1: It's not... Like, Monika is like 9 point, almost 10 out of 10.
Speaker 1: And this is like 2 or 3 out of 10 at best as a whole show.
Speaker 0: So by following Anna Twitter and kind of really paying attention...
Speaker 1: Is it just an ironic meme?
Speaker 1: What's the deal?
Speaker 0: So, it's interesting because I found this article while I was looking up some info on it.
Speaker 0: Because one, Kimono Friends, the story of how and why it got made is actually kind of weird and interesting.
Speaker 0: But the gist of it is, it was like a crass marketing ploy where this really dumb, simple, low budget show was basically a giant ad for this bigger property with a phone game, like a video game.
Speaker 1: Like a hack sign thing?
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Quote, "But it wasn't until the series began airing that the project really caught fire.
Speaker 0: The smartphone game was released in March of 2015 and ended its service shortly before the anime series began
Speaker 0: airing.".
Speaker 1: So they made an anime to promote a phone game.
Speaker 0: The phone game came and went.
Speaker 1: The phone game came and went, but they kept making the anime anyway.
Speaker 1: The anime was just an ad for the phone game.
Speaker 1: And now the anime is doing well on its own?
Speaker 0: Yup.
Speaker 0: And this article...
Speaker 1: I did read something.
Speaker 1: This isn't just an American fan thing.
Speaker 1: For some reason...
Speaker 0: No, this show is going crazy.
Speaker 1: I read something that said there was a pop-up store, a temporary shop, that's selling Kimono Friends merch.
Speaker 1: And everything in the store, except for audio CDs, sold out.
Speaker 0: Yeah, in two days.
Speaker 1: Because who buys audio CDs, even if they're your favorite thing ever?
Speaker 0: And the merch looks like typical AnimeCon stuff, except it's all Kimono Friends.
Speaker 1: Sure.
Speaker 0: And you know, the character designs are cute.
Speaker 0: I can see why people would be into that aspect of it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean, the show isn't... I didn't give it a zero, right?
Speaker 1: It's not the worst ever, but it's bad.
Speaker 1: I'm not gonna put any more watching time in my life into this.
Speaker 0: I've enjoyed watching other people talk about it.
Speaker 0: I've enjoyed animated gifs from it.
Speaker 1: I mean, I enjoy animated gifs from pretty much anything.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So this article on Anime Now, which is where I got that quote from, it goes a little more into the story of how it came to be and what's going on here.
Speaker 0: But this article tries to explain why it's so popular in Japan and also among... I don't want to say normal anime fans, because normal American anime fans have no idea what the hell this is.
Speaker 0: This is like, if you go to AnimeCons and you're in anime culture, those are the kinds of people talking about this show.
Speaker 1: If you're an anime person, this show's the biggest deal.
Speaker 1: If you're not an anime person, you're just a person who might watch anime.
Speaker 0: If you're just watching Boruto.
Speaker 1: You don't know what this is.
Speaker 0: You know about Boruto, right?
Speaker 0: Naruto's son?
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I could just put "bort license
Speaker 0: plates."
Speaker 0: Bort.
Speaker 0: But this article basically, and this is not the only article that has expressed basically the same sentiment, says that the reason it's popular is because it's earnest and simple and it lets you forget about the bad world around you.
Speaker 0: It basically gives the case that perverts give for why they watch moe shows, where they want to make it very clear that they are not watching it for perverted reasons.
Speaker 0: So, they're saying that because it's just fluff and there's basically nothing going on, that is why it's so popular.
Speaker 0: I feel like the only reason it's popular among the Anna Twitter types is because Cat girls?
Speaker 0: All the background clues are that humans are gone, post-apocalyptic.
Speaker 0: You see bombs, Adventure Time type stuff in the background all over the place.
Speaker 1: So it has fanboy appeal?
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Bombs, cat girls, cute things.
Speaker 1: Everything fanboys like.
Speaker 0: I think the best thing that came out of this show, other than me being able to talk about Dama Kidobatsu again and remind people to watch that, is that someone did a whole bunch of really good illustrations of mashing this up with Galaxy Express 3 9.
Speaker 0: Really?
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 0: They're real good because that's Mettalu and that's the kid and it's really good.
Speaker 1: Tetsuro?
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: That's it.
Speaker 0: That's the best I've gotten out of this.
Speaker 0: Maybe you guys could convince me that I gotta go back and watch more of it, but I'm not convinced and I've read every spoiler and I have dug through later episodes.
Speaker 1: I mean, I'm watching your petal, which is not good.
Speaker 1: It's just a thing I'm into, but it's bad.
Speaker 1: It's barely better than Initial D. And I'm not gonna watch Kimono Friends.
Speaker 1: That's how bad Kimono Friends is.
Speaker 0: I would probably finish Dragon Maid before I would watch more Kimono Friends, to be perfectly honest.
Speaker 1: If I had to watch...
Speaker 0: But the same people who were really talking up Dragon Maid were the ones who jumped off that ship to this one.
Speaker 1: That's actually a tough call for me, right?
Speaker 1: Because on the one hand, I think they're pretty much even in my desire to watch more of them, which is not at all.
Speaker 0: Dragon Maid's funnier and better animated.
Speaker 1: That's true, but I do care about the... I mean, as much as I said, there's a stupid mystery, that's what everyone cares about, and I don't care.
Speaker 1: I've seen enough of those.
Speaker 1: It's still a thing, right?
Speaker 1: And that's about equal.
Speaker 1: That level is about equal to the level of what's that mystery going on in Dragon Maid with the sword.
Speaker 1: It's like they're about equal mysteries.
Speaker 1: I don't care about either one, but if I gotta pick one, it's like, "Oh, they're so
Speaker 1: even.".
Speaker 0: Well, think back to Attack on Titan, and even to an extent, the original Fullmetal Alchemist.
Speaker 0: Both those shows, I was really into, and then when they were done, or there wasn't more to watch...
Speaker 1: Stop caring.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I just didn't care at all.
Speaker 0: And Attack on Titan, unlike Fullmetal Alchemist, pretty sure that show ain't going anywhere.
Speaker 1: I went with the manga even further.
Speaker 0: I read every spoiler from the manga up until the new anime came out.
Speaker 0: Every one of the answers that you get in the show after the anime ends, the first season, not worth it, not good.
Speaker 1: If anyone wants a big stack of Attack on Titan manga, I got it.
Speaker 1: You can have it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but it came back, and I realized that everyone who's talking about it really seems to only care about finding out what the deal is with the crap.
Speaker 1: Just read the spoilers and save time in your life to do something more productive.
Speaker 0: I think you're better off not reading the spoilers, because every answer to every question you come up with is way less satisfying than whatever you were going to make up on your own.
Speaker 1: Oh, so just make something up on your own and be productive, and then pretend that that's the real deal.
Speaker 0: Pretend the show's just about the potato girl, and that's it.
Speaker 0: In other news, we're going to talk about Your Name, which is a fantastic movie, but it's not just us saying it's a fantastic movie.
Speaker 0: If you were not aware, Your Name is...
Speaker 1: Shouldn't we talk about this in the main bit?
Speaker 0: No, so Your Name did crazy, crazy.
Speaker 0: well.
Speaker 1: I was going to talk about that during the main bit.
Speaker 1: You're taking time away from the main bit.
Speaker 0: Alright, then I'll be very short on this.
Speaker 0: It's the fourth highest grossing film of all time in Japan.
Speaker 0: It's a big deal.
Speaker 0: That includes foreign films that screen in Japan, and it is the second highest grossing Japanese film ever.
Speaker 1: As in a film that was made by a Japanese movie studio.
Speaker 0: And it is still in theaters, but the news is that it's not just Your Name, so Toho also made Shin Godzilla.
Speaker 1: Anytime you see a movie, and at the beginning of the movie, there's that circle.
Speaker 0: Oh yeah, that kanji.
Speaker 0: It's one big kanji.
Speaker 1: That kanji that says "guaranteed good
Speaker 1: movie."
Speaker 1: And apparently "guaranteed good movie" in Japanese is Toho.
Speaker 1: That's how you say that.
Speaker 0: Toho is making crazy money.
Speaker 0: They have set record profits due primarily to Your Name and Shin Godzilla.
Speaker 0: And they have made record profits every year for I think three years in a row.
Speaker 0: So we talk about all these different things that have saved anime over and over again.
Speaker 0: I feel like Toho/Your Name is what has actually saved anime.
Speaker 0: Your Name has transcended the traditional boundaries that anime tends to run up against on the global stage.
Speaker 0: And this movie is getting legit wide traction.
Speaker 1: There's another symbol you may have seen.
Speaker 1: It's when there's water splashing on some rocks with this triangle.
Speaker 1: That says "almost guaranteed good
Speaker 1: movie."
Speaker 1: Not quite as good as the circle.
Speaker 0: Oh, I had a thing of the day.
Speaker 0: I keep forgetting to use.
Speaker 0: I gotta go find it again.
Speaker 1: Someone went to the rocks?
Speaker 0: Yeah, they found the spot.
Speaker 1: That's old.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and the rocks are mostly the same.
Speaker 0: They're a little worn down, but they found the exact spot.
Speaker 0: And then they confirmed with the studio that that was the spot.
Speaker 1: Yes, we know the spot.
Speaker 1: I've seen that.
Speaker 1: It's years and years old.
Speaker 0: I've never used this as my thing of the day.
Speaker 1: I think we may have actually.
Speaker 1: I don't think we did.
Speaker 1: I think we did like 2,000 long times.
Speaker 0: But anyway, things of the day.
Speaker 0: So I was thinking about anime cons and anime music videos recently.
Speaker 0: And I've noticed that anime, anime music videos, not nearly as popular as they used to be.
Speaker 0: Not the biggest part of the conventions that they used to be.
Speaker 0: And there's a whole thing we could do about that.
Speaker 1: You found a good one?
Speaker 0: No, but independently, I've just noticed that there have been a lot of things.
Speaker 0: And there's a lot more of them now than there used to be.
Speaker 0: that are basically AMVs.
Speaker 0: But they're not anime.
Speaker 0: It's like that culture has expanded to everything but anime.
Speaker 0: But what I noticed looking through AMVs and then these newer things on YouTube.
Speaker 0: Is that AMVs get very few views.
Speaker 0: Even very expectedly popular ones.
Speaker 0: But the exact same thing done with like Western cartoons or just movies lately.
Speaker 0: Is getting tons and tons and tons and tons of views.
Speaker 0: And I realize I've just been watching a lot of these things without even really thinking about it.
Speaker 0: So my thing of the day is just this really good AMV swimming pools drank Rick and Morty.
Speaker 0: It's actually pretty good.
Speaker 0: All the things you used to watch AMVs for apply to this stuff.
Speaker 0: And AMVs are... I think they're going to disappear from the con scene.
Speaker 0: Or at least they're going to become niche and they will be to anime cons.
Speaker 1: They've already become niche.
Speaker 1: That's already happened.
Speaker 0: No, within the anime con scene, because they still put them in the big rooms.
Speaker 0: I feel like it won't be too long before they fill the spot that those 12 guys playing Warhammer fill at a mid-sized gaming convention.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so there's this thing I never heard of before until just by luck I came across this.
Speaker 1: So British Pathe.
Speaker 1: Or it's spelled P-A-T-H and then the E has one of those accents on it.
Speaker 0: What direction is the accent going?
Speaker 0: Up or down?
Speaker 1: To the right.
Speaker 0: To the right up?
Speaker 1: Up to the right.
Speaker 0: Accent to you.
Speaker 0: So A.
Speaker 1: Anyway, that's weird because that's a French thing, but the first word is the word British.
Speaker 1: Anyway, it's considered to be the finest newsreel archive in the world as a treasure trove of 85,000 films, unrivaled in their historical and cultural significance, spanning from 1896 to 1976.
Speaker 1: It's a big treasure trove of newsreels, right?
Speaker 1: These people, British Pathe or whatever, they keep this because people who want to use these films pay them for rights.
Speaker 1: It's all rights reserved.
Speaker 1: It's not some public thing.
Speaker 1: It's just like they have this huge library of newsreels and if you want to use one, you give them money.
Speaker 1: And if you're a teacher or broadcaster or any reason you would need one of those, you give them money and you use it.
Speaker 1: So that's great.
Speaker 1: What does that matter?
Speaker 1: Well, I came across by, I don't even know how, their YouTube channel.
Speaker 1: Ooh.
Speaker 1: Their YouTube channel is basically a gold mine, a very large gold mine.
Speaker 1: Perhaps it's even a platinum mine, you could say.
Speaker 1: So here is one thing from this platinum mine, one nugget of ore to give you a taste.
Speaker 0: Give me my nugget.
Speaker 1: This is video from 1966 at Charlie Chaplin's 77th birthday where they made a cake that looks like him.
Speaker 1: And there's mad famous people there, mad famous people, some of which are still children at the party.
Speaker 1: And they have, I don't think all their films are on YouTube, but the other stuff they have on YouTube is of this quality.
Speaker 0: That is real high quality right there.
Speaker 0: That's not just chocolate, that's white chocolate.
Speaker 1: You could just stop watching all anime, all whatever it is that you're doing and spend the rest of your time and guess until you run out of their YouTube material.
Speaker 1: A lot of that's going to be better than whatever else is out there.
Speaker 0: I got to turn those into AMVs.
Speaker 1: Go for it.
Speaker 1: It's only four minutes long.
Speaker 0: In the meta moment, the Book Club book is Frank Erbert's Dune and we're going to do it way later because we're still playing Zelda and I'm not going to even start reading that book.
Speaker 1: I haven't even played Zelda in like a week because it's too busy.
Speaker 0: Shit is lit.
Speaker 0: I had the Master Sword for a long time.
Speaker 0: Now I'm doing the bird people, the great beast right now.
Speaker 1: I already took care of that.
Speaker 0: I went over to do the desert one and then multiple people have warned me that if I go mess with the Yiga Clan, the ninja problem gets way worse.
Speaker 1: It's true.
Speaker 1: Once I defeated the Yiga Clan, everywhere else in the world, ninjas just keep appearing randomly all the time.
Speaker 0: So I'm letting them be for now and I'm going to go.
Speaker 0: I got plenty of mighty thistles and I'm going to take care of the other two guardians first.
Speaker 1: I'm sorry because I'm pretty good at killing them now.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Well, if you got a long stick, it's real easy to kill those guys.
Speaker 1: It depends.
Speaker 1: The arrow ones I can kill with arrows and the fighting ones, you know.
Speaker 0: The fighting ones I just end up poking with a spear and they're gone.
Speaker 0: There's nothing they can do.
Speaker 1: You haven't fought the big ones.
Speaker 0: No, I have not fought the big ones.
Speaker 0: But I beat a bunch of big guardians.
Speaker 0: so I got all these like gigantic guardian plus plus swords.
Speaker 1: Yeah, guardian plus plus swords are trash and are really only good against guardians.
Speaker 1: They're not really good against anything else.
Speaker 1: They also break really quickly.
Speaker 0: Yep, so two of them have that durable bonus on them.
Speaker 1: That barely helps.
Speaker 0: I've been using one for a while.
Speaker 0: It's still going.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I'm collecting guardian bits.
Speaker 1: I just need some gears and a pile of money and I'm going to get the ancient armor.
Speaker 0: I have more than 50 gears.
Speaker 1: Which basically makes me invincible.
Speaker 1: But then I think I need like a pile of diamonds to upgrade it to the max level.
Speaker 0: Ugh, diamonds.
Speaker 0: I need way more diamonds.
Speaker 0: Otherwise, we are going to be at, well, I'm going to be at because Scott is skipping it, Zenkai Con.
Speaker 0: At the end of the month, Saturday, I'll be doing grinding mechanics and game design.
Speaker 0: It's the one you've seen before.
Speaker 0: And I'm also doing foreign anime openers.
Speaker 0: The condensed mega version of only the best of.
Speaker 0: And on Sunday, I'm doing flip the table, rage quitting in games, and then I'm coming home.
Speaker 0: Otherwise, Kineticon, if you haven't submitted your panels and you want to perform a panel at Kineticon, submit it basically like right now because I'm literally filling in the schedule.
Speaker 0: Like, every night I'm putting panels in their spots.
Speaker 0: The longer you wait, the shittier your spot's going to be.
Speaker 0: I pretty much schedule everything myself and I'm just scheduling.
Speaker 0: I'm not waiting for it.
Speaker 0: I wait for no man.
Speaker 1: He waits for women though.
Speaker 0: I wait for.
Speaker 0: no they.
Speaker 1: No they?
Speaker 1: No human?
Speaker 0: No human.
Speaker 1: He's waiting for alien.
Speaker 0: If a xenomorph submits a panel, they're going in the small room because they have to keep that contained.
Speaker 1: He's waiting for a tiger.
Speaker 0: I give him a panel.
Speaker 1: Waiting for a tiger.
Speaker 1: Rawr.
Speaker 0: Did you see someone, because everyone's freaking out about how hot Sidon is in Zelda, the shark guy.
Speaker 1: They're still freaking out about him?
Speaker 0: So someone drew, I just saw this.
Speaker 0: It was the similar art of the cat guy equivalent of that like tiger guy.
Speaker 0: It's just a full tiger for a head.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: So I saw your name, actually a long time ago, because I just was on a flight.
Speaker 1: It wasn't a long time ago.
Speaker 0: It was months ago.
Speaker 1: It's not a long time.
Speaker 0: That's a long time ago.
Speaker 1: And I actually- In the dark ages.
Speaker 0: It was good enough to where, when it came to the US in theaters, and Scott and Emily of course wanted to go see it, I was 100% ready to just see it again and to see it in the theater in glorious high res.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean, so Makoto Shinkai, we've talked about him before, but I guess in case someone's new, we'll talk about him again, right?
Speaker 1: He's a guy who I think with his wife made an anime in their basement on their own.
Speaker 1: And it was good enough that he got to make more animes, and eventually he made, I guess the breakout anime was Hoshino Koe.
Speaker 0: Voices of a Distant Star.
Speaker 1: Which I think we've done an episode on.
Speaker 0: So let's see, Voices of a Distant Star is about lovers separated by space and time.
Speaker 0: Then there's The Place Promised in Early Days, which is about lovers separated by space, time, and possibly dimensions.
Speaker 0: Five Centuries for a Second, which is a short show of three episodes, which is lovers separated- I think it's also a manga.
Speaker 0: Lovers separated by space and time.
Speaker 0: Children of Chase lost Miyazaki movies, which is just a knockoff Miyazaki movie.
Speaker 1: We couldn't tell.
Speaker 1: We saw that.
Speaker 1: When we saw that, he was there.
Speaker 1: I'm sure there's Geek Nights episodes about all these things.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: We reviewed all these.
Speaker 0: He was there.
Speaker 1: We went to see him.
Speaker 1: He talked at a panel, and also after showing us that movie, I really barely remember that movie.
Speaker 1: It was like, "Go to a fantasy world.
Speaker 1: Weird shit happens.
Speaker 1: The
Speaker 1: end.".
Speaker 1: I had no idea what the hell it was, and I don't have no desire to see it again.
Speaker 1: I can't imagine that it's good.
Speaker 1: I'm really curious to see what I said about it at the time.
Speaker 0: It was long.
Speaker 1: I don't know how long it was, but thinking about it, it feels long.
Speaker 0: You know what it was?
Speaker 0: It was like a post-apocalyptic Miyazaki movie.
Speaker 1: I don't know what it was, but yeah.
Speaker 1: This is not someone who's only hit home runs, is what I'm trying to say, right?
Speaker 0: But he's pretty much always hit at least an RBI.
Speaker 1: His trademarks are beautiful clouds.
Speaker 1: Even in TV commercials he makes, the same beautiful clouds.
Speaker 1: Even in the things he made in his basement, beautiful clouds.
Speaker 0: Beautiful clouds in front of a sky that has a lot of purple and stars.
Speaker 1: Stories about lovers who are separated by space and time, right?
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: Your name comes, and for once, this is someone who had been oddly successful considering he started in his basement, but your name comes, and I'm reading about it.
Speaker 1: I'm like, "Oh, new movie from the guy I know.
Speaker 1: That's all right.
Speaker 1: I definitely want to see it at some
Speaker 1: point.".
Speaker 1: Then you start reading the stories like we talked about before.
Speaker 1: Most grossing movie.
Speaker 1: Oh my God.
Speaker 1: It's popular like crazy.
Speaker 1: Holy shit.
Speaker 1: It's the biggest deal.
Speaker 1: I'm like, "Really?
Speaker 1: Nothing else he made is a big deal.
Speaker 1: Why is this a big
Speaker 1: deal?".
Speaker 1: Right?
Speaker 1: How is this different from anything else he made?
Speaker 0: The short answer is we'll talk in depth about it.
Speaker 0: Don't worry.
Speaker 0: No spoilers.
Speaker 0: At least not until the end of this, but it's his best work.
Speaker 0: Holy shit.
Speaker 1: What happened is this guy who has been an expert at clouds and lovers separated by space and time just kept doing what he was doing.
Speaker 1: He made something.
Speaker 1: I had beautiful clouds and lovers separated space and time, but he made the best possible version of that better than all the previous possible versions of that.
Speaker 0: If you had a checklist of things that will make an anime movie popular, it just checks pretty much everything outside of the robots fighting world.
Speaker 1: Regardless of the content of the movie itself, seeing it made me really think about it because I'm always trying to do new stuff.
Speaker 1: I'm like, "Oh, let's do something
Speaker 1: different.".
Speaker 1: I'm tired of doing the same stuff over and over, but it's like maybe in life, a good way to just live.
Speaker 1: a good philosophy on life is to find the thing you're good at and just polish the fuck out of it and do it over and over and over and over again.
Speaker 1: I'm like,
Speaker 1: "Huh."
Speaker 1: When I think about doing that, it's like that feels bad.
Speaker 1: I shouldn't do that.
Speaker 1: I'll keep wanting novelty and variety, but Makoto Shinkai doesn't want novelty and variety.
Speaker 1: He wants to make the best lovers separated by space and time.
Speaker 1: cloud movie there ever was and he made it there.
Speaker 1: Good job on you.
Speaker 1: Maybe he'll do even better.
Speaker 0: I guess it's always possible.
Speaker 0: My only worry, because this one hits real emotionally hard.
Speaker 0: It's a good movie.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean, it's not material.
Speaker 0: So there's a moment, a real emotional low point, shall we say, near the end of the movie, and just when it's about to go a little too far down, because some of his earlier works- Yep, take you a little deeper than probably is necessary for this kind of story.
Speaker 1: Yeah, Hoshino Koe ends sad.
Speaker 1: It's just like, "Sad, the
Speaker 1: end."
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: Right?
Speaker 0: Oh, and Place Prom is in early days.
Speaker 1: This one has a slightly different curve.
Speaker 0: It's either the happiest sad ending or the saddest happy ending I've ever seen in my life.
Speaker 1: Right, but this one goes down and at the very end, it goes up a little bit.
Speaker 0: But just technically, from a storytelling standpoint, from the use of side characters characters and backgrounds and not having extraneous elements, it's a technical, I don't want to say masterpiece, but it is technically perfectly done.
Speaker 1: It's not so much, it's not selling crazy tickets at the box office for no reason.
Speaker 1: It's not unwarranted, right?
Speaker 1: It's hella good.
Speaker 1: Usually when there's an anime movie and we review it, we're like, "This is good.
Speaker 1: It's an anime movie though, so you should go see it even if it's not the greatest thing ever because anime movies that aren't just Pokemon, the 20th movie, are rare and worth your 90 minutes pretty much no matter what.
Speaker 1: So go see them
Speaker 1: all.".
Speaker 1: But no, even if you're a person who doesn't give a shit about any animes, you've never seen any animes, this is a movie worth seeing in your life, period.
Speaker 1: It is on the higher level.
Speaker 0: It's a movie that you can just get someone who's never heard of anime to watch.
Speaker 0: Get your mom down and be like, "Hey, let's watch this
Speaker 0: movie.".
Speaker 1: It is not a masterpiece, all-time, Citizen Kane level movie, right?
Speaker 1: It's not that high, but it's in damn good movie territory.
Speaker 1: Is that every- Matrix level.
Speaker 0: Everything it tries to do is executed basically perfectly- It had a lot of practice.
Speaker 0: In terms of like, all these little things happen, like there's side characters and all these, like the plot is actually pretty expensive.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it was much, see, I didn't realize it was going to be so long.
Speaker 1: So during the movie, there was a time where it felt like the movie was going to end just then and I'm like, "No, it's too soon.
Speaker 1: This is way
Speaker 1: short.".
Speaker 1: And then, of course, it didn't end even though it sort of like, the way it was shot, there was a fade out or something.
Speaker 1: It felt like an end.
Speaker 0: It could end it there.
Speaker 0: That would have been a downer.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there was like a fade out and a plot point.
Speaker 1: It felt like it could have been an end even though it was way too soon.
Speaker 1: But then later on, it happened, it was a similar kind of thing where I'm like, "Oh, is that the
Speaker 1: end?".
Speaker 1: And it wasn't.
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 1: And then it happened, I think, one or two more times vaguely, I've only saw it once in the theater.
Speaker 1: That was it, right?
Speaker 1: So I vaguely remember it multiple times where that could have been the end and it wasn't until eventually there was an end.
Speaker 1: and I'm like, "Oh, that's, yeah, definitely the end.
Speaker 1: That one for
Speaker 1: sure.".
Speaker 0: But there's little, so all those little side bits, there's a thing that happens, especially in a lot of anime movies, there's movies in general that aren't that good.
Speaker 1: But the point is, it's like two and a half hours long.
Speaker 0: It's a lot.
Speaker 0: It's 107 minutes actually.
Speaker 0: It's long.
Speaker 0: Full of runtime.
Speaker 0: But there's expected scenes that'll be drawn out or you don't care and you see them coming.
Speaker 0: And this movie very definitely avoids every one of those scenes where you'd go, "Well, this is the part that I expect.
Speaker 0: I'll just wait for, you know, to get to the good stuff
Speaker 0: again.".
Speaker 1: But yeah, we went to see Enchin and the Magic Tablet and that had a lot of that action going on, but this did not happen.
Speaker 0: Well, like a point where this one could have had that is when the people have to convince other people to do something that might be crazy, a normal movie would like draw that part out.
Speaker 0: This movie skips that and goes right to the bombing.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: Bombing indeed.
Speaker 0: Though in retrospect, the fact that that kid is like, "Fuck yeah," that easily.
Speaker 1: He just wants to bomb.
Speaker 0: Like I wonder what his life would have been like had the bombing not taken place.
Speaker 0: I feel like something was going to get bombed.
Speaker 1: You know, he also wants to sort of get revenge on his dad making him work there and stuff.
Speaker 0: But it does a good job of all, like every character.
Speaker 1: So he has a motivation even if the whole thing's a sham.
Speaker 0: But that's it.
Speaker 0: Every single character who says words pretty much and has a name has a moderately complex set of motivations and their story is told purely through background and environmental stuff.
Speaker 1: There's some side characters like this sort of secondary couple at the school and it's like, normally in another movie, they would be just sort of like decorations basically.
Speaker 1: But no, every character has a meaning and comes in and does something or they're not even a character.
Speaker 0: But those meanings are not just explained like you see often.
Speaker 0: It's not like there's a scene at the end where you'll do this because you're in the broadcast club and they blah, blah, blah, blah, blah.
Speaker 0: You know she's in the broadcast club because they just show a different character sitting in the broadcast club's room and then later you see that he has a crush on her and you can basically piece together and foreshadow literally every beat of this movie.
Speaker 0: It's so consistent.
Speaker 1: So the story of your name.
Speaker 1: So before I saw it, all I thought what it was about was based on the trailers and stuff is there is this high school guy and girl in Japan and when they go to sleep, they dream that the other person and they try to find each other.
Speaker 1: That's not a hundred percent accurate.
Speaker 1: What it is about is that these high school guy and girl in Japan go to sleep and they meet in the dream world vaguely, but basically when they wake up, sometimes they switched bodies.
Speaker 1: Oh shit, it's a trope.
Speaker 0: But the way they show the opposite of what a movie that is about that kind of thing would normally show.
Speaker 0: So they don't like the first.
Speaker 0: when this is happening, you basically see the guy like meeting his friends and friends are all like, what the fuck was up with you yesterday?
Speaker 0: And the girl meets all her friends and they're like, yeah, that was quite a scene you caused yesterday and you get the story like sort of second hand.
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 1: Like they thought they were dreaming and they, but yeah, they do try to find each other.
Speaker 1: like when they're awake, uh, somehow they're communicating with each other.
Speaker 0: Like they try as best they can cause it's like dreams.
Speaker 0: They don't have full memories of what they were up to, but they're like texting each other.
Speaker 0: Yup.
Speaker 0: Well, they start leaving messages for each other to try to like, like they're basically, they're trying to not mess up each other's lives because they start messing up each other.
Speaker 1: Like if one person messes up the other person's life on, you know, one day, then the other person is just going to get revenge.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: So they come to some sort of truce or whatever.
Speaker 0: And you might think at many points, well, why don't they just do X?
Speaker 0: Why don't they just, they pretty much try to do all the things you think of.
Speaker 1: There's nothing ridiculous where you're like, Oh, do this.
Speaker 1: It's like, no, it's, it's, you know, it makes sense.
Speaker 1: at one point, I mean, except for switching bodies, it makes sense.
Speaker 0: At one point, the guy's like, I should actually just try to call her.
Speaker 0: And at one point the girl's like, I should go meet him.
Speaker 1: And it's when they try, it says number disconnected or whatever.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: But the, everything that you think, why don't they do X is explained sufficiently as to why that didn't work.
Speaker 1: You're not going to be sitting in the theater going, why don't they just do this like my mom does.
Speaker 0: And I really, really recommend that you just go see this movie no matter what.
Speaker 0: it's the best anime movie I have seen in a long time.
Speaker 1: It's very unlikely that there will be a better anime movie soon.
Speaker 1: And it's been a long time since there's been an anime movie is good.
Speaker 1: You've got to dig into Satoshi, Khan and Jiv, you're someone who listens to, if you're someone who listens to geek nights, how can you at anime day, how could you not see this and do yourself a favor?
Speaker 0: If you don't know anything more about the movie, uh, don't go read about like what it's really about because of course a movie like this, it's going to swerve and it does obviously not, it's, it swerves in ways that could not be foreseen.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Kinda like, uh, so, uh, what was the, uh, there's a couple other movies we've seen that do this, but where you think the movie is going to be like, start to finish.
Speaker 0: This is what I expect.
Speaker 1: It doesn't just take and zag.
Speaker 1: It zogs and zugs.
Speaker 0: It's just like, whoa, the point where you think the movie would wrap itself up is probably like it gets past that in the first quarter, first, fifth.
Speaker 0: And it even does a thing where just when you get into the rhythm of, okay, they're swapping bodies, it passes a lot of time and cuts to a montage, just like a brave story did.
Speaker 0: And I feel like both movies did that to very good effects.
Speaker 1: Well, also, uh, what's it called the, uh, the one where the guys getting trained by the Wolf and the, uh, what was that movie called a boy and the beast, which is also a movie that had a big ass montage where of training of getting strong, right?
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: Well, that movie also spanned a lot more years than I expected.
Speaker 1: But that point is it had a big ass montage in it.
Speaker 1: That's what I thought of it, but this is way better than that.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: This one's more like the brave story one where a typical movie might show better than brace.
Speaker 0: But brave story is still, I think, a really good movie.
Speaker 0: I think it's criminally underrated.
Speaker 1: All I remember is the circus part.
Speaker 0: That circus part is the best animated circus scene I've ever seen.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: Name a better animated circus scene.
Speaker 1: Atari circus.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: I mean, sailor moon super S has a bunch of circus stuff, but it's not super well animated.
Speaker 0: You don't say, you don't say, but, uh, the montage is one of those moments where the movie basically skips all the crap.
Speaker 0: Dumbo has a better anime than a movie would normally deal with in this context to give you all that passage of time and equilibrium and everything to then get to what the movie is actually about.
Speaker 0: And it goes so far beyond the, they just swap bodies and I cannot recommend this movie enough.
Speaker 0: This movie is great.
Speaker 1: It's way good.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So I want to, I want to talk about some of the spoilers and the actual stuff that happened in the movie.
Speaker 1: I mean, you know, I don't, we can just tell you what the plot is, is like, okay, so first it was crazy.
Speaker 0: when spoilers spoil, we're going to, if you haven't seen the movie, just don't.
Speaker 0: it's crazy when every character died and then came back to life two times and then it turns out that they actually, the world gets destroyed and then animal people called friends take over.
Speaker 1: Anyway.
Speaker 1: No.
Speaker 1: So, uh, first off, where they suddenly stopped switching bodies.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: That, that hit real hard.
Speaker 1: It's just like, wait, what?
Speaker 1: And then it's just like, we're just going to continue now living our own lives with no more body switching and let's see what happens to them.
Speaker 1: And years pass by.
Speaker 1: It's like, whoa, what?
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: And you think like you would just skip that over or like, but it's like, wait, why?
Speaker 1: What happened?
Speaker 0: You feel like the movie is going a certain way.
Speaker 0: And then the three big moments, I think the emotional hits that really got me other than the end.
Speaker 0: Cause the end is the Makoto.
Speaker 1: And it's like there, it doesn't even seem to be a reason for it.
Speaker 1: It's like, you know, things are sort of moving along and coming to a thing and then it's just like, Oh, we didn't switch again after that.
Speaker 0: But just the, those, that scene of like suddenly it's over and you see the comment, you don't really understand what happened.
Speaker 0: Was very well designed to manipulate the emotions of the audience, which then there's a long build.
Speaker 0: It turns into almost a mystery story where the guy's like, so what happened?
Speaker 0: Like doing research.
Speaker 1: Because it's, you have basically these two people see, they switch the camera between the two people, however they want, you know, and then like at certain points it's like, it's all on the girl all the time and you don't know what the hell's going on with the guy at all.
Speaker 1: And sometimes on the guy, you know, and after, you know, they, they stopped switching.
Speaker 0: It's like, it's all on the guy a hundred percent, but that moment when he's in the diner and the guy's like, Oh, that's a really good picture of blah.
Speaker 0: And then like everyone knows except him, what happened.
Speaker 0: And one of my favorite moments is when he wakes up in her body and like, there's still time, like there's still time and he's just crying and holding his breasts and the sister comes in and she's like, Nope, nothing to do with this.
Speaker 0: Fuck this.
Speaker 0: It does.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: It's not a comedy, but it does do a good job of not pulling it back for something so serious and so heavy with the material.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Uh, you know, and it, you know, even though it's got the supernatural and the spiritual action going on, it does a pretty good job of leaving in, you know, just enough humor.
Speaker 1: This is still a cartoon or anime or whatever.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: You get the humor with the, in, in the, in the restaurant, you know, you get the humor and the school.
Speaker 0: It's a complex movie.
Speaker 0: It's super serious.
Speaker 1: I'm in a girl's body.
Speaker 1: I'm going to touch my boobs.
Speaker 0: It's also super funny.
Speaker 0: Like it's legit funny.
Speaker 1: I learned the funny parts and you reach a point where there's no more funny parts.
Speaker 0: But at the, at the lowest point, you get a very tactical, funny part to sort of keep you from just crying out loud in the theater.
Speaker 0: I don't know what else we can say.
Speaker 0: I mean, just go see this movie.
Speaker 0: It is really good.
Speaker 0: There's a reason why it's not, it's still in theaters.
Speaker 1: Uh, have we talked enough about it?
Speaker 0: Uh, I think so.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but yeah, it brings it like it's, you know, it gets really crazy.
Speaker 1: Like the whole thing with the fucking, you know, that's the first thing you see in this movie is like the, you know, the space, like it was a meteor, asteroid, whatever it is.
Speaker 0: The first thing, literally everything.
Speaker 0: So there's all these.
Speaker 1: And as soon as I saw that at the beginning of the movie, as that was the opening scene, I was like, oh, that's just not, that's just not just decoration like this.
Speaker 1: That's something in this movie is about that.
Speaker 1: But I remembered it, but I couldn't, I had no fucking clue until eventually they tell you.
Speaker 1: And it's like, oh shit.
Speaker 0: So I, because I've seen it twice, so I, so I saw it again, knowing like the full deal so I could watch for stuff.
Speaker 0: It is freakishly consistent in details to where you could have figured it out if you were paying attention, little details, like what kinds of cell phones people have.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Well, when the guy is like, oh, you know, we can go see the meteor shower tonight and everyone's like, what the hell are you talking about?
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: And it's on the, it's on the girls knew the girls watching the news and in the news is all about this meteor shower or whatever.
Speaker 1: And no one in the dude doesn't in the Tokyo seems to know anything about that.
Speaker 0: And there's, and it's also very much predicated on the idea that the whole movie, the primary mystery of the movie is basically because there is one short scene that actually happens way early in the movie, but you don't actually see it as an audience until near the end.
Speaker 0: And it literally like literally, literally ties a bow around the entire plot.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: I like that trope when movies do it well, where there's like the missing scene and you're seeing all the events around it.
Speaker 0: And then that's how to,
Speaker 1: like, she, like, she, like the very beginning of the movie, she wakes up from this dream and you see like a few seconds of what she was dreaming and then late, late, late in the movie that you finally see the whole scene and it's like, oh, that's what that was.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: Dun dun dun.
Speaker 0: Why didn't she ask?
Speaker 0: Why didn't he ask?
Speaker 1: Oh, everything makes sense now.
Speaker 0: But there are zero wasted scenes.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: For something so long, you think there would be like a bunch of bullshit, you know, time killing stuff.
Speaker 1: And they're almost like, they get close to it, right?
Speaker 1: There's some scenes where like, you know, they're doing, they're like, uh, you know, doing the thing with the weaving or whatever.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: But then that ends up being a very important part of the later plot.
Speaker 1: Obviously, but it's like those scenes are like, they take just as many seconds as they can for those scenes and if they took like one, even one second longer on any of those would have been sort of like, eh, and one second shorter would have been, I guess not the end of the world, but it's like, you know, they, they make it just enough to where it's not a problem.
Speaker 1: Unlike, you know, the other, I'm only thinking about, cause I saw it recently, the option and the magic tablet where the guy runs up extra flights of stairs and it just like you could have run up like four less flights, dude, it's like you could have just, you know, zip past that.
Speaker 0: But a lot of like a lot of those scenes, like I keep bringing it back to it, but it's like a perfect example of it.
Speaker 0: When the bomb dude, there's that one scene in the beginning where just randomly you see him sitting in a room filled with radio equipment and then it cuts away.
Speaker 0: Like he's sitting there for a while and then it cuts away.
Speaker 0: And then later when you realize that he's not in that club, the girls in the club and you figure out this whole side story of who likes who based on literally one scene with no dialogue that lasts maybe six seconds.
Speaker 0: And then at the end, of course they're married, so I mean, yeah, but that's actually important at the end because all, a lot of Makoto Shinkai's earlier stuff either left the like lovers separated by space time unresolved or tragically resolved.
Speaker 1: This one, he made it less tragic.
Speaker 0: He made it very clear that the events of this movie literally happened and if they meet again, they could figure shit out.
Speaker 0: Like there is, there is a trail of evidence of stuff.
Speaker 0: They made it very real and set that up at the end, which I do appreciate because the place promise in our early days, that end is a little bit brutal to watch despite it being happy.
Speaker 0: Sad.
Speaker 1: Only a little bit.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: It's happy, sad, sad, happy.
Speaker 0: This one's just intense and emotional, but also wraps a bow around everything.
Speaker 0: There's no loose ends.
Speaker 0: This has been Geek Nights with Rim and Scott.
Speaker 0: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design, and Brando Kay for the logos.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at frontrowcrew.com for show notes, discussion news, and more.
Speaker 0: Remember, Geek Nights is not one, but four different shows.
Speaker 0: Sci-Tech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays, and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: Geek Nights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: Geek Nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 1: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.
Speaker 1: And the Patreon
Speaker 0: Patreons for this episode of Geek Nights are Rebecca Dunn, Nicholas Brandau, Alan Joyce, Heidi McNichol, Amanda Duchette, Great Job Emoji, MyStady.com, William Eisenraus, Jeremy Minor, If This Is A Consular Ship, Where Is The
Speaker 0: Ambassador?,
Speaker 0: We're No Strangers To Love, You Know The Rules, And So Do I, The Terrible Secrets Of Space, 421 Creations, It Keeps Me Up At Night, Shervin Van Hor, Rara Lavelle, James David White, Michelle Montanona, Superboy, Oh Scott Your Beard Tickles When We Kiss, Sailor Vista, Matthew Smith, Don Schleit, Kishar Toppeshen, Joe Shor, Joe Starr, Tyler Eller, Sean Yeager, Sam Cordray, Clinton Walton, Ren from New Zealand, Ryan Perrin, Help My Son Is A Nerd, Brian Cedroni, The Space Time Vector Of An African European Swallow, Karen Kiwi, Redacted, Chris Midgiff, Chris Knox, Daniel Redmond, Sean Clyde, Chris Reimer, Thomas Hahn, and now I leave you with something.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I guess so.
Speaker 0: And down there's me too,
Speaker 1: there's me, there's me, there's me, there's me, there's me, there's
Speaker 0: me, there's me, there's me, there's me, there's me, there's me, there's
Speaker 1: me, there's
Speaker 0: me, there's me, there's me, there's me, there's me, there's me, there's me, there's me, there's me, there's
Speaker 1: me, there's me, there's me, there's me, there's me, there's me, there's me, there's me, there's
Speaker 0: me, there's me, there's
Speaker 1: me, there's me, there's
Speaker 0: me, there's me, there's me, there's me, there's.