Speaker 0: It's Monday April 3rd 2017.
Speaker 0: I'm rim.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott and this is geek nights tonight.
Speaker 0: build versus buy.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: Today is April 3rd Slash 3. it's big.
Speaker 1: It's a big day.
Speaker 1: First of all, it's 4/3 day.
Speaker 1: So 4/3 day every year the micro 4/3 consortium has a contest.
Speaker 1: you take pictures on 4/3 day with a 4/3 camera and lens and Which I have and then you can submit it somehow and win something.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: they just do this every year.
Speaker 1: All right, whatever.
Speaker 1: So that's the thing if you're a camera person.
Speaker 0: It's a. it's an inferior and obsolete aspect ratio.
Speaker 1: I mean you can take a non 4/3 aspect ratio photo.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's just inferior for television.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah as an aspect ratio for watching things like this monitor is 16 by 10 for a reason.
Speaker 1: Yeah No, it's.
Speaker 1: no we're not talking about video and TV.
Speaker 0: We're talking about 4/3 in all its forms.
Speaker 0: I guess there before colon 3.
Speaker 1: what's wrong with the 4/3 shape photograph versus it?
Speaker 1: You know, you know, you're a 16 by 9 photographs.
Speaker 1: really weird.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like one by one for photographs these days.
Speaker 1: Yeah, sure, but I mean different photographs are used for different kinds of different aspect photography different aspect ratios just for different compositions.
Speaker 1: It's not like.
Speaker 1: yeah, if you got a monitor that you're using to compute, you know a 1610 is useful But if you're watching video you want a 16 9 or even wider right for the which you would hate for using on your computer.
Speaker 0: Yeah, maybe anyway.
Speaker 1: Also today, I think technically the first day of baseball in 2017 was yesterday, but Mets baseball started today And seasons over we won six nothing.
Speaker 1: So if the season's over this fucking great Because that's not gonna last very long.
Speaker 1: So there's that.
Speaker 0: That's game I think I can go see a Mets game.
Speaker 1: It's real cheap.
Speaker 1: We can go whenever it is as long as we sit up high and we're waiting till it's warmer.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you don't want to pay to sit down low.
Speaker 1: if we go on like a Wednesday afternoon You could go like like almost nothing Like, you know you sit in the outfield like zero dollars almost used to be back in the day.
Speaker 1: you could.
Speaker 1: in Shea Stadium They had like the Pepsi porch or whatever Perhaps know the Pepsi picnic area and you could bring like a can of Pepsi and just get in.
Speaker 0: When I was a kid Tiger Stadium had a very similar thing.
Speaker 0: where you could you could bring Various implements depending on who was sponsoring that stuff and get in for free or for a nickel.
Speaker 1: I mean this was also cuz you know Shea Stadium had way more seats than Citi Field So they couldn't really fill it in except for you know, once the meds were not good.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like I'd been there in like the late 80s early 90s when it would fill but it didn't fill towards the late 90s 2000s, I don't think it filled and I don't think I saw it full at that point.
Speaker 0: Anyway, I'll also just recently I mean the Rangers clinched their.
Speaker 0: They declinched they.
Speaker 0: they clinched the non Participation of a hated team in the Stanley Cup playoffs and now nothing they do for the season matters.
Speaker 1: three meaningless hockey games And then the most real hockey game.
Speaker 1: Yeah Also hockey can.
Speaker 0: NHL confirmed it will not take a break during the Olympics Which is you know, I hate to say this but and it's Stanley Cup's a little more important than the Olympic hockey.
Speaker 0: I think Olympic hockey is the best though, but format of Olympic hockey is the best.
Speaker 1: with the wide Drinks players, I think players just gonna run away and go we'll say even while games are happening.
Speaker 1: They're just gonna go Definitely go and I don't think they could stop him.
Speaker 1: They just be like, why aren't you here at the game?
Speaker 1: Yeah, what are you gonna fire him?
Speaker 1: Yeah, I Mean you could just not.
Speaker 1: you could not pay him or suspend him and whatnot.
Speaker 1: He's like, I don't give a fuck.
Speaker 1: And Russia will probably win because they have KHL players Yeah, and the other countries all their players will be stuck in the NHL.
Speaker 0: Oh So you got any news and it's a. it's a Monday.
Speaker 1: I do have a news.
Speaker 1: it's tech news.
Speaker 1: So check this out.
Speaker 1: They announced there's the Consortium that decides things about RAM which I didn't even know existed.
Speaker 1: I didn't really understand how this worked until very recently.
Speaker 0: Oh, I I knew more about this but that was because I did a lot of research about it many years ago.
Speaker 1: Like I never really thought about like who invents new kinds of RAM?
Speaker 1: who comes up with them, right?
Speaker 1: You need so many people to agree on this.
Speaker 1: It's obviously a consortium, right?
Speaker 1: You've got the motherboard makers the memory the RAM makers Intel, you know, everyone's got to get in on this.
Speaker 1: They make the same RAM work and all these different PCs.
Speaker 0: wasn't the thing with RAM bus and that already ran that they like.
Speaker 0: they had a Patent on something that was part of a consortium standard and something weird happened there.
Speaker 1: But anyway, the group that decides things about RAM has unveiled DDR 5 which is gonna be like way better than DDR 4 Way better, but you're probably not gonna see like if the final thing until like next year 2018 And you're not gonna be able to buy it on Newegg and put it in your computer.
Speaker 1: It's so probably 2019.
Speaker 0: This does more like 2020, you know in the main day We're not talking about building computers like this is.
Speaker 0: we're talking about everything but computers really.
Speaker 0: but in terms of Buying computers or building computers for the last many years There's this problem where every time you think I'll buy a computer because we're at a plateau If you look at websites like this, you're gonna say oh if I just wait one more generation I'm gonna get the crazy RAM.
Speaker 0: if I just wait one more generation.
Speaker 0: I'll get the crazy video card.
Speaker 0: Actually right now it's probably a real good time to buy because this shit you can get a crazy m2 drive right now.
Speaker 0: Yeah But this stuff is not gonna come out until next year or no.
Speaker 1: This probably won't come out for like two three years in.
Speaker 1: you know for your dude for you to buy.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but now is actually a real good plateau to buy a high-end computer For example.
Speaker 1: DDR4 was finalized in 2012.
Speaker 1: You couldn't put it in computer till 2015.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's anyway, but yeah the organization that decides this is called JEDEC J E D E C. I didn't know that until today.
Speaker 1: But what's other interesting news that Intel has these obtained?
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, there's like the cash drives, right?
Speaker 1: So these obtained things are basically somewhere between a RAM and an SSD.
Speaker 0: so it's like I Where they'd have like an SSD or some RAM or something in the drive and then they'd have a spinning disk for the bulk store.
Speaker 1: Right, but there's no spinning disk no more.
Speaker 1: So basically these obtained drives.
Speaker 1: They're slower than RAM, but they're not that slower than RAM.
Speaker 1: They're like ten times slower, but RAM is so fast.
Speaker 1: It's still ridiculous speed and The idea is that well, you know for a lot of stuff like that's fast enough and it doesn't erase because it's solid state.
Speaker 1: So like, you know, it's crazy fast.
Speaker 1: ish not as RAM fast But fast and it doesn't clear when you turn the computer off like RAM does because the way RAM works people don't realize this.
Speaker 0: It's basic capacitors and you keep going.
Speaker 0: Hey, don't forget.
Speaker 0: Don't forget.
Speaker 1: Don't forget No, it's their capacitors that are like charged up right.
Speaker 1: and then now that's that's how you hold a one in there.
Speaker 1: But and then you know, you don't keep electricity going into it.
Speaker 1: It drains out.
Speaker 1: That's what a capacitor does, right?
Speaker 1: It's sort of like a battery that only doesn't last forever, right?
Speaker 1: It didn't you?
Speaker 1: so a RAM is just a huge grid of capacitors Whereas solid-state is actually a thing that switches and stays switched.
Speaker 1: But that'll be really interesting.
Speaker 1: Like if you could maybe these obtained things like you could suspend your computer and like turn it on But like everything's already in RAM, so it turns on.
Speaker 0: even it turns on like a TV Computer already boots in under three seconds.
Speaker 1: We're talking like it doesn't even boot.
Speaker 1: It's like you.
Speaker 1: you you think you just turned your monitor on like boom.
Speaker 1: There it is.
Speaker 1: But actually no your computer was off and is now on.
Speaker 0: like I'm saying it's it's a hell of a time for computers because already now Super fast like m.2 form factor SSDs are actually really affordable like if you're buying a fancy computer like.
Speaker 0: there's a reason I bought a.
Speaker 1: Maybe like if you had RAM and an optane drive and the optane drive was so big you could just like have your Applications just like every like you don't install applications you like.
Speaker 1: you just load them and they're just always loaded I'm sure in applications.
Speaker 1: They're just every application on your whole computer is always open.
Speaker 0: Well, I'm pretty sure that the optane right now the ones that consumers are going to be getting as they like launch aren't the super High-capacity like I don't know because I have a. you can get a two terabyte SSD from Samsung like today if you want it sure, but I'm saying like that's normal people don't need that.
Speaker 1: This is the road.
Speaker 1: We could be going down.
Speaker 0: This is a road We're gonna be going down.
Speaker 0: come on.
Speaker 0: years are about computers.
Speaker 0: keep getting in the 2020s.
Speaker 1: That's the kind of computer you're gonna be looking at something where it's just like You know.
Speaker 1: like you'll.
Speaker 1: you'll be looking at the SSD the way we look at like the spinning does now.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's just like.
Speaker 1: no my computer's like a hundred percent RAM and is a wafer thin And I mean we don't throw away some of this stuff like.
Speaker 0: I mean I still haven't spinning discs But they serve.
Speaker 0: they've replaced NASA's for me sure anyway, so in some other news This I don't know if anyone cares about this But you always complains got about.
Speaker 0: most of what we talk about is business news and not tech news.
Speaker 1: That's right.
Speaker 1: I just heard about actual tech news technologies.
Speaker 0: This is some legitimate tech news.
Speaker 0: Firefox is Dropping or has dropped also support, so if you use also In the raw or this is only a Linux issue by the way anyone listening is know what the hell's going on.
Speaker 0: Well, I did that poll.
Speaker 0: I was like pulse audio Also, Jack D for some reason or what the fuck rim and what the fuck rim won by a lot.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so basically you know if you have windows.
Speaker 1: You don't or Mac.
Speaker 1: You don't think about like the sound system.
Speaker 1: It's just like there's sound sound plays.
Speaker 0: It works like if you if you have a complicated computer you think oh I have weird sound devices And I have to set a priority order for which one.
Speaker 1: but like you just open the mixer or whatever.
Speaker 1: But you don't think about the sound system itself like how that's coded.
Speaker 1: But in Linux you know that's.
Speaker 1: you have to choose one and like install it and set it up And there's different choices.
Speaker 0: You know who thinks about this a lot.
Speaker 1: we taught it listen to the oldest possible geek night like OSS.
Speaker 1: I know and you'll hear talk about this stuff wasn't it OSS?
Speaker 1: And then also was like they used to be open sound system Yeah, and then there was also and now this pulse audio is like the new the relatively new hotness.
Speaker 0: But yet I was pretty sure that pulse audio was based on or relied on all.
Speaker 1: since I'm no I I don't know because I haven't used it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'm still not super clear on this.
Speaker 0: meanwhile when I had a Gentoo box I'd use Jack because I was running real.
Speaker 0: I was running our door and resound.
Speaker 0: I needed a real-time system.
Speaker 0: to this day I cannot really understand how to use any of the functionality of Jack.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't understand any.
Speaker 0: I never understood it.
Speaker 0: It makes no sense.
Speaker 0: I installed a bunch of stuff and I kept fucking with configuration files until eventually our door and resound both worked And then I never touched it again.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like if you want to write a computer program that plays sound.
Speaker 1: Right it's like you.
Speaker 1: pretty much just get a library that handles it for you like DirectX cuz comes with direct sound.
Speaker 1: The case SDL has a sound thingy that lets you play sounds, you know, but generally you're just playing wav files.
Speaker 1: You're saying wav file send.
Speaker 1: Okay, it played.
Speaker 1: I'm good.
Speaker 0: There is a place.
Speaker 1: even even really fancy programs like say counter-strike our program pretty much that way where they Have wav files and they send them.
Speaker 0: So what I was getting at is actually most like bigger-tier modern gaming.
Speaker 0: There's been a shift over the last many years toward using Dedicated proprietary audio middleware in game design instead of playing sounds directly, right?
Speaker 1: But the point is imagine having to write that dedicated audio middleware.
Speaker 1: That's.
Speaker 1: that's.
Speaker 1: that's what this pulse audio also stuff is.
Speaker 1: is that kind of that level of code?
Speaker 0: That is also.
Speaker 0: what the main bit is going to be about is whether or not you should write all this complicated shit to play In layer audio files in a game anyway.
Speaker 1: So Firefox is removing support for also for they're only gonna use pulse audio.
Speaker 1: So if you have a desktop Linux and you want to use Firefox and you want to hear sound when you're say watching a YouTube Video your Fox you have to use pulse audio or you're gonna hear nothing.
Speaker 1: You have no choice pulse audio or bust.
Speaker 0: So as far as I can tell the only people on earth who are complaining about this are the people in this slash-dot thread And it's amazing that there are people who are so mad
Speaker 1: because if you were writing Firefox it for Linux something which doesn't have You know a ridiculous number of users, but it has enough where they got to keep doing it.
Speaker 1: Yeah is are like such a pain in the ass is also shit.
Speaker 1: Let's just stick to one.
Speaker 1: Okay, we can actually do this.
Speaker 0: The best part is this jerk here is like all you need to do is the dash dash enable also configure option and then the Immediate response is actually no that's the thing that's going away.
Speaker 1: Yep That's the thing that's going away.
Speaker 0: But call but quote with pulse audio being criminally broken case in point doesn't work on the box I sit my butt at right now.
Speaker 0: at the moment what you got?
Speaker 0: some like Special gen 2 build.
Speaker 0: you're running there.
Speaker 0: I don't know but the point is sound Gen 2 won't notice if you're running gen 2 the e-bill.
Speaker 0: Okay, whatever.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I already don't care.
Speaker 1: The point is sound in Linux has always sucked.
Speaker 1: It sucked since I wrote about surround sound not working.
Speaker 1: There's a blog post I wrote somewhere about surround sound and Linux not working.
Speaker 1: and like still 2000 something early 2000 and guess what?
Speaker 1: She still don't work.
Speaker 0: Yep So that's why and like I was driven away to Linux on the desktop from Windows for a lot of reasons I use Linux on the desktop for a long time but Windows and OS X are the only modern desktop operating systems.
Speaker 1: The thing is even among Windows and OS X sound has a lot of issues Yeah, but at least it you can get it to work.
Speaker 1: on Linux a lot of times You're just like rough.
Speaker 1: I can't do it.
Speaker 1: But on Windows, it's like it sucks, but you can make it happen.
Speaker 0: well, the thing is the only things you can't make happen on Windows are Complicated things.
Speaker 0: where again?
Speaker 1: No, there's a very simple thing.
Speaker 1: You can't do which is play one sound thing out of two out holes.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, if I have two sound cards I just want to play the same.
Speaker 1: I want to open up iTunes play music and have it go to both sound cards out at the same time.
Speaker 0: There's a lot of reasons why that would.
Speaker 1: unless those two sound cards have a unified timing mechanism Which they put if I don't care if they're in sync I just want the sound to just go out both holes.
Speaker 0: that why do so?
Speaker 0: why would you want to do that?
Speaker 1: There's a lot of reasons.
Speaker 1: maybe I got you know I said his speakers in one room instead of speakers another room and using that's where you use and your audio splitter.
Speaker 1: I'm just saying there's a Amplifier.
Speaker 1: there are legit reasons.
Speaker 1: Don't want to do this.
Speaker 1: Yes, there are there a lot of you know, you can't do it.
Speaker 0: There's no legit reason you would want to do that.
Speaker 1: I want to send it to my headphones and also speak.
Speaker 0: now.
Speaker 0: I can do that on my computer right now Because I'm using a giant mixer right here.
Speaker 1: So you send your sound out of your computer through one hole the mixer and then on your mixer you have multiple holes.
Speaker 1: That's cheap.
Speaker 1: That's no different than a splitter.
Speaker 0: But I can have audio from the mixer coming back into the computer and back out of other holes.
Speaker 0: so I can in effect Have playaway file.
Speaker 0: have it go out like ten different places analog and digital Plus.
Speaker 1: it would get out of saying the windows is still only sending out the same reason.
Speaker 1: I think it's only.
Speaker 1: Windows itself is still only sending the audio from one application to one hole.
Speaker 0: now.
Speaker 0: Also you as far as Windows knows that the reason that things don't let you do that is the same reason why you can't record In any application from two different sound cards at the same time.
Speaker 0: Ah, yep There's reasons for that.
Speaker 0: that she won't work in Linux either.
Speaker 1: Did you just let you do it?
Speaker 0: No good now Not.
Speaker 0: let people do that.
Speaker 1: Let it do it.
Speaker 0: Also don't cater to the edge case because it'll just make your application harder to use for the vast majority of humans.
Speaker 0: Fuck the edge case.
Speaker 0: They can buy their own software.
Speaker 0: They can write their own.
Speaker 1: Here's an example, right?
Speaker 1: I got winamp open.
Speaker 1: I want to play a music in winamp But I also want the winamp music to be sent out a different hole to someone I'm skyping Can't do it.
Speaker 0: Just tell Skype to take the input.
Speaker 0: That is the output of your winamp if you're using some sort of but then I can't hear the Skype on my speaker.
Speaker 1: Well, I also want to send it to my store again.
Speaker 0: If you're the edge case, I can just do that.
Speaker 1: I'm just saying but you can do that but Windows doesn't do it.
Speaker 1: You wouldn't?
Speaker 0: there's no reason windows have to do that.
Speaker 1: Buy a multi-thousand dollar piece of equipment to do that.
Speaker 0: repeating of People who use windows do not need to do the.
Speaker 1: there are actually people selling like weird Unshady software is to do this.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and that shady software sucks ass is also probably full of malware.
Speaker 0: if there was a legitimate use case Cases would sell that software.
Speaker 1: legitimate use case want to do that.
Speaker 1: don't want to spend a bunch of money on hardware.
Speaker 0: Actually wanted to do that any time when.
Speaker 0: many times when give me our use case you actually these case.
Speaker 0: you.
Speaker 0: yeah I doubt your use cases or something.
Speaker 0: You've actually wanted to do in the real world.
Speaker 1: I just use these case.
Speaker 1: I wanted to have a music play send it to Skype and also would you send music to Skype?
Speaker 1: I want to play music for somebody would know you don't.
Speaker 1: I want to play music in counter-strike to harass people But also listen to it.
Speaker 0: Uh, yeah, you know what?
Speaker 0: in that case you buy this troll app that I've seen.
Speaker 1: No bitcoins no.
Speaker 0: actually when we were playing the old days with our NS I used a set of scripts and what those scripts would do is take away files and route them as Audio from a fake microphone interface and I got banned from a bunch of servers.
Speaker 0: then I stopped using it.
Speaker 1: I Got three Apple twos and I want to.
Speaker 1: I don't have a cassette tape recorder and I want to play the same You know data file to all three at the same audio splitter.
Speaker 1: I'm just saying the answer to almost any one of them has an optical in and the other one has an analog optical in on your Apple - I'm sure someone does.
Speaker 1: You should see this shit people guy I seen Apple twos running Wolfenstein 3d but anyway things Of the day, what do you got?
Speaker 1: So, I don't know who set this up or where they got their data from but it exists.
Speaker 1: And even though it's you might think it's an anime day thing.
Speaker 1: It's a technology thing.
Speaker 1: So what this is, I guess instead of setting up a website that was like Studio Ghibli database They just set up an API so they didn't have to make a website.
Speaker 1: So if you use you know, it's a restful API that sends back JSON and they have a database full of Ghibli information.
Speaker 1: You know, I'm sure this information is on IMDB, but whatever so interesting because I'm just.
Speaker 0: I'm literally right now Because I'm doing a lot.
Speaker 0: I'm architecting a lot of big projects.
Speaker 0: So I'm reading this book on like the current state-of-the-art best practices for restful like interfaces for website stuff.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm this seems to follow pretty.
Speaker 0: this looks like the kind of thing that I would write if I were trying to like make sure that I know how this stuff works by reading that book and then making a good rest.
Speaker 1: so not only is this a Very useful API if you want to know about Ghibli things or maybe write some kind of app that needs Ghibli data But also a really example of a well-designed standard.
Speaker 0: I don't know if it's actually well-designed.
Speaker 1: Well, it's.
Speaker 1: it's a pretty easy to make this kind of API because it's only forgetting data, right?
Speaker 1: It's not an API where you have to like post or submit anything.
Speaker 1: It's real simple to make one of these because every call is a hundred percent independent.
Speaker 1: All your it's just selects it just selecting from.
Speaker 1: they have a database of Ghibli stuff and you select from it and effectively Just instead of sending them SQL you send them HTTP because instead of them sending you SQL results.
Speaker 0: They send you JSON strings and a Book is basically like as soon as you start doing more complicated stuff.
Speaker 0: Most things that say they're a rest interface don't actually follow restful principles No And are actually basically just garbage old like it's.
Speaker 1: cuz restful principles are like don't?
Speaker 1: you don't exactly match You know designs of modern applications.
Speaker 1: You can't really can't follow them necessarily.
Speaker 0: You're kind of limited by the fact that we're still using HTTP, right?
Speaker 1: I mean if you if you make something that follows because HD I'm not gonna talk about HTTP.
Speaker 1: That's a different show.
Speaker 1: But yeah If you make something on that if you make something and you're if your application matches the sort of design for the original You know Tim Berners-Lee HTTP, then restful is gonna work really well for you.
Speaker 1: But if your application sort of like a normal kind of like a Twitter thing, you know, it's like yeah restful Mostly matches up but it's like, you know, all you have is put post delete, you know And some of the weird new ones that might not work.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you can give get put post and delete and none of those are login.
Speaker 1: You're gonna use post for login, even though that's not what post is, right?
Speaker 0: For example, so but yeah If you're an aspiring programmer Poking at an API like this and trying to make it like trying to take the data into a little application And do something with it or like display it on a web page.
Speaker 0: That's like the best way to learn this stuff Because someone else did the annoying work of make a useful set of data.
Speaker 0: All you have to do is be like I'm gonna make a website where I type a word.
Speaker 0: It shows me all the Ghibli movies that appears in like.
Speaker 1: this would be really useful if for example, you wanted to make like a Automatic Ghibli trivia generator or yeah something like that.
Speaker 0: Name Baron Humperd von Gekengen.
Speaker 0: gender male hair color yellow eye color green.
Speaker 1: Is that from Forco Rosso?
Speaker 0: Or is that the?
Speaker 1: is that the guy from Lapada?
Speaker 0: I think it's a guy from Lapada, but I don't remember any of the names of any of those people.
Speaker 1: I don't know anything.
Speaker 0: All right, you know who?
Speaker 0: Ronaldo moon aka moon aka Muta.
Speaker 0: male beige hair white eyes.
Speaker 0: No, you know who Gigi is.
Speaker 0: or cat bus cat bus, you know, I know a cat buses.
Speaker 0: hair color brown.
Speaker 0: I feel like actually how cat bus has multiple.
Speaker 0: Well, yeah, I'm not gonna quibble about the data set.
Speaker 0: So When I was young I like most nerds who played Dungeons & Dragons Thought oh I have all these pewter or relitium.
Speaker 0: I guess no one has relitium anymore.
Speaker 0: miniatures.
Speaker 0: I didn't have miniatures.
Speaker 0: I Well, I did but also our game master like painted them legit and one thing he did that was super cool.
Speaker 0: It's him and his brother.
Speaker 1: Did he actually paint him legit or were you just young?
Speaker 1: He didn't know what it was.
Speaker 0: He was real good at this shit.
Speaker 1: It's like I used to see miniatures I thought were good like in the game store and then you go online and then the ones in the game store on the shelf Look like crap.
Speaker 0: These were legit good He was limited only by the fact that these were the tiny like one-inch scale ones, but they look real fucking good Mm-hmm, and he painted all our main characters for those super long campaigns.
Speaker 0: So I thought I'm gonna totally get into this hobby and I tried to paint miniatures and they looked like god.
Speaker 1: I always want to do the free paint and take it packs.
Speaker 0: I've had 21 opportunities to do so and I've done it zero times Yep, so then I read a whole bunch of tutorials in dragon magazine And then I tried again and they were still garbage.
Speaker 0: and then I read a whole bunch more tutorials.
Speaker 0: They were still garbage and I watched him do it and I tried to do what he did and still look like garbage.
Speaker 1: I thought about painting Gundam models and then I gave up.
Speaker 0: the moral is don't paint your miniatures You're gonna suck at it forever.
Speaker 0: But if you insist on painting them or if you're good at it if you insist on doing this Thin your paints.
Speaker 0: Oh, yes, if you do not thin your paints.
Speaker 0: This is what happens.
Speaker 1: And also you're gonna paint that they sell is not thin enough.
Speaker 1: when they sell it to you You must make it thinner with paint thinner.
Speaker 0: There are reasons you might want to use thicker paints in certain situations.
Speaker 0: None of those reasons apply to you and you're wrong if you think otherwise.
Speaker 1: Also, if you're using an airbrush, you need to get it thinner or it'll gob up the airbrush.
Speaker 1: They make it's like mandatory to thin it to go in the airbrush.
Speaker 0: This is a public service announcement about why you need to thin your paints.
Speaker 0: But more importantly I have a piece of advice.
Speaker 0: is not in this video.
Speaker 0: piece of advice number two If you somehow start painting the paint, yeah, that's number three.
Speaker 0: Also on number four most of those old miniatures are made out of lead.
Speaker 1: So don't eat the miniature.
Speaker 0: be aware of that, especially if you're handling them playing D&D and eating your Cheetos.
Speaker 0: That's why they had relitium which doesn't have lead in it, but sucks.
Speaker 1: get plastic It's just fine.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Well, I like the pewter like heavy miniatures get a plastic one with a weight in the middle of it.
Speaker 0: But my second most important piece of advice is if you get even the most minuscule amount into this hobby and start painting miniatures Someone at some point is gonna say yo dog.
Speaker 0: You got an ink to make stuff look real good You're going to fail and inking is super hard.
Speaker 0: Don't even do not try to ink.
Speaker 0: you're gonna take What is a perfectly serviceable miniature and ruin it?
Speaker 0: They're gonna try to get that ink off of there and you're gonna make it even worse Mm-hmm, and then your hand is gonna be black for like a month and your fingernails gonna have black ink under it for the rest Of your life.
Speaker 0: That is my experience with inking.
Speaker 0: do not ink your miniatures In the moment the book club book is Frank Gerberts do not do like a sand dune.
Speaker 0: Yep Spice and such.
Speaker 0: we're gonna read it at some point.
Speaker 0: I kind of has been busy playing Zelda.
Speaker 1: So yeah, I'll read it when I finish playing Zelda Just when I'm gonna do everything else in my life when I finish playing.
Speaker 0: so as long as we're on the same boat here Because I'm not gonna stop playing Zelda anytime soon.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and if I have free time the geek nights video game Yeah side geek fight, you know, you're not allowed to play Breath of the Wild unless you play Zelda 1 first.
Speaker 1: cuz I say so You know what?
Speaker 0: If you play Zelda 1 first, you're.
Speaker 0: there's some areas of Breath of the Wild that are shockingly reminiscent.
Speaker 1: Oh, there's a rectangular island that sort of you got to get to with a raft and the northern east of the map.
Speaker 1: in both Games, it's also based on some Spectacle rock.
Speaker 1: in both games is the old man who wears red.
Speaker 0: in both games wand of Gamelon appears to be canon Really?
Speaker 0: There's there's a big skeleton in a wand of Gamelon of this thing like in a desert area.
Speaker 1: the same skeleton I just I just saw.
Speaker 0: that's going and the same landscape is in Breath of the Wild.
Speaker 0: So danger for the CGI Zelda's being canon.
Speaker 0: maybe There's no way.
Speaker 0: it's a coincidence Cuz it's too close.
Speaker 0: But otherwise the previous book club was Rebecca.
Speaker 0: We got no cuz.
Speaker 0: I guess I'm gonna be a Zenkai Khan at the end of the month doing some panels.
Speaker 0: I don't know what but I'm doing panels.
Speaker 0: I assume they're Saturday and Sunday because I didn't take Friday off work.
Speaker 0: Then we got PAX West, PAX Unplugged, PAX Australia.
Speaker 0: Geek nights will be at all of them.
Speaker 1: Sure.
Speaker 0: All of them is happening.
Speaker 0: and Yeah, I don't know.
Speaker 0: follow our YouTube channels.
Speaker 0: If you guys double the number of YouTube subscribers on either of our channels.
Speaker 1: if you get me above 10,000 I don't know how many I have them.
Speaker 0: I have.
Speaker 0: no I don't know how many you have either.
Speaker 0: right now YouTube slash a French you have.
Speaker 0: The problem is we're using our separate YouTube channels.
Speaker 1: You have 1438 so 2,800 would be double.
Speaker 0: so you need you need 10,000.
Speaker 1: surprised to have that many You have.
Speaker 0: you have a good YouTube channel your pot your most popular of those.
Speaker 0: still two pony things.
Speaker 0: Yeah, my most popular.
Speaker 1: No, I thought bike commuting was my most popular bike.
Speaker 0: Nope Oh my gosh is a little bit more is an order of magnitude more popular Than either of them.
Speaker 0: My gosh, my number one video is my Kanye pony video to this day All right, and my number two video is that Game of Thrones goonies mashup?
Speaker 0: I made mmm, but it gave me above 10,000 and I can get some shit out of YouTube.
Speaker 1: It used to be one of those silver play buttons.
Speaker 0: I think I need I don't know what I need for the silver play button.
Speaker 0: I think you need a hundred thousand.
Speaker 1: You just want the silver play button.
Speaker 0: I bet I could just buy one.
Speaker 0: Let's see, I need a hundred thousand to get the silver play button.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 0: Wonder if I could just buy one.
Speaker 1: Let's see on eBay It won't have your channel name on it.
Speaker 1: It'll be like for some other channel.
Speaker 0: I'll get it to say Chester Pocklington YouTube play button.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Oh, so yeah, there was a cooking contest.
Speaker 1: Oh, so it's making fake ones.
Speaker 0: Yeah, people are making bootleg ones.
Speaker 1: Nice.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Anyway game.
Speaker 1: so There's a cooking contest I had to make a video for.
Speaker 1: so we made the video On Sunday Saturday.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 0: We made a cooking video.
Speaker 0: Scott cooked.
Speaker 1: It's due on Wednesday.
Speaker 1: The contest closes.
Speaker 1: so I get it completely edited.
Speaker 1: morning or Wednesday midnight I don't know but I have to.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna finish the whole thing tonight Editing and I'm gonna upload it to YouTube when I wake up tomorrow and this I'll be cooking with Scott episode one Even if I don't win the contest, which I don't expect to do.
Speaker 1: so, I'm gonna be honest.
Speaker 1: I was planning on doing cooking with Scott anyway, but the contest sort of forced me to do it.
Speaker 0: Legit honest because I had to stand there silently working the handcam when Scott.
Speaker 0: we had a couple other cameras set up and basically like Well, you know manage all that crap.
Speaker 0: Keep an eye on the levels.
Speaker 0: It was legit entertaining to watch Scott cook even without editing out all the parts where we just stood there We're gonna edit out a lot of weight.
Speaker 1: There's a lot of times you're just waiting for stuff to cook.
Speaker 1: we're gonna edit all that out.
Speaker 0: But there's also a lot of parts where you're legit funny.
Speaker 0: And also the recipe was pretty good.
Speaker 1: It was mad delicious.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I feel like what cooking was gonna be a thing.
Speaker 1: There was some.
Speaker 1: Basically what the story behind the contest is that we get the Blue Apron not promoting them.
Speaker 1: They don't pay us.
Speaker 0: We pay them like Emily's cooking a Blue Apron right now.
Speaker 1: Yeah, don't.
Speaker 1: actually I'm gonna tell you You probably don't want to become a Blue Apron customer.
Speaker 0: It's good.
Speaker 0: If you have I will.
Speaker 0: I have between two and four people in your household.
Speaker 0: It is great.
Speaker 0: If you have one it's a little bit.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: I mean we can talk about the benefit.
Speaker 0: You should do a Thursday show on it.
Speaker 0: We should review it, right?
Speaker 1: But the point is you probably don't want to sign up for it.
Speaker 1: If you are thinking about it talk to us because we can just give you a free meal and then you can cancel right away.
Speaker 1: A free box actually with three meals in it.
Speaker 1: then you can cancel right away.
Speaker 1: But basically there was a TV show of cooking one of those reality cooking contest shows Which are actually game shows in my opinion not reality shows.
Speaker 1: and the person who won made a recipe very similar to the one that they gave me in the box.
Speaker 1: and so I was making that recipe.
Speaker 1: and the prize for the contest is Cooking lessons with the person who won the cooking TV show.
Speaker 1: and even if it's some lowbrow cooking TV show That person is still probably amazing at fucking cooking.
Speaker 1: their meal was delicious And I they definitely know more about cooking than I do and can teach me a lot.
Speaker 1: So I wouldn't.
Speaker 1: I want that prize.
Speaker 1: the prize also includes like six months of free blue apron Which is a fortune of money that shit's expensive Which is why you shouldn't get it.
Speaker 1: and also the prize includes a trip to New York, which is completely useless fart noise.
Speaker 0: so Whatever I'll be like, all right, you got to fly me round-trip to New York from Seattle.
Speaker 1: Yeah, fly me from go to Seattle.
Speaker 1: I want the helicopter ride from LaGuardia to the cooking lesson.
Speaker 0: You know what?
Speaker 0: I'll bet you could convince him of that.
Speaker 0: You're like just helicopter me once.
Speaker 1: Yeah, just helicopter me.
Speaker 1: It's cheaper than the flight, right?
Speaker 1: Only like 500 bucks for the helicopter.
Speaker 0: I'll fly to Seattle hang out with like rowing Jeremy.
Speaker 0: Then I'll make them fly me to New York and back to Seattle and then I'll hang out with them again.
Speaker 0: But then you're still buying a flight to Seattle, yeah, but I basically get to be in Seattle twice, I don't know.
Speaker 1: Oh, I'm sorry.
Speaker 1: I'm going to be in Paris Back home.
Speaker 1: I'm saving halfway.
Speaker 1: I'm a Buy me a round-trip ticket and I'll find some Parisian person who can then go back home for free.
Speaker 0: No But yeah, this was legit entertaining and stay tuned for all that.
Speaker 0: Also, I've mentioned this on the Patriot a bunch, but I guess I haven't mentioned like in the main part of the show.
Speaker 0: Yes, the you tennis show is continuing.
Speaker 0: In fact, I've actually we've never stopped it.
Speaker 0: we just don't have a set schedule for making it and and when I got the new computer one of the things that I vowed to do was make a pipeline for it because You might have noticed I'm cranking out those geek nights board game videos, right?
Speaker 1: Those are much easier.
Speaker 1: They don't have video.
Speaker 0: but also I took a lot of time.
Speaker 0: the first three of those took a ton of time to make because most of my effort was making A pipeline so that now I have a process I can follow that just cranks the videos out.
Speaker 0: I'm doing the same thing for the you tennis show.
Speaker 0: It just took a while because that's a very complex show to make so stay tuned.
Speaker 0: The you tennis show is coming back Relatively soon.
Speaker 0: We'll be recording the next episode.
Speaker 0: So this is actually a Monday show that is relevant to both of our careers.
Speaker 1: I think we may have talked about this before but it's impossible to search for.
Speaker 1: and if we did talk about it before it was probably in 2005 over like 12 years ago or
Speaker 0: We've probably talked about this concept because it looks like a lot of people in the chat for the live stream thought That we were gonna be talking about building computer versus buying computer.
Speaker 0: That's now what we're talking about at all.
Speaker 0: We're talking about the general case.
Speaker 0: So the idea is you are a person or a company You're an entity of some kind and you're making something.
Speaker 1: Yep, usually software, but not necessarily software, but Regardless of whether you're making software you need soft.
Speaker 1: Yes maybe Maybe you're.
Speaker 1: you could be a dentist and you need like a database to store all your x-rays and patient data.
Speaker 1: Or maybe you're a software company and you're gonna make a search engine, but you also need analytics stuff.
Speaker 0: You're a podcaster and you're making videos and you need something to manage the copyright of all the assets You're using in the thing.
Speaker 1: You need something to edit videos with.
Speaker 1: yeah All right, this software that whatever your business is whether it's a personal business or a real business you need software.
Speaker 1: You also need hardware, but whatever.
Speaker 1: but you know, should you buy a software with money?
Speaker 1: That already does what you do, which is the effect?
Speaker 1: or pay zero for an open source that already does.
Speaker 0: I was actually gonna break that into.
Speaker 0: well, it's billed by Cobble together from open source, right?
Speaker 1: But even by me cobbling, you know, it doesn't Acquiring right?
Speaker 1: It doesn't matter whether it's zero dollars or a million dollars, right?
Speaker 1: I think you take an already existing software and use it even though it might not exactly match what you need But it gets it done.
Speaker 1: hopefully Should you make a software that is exactly what you need rather than using something else?
Speaker 1: Yep, so a lot of times this decision is obvious, right?
Speaker 1: If you're an artist, you don't make a Photoshop You just buy fucking Photoshop.
Speaker 1: Yeah Cuz to make Photoshop would obviously be so time-consuming so expensive and never as good as the original deal.
Speaker 0: Well also we know that if you try to cobble together from open source or if you build it yourself without all the expertise and Institutional domain knowledge that Adobe has at best.
Speaker 0: You're gonna make the gimp.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm Sure, but I mean and there are other obvious situations, right?
Speaker 1: You're making a website.
Speaker 1: Should you a website even if you're coding the website itself?
Speaker 1: You need a database.
Speaker 1: You're gonna use MySQL or Postgres.
Speaker 1: You are not going to make a database.
Speaker 1: Yep It's not.
Speaker 1: it's obvious at situations but non obvious situations.
Speaker 1: should you make a website by coding or Should you just install WordPress?
Speaker 1: That's not necessarily that obvious because coding up a website isn't that did?
Speaker 1: you can do it and you do better than web?
Speaker 1: Press depending on your WordPress based on your website, maybe and then there's also in this middle area.
Speaker 0: So you're gonna make your own website.
Speaker 0: Let's say so you decide that's what you want to do.
Speaker 0: Do you?
Speaker 0: Code it up from scratch.
Speaker 0: Do you use a minimal framework?
Speaker 0: Do you use a full-on framework?
Speaker 0: There's a lot of degrees of build-it-yourself from literally writing assembly right all the way up to Download Django and then start throwing some stuff at it.
Speaker 1: You're gonna make a video game.
Speaker 1: Do you make an engine?
Speaker 1: or to use Unreal Engine or unity or like we talked about just before audio middleware?
Speaker 0: And this is the problem where a lot of people who are making the build versus buy decision don't actually know What already exists.
Speaker 0: there's a lot of.
Speaker 1: sometimes it's hard to find what already exists.
Speaker 1: you google around and you can't find anything But then it actually did exist.
Speaker 1: You just couldn't find it.
Speaker 0: I only learned that audio middleware was a mature market where you could just get middleware to do this stuff.
Speaker 0: less than five years ago at a pecs dev when someone on a panel was like blah blah blah blah blah wasted all this time trying to code this audio shit and then we use this middleware instead and I looked At that middleware and I was like, oh shit
Speaker 1: Yes Someone did it
Speaker 0: like.
Speaker 0: you might not know.
Speaker 1: even if you're in an industry and even if you search and do your research It's hard to find some of these things that are out there and then there's kind of this you might be searching for the a lot Of times.
Speaker 1: it's you don't know the word for the thing.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like I need an audio system for my games.
Speaker 1: you type typing into Google a game audio system.
Speaker 1: You never type in audio middleware so you don't find it.
Speaker 0: Oh, so even worse.
Speaker 0: This is someone from my real from my day job.
Speaker 0: so But one of the products that my real company makes is something called a fix engine Which is basically there's the fix protocol for finance shit and we make some software that is like the middleware to manage that.
Speaker 0: So like it connects to all these fixed protocol sessions.
Speaker 1: Are you the first search as well?
Speaker 1: You'd be searching fix it.
Speaker 0: No, this is actually.
Speaker 0: that's a point of.
Speaker 0: that's a point of contention and I haven't asked repeatedly to make us higher.
Speaker 0: There's nothing you can do about that or on the first page but sure anyway.
Speaker 0: the problem is if You don't already have enough inside baseball to know that that industry calls that thing a fix engine.
Speaker 0: Like if you didn't work in finance and you look up the fixed protocol, you'd be like, alright I guess I need some middleware that speaks fix.
Speaker 0: and if you start typing to fix middleware You're gonna mostly find results on how to fix problems with other people's middleware.
Speaker 1: Also the word.
Speaker 1: Yeah the word fix Yeah, not the fixed protocol.
Speaker 0: so if you search for a fix engine you're gonna see all this stuff about fixed engines, but you also find all this shit about fixing car engines and Trouble and you're gonna find all these vendors and it might not be clear.
Speaker 0: if there's open source stuff And you don't really know where to look and also most of the kinds of things that you buy as opposed to build Especially if it's enterprise or if it's corporate or anything like that.
Speaker 0: There might not be any way to evaluate which one is better than another one, right?
Speaker 1: So let's not so buying right?
Speaker 1: so the reasons you would buy something is.
Speaker 1: we already talked about a. It's so complicated to make that you could never make it and it just distracts you from doing the thing You actually want to do, right?
Speaker 1: You would never get around to doing the thing you wanted because you're too busy building.
Speaker 1: You can't make draw the picture you want it because you're busy making Photoshop.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I get that right.
Speaker 1: B you would buy something Because just you know the time savings right even if it doesn't do exactly what you want, you know, you could do better.
Speaker 1: It's not that good.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's just.
Speaker 1: it's still mostly done and gets you far along.
Speaker 0: You see like case in point time to market if you make it a new website Like you start a tiny game studio.
Speaker 0: You need a website the most minimum the quickest time to market every website.
Speaker 0: I'm just gonna like square some squares face Be like click a button.
Speaker 0: website appears type stuff in.
Speaker 1: it won't be the perfect website, but it's up now Which is better than no website?
Speaker 1: Oh and no website is what you would have if you sat around trying to make one for a month And even then most people who quote-unquote make a website.
Speaker 0: they still use WordPress as the back end.
Speaker 0: They just heavily customize the front end of it.
Speaker 1: Sure, but you still you know, it's still thing you had to do.
Speaker 1: You could also, you know buy as a temporary measure while you build.
Speaker 0: Yep,
Speaker 1: right things like that
Speaker 0: But yeah, so but the other reasons you'll buy are highly specialized like middleware corporate nonsense mark, you know, I'm thinking mostly like finance or hospitals or Factories where the thing you need Is a thing that other companies that do the same kind of thing need and no one outside of that tiny world will ever need It.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: Unless you think you can make money by selling that thing.
Speaker 0: You definitely do not want to write that thing, right?
Speaker 1: so there'll be some sort of thing that's like an industry standard and If you make your own custom thing and don't use it everyone else is using.
Speaker 1: how do you hire people?
Speaker 1: Right people won't know how to use your custom thing.
Speaker 1: It'll sell and people who won't work for you won't be able to go anywhere else.
Speaker 1: So it's like oh, yes And all right, let's say you manage to make a Photoshop and it's just as good.
Speaker 1: that's not gonna pretend you did that Right you try to hire artists and they make them use this other thing.
Speaker 1: That's not Photoshop because you're not paying for Adobe because you made a thing as good as Photoshop, but it's not Photoshop.
Speaker 1: So they have no idea how the hell to use it.
Speaker 1: yep, and anyone who does know how to use it can't use that.
Speaker 1: they go somewhere else.
Speaker 1: so they use Photoshop and they don't understand What's going on.
Speaker 1: and you can't share, you know, PSD files with anybody.
Speaker 1: All right, they send you PSD's.
Speaker 1: You're like I can't use these.
Speaker 1: we have our special own Scott shop here.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Here's some SSD files.
Speaker 1: Just Scott shop documents.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I know I ran into someone who was using God, you know, I use InDesign for like all Printed design that I ever do.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: And occasionally I get files that are not from InDesign that are from something else, but you can probably open them Usually not because it's old crap.
Speaker 1: What the hell are they from?
Speaker 0: Old crap.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right, but it's like there's some industry standard.
Speaker 1: But even if you don't have that there are other reasons you want to use industry standards, right?
Speaker 1: Maybe you know, you got a fix engine there, right?
Speaker 1: Well, maybe you roll your own fix engine and you know the fix protocol.
Speaker 1: there is a pretty well documented protocol.
Speaker 0: You can follow it, but it's a super.
Speaker 0: there's hundreds of pages of.
Speaker 0: here's how I should behave in all these situations.
Speaker 0: So what?
Speaker 0: if so, you might not it's not it would be difficult.
Speaker 0: there's a. there's a lot of fiddly stuff that all the existing fixed engines just kind of do around like how to resend messages in particular race conditions and they all Kind of behave the same way.
Speaker 0: But if you just read the spec It might not necessarily be clear because they're not doing it that way based on the spec.
Speaker 0: They're doing it that way because they all already do it.
Speaker 1: But that's also like.
Speaker 1: that's pretty good.
Speaker 1: as far as like there's a lot of things out there where it's like if you don't use The industry standard thing you can't talk to any other computers that are using the industry standard thing.
Speaker 0: Right, especially with binary protocols Anything that uses binary streaming protocols.
Speaker 0: you would better be 100% in lockstep with that spec or you are F right like you need your computer to talk to someone else's computer.
Speaker 1: You know You better use the same software they're using and it is guaranteed that it works.
Speaker 1: if you try to make something Yeah might not you?
Speaker 1: it's gonna take you a Ridiculous amount of effort to make your computer talk to a different piece of software and have it work properly.
Speaker 0: Yeah So in terms of building I feel like there are only two reasons you should ever build your own tool Partly because we're in a world right now where there are programmers There are programmers who also know something else and there are people who only know something else.
Speaker 0: We're not at that future where everyone's a programmer even though we probably need to be just the way society is going.
Speaker 0: No, so Not every company is going to have programmers if you don't have programmers.
Speaker 0: Don't try to build shit.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean what you got to start hiring them, right?
Speaker 0: Yes, but you have to hire them and keep so Hire programmers to build you something custom and then walk away, right?
Speaker 1: So that is like the worst case scenario because now you have a piece of software that someone made that person's not gonna help you or talk to you anymore.
Speaker 1: and now That you don't have anyone who knows what's going on That's bad.
Speaker 1: But if you would say bought something if you'd bought Photoshop and the person leaves who knows how to Photoshop?
Speaker 1: You can get someone else.
Speaker 0: Yep Or if the software stops working because you bought some software you call whoever made this offer and be like yo dog.
Speaker 1: you build a Thing when there is really nothing out there that comes close enough to what you need.
Speaker 1: That's affordable.
Speaker 1: or you build the thing.
Speaker 1: That is your business.
Speaker 1: Yep, right Even if there are competitors to you if the thing is your business Well, that's the business you're in.
Speaker 1: you're competing with those things.
Speaker 1: Don't buy one from them.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you're gonna beat them.
Speaker 1: You're gonna do something better right?
Speaker 1: if you're make if your company makes an office suite, you don't buy Microsoft Office.
Speaker 1: You can hear how you use the the opposite you're making because you're gonna beat Microsoft Office.
Speaker 1: But you know if you just need an office suite in order to do your business, which is making something That's not an office suite Don't waste your time building why it's a Microsoft Office because you still need fucking Excel to do spreadsheets Corollary there around.
Speaker 0: if if the majority of what you're doing is Custom to you, then you definitely need to build it.
Speaker 0: If you need super specialized custom stuff because you have some secret sauce like it's your business model You should probably build it because if you can buy that thing Your business model is not as special as you might have thought it was.
Speaker 1: that's right.
Speaker 1: There are other times even though the software you might not be in the software business But you still might need to build something to get it done right if your business is unique enough.
Speaker 1: So for example, if you were a professional sport, right, you know Do you need a scorekeeping app?
Speaker 1: right things like this?
Speaker 1: that right but that's custom to your sport.
Speaker 1: So if you make up invent a new sport out of nowhere, and it's actually people are into it say, you know There's a lot of small sports.
Speaker 1: Imagine like when they started the arena football league.
Speaker 1: That was.
Speaker 1: that wasn't that long ago and it's not that popular, right?
Speaker 1: You know, there was no software for like keeping score of arena Roller.
Speaker 0: derby is way different from a lot of sports.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but that's been around a while.
Speaker 1: other rules actually changed but the point is right.
Speaker 1: they had to you know Their business was roller derby.
Speaker 1: their business wasn't software, but there was probably I imagine no existing Roller derby score keeping software that existed, right?
Speaker 1: So they either didn't have any or maybe they don't have any or someone made some right because you couldn't buy any.
Speaker 1: there was Nanda.
Speaker 0: by now there is a weird Twilight area of build and buy.
Speaker 0: this mostly only exists if you fuck up Because it hit like remedy BMC.
Speaker 0: rent like that kind of software the kind of software where you buy a big old Application from some enterprise company and it lets you configure everything inside of itself.
Speaker 1: Well, there are also things that like have plugins, right?
Speaker 1: You might buy some sort of like AutoCAD But then it's like oh but we're you know The architectural plugins don't help us because we're not architects and the machining stuff plugins don't help us because we're not making machines Right, we make weird stuff, but we still need AutoCAD because it's too like, you know doing industrial manufacturing.
Speaker 1: But the things the things we make there's no existing tool set and AutoCAD for helping us draw them better.
Speaker 0: I think you're gonna contract the plug.
Speaker 1: Oh, well, they're gonna make a plug-in or we're gonna you know We're gonna build, you know an add-on thingy the plug-in model.
Speaker 0: It seems to be the best bang for your buck or the best way to go because it basically means you're using Standard platforms and tools to be like the scaffold of whatever it is you're doing.
Speaker 0: But then the parts that are that make you special you're making yourself because that's the whole like.
Speaker 0: that's what makes you special.
Speaker 0: So like if you use WordPress to run your website cuz like everybody uses WordPress, it's fine, right?
Speaker 1: If you're doing e-commerce like everyone does e-commerce you can find e-commerce stuff.
Speaker 1: But there's something special about your website something that no one else is doing.
Speaker 1: It's a. it's a VR podcast, right?
Speaker 1: And you need us.
Speaker 1: you need some special this thing to distribute it right.
Speaker 0: a word press doesn't exist because you're the only VR podcast In town, yeah write a plug-in for WordPress that sits in your WordPress like right in alongside all your other stuff and it connects to the API of Whatever your like backend.
Speaker 0: magic is so like.
Speaker 1: we actually like.
Speaker 1: so geek nights We started off with WordPress and then I made something and sometimes I regret I'm like I wish we just still had WordPress now.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but sometimes I'm like, no if we went back to WordPress Nothing is exactly what we do.
Speaker 1: Yeah geek nights.
Speaker 0: It wouldn't work like nothing on this page is perfect But it is exactly what we wanted it to be when we made this.
Speaker 1: And the only reason it would be just fine if I actually worked on it and updated it cuz I don't have anyone to work On it and update it for me You know, but yeah, it's like cuz we do weird stuff, right?
Speaker 1: We have like different shows like really that's the thing.
Speaker 1: It's like there were plenty.
Speaker 1: if we were just doing a normal podcast with episodes It would have been just fine.
Speaker 1: But because we needed a thing we're like we had the four feeds of Monday Tuesday Wednesday Website had to generate the RSS and all the other pieces, right?
Speaker 1: It's like I could have written a bunch of WordPress plugins But it's actually easier to just write a new website than to write WordPress plugins cuz they suck and it's just easier to write HTML from scratch than write WordPress templates because they suck now.
Speaker 0: also part of that Is that when we started podcasting there were not many podcasts
Speaker 1: and I was adding I had to add in all these features like auto Tweet and video and different behaviors to different ones and the plug-in like this plugins for WordPress to auto tweet But they didn't do everything exactly right the way we wanted, you know, and there was.
Speaker 1: no they had configuration options but they didn't have the configurations.
Speaker 1: obviously we needed and something we've been doing for 10 years and I have I'm already a programmer so we had a programmer already.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's really the half of the way.
Speaker 0: reason geek nights has done as well as it has is because we were both already Technologists.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we could do both.
Speaker 1: and we if neither of us are programmers.
Speaker 1: We should not have made a website.
Speaker 0: We should have used the WordPress forever But like back then there weren't services to buy.
Speaker 1: That's also true is when we started like if we had started now I could probably find something that would do it Geek nights directly in the lips in shit maybe but when we started that stuff did not exist.
Speaker 0: So we have to read like we still do this.
Speaker 0: they have to like Upload manually through the website like it sends our fee audio to the back end of lips in it We don't use any of their front-end stuff and then we like publish back out to our own website ourselves Which that might not be ideal but they get.
Speaker 0: that's the you know.
Speaker 0: The the problem with build is that then you have to maintain and if the thing you build is Not the primary thing you're doing because the primary thing we're doing is just making this happen.
Speaker 0: The website just lets you see this Then you will probably not continue to keep all that stuff you built on The leading edge of what other people will eventually do.
Speaker 0: So now other people have caught up and surpassed what we built but yet we have a lot of invested Momentum in the thing we built to where moving would be a bigger pain in the ass than keeping the status quo.
Speaker 0: We're not gonna hire a programmer Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: So yeah, you know the next time you sit down you're about to code something.
Speaker 1: think real hard.
Speaker 1: It's something you could just buy.
Speaker 1: Also when you go shopping for software think real hard, you know, should I just make this?
Speaker 1: and there's a lot of people You know that we linked like not invented here.
Speaker 1: There's a lot of companies especially software companies that have this not invented here syndrome, right?
Speaker 1: Where basically, you know anything that wasn't made by them.
Speaker 1: It's like no we got to make it, you know weird software people.
Speaker 1: Why should we buy any software?
Speaker 1: Look I was like it can be really bad If you're a place like Google or Microsoft or on Wall Street.
Speaker 0: This is the worst because every Wall Street firm has a giant army of developers because like that's how the business is.
Speaker 0: So they always think we can build literally everything in-house.
Speaker 0: I've seen people build like entire content management systems internally.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like if you're especially if you're a Google or Microsoft or Facebook this kind of place.
Speaker 1: You know if I can, you know buy anything you just make everything.
Speaker 1: It's like why should we buy some, you know?
Speaker 1: They don't like wait, there's a there's.
Speaker 1: sometimes you might buy another company and buy.
Speaker 0: You can buy the company that makes the thing you want and force that right customize.
Speaker 1: It's like it's like Yahoo bought flicker, but Google made Google Photos, right?
Speaker 1: I think it actually was.
Speaker 1: no it was Picasa first.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they bought it too.
Speaker 0: Did they buy that or did they make Picasa?
Speaker 1: Facebook made their photo thing on their own right?
Speaker 0: I lose track.
Speaker 1: The point is, you know, they don't they're not they don't consider.
Speaker 1: You never see a situation where Google just like he's paying some other company.
Speaker 1: They either Google.
Speaker 0: in June in 2004 Google acquired Picasa from a life scape, right?
Speaker 1: You.
Speaker 1: they either buy the company or make it themselves.
Speaker 1: They don't.
Speaker 1: they're not a customer of anyone else for software.
Speaker 1: They don't do that.
Speaker 1: I'm sure they do it somewhere.
Speaker 0: someone will find an example, but they don't do it often, but I guess Only build software or anything really if You have the expertise to do so and the thing you're building is the important thing anything that isn't the important thing.
Speaker 0: Someone else probably did it better and you'll either cobble something together from open source stuff or just pay Adobe to use stupid Audition.
Speaker 1: the main thing you have to get over is that when you buy something it won't.
Speaker 1: it will never be perfect even if you're the smallest kind of job.
Speaker 1: if you're just making like a blog for one person and you use WordPress and Like that's what WordPress does.
Speaker 1: it shouldn't be perfect, right?
Speaker 1: It'll be.
Speaker 1: they'll be like one or two things that like niggle you like.
Speaker 0: Oh, I want to customize this.
Speaker 0: the one thing that you can't customize I want to come even for.
Speaker 1: like your most basic blog You're gonna have that one thing like for your restaurant or your whatever you're blogging about.
Speaker 1: That's like this is slightly wrong and you try to fix it and you just can't get it a hundred percent, right?
Speaker 1: It'll be 99% right.
Speaker 1: That's not a reason to go.
Speaker 1: make your own blog just to fix the one thing.
Speaker 1: If that one just you got to suffer with it.
Speaker 0: if that 1% thing matters that much then you probably grossly Misunderstand what it is that you're actually doing.
Speaker 1: Yeah But that's a lot of times you'll see people build something because it's not the thing they buy isn't 100% perfect.
Speaker 0: And then they build something that's not even close to 100% Because they forget about all the boring crap like people vote like especially with web stuff.
Speaker 0: People forget about how to actually make like secure user logins if you try to roll to your own.
Speaker 0: That's not a trivial problem.
Speaker 1: Yeah, don't do that.
Speaker 0: Like you think you know SSL?
Speaker 0: You don't actually really know SSL.
Speaker 0: No, there's this.
Speaker 1: encryption is definitely a thing that you should never make yourself.
Speaker 0: ever ever Nope, never never never never never.
Speaker 1: do not make anything that has to do with encryption.
Speaker 1: Just use someone else's good stuff.
Speaker 0: That's the thing you're trying to do with.
Speaker 0: encryption doesn't exist.
Speaker 0: You are probably already making a terrible mistake.
Speaker 1: or if you're not a cryptographer Don't do it.
Speaker 0: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at front row crew comm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 0: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 0: But unlike those other late shows It's actually recorded at night and the patreon patrons for this episode of geek nights are Rebecca done Nicholas Brando Alan Joyce, Heidi McNichol Amanda Duchette.
Speaker 0: great job emoji my state You calm William ice Rose Jeremy minor.
Speaker 0: every guy here loved me you gets and even when taking your lumps the Cronenberg interdimensional fan club.
Speaker 0: It's one of life's great mysteries, isn't it?
Speaker 0: Why are we here?
Speaker 0: Sherman Van Horl rarely rarely valve of all.
Speaker 0: James David White Rochelle, Monta, no no super boy.
Speaker 0: I paid five bucks to make rim say carburetor.
Speaker 0: Sailor Vista Matthew Smith Don Schleich jar Tobish and Joshua Joestar Tyler Eller Sean Yeager Sam Cordray Clinton Walton Ren from New Zealand Ryan Perrin Damn you paparazzo Brian Cedroni.
Speaker 0: I've had a bit of a tumble.
Speaker 0: redacted Chris mid give Chris Knox Daniel Redmond Shawn Klein Chris Reimer and Thomas, huh And yeah, I'm real hungry.
Speaker 0: So I'm gonna cut this off and now I leave you with something cucumber Vitamins minerals very I number silica here and nails get longer.
Speaker 2: other vitamins make your bones them stronger.
Speaker 2: Anti-wrinkle make you look younger 95% water.
Speaker 2: kidney cleanser great hydrator.
Speaker 2: detox fiber good regulator.
Speaker 2: your body good things.
Speaker 2: Don't be a traitor.
Speaker 2: get the cucumber.
Speaker 2: cut it in a slice.
Speaker 2: put it in a jug of water overnight.
Speaker 2: You know what you get for a fraction of the price.
Speaker 2: energy drink full of electrolyte.
Speaker 2: Roaring salad is one of the user as a base for your vegetable juice.
Speaker 2: another surprise for a slice on your eyes Take away the dryness revitalize.
Speaker 2: Oh, yes one thing I have left.
Speaker 2: cucumber can also help with bad breath.
Speaker 2: Watch where the bacteria that cause the odor.
Speaker 2: cucumber water instead of soda.
Speaker 2: a Maccabi a medical Monday cucumber.