Speaker 1: It's Thursday, November 9th, 2017.
Speaker 1: I'm Rym.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott.
Speaker 1: And this is Geek Nights tonight.
Speaker 1: Snacks.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: So, uh, Scott paid me to go to the Rangers game with him last night.
Speaker 0: I accidentally pushed the wrong button on the incredibly simple Google Wallet.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm sitting at work and I get basically just I get this Google notification.
Speaker 1: It's like Scott sent you 130 bucks.
Speaker 1: I'm like, huh, I'll bet Scott's hit send instead of take.
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 1: And I bet he's gonna message me and then immediately there's a message like oops.
Speaker 0: There's a message take twice as much as twice as much as was just given.
Speaker 1: But not to get too much into it because I know you nerds don't care but you should because sports are pretty great.
Speaker 1: The Rangers, the hockey team of whom we are fans.
Speaker 0: They started off the season El Garbajo.
Speaker 1: They're one of the original six and they have been a reliably good team.
Speaker 1: Not always a great team, but a contender for a while now.
Speaker 0: Last year they were good.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 1: They made it to the playoffs.
Speaker 1: It's already better than most people can hope for.
Speaker 0: NHL playoffs let a lot of teams in.
Speaker 0: They should probably eliminate the first round.
Speaker 1: But they played well, like they were.
Speaker 1: they were a respectably good team.
Speaker 1: They were not embarrassing.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and this season began and they went from being a respectably good team to being like the third worst team in the entire NHL.
Speaker 1: I think Buffalo, like the Sabres and the Coyotes were the only teams doing worse than them because at that point the Coyotes hadn't won a single game.
Speaker 1: And that seems to have turned around.
Speaker 1: They've won five games in a row now.
Speaker 1: The game we saw last night was actually pretty fucking great.
Speaker 0: I was at the first game of this five game win streak and the fifth game of this game win streak.
Speaker 1: It was a good feeling.
Speaker 0: Started on Halloween and it's continued until yesterday.
Speaker 1: The only the only the bad part was they still gave up some shitty goals.
Speaker 1: So we scored a goal and we start celebrating and then before they even finish announcing that goal Boston just scored.
Speaker 0: That is a weird thing.
Speaker 0: is that I've always wondered like they don't.
Speaker 0: whenever the the pug drops they cut off all music immediately.
Speaker 1: But they don't cut off announcements.
Speaker 0: But it's like they'll score a goal then there'll be a face-off for that to start play again and then they'll start while they're playing.
Speaker 0: they'll start announcing the goal that was just scored like goal scored by such-and-such.
Speaker 0: and it's like they're playing and like you're half paying attention.
Speaker 0: Apparently the players are half paying attention too because that's when people score right away again.
Speaker 0: It's like you should do the announcement while you know, and then drop the puck again.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but I like how I'm looking at that.
Speaker 1: I just I typed Rangers and I see the game here and it says quote Jimmy Vesey turned nightmare season around in 29 stunning seconds.
Speaker 1: Vesey's like the rising star, but none of you nerds care even though you should.
Speaker 1: but that's what we're up to last night.
Speaker 0: Also, the game started at 8 instead of 7 because it was on NBC because it's a Northeast original 6 matchup.
Speaker 0: so then that you know gets NBC's, you know dick real hard.
Speaker 1: Games starting at 8 actually really sucks.
Speaker 1: It's amazing how much that hour means when the game starts at 7. it's like I leave work at the normal time I get some food and I go to the game.
Speaker 1: 8 is like I've got too much time to kill to just like stay at work.
Speaker 0: I basically spent an hour at like the mermaid house of Wi-Fi just killing time.
Speaker 0: I don't know how people do work in those places because it's just noisy and bothersome and people coming in and out and it's like I just wanted to kill people.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's not like a normal like a co-working space where you literally just like get a tiny office somewhere.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like it's not like we work.
Speaker 0: Anyway.
Speaker 1: Yeah, thing is I'm it's weird because I'm in this giant open floor with like hundreds of people in my new place and yet like other people's conversations never really bother me and like it's just it feels like being in a normal office.
Speaker 1: It's weird.
Speaker 1: I don't know if there's like white noise generators.
Speaker 1: I just don't notice like I got to try to figure out but I can open a ticket to change the temperature of like the area right around my desk.
Speaker 1: So it was a little chilly so I did it.
Speaker 1: I like open this ticket and then like a minute later it gets like noticeably warmer right at my desk and I walked away a little bit and it was the normal temperature away a little bit.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: It's kind of amazing.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: What happens if someone actually has a good office?
Speaker 1: and yeah, he does everything and uh, you know, so uh, Oh, I can hit a button to play an ad in the live stream.
Speaker 1: That wasn't there before.
Speaker 0: Don't do that.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 1: Well, it's grayed out because I don't think I've been able to thing good I should make an ad for us and hit play and see what happens.
Speaker 0: That would be okay.
Speaker 1: That would be funny.
Speaker 0: Would we have to pay YouTube and ourselves for that?
Speaker 1: Maybe if someone clicked on it.
Speaker 1: That would be bad.
Speaker 1: You'll all click on it.
Speaker 1: Then I have to pay myself money minus the cut.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Maybe I won't do that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, don't do that.
Speaker 1: So, uh, there's only one news really cuz I don't feel like talking about anything else.
Speaker 1: and also it's really funny.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: If you're not aware out there, there's these things called Funko Pops.
Speaker 0: Alright, so the story of Funko Pop as I see it, right, as someone who's a nerd who sees sort of on the out not into that fandom, but you know from outside the fandom looking in, right, is that obviously nerds always like to collect plastic doodads.
Speaker 0: Yup.
Speaker 1: Especially if those doodads are one, associated with some IP they like and two, there is a set.
Speaker 0: Right, so in college I collected some plastic doodads when I finally had money, but then I stopped.
Speaker 1: I've still got a bunch of those plastic doodads.
Speaker 1: I got that Lupin.
Speaker 0: I got a whole box full of them, but then I stopped.
Speaker 0: cuz I wizened up, right?
Speaker 0: Even that Mech Warrior game.
Speaker 0: Anyway, um, you know, and then what happened was is like sometime after I moved to like New York after college these like vinyl figurines became real popular like the Kid Robot store and stuff like these, you know, stylish high-fashion like fancy vinyl figurines were like all the rage.
Speaker 0: There was a whole geekery about those which is I could respect it.
Speaker 0: like, you know, there was something going on there.
Speaker 1: Like I don't know.
Speaker 1: I'm not gonna collect that stuff anymore, but at the same time I have a handful of like high-quality vinyl type things.
Speaker 1: They're really high-quality like they feel good.
Speaker 0: So this company Funko Pop appeared at some point and basically they were like there's a barrel there, right?
Speaker 0: They were mass at the bottom of this barrel mass market producing that sort of.
Speaker 0: they made it like this kind of toy with every possible licensed property imaginable.
Speaker 0: But what they did is they made everything from like pro athletes to Ninja Turtles to you know obscure characters in a video game that only a few people know.
Speaker 1: now prior to this when you Usually when you saw like your favorite rock star from a thing you like in a particular style It was always like an artist in an artist alley at a con Like I draw in this style and I draw all the characters from all the anime you're like in that style.
Speaker 1: that was a thing and this company seems to just taking that and remove the soul from it and made this like Mass market right crank out IP for things that don't have enough social currency.
Speaker 0: It's all sort of like.
Speaker 0: it's certainly Beanie Babies with intellectual property.
Speaker 0: so the idea was that hey we can sell to people who like our toys and they'll buy any of them and Will also people who care about a particular intellectual property, which everyone cares about Something right.
Speaker 0: as a Transformers fan a football fan a baseball fan, you know metal fan We will have a figure for pretty much everyone.
Speaker 0: So everyone's gonna buy a few of these no matter who they are Right, and that's how we'll make some whole ton of monies.
Speaker 0: and apparently they got enough money from somewhere to produce all these fucking things Zillions of them everywhere.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean it's pretty like the process of making these cannot be very different.
Speaker 0: No, there's obviously a factory that spits out just zillions of them for nothing.
Speaker 0: But and then it must cost like 50 cents to make and they charge a lot like dollars for them, right?
Speaker 0: but if you look like I knew long ago these things are going down the toilet when I saw them like Stop every single nerd store every single booth at every single con and all the lead like
Speaker 1: a little tower of these and
Speaker 0: all the loot Crates in the universe right specifically the loot crate.
Speaker 1: at this point I'm pretty sure loot crate means the things that are in this box are about to fail in the mass market.
Speaker 0: Yes Cuz loot crate is a way for companies that make nerdy shit to dump their excess inventory and still get some money for it because if you just put it on a clearance shelf No one will buy it for any amount of money.
Speaker 0: again.
Speaker 1: The anime cons were ahead of the game because the the low tier like anime Sellers it would show up at conventions would make grab boxes of mystery boxes and stuff like that inventory You can't move.
Speaker 1: and when you bought him It was 40 bucks for basically a bunch of garbage that they were literally going to throw away if they couldn't sell right?
Speaker 0: So Funko pop.
Speaker 0: when you see so many Funko pop things everywhere Just trying to sell trying so hard to get rid of these things, right?
Speaker 0: You see just so so much, you know over production and such not enough demand.
Speaker 0: There was demand.
Speaker 0: There were.
Speaker 0: people were into these like almost every nerd I know except for me like has some of these but at the same time people are way into them more than others.
Speaker 0: But the demand did not meet the supply.
Speaker 0: It's not like they were flying off the shelves at the conventions.
Speaker 0: at the end of the convention It'd still be tons of these things at Barnes & Noble.
Speaker 0: There's just tons of them at the local game store.
Speaker 0: There's tons of them.
Speaker 1: I guess about them is that I mean I didn't like the aesthetic.
Speaker 1: but that's not.
Speaker 1: that doesn't necessarily mean something's bad.
Speaker 0: There's a lot of things I don't like.
Speaker 0: that succeed.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah But the aesthetic is basically like those black soulless eyes.
Speaker 1: and as soon as I saw these start to appear everywhere All I could think was that those black soulless eyes are the soulless eyes of the person who's trying to catch this out.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so I didn't know this was happening or else I might.
Speaker 0: I sold short but the Funko pop is its own company It's not owned by anything.
Speaker 0: and they made an IPO which seems like the dumbest idea in the universe to go public.
Speaker 1: and if I don't there or not there was an IPO and I Knew anyone involved in it.
Speaker 1: I would have I would have pointed out to them that this is a bad idea.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and this is not just us like.
Speaker 1: Oh hindsight is not the worst idea.
Speaker 1: I a pair as best I can tell part of the reason the IPO does that I think some initial investors like Took their money back and as a result, they needed money to cover debt.
Speaker 0: Yeah, something like that, but that's not shady.
Speaker 1: stuff like that happens all the time.
Speaker 0: Like that's normal business Yeah, but anyway, this IPO is the worst IPO.
Speaker 0: like all time They said I said a starting price anyway.
Speaker 1: It's so bad that when I typed Funko pop IPO into Google to get the article to talk about this on the show every article I see is either the announcement or All these things talking about how crazy this IPO is gonna be like right here, right?
Speaker 0: Cuz when you're doing an IPO and it hasn't happened yet you pump the news You do all sorts of press releases and stuff with your numbers that you've worked out.
Speaker 0: Like please buy our stock.
Speaker 0: Here's all the great reasons.
Speaker 0: We're gonna perform so well.
Speaker 0: We're making tons of money in this.
Speaker 1: from a little while ago Funko pop IPO could top 245 million more than doubling initial estimate.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm Funko pop.
Speaker 0: That's a new.
Speaker 0: that's a news created by Funko pop before the IPO.
Speaker 0: That's how I peels.
Speaker 0: every IPO has this.
Speaker 0: any IPO ever has new people pumping the news Full of hype to get people to buy the stock and also to get bots to buy the stock.
Speaker 1: Funko bumps up Size of planned IPO.
Speaker 1: so they raised the size of the IPO as well like their projections.
Speaker 1: now I'm not gonna get into explaining how IPOs really work cuz you don't care and you won't understand any.
Speaker 1: well Yeah, but it's it's.
Speaker 1: it's not as complicated as you'd think.
Speaker 1: it's just not really relevant to this.
Speaker 1: because what's relevant is that as many of you know, I I do some stock investment and I tend to invest in a lot of nerdy stuff.
Speaker 1: But I do it because I understand nerdy stuff Like I know a lot about nerdy company what you want to invest in real estate if you don't know anything about real estate Nerdy things.
Speaker 0: so we invest in nerdy things.
Speaker 1: I've made a lot of money on my stocks over the years.
Speaker 1: Like I'm not gonna lie about that The reason I have in my opinion and I'm not giving you investment advice.
Speaker 1: This is not advice.
Speaker 0: Hey, everyone call the SEC and they'll shut rim down.
Speaker 1: Hey, they'll take his patreon monies, but I When I invest whenever I think that Wall Street has an opinion about a nerdy thing But I being the person who is involved in nerdy things Understands it better than they do So.
Speaker 1: for example, I bought a shit ton of Hasbro a long time ago because I was like Hasbro's got the my little pony license And holy shit, is that gonna make that money?
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm or Hasbro's got the Disney Princess license
Speaker 0: and D&D and yeah This is the coast and magic
Speaker 1: I like how I bought a bunch of Toyota stock a long long time ago because they had that scandal about breaks like though the the Accelerators and breaks are failing and killing people.
Speaker 0: You don't want to invest in this company.
Speaker 0: that's depending on buying licenses from people to make stuff.
Speaker 0: you want to invest in the company that has the license and is selling it to funko pop.
Speaker 0: because Even if funko pops don't sell Hasbro still got their money from all the transformers funko pops.
Speaker 0: It doesn't matter whether those funko pops actually sell or not.
Speaker 1: So what happened with the funko pop IPO is not just like ha ha.
Speaker 1: look at this nerd company.
Speaker 1: This is like legit Wall Street people whose job it is to underwrite IPOs Literally had no idea what funko pop was and what its real value proposition was.
Speaker 0: I can imagine the going out of business soon, right?
Speaker 1: Uh, so funko pop shares plunged more than 40 percent after the IP.
Speaker 0: This is actually really good because it means the CEOs and executives and board members of funko pop won't be mega rich from it.
Speaker 0: This was really got more money than we do, but they lost a lot of money.
Speaker 1: This was the worst less rich the worst first day for an IPO Full stop in two decades.
Speaker 0: What was the one two decades ago?
Speaker 1: I don't even know.
Speaker 1: I don't.
Speaker 1: so they're having to caveat that IPO is really dropped off after the like 2008 like when the market went south.
Speaker 0: Yeah, everyone just gets a VZ now.
Speaker 0: Yeah, which I think that's they don't depend on going public to get investment.
Speaker 1: VC has its own problems.
Speaker 1: So I like the pendulum is gonna go back but knows There are many ways.
Speaker 0: there are many ways to get your monies, I wish the pendulum would swing toward just getting a loan.
Speaker 0: No one seems to do that anymore.
Speaker 1: It's very interesting to me how little anyone involved in this IPO process seemed to know about like nerd stuff.
Speaker 1: And yet funko like pop.
Speaker 1: this company their entire business model seemed to be Panda to the lowest common denominator of nerds like you'd think.
Speaker 1: they can hit that out of the park.
Speaker 1: But it seems like they are super overvalued and this is all really funny to me.
Speaker 0: I feel like funko pop could have done Well, if they simply produce the right numbers of each funko pop, right?
Speaker 0: It feels like they just made too many of ones that weren't gonna sell.
Speaker 0: and maybe right.
Speaker 0: It's like you just have to calculate like aha.
Speaker 0: This character has this many fans.
Speaker 0: It's like.
Speaker 0: it's like a. it's like the least popular Harry Potter character, but Harry Potter is still popular.
Speaker 0: Well this many if we have if they have good analytics.
Speaker 0: Well, there's this many people who will collect every single Harry Potter funko pop no matter what and is.
Speaker 0: this many people are specifically a Fan of this character judging by the amount of fanfiction and we'll make a few extra like one for each store.
Speaker 1: so make this many instead of now you go and there's like a thousand of them and no one wants them, so Part of the reason why I think they had so much trouble is that they had a lot of that private equity money Like.
Speaker 0: that's how a lot of companies they just set it on fire without caring about spending it wisely.
Speaker 1: No, I don't think it's even that.
Speaker 1: the problem with private equity money is that those people want to make money
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm,
Speaker 1: and as a result, they're not actually that interested sometimes in the long-term viability of your company Mmm, and there's a lot of issues with the things they might want to do that You may not want to
Speaker 0: do.
Speaker 0: are you saying that those are the people who got stock before the IPO because they own they invested And then they sold it once the IPO happened.
Speaker 1: It's not actually stock.
Speaker 1: It's way more complicated than that.
Speaker 0: The point is they own part of the company PC as soon as it goes public.
Speaker 0: they sell and then the IPO tank.
Speaker 1: if you have a company that say could be worth 10 mil and could make a million dollar profit a year like forever, but you take a hundred mil or 500 mil no one.
Speaker 0: No one can wait a hundred years.
Speaker 0: I mean even I'm not great.
Speaker 0: I'm like against greed, but honestly if I gives you a hundred mil I can't wait a hundred years to give a hundred mil back.
Speaker 1: But basically if Like if your investments are too big your company will have to grow bigger than might actually be viable or than what you might have Actually wanted to do if you didn't take all that money like if you gave geek nights 500 grand.
Speaker 1: we probably keep doing what we're doing now and quit our jobs.
Speaker 1: if you gave us like 500 million dollars I would just buy like we would just.
Speaker 1: I would just retire forever and never do anything.
Speaker 0: I would buy a cheap sports team somewhere and then yeah instead of doing geek nights and then you'd get paid back from that.
Speaker 1: I could make more returns for you by investing that money just back in the market.
Speaker 0: I could just buy an index fund and give you half of the interest.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like I couldn't do anything with that money to make geek nights better.
Speaker 0: No, there's no way.
Speaker 0: There's no way geek nights could make even at the most successful geek nights If it was like a Broadway show and a TV show on primetime could make back five hundred million dollars.
Speaker 1: but the other thing is that I've never liked Funko pop because it really feels like.
Speaker 1: The only reason this exists at all in the scale that it did was that and this is the same thing again.
Speaker 1: Anime cons are always kind of ahead of this.
Speaker 1: nerds would be fans of some anime in America.
Speaker 1: but they want merch because a lot of nerds really want like this social currency to carry around and Officially licensed merch lagged behind the thing that they were into by three to five years.
Speaker 1: As a result they would buy bootleg shit because they really needed a full metal alchemist t-shirt and plastic thing and plush to prove that They are fans of that thing.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I just I just got over needing to have a plastic figurine like, you know, 15 some odd years ago.
Speaker 0: And now I'm done with that part of my life and I have a bunch of figurines in the closet and that's it.
Speaker 1: I'm happy to express my fandom for say little witch academia by when talking to other anime fans saying things like hey guys I really like little witch academia, you know in a Gundam I can buy a few Gundams because that's an activity of building them just like Legos.
Speaker 0: There's an activity going on but you buy a Funko pop and you put it on the shelf and it sits there looking at you.
Speaker 0: I guess you spend a bunch of money on that.
Speaker 1: The reason I didn't trust Funko pop in the end was that the business model of selling the social currency That of IPS that you don't own two people who literally build their personal identity Around those IPS and thus that social currency.
Speaker 1: that demographic is not a demographic you want to tie yourself to know as a company and doesn't have a lot of money because then you get.
Speaker 1: then you're gonna Turn into like Marvel and DC comics themselves the floppies and the demographic they cater to.
Speaker 1: and I definitely noticed in my nerd dealings that most of the people have money if They're buying the like vinyl nerdy stuff.
Speaker 1: They're not buying the Funko pops.
Speaker 1: They're buying the like much more expensive smaller run limited things.
Speaker 1: They're not more discerning in terms of buying social currency and wrapping their identity up, but they're not buying the Funko pops.
Speaker 1: so this is all just kind of funny and I Laugh at it more than I'm saddened by it.
Speaker 1: what anyway?
Speaker 1: things of the day?
Speaker 1: So I gotta say I gotta tip my hat to Scott.
Speaker 0: your thing of the day My thing of the days are always better than your thing of the day.
Speaker 0: It's just this week in particular.
Speaker 0: I had a plus things the day.
Speaker 1: Do our thing of the day off?
Speaker 0: this is just showing is just a Key example of how much better my things of the day usually are.
Speaker 0: but it's just this week.
Speaker 1: So I was looking at stats though in the forum my things that they get clicked on more often than yours do.
Speaker 0: how do you?
Speaker 0: Know that?
Speaker 1: because it says how many times any link I clicked on in any forum post.
Speaker 1: Uh-huh So that's I haven't looked at old threads to see if that still is true But that there's an interesting metric we can use.
Speaker 0: in the future We'll have to make one of those things really get shows two things.
Speaker 0: the day you click one Which you and you think is better like hot or not?
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, you just keeps picking random ones and then at the end it'll be like aha Well, we were gonna do at some point is do a thing of the day Thursday.
Speaker 1: This is like about our Thursday shows.
Speaker 1: That's like if we really don't have an idea is we're both gonna pick what we think are our own personal best top 10 things of the day and then try to do some sort of tournament with them and let you guys decide who is truly the king of Things
Speaker 0: Thousands of things of the day and how many of them are 404. now, I'd like figure out.
Speaker 1: Yep That's why we haven't done it yet.
Speaker 0: I'd have to take me a whole day just to go through my things of the day and figure out which ones.
Speaker 1: Meaning this episode is not happening until it's like the worst weather outside.
Speaker 1: It's not gonna happen Someday ten years from now.
Speaker 1: We're really out of episode ideas.
Speaker 1: So I'll do my thing today.
Speaker 1: first Because Scott's is just - I can't get over how great this is.
Speaker 1: So I chose a Simpsons appropriate thing of the day because I realized that I quote.
Speaker 1: my favorite character on The Simpsons was always Moses like.
Speaker 1: but My second favorite character was always Gil Gunderson.
Speaker 1: All gail old gills eating food tonight.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: And he's done in that many episodes for what he is is pure gold.
Speaker 1: and I realized that I quote Gil a lot Like some people quote like certain things from The Simpsons like that's their thing Gil's.
Speaker 1: the one I quote.
Speaker 1: and I realized that a bunch of our friends.
Speaker 1: They assumed I was quoting something rightly But they didn't know is from The Simpsons.
Speaker 1: They didn't know who old Gil was.
Speaker 0: I did not know kennel Gil.
Speaker 1: get a taste.
Speaker 1: I'll look at that brass ring.
Speaker 1: So this is a compilation of the best of Gil Gunderson.
Speaker 0: Okay, great I'm sure as rim picked The Simpsons thing today because y'all saw that I had already picked The Simpsons thing of the day.
Speaker 0: This is steamed hams Except it's a custom guitar hero song.
Speaker 0: apparently there's like a mini genre of this on YouTube that I wasn't aware of where you'll take something that is Definitely not rhythm a rhythm song and then make a guitar hero track custom guitar hero track to it.
Speaker 0: So this is literally just that scene from The Simpsons where Super Nintendo Chalmers goes to Skinner's house for dinner Like top five favorite scenes in the entire run.
Speaker 0: then on top of it There's a guitar hero fretboard with the dots coming down that you can I guess play if you've got a modded guitar hero set up.
Speaker 1: It is.
Speaker 0: and if you go on YouTube and look at related videos, there's tons of these things.
Speaker 0: But this is the best of them by far kind of like a rhythm heaven.
Speaker 1: Like that's another thing people would make like fake rhythm heavens.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and the pony one was probably the best one of those should just put DDR hours instead.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah Well, so I did find someone made arrows and I found this by accident But it seems like the thing that I would seek out or that I would have secretly made.
Speaker 1: But someone made pretty good arrows to piss Admiral dildo captain.
Speaker 0: Oh, but yeah but anyway the the.
Speaker 0: what's fun about this is that the the notes you have to play not only include all of the dialogue between Skinner and Chalmers but also the background music like didn't do which you call steamed hams.
Speaker 1: Yes The Aurora Borealis The see I got literally top five Simpsons scenes like.
Speaker 1: I Cannot express to you how much I like this thing today because of how much I like this scene.
Speaker 1: So Scott you make a fine steamed ham.
Speaker 1: In the moment we were at gamer X East it was exactly what it purported to be And we have a weekend to relax.
Speaker 1: and then next.
Speaker 1: well, we gotta prepare but Next weekend is packs unplugged.
Speaker 0: Oh crap.
Speaker 1: It is the tabletop only packs.
Speaker 1: We will be there enforcing and doing an event on Saturday and tabletop tourney for 3 30 p.m.
Speaker 1: For two hours.
Speaker 1: It's just gonna be great and you should be there.
Speaker 0: the badges for packs east one on sale today Which for you is probably already yesterday.
Speaker 1: They're already sold out.
Speaker 1: You're fucked.
Speaker 1: The hotels are sold out.
Speaker 0: If you're gonna be there though, so away probably.
Speaker 1: yep, we're gonna be enforced.
Speaker 0: We'd haven't had like some panel approved, but it's like 99 submissions are not even open.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there's 99% chance We're gonna enforce there again, and we'll be there again.
Speaker 0: We already got 100% chance will enforce.
Speaker 0: cuz we're already they could reject us.
Speaker 0: No, we're counting.
Speaker 0: I'm accounting for that possibility.
Speaker 1: I don't think they reject people who are already registered.
Speaker 0: Listen, there's a non zero percent chance They could decide.
Speaker 0: you know what?
Speaker 0: We don't like those veganized guys.
Speaker 1: Yeah I mean there's a chance that they could just cancel packs East like.
Speaker 1: well.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Sorry guys We also have to account for that.
Speaker 1: You know what?
Speaker 1: I don't account for that.
Speaker 0: Okay in the not accounting for things like that We're a hundred percent going to be there.
Speaker 1: Yep I mean that is like worrying about the existential solipsistic nature of the universe.
Speaker 1: Like I don't roll that Determination into my chances of whether or not packs will happen anyway.
Speaker 1: But I actually only Saturday is sold out because packs East is a good packs.
Speaker 1: But it's now four days Thursday Friday Saturday Sunday Yep, but packs East has probably the highest percent percentage of day trippers like people who literally only come for a day.
Speaker 0: Also, there's hotel issues.
Speaker 0: We tried to book a two-bedroom for Wednesday night Thursday night Friday night Saturday night Sunday night check out on Monday.
Speaker 1: there are zero of those at Hotels that matter.
Speaker 1: and I say that matter because the main problem with packs East is that it is the biggest packs by.
Speaker 0: People keep taking shuttles to these faraway hotels on the other side of town.
Speaker 0: Only we don't do that shit.
Speaker 1: There are only Arguably four or five hotels that are within a reasonable distance.
Speaker 0: Yeah So the hotel that we wanted to stay at their two bedrooms didn't have Wednesday night So I had to.
Speaker 0: we got to one bedrooms.
Speaker 0: It's not ideal in a different hotel that is still right next to that one.
Speaker 1: This nearly doubled our costs for packs East.
Speaker 1: I'm telling you guys pack South cost less to go to then packs East.
Speaker 0: no matter where you live Even no matter where you live on earth pack South is cheaper than packs.
Speaker 1: If you live in Southie and are just going to like walk to PAX East.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: This is cheaper.
Speaker 0: Sure That's right.
Speaker 1: But if you live in New York pack South is cheaper than packs East.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm, and especially now that there's a fourth day If you can get to PAX East without using a car from your house, then it's cheaper.
Speaker 0: otherwise not.
Speaker 1: but yeah, it's gonna be a real busy time for us because right after PAX East or packs unplugged is Holidays and then more holidays and then we got New Year's mag.
Speaker 1: fast packs unplug or pack pack South one two three boom boom boom and then packs East is like right after that.
Speaker 1: so anime Boston is great and really the only reason we stopped going to anime Boston is that I need a break between all that Nonsense and the nonsense that happens starting in May.
Speaker 1: So yeah, we got a lot of cons coming up Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: Otherwise follow scops YouTube channel and my youtube channel because there's a ton of crap there.
Speaker 0: all the other internet services That you can think of social media networks and whatever.
Speaker 0: look for me rim and or geek nights on those things because we are there.
Speaker 1: So snacks because Thursdays is like.
Speaker 0: are you sure we didn't do the show already?
Speaker 1: I could did a cursory like half-assed search.
Speaker 1: Okay, and I don't know if we did it.
Speaker 1: if we did it in the past I'm sure someone will say something if no one says anything.
Speaker 0: That's fine.
Speaker 0: Let's let's let's be pedantic cuz that's.
Speaker 0: that's how geek nights do right.
Speaker 1: Wikipedia.
Speaker 1: What is a portion of food smaller than a regular meal?
Speaker 0: What?
Speaker 0: how big is a meal?
Speaker 1: What if I?
Speaker 1: so let's go to the Wikipedia.
Speaker 1: wait, so there's Wikipedia articles on both food measuring calories like.
Speaker 1: so Scott Do you want to argue about what constitutes food or what constitutes a meal a meal?
Speaker 0: Cuz the snack is smaller than a regular meal meal.
Speaker 1: a meal is an eating occasion.
Speaker 1: eating has its own Wikipedia page That takes place at a certain time.
Speaker 1: Oh That actually sets us up pretty well and includes Specific prepared food or the food eaten on that occasion.
Speaker 1: Okay, so meals are scheduled.
Speaker 1: snacks are unscheduled.
Speaker 0: I agree with this.
Speaker 0: snacks are the things you eat in between Breakfast lunch dinner and not dessert either now.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I would argue if you it's like.
Speaker 0: it's like.
Speaker 0: oh I already ate breakfast which is a nice breakfast sandwich.
Speaker 0: It's not yet time for lunch.
Speaker 0: some pizza, but I'm hungry and it's morning I will eat this fruit and that counts as a snack.
Speaker 0: or oh it is lunches past.
Speaker 0: I already ate pizza and I'm not yet home to cook a dinner.
Speaker 0: I am still at work, but I am hungry And it's three o'clock.
Speaker 0: Let me eat this granola bar.
Speaker 0: That is a snack.
Speaker 1: So I think the scheduling aspect is what makes the difference.
Speaker 1: Primarily so that means that if you are the kind of person who eats second breakfast, that is not a snack.
Speaker 1: That is just another meal and you're gonna get fat or your hobbit All right, so I I think we need to argue about what food is but I actually I'm gonna click on this Wikipedia article.
Speaker 1: All right food is any substance consumed to provide nutritional support for an organ.
Speaker 0: I agree with that anyway.
Speaker 0: so Snacking like.
Speaker 0: I guess I don't remember what snacks I ate when I was a vivid.
Speaker 1: I actually yeah, baby I don't.
Speaker 1: but from elementary school on I have a Perfect memory of the kinds of snacks that I ate.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: There are many snacks I ate.
Speaker 0: I ate a cup of yogurt with fruit on the bottom when I was a kid on the bottom.
Speaker 1: I hated yogurt.
Speaker 1: I never ate yogurt as a kid.
Speaker 1: That shit was disgusting.
Speaker 0: I like yogurt.
Speaker 0: I had to have fruit on the bottom.
Speaker 0: just yogurt was no good.
Speaker 1: I also liked jelly to up to a point and then at some point in my young childhood I decided that jelly was bullshit, right and I stopped eating jelly of any kind until I became an adult and I started eating jelly again.
Speaker 0: Okay
Speaker 1: Others Remember so a thing I would do when I was a young kid and it's so specific and I remember this partly because it came Up in conversation recently because I once fell down the stairs and hurt my neck real bad had to take a ride in an ambulance Mm-hmm, and I remember the moment when I fell down the stairs.
Speaker 1: My mom thought I was pushed by a ghost But I actually just slipped.
Speaker 1: and I remember so specifically that my heel of my left foot Brushed the front of the next step instead of landing firmly on the step and then I slid like Forward off of it and that caused me to roll down the stairs.
Speaker 1: But just as the reason I was distracted walking down the stairs It was jelly was that I had been in the kitchen eating snacks Right before this and I ran upstairs.
Speaker 1: I don't remember why.
Speaker 1: I went upstairs to do something and then I came back.
Speaker 1: I was coming back down the stairs and I was thinking to myself Should I eat the cheese it and then the alphabets?
Speaker 1: Well, like one of the other or should I combine them before I put them in my mouth?
Speaker 1: Yeah, well, why savory alphabet?
Speaker 0: alphabets are like a gross.
Speaker 0: They're basically Cheerios in a different shape.
Speaker 1: They were sweeter.
Speaker 1: They had like sugar.
Speaker 1: I had sugar in there.
Speaker 1: I never ate discuss Alphabets in a bowl without milk and I'm one bowl of that.
Speaker 1: and I also had a bowl of cheese.
Speaker 0: What the hell's wrong.
Speaker 1: and I remember vaguely that I had some sort of rhythm to like how many of each I would eat.
Speaker 0: So I remember a lot like cheeses.
Speaker 0: I should buy cheeses again.
Speaker 0: I
Speaker 1: used to actually through elementary school middle school high school I actually thought a lot about snacking like I would prepare snacks like they were meals like I'd come home from high school and I would like go to the kitchen and get out like three kinds of cheese and like Make all these different slices and like arrange them on a plate with crackers and croutons and peanuts
Speaker 0: Probably
Speaker 1: like a third of a pound of cheese.
Speaker 0: all told I would just go into the kitchen.
Speaker 1: I would sit at the computer Eating this cheese and snacks while I was doing whatever it is.
Speaker 1: I did on computers before the internet was really
Speaker 0: all I did if I was hungry and I would go into the kitchen and try To find something and I take it and eat it and then I'd go back and then if I was still hungry I'd go back again and get something else and was still hungry go back again Get something else and repeat but I would never eat the same thing two times in a day.
Speaker 1: You you're weird about that.
Speaker 1: even now, you know, we'll be like, hey, let's get some Italian food You'll be like I had Italian food.
Speaker 0: Okay, so if it's a meal, I can't have the same scheduled meal two days in a row.
Speaker 0: So if I ate Indian food yesterday, I can't eat Indian today.
Speaker 1: higher Ethnic class of food is what's covered.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if I ate Italian food yesterday American food two days in a row.
Speaker 0: if I ate hamburger yesterday, I don't get hamburger today.
Speaker 1: But would you eat a hot dog today?
Speaker 1: Is that the same class of food?
Speaker 1: Probably not Okay, but yet all Indian food is the same is pad.
Speaker 1: See you and pad kebab Those are two different kinds of food.
Speaker 0: if I ate Thai food yesterday won't eat that food.
Speaker 1: Okay, so you've just got racist food preferences.
Speaker 0: Anyway, the point is just saying if it's a snack Right say like a banana, right?
Speaker 0: Well, that's not a meal.
Speaker 0: I can eat one banana each day.
Speaker 0: I just can't eat a tube banana in the same day unless it's some extenuating circumstance like long bike ride After a bike ride.
Speaker 1: So the other day I ran a half marathon.
Speaker 0: We have free bananas for you.
Speaker 0: Well, I guess I will eat ten of them.
Speaker 1: the other day I ran a half marathon and when I run a half marathon usually means I run to some distant point and then I take the Subway home.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: So cuz I don't want to run a big loop cuz I'll get bored.
Speaker 1: Yes I ran up to the top Manhattan and There's fucking nothing up there.
Speaker 0: Like there's like a fruit stand in the corner.
Speaker 0: No, I'm talking like 225th Street even a dirty hot water dog.
Speaker 1: So up there.
Speaker 1: There's no street food.
Speaker 1: on a Saturday There's delis.
Speaker 1: that looked so bad that I would rather like I wouldn't.
Speaker 0: you can get some yellow food group from there.
Speaker 1: Uh, yeah, I did not trust the yellow food group in that place.
Speaker 0: You know wrapped in sealed yellow food group.
Speaker 1: Well, so on my body rejects food like that at this point.
Speaker 0: Like not hungry though.
Speaker 1: I would read no matter how hungry I am.
Speaker 1: I'd rather go hungry than eat a Twinkie.
Speaker 0: I mean I've never been hungry enough to eat the Twinkie.
Speaker 0: not they don't make Twinkies anymore But there is a point at which I will eat.
Speaker 1: when I was a kid I would eat like two packs of Twinkies and I actually didn't like Twinkies.
Speaker 0: I was all about the ring ding ring.
Speaker 0: So I like those hostess cupcakes, but I like those are okay But I like the non chocolate one one.
Speaker 0: There was a snack that I had a lot when I was high school and such with cakes.
Speaker 0: No, it was a box full of Not real ring dings, but these you would get into it.
Speaker 0: There were these little plastically wrapped two tiny ring dings.
Speaker 0: So you'd go in there and grab and open the plastic and there'd be two tiny ring dings.
Speaker 1: How tiny cuz.
Speaker 1: I would get the box like this.
Speaker 1: Bing I get the bot.
Speaker 1: Okay Cuz I had the box of zebra cakes and they'd always come with individually wrapped plastic things.
Speaker 1: that had two zebra cakes each Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: But yeah, I was like.
Speaker 0: it was like mini ring dings in a box and you get two at a time.
Speaker 1: so I ran all.
Speaker 1: I ran from my apartment all the way to the top of Manhattan and it was like I ran like 14 or 15 miles and I Needed to eat something and there's nothing up there except the gentrifying is happening.
Speaker 1: So there's this like super overpriced bullshit food seller type supermarket in the middle of this.
Speaker 1: Uh-huh, so I go in there and I basically bought like four bananas and a much more of those bananas way too much money Like 40 cents each.
Speaker 1: Okay, and a small bag of clementines and I just ate them all as I rode the subway home Because the biker eating a bike ride.
Speaker 1: tires are out run as far as you normally bike that.
Speaker 1: no, I don't.
Speaker 1: yeah My body was like I will kill you if you don't need something.
Speaker 1: It was like eat oranges eat lemons If you have to it's other snacks that I see.
Speaker 0: it's weird like this.
Speaker 0: I gotta address something the snacks I eat back in the day or nothing like the snacks I eat today.
Speaker 0: Oh back at some point I changed from one kind of snack to a different kind.
Speaker 1: So I when I was like when I was elementary school up through high school The primary snack I ate was savory.
Speaker 1: usually snack mixes Like doodads was my favorite snack mix in the world like that when doodads disappeared.
Speaker 1: I literally do.
Speaker 1: that is I don't know if they were sold around.
Speaker 0: the things I ate before right.
Speaker 0: I ate the mini ring ding.
Speaker 0: I ate the string cheese.
Speaker 0: You get one string cheese, right?
Speaker 0: I would eat yet.
Speaker 0: I don't know if they still make these as a kudos.
Speaker 1: Like imagine checks and checks makes but like way more flavorful, okay, so I eat these kudos bars.
Speaker 0: I don't know if they still make them but what they are.
Speaker 1: I remember those things.
Speaker 1: I did not like those things.
Speaker 0: So imagine like nowadays they have bars like kind bar, right?
Speaker 1: Oh my god, my by crave doodads so much now.
Speaker 0: So a kind bar is kind of like this stiff granola bar that's supposed to be healthy or whatever.
Speaker 0: Right a kudos bar is basically that with absolutely no pretending to be healthy, right?
Speaker 0: It's it's granola filled with like chocolate chips and some kind of sticky sugar to hold it together and then 100% sealed in chocolate.
Speaker 0: This chocolate on every edge like that ice cream on a stick.
Speaker 0: That's just chocolate with the ice cream inside of it.
Speaker 0: It's like that.
Speaker 0: so it's like yeah It's a granola bar that does not pretend to be a healthy kind or whatever.
Speaker 0: crud with those like Clif bar.
Speaker 0: It's like no no, no, this is chocolate.
Speaker 1: It's interesting.
Speaker 1: I don't treat Bars as snacks like I. never I never.
Speaker 0: a bar is a snack.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so here's the thing.
Speaker 1: I never but I never eat those kinds of things in the context of I'm sitting here and I'm hungry.
Speaker 1: I only ever eat those things in the context of I am on a long sporting thing and I need to bring.
Speaker 0: I'm talking about.
Speaker 0: You know the olden days, right?
Speaker 0: I would all see, you know yogurt with the fruit on the bottom and eat.
Speaker 1: I mostly eat things that were like actual fruit like an actual banana.
Speaker 0: Oh pretzel stick out all pretzel stick.
Speaker 0: The thing with pretzel stick right is that we get the big rods.
Speaker 0: rods are the way to go.
Speaker 0: I would always eat two pretzel rod.
Speaker 1: I didn't like cigar.
Speaker 1: I just keep eating them.
Speaker 1: Just hold it in my mouth like a cigar and suck on it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, two pretzel rod.
Speaker 0: and the way I'd eat it is I'd eat all the salt first and then I need the pretzel Right.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and then I would do it through the other pretzel.
Speaker 1: I pretty much when I snacked I only wanted cheese and snack mix type things and nuts.
Speaker 0: if it was a cheese situation It was the string cheese.
Speaker 0: But actually when I was way younger you would I would get the thing that was Four crackers a red plastic stick and a little cheese bucket.
Speaker 1: Oh when I was in elementary school I love those in first grade I eat like two or three of them.
Speaker 0: one go in first grade.
Speaker 0: in the toy section of the room There was a bowl a big bowl like a mixing bowl Yeah And it was 100% full with red plastic sticks that were cleaned off after everyone ate and tossed.
Speaker 0: It was like there must have been a thousands of red sticks in this bowl.
Speaker 0: It was great.
Speaker 1: Yep, so I got to address something because in the stream a lot of people to get you the fact that I stopped eating jelly And they all have the same question.
Speaker 1: So what'd you put on your peanut butter and jelly?
Speaker 1: You know what?
Speaker 1: I'm not I'm gonna be blunt.
Speaker 1: I think peanut butter and jelly sandwiches are fucking disgusting.
Speaker 0: No, they're great.
Speaker 1: I and I like savory sweet combinations.
Speaker 1: I like peanut butter.
Speaker 1: I like peanut butter sandwiches peanut butter toast.
Speaker 1: I like jelly preserves and marmalade and all those things.
Speaker 1: peanut butter and jelly on white bread is Disgusting.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: So here's the thing.
Speaker 0: white bread is disgusting has to be wheat bread.
Speaker 0: I can't do.
Speaker 0: no.
Speaker 1: white peanut butter and jelly on bread is disgusting.
Speaker 1: Oh, no, no, I do not like that.
Speaker 0: It's so good.
Speaker 0: It's a staple.
Speaker 1: But what really amazes me is that as a kid?
Speaker 1: I would eat snacks all and when I say kid, I mean all the way through high school I would eat snacks that are bigger than meals I eat today Like I would get home from school and maybe added the snacks together.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'd literally eat like a third a pound of cheese and like half a box of crackers and just like wall I was fucking around on the computer Pretty much right before dinner and then I'd eat dinner and I'd be totally fine.
Speaker 1: Yeah nowadays I basically like I almost never eat snacks.
Speaker 0: So that's the thing is like in college snacks are all over the place because food was hard to get.
Speaker 1: yeah I was dead in college.
Speaker 1: That's it.
Speaker 1: No, it wasn't snacks.
Speaker 0: That was fuel like Calories I consume just like food all over the place random who knows what.
Speaker 1: right if you got calories in college You fucking ate it cuz you didn't know when the next calories.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but then once you know entered the real world like the snacking.
Speaker 1: so there's no animals.
Speaker 1: Right, if you like you rescue certain kinds of animals They'll do a thing where they're food aggressive because they were deprived of food.
Speaker 1: So when they have access to food, they don't trust that they'll still have access to be eat all of it.
Speaker 1: I was food aggressive in college and it wasn't until I had like several years in a row of having money and literally like Going to the grocery store and just buying whatever I wanted instead of thinking I can afford $14 worth of groceries.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but nowadays like I've almost eliminated all like, you know, there were times when I would be snacking right?
Speaker 0: I switched from.
Speaker 0: you know I stopped eating yogurt with fruit on the bottom and started eating the fah-yay Greek yogurt with the fruit next to it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I went on to the ciggas and that's where it's the only yogurt.
Speaker 0: It's gross.
Speaker 1: It's so good.
Speaker 1: So good Try the cream ciggas.
Speaker 1: It's in the flat bit.
Speaker 1: Try it once.
Speaker 1: It's not what you think.
Speaker 0: No, it's no good.
Speaker 1: It's real good.
Speaker 0: Why would I do that?
Speaker 0: when I can stick with my fah-yay is okay.
Speaker 1: I mean, I only like the fah-yay with the honey though.
Speaker 0: Maybe all of them are good.
Speaker 0: There's so many flavors kiwis Pear berries so mangoes when I snack Cuz when I start.
Speaker 1: when I worked at IBM like way back in the day I snacked all the time for the vending machines because I was just always hungry.
Speaker 1: But now I work in a place that just has like free snacks all the time And it's funny because they definitely want you to like be healthy about it.
Speaker 1: So like most of the snacks are like bean crisp type things But they know there is garbage food if you want it, but it's like here's a tiny wrapper with one Oreo cookie in it.
Speaker 1: Mmm, no good, but they do have.
Speaker 1: there's this thing.
Speaker 1: There's this cart that comes out every day at like 2 30 and it's there until the end of the day And it's snack mix like the kind of snack mix I keep talking about like Chex Mix doodads type stuff and I've been eating that again cuz I still like that kind of food.
Speaker 0: the other snack the other snacks I still eat is like a fruit like I'll go to the Apple House buy a bunch of apples and eat one apple every day.
Speaker 0: or You know, I got like a bag of nuts.
Speaker 1: right I'll get like a bag of nuts, you know I don't eat fruit as snacks anymore But I eat fruit as a meal cuz I'll eat like a banana and like an orange as breakfast.
Speaker 0: Banana alone is not breakfast.
Speaker 0: I got to cut up that banana and put it in a Rice Krispie to make it break.
Speaker 1: So for most of my life, I just either didn't eat breakfast or I'd like especially in college Like I pretty much would eat a I a tree.
Speaker 0: This is the most best food.
Speaker 1: No I treated lunch like dinner and I'd eat a giant lunch and a small dinner and I'd skip breakfast for a long time.
Speaker 1: I only started eating breakfast again very recently.
Speaker 0: other snacks I eat are like these days is like I'll get a bowl put some salsa in it and get the chips and Just eat until I want to stop.
Speaker 0: but my pro technique is I put sour cream in that bowl of salsa.
Speaker 0: That's my pro technique.
Speaker 1: That's pretty good.
Speaker 1: So nowadays.
Speaker 1: Yeah, when I want to usually when I snack it's either I'm desperately hungry between geek nights and eating dinner.
Speaker 1: So I'll go eat like a handful of peanuts or something Like.
Speaker 1: I'll just go open the kid like whatever crackers are open.
Speaker 1: I'll just eat some of them.
Speaker 1: but when I actually snack now, there's the only kind of snacks I have that aren't like a random banana are?
Speaker 1: I'll get out like a small collection of cheeses and meats and cut like a small Charcuterie kind of plate and I'll eat that like some olives and some cheese and some crackers like.
Speaker 1: I'll prepare it Like it's a meal and then I'll eat it from a little plate.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean the thing is like, you know, I don't eat like Prepackaged snacks anymore.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there are times when like some snacks would get into my house I would buy them or whatever and then if I had a like a box of snack It sort of fell into two categories.
Speaker 0: right category one.
Speaker 0: I forgot about it and didn't eat it like.
Speaker 1: oh no What's this bag of tidbits?
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like.
Speaker 0: how did what's this in my cabinet?
Speaker 0: Oh my god.
Speaker 0: How old is this?
Speaker 0: Or the category of like I would buy a bag of golden Oreo and every day I would eat two or three golden Oreo.
Speaker 0: Usually is dessert though, but something sugary like that.
Speaker 0: But you know just like once a day eat one serving of the thing until it's gone.
Speaker 1: I guess what's interesting is that most of the sweet snacks that I ate through high school and Into college until I stopped and that I don't eat now Basically just garbage.
Speaker 1: Yep, like the good like their garbage to the point that I feel vaguely sick like zebra cakes Disgusting and yet I would eat two to five of them a day in high school.
Speaker 0: I mean that's really been the.
Speaker 0: you know The key is like I don't.
Speaker 0: I just don't.
Speaker 0: I eat the meals of the day and I don't eat a lot of other food.
Speaker 0: I haven't even bought fire yogurt and like many many moons mostly cuz it hasn't been on sale.
Speaker 0: They buy it was on sale.
Speaker 1: So I think part of that is that while I am still hyperactive like you bike a lot I ain't run all the time, but I'm not also growing like I was in high school
Speaker 0: obviously,
Speaker 1: but to a Lot of the garbage I ate was sort of like the cheap garbage and now that I have some money I just pretty much always eat really high quality food.
Speaker 1: and Once that happened, I find it very difficult to eat.
Speaker 1: like when I say the high quality versus low quality I don't mean like cheap food is not bad.
Speaker 1: There's really good cheap food but like Like the food you would buy in the grocery store For like kids to snack on like zebra cakes and things like that are just so disgusting to me that I cannot eat them anymore.
Speaker 0: It's like I just you know by if I have a food in the house in the apartment and it's noticeable It's not hiding somewhere like the back of the fridge and I see it.
Speaker 0: then I'll eat the one serving a day.
Speaker 0: So I just don't put that kind of food in the house, right?
Speaker 0: And it's.
Speaker 0: but you know, it helps a lot is actually the blue apron like food delivery?
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like if you don't go to the grocery store, you don't see those things.
Speaker 0: So you don't buy them So you don't need them.
Speaker 1: when I go grocery shopping It's not wander around the grocery store and grab all the shit I want.
Speaker 1: It's what do I need to cook the meals for the next few weeks?
Speaker 1: All right, I need.
Speaker 0: yeah I have a recipe and I get the ingredients for that recipe.
Speaker 0: I don't buy anything else in the grocery store.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't browse fresh right?
Speaker 1: I literally type like white onion because I need white onions and then I click buy then I type Dandelion.
Speaker 0: so these things aren't in my house They're not there.
Speaker 0: so I don't eat them even though I might and I might want to.
Speaker 1: it doesn't happen And that might be part of why we're not.
Speaker 0: that I don't know.
Speaker 0: But I've never been fat even when I was eating those new.
Speaker 0: even I was eating many ring things.
Speaker 0: That is one thing.
Speaker 1: cuz you ate that crap when you weren't that active like before you started biking a lot But I ate that crap and I was crazy active and neither like we didn't either one of us really gained.
Speaker 0: Anyway, DNA matters a lot.
Speaker 1: Yeah but Most the list of snacks that I ate as a kid That I find disgusting today is so expensive like Doritos Cheez-its.
Speaker 1: Well, I used to eat Cheetos.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't I never eat.
Speaker 1: Pour like a quarter of a bag of Cheetos into a bowl and eat them all while I play video games.
Speaker 0: See my whole life.
Speaker 0: I never ate anything with what I call flavor powder, right?
Speaker 1: I did.
Speaker 1: I love the shit out of Oreos in middle school Oreos Doritos in middle school, right?
Speaker 0: So for example, like when I was talking about getting a corn chip with salsa I get a corn chip that has nothing on it, but corn and salt pretty much.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if you go to the potato chip aisle, it's like I'll get regular potato chip.
Speaker 0: I'll get roughly potato chip.
Speaker 0: I'll get a darker russet potato chip.
Speaker 0: It's made with a or kettle chip.
Speaker 0: Those are all just fine.
Speaker 1: I'll go one step further and sometimes I'll get like vinegar and sea salt.
Speaker 1: No, that's okay.
Speaker 0: No, we'll not do that.
Speaker 0: No, I don't do any.
Speaker 0: as soon as it's like barbecue chip or The chips that have powder on them are disgusting right but this that's the.
Speaker 0: I don't get Vin.
Speaker 0: Nope I don't get any but flavored but not.
Speaker 1: it's not like it's synthetic vinegar.
Speaker 0: All Doritos are like these basically tasteless chips that are covered in like this powder of flavor and it's like.
Speaker 0: no I don't eat.
Speaker 0: I don't cheese balls.
Speaker 0: Nope.
Speaker 0: Don't eat cheese balls Combos those pretzels with the poison in the middle.
Speaker 1: So when I was So I would eat like I had the snacks I would eat.
Speaker 0: but most of the memory in those my whole life They're that I knew in middle school.
Speaker 1: in high school Like everyone else like one they get lunch from the school cafeteria, which I never did cuz that shit was disgusting.
Speaker 0: I would only Occasionally buy just a french fry in the school cafeteria if I had some money because they actually made a good fry.
Speaker 1: Like I got the burger for my high school once and I can't imagine eating that as a human be.
Speaker 0: Oh, no, I never ate the burger from the high school is disgusting but Everyone in my middle school in high school.
Speaker 1: They eat like combos and the slush puppies.
Speaker 1: yeah, and That shit always looked disgusting and felt disgusting and I remember the one time I put like a combo in my mouth and it Disgusting.
Speaker 0: no Whenever I brought my lunch, mostly my mom would make a lunch and put it in a baggie.
Speaker 1: Oh, there was a definite turning point in my life when my mom was like you can make your own lunch and for about four years I packed a Bag of garbage every day took it to school ate it all before first period And then went out to Arby's and bought lunch.
Speaker 0: I had to usually one or two sandwiches peanut butter and jelly or salami or whatever and then some snack action in there right and then at lunch I would open it and eat all of it and then I'd only get like a french fry if I Was still hungry.
Speaker 0: and then actually in high school.
Speaker 0: There was a there was a period.
Speaker 0: they had this little candy store That would open during lunch.
Speaker 1: Oh, we had one of those.
Speaker 1: the students ran it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, pretty much sort of I would go in there and I would buy something that was new at the time Which is mini M&Ms.
Speaker 0: It was this plastic tube Full of tiny tiny M&Ms and you'd open up the tube and just dump the whole tube of M&Ms in your mouth All at once like a shot.
Speaker 0: I Collected every single one of those tubes at a plastic bag full of tubes.
Speaker 0: I don't know if I still have it somewhere if I got thrown out But I had those tubes from all those mini M&Ms I ate.
Speaker 1: But yeah, I guess I don't know if it's just that our lifestyle changed or that we have money.
Speaker 1: But when I snack nowadays, I pretty much like I said, I only make like I cry making a snack for myself I treat it the same way as cooking a meal.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm If you're I'm just gonna say I'm not a doctor.
Speaker 0: do not take Scott's.
Speaker 0: non doctor non science.
Speaker 0: They say don't snack non science.
Speaker 1: diet advice because I've read science stuff that says if you just don't snack You are better off.
Speaker 0: If you are someone who's doing some weird fad diet nonsense, or you're thinking about it or whatever Try doing the diet of Scott, which is a eat when you're hungry.
Speaker 0: B. Don't eat when you're not hungry All the time.
Speaker 1: I mean you're just gonna have to suffer and I'm gonna admit I am literally hungry all the time.
Speaker 0: I'm hungry right now.
Speaker 0: I'm hungry right now, but I'm gonna go home and reheat my food and eat it.
Speaker 0: But yeah, just don't eat a snack or a dessert.
Speaker 0: only eat the three meals a day and that's it.
Speaker 0: They could be big meals, but just don't eat anything else.
Speaker 1: Well, don't eat bags of garbage.
Speaker 1: Yeah, don't eat feed bags.
Speaker 0: Don't need to don't eat too many ring things every day.
Speaker 1: But at the same time if doodads if I found a box of doodads that was somehow not expired I would probably eat them.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: But at the same time I I used to eat Nilla wafers.
Speaker 0: Those are good.
Speaker 1: Those are okay.
Speaker 0: I like Nilla wafer.
Speaker 0: The way to eat Nilla wafer is I put it in my mouth and suck on it a little bit.
Speaker 0: I would suck on it a whole bunch to drain it of all sugar and then eat it.
Speaker 1: I would do that with the Precursor to Cheez-Its.
Speaker 0: It's weird that like these foods have a particular way you to eat them.
Speaker 1: That's why I fell down the fucking stairs Broke my neck because I was working out the way to particularly eat the combination of different.
Speaker 0: the way I eat the fire Yogurt is like I don't.
Speaker 0: some people I guess flip over the fruit and squeeze it onto the right.
Speaker 0: No, I do is?
Speaker 0: I take I spoon some yogurt and then I spoon a tiny amount of fruit and I try to get Fruit into every single spoon and measure it exactly right.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: Yeah With the fruit on the bottom yogurt, I would just stir it up real good.
Speaker 1: When I make myself like a little charcuterie plate of some kind I will literally like pick a particular cracker and take like the piece of salami and one of the pimento olives and then I'll eat all of those together.
Speaker 1: and I like craft every one of the like Things that I put into my mouth one by one.
Speaker 0: if I spread the cheese onto the cracker with the red stick each cracker needs The perfect coating.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: No, I would put and then all the left all the leftover cheese I scoop with the red stick and put directly in my mouth.
Speaker 0: So I scooped out with my tongue and so there is until there is none left.
Speaker 1: I would throw the red stick away after I had spread the cheese.
Speaker 1: I would just lick the inside of that thing out.
Speaker 0: I would I do if I spread some.
Speaker 0: if I use a knife to like make a peanut butter the jelly sandwich I spread the peanut butter then I lick the knife clean then I spread the jelly then I lick the knife clean.
Speaker 0: You might say oh my god, you licked a knife.
Speaker 0: They went in the jelly.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I'm the only one eating that jelly.
Speaker 0: So whatever.
Speaker 0: No one else is eating my jelly.
Speaker 1: I would not do that Even if I was the only one.
Speaker 0: if I am sharing the peanut butter and jelly with other people I get my own plastic disposable knife to lick and don't use the knife everyone else is using.
Speaker 0: so I am respectful of other people's.
Speaker 0: You know not getting my spit in their jelly So interesting.
Speaker 1: when I think about it, I don't consider cook, but I like to like.
Speaker 0: I like to lick the knife.
Speaker 1: But I eat cookies like all the time cookies or snacks, but unless after dinner.
Speaker 0: that is dessert.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but I just eat cookies all the time.
Speaker 1: Like if there's cookies I eat them.
Speaker 0: Well, yeah, but the thing is if there's cookies I feel food aggressive.
Speaker 0: But the only time there are cookies is packs.
Speaker 0: If I buy a bag of cookies, which I haven't done in forever or if I bake cookies, right?
Speaker 0: There aren't cookies around that often.
Speaker 0: So when they are around I'll eat one or two or three or four.
Speaker 1: Well, you know what?
Speaker 0: The difference is when I heard snack period when I eat a bunch of cookies like the most cookies I'll eat like let's say there's a bucket of cookies.
Speaker 0: I'll eat one time between lunch and dinner three or four cookies And then if I am hungry after dinner for dessert three or four cookies And that is the most cookie.
Speaker 0: I will eat this maximum.
Speaker 1: But that is why like I eat a lot of cookies Compared to the amount of cookies I buy but I basically only buy or make like nice fancy cookies.
Speaker 1: I basically don't eat things like I don't know.
Speaker 0: you don't buy the goods every time I kind of mix it up.
Speaker 1: Those shortbread cookies for fresh direct are real real goddamn good.
Speaker 1: And as I've gotten older, I've come to particularly appreciate the simple the humble sugar cookie and the simple shortbread cookie.
Speaker 1: Those might be my favorite kinds of cookies.
Speaker 1: But when I think of snack, I pretty much always think of savory things vaguely in the realm of pretzels peanuts Chex mix type stuff Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: There is the magic mix which when I if I have a whole but usually I'll make the magic mix because I need it For some you know thing to take it somewhere like biking or whatever, but I treat that.
Speaker 1: I treat that like fuel.
Speaker 1: I don't think of it as a snack.
Speaker 1: I think of it as I am on a long run and I need to eat something halfway through it.
Speaker 0: But if I happen to have a I make them the magic mix in a like a gallon ziplock bag.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so there's a ton of it when I make it and if I have it in the fridge and I'm hungry between meals I'll go in there take the whole bag out and just eat a few fistfuls of it till I don't want anymore.
Speaker 1: So I realized the thing I was talking about where as a kid I would be very weirdly particular about how I combine my snacks.
Speaker 1: I realized I do still do that because When I went when I do the like standing in the kitchen I needed II.
Speaker 1: I need to eat a handful of something because it's gonna take me a while to cook dinner.
Speaker 1: my go-to is to eat like Some croutons and then some peanuts and stop eating the croutons.
Speaker 0: So croutons are for salad only.
Speaker 1: I Actually will put.
Speaker 1: I'll bite into the croutons first and then I'll put some peanuts in my mouth and then I'll chew them up together.
Speaker 0: What the hell?
Speaker 1: That is a better experience than the croutons.
Speaker 0: peanut and crouton do not go together.
Speaker 1: I think if pop culture had put croutons in checks mix tile style snack mixes you would have no problem with this.
Speaker 0: No, I would have a huge problem with that.
Speaker 1: But do you have a problem with snack mixes?
Speaker 1: the ones that are like peanut checks pretzel stick cheese thing maybe a raisin cheese cheese stick Like a tidbit What you don't remember.
Speaker 1: what's in like checks mix do ya?
Speaker 1: This checks like this kind of raisin.
Speaker 0: I know you hate raisin.
Speaker 1: I do not hate raisin.
Speaker 0: I thought you hated raisin.
Speaker 1: I like raisins fine.
Speaker 0: Pretty sure you change your mind on raisin.
Speaker 1: I'm not a fan of eating a fistful of raisins by themselves, but I like raisins like in certain other things.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm golden raisins in.
Speaker 0: that reminds me.
Speaker 0: I got grapes in the fridge.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna eat tonight.
Speaker 1: Oh, I got some blueberries, but they're kind of sour.
Speaker 0: No my grapes are good blueberries not great that I'm gonna go to the grocery store.
Speaker 0: if you see some grapes eat one grape to See how any good and if they're good then buy bad grapes.
Speaker 1: when I was a little kid I would occasionally peel my grapes and then eat them.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I peel.
Speaker 0: Oh if I eat a grape I would peel it and eat the skin and then I would peel it in my mouth.
Speaker 0: until so then in my mouth is a peeled Grape, I'd eat the skin and but all in my mouth.
Speaker 1: I wouldn't know if I peeled grapes.
Speaker 1: I ate the skin.
Speaker 1: I'm not.
Speaker 1: so I'm not like.
Speaker 1: not like the person who cuts the Whole grape in my mouth.
Speaker 0: eat the skin in my mouth and then eat the grape in my mouth.
Speaker 1: I have done that.
Speaker 1: That's a good feeling anyway.
Speaker 1: Snacks your favorite snacks.
Speaker 1: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Speaker 0: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 1: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 0: But unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night And the patreon patrons for this episode of geek nights are Alan Joyce, Heidi McNichol Amanda Duchette a shimmering ruby obelisk hanging in the sky.
Speaker 1: mystady.com.
Speaker 1: Jeremy minor genuine bonafide electrified six car monorail Sean Yeager Matthew Smith Nicholas Brando captain Chico Ocassie Rebecca Dunn for two one creations.
Speaker 1: No, I never ever wonder why we're here.
Speaker 1: It's number five bitch Shervin von Harl rare Laval James David White Rochelle, Monta, Nona superboy.
Speaker 1: rim says something funny here.
Speaker 1: sailor Vista Don Schlegs You're tops and Joe Joe.
Speaker 1: Joe starts Sam Cordray Clinton Walton Ren from New Zealand Ryan parent drew open lander Brian Cedroni Finn Chris midkiff Chris Knox Daniel Redmond Sean Klein Chris Reimer and Thomas Hahn.
Speaker 1: Uh Yeah, like I said, we got a lot of conventions coming up.
Speaker 1: There's a lot of biz coming in the future and Now I leave you with Ol' Gil.
Speaker 1: Ol' Gil's gonna eat some food tonight.
Speaker 0: Oh, this is bad.
Speaker 0: This is really bad.
Speaker 1: You're working your slave and you steal just enough for a sweet lick of that shiny brass ring.
Speaker 1: Don't I get a lick?
Speaker 1: doesn't Gil get a lick?
Speaker 1: She's a beaut.
Speaker 1: You can't beat a calico.
Speaker 1: Hey, how many can I put you down for a lot?
Speaker 1: Please say a lot.
Speaker 1: I need this.
Speaker 1: Ah Would you mind lacing him up kid?
Speaker 1: I have a bad back.
Speaker 1: Hey, if you didn't want to tie shoes, you shouldn't have become a shoe salesman.
Speaker 1: Yeah Clean up in aisle three.
Speaker 1: Oh Finally Gil's moving up to the big leagues boy.
Speaker 1: Oh Yeah my back.
Speaker 1: Oh Lord my hot plate.
Speaker 1: I only had two payments left.