Speaker 0: It's Tuesday, December 5th, 2017.
Speaker 0: I'm rim.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott and this is geek nights tonight 1846 the race for the Midwest.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: So, uh, yeah, we're back.
Speaker 0: We actually had some fun times just now.
Speaker 0: so I got a brand new opening bit basically in the last episode of geek nights.
Speaker 0: anyone who's watching the live stream might have noticed that After like three chords the show Scott just got really quiet for a while and then he got loud again.
Speaker 1: So how come you can't just set up the audio equipment perfectly one time and leave it that way forever?
Speaker 1: Why are you gonna mess with it?
Speaker 0: So I didn't mess with it.
Speaker 0: It has been the same for years Uh-huh.
Speaker 0: I had not touched it at all.
Speaker 0: Uh-huh.
Speaker 0: And then after you left I was like, huh, that's weird.
Speaker 0: So I corrected it for that because the raw audio goes into like the computer and what's going out to the live stream is actually Something.
Speaker 0: it's like a different pipeline.
Speaker 0: So they're independent of one another.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: So basically Previously the last time that this happened I identified an XLR cable that was legit bad and I threw it away and I replaced it with a new XLR cable.
Speaker 0: It seems like the port Scott was plugged into is also having a problem Mm-hmm as Scott saw me test and go hey something's wrong here.
Speaker 1: But you plugged your microphone in port 2 and it looked like it was working.
Speaker 0: it was but what you didn't hear because I got these headphones on is There was a really weird crackling sound and I would cut out and get quiet.
Speaker 0: I thought you the crackling was in the compressor area that it was in that compressor pipeline because that's a different pipeline.
Speaker 0: So when I monitored that that crackle went away when I removed this port from the equation.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: So the plot thickens, but I don't want to replace this mixer because I really like this mixer.
Speaker 0: So I'm gonna have to investigate that port.
Speaker 1: get your rice krispies outta here.
Speaker 0: The thing is remember this mixer is The firewire only one.
Speaker 0: so I kind of want to go USB.
Speaker 1: no, it's your money's.
Speaker 0: well The thing is I don't want to replace this mixer unless it's dead.
Speaker 0: Uh-huh.
Speaker 0: So I got four ports.
Speaker 1: rim loves.
Speaker 1: This is a another situation.
Speaker 1: room is gonna break something on purpose.
Speaker 0: to feel not bad about buying a new thing I do not want to buy a new mixer.
Speaker 0: This mix is great.
Speaker 0: And actually as far as I can tell all the good mixers are also firewire.
Speaker 0: So I can't even achieve what I wanted.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: So we'll see that's neither here nor there.
Speaker 0: We'll talk about that more on Monday when I'll figure out.
Speaker 0: we'll do a Monday show on QA.
Speaker 0: We'll talk about the mark 14 torpedo.
Speaker 1: So this is just some tiny gaming news is going down right.
Speaker 1: on Thursday the hearthstone expansion comes out and it's gonna have.
Speaker 1: You know, I'm not gonna encourage people to go spend their money on digital cards.
Speaker 1: You're better off spending your money on real cards first, right if you're gonna do collectible cards Magic cards, they're adding a single-player Free-to-play mode that is actually has significant play and replay value So and you don't have to pay a single dime for that.
Speaker 1: So why not check it out?
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, if you play hearthstone, I uh Play hearthstone.
Speaker 1: It's like you could.
Speaker 1: just it has this freeze.
Speaker 1: They're gonna add a free single-player mode that is worth playing and worth, you know, like into play until you get bored of it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I guess I kind of avoided Going down the road of hearthstone because between that and overwatch I can really only have one game that I play every day.
Speaker 1: Oh, I mean you only.
Speaker 1: I only played every day for like 30 minutes less.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I play overwatch every day for like an hour pretty much.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Anyway, I'm still only like gold here.
Speaker 1: So speaking of overwatch your you know We've been waiting for them to actually have this league with teams that are actually located in cities.
Speaker 1: So we can have our New York eSports team for finally And I guess tomorrow the jerseys go on sale, so we'll see if they're ugly or not.
Speaker 1: I imagine they will be.
Speaker 0: it better say New York something's.
Speaker 1: yeah, but you know Maybe it'll be good enough to buy but I doubt it.
Speaker 1: But if it is I will but probably won't.
Speaker 0: I do Appreciate the fact that the teams have in-game jerseys for all the characters - I think you got to pay for those.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah you but if you're.
Speaker 0: but if you're the team you wear your jersey in the game.
Speaker 1: Yeah, wouldn't that be weird if you were playing like hockey online and you couldn't wear Rangers Jersey hundred?
Speaker 0: or you're watching a real NHL game back in the future when the NHL is replaced by nothing but eSports and like the equivalent of grab nurse Zuccarello is Wearing like a dragon mask and boffer shoes and carrying a broom instead of a hockey stick.
Speaker 1: Yeah, let's not go to that world.
Speaker 0: There is actually some pretty big news and we're not gonna be able to talk about the full extent of what this means But it's something I want to bring up today.
Speaker 1: Yeah, this was this was so awesome when I saw it and I was like, whoa What have I been missing out on?
Speaker 0: I'm gonna read the headline on Ars Technica because you get literally summarized as my full sentiment.
Speaker 0: Yeah formula one eSports now more exciting than the real thing and that's a problem.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so there's always been this formula one racing games even back going back like the Gameboy, but this There's an official f1 game that like is licensed and has all the actual drivers and cars in it.
Speaker 1: That's been coming up for quite a few years and I never bought it because every year it would come out and I say Ooh, that looks really cool.
Speaker 1: But how much am I actually gonna play it?
Speaker 1: Yeah, and it's a real expensive.
Speaker 0: and also I've played realistic driving simulators before.
Speaker 0: I suck ass at the very simulator of how many ways Rim can die, right?
Speaker 1: It's definitely a sim like.
Speaker 1: it tries to be super accurate to the real world like you could practice driving with it right if you get a wheel in pedals and Then it would get cheap and I'd be like, ooh, and then the new one would come out like wow I don't want to buy the old one.
Speaker 1: Oh, it's only worth it to get the new one, but no one's expenses.
Speaker 1: I never played it, but apparently it's actually an eSport like playing this game and Because it doesn't have any even though it's modeled on the real world formula one It's not constrained by real the real world.
Speaker 1: in the same way It's still a simulation and I'm not sure exactly how which parts are accurate and which parts aren't.
Speaker 1: but like they had to go in They were playing with realistic damage on.
Speaker 1: I noticed that part.
Speaker 1: Yeah But I don't know if like are the cars actually faster than is like hurt you to get in one car.
Speaker 1: That's faster?
Speaker 1: Well, here's here's one.
Speaker 0: Here's a very interesting example of where this could go.
Speaker 0: So One of the most exciting things about Formula One would be the ridiculously dangerous nonsense that they ban because it's too dangerous people to drive Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: with an eSport of Formula One you could bring back ground effect.
Speaker 1: There's no reason to not.
Speaker 1: the thing is if you're gonna have an eSport that's a racing game straight up You might as well just have f-zero.
Speaker 1: Why have I have f1?
Speaker 0: Well, so that the here's the interesting like overlap between just go to f-zero.
Speaker 0: Right now f1 as a real physical sport has a lot of like cultural cachet.
Speaker 0: Yeah There's a lot of reasons to be excited about it and to be able to be follow and be interested in it but as a pure spectator The graphics and the way it plays out if you watch someone playing the eSport version It could be an identical experience.
Speaker 1: Yeah, watching the eSport f1 was not very different than watching the real one except obviously you can tell it's not the real world Even though it still looks incredible, but it looks pretty close.
Speaker 0: Like if you had not a great TV, they look the same.
Speaker 1: Yes, also, uh, you know, no fuel is being consumed.
Speaker 1: There's no environmental damage Okay But it's just a lot shorter.
Speaker 1: They don't run like a you know, 30 whatever 60 laughs.
Speaker 1: however many laps it is Right.
Speaker 1: It was really quick.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but it was also a lot more exciting and part of that It was definitely one of the most exciting f1 races I've seen recently.
Speaker 0: the people racing can take The risks that a human might not take in a real race.
Speaker 0: They could also have a lot more races because you don't need all this physical infrastructure to make them happen.
Speaker 0: It's a lot more accessible.
Speaker 0: you can you can do a lot of stuff to make it interesting.
Speaker 0: and the problem part is that For the average consumer like someone who wants to watch f1, but isn't like a hyper purist It's a better experience than literally every way Most people cannot go see f1.
Speaker 0: The fact that I have seen f1 races in person is a position of privilege and even then I only saw them because someone else Paid for it.
Speaker 1: It's also because it's shorter.
Speaker 1: It's a lot less time-consuming.
Speaker 1: Yeah The length of that race is the amount is like.
Speaker 1: I do like f1 But I don't like it enough to wake up early on every Sunday morning and watch a race for hours But I like it enough to watch one of these maybe once a week once a month for 15 20 minutes.
Speaker 0: if this continues eSports of Physical car racing that are close enough for the layman are gonna be the kind of thing I would watch.
Speaker 1: I mean, I'm gonna go look for like competitive for the Gran Turismo and you know, see what's up with that.
Speaker 1: Right, there must be a scene and it's like.
Speaker 1: that's a scene I could spectate and be into if it's good.
Speaker 1: But really let's just fast forward and get to f0 already.
Speaker 0: Yeah, what's the problem?
Speaker 1: What's holding you up?
Speaker 1: Make an f0 that controls realistically and is very difficult so that it can become an e-sport But still have loop-de-loops and jumps and ridiculous cars because hey There's no constraints of the real world in there.
Speaker 1: make it go like 10,000 miles an hour.
Speaker 0: who gives it stunts 4d.
Speaker 0: That's where we'll get down the road.
Speaker 0: Whatever Down the road.
Speaker 0: All right, so it'll be a race between this and the other crazy side of that Which is the drone racing of robot cars in the real world controlled by people who are not in them.
Speaker 1: Well, let's just fast forward again and have robot AI's controlling e-sport cars But the the the driving point so it becomes a pretty good addition.
Speaker 1: Yeah the dry
Speaker 0: the driving point of all this the thing that you really need to think about let's simmer in your head for like when we talk About this in more depth in the future Is that the only thing that matters for the like future of a sport is the spectator?
Speaker 0: Experience.
Speaker 0: is it exciting?
Speaker 0: Is it accessible?
Speaker 0: And eSports are already on track to be better than most real sports at both of those things.
Speaker 0: Mmm, that is that is the important part This news is is a very important thing that not a lot of people are talking about The direct competition between traditional sports and eSports and how eSports are well positioned to destroy the former Mm-hmm, and if you think that isn't true as we like to say boxing used to be literally the most popular sport on earth.
Speaker 0: Where is it now going?
Speaker 0: occasionally on a hockey field Occasionally on the ice Sure, so you got some other news.
Speaker 1: Yeah So it also sports news.
Speaker 1: everybody knows that in previous Olympic and other international sporting competitions Russia do some big-time cheating action.
Speaker 0: and this isn't just like an individual player cheating.
Speaker 0: This is like a speculation like oh that country is cheating.
Speaker 1: This was organized like organized across-the-board cheating like almost every Russian athlete was probably Government-assisted big-time doping organized by their you know whatnot, right?
Speaker 1: It was like, you know an epidemic not like oh one individual from your country on their own cheated.
Speaker 1: It's like.
Speaker 1: no the whole country's sporting organization got together to have a system of cheating in place.
Speaker 1: right and they were caught.
Speaker 1: they were caught so red-handed and now you know the Winter Olympics are coming up real soon in South Korea and The big news is that Russia is getting penalized and they're getting penalized for this cheating.
Speaker 1: a punishment likes the wit and this might be the greatest punishment to a sporting organization in the history of Sports like within the context of sport.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean it's like it might be like I guess before that maybe Lance Armstrong has always you know the Tour de France is taken away.
Speaker 1: This might be a bigger punishment than that.
Speaker 1: So what they're doing is all Russian Russia cannot participate in the Olympics period.
Speaker 1: no Russian flags No Russian anthems.
Speaker 1: No Russian nothing.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: They're basically banned.
Speaker 1: However, if any athletes from Russia right want to go they can go but of course they have to be Extra-doubly triply quadruply thoroughly vetted to make sure they aren't cheating.
Speaker 1: Yep, and if they do participate They're gonna have to wear like boring generic Olympic things.
Speaker 0: they wear the dunce uniform.
Speaker 1: They cannot use the Russian flag right like a white like a blank white uniform with Olympic rings on it.
Speaker 0: They don't even get their own national anthem.
Speaker 1: No, they get the Olympic anthem, you know That one?
Speaker 1: yeah, right they don't get nothing.
Speaker 1: nothing.
Speaker 1: Russian can be at the Olympics in South Korea Which is really close to Russia geographically.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: This article says the best.
Speaker 0: the IOC after completing their investigation blah blah blah Handed Russia penal is for doping so severe.
Speaker 0: They were without precedent?
Speaker 1: No, definitely.
Speaker 1: I said with that they've never seen penalties this severe for anyone ever.
Speaker 0: This is exactly this is the kind of penalty that I want to see in eSports - yeah, well, yeah Yeah, I want to see.
Speaker 1: you know, if you cheat if you do something wrong if you're harassing people in a game Why shouldn't the penalties be incredibly severe now?
Speaker 0: This is breaking news.
Speaker 1: We're not talking about like, you know, I'm not someone who's in favor of death penalties or lifetime prison sentences But these are penalties which like they're within the context of a game You can make them as severe as you want and they actually do work as a deterrent because it's within the context of a game.
Speaker 1: So why not make them ridiculously severe?
Speaker 0: but as this is breaking news today?
Speaker 0: We don't know yet how Russia has responded or will respond, right?
Speaker 0: Well, they didn't let their athletes attend, right?
Speaker 1: Is there a boycott?
Speaker 0: the Olympics?
Speaker 1: is there gonna be a hockey team?
Speaker 1: That is like the Janeiro Olympic hockey team because the NHL is not going to the Olympics So it's gonna be all junior teams and supposedly KHL people would have gone and dominated.
Speaker 1: Are they gonna go?
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm, right, so It'll still be great to watch some hockey's though with some swamis and some three gays and some but the two Some Canada's will especially the hockey is some check.
Speaker 0: do the hockey kids care so much about hockey that they'll go play just to play even if they don't even get to play under their own flag?
Speaker 0: and Secondarily will the Russian government even let them do that?
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm, cuz I Especially because there's more to this I think you also need to be invited and you got to pass through the muster that you know.
Speaker 1: If you're from Russia, you're gonna have to pass a lot more qualifications and such than anyone from any other country.
Speaker 1: There is even more they'll check your PP every two hours.
Speaker 0: So the investigation cost the IOC over 15 million dollars.
Speaker 0: Russia has to pay all that money before Anyone before they can even have the option of competing not under their own flag.
Speaker 0: So I Suspect that Russia is going to tell them to eat a dick and this is gonna be a really interesting geopolitical situation Which is extra.
Speaker 0: It's not really a Tuesday show topic, but considering the current Shall we say troubles between the United States and Russia?
Speaker 0: The fact that Russia might end up boycotting current troubles You mean they be almost 50 60 year long 70 year long troubles I guess the re-emergence into the public sphere since the mid 40s troubles the Russia literally Troubles.
Speaker 0: as old as Stalin swung the American election the wrong way.
Speaker 1: that are the same troubles.
Speaker 0: So I guess I'm gonna get to live through a cold war where Russia boycotts the Olympics already lived through cold war.
Speaker 1: We've been living it all lives.
Speaker 1: They were born in it and it hasn't ended.
Speaker 0: take to boogaloo.
Speaker 1: Cool facts.
Speaker 1: Ovechkin if he wants to almost definitely won't can go compete for Schweiss.
Speaker 1: if he wants to oh, yeah That'd be interesting.
Speaker 1: It won't happen.
Speaker 1: I do.
Speaker 1: well, they'll probably just stay and compete for das Kapital.
Speaker 1: I feel like Especially like you what I did there.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I see what you did there.
Speaker 0: I feel like if there are any Russian athletes who could compete under another flag, that would be tantamount to suicide to do so.
Speaker 0: Political also.
Speaker 1: Ovechkin is like super pro-putin.
Speaker 1: He's like Putin's biggest fan.
Speaker 0: Well, I either he's pro-putin or it is not safe for him to not be pro-putin.
Speaker 1: I mean he could just stay in the u.s.
Speaker 1: Isn't the go-dealing.
Speaker 0: Yeah staying in the u.s.
Speaker 0: Man always been safe.
Speaker 1: many other Russian athletes in the NHL are not pro-putin.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but it's a.
Speaker 1: It's a complex situation and also he goes out of his way to be extra pro-putin Just quietly not being anti-feud.
Speaker 0: There's a fun little bit at the end of this article - this might be even more interesting down the road.
Speaker 0: Quote Tuesday's decision could have consequences for another major sporting event scheduled be held in Russia next year's 11 billion dollar soccer World Cup.
Speaker 0: I like how the article has to specify that the World Cup is soccer.
Speaker 1: I mean, I don't think it's an issue because even if the Russians cheat they're not winning the World Cup.
Speaker 1: No, no, no, but they have to.
Speaker 1: they have to bribe the refs or something because their reps really control soccer.
Speaker 0: It'd be interesting if the World Cup follows suit and maybe that event moves or changes.
Speaker 1: Well has the as Russian soccer been cheating as much as Russian Olympics are cheating.
Speaker 0: I don't know different organization, right?
Speaker 1: You know like you know what not yeah, and I don't know.
Speaker 0: so it'll be interesting to see how this all shakes down because this Is Britain even qualify for the World Cup?
Speaker 0: Well, it's breaking news and it's night in Russia So I don't think there's even gonna be any response until tomorrow.
Speaker 1: No, it's gonna be morning there soon.
Speaker 0: Yeah We'll see how this goes.
Speaker 0: so anyway things of the day.
Speaker 0: So I was at the scojo Laura house party that Scott skipped and I played a lot of st Petersburg there.
Speaker 0: But the night before we were doing the thing that members of the front row crew do when it's late at night We're hanging out at someone's house.
Speaker 0: We were looking at random YouTube videos Yeah random YouTube videos and we kept seeing this one video recommended and It was like it looked like this guy who had made a lot of chicken fingers.
Speaker 0: We don't really think much about it But eventually we clicked on it and the video was from this channel called grandpa kitchen Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: The channel has a lot of videos and some of the other videos involve such things as good at cooking.
Speaker 0: making a 1,000 egg curry.
Speaker 1: whoa Followed immediately never made curry with any egg.
Speaker 0: the next video was a recipe that involved him using 2,000 eggs.
Speaker 1: All right Every recipe is 1,000 eggs more than the last one.
Speaker 0: So I'm not gonna.
Speaker 0: basically one of them was he just makes pancakes.
Speaker 0: Holy shit.
Speaker 0: Where those pancakes?
Speaker 0: those look so good.
Speaker 0: The problem was we started watching this video.
Speaker 1: How could I go if he's making something with that many eggs?
Speaker 1: It's got to be enough food to go around.
Speaker 1: Can I go eat with grandpa?
Speaker 0: Ah, so these videos are long and we watch many.
Speaker 0: we stayed up way late watching these videos to their conclusion.
Speaker 0: And I'm gonna warn you right now if you watch this video You're going to be desperate to eat the thing that he made and it's gonna be a problem for you.
Speaker 0: and we were in, Pennsylvania.
Speaker 0: So there was no way for us to in fact get chicken fingers or pancakes at 3 in the morning.
Speaker 1: No, I can do that.
Speaker 1: I can do that right now.
Speaker 0: So you realize the next morning we all got up early and went to a diner to eat pancakes because otherwise we couldn't made it.
Speaker 0: No, so this video I'm gonna link to is the chicken fingers one.
Speaker 0: these look like the best chicken fingers anyone's ever made on earth and Grandpa is in India and he cooks these giant meals for orphans.
Speaker 0: Oh That's why he's got a thousand eggs and the videos are just very long procedural videos of him cooking in the woods with very simple tools Amazing recipes in quantity and the first half of every video.
Speaker 1: Why don't we make grandpa's chicken fingers?
Speaker 0: I want to make grandpa's chicken fingers.
Speaker 0: In fact, I plan to make grandpa's chicken fingers.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they look pretty straightforward.
Speaker 0: They look so good.
Speaker 0: So you watch it make these crazy recipes and then the end of every video is all the orphans Eating the food and it looks fantastic.
Speaker 0: This channel is just amazing to watch when you want something kind of chill and low-key.
Speaker 0: It's it's why I think it's just my top ten of favorite things that I've ever found.
Speaker 1: that reminds me.
Speaker 1: There's a. there's a I think I've told you before but I don't know the listeners know.
Speaker 1: there's a Korean cooking show I watch occasionally called please take care of my Refrigerator and I don't want it.
Speaker 1: to explain the entire concept of the show would take a while but basically celebrities bring their actual Refrigerators to the show and a bunch of chefs compete to see which food they can make from the celebrities fridge Right and which and the celebrity decides which one they like most.
Speaker 0: it's always celebrity shows up.
Speaker 0: There's just beer and like.
Speaker 1: Sometimes there is but basically it's an excuse to for the celebrity to promote their stuff whatever they're up to.
Speaker 1: Right for that for you to see some cool cooking and also to enjoy a lot of banter between the chefs and the celebrities.
Speaker 1: Right, but usually the episodes are split over two weeks.
Speaker 1: They'll have like one recording session with two celebrities.
Speaker 1: It's one celebrities meals get cooked the first episode and then the week later you see the other celebrity right getting cooked for right?
Speaker 1: But this week and next week or truly special The it was the first time I've seen a chef not from Korea on the show.
Speaker 1: the famous Most maybe most famous chef on earth the Gordon Ramsay appeared on this show.
Speaker 0: Ha I should watch that one episode.
Speaker 1: He's gonna cook next week.
Speaker 1: He's got 15 minutes to cook something from a celebrity Korean celebrities fridge.
Speaker 0: whose fridge is it?
Speaker 1: I don't know who is it is.
Speaker 1: I didn't watch.
Speaker 1: Okay, but I just I'm gonna watch.
Speaker 1: so oh man.
Speaker 0: So the only other thing about this videos is want to point out that's cool.
Speaker 0: Is that he makes these giant recipes with a very simple and limited set of tools?
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm, and that is part of why it's so fascinating to watch the entire thing.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so my actual thing of the day.
Speaker 1: another excellent Craftsman, I guess you could say artisan artisan here is a man who is I guess his job is exterminator and He is called in for this hornet's nest in someone's shed and the hornet's nest is like engulfed.
Speaker 1: You know many things in the shed like this is some Right here.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's a huge ass hornet's nest and he removes it with the greatest of ease without getting stung even once.
Speaker 0: Well, he's basically wearing like armor.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but you got to check out this hornet's nest.
Speaker 1: Yeah, he's got basically got a GoPro with him I assume as a GoPro while he's a De-nesting the shed.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna say if one how did these people let their shed get to this state?
Speaker 1: I don't know, but it's also kind of awesome because when he rips the hive out of there You can see all the queens at the bottom and stuff and it's like oh man.
Speaker 1: But if I were them, it's like a whole bunch of queens.
Speaker 0: I would just burn the shed down and start over.
Speaker 1: Well, but this guy got their stuff in there.
Speaker 0: Yeah a bunch of garbage.
Speaker 1: basketball their lawnmower.
Speaker 0: They got this faded-ass basketball.
Speaker 0: They got this pile of what looks like all their garden tools, you know Just it's a shed filled with mostly garbage.
Speaker 0: and look look at the super soaker.
Speaker 0: That looks like a vintage super soaker.
Speaker 1: Oh, man, I want it.
Speaker 0: I don't think I think it's off-brand actually.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's.
Speaker 1: the colors are backwards.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's not a super circuit 50.
Speaker 1: Anyway, this is the video still awesome.
Speaker 0: So in the meta moment, it is the calm before the storm.
Speaker 0: We are home Just you know making geek night stuff, but coming up real soon is both mag fest and packs.
Speaker 0: a pack south Mm-hmm not packs unplugged.
Speaker 0: We're just at packs unplugged.
Speaker 0: also New Year's and Holidays, there's gonna be a lot of biz in January.
Speaker 0: So if you are at pack south one, it's a full-on packs and it's one of our favorite paxes.
Speaker 0: It's more fun than packs East.
Speaker 0: I'm just gonna say it.
Speaker 0: I'm sorry pecs East is true And we're gonna be there on Friday for that's just like saying well Platinum's worth more than gold.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I ain't scoffing at gold I just I like platinum more.
Speaker 0: Yeah Got some electrum.
Speaker 0: That's that's packs.
Speaker 0: So pack sauce is the electrum.
Speaker 0: So we're gonna be there at 4 p.m.
Speaker 0: Doing a brand new panel a Scott panel balance in game design.
Speaker 0: It's looking pretty good like 30% done.
Speaker 0: Yep At mag fast, we're gonna be doing a bunch of panels.
Speaker 0: We're doing probably three with the mages one of which is a different version of this balance panel where we might have dr Pat hazard honors someone of his caliber with us.
Speaker 1: What else do I have to do there?
Speaker 1: What else is gonna pull me away from my dig dug machine?
Speaker 0: I forget what panels I put in.
Speaker 0: I gotta go I'm also.
Speaker 0: I put in a brand new one.
Speaker 0: Not a mages panel, but a regular panel.
Speaker 1: Top 40 tabletop games you should play and you're gonna come up with this list on your own.
Speaker 1: I already started writing it because I saw make a Google Doc so I can edit your incorrect list.
Speaker 0: Ah, so I saw someone else do a similar talk about games as a whole and the angle wasn't the best.
Speaker 0: 40.
Speaker 0: The angle is also not the most important.
Speaker 1: Cover all the bases.
Speaker 0: 40 it's.
Speaker 0: if you've played these 40 tabletop games You will be a player of games and have gnosis about tabletop gaming.
Speaker 1: That's right.
Speaker 1: so if there's even a game like pandemic will make that list and you basically you look at a category.
Speaker 1: you look at every Category of games right the 40 most important types of game and you pick the iconic game from each of those guys Not the first one not the best one.
Speaker 0: I don't illustrate.
Speaker 1: I don't like co-op solitaire pretend garbo garbo games But you must play one of them to understand them and pandemic is the one Yep, and you have to play Hanabi to understand why that was a garbo Yep.
Speaker 0: and if basically I want to try this panel out at magfest and then we'll probably tweak the list and I think we're gonna do It at paxies like legit.
Speaker 0: That's my plan.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's a cool one and I'm doing Magfest has a Saturday morning cartoons panel block where they do a bunch of this fun Saturday morning cartoon type stuff.
Speaker 0: So I'm gonna do the anime openers thing at 8 a.m.
Speaker 0: On Saturday.
Speaker 0: Cuz.
Speaker 0: apparently there's a big crowd of people.
Speaker 1: look at the free badge.
Speaker 1: cuz I'm paying for one.
Speaker 1: Yeah And I didn't pay for one.
Speaker 1: It would be sad if I showed up and couldn't get in I would make.
Speaker 0: this is one of the rare cons I would pay to go to if I were not a guest.
Speaker 1: I might but I just want to make sure I'm doing My.
Speaker 0: are you kidding?
Speaker 0: You would skip magfest for the like.
Speaker 0: how much does the badge even cost?
Speaker 0: 50 bucks?
Speaker 1: I don't know, but I'm just saying I also know for the free badge, right?
Speaker 1: Cuz I don't have to fill any other forms or anything.
Speaker 0: I don't believe so.
Speaker 0: We should just be some follow-up link or something should be fine.
Speaker 0: I just want to confirm it because times getting the consternation right now is making sure all the panelists have hotel rooms We don't need to worry about because we just get our own.
Speaker 0: That's right I don't get.
Speaker 0: I don't try to get into like the weird hotel room.
Speaker 0: We don't got our thing Nope, so yeah, we will be at packs on pec south now pecs unplugged.
Speaker 0: We were there and mag fest and pax East is like not too long after that.
Speaker 0: We will be there two months.
Speaker 0: so if you had to Describe a game that most people would assume that rim and scott would have no interest in 1846 should be near the top of that list.
Speaker 1: No, I mean, it's not a game We have no interest in.
Speaker 1: it's one of those like stereotypical games.
Speaker 1: We sort of always jokingly referred to right?
Speaker 1: It's like we laugh about like aha train game that uses crayons or grog nard war game or train game Where you only take four turns?
Speaker 1: Yeah, this is this is a you know It's stereotypical grog nard train game that we sort of you know The kind that you see in the game store and you look at and you go I know that kind of game and then you don't ever play it.
Speaker 0: You very rarely see people playing these kinds of games and when you do they tend to fit certain stereotypes.
Speaker 0: Yes games tend to take a very long time.
Speaker 0: The games tend to be more Simulatory than the sort of elegant machine building type games.
Speaker 0: We tend to prefer They tend to be more experiences where you explore a set of complex mechanics Rather than a game where you read the rules and already have a pretty good heuristic about what to do.
Speaker 1: They also Accurately represent true historical events at least related to trains in this case so that you can you know learn.
Speaker 1: So someone who's a nerd about old trains would like get jollies playing this game right regardless of the winning and losing factor.
Speaker 0: now What's funny is that even games like not age of steam but railroad tycoon like the baby version That game all the cars.
Speaker 0: when you buy trains they have that numerical like 422 like this is a 422 train and because of that I actually know what that means.
Speaker 1: I don't know what that means.
Speaker 0: It's those guide wheels versus drive wheels versus those trailing wheels.
Speaker 0: how many of each there are?
Speaker 1: Okay, and I mean only on the locomotive.
Speaker 1: that all the cars but yeah the locomotive itself.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but 1846 has that amped up to 11.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: So this game was presented.
Speaker 0: basically our friends Chris and Anthony like this game.
Speaker 1: They played it and well, there's a whole series of 18xx games that are all train games from different Geographies and areas.
Speaker 1: like is mostly in the u.s.
Speaker 1: But I assume they've also got euro rails and stuff like that.
Speaker 1: but you know that are you know, so this one is about the Midwest and of course the year 1846 like what was happening with train companies there and then yep And apparently the.
Speaker 0: I have not looked at these other games, but I've learned a little bit about them.
Speaker 0: all the other 18 Dot-dot games are very similar but have like soul crushingly Esoteric differences or like very specific nuances that make them completely different game, right?
Speaker 1: So it's like you could learn one and then easily learn to play another one in a short amount of time Once you've learned one, but there will be significant differences.
Speaker 1: You'll probably not win because you like you'll mess those up right because.
Speaker 1: but I guess if you're super studied on train history Maybe you'll just anticipate those differences because they match real-world event.
Speaker 0: Yeah like you might know about One of the like small railroads like it like the Erie line or something and what happened to it.
Speaker 1: and then you when you see What happens to in the game like oh it makes perfect sense Cuz actually there is this this line that used to go around Lake Erie.
Speaker 0: It's not in this game, but it is a train line.
Speaker 0: I know a lot about what.
Speaker 1: was it there in 1846 or before then or after then?
Speaker 0: Uh, I think it was around.
Speaker 0: it was around before then.
Speaker 0: Definitely.
Speaker 0: It just does not play in the 1846 game.
Speaker 0: I think it's heyday was earlier, but I know stuff about it because it's intrinsically tied to the history of Cedar Point anyway.
Speaker 0: So yeah, but the other interesting thing about this game like the the the core point I want to get out in the review before getting the details is that We both enjoy it.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm And I did not expect to feel the desire to not only play it but to play it again And having played it twice to actually really want to play it a third time.
Speaker 1: Well, here's the thing is like I don't Super want to play it, right?
Speaker 1: But it's like I totally will play it and it's sort of on this borderline where it's like it's got a lot of action Right.
Speaker 1: One thing I really like about it Is that even if you're losing and getting your ass kicked like you still do stuff.
Speaker 0: There is an exception to that.
Speaker 0: Amanda got into a specific situation where she was pushed to bankruptcy by Nonsense and literally could not do anything meaningful for many turns in a row.
Speaker 1: But it's really hard to not do.
Speaker 1: it was.
Speaker 0: it was such a like crazy Situation a turn of events that happened that she had no control over.
Speaker 1: It's also like a lot is a lot of even though the rules are sort of esoteric There's a lot of flexibility and what you can do.
Speaker 1: and yeah terms of like stock trading and train building and train buying it's like.
Speaker 0: so there's a bunch of very fiddly specific arbitrary seeming exceptions to general rules, but they are To do.
Speaker 0: then the games are I would complain about that like there's limits on how many stock certificates you can own But that doesn't really come into play until the very end of the game.
Speaker 0: So even though that is an arbitrary distinction It is not something that I bumped into in the course of natural play anyway.
Speaker 1: So the main thing is like the game takes a little while to play.
Speaker 1: it takes a few hours.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you can play fast if you've got skills and help and experience.
Speaker 1: But it still takes a while no matter what the game is sort of on this border Between where it takes too long.
Speaker 1: It's not worth it.
Speaker 1: If it was shorter, it would be like the best game ever.
Speaker 1: but it's not so long like Monopoly long You want to kill yourself?
Speaker 1: It's like, okay.
Speaker 1: I put the time aside.
Speaker 1: It's still and unlike say Eclipse where there's a lot of time sitting doing nothing.
Speaker 1: You're doing stuff the whole time You don't you know, I haven't gotten bored and distracted.
Speaker 1: usually when there's an Eclipse playing Eclipse takes as long or longer But I'll spend a lot of time during an Eclipse game sitting around being bored Waiting for my turn in this.
Speaker 1: that's almost never happens, right either either.
Speaker 0: while I'm waiting for my turn I'm thinking about like Stock value and like could I pull this off over the next few turns and wonder what Scott's gonna do?
Speaker 0: or I'm watching some drama Unfold in the stock market.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and you can only do a very small number of things on your turn.
Speaker 1: So the the rounds go around very quickly and then everyone sort of calculates simultaneously.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so without that downtime like you're into it for those hours You're actually probably in sort of play per time.
Speaker 1: It's very efficient right whereas Eclipse if you actually you know how like they talk about if you took an NFL game and cut out all the commercials the game is only like 20 minutes of real time or something like that of Actual playing from like start of plays to end of plays.
Speaker 1: this game is like no It's actually four hours long.
Speaker 1: and use the whole four hours.
Speaker 1: Eclipse is like five hours long but you actually you're only using like one hour of your own time and four hours of waiting.
Speaker 0: but it is also interesting how such a Sort of diversion and simulatory experience is crafted from a relatively small set of relatively elegant mechanics.
Speaker 1: Yeah, no, there's not.
Speaker 1: actually it's like it looks complicated It feels complicated.
Speaker 1: but if you were to say Redraw this game or read graphically design it to remove all the history stuff and the reality stuff and I would not be interested Mate, well, yeah, but make the symbology, you know more.
Speaker 0: Oh, I see where you're going on this, right?
Speaker 1: You would see the game actually isn't really as complicated as it appears.
Speaker 1: Yeah it is.
Speaker 1: it is actually not.
Speaker 1: it's like oh you have a round where you do stock stuff and Then you do have two rounds of not of playing the game and then you do stock stuff again.
Speaker 0: But what's also interesting is stock market play.
Speaker 0: play stock market games you go around and around like this that are reasonably Simulatory like that kind of game style the fact that it has so much history steeped into it like the proper nouns and all Those like other train companies.
Speaker 0: it actually helps you build Pretty reasonably good directional heuristics.
Speaker 0: Yeah Yeah based on just associating the fiction of the game with the mechanics like the combinations of some of those like independent railroads and Certain things you might want to do in a region is very intuitive like it would be in the real world.
Speaker 0: So the only real problem I have with this game before we get into like explaining how it actually works Is that so there's a concept in that book characteristics of games on Called busy work like games that have busy work like this
Speaker 1: does have one busy work in it.
Speaker 0: But I'm gonna go one step further and there's I think I want to make a distinction I've been using this word a lot lately in game reviews between Pure busy work and what I like to call rituals.
Speaker 0: This game has a lot of rituals.
Speaker 0: rituals are fine meaning but meaning that they are things that are moderately complex to do need to be done for the game to continue But they can be basically Entirely removed from your like.
Speaker 0: you don't need to know them to play as long as at least one person playing knows them.
Speaker 1: I think it was.
Speaker 1: I think it's basically there's a bunch of stuff that a computer could do and then the game would take a Little hands.
Speaker 0: Chris had that spreadsheet that we use for the dividends and all that crap Mm-hmm, and if you don't have that spreadsheet it takes longer to figure that out.
Speaker 0: so there and there is a ritual of moving the stock stuff up and down and Figuring out the numbers on the dividend.
Speaker 1: Yeah, this one makes a triple jump.
Speaker 1: That one makes a double jump.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I didn't need to know.
Speaker 1: I mean, I guess I would have helped me have better direction or his sticks if I did fully understand that.
Speaker 0: But I thought you don't need to fully understand.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I didn't play.
Speaker 1: well I didn't need to.
Speaker 1: I was.
Speaker 1: I was able to play well enough without knowing the exact Excruciating details.
Speaker 1: but because the board game someone has to know them But only one person needs to know them and sort of be the computer.
Speaker 0: So that's my difference.
Speaker 0: busy work is things that are generally equally spread among the players.
Speaker 1: Imagine if you were playing civilization the video game on a tabletop, but the rules are not changed at all.
Speaker 1: You have to be like, okay this city produces this much food this turn.
Speaker 1: Okay, it has enough food for population to increase.
Speaker 1: Yeah Which means this much food gets eaten and this much surplus food is left over.
Speaker 1: and it's like a thing that when you play the Video game the computer just does for you, but because you're playing a board game here.
Speaker 1: You have to do that yourself.
Speaker 1: Yeah You are.
Speaker 0: you can choose to zoom in and pay attention to the specific math if you want to but you don't need to for Just need to know generally.
Speaker 1: I want my population to go up.
Speaker 1: I need more food.
Speaker 0: so in this game the ritual is that as long as only as long as one person can Facilitate all the details which Chris did for us then I probably couldn't play it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the game is way more fun and That's why I'd be very interested in a well-made computer version of this game because the only other thing that has significant Ritualistic well, this one actually is busy work as well as that's dude on their own.
Speaker 1: This is the busier.
Speaker 0: guys are calculate the optimal set of routes to run your trains on right?
Speaker 1: So here's how this works.
Speaker 1: is your each train company.
Speaker 0: Yeah, let's talk about how the game actually plays.
Speaker 1: You have a train company.
Speaker 0: Well, no, you don't.
Speaker 0: you found a train company.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 1: Sure Whatever and you might have more than one.
Speaker 1: There's the tree.
Speaker 0: one might steal it from you Whatever.
Speaker 1: the train companies have money and trains and stocks.
Speaker 1: You as an individual person also have monies and trains and stocks.
Speaker 1: right and whoever has enough stock in a company Controls that company, but obviously someone could buy all the stock and take the company.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there's companies that don't exist yet in the game.
Speaker 1: ever at the beginning of the game Everyone buys one company or founds one, but there's some unfounded ones.
Speaker 1: You can always pick those up.
Speaker 1: mid game.
Speaker 0: You might found a second one.
Speaker 0: You can have two different drink company.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like, you know, but anyway, there's the independent drink When it's your turn when you operate you operate the companies that you control because you have enough stock in them that you're the president and You you you are the boss of that company.
Speaker 0: now This is where it gets fascinating.
Speaker 0: The goal of the game is for you the player to have the most money at the end.
Speaker 0: Yep, but your money is entirely distinct from the company's money.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: That is the interesting thing.
Speaker 0: So when you operate a train company you spend the train company's money.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you can't use your personal money to buy a train for the train company But you can order stock in a train company And that money goes to the train company.
Speaker 1: if the company still owns some of its own stock.
Speaker 1: You could buy stock from the company does to move your money in and the stock out and then when the train company Gets revenues those monies go to the shareholders.
Speaker 1: So if you own shares in a company or your opponent's companies when that train company operates and brings in revenue You would get some of that money.
Speaker 1: but the train company still owns some of its own shares.
Speaker 1: That's how it gets more money.
Speaker 1: if a train company lose all of its shares It can't really make any more money and it has to continue to operate without any revenues because shareholders are taking all the revenue.
Speaker 0: Yep Now the other interesting thing is that the train companies they can invest in their own infrastructure Which basically just means buying trains.
Speaker 0: Yep, and they can invest in shared track infrastructure.
Speaker 0: Literally anyone can use.
Speaker 1: this is the most interesting part of the game Right?
Speaker 1: is that in most train games like in rare or tycoon you're moving cubes around and stuff like that, right?
Speaker 1: That's not what's going on here.
Speaker 1: Right what happens here is on a train company's tournament operates.
Speaker 1: It can basically like do only a little bit very limited how much track they can lay out.
Speaker 1: They could like what do one upgrade in one piece of track?
Speaker 1: Yep, pretty much or two pieces of track.
Speaker 1: I think it's not two upgrades.
Speaker 0: No, I messed that up like twice.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so you can only lay out a little bit of track and what you want.
Speaker 1: and the thing is the tracks belong to everybody.
Speaker 1: There's no owner of track It's just you're upgrading the tracks around the country or the city where the train station is.
Speaker 0: If you upgrade Centralia and have a better train station, that's great for everybody.
Speaker 1: and now the train company has stations.
Speaker 1: And if all the stations in a city are blocked up, well, then someone else can't run their trains past it.
Speaker 1: But as long as they basically your trains start from one of your stations and then they run Where as long as it's not blocked pretty much to wherever they're gonna make the most money.
Speaker 1: And so this is the busy work part is basically you say well this train company has these two trains.
Speaker 1: These two trains can drive this far.
Speaker 1: Here's where my stations are.
Speaker 1: What are the routes that will make the most money for these two trains?
Speaker 0: and this is where a video game you could literally hit?
Speaker 0: And it would tell you the maximum run.
Speaker 1: yeah, it's not like a decision it's just like what's the answer?
Speaker 1: You're trying to look at the board and figure out like how much money.
Speaker 1: it's like you audio The rule is you make the maximum, but it's like what is the maximum you had to some?
Speaker 0: It's like a little and you might choose to make less but and there are situations where that might make sense Yeah, sure, but yeah, you make the maximum.
Speaker 1: Yeah, pretty much you might fail to figure out the maximum because it's trying to hard to figure out.
Speaker 1: Well, I can use all the tracks on the board.
Speaker 1: What is the best route?
Speaker 1: Well, I guess it's these four stations and you most of the time you get it, right?
Speaker 1: But it's like annoying.
Speaker 1: I if you played in a computer the computer could just be like your revenue is X done.
Speaker 1: It would take a fraction of a second part of my brain.
Speaker 0: It's kind of fun until the map gets really complex toward the end.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and the early game is very obvious because you've only got like two stations like.
Speaker 1: well Yeah, it's these two stations.
Speaker 1: I get 80 bucks, but later in the game.
Speaker 1: It's like oh, no I can get ten more dollars if I go this way.
Speaker 1: Alright, and the other thing is that your your trains cannot share Track.
Speaker 1: they can't like bump into each other like each track Route or each hex edge can only be used once for you for you But someone else can use those hex edges.
Speaker 1: just not.
Speaker 1: you can't use your own hex edge twice.
Speaker 1: We have more than one train.
Speaker 0: So yeah, and there's all these other mechanics like so you can buy.
Speaker 0: at the beginning of the game There's this whole draft where you can buy Independent companies that do different things up to and including Entire small independent railroads that run like a real company and eventually get brought into the big railroad.
Speaker 0: But you the player buy them with your own money, but then maybe you sell them to one of your train companies.
Speaker 0: But the game ends.
Speaker 0: there's a there's an amount of money.
Speaker 0: when that amount of money is taken from the bank then You the game ends.
Speaker 1: imagine playing Monopoly and the bank has ten thousand dollars in.
Speaker 1: I'm just making up a number.
Speaker 0: Yeah Once that number was like it's zero right.
Speaker 1: and once the ten thousand dollars in the bank is completely gone The bank has zero left.
Speaker 1: you keep giving people money for that round until everyone has the amount of money They're supposed to have.
Speaker 1: yep, and then whoever has the most wins.
Speaker 0: So when that happens then the the winner is whoever themselves not their companies Just themselves has the most money between their money and the actual value of the stock they own.
Speaker 1: That's it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so this game has like the the interesting parts of the game.
Speaker 1: right you know the the large macro strategy parts is.
Speaker 1: The big one is the buying of trains Because the trains go out of style and they become obsolete and if the train company can't afford to buy new or better trains They're just done They're screwed right.
Speaker 1: so you have to basically acquire get a big pile of money in the train company So that the train company can buy a larger better superior train like two or three times during the game.
Speaker 1: What happens almost immediately then is the next one is a little hard and the final one is super hard And you can get into situations where?
Speaker 0: Older trains become like obsolete and run a little bit, and then they're just like literally work.
Speaker 1: Those trains get like one last run, and then they're out.
Speaker 1: you better have the new train lined up And it's like you have to make your trains Companies profitable enough that they can keep upgrading the trains and get that final up And you have
Speaker 0: to manage how much of the stock you like you buy for someone should leave in the company.
Speaker 1: Yeah If you leave too many shares in the company Then you're sort of losing out on money and also leaving those stocks available to like be bought up by other people.
Speaker 0: But you're letting the company profit from its own work instead of extracting that wealth early.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but if you buy the shares - you know you got to buy.
Speaker 1: It's like you got to buy them, but you don't want to buy them too early on buying too late.
Speaker 1: But you know shares in other people's company.
Speaker 0: Yeah, which is crucial.
Speaker 1: so like yeah It's like.
Speaker 1: well rims train company is better than mine.
Speaker 1: doesn't mean I'm gonna lose.
Speaker 1: You know I could maybe buy all his shares out right now his train company doesn't.
Speaker 0: it's interesting How accurate to the time the corporate stuff is yeah?
Speaker 0: You literally you're trying to extract as much wealth from the system as possible.
Speaker 0: You don't give a fuck about the train company.
Speaker 1: It doesn't?
Speaker 1: your train company has to be the best one.
Speaker 1: You know.
Speaker 1: the strategy I saw Chris use a lot was have one train company Run it into the ground then have a second one that comes in later And that one runs to the end game.
Speaker 0: because when you find a train company you do an IPO And you can pick the value of your stock right.
Speaker 1: so it's like he makes a bunch of early game money by running one train Company in the ground uses that on a second train company that now has a bunch of money in its coffers So it can buy the better train.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so the get in terms of play and the way it feels you're using more real-world fuzzy heuristics.
Speaker 1: Also when that second train company comes in doesn't really need to buy tracks.
Speaker 1: There's already tracks everywhere exactly.
Speaker 0: but you sort of have to just play it and Explore these mechanics kind of bounce off of them like if you play this game with anyone who's played it before You'll have fun.
Speaker 0: You'll lose.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's I think that's the one best thing I can say about this game Even though it is a competitive skill game and also has this historical element and a thematic element, right?
Speaker 1: You know it takes a while never been upset by losing or winning at this game.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's an experience.
Speaker 1: It's just like.
Speaker 1: it's just like oh you get to have a bunch of fun times playing trains running trains buying and selling stocks And like it feels good.
Speaker 1: It doesn't feel like some roll and move garbage like Monopoly.
Speaker 1: It's all decisions.
Speaker 1: This is not like.
Speaker 1: what luck is there in this game?
Speaker 1: Nothing.
Speaker 1: Is there any luck at all in this guy just the initial drafting?
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't think there's not a. there's not a deck There's not a dice roll.
Speaker 1: There's not a nothing.
Speaker 1: Yep, right and it just feels way good the whole time.
Speaker 1: So you don't really.
Speaker 1: you know You don't get too upset and even though I don't think I don't think I've ever won I've always had done well enough had like a bunch of monies.
Speaker 1: It's not like I got blowed up and sat there getting crap.
Speaker 1: You know the shit kicked out of me, but I could play this a few more times.
Speaker 0: I'm curious about trying the because apparently as from what I gather this one is probably the most accessible.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't see a reason to play the other ones unless you're a super trained nerd or unless you've played this one a bunch Of times and you're kind of sick of it.
Speaker 1: Yeah The one thing is that every time I play this I've played it three times.
Speaker 0: now actually play one of the other ones might Give insight like if the rules are a little different about a thing.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like strategies back I think you'd only do that if you're way into it.
Speaker 1: true if you're just a board gamer in general It's like you're gonna try one of them.
Speaker 0: try this one if you want to try a game That's more like these stimulatory war game II like weird stuff.
Speaker 0: This is a pretty good one for a euro gamer to try as long as you have someone who is going to teach you into The rituals.
Speaker 0: yeah
Speaker 1: anyway, so the one thing about this game I played it three times and even though I played it three times There's plenty of time to learn the rules of a game is that it's this much time between plays that I sort of forget The not the maid done the general rules But these small details right.
Speaker 1: when exactly do these trains expire?
Speaker 1: when exactly?
Speaker 1: Can you start doing this versus doing that and whatnot?
Speaker 1: and those details matter a lot?
Speaker 1: So what happens is I forget those details the next time I play and I'll make a mistake.
Speaker 1: for example the most recent time We played at pecs unplugged.
Speaker 1: I Definitely made a huge mistake.
Speaker 1: I did something on a turn and there was no reason I couldn't have done that thing a turn earlier Which would have been just better.
Speaker 1: I just did a turn later than I could have for no reason just because I didn't realize I could at that time and That cost me some money whatever right?
Speaker 1: But it's like if I could play the game twice in a row or twice very close to each other.
Speaker 1: I would basically remember all those tiny details that I've probably have already forgotten since pecs unplugged in the first game like the warm-up.
Speaker 1: Remember how to play remember all the details game Yeah And then play a second game with no excuses and no forgetting of those details and probably perform Really?
Speaker 1: Well, like I give myself an actual above zero percent chance of winning if I could play twice in a row in game two In game one no zero percent chance, but in game two, I think if I played twice in a row I would have a greater than zero percent chance of winning.
Speaker 0: So you wanna know the kind of person who plays this game?
Speaker 0: I'm looking at board game because had like the screenshot up The first comment.
Speaker 0: someone commented on this individual picture Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: And the comment is why is there a city tile on the hex immediately to the west of Detroit?
Speaker 0: and sure enough There's one there because there's no city there in the game.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: And the next response is did they house rule Ann Arbor in and get a third person said basically There's a lot of people chatting about this error in this one random screenshot on board game.
Speaker 0: Can you mean photograph?
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's not a screenshot.
Speaker 0: it's not a screenshot.
Speaker 0: no board game it's not.
Speaker 0: I'm going with that.
Speaker 1: okay, it's a photograph.
Speaker 0: But someone noticed that and there is a robust discussion in this one thread about literally this one picture among dozens.
Speaker 1: Yeah So yeah, if you are at all, you know, it's like, you know If you hear people talk about like these You know things that you know.
Speaker 1: It's sort of like I talked about back in the day fist of the North side.
Speaker 1: keep hearing about fist of the North Star But you never actually go to watch it, right?
Speaker 1: It's just like a thing, you know That's in your hobby a thing you keep hearing about but you never experience it yourself.
Speaker 1: You keep hearing about like super nerdy train games super nerdy war games or things like that But you never actually go and play them ever.
Speaker 1: You just know that that's sort of out there.
Speaker 1: It's like that is.
Speaker 1: it's out there.
Speaker 1: you heard of it.
Speaker 1: It's a thing go check it out at least once.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it might be worth it.
Speaker 1: You might like it You might discover something new and even if not, you'll learn something and then you'll learn.
Speaker 1: you just don't have to do it again.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and actually to be honest this game is Literally the ins the reason why I was inspired to make that new panel on the top 40 board the 40 board games.
Speaker 0: You should play well tabletop games cuz I'm a sneak some RPGs and card games in there.
Speaker 0: Yeah, cuz yeah Yeah, uh, we enjoyed this game and it's the kind of game that a lot of people who know us would assume We would not enjoy.
Speaker 0: and shows what you know, I mean, I wouldn't buy it I wouldn't play no, I would not play it without someone who was able to do the ritual.
Speaker 1: I wouldn't I wouldn't play it super frequently, but it's the kind of thing I could play.
Speaker 1: you know me a few more times before, you know, I've had enough of it and You know, I don't think I could keep enjoying it forever though.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like it's.
Speaker 0: eventually you've explored all the sort of mechanics and once you've explored them if you actually try to Hyper-optimize the game.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't know it would still be fun.
Speaker 1: I have no interest in that.
Speaker 1: but is it's just like it's a?
Speaker 1: really?
Speaker 1: in terms of even though it's cost a lot of time To play I can't get over the fact you get so much value like you're constantly doing stuff that whole time.
Speaker 1: It's like every time I've played it like time is flown by.
Speaker 1: it's like whoa It's already that time and it's like because you're just playing the whole time.
Speaker 1: There's no.
Speaker 1: there's no downtime where you're getting bored or feeling like it's long.
Speaker 0: Yeah I also do like these simple thing that I wish more games did of.
Speaker 0: if you have a Machine you can crank or a thing you can operate the turns are do the stock thing and then you crank that machine twice.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and you're already machine games.
Speaker 0: Don't let you crank it enough times and your mother game that does.
Speaker 0: this is oh my good.
Speaker 1: the decisions you're making you're engaging and Interesting and you have a lot of flexibility to be creative.
Speaker 1: It's like you.
Speaker 1: can you have money?
Speaker 1: What are you gonna do with it businessman?
Speaker 0: Which is a lot of games.
Speaker 0: if you have a machine the players can crank.
Speaker 0: Let him crank it more.
Speaker 0: the game's gonna feel better.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: Go my goods at the end of the game crank it twice.
Speaker 0: Yep, that I like that.
Speaker 0: I haven't seen that enough.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: All right, I'm so hungry I might.
Speaker 0: I can smell what Emily's cooking in there.
Speaker 0: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Speaker 1: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 0: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 1: But unlike those other late shows It's actually recorded at night
Speaker 0: and the patreon patreon for this episode of geek nights are Ellen Joyce Rebecca Dunn Heidi McNicholaw's shimmering rubiobolus hanging in the sky my statey comm Jeremy minor Genuine, but if I'd like to magic scar monorail Amanda Duchette, Sean Yeager, Matthew Smith, Nicholas Brando, Captain Chinguacos.
Speaker 0: He forgot to one creations.
Speaker 0: No I never ever wonder why we're here.
Speaker 0: Semper Fi bitch Shervin von Horrell rarely Val James David White Rochelle, Monta notice super boy Rim says something funny here.
Speaker 0: sailor Vista Don Schleich Jartavish and Joshua Joe star Sam Cordray Clinton Walton written from New Zealand.
Speaker 0: Ryan Perrin drew open Lander Brian Cedroni Finn Chris midkiff Chris Knox Daniel Redman Sean Klein Chris Reimer and Thomas Hahn Feels weird when the pen doesn't end just like that.
Speaker 0: It feels right this way.
Speaker 0: But anyway, I got two Rims rants.
Speaker 0: I also got a special that Emily and I recorded about stranger things.
Speaker 0: That's gonna go in the main geek night's feed.
Speaker 0: But uh, all the patreon stuff will be resuming starting this weekend with gusto.
Speaker 0: This is the call before the storm.
Speaker 0: I got time to actually work on stuff.
Speaker 0: We're gonna make a uh He nice presents for the anime.
Speaker 0: We're gonna make a nice presents for you.
Speaker 0: tennis.
Speaker 0: specifically got a bunch of new rims rants.
Speaker 0: We got two new panels one of which I wrote on a whim the other night.
Speaker 0: That's gonna be pretty good.
Speaker 0: I think that 40 games thing.
Speaker 0: and now I leave you with the oddly creepy song about the master and the brave little toaster.
Speaker 0: Get us meet the master.
Speaker 0: We don't want to make him wait You just keep.
Speaker 0: Master is a man with a plan.
Speaker 0: I can understand.
Speaker 0: master is a man of great reflection.
Speaker 0: Master is a man who lays his hand across the land.
Speaker 0: Master is a man.
Speaker 0: I'm Time stands still in the country And I'd be satisfied just to be not denied to the side.