Speaker 1: It's Thursday February 2nd 2017.
Speaker 1: I'm rim.
Speaker 1: I'm Scott, and this is geek nights.
Speaker 1: tonight We are late to the party with a review of rogue one rogue use Star Wars Rouge 1 or war.
Speaker 0: what is good?
Speaker 1: Absolutely nothing except defeating Nazis and possibly beating the Empire and movies.
Speaker 1: Let's do this So not to get too deep into the politics of all that.
Speaker 0: he's going deep.
Speaker 1: I'm going deep I know.
Speaker 1: so right now You know the.
Speaker 1: the probably the biggest threat to American democracy is that Bannon guy.
Speaker 1: you know the Nazi like the actual Nazi white Supremacist who was on the National Security Council, so I know I called the Senate office to be like yo as a constituent.
Speaker 1: do not put him on that body.
Speaker 1: and I was standing in City Hall Park like I try to make these calls before I got on the subway to go home And I call like five times busy signal busy signal busy You know.
Speaker 1: then I get a ring and it goes to their voicemail.
Speaker 1: So I leave a voicemail, and I think and then it became full and then I'm by myself.
Speaker 1: So I think I like you know I make the phone call.
Speaker 1: I'm just like out in the park.
Speaker 1: There's no one really around me, and I hang up and just as I'm walking away There's this dude who was sitting like a ways away But I guess he overheard me and he just looks at me and says fuck Nazis.
Speaker 1: And I'm like yeah, and then he's like.
Speaker 1: I called this morning, and then I got in the subway, okay?
Speaker 1: I would have told the story about the weird guy on the subway, but it's not weird enough Wasn't like I'd see?
Speaker 1: no just you know.
Speaker 1: you know sometimes you run into someone who's like something weird going on But you're not quite sure what.
Speaker 0: and sometimes they drugs and or mental illness.
Speaker 1: yeah But you know you know the the New York sense like you see someone on the subway And you don't know what their deal is, but you know there is a deal, so you know drugs or mental illness.
Speaker 0: There's no reason to like pay attention to them.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well other than you don't turn your back fully on them.
Speaker 1: well Keep them in the peripheral vision and if they escalate one more step you hold your phone You don't do anything with it, but you're ready to start recording.
Speaker 1: So he was like Almost at the line of.
Speaker 1: this will be an interesting story, and then nothing happened.
Speaker 0: Okay, so new is this is one of those days where I can get away with free news.
Speaker 0: I probably have done this many times, but this Sunday is oh yeah the superb owl Lee Li.
Speaker 1: they went back to Roman numerals correctly, but you said they wouldn't.
Speaker 0: you were wrong.
Speaker 1: I didn't think they would.
Speaker 1: I'm actually really happy.
Speaker 1: they went back whoo-hoo.
Speaker 0: It's superb owl?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I won't watch it cuz I'm just I'm.
Speaker 1: the CTE stuff has bothered me enough.
Speaker 0: to where I'm trying to not watch football anymore, but you're watching hockey which is the same problem.
Speaker 1: I think hockey has a significantly less degree, and I've seen substantial changes.
Speaker 1: So actually I was talking about this today on Twitter cuz someone reminded me how much I hate the rules of soccer But the I. the problem was that there is now real evidence that headers in soccer Do cause CTE and on concussion like symptoms.
Speaker 1: sure yeah, you hitting your head against anything is bad Yeah, but it's particularly like you can hit your head occasionally like everyone hits their head.
Speaker 1: You can't hit it.
Speaker 0: I was dropped out of the sidewalk.
Speaker 1: Yeah, when I was baby I got knocked the fuck out in a ski accident once a long time ago But they were like.
Speaker 1: headers are specifically bad.
Speaker 1: so Jane McGonigal was like It's just a game.
Speaker 1: We can change the rules to games.
Speaker 0: yep.
Speaker 0: So why don't we?
Speaker 0: because people care about tradition more than they care about what's fair?
Speaker 0: What's right?
Speaker 1: Yep?
Speaker 1: So I got into a discussion with some game design.
Speaker 1: We're just sort of talking about like.
Speaker 1: well What how would you change that rule?
Speaker 1: and is there a clever way?
Speaker 1: To avoid the dangers of that without making like a really restrictive rule on the game?
Speaker 0: Don't hit you can't hit the ball with your head.
Speaker 0: very done.
Speaker 0: so problem solved.
Speaker 0: so it's the same as a handball.
Speaker 1: Hockey has a really interesting example there in the icing rule change because that was what like Hockey is the most willing to change the rules.
Speaker 0: yeah, and hockey has done things over time like hey go They got to wear a mask.
Speaker 0: hey great Everyone's got to wear a helmet now, and they don't grandfather everyone in.
Speaker 0: they say deal with it.
Speaker 0: There's other sports.
Speaker 0: They're like baseball.
Speaker 0: do this and the baseball players union the strongest sports union on the earth is like nope It's like stop stabbing yourself in the arm every time you Come up Gavin at bad.
Speaker 1: They're like, but it's tradition.
Speaker 1: They're like, but you guys all have gangrene.
Speaker 1: It's like no, but tradition man.
Speaker 1: So but hockey.
Speaker 1: they'd like the changes.
Speaker 1: I thought was most interesting.
Speaker 1: Relevant to that was the icing rule a few years ago because in the old days You know icing for those of you who don't know is
Speaker 0: if you hit the puck and it goes
Speaker 1: over too many
Speaker 0: lines Wards the zone where you are going to be on offense It crosses over two red lines meaning the one in the middle of the ice and the one that's you know lined up with the goal.
Speaker 0: if it crosses both those lines and You don't go and get it before the other team gets it then it's icing.
Speaker 1: yep.
Speaker 1: now If you shoot it over there, and you already got a guy over there That's offsides you know.
Speaker 0: if your guys waiting about the blue line, and then runs.
Speaker 1: It's okay gets it But but he can't be over that blue line He's got to come back right.
Speaker 0: But anyway the problem is to go over the blue line before the guy.
Speaker 1: now icing was a rule that was intended to prevent really Boring hockey of people to shoot it all the way the fuck across constantly, but you're the rule goes away During a power play because otherwise you'd be fun.
Speaker 1: So the problem with the icing rules until a few years ago Was that the offense and the defense had an incentive to race for the puck.
Speaker 1: so you have two Huge dudes sometimes three skating as fast as they can Toward a wall and each other people still do that.
Speaker 1: So the problem was when they got to that wall the puck and two or three huge dudes are there And they would crash into each other.
Speaker 1: and the NHL recognized pretty rapidly that this was causing an Inordinate number of serious head injuries and other kinds of injuries.
Speaker 1: like that action alone accounted for a huge percentage of the total injuries in the hockey right.
Speaker 0: so now they have Automatic icing which is like if you're if the puck is like way far away from everybody, and it's just icing.
Speaker 0: It's just icing they don't let you.
Speaker 0: Only let you chase it down if you're like already kind of close to better.
Speaker 1: even if there is a chase if the linesman Not even the ref if the linesman as far as I know Decides that the defense guy is definitely gonna beat that like win the race They'll just blow it dead.
Speaker 1: so you don't have the crash at the end right, but if the offense guy has a chance You still get the dramatic chase.
Speaker 0: But the defense guy winning is the same as just automatic out right.
Speaker 0: so it doesn't.
Speaker 1: there's no reason to chase But they only let the risky thing that causes injuries happen.
Speaker 1: if there's a like a legit shot It was gonna make it pretty rare.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so think instead of just like Drastically changing the rules of hockey they made this subtle change that kept the drama while substantially reducing the number of head injuries in hockey.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm problem is soccer's rules are so simple except for their stupid offsides.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you thought the icing rule.
Speaker 0: I just talked about was complicated.
Speaker 0: What easy.
Speaker 0: the soccer offsides rule.
Speaker 1: yep, but anyway yeah I really have increasing issues with football because I feel like football is the most damaging and least morally Defensible sport in America right now.
Speaker 0: sure I mean we used to have boxing though.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but boxing Is still a thing.
Speaker 1: yeah, MMA is complicated though.
Speaker 1: I get the impression.
Speaker 1: There's no boxing Yeah, but at the same time the fights are over quicker.
Speaker 0: And sure I saw a fight the other day.
Speaker 0: this guy Smacked this guy real hard.
Speaker 0: he went down And then he went over to jump and stomp him on the face And then he got.
Speaker 0: basically he got immediately disqualified because yeah But that the reason he got the.
Speaker 0: why did he stomp a guy's face though and getting me this qualified?
Speaker 0: because in the previous Version of MMA that he was in like the other league or whatever you were allowed to stop on people's faces.
Speaker 0: He was used to it, and then as soon as he got disqualified.
Speaker 0: He was like no Oops Oops Cuz he basically had won already.
Speaker 0: yeah, if you just hadn't tried to stop the face after winning you would have been fine.
Speaker 0: I just won.
Speaker 0: yeah.
Speaker 1: But also think about the difference of boxing.
Speaker 1: had the sort of subtle problem of the constant lower impact hits to the head would cause All right.
Speaker 0: one punch to the head in boxing is is way worse than one hit in football.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but how many you take Boxing over 20 years.
Speaker 0: It depends on your style of boxing right?
Speaker 0: yeah, Muhammad Ali in his early days He didn't take so many hits.
Speaker 0: It's only you know after he came back after dodging the draft and not being able to box for some years and then getting old And deciding to keep boxing.
Speaker 0: Oh, that's when he started robed open and taking all the hits.
Speaker 0: So if you're just a badass and knocks people to fuck out like Mike Tyson say or you know early in his career It'd be over in two seconds.
Speaker 0: Oh, you're not taking too many hits, but basically boxing.
Speaker 1: I'm kind of glad it's dying MMA.
Speaker 1: I will see how safe it gets.
Speaker 1: I feel like football just has the least moral high ground to stand on.
Speaker 0: but football on The other hand is the most game like of game.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right It's like regardless of the people hurting each other.
Speaker 1: He's pretty close in a lot of ways.
Speaker 0: High football is basically a board game with real people as pawns.
Speaker 0: That's it's like what every nerd wants to play.
Speaker 0: That's why we have blood Bowl.
Speaker 1: I would be into football with semi-intelligent robots or animatronics actually doing the playing.
Speaker 0: I'd be into football with Actually blood Bowl with orcs and elves dwarves Actually killing each other.
Speaker 1: Maybe we can get that with some VR AR action.
Speaker 0: I'm sure.
Speaker 0: but I mean blood Bowl video game where it exists.
Speaker 0: I'm sure it will just in every other form.
Speaker 1: of course I can't watch Super Bowl anyway because I'm gonna be on a ski trip And I don't really feel like putting forth the effort to see it even though I assume it'll be on in every sports bar in New Hampshire.
Speaker 0: It'll probably be on every television And everywhere.
Speaker 1: yep I pretty much always take a ski trip these years during the Super Bowl So I never see it.
Speaker 0: not a lot of people skiing at that time.
Speaker 0: well happens to be a cold time Right around.
Speaker 1: now is like the best time to do a ski trip.
Speaker 1: if you do it midweek is in the middle of the week No one skis.
Speaker 1: yeah of course not except like rich people who live there.
Speaker 0: And this is crazy good weather and people are crazy enough to take the day off because it's so good.
Speaker 0: It's not like if
Speaker 1: you're out west like I was talking to people in Utah when I was there like yeah People just all call in sick if there's a good snow day on like Tuesday And that's like it's acceptable like the boss would be like why'd you come into work?
Speaker 1: There's snow.
Speaker 0: I don't ski.
Speaker 0: why do I live here?
Speaker 0: Why do you live in Utah?
Speaker 1: You don't ski?
Speaker 1: There's literally no other reason to live in Utah.
Speaker 0: That's correct.
Speaker 1: So who do you think is gonna win the Super Bowl?
Speaker 0: I think the New England Patriots will win because they play to win unlike other teams that don't play to win.
Speaker 1: That is what I could say about the Patriots.
Speaker 0: other people right they always be saying like hey Patriots cheating And you know what I say.
Speaker 0: I say this look Lance Armstrong.
Speaker 0: He cheated.
Speaker 0: yeah He cheated big-time, and you know.
Speaker 0: you know what they did when they caught him cheating.
Speaker 0: They said guess what you didn't win anymore.
Speaker 0: now You lose.
Speaker 0: you lose that you've won zero Tour de France's Lance Armstrong zero because you cheated, and he did right.
Speaker 0: no But Patriots they cheated.
Speaker 0: So they broke the rules.
Speaker 0: and what did they say?
Speaker 0: they said oh you broke that rule?
Speaker 0: We will fine you and suspend you for four games, and you know here are the penalties.
Speaker 0: and they said oh But we still won.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you still won.
Speaker 0: well If I'm playing a board game if I'm playing settlers, and you tell me I'll give you two victory points for ten dollars.
Speaker 0: I mean I didn't earn the two victory points.
Speaker 0: I just give you ten dollars, and I win.
Speaker 0: I'm doing that every fucking time I think.
Speaker 0: the other teams Why aren't you doing everything that you're allowed to?
Speaker 0: if the penalty up to?
Speaker 0: Write any penalty that only includes money or whatever.
Speaker 0: that doesn't make you lose.
Speaker 0: You should be doing all those things if you believe they will really give you an advantage to winning because winning is priority one.
Speaker 0: Yep, I'm very glad that you know the hoodie plays football a game in which I don't know how to compete with him.
Speaker 0: Imagine if like that player of games played like Magic the Gathering or chess or Netrunner or Overwatch or anything else.
Speaker 0: right he would be like winning everything every day all the time.
Speaker 0: It's good that he plays football a game only like 30-something.
Speaker 0: people have to compete with him and none of them can win.
Speaker 1: So in other news minor giants minor politics news.
Speaker 0: Interesting fact despite the Patriots winning so many Super Bowls and appearing in the Super Bowl so even many more times than that over the past 16 or so years In the past 10 years the only team with two Super Bowl wins is the New York Football Giants.
Speaker 0: Wow really yeah Cuz the Patriots won Once recently.
Speaker 0: they appeared multiple times in the past 10 years true, but they kept losing to the giant And they would this the other.
Speaker 0: the time they won before their recent win was you know 11 years ago.
Speaker 0: So if you only take the most recent 10 years they only won one.
Speaker 1: Because I don't have much of a horse in this race I mean the only the only bowl I care about is not a bowl.
Speaker 0: I got no horse.
Speaker 0: I both I mean even at the pages lose.
Speaker 0: It's like.
Speaker 0: I don't care.
Speaker 0: I mean I want them to win for reasons, but I don't.
Speaker 0: it's like.
Speaker 0: there's no evil teams left therefore.
Speaker 1: It's all good.
Speaker 1: I don't care about a bowl so much as a cup and we're getting not.
Speaker 1: we're not too far away from the cup stuff.
Speaker 0: You got like to May and June.
Speaker 1: yeah, yeah, we're over the halfway point.
Speaker 1: Yeah, sure I'm worried about the Red Wings prospects of making the end of the playoffs.
Speaker 1: I don't want that streak to end, but it's uh it's gonna be a dicey affair.
Speaker 1: We'll see what happens.
Speaker 1: So in some minor well not minor news, but some interesting news you might see on Twitter There's a lot of people tweeting about a general strike.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, it's not time for that yet.
Speaker 1: like The only thing worse than like not trying a general strike when shit gets bad politically is trying and failing at a general strike.
Speaker 1: I think he says hey guess what we're powerless.
Speaker 0: I mean the thing is I think you got a because it's such a scary deal.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you got to ease into it right you get back all right everybody Everyone.
Speaker 0: let's stay home on Friday and see who doesn't show.
Speaker 0: yeah, right And you just sort of test the like you got to put the toe in.
Speaker 0: you can't you can't cannonball into the pool on that.
Speaker 1: That is my news because that is what's happening right now.
Speaker 1: That easing in because you might not have noticed because it didn't only happen for a little while.
Speaker 0: But it's not happening where those people live.
Speaker 1: But during the protest around the executive order and the travel ban and all that stuff you know when you know Pretty much every international airport in America had a mob of lawyers and smart people protesting.
Speaker 1: the New York City taxis Temporarily went on a full strike against going to the airport.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm that ain't that is not easy to make happen.
Speaker 1: The fact and they didn't it wasn't forever like they resumed doing the airport stuff like the next day.
Speaker 1: They weren't saying like this strike is the moment they were saying we are capable of striking take note Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: and then today strike to the Comcast workers thousands and thousands of Comcast workers.
Speaker 1: Comcast let him go yeah But that plus one for Comcast.
Speaker 1: basically Comcast workers walked out of the job to do a big protest.
Speaker 1: and today All the Yemeni owned bodegas.
Speaker 0: I didn't know there's so many.
Speaker 0: I mean bodegas are owned by pretty much Yeah, you've never seen a bodega owned by someone who wasn't an immigrant right, but they're owned by such a wide variety Yeah of immigrants like.
Speaker 0: there's not a country you could think of where that someone from that country owns a bite.
Speaker 0: It's like I seen the Jew bodega.
Speaker 0: I seem like any country on earth.
Speaker 0: There's a sushi place near me.
Speaker 0: That's like What's the fucking country?
Speaker 1: All right, I'm really curious.
Speaker 0: No.
Speaker 0: It's it's over.
Speaker 1: You forgot.
Speaker 0: It's the really tiny country near Vietnam Cambodia.
Speaker 0: It starts with a B. I think I forget but whatever it's like the craziest tiny countries that you never think about ever.
Speaker 1: Uh Right, all right Burma, yes, Bangladesh.
Speaker 0: There's a Burmese sushi place in a story.
Speaker 1: Majority bodegas are Yemeni owned.
Speaker 0: I didn't realize so many bodegas were owned by Yemenis because I checked the bodega near me.
Speaker 0: It was totally open.
Speaker 0: I guess it's not Yemeni.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: Now there were a lot of non-yemenian bodegas who closed in solidarity.
Speaker 0: Sure I mean if I had a bodega I closed that shit.
Speaker 1: but Lot of bodegas shut down and no one outside of New York.
Speaker 0: I didn't actually see a shut down one Which I kind of wanted to see.
Speaker 1: the one in my building at work was shut down cuz then I'd know which one to go To.
Speaker 0: yeah, I guess the one near me that I go to the most didn't shut down.
Speaker 0: So, I don't know if I should.
Speaker 1: I go there one by my office that was shut down.
Speaker 1: All they had in the door was a hashtag resist and a big American flag.
Speaker 1: So no one outside of New York City knows that happened.
Speaker 0: That's our.
Speaker 0: New York City knows that bodega is yeah But they go stop and shout that shit ain't closing that.
Speaker 1: my news is just to remember very clearly because I know you know The labor movement was good at this sort of thing and the labor movement has been all but destroyed in the United States.
Speaker 1: Like they lost a lot of their power, but they know how to organize.
Speaker 0: Well, they shouldn't have been corrupt.
Speaker 0: Yeah They lost their power by being corrupt.
Speaker 0: So they took the power away from them, right?
Speaker 0: It's like they had.
Speaker 0: they were a good thing and then they use their power for evil.
Speaker 1: What are you gonna do?
Speaker 1: But anyway Those people I'll take the low relatively low level of corruption we've had.
Speaker 0: yes cuz the Union leaders You know taking embezzling all that money.
Speaker 0: I was low-level.
Speaker 1: I'd say that's relatively low-level.
Speaker 1: I've been to places where there is high-level corruption.
Speaker 0: So you go and you just find out your 401k there is missing some money, you know, where'd it go?
Speaker 1: Yeah, yeah, I mean there's places where like the banks like who are you again?
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm, huh?
Speaker 1: That's an interesting savings account.
Speaker 1: You've got your shame if anything were to happen to it.
Speaker 1: But just bear in mind when you see these little strikes every time there is a short pointed protest strike That is wide-scale in the US.
Speaker 1: now That is.
Speaker 1: that is not the primary action like it is.
Speaker 1: it is an action like it is a signal.
Speaker 1: It is a protest but that is primarily a signal saying if there is a general strike We will join it and saying we are capable of joining it.
Speaker 1: So keep an eye on People who bit by bit do little protest strikes in the coming months.
Speaker 1: because there is a general strike You suck at protesting also, by the way, right?
Speaker 0: I've got a country on earth is like way better at it than we are.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I have a Venezuelan co-workers.
Speaker 1: I see a lot of what's going on Venezuela.
Speaker 1: They know how to fucking protest.
Speaker 0: Yeah, hey Korea, right South Korea their whole cut big people don't realize this.
Speaker 0: right South Korea?
Speaker 0: After the Korean War what kind of government do you think South Korea had?
Speaker 0: basically a dictatorship is basically military Dictatorship.
Speaker 1: until when I want to say the late sing early 70s I want to say more.
Speaker 0: like the 80s right South Korea.
Speaker 0: now is democracy.
Speaker 0: ish, right?
Speaker 0: Yes, it's can.
Speaker 0: it's more you it's pretty conservative and you know, whatever.
Speaker 0: but they vote right is voting.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right.
Speaker 0: so That happened because of pretty much all the changes in the South Korean government for the better are due to student protests.
Speaker 0: Right, basically, you know, it's a small country, but almost everyone comes out.
Speaker 0: it's like Oh after work going down to the protest they all go and that's like.
Speaker 0: it's like the after work activity and Like the note.
Speaker 0: they get millions of people to shove to these things.
Speaker 1: Are you seeing little bits of that?
Speaker 1: but only in big cities like in New York?
Speaker 0: and the reason they do it Right is because they believe that it will work and then it does work, right?
Speaker 0: The government actually does something in response is why they do it, right?
Speaker 0: Here I don't think people believe everyone who even people who agree with it believe it will work and That also, you know not believing it will work makes it not work, but you're seeing it a little bit like bit.
Speaker 0: And also will it work?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I don't know if it'll work bit by bit like I'm seeing like in New York City at least like Spontaneous flash protests will spin up and get a lot many thousands of people in a hurry.
Speaker 0: People want to go.
Speaker 0: they just need someone to say where and when.
Speaker 0: they'll say it's definitely happening Like.
Speaker 0: you just need that reassurance that like yes, we're all like.
Speaker 0: it's like.
Speaker 0: imagine if like, you know, you forget protesting, right?
Speaker 0: You're gonna work and it's like you just want to leave.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and But it's like, you know, it's it's the day before Thanksgiving, right and it's like three and normally get out at five.
Speaker 0: But you're like, yeah, can I just leave it three because tomorrow's Thanksgiving, right?
Speaker 0: But like no one else is leaving.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but if someone else leaves first and it's like ah, yeah I can leave now.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna break the seal.
Speaker 0: you got to break the seal.
Speaker 0: So it's like everyone wants to leave.
Speaker 0: Oh, right, but the seal has to be broken.
Speaker 1: So, uh, just take note be ready.
Speaker 0: Most of the people listening are not people with jobs in America.
Speaker 0: I think Of Australia.
Speaker 0: if you take all of our listeners, I think that less than half of them are employed United States citizens.
Speaker 1: See I would have agreed 49% or less.
Speaker 1: I would agree with that eight or nine years ago.
Speaker 0: It could be 40% percent.
Speaker 1: a lot of our listeners Listen to us in high school, and I don't think I think you don't realize.
Speaker 0: a lot of students a lot of unemployed Americans you do not realize how old we are now saying.
Speaker 0: the students the unemployed people and the non-americans will be 51% Or more.
Speaker 1: we there are many people who were those kids a long time ago who are now adults with productive lives Whatever reason.
Speaker 0: they're still listening to that, you know, they got jobs.
Speaker 1: I think they got job.
Speaker 0: How do you know?
Speaker 1: Talk about him in the forum.
Speaker 1: Sometimes I know they're Americans, but it is you can definitely see based on who posts when Surprising number of Australians.
Speaker 1: and I think it's just because we went to multiple packs.
Speaker 0: Aussies like Australia is desperate for nerdery.
Speaker 0: We know this.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean we went there and like people line up for now Like they got no nerdery there.
Speaker 0: They don't have much of anything.
Speaker 0: I'd import everything including the podcast.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you want your Adventure Time backpack 140 bucks.
Speaker 0: Fuck you Here five bucks piece of shit.
Speaker 1: But anyway things Of the day, what do you got?
Speaker 0: So there's this guy?
Speaker 0: I mean, I hope you talked about him on the show before.
Speaker 0: his name is DJ hammers trains.
Speaker 0: I think it's just DJ hammers.
Speaker 0: You'll see him on like the New York subreddit.
Speaker 0: You'll see him on YouTube.
Speaker 0: You see him on to what you see him all over the place and he's basically the train nerd.
Speaker 0: God Right, like the Oda King was the king of anime nerds.
Speaker 0: This is the king of train nerds DJ hammers.
Speaker 0: He knows everything about subways and trains there is to know in New York, right?
Speaker 0: He is the master of that domain the number one most respected train nerd.
Speaker 0: So he has YouTube and usually his YouTube is like boring stuff.
Speaker 0: Like yeah, here's a train going.
Speaker 0: It's like okay.
Speaker 0: Yep, that it gives if you're a train nerd.
Speaker 0: You're loving the shit out of this, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, and occasionally you want a video like that.
Speaker 1: You're like, I wonder what's up with the W train?
Speaker 1: something something like.
Speaker 1: I got a video.
Speaker 0: It's like a video of like something I see every goddamn day.
Speaker 0: I don't need to watch it.
Speaker 0: But here's a video that showed up of something I hadn't seen which is if you don't know you probably don't.
Speaker 0: In New York City, there is a train called the S train.
Speaker 0: It's a shuttle.
Speaker 0: All it does is go to Grand Central and then it goes to Times Square and then it goes to Grand Central and then it Goes to Times Square.
Speaker 0: It's got three tracks.
Speaker 0: There's three trains just going back and forth back and forth back and forth.
Speaker 0: That's all they do, right?
Speaker 0: So it's really convenient for like tourists or if it's raining Or you know those kinds of situations and it takes two seconds and it's like a five-minute walk.
Speaker 0: It's like a one-minute train.
Speaker 0: So depending on where you happen to be standing.
Speaker 0: It's might be convenient.
Speaker 0: Whatever How do they get that train out of there?
Speaker 0: Right?
Speaker 0: It's like the train is stuck in this little back-and-forth track.
Speaker 0: Yep, how do they get it out to the train yard if they need to fix it?
Speaker 1: So if you've been in New York Wait, one thing you will know is that there is this weird area where there's all these like beams and plates and you see track Goes under that like you can walk on it And there's track that goes under it and goes over to the one train.
Speaker 0: So here's a video He found he went there DJ hammer.
Speaker 0: He's a train nerd at the time when they were getting that train out of there and removing the little floor, you know bridge Which is looks like a huge pain in the ass and they do it every few weeks Apparently and getting that as train out of there and then it's funny if you're a New Yorker to see the shuttle train Riding on the non shuttle track.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it'd be like if you saw the space shuttle riding down the highway.
Speaker 0: It's like it doesn't go there.
Speaker 1: I mean we did see the space shuttle fly over.
Speaker 0: There's a car in space.
Speaker 0: It's like a vehicle where it doesn't belong, right?
Speaker 1: Space is one cold motherfucker, right?
Speaker 1: So So this is a video.
Speaker 1: It's making the rounds yesterday and today it was posted.
Speaker 1: Looks like was posted actually today in the morning, but I saw it.
Speaker 0: It's real everyone's seen this.
Speaker 1: I don't think everyone's saying oh, it's all because even in my company's slack how many views it's got.
Speaker 1: It's already taken down.
Speaker 1: Right, it only got 40,000 views.
Speaker 0: I'm sure it's somewhere else to be seen.
Speaker 1: It got taken down hard.
Speaker 0: I'm sure you got it somewhere.
Speaker 1: This video contains content from Sony Pictures.
Speaker 0: Sony it'll be somewhere else.
Speaker 1: Anyway, I'll link to the verge article about it.
Speaker 1: But basically this video takes all the days from Groundhog Day, which is today.
Speaker 1: We were yeah, if you couldn't guess also the two groundhogs disagreed with each other.
Speaker 0: Yeah, of course shows you what they know.
Speaker 1: We got to go to the Groundhog Electoral College.
Speaker 0: now I'll go to my meteorologist.
Speaker 1: So it take there.
Speaker 1: so there's a similar video someone made.
Speaker 1: there's a Rick and Morty episode.
Speaker 1: where?
Speaker 1: Like the multiverse splits and all the alternate realities and you keep zooming around like all the different permutations But they overlaid them all to show you the care that was put into that scene.
Speaker 1: This is the same thing for the fantastic and brilliant movie Groundhog Day and it really highlights the ridiculous attention to detail They put into the overall theme and message of this movie.
Speaker 1: if you can find this video which was taken down in the last four hours By copyright, even though it's clearly fair use you can find it.
Speaker 1: You should definitely watch it because yeah, it only got 40,000 views for they haven't seen Groundhog Day.
Speaker 1: Seriously Yeah, if you haven't seen Groundhog Day I guess don't watch this video because it'll spoil the fuck out of that movie.
Speaker 1: But that movie is one of the classic movies for all time in my opinion And you should probably watch it if you've never watched it.
Speaker 1: It's real good.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's funny.
Speaker 0: It's also serious and interesting and dated a little bit.
Speaker 1: He was there.
Speaker 1: someone figured out that based on the stuff he did Definitely at least 37 years of repeating that day.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: That's the number they came up with.
Speaker 0: now I just spoil the move everybody.
Speaker 1: I think people can figure but I don't think that spoils it.
Speaker 1: His change of heart is what spoils it?
Speaker 1: In the moment the booklet book was Rebecca you can listen to the thing and watch the movie Rebecca.
Speaker 1: It's about Rebecca.
Speaker 1: I have not watched the movie yet.
Speaker 1: Mmm, but I did see it as a kid.
Speaker 1: I just have not watched it again since I read the book as an adult.
Speaker 1: But that was the book club book and I'm gonna pick the next book club book.
Speaker 1: I think I'm leaning toward Dune because I've never actually read the first Dune book all the way through.
Speaker 0: Neither did I only read like a chapter and it's like fuck this.
Speaker 1: But I know a lot about Dune and what I'm actually curious about is if I actually read the first Dune book.
Speaker 1: one How much do I actually know versus like?
Speaker 1: I think I know but I'm wrong.
Speaker 1: and two How much do I know?
Speaker 1: that's actually from later Dune books, which I've heard are not that great?
Speaker 0: Oh, really?
Speaker 0: So find out but I think how many Dune books are there?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I know there's a bunch like this post Dune.
Speaker 1: I But maybe maybe I'll make it do and I'm gonna decide soon.
Speaker 1: Otherwise, check out my youtube video my youtube channel.
Speaker 1: It's got youtube channel.
Speaker 1: We got a whole bunch of stuff up.
Speaker 1: a rockin new forum is not informed.
Speaker 1: our front row crew calm but community dot front row crew Kaka, it's no longer Greek in nature.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but forum dot front row crew calm is still up in stasis in perpetuity Every post until the end of the internet.
Speaker 1: Yep, or unless we both die and then our bank accounts run out If there's a ghost in the shell situation, don't worry.
Speaker 0: I'll bring it into cyber land.
Speaker 0: I'll port it over.
Speaker 1: and the video of our quitting panel our newest panel We did it at magfest is up on YouTube.
Speaker 1: You just watch it.
Speaker 1: And if you missed our Grinding panel at PAX South.
Speaker 1: Well, guess what?
Speaker 1: We also did it at PAX Prime and guess what video of that one is already on YouTube.
Speaker 0: the next conventions are PAX East where we are doing a panel on winning and then That's it.
Speaker 1: that's it until I guess packs unplugged and That's unplugged is after pecks west.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah pecks west, I guess Anime NYC is the same weekend as pecks unplugged.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and then after that I guess magfest.
Speaker 0: Are we gonna do that?
Speaker 0: a con are we gonna do kinetic on?
Speaker 1: I'm gonna I'll probably I think I will remain the head of the panels department.
Speaker 0: I've seen kinek on making some movements.
Speaker 1: Yep, the the sleeping giant is rumbling.
Speaker 1: I'm guy have emails in my queue.
Speaker 1: I have to respond to.
Speaker 1: Actually panel submissions are open But if you go to the website, it still says kinetic on 2016 like everywhere.
Speaker 1: But cuz I have no control over that.
Speaker 1: but trust me panel submissions are open.
Speaker 1: I will link to it.
Speaker 1: just start fucking submitting panels and I'll take care of it.
Speaker 1: Trust me and Regardless of what the website might say about how comp badges work for panelists I will assure you they will work the same way.
Speaker 1: They always have regardless of any language you might see somewhere.
Speaker 1: And yeah, can I count?
Speaker 1: I guess that's the one we forgot.
Speaker 1: So I guess it's safe to assume by now that you've all seen Star Wars.
Speaker 1: Rogue One.
Speaker 0: I mean if you're a nerd you see everything you.
Speaker 0: if something is Star Wars and it's official style Like you see it within 48 hours of it coming out.
Speaker 0: You're on that shit nowadays.
Speaker 0: I like that.
Speaker 0: It's pretty much every Christmas.
Speaker 0: There's a Star Wars something.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so now every create I don't you know, even if it comes out a couple weeks before then I just every Christmas.
Speaker 0: now I'm going to Star Wars.
Speaker 0: It's just like oh you've locked this in for me.
Speaker 0: Now.
Speaker 1: It's life is so convenient yep, so We're just gonna assume you saw it.
Speaker 1: Like we're not gonna worry about spoilers.
Speaker 0: so I guess if you somehow didn't you can't spoil this if you've seen Star Wars Episode 4 because it's direct prequel to Star Wars Episode 4 it's the events that took place right before it.
Speaker 1: like immediately right before you could spoil a few notes.
Speaker 1: Like I did not know some things that happened in it, of course, but we're assuming you saw it.
Speaker 1: We're not gonna explain the plot to you.
Speaker 0: So the plot has problems, but not too many though.
Speaker 1: Yeah I think I don't think the plot problems are actually too far out of the realm of every other mainline Star Wars movie.
Speaker 0: No, no, I mean how many things did they just explain with like, you know magic, right?
Speaker 0: It's like you're gonna.
Speaker 0: you're gonna just believe.
Speaker 0: you're gonna.
Speaker 0: you're gonna allow this believe in the force But you're not gonna believe in some other plot hole, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like come on, but overall I liked it a lot.
Speaker 1: I actually liked it a lot more than the force awakens.
Speaker 0: I also liked it more than force awakens and more than prequel movies But not more than any real Star Wars movie.
Speaker 1: I think it's real close to being tied for the third best Star Wars movie, though I think it's real close.
Speaker 0: No It's like.
Speaker 0: so there's the three real Star Wars movies.
Speaker 1: cuz honestly Empire Strikes Back is actually my favorite Star Wars movie.
Speaker 0: I think it's always hard to say I like.
Speaker 0: see the thing is a lot of you like.
Speaker 1: I first react a lot.
Speaker 1: then I watch A New Hope again, and I'm just like, oh, yeah I think part of this.
Speaker 0: I think really we're not disagreeing here too much about the quality level of Rogue one so much as we're disagreeing about the quality level of Return of the Jedi true, which I like way more.
Speaker 0: Then I might even be my number one, right?
Speaker 0: Because it's like people always think about you walks and I don't hate you walks First of all, but they forget about B wings and I fucking act bar, right?
Speaker 0: And also I made Oh being awesome.
Speaker 0: Just the Emperor.
Speaker 0: The Emperor is my guy.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: You see those red guys, right?
Speaker 0: It's like come on you forgot that fire was in that movie.
Speaker 0: It's like that's the best shit right there Anyway, but meanwhile, so basically three real Star Wars movies.
Speaker 0: then there's a big gap.
Speaker 0: then there's still.
Speaker 0: you're still in decent movie territory and you got the rogue one and then you've got the Force away.
Speaker 0: force awakens and not too far behind it.
Speaker 0: really, you know I mean you got another big gap and then you got all the garbage but they go backwards.
Speaker 1: then it's episode 3 then episode 2 Then episode 1, uh, you know Maybe this will be controversial.
Speaker 1: I mean both awful way which Both read carefully.
Speaker 0: So episode 3 is obviously the best of the three shitty prequel movies.
Speaker 1: So you're gonna say that 2 is better than 1.
Speaker 1: I'm going to say the one is better than 2.
Speaker 0: that yes 1 & 2 are both crap.
Speaker 1: Yeah - yet - is worse than 1.
Speaker 0: I was forced to watch one.
Speaker 0: I would watch Phantom Menace rather than clone whatever.
Speaker 1: Here's the problem - has higher highs than one did But it also has way lower lows.
Speaker 1: Mmm, maybe cuz 2 has some decent.
Speaker 0: anyway, we're here to talk about just Rogue One now, not all Star Wars.
Speaker 1: So I'm putting Rogue One way closer to Empire Strikes Back So in Rogue and way closer than Return of the Jedi, right?
Speaker 0: So in Rogue One, you basically have like a lot of stuff going on.
Speaker 0: That is like these nostalgic callbacks that are like simultaneously good and bad.
Speaker 1: I would say that the majority of them are really subtle and really good in that they were.
Speaker 1: So if you're a Star Wars nerd you're like But it doesn't get in the way it's just artistic right.
Speaker 0: some of those are but like.
Speaker 0: there's a handful.
Speaker 0: There's the guys that are like, I don't like you.
Speaker 0: I was about to say that's the only doesn't like you either.
Speaker 0: Right
Speaker 1: is
Speaker 0: the bad one and to their credit I actually when I saw that scene I was like,
Speaker 1: uh,
Speaker 0: but then I laughed well And then I actually forgot that scene was in the movie until someone mentioned it and then I was like Oh, you made me remember that awful part of the movie that awful five-second scene or whatever Right.
Speaker 0: So all the shit that was like that was like distasteful.
Speaker 1: I think there's very little of that though I think most of those callbacks were very artistically done.
Speaker 1: Yeah So anyway them because they did make sure like they tied the plot of this movie to you know Basically, they were foreshadowing the fact that this movie would literally fucking end with the minutes leading up to the opening of episode 4 Which I knew.
Speaker 1: this was like the story of how they got the plans.
Speaker 1: What I did not expect at all was the direct like second.
Speaker 0: Oh really?
Speaker 1: continuity at the end.
Speaker 0: Oh, I know I basically knew that as soon as I knew them I didn't know the movie was about getting the plans.
Speaker 0: I like all I knew about the movie going to see.
Speaker 0: it was like it's called rogue one.
Speaker 0: It's gonna be all about x-wings and shit.
Speaker 0: cuz you know rogue leader, right?
Speaker 0: Yes I thought I was thinking about Rogue Squadron and all this other nerdy Star Wars knowledge I had and I was just like I was Ready for x-wings.
Speaker 0: and then it's like oh, it's about that still has x-wings though But it's about that.
Speaker 0: and then I'm like, oh I'm like they're going to get the plans and the immediately think How does r2d2 get the plans?
Speaker 0: Yeah, and it's like.
Speaker 1: so you're trying back.
Speaker 1: You're just the whole movie You're watching right in time and you're thinking from the beginning of episode 4.
Speaker 1: Where's the link, right?
Speaker 0: I'm like, I'm basically like oh How is how are these plans that they're going to obviously get?
Speaker 0: because I know they get them.
Speaker 0: I already know the end of the movie, right?
Speaker 0: How did they get into r2d2's body?
Speaker 0: and then I'm pretty much like as soon as I see they're having scenes like Mon Mothma And then I see and then I already knew I'm like, oh they're gonna like end the movie right at that.
Speaker 0: They're gonna end the movie with that.
Speaker 0: and then you got scenes with like Leia's dad leaving to go to Alderaan or whatever.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and I'm like, oh, okay.
Speaker 0: I mean, I think the thing is because I'm a nerd.
Speaker 0: I Realized that that was Leia's adopted dad.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and other people did not know that so they wouldn't write.
Speaker 0: It's like you get.
Speaker 0: I guess being a Star Wars nerd makes the movie see.
Speaker 1: so that's it those.
Speaker 0: see I'm not even a crazy Star Wars nerd I just know as much as a nerd does and not as much as a Thing.
Speaker 1: those scenes.
Speaker 1: when I went into the movie I knew the linkage but as the movie went on But I kept pushing the point where I thought the movie would end in the Star Wars world Further and further toward episode 4.
Speaker 0: I knew I mean I knew pretty as soon as I realized it I knew it would end at that.
Speaker 1: but what I really appreciated was the fact, you know, like they all die Which I didn't know I sort of have to all die.
Speaker 0: There's no there's no they have to otherwise ever so they would have to be in episode 4.
Speaker 1: Well, yeah, you there were since there's this possibility in the attack on Yavin.
Speaker 0: if they were not dead, of course Maybe they were.
Speaker 1: no they weren't.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but they weren't because they all died.
Speaker 0: but it could have been You wouldn't?
Speaker 0: you wouldn't fly Porkins if you could fly those people.
Speaker 0: Yeah, okay You only got so many x-wings and your little rebel, you know pathetic band, right?
Speaker 1: the way the movie did it that last scene is probably my favorite scene in the movie because it just is this like like the Climax of the movie is the nuke is destroying the planet basically.
Speaker 1: and then you just see this long Denim on of like the chain of custody of that hard drive all the way through to literally Carrie Fisher Fisher standing there the second
Speaker 0: big Yeah,
Speaker 1: yeah she worked better than the target like half the time worked and half the time like would turn his head and like I Saw the skin on his nose like move a weird way,
Speaker 0: right?
Speaker 0: So let's talk about these CG people.
Speaker 0: I see a lot of people praising the CG people and no doubt Half of Tarkin was like perfect like for a second.
Speaker 1: I was like, holy shit, and then I was like, oh, right CG.
Speaker 0: So there is no doubt that that CG that was used for those the two characters was better than any Recreated character that has previously been made and I'm sure the people who made it worked very hard and are great animators.
Speaker 0: good job.
Speaker 0: We did the best you could with the technology that we have in the year 2016.
Speaker 0: I applaud you.
Speaker 0: However It's still obviously not a real person.
Speaker 0: Tarkin worked For a few seconds because he's in the dark.
Speaker 0: They put him in the dark to me and it worked when he was in the dark But as soon as like they showed light on his face, it's like obviously a digital person not a real person.
Speaker 1: I would say he worked you did not cross.
Speaker 0: you failed to cross the uncanny valley Which I can't blame you for because no one's crossed it ever.
Speaker 1: No, he worked in the light too But only when he was talking and not if he turned his head.
Speaker 1: the problem is that?
Speaker 0: the main problem?
Speaker 0: With doing it this way is not that it was necessarily bad.
Speaker 0: It's that when you watch this shit again in ten years, it'll be remastered.
Speaker 1: You either have to redo it because I guarantee every Will not hold up.
Speaker 0: However, right?
Speaker 0: This is why you know, normally I'm like, you know a technology person like hey Use the computer is the best right?
Speaker 0: Why would you do?
Speaker 0: Why would you make models like they did in the old days, right?
Speaker 0: And the reason the models work, you know It's like why go through the effort of the stupid models and you could use the computer.
Speaker 0: It's because those models still hold up.
Speaker 0: You never have to update it.
Speaker 0: It's just still looks great.
Speaker 0: No matter what year it is Right, whereas the computer shit.
Speaker 0: go watch some Tron or something.
Speaker 0: even the super advanced can watch Toy Story 1. now, man Looks like PlayStation.
Speaker 0: It's like it doesn't look as bad as PlayStation 1. like it's not good if you watch right, but you know.
Speaker 0: So it's like that's you know, you think of Toy Story 1 came out.
Speaker 0: It blew everyone away and it doesn't hold up.
Speaker 0: So this even though it blew some people away will not hold up.
Speaker 1: So I also think I noticed something.
Speaker 1: people this is purely anecdotal people who didn't watch it in 3d.
Speaker 1: They worked way better.
Speaker 0: I did not see it in 3d.
Speaker 1: I saw it in 3d.
Speaker 0: I huge I'm parking skin not because I'm not because I'm anti 3d but because you know My mom would want to see in 3d and also in Connecticut the non 3d.
Speaker 0: the 2d ticket is so cheap It was like we want to see it at the fancy 84 street.
Speaker 0: This is like $8 like I. basically we had so much extra money.
Speaker 0: You could just buy a giant pile of quite a night even get.
Speaker 1: we won't go to the theater anymore Unless it's either like a fancy theater showing something weird like the kids the New York International Children's Film Festival or something The 84th Street fancy theater or one of those like dinner and drink the.
Speaker 0: I only go to special showings and Star Wars.
Speaker 1: So the Nighthawk theater has good stuff.
Speaker 1: Like they'll do like midnight showings of vampire hunter D with like for real food.
Speaker 0: But yeah, so what else about this movie?
Speaker 0: So the movie's got some plot holes.
Speaker 0: You though they'd like and it has a lot of things that are kind of ridiculous and you started to push out of your Brain, the only ridiculous one is how the fuck did those two?
Speaker 1: I don't like you people get the fuck off that planet.
Speaker 1: No, no quick is that?
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: So here you go.
Speaker 0: So why is like the data stored like this physical hard drive?
Speaker 1: because So look today if I want to give you a terabyte of data I could give it to you on this tiny ass little disk.
Speaker 0: Why does it like look like a hard drive but then they can beam it and then it's on this little disk And they have to hand off and then stick physically and RDD.
Speaker 0: it's like.
Speaker 0: so Imagine their data storage doesn't make sense.
Speaker 1: Here's how.
Speaker 1: here's the way the thing is.
Speaker 1: it is rationalizable for a lot of reasons.
Speaker 1: for one Look at how fucking janky half the technology in the Star Wars universe is at this time in the air.
Speaker 1: I mean they have like these amazing technological capabilities and lightsabers and all these fighters and everything.
Speaker 1: and yet the Holographic projection capabilities are like worse than what we have today.
Speaker 0: Okay, so here's another thing, right?
Speaker 1: So the fidelity of data transmission is shit in that universe.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: So the the dad right he put.
Speaker 0: he built a weakness into the station and he had to hide it deep.
Speaker 1: So the only place that data was was in like the fully unrendered like like anyway He said he said a message to his daughter and he was just like.
Speaker 0: he's like.
Speaker 0: there's a way to go.
Speaker 0: get the instructions.
Speaker 0: I had to blow this up.
Speaker 0: He could have just told her here's how to blow it up.
Speaker 1: No, I don't think he could because I think the instructions were actually very detailed instructions.
Speaker 0: Okay, however The plans fit as we saw on a little a thing that looked like basically a PlayStation Portable UMD disk right as far or a mini disk, right?
Speaker 0: It's what it looked like when they were handing it off at the end, right?
Speaker 0: It was not large.
Speaker 0: It was in fact not significantly different in size from the holographic message.
Speaker 0: He could have just sent that data and they wouldn't had to go to the planet and fight a battle to get it.
Speaker 1: I will bet he did not have access to that data because he made the data.
Speaker 1: if it's a military system with an air gap Probably that data is only accessible physically at that location.
Speaker 1: I'm just saying Couldn't smuggle the data.
Speaker 0: the place that they went to get the data from was like the archive.
Speaker 0: That'd be like going to the Library of Congress to get it.
Speaker 1: No It'd be more like remember in Mission Impossible Where they he goes into the server room that has no connection to the outside world to steal some data.
Speaker 1: It's that situation.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm that data had to be created somewhere else.
Speaker 0: it the person who made the data wasn't in that room.
Speaker 1: Ah, that data was probably created in an air gap facility of some kind and then pieces of it were rendered out as needed.
Speaker 1: I'm just saying I can.
Speaker 1: it is possible to nerd rationalize that way easier than some shit that happens.
Speaker 0: episode 4 5 You're saying you got to jump through some hoops.
Speaker 1: It's there is no plot point except for how did those two like serial killing?
Speaker 1: Bar-dwelling monsters get off of that planet in time.
Speaker 0: Okay, so here's some other shit, right?
Speaker 0: So, uh Characters right the droid.
Speaker 0: It's the best car.
Speaker 1: Oh my god.
Speaker 1: He was the best ever like I want.
Speaker 1: Yeah, why don't I get a phaser or a blaster like that was my favorite line of his.
Speaker 1: why don't I get a blaster?
Speaker 0: Anyway, he was like the best character.
Speaker 0: like that's the person you want to buy.
Speaker 1: an action figure Won't even tell them that he's in trouble.
Speaker 1: He's just like shooting stormtrooper Nazis over his shoulder while he's like sacrificing his life taking out the data, right?
Speaker 0: So that guy's awesome.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: However, a lot of the other characters are kind of like.
Speaker 0: I don't really care about you, right?
Speaker 1: I cared about pilot guy main girl.
Speaker 0: I Cared about droid guy.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and you know what I cared about Mon Mothma.
Speaker 0: Yeah I mean, I already cared about Mon Mothma in advance.
Speaker 1: I care about my mouth.
Speaker 1: as a kid I was obsessed with Mon Mothma.
Speaker 0: I was a gender Donna like who is that guy?
Speaker 0: And now I know now I know his name without having to look it up every time.
Speaker 0: I was like who is that guy?
Speaker 0: He wasn't in the movie until now.
Speaker 0: What does he do?
Speaker 1: My biggest my three biggest obsessions were in order.
Speaker 1: number one Boba Fett.
Speaker 1: Number two the red guys red guys.
Speaker 0: number one.
Speaker 1: number three Mon Mothma.
Speaker 1: I was like she's in charge.
Speaker 1: Like what's her deal?
Speaker 1: Why?
Speaker 1: what's going on?
Speaker 1: How the rub?
Speaker 1: What's the structure?
Speaker 0: Mon Mothma the movie 2023.
Speaker 1: I'll watch it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's maybe the best one But I want to see Akbar the movie.
Speaker 0: so I noticed something.
Speaker 1: the whole movie the whole Star Wars episode 30 Notice something really interesting and I suspect it's on purpose and some Star Wars nerd Probably can figure this out way better than I can.
Speaker 1: so, you know the red guys, right?
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm there.
Speaker 1: What are they?
Speaker 0: They're the Imperial like guards.
Speaker 0: They're like they'd like the high bird like the Emperor's personal dude like the Secret Service Basically, so did you notice that?
Speaker 1: you know, the Jedi religion is defunct in rogue one?
Speaker 1: Yes but there are people.
Speaker 1: try like we have a couple characters who are trying to keep the remnants of it alive and there are Obviously like it is still a religion.
Speaker 1: It's just the religion does not have it's not it's not completely forgotten.
Speaker 0: people remember it.
Speaker 0: It is no it is a religion, but there are not practitioners like if it's right.
Speaker 0: It's like if there are people who still believed or knew about Catholicism and like, you know, but the church is gone But there's no Pope and there's no church.
Speaker 0: and there's no.
Speaker 0: you know, there's no church.
Speaker 1: You can't go to church in town that many of the people Proselytizing in the streets of Jeddah We're dressed in.
Speaker 1: they were dressed in ways that are really evocative of what those red guys dress like.
Speaker 1: Mmm, I wonder if those red guys There's probably like some other religion.
Speaker 1: Oh, no that that's like.
Speaker 0: the dark side is a different.
Speaker 0: religion believes in the force.
Speaker 1: It's like easily say that the red guys like the church.
Speaker 1: the church of the of this stuff still existed but only an imperial Precincts for like Darth Vader and all that nonsense in its ceremony for church.
Speaker 1: Yeah But basically that that I know.
Speaker 0: I want to believe in the Sith Church, but I think you're just stretching it now.
Speaker 1: but why was that type of regalia and garb shown multiple times by the remnants of the Jedi religion.
Speaker 0: as it looks it looks Star Wars II Yeah, and it ties.
Speaker 1: it doesn't matter why.
Speaker 1: the fact is that continuity was there and I saw it.
Speaker 0: So I do like how they kept.
Speaker 0: like the whole thing with the crystals, right?
Speaker 0: It's like I knew that right.
Speaker 0: as soon as they're like, oh, yeah, they need crystals.
Speaker 0: I'm like, yeah, you need the crystals that you make lightsabers with.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's what you need.
Speaker 0: It's like oh they kept.
Speaker 0: they totally kept that.
Speaker 0: so if you're a nerd you knew it already.
Speaker 0: And also right.
Speaker 0: so Donnie Yen.
Speaker 0: He's my guy.
Speaker 0: in most movies like it man an iron monkey Like.
Speaker 0: I love this guy.
Speaker 0: He's good.
Speaker 0: But in this movie, I didn't like his character so much.
Speaker 1: I like that guy.
Speaker 0: Okay, I like him right as actor but his character I didn't like cuz I felt it was sort of like Stereotypical mystical martial arts Asian guy.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like oh the blind master and it seemed like a caricature.
Speaker 0: And I was sort of like man.
Speaker 0: and also he didn't his you didn't have like a personality.
Speaker 0: That made me like him the way the the droid did right the little that you saw of his character.
Speaker 0: I wish that he would have had like a like a pi may kind of character or even though he's even pi maze even more Of a stereotype.
Speaker 0: at least pi may is so fucking badass.
Speaker 0: you love him and just want to see him.
Speaker 0: all the time.
Speaker 1: They hinted at all the backstories and relationships between these sets of characters without showing them to you.
Speaker 1: So the problem is if you're like if you watch these characters you like them at all.
Speaker 1: You kind of want to know what their deals are and you don't get to see any of that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I want to know.
Speaker 0: I want to know the droids deal is but I don't want to know what else's deal is yeah, but then again, I do think though the A big part of Star Wars as a whole is.
Speaker 1: here's the character.
Speaker 1: They seem cool.
Speaker 1: You don't know their deal and you never fucking find out their deal.
Speaker 0: Right?
Speaker 0: Well, there's the I Forget his name, right?
Speaker 0: He's the guy who was like even more to rebel for anybody.
Speaker 0: He rescued the girl at the beginning Oh, yeah, you know.
Speaker 0: and then he was like the basically like crazy.
Speaker 1: I saw a good critique from a writer about how he was a weirdly like Appropriative of Black Panther like black resistance movements in that.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah that guy happens to be the one who's too extreme for the rebels.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's true.
Speaker 0: He definitely seemed like a character I had seen before in that role in many other Soon like he could have escaped with them and help fight.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and he just gave up for no reason.
Speaker 0: That is also true.
Speaker 0: He seemed a lot like, you know, like he gave up way too kind of any seven with a gun for a hand.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, it's like the same exact character.
Speaker 0: Basically you've seen a hundred times before Barrett, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, exactly, but Even though that's all true.
Speaker 0: I think he's this character.
Speaker 0: I like the second most because he at least was interesting and also he was fighting the Nazis while everyone else was equivocating.
Speaker 1: Sure, he was like, I'm a fight with my weird slug brain monster.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah the slug brain was.
Speaker 0: that was just weird.
Speaker 0: It's like Star Wars II nonsense.
Speaker 0: It is.
Speaker 0: it is Star Wars II nonsense, right?
Speaker 0: It's like Java thought just has this monster this guy.
Speaker 0: He just has a monster.
Speaker 0: Yeah, people just have monsters but that monsters that are useful to them.
Speaker 0: That is the I mean saga has that to lion cat.
Speaker 1: that is the primary Character plot hole that bothered me was that he the like the fighter the person who is like fighting above all else.
Speaker 0: Final Fantasy 4.
Speaker 1: I do like Final Fantasy 4, but the fact that that dude just fucking gives up that the same thing.
Speaker 1: No, this check this guy just gives up.
Speaker 0: I'll open this door for you.
Speaker 1: Yeah But he doesn't sacrifice like he doesn't.
Speaker 1: it's not like he blows himself up to let them all escape.
Speaker 1: He just doesn't escape with them.
Speaker 1: Well, his body was old He was not in good health, but he decided to give up right then right when like something there's a real chance.
Speaker 0: I guess he figured like, you know this is the reason I was staying alive with this unhealthy painful uncomfortable body was to accomplish this.
Speaker 0: and now that you've got now that You're here and I've given you the thing you've gotten away.
Speaker 0: now I don't have to bother staying alive anymore and living a suffering horrible life Maybe pain.
Speaker 1: you could have fought a little bit longer.
Speaker 0: But even though I just said that that was not clear in the movie Yeah, he didn't express like.
Speaker 0: oh, he didn't say like, you know have a little monologue.
Speaker 0: We're like, yeah, listen I'm living every day the shitty ass body.
Speaker 0: It's very I'm just trying to stay alive so I could get this message.
Speaker 0: Now that I have I can die in peace.
Speaker 1: It would be very on the Star Wars to have the characters all express their motivations that succinctly.
Speaker 1: Yes Like that would literally ruin.
Speaker 1: like.
Speaker 1: and think about episode 4. obi-wan like.
Speaker 1: his motivations are not a hundred percent.
Speaker 0: Well, that's exactly what obi-wan did do.
Speaker 0: obi-wan is like, yeah, that's all right.
Speaker 0: Luke's got this.
Speaker 0: I can die now.
Speaker 0: Yep I'll die so you can get away.
Speaker 1: but he did it with subtlety and actin.
Speaker 0: just by what he turns looks at Luke because the Obi-wan was a thousand times better actor than anyone.
Speaker 1: this day whenever I watch episode 4 There's that one moment where Ben Kenobi raises the eyebrow and all I can think is wow You can fucking act and no one else in this movie can really do it.
Speaker 0: No, Harrison Ford a little bit a little bit but old.
Speaker 1: but Harrison Ford kind of plays the same dude most of the time.
Speaker 0: Yes, but he can do it But only Ben Kenobi and also as great actors Alec Guinness is.
Speaker 0: he doesn't play too many different dudes.
Speaker 0: Go watch like was it?
Speaker 0: bridge over the river qua is the one he's in or is it?
Speaker 0: I think that's the one he's in.
Speaker 0: Let me check.
Speaker 0: Yeah, where he's he's?
Speaker 0: uh, you know, he's an army guy.
Speaker 0: him and Peter Cushing are like the actors Cushing the same actor also and everything go watch Dracula and it's just like oh look, it's grandma truck in the vampire.
Speaker 1: But I think what another thing I really appreciate about this movie was that you watch episode 4 and There's you know, it starts in media res with a certain sense of urgency but then it does it sort of rambling around the fact that this movie sort of adds this like Really extra sense of urgency like
Speaker 0: his bridge over there require.
Speaker 0: I was right.
Speaker 1: the fact that like you could just put these two movies together and It's just like what the fuck how they gonna stop the Death Star like oh my god Like it sort of implies this huge chain of constant urgency Throughout like leading up to the destruction of the Death Star at the end of episode 4 That you wouldn't have gotten without a prequel like this.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm cuz episode 4 could have been like long build up and plans are found and then like oh we get him.
Speaker 1: and now like the urge like it felt like the rebels had The initiative and the Death Star came out of them in reaction to that.
Speaker 1: But you watch this movie and now it's.
Speaker 1: no the Nazis like the Death Star is on its way real fucking quick and like you Got a move.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: All I wanted to do when the credits rolled was immediately watch episode 4 like I felt this powerful urge.
Speaker 1: Yeah, immediately.
Speaker 1: the main complaint I saw from people that seemed legitimate But I actually have a counterpoint to it was a lot of people were saying the soundtrack was uninspired Lame boring not up to the John Williams stand.
Speaker 1: It wasn't John Williams.
Speaker 0: So first of all, wasn't it John Williams?
Speaker 1: No Oh, I thought it was.
Speaker 1: it was Michael Giacchino.
Speaker 0: Also, I heard this is apparently as far as I know this is true.
Speaker 0: John Williams has never watched a Star Wars movie.
Speaker 1: I Will not make any comment on that.
Speaker 0: that's what I heard but anyway until I verify cuz I don't know I mostly agree with those people.
Speaker 0: there were a few moments right but there was.
Speaker 0: no I can't hum for you a goddamn song.
Speaker 1: So I did agree, but I noticed something and I have not.
Speaker 1: yet I get to listen to the rogue one soundtrack.
Speaker 1: I did own on Spotify and think about this.
Speaker 1: I have this feeling cuz I noticed something.
Speaker 1: people complained that the soundtrack was muddy and That it didn't have a lot of in that it didn't have a lot of strong clear melodies.
Speaker 0: Yes it was doesn't definitely doesn't have the strong clear melody.
Speaker 1: but something I noticed was that the way it seemed to work is it had all these motifs sort of blended together all the time and They would occasionally edge toward a more recognizable Star Wars theme and but in an edge away, right?
Speaker 1: It's like like they'd be like it's almost gonna be Leia's team.
Speaker 0: You know, it's No, even the actual Star Wars soundtrack.
Speaker 0: go listen to like the episode 5 soundtrack Yeah, and you'll be listening to like Yoda's theme.
Speaker 0: and in Yoda's theme They're like hint it like, you know some you know, main Star Wars Right.
Speaker 0: It's like they're coming in all the time in every song, right?
Speaker 0: It's like you'll hear.
Speaker 0: you know Imperial March sneak its way in.
Speaker 0: you hear a little right, you know.
Speaker 1: What actually does that?
Speaker 0: And I'm gonna say it even though it was the same movie.
Speaker 1: so Undertale score does that equally well to Star Wars.
Speaker 0: that's interesting, but that's like.
Speaker 1: the main reason to play Undertale is the soundtrack the This movie right.
Speaker 0: it sneaks in even less.
Speaker 0: It's not even like motif.
Speaker 0: It's like an extra light.
Speaker 0: I think that's on purpose even if it's on purpose.
Speaker 0: I don't like it.
Speaker 0: I have a purpose is good.
Speaker 1: Sure I don't know if this is true and I have not even like tried to verify this either by listening and figuring out of my Own or by reading what other people have written.
Speaker 1: my suspicion is that Giacchino?
Speaker 1: Tried to do too much with it.
Speaker 1: It sounds to me like this soundtrack was purposefully muddy and purposely like Evoking Star Wars, but not being Star Wars even as a long I'd rather I don't like that as a long slow Musical build-up to like.
Speaker 1: the themes of Star Wars are still resolving themselves Because they eventually resolve.
Speaker 1: at the very end of this movie you get the Star Wars theme.
Speaker 1: It's like all these factors all these people all these circumstances have to come together to make the Star Wars happen
Speaker 0: And I
Speaker 1: I would guess that Michael Giacchino Was just trying to be too clever in a way that the vast majority audience would not get and that even if you get it You might appreciate the effort but not appreciate the result
Speaker 0: the X if even if that was the plan, right?
Speaker 0: it's like it doesn't matter because Execution it didn't work.
Speaker 1: now I like the soundtrack and it did work for me But only because I felt like it resolved into the strong themes Right at the end of the also.
Speaker 0: that would have worked better if episode this is a star wars didn't exist.
Speaker 1: because right Oh, I'm pretending they don't as far as I don't and this is the first Star Wars.
Speaker 1: Yeah I just died.
Speaker 1: This was so much better than them.
Speaker 0: You know the other problem and this is I think the biggest problem with this movie There is no opening crawl on this movie.
Speaker 1: that's because this is not a mainline Star Wars movie.
Speaker 1: It is a Star Wars story.
Speaker 0: I don't give a fuck.
Speaker 1: My the bigger concern is if episode if episode seven eight eight Starts right where six four seven left off Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: What are they gonna put in that crawl?
Speaker 1: You just watched a movie and now we're going to continue with the next scene.
Speaker 0: I mean they could just sum up the events of.
Speaker 0: I mean It says in the crawl of any Star Wars movie Don't remember offhand cuz you just don't like yeah, you ever actually read those things?
Speaker 0: You just need the yellow words to go past.
Speaker 0: They could be drunk and gibberish.
Speaker 0: You don't even care.
Speaker 0: And the reason the crawl didn't go by you know, why is?
Speaker 0: because we just talked about this.
Speaker 0: It's a Star Wars story because the soundtrack they couldn't.
Speaker 1: they want to put that song there Yeah, but you couldn't because it wasn't Star Wars yet.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you can put the song there.
Speaker 1: This is the precursor to Star Wars.
Speaker 0: You can put the song there.
Speaker 1: If you put the song there wouldn't worked.
Speaker 0: I'd say it worked and you didn't even have no Imperial March going on.
Speaker 0: It's like come on you had no so and you had a dark sound.
Speaker 0: Liz remember think back to what I'm gonna do in.
Speaker 0: James Oh Jones is dead.
Speaker 0: He's old man.
Speaker 0: He's old.
Speaker 1: think back to episode four or don't die Five.
Speaker 1: there's this note like a musical note.
Speaker 1: not a. not a note like a see but like a note like a court.
Speaker 1: There's this musical Accent that happens whenever we cut to a scene where Imperial bullshit is happening And they use that in Rogue One.
Speaker 1: They took the notes from the later Star Wars, but not the theme.
Speaker 0: I'd rather just play the Imperial March.
Speaker 1: So I think that I think this movie did really well is If I think about the things that young rim cared about in Star Wars like the things that I would obsess over and want to see more of
Speaker 0: lightsabers X-wing
Speaker 1: x-wings
Speaker 0: Emperor
Speaker 1: like there's this big shield and I'm just like, oh, how's that work?
Speaker 1: What's going on with that shield?
Speaker 1: So he's gonna crash into.
Speaker 1: let's have Star Destroyers crash into each other.
Speaker 0: Lots of pew pew pew.
Speaker 1: when the Star Destroyer started crashing into the other Star Destroyer.
Speaker 1: I imagine young rim That's the kind of scene young rim would flip the fuck.
Speaker 0: once you get to that part of the movie.
Speaker 0: This definitely delivers on the pew pew pew more than any other Star Wars movie.
Speaker 1: and they did it right cuz they introduced What.
Speaker 1: do you have any of it?
Speaker 1: Is there a hammerhead?
Speaker 0: The one part of the movie where I was mad legit excited because there was so much pew pew pew Such high quality pew pew pew.
Speaker 0: I was just like, oh, baby Yeah, the red everything with everything was bad and everything was accurate to the nerdiness that I already knew.
Speaker 0: Yep, it was just feeding my fanboy for pew pew and I was like eating it all up like oh, I'm giving more.
Speaker 0: that like.
Speaker 1: I think if rogue one had come out like When I was a kid and stuck if rogue one had come out the year that episode one came out instead I feel like Star Wars fervor in the world would be like ten times what is like Star Wars The biggest thing
Speaker 0: ever.
Speaker 0: Oh my glob was Peter Cushing alive when this episode one came.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like yeah Maybe Peter Cushing.
Speaker 1: When did he die?
Speaker 1: Let's see Peter Cushing 90 or 2,000 something 1994.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you really he would have been too old.
Speaker 1: Oh Well, Oh prostate cancer.
Speaker 0: Mmm.
Speaker 1: Hey made it 81 in bed.
Speaker 1: I'll take 81 I'll take 81 and prostate cancer if I could.
Speaker 0: yeah, they're way worse ways to go.
Speaker 0: I'll tell you so overall You if you're a nerd see this movie that Star Wars.
Speaker 0: if you're not a nerd I mean, you'll probably still see this movie.
Speaker 0: So we had a little extra like this podcast either cried at the end hard No, you got problems.
Speaker 1: Well, so one.
Speaker 1: it was a really emotional and I think was good the fact that you know The death happened.
Speaker 0: I didn't care about them dying.
Speaker 1: Normal movies end on that scene and this one.
Speaker 1: the music just kept playing and you got that long Montage of the chain of custody of those plans, but I saw the movie after Carrie Fisher died.
Speaker 0: So I did not.
Speaker 1: I was a hammer blow that I did not expect.
Speaker 0: I expected it.
Speaker 1: But yeah Part of me said yeah, I don't see it.
Speaker 1: after that part of me said like it ends with Leia getting the plans But then actually seeing Leia on screen saying hope Right after she had died suddenly.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you saw.
Speaker 0: I thought you said you see it right away.
Speaker 0: I saw before you.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I waited cuz I was busy not a town and stuff.
Speaker 1: But I saw it reasonably right away.
Speaker 1: I saw it over the whole New Year's holiday area but the whole audience when she appeared on a screen like you heard everyone just like Like everybody got choked up.
Speaker 0: I mean, it's easy to write that but it works.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's why you do it, right?
Speaker 0: It's like any.
Speaker 0: that's how writers do.
Speaker 0: if I was a writer I do that same cheap shit.
Speaker 0: cuz it's good.
Speaker 0: Why wouldn't you do that?
Speaker 0: It's not hard to come up with it's easy to see through but it don't matter.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and that's why the same kind of things I'm saying.
Speaker 0: Otherwise, like don't try too hard on that music Just play the fucking imperial march.
Speaker 0: It works.
Speaker 0: Just take the easy road.
Speaker 1: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott.
Speaker 1: special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and brand.
Speaker 0: Okay for the logos be sure to visit our website at front row.
Speaker 0: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 1: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 1: But unlike those other late shows It's actually recorded at night and the patreon patrons for this episode of geek nights are Ellen Joyce Rebecca Dunn Nicholas Brandau Heidi McNichol Amanda Duchette construction noises Ivy Faye my statey.com.
Speaker 1: William Isen rose Jeremy minor.
Speaker 1: We're no strangers to love, you know the rules and so do I. Chris Reimer and Thomas Hahn is a false statement.
Speaker 1: I see a little silhouette of a man Shervin one horrible.
Speaker 1: James David Wright Rochelle, Monta, Nona superboy Abraham link says Aaron Cerise Brian Fisher sailor Vista Matthew Smith Don Schleicher top vision Joe Joe Joe star Tyler Eller Sean Yeager Sam Cordery Clinton Walton Ren from New Zealand Ryan Perrin drew open Lander Brian Cedroni.
Speaker 1: Remember when remarried?
Speaker 1: all of us redacted Chris midkiff Chris Knox Daniel Redmond Sean Klein Chris Reimer and Thomas Hahn.
Speaker 1: No episodes next week because I'm gonna be on a ski trip.
Speaker 1: This is like the one big vacation I take a year that has no work components at all.
Speaker 1: I'm just gonna be skiing at Loon Mountain and atta - Maybe Midersil if it has snow probably all those Bretton wood glades and it's gonna be awesome.
Speaker 1: No geek nights No, nothing taking a break.
Speaker 1: And like I said, remember way back when I said that stay in my orbit if you want to do political stuff in these dark Times.
Speaker 1: I think is happening soon.
Speaker 1: ish and working on it and stay tuned.
Speaker 1: I got stuff but now I leave you with No scrub scrub No scrub scrub is a guy who can't get no love from me hanging out the passenger side of his best friend's ride.