Speaker 0: It's Thursday, April 13th, 2017.
Speaker 0: I'm rim.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott and this is geek nights tonight chocolate.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: So if you follow me on Twitter, you know that one of the militant things I do is that I when I'm biking I literally stop and report to the police every single car that's in a bike lane.
Speaker 0: and because the way New York works use this app to do it and You actually get status reports and probably 90% of the time they're like like three days later the status changes to like Yeah, the cops are looking into it and then a week later.
Speaker 0: It's like yeah We showed up and the the person who was parked there wasn't there anymore.
Speaker 0: It's like no shit.
Speaker 1: There's apparently some car dealer on Queens Boulevard.
Speaker 1: That's parking all their cars in the bike lane.
Speaker 1: Oh, it's like some used car dealer.
Speaker 0: You got a check recurring problem And if you keep reporting it like event they'll go and like fuck up the business.
Speaker 1: Apparently that police precinct like doesn't give a shit or something.
Speaker 0: You got to put him in the ad because the stats from that Cause ripples and eventually like people like people get worried about go bike around Queens Boulevard find where this car dealership is.
Speaker 0: I'll show you on Google man, you know, you can report things just by putting the address in.
Speaker 0: you Don't actually have to be there go for it.
Speaker 0: But there's one thing that happened that the other day that I did not have to report Because I watched it go down because a cop was already there.
Speaker 0: Like literally I see a situation and this situation was kind of amazing.
Speaker 0: So I stopped and I pull out my phone.
Speaker 0: I'm about to like I take some pictures of it because it's pretty funny and I'm about to like report it.
Speaker 0: and Then I see a cop and I kind of wave at the cop and the cop kind of pulls up slow he slows down and he gives me this look.
Speaker 0: and then he because he looks at the thing that I'm looking at and we're Looking at it together and he gives me this look.
Speaker 0: that's like I got this And he gets out and deals with it.
Speaker 0: So, you know Kent Avenue like where the bike path is that goes along the river.
Speaker 0: So it's like a great bike path and cars have learned not to park there because cops do like just ticket you immediately there.
Speaker 0: now.
Speaker 0: But there's this one building that has a loading dock and I never really thought about it.
Speaker 0: But the loading dock is like at the sidewalk and it faces directly into the street.
Speaker 0: I never see anyone use this loading dock and I realize now that I saw this situation occur It would be literally impossible to use this loading dock because what happened was a giant ass truck backed up to the loading dock blocking the sidewalk blocking both lanes of traffic and blocking the bike lane
Speaker 1: blocking
Speaker 0: the entire Streets.
Speaker 0: on Kent Avenue and the street isn't just a bike lane like because of gender You could load with a not giant truck you could load from like a van.
Speaker 0: even a van Would block one lane of traffic Really?
Speaker 0: Yeah, if the sidewalk is not wide there.
Speaker 0: So this truck is blocking the entire thing.
Speaker 0: So the cop walks over and there's a guy like unloading.
Speaker 0: There's another guy in the truck and he says and I quote what the fuck are you doing?
Speaker 0: How do you think this is okay?
Speaker 0: He's like we got to use the loading dock and the cops like I don't care what you got to do.
Speaker 1: You can't just you can't do this can't block the road But he said it like that.
Speaker 0: He's like you can't do this and he makes his arm motion like this.
Speaker 0: all of this around And the guys like what do you expect me to do and he's like well you're gonna get a ticket.
Speaker 0: It's really a question of whether or not you move the car before we escalate this.
Speaker 0: and it was real funny.
Speaker 0: And then I kept biking.
Speaker 0: so I'm curious to see how this evolves over time because I'm pretty sure this building's loading dock existed Back when Kent Avenue was not used for much and no one gave a shit.
Speaker 0: And now Kent Avenue is used for a lot of stuff and that loading dock can't be used anymore Night when no one gives a shit.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the thing is if I really wish I really understood Why I am on a Sunday and I see a carnal in a bike lane.
Speaker 1: I still report it Sure, but like why isn't there some sort of law in New York City that like all Major delivery type things must occur late at night Like you shouldn't be able to drive a tractor-trailer around, you know, the New York City at like 3 p.m?
Speaker 0: I'm pretty sure the argument would like just waiting.
Speaker 0: that would be more expensive.
Speaker 0: My answer is that sucks.
Speaker 1: Yeah, just wait your ass in Jersey until you know The Sun Goes Down and then everyone goes home and then you can come deliver.
Speaker 1: You're getting.
Speaker 0: a better way to go would be ban all personal vehicles in almost all of New York.
Speaker 0: I mean, yeah ban cars obviously But and then delivery like basically let commercial cars drive and use do their business because if there aren't regular cars on the road They could just park in the street and it's totally fine.
Speaker 1: well Also, you could ban cars and then you could put like a freight train on say one of the you know avenues Yeah, and that everyone who needs delivered shit would just use the freight train.
Speaker 0: Well the freight train you still got to do the final distribution.
Speaker 0: You still need a bunch of little drones.
Speaker 1: Well, no, I mean it's like if you're a bodega you walk over the freight train you pick up your crate of bananas, right?
Speaker 0: You're not just gonna walk that stuff.
Speaker 1: if you if you're proposing the 1870s solution Yeah, if you're uh, but the train is like it can't be more than a few blocks away It goes right down the middle, right?
Speaker 0: So it's like yeah, so my business is on I don't know.
Speaker 1: 11th It's up to your business to use a smaller conveyance mechanism That isn't a car to get your stuff from the vehicle of some kind to your place of business.
Speaker 0: I feel like yeah.
Speaker 0: My solution is to do technology for 200 years in the future and yours is to go 200 years back.
Speaker 1: Listen there are many ways you can go get your stuff from the train Personal vehicles in Manhattan anymore.
Speaker 1: I don't want any cars anywhere on earth.
Speaker 1: Destroy all cars.
Speaker 0: cars have their purpose.
Speaker 0: V the idea of vehicles is one cars have a purpose.
Speaker 0: There's a reason why you're not Inelected official banned cars.
Speaker 0: So anyway, it's Thursday.
Speaker 1: It's the lounge news Tiny news and then a medium.
Speaker 1: basically two tiny news cuz like this got some news though.
Speaker 1: Yeah, whatever.
Speaker 1: so news number one for nerds the Star Wars celebration.
Speaker 1: Is it annual or every other year?
Speaker 1: They keep changing the schedule for this.
Speaker 0: I only know about it because I follow some people on Twitter who work it or have worked.
Speaker 1: If anyway, it's the Star Wars convention.
Speaker 0: They tweet a lot about it, right?
Speaker 1: There's an official Star Wars convention.
Speaker 1: It happens every year every other year, but it's happening right the fuck now and this news is coming out of it.
Speaker 1: But all of these news's are so considering like you this thing has been happening for years.
Speaker 1: It was even happening like all the years between.
Speaker 1: I don't know when it started But there were a lot of these things even before Star Wars was revived, right?
Speaker 0: I mean, there are still Firefly conventions, right?
Speaker 1: So it's like what nothing was happening at those except like Star Wars comic books.
Speaker 0: You know what it is, you know the anime con like circle jerk where fandom of the thing becomes like it becomes fans.
Speaker 1: Exactly a fandom of the fandom of the thing twice removes like for years and years They'd no new official products other than like novels comics Fans of the fan culture of an old man, but this is an official convention.
Speaker 1: This isn't some unofficial garbage.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like fucking.
Speaker 1: you know, all everyone's there.
Speaker 1: George Lucas is there?
Speaker 1: Yeah, this is like Harrison Ford.
Speaker 0: I'll do a keynote or whatever.
Speaker 0: I don't think.
Speaker 1: I don't think he's there but Mark Hamill's there.
Speaker 1: I don't know Mark Hamill's definitely there.
Speaker 1: anyway the point is All the news is coming out of this thing are the tiniest time.
Speaker 0: Yeah, not only is he there but he had a story about his plane having a problem landing.
Speaker 1: Yeah, wasn't that when he almost died or whatever like just now?
Speaker 1: just now anyway.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so the tiny news is are like, oh they made a Carrie Fisher tribute thing and it's like yeah, we know that right It's like oh, there's a. there's some Thrawn Thing now that like Timothy Zahn has a new Thrawn thing that talks about origin of Thrawn.
Speaker 1: You know, okay fanboys I like the idea of vice-admiral throw I like the character of vice-admiral thrown and I like his character design.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I read the all three Thrawn books.
Speaker 1: I read them complete a hundred percent.
Speaker 0: I didn't even do that.
Speaker 0: Here's my extent.
Speaker 0: every.
Speaker 1: all the nerds say those are the best Star Wars books and it's like yeah Those are the best Star Wars books.
Speaker 1: They're the least smelly poop.
Speaker 1: The character is cool.
Speaker 1: The books are not.
Speaker 1: so I don't think this new book is gonna be cool.
Speaker 1: But apparently the story of Thrawn is like he was a badass general in whatever race He's in.
Speaker 1: but they sort of like shunned him and then the Empire found him and the Emperor was like Oh, this guy's actually pretty good.
Speaker 1: Let's make him awesome.
Speaker 0: And then so he was just I feel like especially in a canon like Star Wars You're almost better off when the cool characters that don't have backstories at least backstories that were public Can you to have mysterious on.
Speaker 0: yeah, I mean if you just watch the Star Wars movie Boba Fett Fucking badass bounty hunter.
Speaker 0: You don't know anything about him.
Speaker 0: Yeah or her?
Speaker 0: Yeah no idea what this entities deal is other than jetpack green armor awesome ship and Super dangerous except not super dangerous because once Boba Fett actually goes into action just falls into the Sarla.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well, well that was not super dangerous pretty much really at any point in the original.
Speaker 0: So he seemed super dangerous at least until a moment.
Speaker 0: Yeah, maybe we see him in episode 5.
Speaker 0: You're just like who is that?
Speaker 1: What's up with that?
Speaker 0: What's that guy doing?
Speaker 0: Why is he hanging out?
Speaker 0: I'm sure I'm sure that Vader who is cool enough to hang out with Darth Vader and not get.
Speaker 1: I'm sure I could get Information on this very easily but there were those other bounty hunters standing next to Boba Fett in episode 5 and I want to know About them, but I'm sure that would be easy to find out about Star Wars.
Speaker 1: nerds You're probably gonna post right now telling me all their names.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I just don't.
Speaker 1: but yeah It's weird that like now that's the thing is right is like why am I talking about this?
Speaker 1: only these tiny insignificant news is right about Star Wars.
Speaker 1: the most significant nerd thing there is is because Star Wars is revived now, right?
Speaker 1: It's like we get a Star Wars movie every year now Like Star Wars is like more alive now than it has ever been since the original trilogy.
Speaker 0: Like it is possible that ten years from now There will have been ten years of just constant Star Wars.
Speaker 1: It is more alive now than ever.
Speaker 1: Why are the news is at the big Star Wars convention just as insignificant as they were when Star Wars was door?
Speaker 1: Shouldn't?
Speaker 1: the news?
Speaker 1: is a guy ginormous Star Wars like so one.
Speaker 0: What there is.
Speaker 0: you can't actually generate that much news from one more movie coming out.
Speaker 0: That isn't just spoilers.
Speaker 1: You can you just you know spill the beans.
Speaker 0: Yeah, too.
Speaker 0: The momentum of the fandom of Star Wars is his hit that second-order circle jerk.
Speaker 0: The people who are invested in Star Wars fandom really care about Star Wars fandom Possibly more so than actual Star Wars.
Speaker 0: at this point This is not the kind of convention I would ever go to because odd which is interesting to me I mean, I don't want to go to it.
Speaker 1: I wouldn't go out of my way But if it was for some reason extremely convenient to go I would go have it's I would go.
Speaker 1: if it was extremely convenient to go for some reason and cheap I would go one time.
Speaker 0: I mean, I like Star Wars in the Javits and I'm in town or two.
Speaker 1: I happen to be in the town where it is for some other reason But that other reason isn't a pack someone.
Speaker 1: if I if there's someone someone flies me there it's my job to go there I don't know.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I guess if they invited me to give the keynote I would go.
Speaker 0: Hi, everybody.
Speaker 0: I don't know why I'm here.
Speaker 1: I know less about Star Wars than the rest of you nerds Even though I like it just as much as even though most of you were born long After the last of the original Star Wars movies came out.
Speaker 1: Yeah, anyway Okay other news tiny news, right?
Speaker 1: So Fuji the camera company not the mountain In stacks, right they have instax cameras.
Speaker 1: people don't know about these.
Speaker 0: I don't know about these.
Speaker 1: They're basically Polaroid cameras.
Speaker 1: They've existed for like a lot of years now And they have two kinds yet the mini and they have the wide.
Speaker 1: so the and you buy basically instax film Which is like Polaroid film and it's you know You stick it in there and it takes photos and they're pretty good.
Speaker 1: and they're fun because they're like Polaroids only modern.
Speaker 1: But the mini ones the pictures they shoot are like these vertical things.
Speaker 1: It looks like someone took a phone photo of you with the phone?
Speaker 1: No, and the wide ones are.
Speaker 1: they're kind of more normal wide shaped But they're kind of more expensive and unpopular.
Speaker 1: Like Polaroid took square photos.
Speaker 1: It didn't take photos in some weird-ass square.
Speaker 0: They were square for this square cuz I had.
Speaker 0: yeah, yeah pretty sure I got some Polaroids.
Speaker 1: Really took the stand.
Speaker 1: old old-ish camera standard Polaroid cameras The default took square photos on standard Polaroid film, right?
Speaker 1: They were squares.
Speaker 1: So now finally after many many moons, they're going to announce like in a week.
Speaker 1: It's almost.
Speaker 1: it's not it's a rumor, but it's pretty much definite.
Speaker 1: the in I mean there's been a website for this for a long time, but they never had like specifics like, you know This is the actual camera.
Speaker 1: This is how much it will cost and we're gonna say right they're gonna have square.
Speaker 1: So if you like some Polaroid action, right where you take a photo and goes and it prints out immediately Now you can have the the real deal and not some weird-ass shape coming out of there, right?
Speaker 1: So, all right, if anyone wants to buy me this You go right ahead.
Speaker 1: I feel like my cell phone suffices because I don't really print I don't need physical pictures But it's like the thing is once you have it it's suddenly like oh like you're at a convention.
Speaker 1: take a photo and like there It is.
Speaker 1: Here you go.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I remember when you said we use the printer and you were taking pictures of everybody and sticking around in Connecticut that one Time people were kind of into it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like you're not into it until like.
Speaker 0: so You know this is for you.
Speaker 0: do it before.
Speaker 0: if you like our friend chase like you.
Speaker 0: just you go to random parties hang out with people if you're at like a random party in someone's apartment where there's Like 10 to 20 people like that level of party.
Speaker 0: This is the kind of thing that breaks the ice and you like take a picture of someone and hand it to them and suddenly People are passing it around.
Speaker 0: So in some other minor news you guys all probably saw that United Airways, which is one of the airlines I've been boycotting for a long goddamn time because they fucked me multiple times.
Speaker 1: I mean, I never flown them ever and I never would.
Speaker 0: they have fucked me the majority of the times I have flown them.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like I've like jet blue.
Speaker 1: if I have if I have to go to a foreign country I'll usually try to use like the airline from that country right because I fly a lot.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you have a very different value proposition there.
Speaker 0: I try to fly in a very limited number of airlines to maximize yes perks and benefits Obviously, right?
Speaker 1: That's why I choose jet blue if at all possible, but if I'm going to say like yerp I'm gonna try to choose like Lufthansa.
Speaker 1: Go fancy, right if I'm going to like, you know, if I got if I can take you know.
Speaker 0: So fancy literally doesn't matter.
Speaker 0: unless you fly a higher class though Coach is pretty much the same everywhere.
Speaker 1: I mean, I'll still take coach on Lufthansa versus coach on Drek.
Speaker 1: Right Drek air you mean?
Speaker 0: Frontier.
Speaker 1: Yeah, whatever it is spirit.
Speaker 1: Yeah exactly what I'm saying, right?
Speaker 1: So but if I have to go on a domestic flight, I can't do jet blue.
Speaker 1: for some reason It doesn't go there right.
Speaker 1: I can go like Southwest.
Speaker 1: It's not bad, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, so I've flown Southwest recently.
Speaker 0: They're not nearly as great as people chalk them up to be or that they used to be.
Speaker 1: no They're not.
Speaker 0: but blue also not that great.
Speaker 0: Like they're on time records been dropping as far as I can see, right?
Speaker 0: There's the last two jet blue flights.
Speaker 1: I took we're more than an hour late But who else do you know who's better at a domestic flight?
Speaker 0: Honestly these days I fly Delta mostly domestically.
Speaker 1: No, it's cost about the same as jet blue and it's not as nice though.
Speaker 0: It's actually nicer in coach.
Speaker 1: The only problem American Airlines is basically equal to Delta also.
Speaker 1: They're both.
Speaker 0: only problem with flying Delta instead of jet blue domestically.
Speaker 0: Is that jet blue has the best terminal at JFK and Delta has two terminals both of which are yeah But jet blue increasingly like even go like go into packs.
Speaker 0: in San Antonio.
Speaker 0: Delta has direct flights that are way better than anything jet blue has for set for that city.
Speaker 0: Yeah, jet blue does not go to most places I go anymore.
Speaker 0: So packs prime is literally the only time I ever fly jet blue anymore.
Speaker 0: Mmm, like when would I ever use them?
Speaker 0: Otherwise, I Florida.
Speaker 0: why would I go to Florida?
Speaker 0: and actually the last time I went to Florida?
Speaker 0: I flew jet blue our flight there and our flight back.
Speaker 0: We're more than an hour late.
Speaker 1: I never have problem It's every time I fly.
Speaker 0: When was the last time you took jet blue to Florida?
Speaker 0: Okay, well we did it last year for a wedding.
Speaker 1: it's like two years ago, but they're really good to go to tropical places.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we'll see.
Speaker 0: But anyway all that aside so you probably know the story fuck United.
Speaker 0: I got no like the fact that the media decided to start talking about the guy who was dragged off the plane.
Speaker 0: and Not only is that fucked up that they're like, ooh, he had a troubled past Even though that has no bearing on the story.
Speaker 0: But apparently most of that troubled past was a different guy with the same name And the guy might have a concussion like shits bad.
Speaker 0: But the Democratic Party like a whole bunch of senators actually put forth a bill like yesterday and this bill The customer is not.
Speaker 0: Carlos act is actually super great.
Speaker 1: What it basically says is if someone's already boarded a plane, you cannot kick them off like too late Dibs, what if you let more people on the plane than their receipts and they're already on the plane?
Speaker 0: It appears that in that case Think not everyone is musical chairs.
Speaker 0: Not everyone could sit down.
Speaker 0: So I guess the last person is not sitting.
Speaker 1: but what if my ticket has a seat and a letter and number on it And someone's sitting in my seat and letter?
Speaker 0: then that's not the right ticket to pass.
Speaker 0: You can kick them off.
Speaker 1: What if there's their ticket?
Speaker 1: also says so You messed up Yeah in those cases.
Speaker 0: I'm pretty sure they just get fined but it goes.
Speaker 0: the most important part is that You cannot bump people Unless they do it voluntarily quote.
Speaker 0: they must provide sufficient incentives to encourage passengers to voluntarily deplane Meaning they got to keep up in the ante until someone says you know what I'll take the hundred thousand dollars, right?
Speaker 0: Okay fly tomorrow.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean they're gonna eventually say alright, we're just not gonna bump anyone.
Speaker 0: But this bill like I was reading through it it's great.
Speaker 1: sure There's a lot of great bills that get written in legislatures all around the world that have legislate places that legislatures and you might think They don't pass.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so you might know whatever.
Speaker 0: well now so there's a difference between.
Speaker 1: let me go.
Speaker 1: You want me to go dig up all the amazing bills that weren't passed?
Speaker 0: Here's your problem.
Speaker 0: You don't really know a lot about how the Senate works.
Speaker 0: There's a big.
Speaker 0: there's a lot of bills that you say that you you think of in this light are bills that are put forth By basically one person's.
Speaker 0: they can say they put it forth and has no chance of passing or even getting the committee.
Speaker 0: But there's another class of bill that has two co-sponsors One from the Democrats and one from the Republicans.
Speaker 0: those bills have a much higher percentage of passing.
Speaker 0: Then there's bills that have a lot of co-sponsors.
Speaker 0: This bill actually has a lot of co-sponsors But they're all Democrat.
Speaker 0: So yeah, it turns out the Republican Party is really against this bill, right?
Speaker 0: Cuz probably as airlines pay them It goes way back than that.
Speaker 0: so there's a Mother Jones investigative journalism article that actually goes through the long history of airline regulation and Basically, the Republicans are the sole reason air travel sucks in the United States and have been for decades.
Speaker 0: the Republican Party It's not news hates you for flying We're not.
Speaker 0: we don't do news on geek nights.
Speaker 0: We do commentary.
Speaker 0: So I highly recommend you read this article because this is actually very detailed and very fascinating about how much better Pretty much everything in America would be if the Republican Party didn't exist.
Speaker 1: You don't need to read any news.
Speaker 1: That's the only sentence you need to know and you could just never read a newspaper.
Speaker 1: I think like and as long as you know that you're good.
Speaker 0: It's not just like the Republicans are wrong about a lot of.
Speaker 1: stop repeating it every day But we know when was the last single person listening knows the sentence you just said.
Speaker 0: I don't think they do.
Speaker 1: How do you not know that?
Speaker 0: why do you get so weird every time people talk about politics?
Speaker 0: It's not about talking about politics really weird and start yelling, you know, it's repetition, right?
Speaker 0: It's like the last time I brought this up on geek nights.
Speaker 1: It's not about bringing up by geek nights.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: When was the last time I brought it?
Speaker 0: up?
Speaker 0: in a casual conversation.
Speaker 1: every single goddamn day when every single person on every single?
Speaker 1: Communications media.
Speaker 0: when was the last time I did it?
Speaker 1: Every last time you tweeted anything about politics anything earlier today.
Speaker 0: What did what?
Speaker 0: Politics today?
Speaker 1: not at all today.
Speaker 1: Not even once.
Speaker 1: no, probably not.
Speaker 1: Let's have a retweet.
Speaker 0: Maybe what did I tweet?
Speaker 0: Let's go to my profile cuz all you need to know about politics.
Speaker 0: Let's see chocolate Kill a ton of something.
Speaker 0: Here's someone failing to use exercise equipment.
Speaker 0: The United thing.
Speaker 1: There you go.
Speaker 1: You're done.
Speaker 0: Okay, the United thing that you're saying that that counts as politics.
Speaker 1: It's all the same news.
Speaker 1: All of these news is are all the same news, which is there are evil people in government who are owned by corporations.
Speaker 1: They're all in the country.
Speaker 0: the end.
Speaker 0: I'll agree.
Speaker 1: That's all the same news.
Speaker 1: I will agree with every single day.
Speaker 1: They could just write that same exact thing on every front of every newspaper and there's no reason to even print anything.
Speaker 0: I will agree that they are all the same.
Speaker 0: if you're a simpleton with simplistic views of the world cuz the details don't matter that Fundamental thing is.
Speaker 0: you have not refuted my point.
Speaker 0: So it stands simpleton with simple views of how the world you know There is.
Speaker 1: it's not a complex thing.
Speaker 0: So in some other political news, actually this one will be pretty interesting.
Speaker 1: Same exact thing.
Speaker 0: You just said this one is pretty much Guaranteed to happen due to the structure of how it's coming to be in the way the Canadian government is right now Also with some Wall Street stuff.
Speaker 0: I was paying attention to that is that is suspiciously related to this.
Speaker 0: But Canada is just straight-up legalizing marijuana by July of next year like hundred percent Recreational marijuana.
Speaker 0: good luck.
Speaker 0: Have fun.
Speaker 0: It's gonna be great All right This will be interesting because it's probably gonna be a huge economic boom for Canada cuz it's basically Semi legal there.
Speaker 0: Anyway, like you can just buy it in Toronto No one seems to care.
Speaker 0: but now it'll be like legit just normal and legal.
Speaker 1: I feel you be smoking weed in the street though.
Speaker 1: See cuz like as much as I'm down with legalization I would rather people smoke weed in the street than cigarettes sure But I'd much rather not have any smoking in the street allowed.
Speaker 1: It's like smoke your brains out in your house.
Speaker 1: smoke your brains out in like your weed special restaurant place.
Speaker 1: That clearly lets people know that this weed goes.
Speaker 0: got it.
Speaker 0: all the places where this happens It's either just as restricted as cigarettes or you can't smoke it in public places, right?
Speaker 1: But smoking this to even too much cigarette smoking on the street, right?
Speaker 1: I want to get rid of that.
Speaker 0: No, no, I agree.
Speaker 0: You should smoke on any street in New York City.
Speaker 1: I mean I think if you want to smoke something you got to go into a private place that allows it or into a box where we Smoking marijuana with like a joint is something that only old people and super like moron potheads Do.
Speaker 1: normal people just use vapes or pills or other things these days Jerry use whatever you want to use But you know don't breathe it on anybody else.
Speaker 0: Yeah, no, I would like to ban all cigarette smoke.
Speaker 1: That's my only concern right?
Speaker 0: It's like I'm all for the legalization In serving in public in any way that will get in your way.
Speaker 1: Imagine if tomorrow, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah the United States which would never happen was just like, alright We just basically the same as tobacco.
Speaker 1: you can just buy it in the bodega everywhere.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right You're gonna start.
Speaker 1: all the people who you know smoke weed, but wouldn't smoke tobacco or not?
Speaker 0: Because people smoke weed in public in New York City all the time not as much as like way more than especially because I bike to work through Brooklyn.
Speaker 0: People are like.
Speaker 0: I literally see people just smoking weed on the street almost everything.
Speaker 1: I imagined it was even more.
Speaker 0: Yeah, cuz the thing is most people would rather smoke it at home because you're gonna chill.
Speaker 0: You're not gonna be walking around the agro city smoking your weed.
Speaker 0: People might.
Speaker 1: it's like suddenly if you're allowed to you will.
Speaker 0: and one more tiny news because I see a lot of you fucking this Up and retweeting things.
Speaker 0: You shouldn't have retweeted.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the US used a giant bomb.
Speaker 0: It's called a MOAB which literally stands for mother of all bombs because that's the kind of awesome name the military uses.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it actually stands for.
Speaker 0: officially stands for something different.
Speaker 1: Everyone it doesn't matter what it officially stands.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's officially pronounced gif - yeah Yeah, okay, but I just want to point out because I saw a lot of people making this mistake Do not compare this bomb to Hiroshima because About that who is doing?
Speaker 0: the major newspapers lots of media people okay, so first of all all I have to say this is I can sum this up real quick Scott a Kill a ton means a thousand tons.
Speaker 1: How many times how many tons is this bomb?
Speaker 0: 22,000 pounds.
Speaker 0: so divide that by two 11 11 tons.
Speaker 0: So this was an 11 ton bomb not an 11.
Speaker 1: so it's a dynamite bomb.
Speaker 1: It's not like a c4 bomb It's just dynamite.
Speaker 0: It's not dynamite.
Speaker 1: What is it?
Speaker 0: I don't actually know.
Speaker 0: I think it's.
Speaker 0: I think it's thermobaric, but I'm not sure.
Speaker 1: All right, but the way this little air bomb It's not even one kiloton right.
Speaker 1: and not only is it not only is it point?
Speaker 0: Oh one kiloton, right?
Speaker 1: So not only is the size of it so small right, but it's not radioactive in any way shape or form.
Speaker 1: So there's.
Speaker 1: no there's no horrible flashing burning.
Speaker 0: They're comparing the size of the explosion because they don't understand that I kill a ton is a thousand tons.
Speaker 0: Yeah, a thousand.
Speaker 0: I don't think you understand.
Speaker 1: wasn't Hiroshima like 15 kilotons.
Speaker 0: It's between 10 and 20 depending on we can't really know.
Speaker 1: that was pretty much exactly right.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you're pretty pretty much right.
Speaker 1: so 15,000 versus 11. yeah 11 is really high right?
Speaker 1: I mean you turn it up to 11.
Speaker 1: That's like a crab.
Speaker 1: turned it up to 11 the crappiest new turning it up to 15,000 and That's the crappiest nuke.
Speaker 1: right that's just the atom bomb.
Speaker 1: if you use you know a nuclear missile an ICBM from the Cold War yeah, that's well That's a that's megaton.
Speaker 0: luckily the modern weapons are not in those old ranges.
Speaker 1: But I'm just saying the biggest weapon ever built our megaton weapon hot.
Speaker 0: so the big deal with the big deal with the biggest nuclear Like actual deliverable nuclear nuclear weapon ever built was the Tsar Bomba.
Speaker 0: You know how many megatons that was?
Speaker 1: that's a much better name than Moab.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they actually called it the Tsar Bomba.
Speaker 0: Do you know?
Speaker 0: I love Bomba.
Speaker 0: how how big do you think it's explosion?
Speaker 0: wasn't it so big?
Speaker 1: they were afraid to use it.
Speaker 1: So they didn't.
Speaker 0: uh they did use it once, but they ran it at half yield Mmm, so it only.
Speaker 0: it only blew up at 50 megatons 5-0 Mega.
Speaker 0: so and if they used a uranium tamper instead of the lead one it would have been a hundred megatons.
Speaker 0: Give or take 20 megatons.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: the biggest weapon the u.s.
Speaker 0: Ever fielded on an ICBM was I believe I want to say 20 to 25 megatons.
Speaker 0: modern weapons are 700 kilotons to about.
Speaker 0: I want to say 1.2.
Speaker 0: Megatons because bigger weapons are Stupid unless you want to end the world or destroy an entire country.
Speaker 1: Hmm, so maybe we do want to enjoy a story an entire country.
Speaker 1: But I don't.
Speaker 1: the thing is the countries who want to destroy are not really that big.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's not like it's like Russia is so big.
Speaker 1: if you want to destroy them you would need so many bombs anyway Even at the max and North Korea is really tiny and Eritrea is even tinier.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the reason we used to have those big bombs is because there's this concept called circular error probable Basically, it's the it's the rain.
Speaker 0: It's the radius where if you launch a nuke.
Speaker 0: There's a 50/50 shot It'll be inside that radius.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the only news weapons used to be terrifyingly inaccurate.
Speaker 1: We made them huge so sure so people don't know anything about bombs.
Speaker 1: I guess that's an interesting thing to show guys.
Speaker 1: But I use of this weapon is the use of the weapon is only otherwise notable in the news We already discussed which is they?
Speaker 1: the people who run the world are evil the end.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but do not just.
Speaker 0: How do you met?
Speaker 0: people don't understand the K.
Speaker 1: I guess people don't understand technology.
Speaker 1: look at look at the science reporting in this world.
Speaker 0: true You know problem is real.
Speaker 0: science reporting is incomprehensible even to smart people.
Speaker 0: so But anyway things of the day, what do you got for me, so What could be cooler than like a grandma?
Speaker 1: Who Like rides a motorcycle?
Speaker 0: grandma rides motorcycle.
Speaker 1: It's pretty good right grandma.
Speaker 0: Who is competitive tier overwatch?
Speaker 1: I've seen a lot of things like that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there was.
Speaker 1: there was a gaming grandma.
Speaker 1: remember Yeah, there was.
Speaker 0: that grandma was really into doom and was really fucking good at it right?
Speaker 1: It's like you know a grandma doing cool stuff.
Speaker 1: It's like if you're a grandma you can just get away with anything, but it's like you're just awesome Just for doing anything.
Speaker 1: That's not like you know things.
Speaker 0: people expect grandma Family wedding and people are beating around the bush of a sensitive issue.
Speaker 0: and then 98 year old grandma just like yeah uncle Dan's a fucking moron.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right, but here.
Speaker 0: I look forward to being old enough to be able to do that.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, but here.
Speaker 1: We have a grandma.
Speaker 1: That is perhaps more awesome than other grandmas I have seen maybe just equally awesome to those other awesome grandma.
Speaker 1: anyway I don't know if she's a grandma, but she's old enough to be a grandma.
Speaker 1: She 87 something.
Speaker 0: 87 year old Japanese woman, right?
Speaker 1: So I don't know if she's a grandma.
Speaker 1: she might not have a husband or children or whatever But she's an 87 year old woman, and she works in a dumpling restaurant that her family owns.
Speaker 1: She's working in a dumpling restaurant making dumplings for like 60 years.
Speaker 1: So it's like you have 60 years of dumpling making practice.
Speaker 1: I don't like.
Speaker 1: those got to be fucking amazing dumplings right like holy shit.
Speaker 1: That'll be good.
Speaker 1: But like once a month She's awesome DJ.
Speaker 1: She just decided to go to DJ school and now she DJs like a dumpling.
Speaker 1: She DJs awesome beats like once in a while and everyone goes to these parties, and they're totally sick.
Speaker 1: How grand it reminds me of the anime?
Speaker 1: I watched.
Speaker 1: where the tonkatsu DJ?
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, where the kid would he?
Speaker 1: his family owned a tonkatsu restaurant the one really racist character.
Speaker 1: He was drawn in a somewhat racist way, but it wasn't really a racist portrayal I don't know.
Speaker 1: ask a person who knows more about it than yeah But it was a cute show regardless even if it had that kind of problem, but he has about a kid.
Speaker 1: He was like a teenager and his family owned a tonkatsu restaurant and he worked in it and then he would go DJ and he became a DJ discovered DJing and He would take you transfer his skills from the restaurant to the.
Speaker 1: you know the dance parties.
Speaker 1: So this reminded me of that.
Speaker 1: it's like well It's a real thing I wonder.
Speaker 1: I wonder if she saw that anime or read that manga and got the idea from it.
Speaker 0: I wonder how long she's been DJing cuz what if she's been DJing since like her 20s?
Speaker 1: No, it's only a few.
Speaker 1: like she went to the DJ school like you know somewhat more recently like only a few years ago.
Speaker 1: I think it says In the video.
Speaker 0: it says the fact that the internet exists and like nerds continued a nerd into their older age.
Speaker 0: like there might be A point.
Speaker 0: we're like we go to the penny arcade expo and we're super old dude.
Speaker 0: Everyone stage is Mike and Jerry and they're both like 80.
Speaker 1: They'll be dead.
Speaker 0: Healthier life over time.
Speaker 0: I've noticed they look a lot healthy.
Speaker 0: They look a lot healthier than they did 20 years ago say that yes, they're.
Speaker 0: they're the the epitome of healthy Looking better than a lot of people who could send the conventions.
Speaker 1: Yes They will outlive many attendees so not outlive us.
Speaker 0: So are you familiar with the gentleman by the name of Alec Guinness, yeah obi-wan Kenobi.
Speaker 1: we talked about Star Wars ten minutes ago.
Speaker 0: yep, so, uh He's an easy notable.
Speaker 0: He's notable for being what an actor.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so he's been an actor for a long time.
Speaker 1: Well until he died.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but he acted a lot of films Bridge over the River Kwai think I love.
Speaker 0: so there is a trope that gets.
Speaker 1: that was him, right?
Speaker 0: There's a trope in movies where you'll have a gimmick where one Person plays a whole bunch of characters in the same movie.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I've seen that that's actually been a trope for a long long long time.
Speaker 0: Alec Guinness did that in a movie once.
Speaker 1: okay.
Speaker 0: So, uh, what do you think is the total the highest number of characters that Alec Guinness personally played in a single?
Speaker 0: Film?
Speaker 1: well, I mean it depends.
Speaker 1: he playing like the side characters like the characters on screen for like two seconds.
Speaker 1: Does that count?
Speaker 1: Like someone walks into a store in the movie and buy something and walks out and he was the clerk Significance.
Speaker 1: someone gets in a taxi for five minutes and he's the driver.
Speaker 0: significant characters relevant to the plot Not the man not the protagonist like named characters named with dialogue and costumes.
Speaker 1: Whoa in one movie in one log is the movie.
Speaker 0: the movie is 106 minutes and it is from the year 1949.
Speaker 1: and is it like a Movie or is it just like us?
Speaker 0: I actually don't know shit about it.
Speaker 0: All I know is it's a black comedy from 1949.
Speaker 1: so it's a black comedy isn't something that's huge and opulent kind.
Speaker 1: hearts and coronets That's a weird name that tells me nothing about it.
Speaker 1: I guess somewhere between like 10 and 20.
Speaker 0: He didn't mine.
Speaker 0: All right, he played the nine members of the das konye family.
Speaker 0: Eight of them are major appearances.
Speaker 0: Uh, but one of them don't appear on screen together.
Speaker 0: I don't think they do okay.
Speaker 0: Buster Keaton apparently also did this I learned recently and he did appear on screen with himself Which is fucking insane when you think about what that would have taken back in the day.
Speaker 1: I mean usually in a Buster Keaton movie, he's like almost the only character in the movie.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know sort of the same thing is like a you know, Charlie Chaplin.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like there's not really any other characters that there are but they're not there.
Speaker 0: Those people where the more you learn about like you might know about him and be impressed just because you know Like he's important or whatever.
Speaker 0: But literally every new thing you learn about him just impresses you more and that'll never stop as long as you learn about that.
Speaker 0: Dude,
Speaker 1: because there aren't people like that anymore that
Speaker 0: guy Well, he was an era where if you were smart and clever Like you could just pioneer in fields in crazy ways because no one had ever gone there before like and
Speaker 1: you didn't have thinking you Didn't have internet and video games to spend on all day.
Speaker 1: So you can.
Speaker 1: instead you know, you're a hundred percent of your efforts were towards being the awesome.
Speaker 0: But anyway My thing of the day is that I learned a lot about like all these topics together and it's all kind of Fascinating and I'll link to the Wikipedia article about kind of hearts and coronets.
Speaker 0: You can see what the deal is.
Speaker 0: kind of want to see this movie.
Speaker 0: All right, why not cuz it's you know 1949 like old movie it is.
Speaker 1: Is it on filmstruck?
Speaker 0: I have no idea.
Speaker 1: Okay filmstruck is like the.
Speaker 1: It's like they took the criterion collection off of Hulu.
Speaker 1: So Then the filmstruck is like a website where you you know, it's a subscription where you can watch movies But it only has like the old highbrow movies from criterion collection and Turner classic movie.
Speaker 0: All right, it did pretty well apparently and was nominated for a bunch of British Academy Awards.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean, you know it lost out to the third man.
Speaker 1: Well, the third man is like an all-time great movie like top ten movies.
Speaker 1: They never exist this.
Speaker 0: so it think of this as the movie that that had Elegantness in it that lost out to the third man and I think it's like one of the best movies there ever is.
Speaker 0: I don't think I've ever actually seen it.
Speaker 1: You should see the third man.
Speaker 0: I should.
Speaker 0: It's like that's a you know, I just I haven't seen it.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, you haven't played Zelda for the game boy.
Speaker 0: There's yeah In the minute moment the booklet book is Frank Gerberts do now.
Speaker 1: I haven't even read one page.
Speaker 0: I'm not even gonna touch it until I finish Zelda and There's a lot going on in Zelda.
Speaker 0: So I gotta do some bowling.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I Found some interesting areas and some stuff.
Speaker 0: So now I found the the other lab where you can get ancient armor and stuff.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's what I'm trying to get rupees for.
Speaker 1: I just need a few more gears.
Speaker 1: I got all the other parts.
Speaker 1: I need you more gears.
Speaker 0: I feel like I could just kill the people in that place and run the machine myself and make the armor without giving them.
Speaker 1: Except you don't have to give them the rupees.
Speaker 1: the machine wants the roof.
Speaker 0: Damn it.
Speaker 0: Why does the machine want the rupees?
Speaker 0: Why do the fairies want rupees?
Speaker 1: the miss you talk to the machine and it says give me this many rupees.
Speaker 0: Why do you need the rupees?
Speaker 0: I'm trying to save the world here.
Speaker 1: because oh, that's true.
Speaker 1: I mean, that's one thing that's always been here is like why are people not helping the guy?
Speaker 0: Well, it's the.
Speaker 1: once you have the master store people should believe that you're the hero and if they're truly anti-ganon They just give you all their arrows and give you everything rights to help you.
Speaker 1: But it is good we did mention it is good that rupees actually matter in this game.
Speaker 0: I'm sure every other Zelda true But I did that quest thinking.
Speaker 0: Oh if I power this thing up, I'll get some awesome stuff.
Speaker 1: It's like no now I can spend.
Speaker 1: You need a lot of gears and springs and shafts.
Speaker 0: I have a lot of the actually everything I need except the money really.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Oh, wow Where'd you get all this?
Speaker 0: a lot of places?
Speaker 1: So one place I was only able to get enough of them by like actually fighting ancient guardian type.
Speaker 0: So, you know that be the big square labyrinth like.
Speaker 0: apparently that's the heart labyrinth.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know the area under it Graveyard.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah down there.
Speaker 0: You can get a lot of that stuff.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but I had to fight.
Speaker 1: there were ancients that are alive.
Speaker 0: I looted them all before I open the chest in the center.
Speaker 0: They don't activate until you touch that.
Speaker 1: Yeah I did that too, but there's still some alive ones.
Speaker 1: Yeah But I can actually take on them now because I know how to parry their lasers But it's still tough and annoying and I can't do too many at once.
Speaker 0: Yeah, at least the scouts aren't scary anymore.
Speaker 0: I can just kill them like not even think of the flying ones.
Speaker 0: No the little guys.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah No, those are.
Speaker 1: I'm talking about the flying guys.
Speaker 1: I don't know what to do about that.
Speaker 0: You know what I do about those.
Speaker 0: I hide from them.
Speaker 1: Yeah, okay I think you can shoot the propellers or something.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but them come the one.
Speaker 0: so I tried that once I was like You know what?
Speaker 0: I'll take these guys.
Speaker 1: I can also parry their laser which is what I know.
Speaker 1: I learned how to do.
Speaker 1: but if you mess up like you lose your shield.
Speaker 1: So it's like you run out of shields if you're not really good at it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, bring ten shield.
Speaker 1: Anyway, ten times other meta things are making more videos lately.
Speaker 0: So a lot more videos.
Speaker 1: the YouTube finally added the live stream directly from your phone feature The sometime between.
Speaker 1: I was wanted to do it last year when I was doing lunch with Scott But they didn't have the feature yet for everybody and then it got cold.
Speaker 1: So I stopped doing it and now they added the feature.
Speaker 1: So today I tested it out and I made Scott live, right?
Speaker 1: So Scott live is now a thing.
Speaker 1: So I guess whenever I feel like it I will.
Speaker 1: uh, you know, I could just turn on my phone and stream something like BAM.
Speaker 0: I stream overwatch sometimes when I'm playing but
Speaker 1: Even Zelda to like whenever I play streaming
Speaker 0: this every episode of gig nights that I feel like I'll just sometimes turn on the string Streaming rig actually set up the old compressor to make the audio for the stream better because I don't have like a Live signal processing pipeline because I haven't needed it because we do everything in post.
Speaker 0: So I actually had to set up like.
Speaker 0: live streaming brings back the concerns We used to have in like ten years ago geek nights.
Speaker 0: in terms of audio.
Speaker 1: I see you can subscribe or to our youtubes or follow us on Twitter's.
Speaker 1: subscribe to both of us because Split on my new account automatically tweets when I could go live or whatever.
Speaker 1: So yeah, that's how it works.
Speaker 0: and more video stuff is coming.
Speaker 0: A lot of you keep asking me recently about the utenna show.
Speaker 0: It's coming.
Speaker 0: I've just been busy with a lot of other stuff.
Speaker 0: We do have a pipeline and what we should be able to once we really start cranking it crank out those utenna videos Mostly right now.
Speaker 0: I'm modifying the pipeline to Try to do some stuff to avoid the copyright stuff because frankly the copyright stuff in that whose tennis show was so bad That if it continues even after I try to avoid it might just not continue because Almost every anime thing we've ever put up like
Speaker 1: three.
Speaker 1: I just put it on not YouTube.
Speaker 0: That's pain in the ass.
Speaker 0: I don't care enough to do it.
Speaker 0: I just won't bother.
Speaker 0: Okay, like I'm putting all my stuff on YouTube and if I can't put it on YouTube, I just don't care.
Speaker 1: So I don't like Vimeo or something.
Speaker 0: Yeah, Vimeo is pain in the ass.
Speaker 0: Don't want to bother?
Speaker 1: How is it a pain in the ass?
Speaker 0: Take down notices.
Speaker 0: Like stuff just lasts there longer.
Speaker 0: a lot of people.
Speaker 0: what they do is they put it up on Vimeo And when it eventually gets taken down, they just put it up on Vimeo again.
Speaker 0: I'm not playing that game and I'm playing whack-a-mole.
Speaker 1: No But I mean, you know Maybe you won't get taken down because Vimeo will actually respect like oh this is a fair use.
Speaker 0: No Vimeo has nothing to do with it because it's even if I go through the motions the companies Usually send me counter notices and I got to go through like danger of suing paper.
Speaker 1: All right, good.
Speaker 1: Bring it on.
Speaker 0: You're gonna pay for the lawyer.
Speaker 1: No, let them.
Speaker 1: they won't actually bring it on.
Speaker 1: They don't dare.
Speaker 0: Do you gonna pay for the lawyer?
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'll just I'll do it.
Speaker 1: I'll just grab on to them and set myself a fire.
Speaker 0: Well, you sign a contract with me that if one of those videos lawyers that we will 50/50 deal with it.
Speaker 1: I think we had to be sure that we're fair usage.
Speaker 1: I'm pretty sure we are.
Speaker 0: And so fair use that's already a problem because fair use actually to use fair use in court You basically have to say and by the way, I'm not a lawyer.
Speaker 0: That's not legal advice.
Speaker 0: Yes I violated this copyright.
Speaker 0: you have to admit guilt and then argue That the there shouldn't be any punishment because of fair use.
Speaker 0: it's real dangerous to go down that road.
Speaker 1: I could just argue that I didn't violate the copyright first.
Speaker 0: They know that that that'll be double the cost of the lawyers.
Speaker 1: Yeah Because that you know what their response will be gonna find someone who's really wants to fix fair use in the country.
Speaker 1: Who's gonna fight for?
Speaker 0: if one of you is a lawyer and wants to be our lawyer on retainer I think about it.
Speaker 1: If you were the lawyer who finally got fair use fixed after all this time, right?
Speaker 1: You'd be like a hero for the ages, right?
Speaker 1: We will be your case if you Want to be that hero to save the whole world from copyright.
Speaker 0: if you would be willing to be our lawyer and you're good We would literally.
Speaker 0: we would be willing to be the case a hundred percent.
Speaker 1: We'd also give you the money we can afford to give you which is not insignificant But it's probably not what you used to make.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I could not pay you and continue to live my life.
Speaker 1: Probably no No, but now you would get from like a big company for the same case.
Speaker 0: It can't be like it's always sunny in Philadelphia where they just break into that one lawyer's office all the time and he gives them Advice just so they'll go away.
Speaker 0: Anyway, anyway, uh chocolate.
Speaker 0: All right, uh at the end of the month Saturday the 29th Sunday the 30th I will be live at zinc.
Speaker 0: I got doing three panels and otherwise, I don't even know if you anyone heard what you just said.
Speaker 0: Otherwise, I'm just gonna be playing tabletop games.
Speaker 1: All right No one's gonna go to.
Speaker 0: a lot of people go to it's actually it's a bit shockingly big.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like way big and actually my panels cuz I go over here after you stop going, uh, Usually fill completely with it like way more cuz nothing else to do there.
Speaker 0: There's actually a lot to do there.
Speaker 0: There's more to do there Scott.
Speaker 0: There's more for us to do at this con than it anime Boston Mmm, maybe just cuz people you know are there with board games.
Speaker 1: No, because what if those in anime con?
Speaker 0: It's never think on like kinetic on sure.
Speaker 0: So there's a lot of non anime content.
Speaker 0: Anyway, I don't know why you're so down on this convention.
Speaker 1: It's a pain in the ass to go there.
Speaker 0: Hey, you don't go.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I go what I have a good time.
Speaker 1: Yeah Anyway, so chocolate is a delicious thing.
Speaker 1: And if you don't like chocolate, which I know some people don't I don't know What's wrong?
Speaker 1: You're a heathen with a broken tongue.
Speaker 1: go to the doctor get your tongue fixed something wrong with you.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: So, uh chocolate Is something.
Speaker 0: when I was a kid?
Speaker 0: I actually for most of my childhood was obsessed with white chocolate and didn't like like.
Speaker 0: I enjoyed regular chocolate But it always felt like inferior.
Speaker 0: I had this idea in my head that white chocolate whatever that was cuz it's a kid.
Speaker 0: I didn't know what the hell it was.
Speaker 0: I just I knew there was chocolate and white chocolate and I knew From going to a chocolatier at like a resort one time that the white chocolate at that place Happened to cost like four times more than the regular chocolate.
Speaker 0: my chocolate does taste better my chocolate is delicious But is it really chocolate?
Speaker 1: I don't know really.
Speaker 1: I don't really give a shit but it tastes better than regular chocolate and it has the same Sort of.
Speaker 1: you can use it for the same functions as regular chocolate because you know, you can melt it down.
Speaker 1: It comes in a form of a bar, you know, the texture is similar, right?
Speaker 0: So it's like sure Yeah, why chocolate is chocolate except there's no cocoa in it, right?
Speaker 1: So it's like even though it's very similar to actual chocolate it is a chocolate derivative.
Speaker 1: sure It's.
Speaker 1: it still tastes better.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but anyway, so the thing with chocolate right is like people when they talk about chocolate.
Speaker 1: I don't.
Speaker 1: actually don't know a ton about chocolate.
Speaker 1: I'm not like a chocolate expert by any means but you know, obviously There's fancy chocolate right.
Speaker 1: that tastes better than Hershey's chocolate.
Speaker 1: This is not something did you know?
Speaker 1: if you go to the?
Speaker 0: well so we should really tear it already because Hershey's is like the baseline Default chocolate.
Speaker 1: Well, that's like the cheapest crappiest chocolate.
Speaker 1: It's cheaper and crappier than here is there.
Speaker 0: there are depths of crappy chocolate below Hershey's.
Speaker 1: What are they for?
Speaker 0: So the chocolate in most of those super cheap Japanese and Chinese like sweets we get Oh, you mean like the chocolate in the middle of a koala?
Speaker 0: Yeah, okay There are.
Speaker 1: there are tiers of chocolate like the chocolate that a crappy Easter Bunny is made out of.
Speaker 0: go to the off-brand Grocery store in a bad part of a depressed town and there's gonna be some off-brand chocolate.
Speaker 1: Chocolate is already like a slightly, you know, this you have to make it like.
Speaker 1: who's putting the effort to make bad chocolate?
Speaker 1: You might as well make it at least her.
Speaker 1: she's gonna make chocolate at all.
Speaker 0: What about things that are only chocolate at chocolate esque, but are not Technically chocolate?
Speaker 0: you mean things disgusting like coffee, uh, that's a totally different class of things.
Speaker 1: I'm saying it's it's chocolate esque.
Speaker 0: I would not argue that coffee is chocolate esque.
Speaker 1: No, no, it's brown food.
Speaker 0: mix it.
Speaker 0: You're going brown food then poops on the spectrum you poop.
Speaker 0: Okay Riven mitts eating food But let's just say that Hershey Hershey's is the baseline in that If I'm presented with Hershey's I'll pretty much just eat it, right It's like there's a lot of people.
Speaker 1: or it's like yeah, I agree with you The Hershey's is nowhere near as good as like that.
Speaker 1: Haha fancy chocolate, right, you know, but it still tastes good Right.
Speaker 1: It's like I was just telling rim before.
Speaker 1: it's like hey, we're making a basketball team You know for like pickup basketball and someone shows up right and they're an NBA player.
Speaker 1: But there's a no-name NBA player who sits on the bench of the worst team in the league, right?
Speaker 1: And gets paid only like a few hundred thousand dollars.
Speaker 1: Not even a million dollars.
Speaker 1: Whatever the minimum is.
Speaker 1: you're allowed to play an NBA player in that Union.
Speaker 1: They're getting it paid and they play like one minute a year or whatever.
Speaker 1: right there that guy That's still an NBA player.
Speaker 1: you get them on your pickup team down at the playground and you're gonna kill it, right?
Speaker 1: And that's what Hershey's is.
Speaker 1: It's like it's still chocolate.
Speaker 1: It died as good as any of the other chocolates, right?
Speaker 1: It's not gonna win any chocolate taste contest.
Speaker 1: It's still gonna win the pickup basketball game, right?
Speaker 1: It's still good.
Speaker 1: I still eat it, right?
Speaker 1: It's easy to get huh?
Speaker 0: So milk chocolate like that kind of chocolate Which is you know, most chocolate that most Americans eat.
Speaker 0: Yes, no chocolate.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm Like actually non milk chocolate is pretty rare.
Speaker 1: unless you're a baker You got a specialty places right and baking like if you actually get baking chocolate don't really eat that.
Speaker 0: well, I mean I kind of like that kind of chocolate sure but that is Enjoying.
Speaker 0: that is like enjoying an ultra hoppy beer, right?
Speaker 1: It's like dark chocolate and you can go to the store and you can buy dark chocolate, which tastes great.
Speaker 1: It's amazing.
Speaker 1: But if you go to the baking aisle, they have like bars of chocolate that are like this is baking chocolate.
Speaker 1: It is meant for like melting or you know, putting into a chocolate cake and it's meant for that.
Speaker 1: It's not meant for eating and it doesn't taste.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's dark chocolate.
Speaker 1: Sure It doesn't taste good the way the bar of dark chocolate you get in the other area.
Speaker 1: It tastes good.
Speaker 0: But apparently milk chocolate wasn't actually invented until 1875.
Speaker 0: That's still a long time ago Yeah, but it's also surprisingly or not surprisingly at least shockingly recent.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm Well, when was regular chocolate invented?
Speaker 0: Well invented it's grown on the planet since I remember but it wasn't in chocolate bar form You know, it was consumed in bean form in forms that you would recognize today like basically cocoa beverages as early as 1900 BCE.
Speaker 1: What what?
Speaker 0: You don't know anything about Mesoamerican chocolate.
Speaker 0: I don't.
Speaker 0: I'm looking at the Wikipedia.
Speaker 0: That's why you that's why you know You're looking at more well-informed than I ought to be because I'm looking at this.
Speaker 0: But I knew that Mesoamerica had chocolate long long long ago.
Speaker 1: I mean, I mean I thought I thought I knew people were eating cocoa beans from you know trees.
Speaker 1: I didn't realize people were able to turn it into like a chocolate bar chocolate beverages at least.
Speaker 0: But what about a son thing?
Speaker 1: What about a bar?
Speaker 1: Well, so there's different kind like a solid chocolate is I'm talking about?
Speaker 0: Yeah, well, there's different kinds of solid chocolate.
Speaker 0: But let's see the moldable chocolate in the form that you think of today was invented basically by adding melted cocoa butter Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: That was 1847 the year before they invented milk chocolate.
Speaker 1: Okay So the milk was like.
Speaker 1: they figured out the bar and they added the milk in the next year and
Speaker 0: apparently they started making it Bitter in the early 1800s, but it seems like what happened was Europeans with their evil colonialism Stole chocolate brought it back to Europe and we're like, ah, this stuff's actually better We don't like it that much.
Speaker 0: and then they spent a hundred years Making it less and less bitter and more and more milky and sweet Mmm, and that's where.
Speaker 1: and now they're making it bitter again because they realize they fucked up.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: They learned their lesson, I think.
Speaker 0: In 1662 the Bishop of Rome declared that religious fasts were not technically broken by consuming chocolate.
Speaker 1: Sounds like sounds like a Caesar wanted to get his chocolate on.
Speaker 1: Yeah So Rome had chocolate.
Speaker 0: - damn well Scott Rome exists today.
Speaker 0: the Bishop of Rome Has existed for many many many hundreds of years.
Speaker 0: This was 1662.
Speaker 0: Okay In fact, there weren't bishops of Rome until I thought you said Christianity.
Speaker 1: I didn't realize you said Bishop of Rome.
Speaker 1: I thought you're talking about the Caesar.
Speaker 1: That's why I said Caesar before but I guess the Bishop of Rome is an entirely different person.
Speaker 0: But uh, yeah chocolate is super good.
Speaker 0: So what are your favorite uses of like?
Speaker 0: what's your favorite if you like?
Speaker 0: if you could get any kind of chocolate right now?
Speaker 0: Literally right now in front of you regardless of cost or expense or difficulty.
Speaker 0: What is your chocolate?
Speaker 1: Well, I mean if I could get any chocolate I want to try the ridiculously expensive fancy chocolate that I can't afford that I want to like from a Custom chocolate.
Speaker 1: I want to see.
Speaker 1: I want to see like is that is the fanciest God chocolate on earth?
Speaker 1: Whatever the hell it is right actually any good?
Speaker 1: or is it just as good as the Moderately expensive semi fancy chocolate that I can buy easily.
Speaker 0: All right, here it is.
Speaker 0: Amadei Porchilana is a dark chocolate made by the Amadei chocolatier in Tuscany.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it sounds that sounds about the level I want to get one the golden bean award.
Speaker 0: I mean that's bean to bar.
Speaker 1: That's probably good enough, right?
Speaker 1: There might be something out there that's even fancier, but that that might as well be it right.
Speaker 1: Is that better than the fanciest chocolate bar?
Speaker 0: special translucent white cocoa bean variety?
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah It seems to be in the style of Mexican or Colombian.
Speaker 1: It's a real chocolate.
Speaker 0: All right, so oh This isn't that expensive.
Speaker 1: how much is it?
Speaker 1: $90 a pound?
Speaker 1: Buy some.
Speaker 0: I could like go on Amazon.
Speaker 1: See if you can get it.
Speaker 0: I've spent way more money on dumber shit than that.
Speaker 1: You can make a video where we get the.
Speaker 1: I'll spend the patreon money Then the patreon money by.
Speaker 1: don't buy just that.
Speaker 1: by the three fanciest chocolates we can get or five or whatever The number is.
Speaker 0: I don't know if this is actually the fanciest but I typed fans most expensive chocolate and that's what came.
Speaker 1: Why don't we go to YouTube and see if anyone has already made this video where they try the fanciest truck them?
Speaker 0: I want an excuse to make the video.
Speaker 1: I also do too.
Speaker 0: But yeah, all these other fancy chocolates are bullshit in that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there's a truffle in it like a real truck.
Speaker 1: Oh get that one.
Speaker 0: So yeah, you know what?
Speaker 0: I want Scott.
Speaker 0: I want a Vintage Maserati that has a chocolate bar in the seat.
Speaker 1: one actual truffle is not as expensive as a Maserati.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I'm saying if you I can just include anything in.
Speaker 1: the chocolate Right is like one.
Speaker 1: some, you know, there are clearly subtle differences between like fancy chocolates.
Speaker 1: I've had quite a few.
Speaker 1: There's like ones that are nuttier and ones that are more dark and less dark.
Speaker 1: You know got the 85% dark, you know, go and whatever and they're all pretty good and different in their own ways.
Speaker 1: But actually, you know Heathen me or whatever right my favorite chocolates have to do with what's when you put stuff in them.
Speaker 1: That's not chocolate right like a sea salt caramel filled Without with almond.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like.
Speaker 1: that's the pretty much the maximum sea salt.
Speaker 0: I really like orange peel.
Speaker 1: I really like when there's a mint cream in the chocolate like Andy's candies is obviously like the cheapo version but like this Ritter sport.
Speaker 1: It's a Ritter sport I don't know if you know, this is called Ritter sport because it comes in a square.
Speaker 1: They are supposed to put in your sport coat pocket.
Speaker 1: It fits in there Okay, but they make like a zillion flavors and they usually charge like, you know in the city depending on where you go These things could be five dollars a bar But you can get them for 250 or even two dollars a bar.
Speaker 1: and if I see that I buy them and they have the Pfefferman's variety which is This basically mint cream inside of it and the second best variety is the choco duo Which is part of its white chocolate and part of its regular chocolate And they have a ton of different varieties though that like, you know, like I think it's like 50 something different kinds you know like pralines and you know Every nougats and all kinds of stuff.
Speaker 0: one thing I will say because I know I don't know if we've talked about this on geek knives.
Speaker 0: We probably did a long time ago, but we learned this a long time ago in case you didn't know.
Speaker 0: unless you Go out of your way and know enough to avoid it Chocolate ice cream is bullshit.
Speaker 0: yeah, it's basically all the it's crappy or leftover ice cream or other flavors or nonsense and they put some chocolate flavoring in it because Chocolate flavor just like hacks the brain and if you add chocolate to things it pretty much makes it taste like chocolate.
Speaker 0: So and then they just put some brown food coloring in it.
Speaker 0: You know the difference right?
Speaker 1: if you want to get actual chocolate I forget a chocolate milkshake unless they're melting chocolate syrup into it, right?
Speaker 1: Well, or just if you do it yourself with you bet no you get the black and white shake.
Speaker 0: That's actually a vanilla shake, but then there's just melted chocolate mixed in.
Speaker 1: Oh my gosh of anyway, so the Was I just saying?
Speaker 1: you messed me up.
Speaker 0: I was talking about chocolate ice cream.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you were talking about the Ritter sport, right?
Speaker 1: I was gonna say you can go and find fancy chocolate ice cream.
Speaker 1: That is real chocolate in it, right?
Speaker 1: It's the expensive stuff at the grocery store and not the friendly stuff.
Speaker 1: Yeah It exists.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know a lot of.
Speaker 1: even Ben and Jerry's I'm pretty sure is real chocolate.
Speaker 1: Maybe it's on the border might depend.
Speaker 0: I mean, there's a lot of things that are chocolate, but there's just some nonsense in them and they're not really chocolate.
Speaker 0: Mmm, I think my favorite form of chocolate in the world is actually probably just simple chocolate bar.
Speaker 0: I actually don't like the Fancy candies that are chocolate with mystery crap inside a mystery crap inside.
Speaker 1: What do you mean?
Speaker 0: Well, like you get the fancy box of chocolates and there's a hundred unique ones.
Speaker 0: Oh those yes, like a dive a type style half of them have just like a really overwrought cream.
Speaker 0: Yeah, yeah a really badly done raspberry.
Speaker 1: So Godiva right is like the slightly overpriced for what it is, but still better than Hershey's But not actually as good as real fancy chocolate, you know chain store Like I need to buy chocolate for someone for a holiday or a gift.
Speaker 1: I go to there and I buy a gold box full of chocolates, right?
Speaker 1: But if you go most of the stuff in the in the Godiva box of stuff is is just like what you said, right?
Speaker 1: It's not any good.
Speaker 1: It's like oh, there's a cherry in there with a bunch of cream and you don't really taste the chocolate.
Speaker 1: But they have some.
Speaker 1: If you buy a box, they have like a little disc and the dicks is full of mint and that's a good one, right?
Speaker 1: And if you go up to the counter at that place I used to do this way back in the day I haven't done this and like maybe since I was in high school for like a dollar each They had these ones that I forget what they're called But it's basically a fancy chocolate and it's like coin of cha.
Speaker 1: I could I could point to it if I was in the Godiva store But it was like really actually really good and I would just get those only and I wouldn't get the variety.
Speaker 1: I'd be like give me three of those.
Speaker 1: Those are the good ones.
Speaker 0: So I realized my chocolate chocolate taste changed as I grew up and learn more about chocolate.
Speaker 0: But also, you know, I was just like in a middle-class family.
Speaker 0: So we bought the cheap stuff in the grocery store usually.
Speaker 0: but when I was a kid a young kid Andy's mint the little chocolate Andy's mint Second ago.
Speaker 0: But I was so obsessed with those as a kid and like they were the special treat Like if I was able to get him it was kind of a rare thing.
Speaker 1: They come in a whole box like a million of them in there, right?
Speaker 1: So compared to the buying like a Hershey bar, which you eat all at once you get a box of Andy's candy.
Speaker 0: He's like, holy shit Yeah, and I'd like rad like eat him one by one like day by day and an RIT for a while.
Speaker 0: We would like get him like have a box of them in the apartment but If you don't eat him for a while, and you've had better chocolates and you go back and eat an Andy's.
Speaker 0: They're pretty shitty Like they're not great.
Speaker 0: When was the last time you ate an Andy's mint?
Speaker 1: I haven't because I've been buying the Ritter Sport Pfeffer.
Speaker 0: Yeah, go eat an Andy's mint and you're gonna get a neck away for feeling really that kind of feeling I felt I feel it.
Speaker 0: I feel like the chocolate is pasty and the mint is weak.
Speaker 1: So, I mean it's never been great, but it's still like, you know, it's still like.
Speaker 1: I was just saying It's like it might as well be Hershey's chocolate with me.
Speaker 0: It just feels thin like I'd rather I'd rather eat a Hershey's bar than a box of Andy's mints these days.
Speaker 0: Mmm interesting cuz I had an Andy's mint like a couple years ago.
Speaker 0: It just like randomly and I remember thinking like whoa.
Speaker 0: Whoa.
Speaker 0: This is not.
Speaker 0: either my taste buds changed or Andy's mints got worse.
Speaker 0: Something's wrong here and I ate another one and there's not that good anymore.
Speaker 0: End of an era not eating the Andy's.
Speaker 0: Oh well So we made this.
Speaker 0: we stretch the show into an hour, I guess we could just stop there.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean, you know I'm sure there's like a million things to talk about chocolate related because it's such a. you could probably do a Chocolate podcast if you were a chocolate expert, you know.
Speaker 1: But I just don't know too much about it other than I like it in almost all its forms.
Speaker 1: It is delicious and essential to life though.
Speaker 0: I learned something actually recently and I see a link to a reference to it in the Wikipedia.
Speaker 0: So, uh, so we talked about marijuana being legal.
Speaker 0: so I occasionally where it is legal consumer chocolate chocolate chocolate weed most of the marijuana I have consumed in places where it's legal is chocolate because that's like The.
Speaker 0: it's one of the best things to put that flavor in because we does a very distinctive flavor and that flavor is It the shall we say an acquired taste.
Speaker 1: Is it anything like it smells?
Speaker 0: Yeah Exactly like it smells.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, that's why.
Speaker 0: so that flavor when most people make a an edible marijuana thing Does not mesh well with the food.
Speaker 0: So it's like you eat a chocolate or you eat a chocolate that a skunk farted on.
Speaker 0: now those are your options.
Speaker 0: But in in Seattle the fancy chocolatiers are making fancy chocolates.
Speaker 0: Let's try to mix the flavor with like certain kinds of dark chocolates where they'll complement each other and they're pretty good.
Speaker 0: They're not great, but they're pretty good like they taste good or at least interesting on their own.
Speaker 0: But I learned through some completely unrelated research tangential to that That some of the chemicals in chocolate are the same cannabinoids that give marijuana its effects.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm now not the THC not the like super high effect, but the cannabinoids the the oils the other pieces.
Speaker 0: There's little effects that eating a lot of chocolate has.
Speaker 0: that could be similar to Some of the sub effects that marijuana has on people but not the super high effects that you typically associate with marijuana.
Speaker 0: It is true chocolate will mess you up but not in not in a like whoa dude way But in a really subtle way.
Speaker 0: And there's a lot of stuff about that that I do not know.
Speaker 0: I've already delved into the extent of what I know about that and this Wikipedia article basically just confirmed that that is a thing.
Speaker 0: it isn't just nothing and the article about it appears to be an Italian.
Speaker 0: so I Can't go any further in this podcast.
Speaker 0: and now we've gone over in hours.
Speaker 0: I think we're done Chocolate eat it.
Speaker 0: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Speaker 1: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 0: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 1: But unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 0: It's actually recorded at night And the page around page rounds for this episode of geek nights are in the or oh my god They've continued to type stuff down there.
Speaker 0: Okay, let's try this.
Speaker 0: Rebecca Dunn Nicholas Brando Alan Joyce Heidi McNichol Amanda Duchette great job.
Speaker 0: emoji mystady.com.
Speaker 0: William Eisnerose Jeremy Minor Mokushikushimoshi mokukumoshi moshikushikumo.
Speaker 0: She was looking kind of dumb with her finger and her thumb in the shape the terrible secret of space 421 creations, you know with the plan for us and stuff.
Speaker 0: I don't know man, but Shervin Von Harl Rare Laval James David White Rochelle Montanona Superboy.
Speaker 0: I paid five bucks to make rim say boner toots Sailor Vista Matthew Smith Don Schleich Kajar Tavashin Joe short Joe star Tyler Eller Sean Yeager Sam Carter Clinton Walton run from New Zealand Ryan Perrin delicious bourbon brownest of the brown liquors.
Speaker 0: Brian Cedroni the space-time vector of an African European swallow carrying Kiwis Redacted Chris mid give Chris Knox Taylor Redmond Sean Klein Chris Ryan or Thomas Hahn.
Speaker 0: I'm hungry We're gonna head it right there and I leave you with something.
Speaker 0: every gun that is made every warship launched every rocket fire signifies in the final sense a theft From those who hunger and are not fit Those who are cold and are not close.
Speaker 0: this world in arms is not spending money alone.
Speaker 1: It is spending the sweat of its laborers The genius of its scientists the hopes of his children.
Speaker 0: the cost of one modern heavy bomber is this a modern brick school in more than 30 cities.
Speaker 1: It is two electric power plants each serving a town of 60,000 population.
Speaker 1: it is two fine fully equipped hospitals.
Speaker 1: It is some 50 miles of concrete pavement.
Speaker 1: We pay for a single fighter plane with a half million bushels of wheat.
Speaker 1: We pay for a single destroyer with new homes that could have housed More than 8,000 people.
Speaker 0: This is I repeat The best way of life to be found on the road.
Speaker 0: The world has been taken.
Speaker 0: This is not a way of life at all In any two cents.
Speaker 1: under the cloud of threatening war it is humanity hanging from a cross of iron.