Speaker 0: It's Wednesday, November 1st 2017.
Speaker 0: It's no longer spooky.
Speaker 0: I'm rim.
Speaker 1: I'm Scott and this is geek nights.
Speaker 0: tonight We're actually reviewing an anime.
Speaker 0: That's new.
Speaker 0: the ancient magus is bride.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: So you went to the Rangers game on Halloween, and it was weird that they won, but that's good.
Speaker 0: But because I didn't go to that Rangers game we did I was gonna throw a Halloween party.
Speaker 0: But the rim who thought he wanted to throw a Halloween party is like from six months ago And the rim right now is just real tired of dealing with like five conventions.
Speaker 0: I got a plan stuff for and I've been busy and like laundries piling up.
Speaker 0: so instead of doing a Halloween party We had a few people over and we just watched Bette Midler in hocus-pocus Which I have not seen since I saw it in the theater as a kid.
Speaker 1: I don't even know what that is.
Speaker 1: I know who Bette Midler is, but I don't know what.
Speaker 0: so you realize Bette Midler played a really over-the-top Witch in a Disney horror movie that sounds about right that get aired in the 90s that I saw in the theaters.
Speaker 0: I did not and I remembered more of this movie than I my brain has any right to have remembered.
Speaker 1: I mean, it's entirely possible.
Speaker 1: It's one of those things where if I see it some dark memory that's buried will just emerge But I never.
Speaker 0: the only weird thing is that I remember There being way more songs than it because it was Bette Midler, but there's actually really only one and a half songs in it.
Speaker 0: There's Bette Midler's big song I'll put a spell on you and then there's this other song that the other weird witch things.
Speaker 1: I think I know a song called off this.
Speaker 1: It sounds familiar.
Speaker 0: It's not a new song.
Speaker 0: Okay, but yeah, so we watched it again.
Speaker 0: I'm probably just gonna do a Geek Bite review with Emily of it because we watched it again recently and I think my strategy for Halloween parties forever is going to be watch a weird old Halloween II thing.
Speaker 1: I Also learned that it's usually a good strategy, but the you know, I got to watch some scary shit.
Speaker 1: There's not a lot of scary shit these days.
Speaker 0: well I feel like I could.
Speaker 1: someday we'll just watch like one of the old classic slasher film and someone's gonna someone's gonna be like Oh, but Scott here's all these great horror movies that came out and I'm saying yeah There are plenty of horror movies that are and some even great ones.
Speaker 1: I'm saying they're not fucking scary.
Speaker 1: Nothing is scary.
Speaker 0: I would argue get out was scary.
Speaker 0: I found get out to be scary What?
Speaker 0: what does it have to be scary?
Speaker 0: does that?
Speaker 0: does the knife have to actually come out of the screen and try to?
Speaker 0: Hey,
Speaker 1: I have to feel terror as it about K imagine
Speaker 0: the difference between scary because it makes you feel terror versus scary in the sense that it shows the Situation of other characters who are scared in a tense situation that causes you tension If not necessarily direct fear, right
Speaker 1: like if I'm in real life and say there's lava coming down from a volcano.
Speaker 1: Now I'm afraid and I'm running right if I don't feel that way watching the movie.
Speaker 1: It's not scary.
Speaker 0: That's real easy to fix.
Speaker 0: So next time we watch a slasher film like on Halloween I'll say content of the movie has to be making me afraid not some outside.
Speaker 0: no, cuz I was about to say all I have to do is stand behind you with a knife and I May or may not just cut you a little.
Speaker 1: I'm saying The content of the movie has to be the thing causing the fear not you with the knife.
Speaker 0: I think that definition is dumb because that is not really feasible or possible?
Speaker 1: There have been scary movies in the past like what Name one that's gonna meet your modern definition.
Speaker 1: I was scared of alien when I was a kid.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you scared of it now.
Speaker 0: No, what would have to change to make you scared of it?
Speaker 1: Make it scarier how?
Speaker 0: What mechanic will they use other than the jump scare?
Speaker 1: or Actually putting you in real physical jump scare doesn't count because that gives me a feeling of surprise and not terror.
Speaker 0: So what is a feeling of terror then?
Speaker 1: the same feeling you have when you're standing at the bottom of volcano and lava is coming.
Speaker 0: That's not terror.
Speaker 0: That is now that's resignation to death.
Speaker 1: No, it's not.
Speaker 0: I'm running While I'm running.
Speaker 0: I still have a nihilistic resignation toward death as opposed to any particular terror.
Speaker 0: Mmm.
Speaker 0: Anyway, I Throw myself down mountains for fun.
Speaker 0: I'm not really afraid of stuff.
Speaker 0: I Mean, I'm not afraid of Monsters, I think your definition of what constitutes scary in the context of media is misguided, but I digress hocus-pocus.
Speaker 0: The things that are worth noting is that VFX when this movie was made in the early 90s Pretty fucking bad.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah there but they are a step above the VFX From the 80s.
Speaker 1: Well, here's the something I noticed a lot is that when a Tron come out the first Tron 80 what?
Speaker 1: 2 4 2 4 something.
Speaker 0: It was 81, but I don't remember right.
Speaker 1: and you look at the old Tron and it's obviously - I was right.
Speaker 1: It's as old as us right.
Speaker 1: and you look at the old Tron and I'm not gonna say it's good Obviously, it's not good.
Speaker 1: You can see that it was made with really old 1982 computers Right with set with sad graphics.
Speaker 1: I kind of graphics that your home computer made in the early 90s.
Speaker 0: But it's dated in a way to where it looks like something from its time as opposed to.
Speaker 0: well weird.
Speaker 1: And even though it is not good Right.
Speaker 1: when you look at computer graphics from movies in the 90s pre Toy Story pre Toy Story Right, they're just awful.
Speaker 1: Even if you watched them when they were brand new Wasn't until later Toy Story and then also even the matrix which you know All right, stuff like that where the seat the computer graphics in the movie got to a point.
Speaker 0: I'm talking more about the VFX like just basic compositing and simple effects like those kinds of things.
Speaker 0: They're just in a movie 80s.
Speaker 0: all use like these same few techniques and if you watch I don't know Howard the Duck or the He-Man live-action movie.
Speaker 0: they both use like this same Because their budget was low right.
Speaker 1: Oh Star Wars didn't have those problems in his front.
Speaker 0: the 70 Star Wars used primarily practical effects.
Speaker 1: However, they'd still lightsaber still look good.
Speaker 0: So yes, they did look good, but a lot of practical effects or hand-done effects, but I digress.
Speaker 1: The x-wing still went pee-pee-pew.
Speaker 0: The other crazy thing is we're watching the movie and all we could think was everyone involved in this is still alive and still working.
Speaker 0: Hocus-pocus to with Bette Midler today would be fucking amazing.
Speaker 0: So a lot of the trip.
Speaker 0: guess what?
Speaker 0: not only is that actually happening and Disney is doing it Mm-hmm, but Bette Midler was like guys.
Speaker 0: stop trying to make this happen.
Speaker 0: I'm not gonna be involved in this It's shit.
Speaker 1: So here's the same story, but the opposite because it's all Halloween II lately, right?
Speaker 1: The there's been talk again of God.
Speaker 0: the article I clicked on randomly is about the remake, right?
Speaker 1: Okay, there has been talk of Beetlejuice because it's Halloween.
Speaker 1: people talking about Beetlejuice.
Speaker 1: I got Beetlejuice is cool.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we have to do it.
Speaker 0: There's a show on you Beetlejuice.
Speaker 0: I have a lot of very specific opinions about Beetlejuice.
Speaker 1: Anyway, the thing is there was a Beetlejuice sequel and this huge story behind it and it could still happen.
Speaker 1: No, like Michael Keaton and Winona Ryder have been like sort of signed on to it since it began way way way back.
Speaker 1: it's called like Beetlejuice in Hawaii or something and It's like still has life somehow even after all those years and it's not a Bette Midler being like.
Speaker 1: no It's like.
Speaker 1: they're like, yes, but it just has.
Speaker 1: it just hasn't come about.
Speaker 0: So with Beetlejuice that we'll get into anime in a second.
Speaker 0: But I noticed something in the course of talking more about Halloween shit after Halloween It's the day after Halloween where you want.
Speaker 0: It's also the 12th anniversary of gig nights.
Speaker 0: last night You're doing this for 12 goddamn years too many years 1,180 episodes.
Speaker 1: I quit and go home.
Speaker 1: I'm done.
Speaker 0: Finally.
Speaker 0: My time is here myself.
Speaker 0: I'll just get the other Scott.
Speaker 0: I got like three Scott's.
Speaker 0: Uh-huh.
Speaker 0: I'll just bring one of them in.
Speaker 0: I I Forced Scott prime to do at least one or two Podcasts in the past and I can.
Speaker 0: I can train him.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: It'll take a while though, but Beetlejuice the in Beetlejuice the movie contrary to every spin-off and Related merchandise everything that wasn't the actual movie that it was ever made.
Speaker 0: They all treat it like Beetlejuice is the hero But in the movie Beetlejuice is the goddamn villain.
Speaker 1: Beetlejuice is only also only in like 20% of the movie.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but he is the villain really.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm He like he's just this villain and he's there and the moral of the movie is don't fucking talk to that guy He's the worst.
Speaker 0: He'll he will ruin everything and he's dumb also kind of annoying.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: He's just a bad dude.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but they went to go.
Speaker 1: He's basically it's a Faustian tale.
Speaker 1: They went to make a deal with the devil and then he was like.
Speaker 1: And then they beat him and they put him back and they did the deal They went to.
Speaker 0: really they went to do with the devil's bureaucracy and that was too hard.
Speaker 0: So then they went and talked to this like low-tier like shit devil and he made the shit that they expect like What did you expect?
Speaker 0: But uh, like if there was a cartoon and that cartoon was just like Beetlejuice and Daria going on adventures together Like all that weird star.
Speaker 1: now, I know that that you know, Lydia is Lydia is very goth and similar in character to Daria.
Speaker 0: My brain was like nope, no, you're wrong.
Speaker 0: So anyway, you know the biggest anime news that we probably haven't talked about is this funimation thing Which I haven't paid a lot of attention to.
Speaker 1: so it's one of those situations.
Speaker 1: That's a news but it's not a news yet Right.
Speaker 1: So funimation is the number one anime distributor in the United States as far as I'm aware possibly North America I don't know if they do Canada or whatever, but and from a Anime fan like anime consumer perspective.
Speaker 0: They're doing a pretty great job.
Speaker 1: They're doing alright.
Speaker 1: They're doing better than the previous ones that all failed like genie on and you know And a lot of those old companies were sort of I guess absorbed into fun.
Speaker 1: I don't know what happened really back then But basically of all the ashes of all those companies that were trying to bring anime to the u.s It's pretty much now just like funimation is the king, right?
Speaker 1: They get the licenses they want and they bring out those shows in the u.s.
Speaker 1: And they're on crunchyroll.
Speaker 0: The prince at this point is Netflix.
Speaker 0: We're just like we're just gonna make our own anime.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we're making like 30.
Speaker 1: Amazon, Japan.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know you got these other players in there the crunchyrolls the Amazons whatever but it's mostly funimation.
Speaker 1: So Funimation Now it's a private company.
Speaker 1: It's not public.
Speaker 1: You can't buy shares in.
Speaker 1: it Has been.
Speaker 1: a majority of it is now owned by Sony play PlayStation Sony that is a7s camera Sony TV Bravia Sony.
Speaker 0: anything Involving Sony is fraught with ridiculous contradictions for the simple fact that different parts of Sony actually want very different things and Sabotage each other and they often operate Independently, but also not independently Sony.
Speaker 1: The only thing a lot of them have in common is the name Sony and that they're all under the umbrella of big Sony in Japan.
Speaker 0: but like Sony's prosumer video stuff is pretty great But it's hobbled often by Sony's entertainment side that wants ridiculous DRM and nonsense and that kind of.
Speaker 1: yeah Even the PSP was hobbled by like the computer department forcing it to use memory sticks.
Speaker 1: It's like, you know stuff like that.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so as of now Sony owns a majority of Funimation.
Speaker 1: the CEO of Funimation Previously, what's his name?
Speaker 1: guy Fukunaga or something?
Speaker 1: His name you see a lot if you pay attention to anime news in the u.s.
Speaker 1: I've never.
Speaker 1: I don't know what the person is like though, you know old geek knives.
Speaker 0: We would have known they.
Speaker 1: Yes, they still own some amount of Funimation, but obviously not enough to.
Speaker 0: so according to this They probably might.
Speaker 0: they own at most 5% now.
Speaker 1: Yeah, something a CEO owns right.
Speaker 0: a CEO owns shares Was only valued at 150 million.
Speaker 1: yeah, but it's not that big that's they're just cuz.
Speaker 1: think about it.
Speaker 1: their profits are not huge.
Speaker 1: They're paying to license animes.
Speaker 1: They're not getting that right.
Speaker 1: They're paying a lot of money in license fees and then Streaming it and selling merchants shit like that to try to make back the license fees Profit.
Speaker 1: and then they send most of the money the revenue right back to the license plate, you know to Japan.
Speaker 1: How much money does Funimation keep?
Speaker 1: how many people even work there?
Speaker 1: It's probably like a small little company in California.
Speaker 1: So the listener says again.
Speaker 0: Yeah Fukunaga.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so Right as of now the CEO still the CEO that all their licenses are the same.
Speaker 1: all their releases are untouched.
Speaker 1: right everything they're doing for the near future is unchanged, but If I know what I know anytime ever in the history of ever that a company has been bought by another company Shit changes eventually, right?
Speaker 1: They always say oh business is usual and then ain't gonna be business as usual.
Speaker 1: So the changes that Sony brings to Funimation are going to have a huge impact on anime Legally released in the United States, but you won't see that impact for a year or plus ish Around a year at least minimum or maybe a little less me a little more.
Speaker 0: It's interesting though that this is also happening at a time when the distribution side like how people actually watch anime Is having a pretty increasingly large splintering to where there isn't just one place.
Speaker 0: You can watch all your anime Mm-hmm, and on one hand I was very happy when it was crunchyroll or bust because that was just easy.
Speaker 0: I could see a lot of anime.
Speaker 0: I'm basically not willing to pay for multiple services.
Speaker 1: Nope.
Speaker 1: I pay for one at a time.
Speaker 0: That's my rule Yep, so I will weigh in the same area.
Speaker 0: So I pay for Netflix and crunchyroll because I watch a lot of Netflix right now.
Speaker 1: right now I'm paying for Hulu and crunchyroll, but as soon as The next your petal season is done and there's a new anime to watch I'll temporarily turn my crunchyroll off.
Speaker 0: ever though cuz we're gonna we're gonna review a lot more anime.
Speaker 0: on geek nights I keep picking crunchyroll shows, but if you switch to Netflix I'll just pick a show that I know is on that right and then one South Park is over.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna switch from Hulu to Netflix and watch some witches and some other stuff.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, you haven't seen witches Scott.
Speaker 0: it saved anime.
Speaker 0: It's so good.
Speaker 1: I mean we trigger saved anime a long time ago Yeah, but it can't save it anime again.
Speaker 0: anyway, it's crashed.
Speaker 0: that that itch I had from Maho skydive.
Speaker 0: so back in the day.
Speaker 0: My brain was just like what's this drug?
Speaker 0: It's back and then it ended.
Speaker 1: it knows like I've seen the little witch academia movies Did we actually do the episode on that second movie?
Speaker 0: No, we didn't know.
Speaker 1: I've seen it.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, I could watch that again.
Speaker 1: We could do episode at any time.
Speaker 1: Yeah Anyway, so yeah, just like when Disney bought Marvel, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, you didn't see changes for a while, but now you fucking do right.
Speaker 0: so same deal Yep, so we don't know if it'll be good or bad.
Speaker 0: I worry the changes will be negative partly because I don't necessarily trust I don't.
Speaker 1: I can't see them being positive.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that Sony will.
Speaker 1: they're gonna be neutral at best.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like I see them doing shady stuff around exclusive streaming deals and weird nonsense as well.
Speaker 1: You watch anime so it makes yourself a PlayStation 4.
Speaker 0: Yeah PlayStation exclusive for the first month on the simulcast who knows doesn't matter.
Speaker 0: I'm not even a lie If I try to pay for anime and I do pay like I pay for country roll and stuff and I even paid for the Funimation thing for a while back to watch like Yurikuma and stuff back in the day.
Speaker 0: Mmm got back in the day.
Speaker 0: That wasn't that long ago.
Speaker 0: No, but in all media the moment I encounter resistance where Figuring out how to click on buttons and pay money to watch something is even remotely challenging.
Speaker 0: Yeah I pirate so fast.
Speaker 0: I can't even blink.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, that's how I do.
Speaker 0: So it's kind of an aside.
Speaker 0: but in the other news, that's not really new news about anime But it's a topic That I feel like we could do a deeper show on in the future because it's starting to actually affect a lot of anime fans Now.
Speaker 0: so when our friends brought hocus-pocus over to watch it, they brought it on a DVD.
Speaker 1: Yeah I had the same problem recently.
Speaker 1: is I needed to show Porco Rosso to Amanda who hadn't seen it when one of the jubilee movies she had not seen better to be a pig than a?
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 1: and I was like, whoa, I actually happen to have the DVD of that and a bonus DVD that came with it.
Speaker 0: Hey remember I got like eight DVDs.
Speaker 0: a beautiful dreamer.
Speaker 1: So I went.
Speaker 1: I found the DVD I had in my binder of DVDs and I went over to the Htbc the new one that has no optical drive to speak of and I said, oh Yeah, my desktop still had an optical drive.
Speaker 1: So I used handbrake.
Speaker 1: I ripped it.
Speaker 1: I transferred it.
Speaker 1: We watched a nice mp4.
Speaker 1: It was all good.
Speaker 1: But I thought hmm maybe what I should do since I ain't planning to buy a computer maybe next year sometime when Nvidia 1180s come out, right?
Speaker 1: I don't not saying I'll buy an 1180, but I'll buy an 11 something.
Speaker 1: Yeah presumably maybe I should buy myself a USB 3 optical drive now and Just have it and then never had to buy another optical drive again.
Speaker 1: As long as I live that is what I did because actually mine doesn't play booray.
Speaker 0: No, why would I ever have booray?
Speaker 1: Well, the thing is I never planned to ever buy a booray in my life and I've managed to not do that up to this Point.
Speaker 1: so I see no reason that that would ever change.
Speaker 1: Yep, but there are occasions where you just come across a free booray.
Speaker 1: it's just lying around or someone else has one.
Speaker 1: and Or external booray drive that I say I know it's blue ray.
Speaker 1: I'm saying booray cuz.
Speaker 1: Same reason I say Titan even though I know it's pronounced Titan My.
Speaker 1: they're not really any significantly more expensive or different than any other optical drive that doesn't do booray.
Speaker 1: So I was like, oh well Why not get the booray one for that one day that someone's gonna bring a booray to your house.
Speaker 1: You can watch it.
Speaker 0: thing is I could probably just pirate whatever it is that they ostensibly have on that booray faster.
Speaker 1: Then I could get the booray Like, you know some data backed up on a booray because they have a booray writer or something or yeah.
Speaker 0: Also put it on the cloud.
Speaker 1: sorry kid it's to pay the ten bucks extra or whoever small amount it is to get the Slightly better.
Speaker 0: Oh, you want to I'm gladly.
Speaker 0: I will gladly sell you my old zip drive because someone might bring a zip disk over.
Speaker 1: What if?
Speaker 1: what?
Speaker 1: if it's like apocalypse times and the important data is on the zip disk and then I go in I pull out My zip drive and I'm like the world is saved bitches.
Speaker 0: All of his zip drives fail and zips fail.
Speaker 1: Why do you think I got my apple 2gs in the closet?
Speaker 1: gonna save the world with that motherfucking?
Speaker 0: But there's no Intel management in there in the old days, the only way to see anime was to pirate it.
Speaker 0: Well, the oldest days I'm skipping the old days.
Speaker 0: as far as most of you are concerned Please is.
Speaker 0: you either bought the DVD you saw in the theater in Japan or you pirated it.
Speaker 1: Japanese TV in this.
Speaker 0: but nowadays Pretty much we all just stream our anime Which is fine because I prefer streaming for almost all use cases and I generally don't buy physical media And I never have the exception to that is I would buy physical media before digital media really existed For things that I did not only watch but I had already seen in their entirety Mm-hmm that I thought were important for some reason and that I expected to not only rewatch Semi off like periodically for the rest of my life.
Speaker 1: give to other people to watch.
Speaker 0: Yes to show to other people like I will to this day be like, oh you haven't seen cowboy bebop.
Speaker 0: take this Come back to me, you know after this weekend and tell me what you think.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and now that physical media is stupid and I don't want all that space being wasted in my apartment.
Speaker 0: I don't really have any way to own anime because I'm certainly not buying physical media the way it's structured today And no one's gonna sell you a DRM free mp4.
Speaker 0: and the other important thing is even if I wanted to buy physical media not gonna buy physical media until I Watch a show.
Speaker 0: and I'm confident that that show is going to be a classic for all time.
Speaker 0: And I'm also not worried about the time I make that determination.
Speaker 0: It's usually out of print again.
Speaker 1: I'm also not worried about preservation because a everything that I thought would be like Oh, you'll never be able to get this is come back eventually.
Speaker 0: I went on YouTube and watch the Halloween special last night in college.
Speaker 1: I want to watch it in college.
Speaker 1: I pre-ordered this macross box set from anime go right for like almost $300 of college money Which is a lot Sitting your poor college student.
Speaker 1: I still have it.
Speaker 1: It's still great.
Speaker 1: I'm still glad I bought it.
Speaker 1: But now you can just watch the real macross not robo attack like on Amazon Prime streaming with subtitles.
Speaker 0: Nope, so You know now I don't want physical media and I'm not even afraid of DRM.
Speaker 0: The problem is streaming services stuff falls out of rotation.
Speaker 0: Then it's gone.
Speaker 0: Can't watch it unless you pirate it.
Speaker 1: Well, you know it comes back eventually.
Speaker 0: and also I'm sorry things don't you know.
Speaker 1: The other reason you don't worry about preserving is because eat there's some other nerd out there who's preserving it, right?
Speaker 1: Yep, it will always be accessible if you can find that one nerd.
Speaker 1: that nerd doesn't have to be me.
Speaker 1: I got better things to do with my short life on this earth now.
Speaker 0: the other reason I you I would have bought physical media was sometimes I want to do a review thing like with antenna and I want to like use that media to make other media which is a pain in the ass To do through a streaming service.
Speaker 0: So I just have to pirate that nowadays.
Speaker 0: But I want.
Speaker 0: there is still the use case where there is a show.
Speaker 0: that I decide is something I'm going to show to other people for a long time to come and I want to have per a file permanent access to it of some kind.
Speaker 0: What I really want is actually just a DRM free file that I can pay money for.
Speaker 0: I'll even pay good money for it And just download it and that doesn't exist.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: I've been doing that with Amazon for certain shows.
Speaker 0: I've been buying Steven Universe and Adventure Time instead of streaming.
Speaker 1: I thought about see the thing is you when you told me you did that I was like first I didn't realize they had that.
Speaker 1: They have like the newest episodes of Adventure Time on there.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like.
Speaker 1: they're up to speed with what like is somebody watching on Cartoon Network?
Speaker 0: so episodes on TV It's on Amazon within like a day, right?
Speaker 1: So that is really tempting.
Speaker 1: but how much does the season of Adventure Time cost on there?
Speaker 0: ten to twenty bucks?
Speaker 1: Okay, so how many seasons are there?
Speaker 0: the number of actual seasons?
Speaker 0: times two because they split them usually.
Speaker 0: So it costs about as much as an old anime box set to buy a many seasons long.
Speaker 1: It cost about the same as a right but it's like compared to the price It would cost to like just subscribe to the thing and keep watching them, but they don't offer it.
Speaker 1: on the prime subscription thing.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's just like I. you know, it's just so much money that it's like it's not worth it.
Speaker 1: But I do want to have access to those episodes.
Speaker 0: Yep, but we're through at the convenience.
Speaker 0: but anime for example can't rely on that kind of thing.
Speaker 1: Can you just give me those episodes so I don't have to buy them?
Speaker 0: Uh, I'd have to pirate them from my service cuz I can only watch them on the Amazon thing.
Speaker 0: But it does just work like it's great.
Speaker 1: I'm sure it does this work.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and I do trust it won't go away.
Speaker 0: I trust it as much as I trust steam.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there was a recent poll of like.
Speaker 1: which of the big tech companies do you trust the most?
Speaker 1: and Amazon was like number one In all categories.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but anyway, I don't want to go down.
Speaker 1: Amazon's not evil.
Speaker 1: They're just evil in such a way that it punishes other businesses that aren't Amazon and is great for customers Which is why people love Amazon, even though they're just as evil as everyone else.
Speaker 1: The difference is Facebook punishes users.
Speaker 1: No, right Twitter punishes users.
Speaker 1: Google punishes users.
Speaker 1: I guess Amazon only punishes other businesses by putting them out of business.
Speaker 0: I still think physical media is stupid because physical media is just digital media locked on to a format for no good reason.
Speaker 0: I'd rather just get a file.
Speaker 1: even if I had the bure drive and I was willing to buy buries I would just rip them all and throw them out.
Speaker 1: Yep, or tell them or bring them to book off or who knows what?
Speaker 1: So just like we did back in high school with PlayStation games.
Speaker 1: Yeah copy them to another CDR.
Speaker 1: Bring them back.
Speaker 1: You turn mod shit on a blockbuster rent the game copy it bring it back.
Speaker 0: So, uh, yeah There's the these fracturing of all these different streaming services coupled with all the different ways to get media It the the problem
Speaker 1: is growing
Speaker 0: again rather than shrinking which I think is gonna drive a lot of people like me back to the high seas, sir, and that's all I got to say about that because it's time for things Of the day.
Speaker 0: So if you don't follow it, which actually not that many people subscribe to this channel.
Speaker 0: And again, I gotta be very clear I am NOT saying that you should watch the original he-man again in any capacity.
Speaker 0: No, I Made that mistake.
Speaker 1: I learned a thing I watched when I was extremely young and had almost no memories of it other than like vague images of and Toys more than the show because the show You know didn't air for that battle damage Skeletor.
Speaker 1: like there's a point in my life where I must have been like five or six and wanted to watch he-man because I had He-man toys and it just was not on TV anymore and I couldn't see it.
Speaker 1: and it's not like you could.
Speaker 1: well It was later by VHS tapes of he-man.
Speaker 1: You know this like it wasn't the thing you couldn't do that, but way more it wasn't until I'm here in college.
Speaker 1: They put out like transformers on DVD and I was like, whoa I can actually see that.
Speaker 0: now way more interesting than actually watching episodes of he-man is Learning about all the meta around the production of he-man itself and the character.
Speaker 1: Didn't I do a thing in the day about that?
Speaker 1: No, I did thunder the barbarian.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so the Official like for real official he-man YouTube account which has less than a hundred thousand subscribers And these videos have fewer views than a lot of our penny like packs lectures.
Speaker 0: So you should probably subscribe to this.
Speaker 0: the content there is pretty good and fascinating.
Speaker 0: So what I'm linking to here is a pretty long video.
Speaker 0: It's like 10 minutes long and it's just 50.
Speaker 0: Interesting things about evil Lynn.
Speaker 0: and if you don't remember who evil Lynn was no I remember this.
Speaker 1: the thing is the only positive.
Speaker 1: the most positive thing about he-man at least for me is the character design.
Speaker 1: You're all these crazy characters because they're trying to make all these toys that I bought.
Speaker 1: If I see a character I go that's a he-man character and unless it's he-man or skeleton or she-ra or something or orko I don't know their name.
Speaker 1: I'm like who the hell is that?
Speaker 1: You could have showed me that character and I say that's the evil lady from he-man.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I didn't know she was evil in till just now.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and I also couldn't tell you the plot of any episode.
Speaker 0: I Vaguely remember the plot of some of these episodes but anyway, this video is just kind of fascinating and If you watch t-man as a child and don't remember much about it, don't go.
Speaker 1: don't go ruin your positive memories by Going to see this show.
Speaker 1: that's awful.
Speaker 0: But this video will probably trigger a lot of weird flashbacks and you'll realize you remember more than you thought.
Speaker 1: Nope, I definitely don't.
Speaker 0: you don't remember the space battleship.
Speaker 0: No, don't remember evil in teaming up with the sorceress woman and Skeletor.
Speaker 1: No.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't.
Speaker 0: so what do you got?
Speaker 1: So You know these days in the in the hockey times.
Speaker 1: There's not as many fights as there used to be which is a good thing.
Speaker 1: Yeah, because fighting is barbaric and bad and we don't want to see that.
Speaker 1: we want to see hockey hockey.
Speaker 1: I went to hockey game last night.
Speaker 1: There were no fights.
Speaker 1: It was still exciting as hell.
Speaker 1: We don't need fights in hockey.
Speaker 1: I'm glad that there are less of them and there should be none of them.
Speaker 0: No, it's it's perverse, but I am also glad that it did exist at some point because I do enjoy hockey fight.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean if it never existed that would have been fine too true, but you can't lie.
Speaker 1: I enjoy a night watching a nice hockey fight, but so many Happened.
Speaker 1: there are already been so many hockey fights and I can already re-enjoy them.
Speaker 1: Thanks to the magic We don't need any more.
Speaker 1: there's already enough that I can get all the enjoyment from hockey fights that I need for my whole life by watching the ones that have already happened.
Speaker 1: and Today, I discovered one that is better maybe than any most I have seen top five maybe.
Speaker 1: so this is not in the NHL it's in the ECH L between a hockey team from Tallahassee, which is where versus the Louisiana ice gators.
Speaker 1: So these are southern United States hockey teams well below the messier line where hockey does not belong.
Speaker 1: February since it was winter 98 is pretty much like.
Speaker 1: this is near the peak of like the last era of this kind of fight and even though this is a minor league hockey game, it was apparently being broadcast and Commentated.
Speaker 1: and whoa, this is some brawl they had here.
Speaker 0: Now frankly even as a kid like minor league hockey had way bigger fights than real hockey.
Speaker 1: It's still true today.
Speaker 1: every time I go to a minor league hockey game.
Speaker 1: There's always a fight.
Speaker 0: the Majority of the Detroit Falcons games I ever went to as a kid had a bench clearing brawl that's halted the game.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like I'm not the the full real majority of the games I ever saw cleared the benches.
Speaker 0: The best part about this video is the announcers.
Speaker 1: It's really weird right because when you get to hockey that's super unprofessional like if you go to the roller hockey down it where I was Taking photos.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you'll never see a fight there cuz the cops will come.
Speaker 1: the cops are actually standing there the whole time.
Speaker 1: I don't think they were looking for fights, but you know the point is You'll be guilty of assault.
Speaker 1: They were looking for offsides sure And it's super professional hockey.
Speaker 1: at the top levels.
Speaker 1: You see less fighting because people are making a zillion dollars, and they don't need a broken face or a broken leg, right?
Speaker 1: But in the in-between hockey, it's all happy Gilmore.
Speaker 0: Oh, baby.
Speaker 0: So in the meta moment the book the book was the fifth season we did the episode.
Speaker 0: Nope, I'm gonna wait until I finish the entire trilogy of this broken earth or whatever the rest of the books from the fifth season because I had just finished the second one.
Speaker 1: and This weekend November 4th and 5th gamer X East LGBT focused gaming convention you do not have to be LGBT or any other have to be in New York and like games and show up and probably not a homophobe.
Speaker 1: Homophobe is probably the only people who shouldn't be there, and it's a pretty great con.
Speaker 0: It's very well organized.
Speaker 0: We're gonna be doing our writing game rules lecture on Saturday at 3 30 p.m.. In panels B. The only notable thing about this lecture because this is a talk we've given before for the most part Is that because of the nature of this con.
Speaker 1: you know relatively metamoment fast is there many moments getting too big okay?
Speaker 0: We're gonna actually take questions.
Speaker 0: Well, we normally don't do that so that that is the only reason to attend.
Speaker 0: if you're already listening to the show I'm sad.
Speaker 1: on September 17 18 19 packs unplugged.
Speaker 1: Oh my god We're doing a carcass own thing.
Speaker 0: on Saturday also at 3 30 p.m.. We're doing the carcass own thing.
Speaker 0: It's weird.
Speaker 0: Parallel.
Speaker 1: okay.
Speaker 1: next on the calendar after that.
Speaker 1: oh I should also mention that this weekend in addition to gamer X is also Blizzcon is Friday and Saturday and the netrunner world championships are Saturday and Sunday.
Speaker 1: So if you're sitting at home and can't go to any conventions you can enjoy lots of gaming goodness on your twitch TV.
Speaker 1: Yep next month Nothing because that's December just it's holidays, and then we got magfest.
Speaker 1: we got packed south January of next year magfest pack south one two one two first week of the month second week of January.
Speaker 1: It's just all con all the time.
Speaker 1: Oh my god.
Speaker 0: It's gonna be great It's gonna be glorious.
Speaker 1: and of course if you can't do any of these things because you're really sad Follow us and all the places on the internet that exist.
Speaker 1: we got multiple YouTube channels Instagram You can find all these things.
Speaker 1: just if you have any brain.
Speaker 1: You know how to use Google.
Speaker 1: you can find it if you want to.
Speaker 1: We are the most public you can be on the internet, and you can follow all of our activities.
Speaker 0: I'm not as public as what's-his-name in a on flux.
Speaker 1: if you're already so sad that you're listening to geek nights And you're hearing my voice right now Then you might as well just you know be even sadder.
Speaker 0: so a nice segue from the meta into our review of an anime shock.
Speaker 0: It's been a while.
Speaker 0: the ancient Magus is bride.
Speaker 0: Part of the reason why we're doing this show and reviewing it is that as you might have noticed on Scott's YouTube channel We have taken the old anime Boston thing where we would review the upcoming season of anime Before
Speaker 1: it came out
Speaker 0: based solely on an image and maybe a paragraph at most Mm-hmm, and we're pretty much always right about these shows.
Speaker 0: so to put our money where our mouth is We're gonna try to review a lot of the shows that we already reviewed on that on that video By actually watching them and see.
Speaker 1: if we don't remind me what we said about this show Let's talk about the show and then remind me what we said about it.
Speaker 1: so the ancient You know I don't taint it to like you know agree with myself my heart's kind.
Speaker 0: Oh, you may wish Yeah, if you've seen my heart's guy tie you can figure out what all those words mean and how they line up it literally.
Speaker 0: is the bride of the ancient Magus or mage or magic user?
Speaker 0: yes, and it is the story of a Reason has replaced his head with a deer skull or always had a deer skull that we don't know what he looks like.
Speaker 0: We don't really know.
Speaker 1: yeah at one point.
Speaker 1: He does cover it up with like a sheet Yep, so I guess he also uses that magic to hide it from muggles when he's out.
Speaker 1: It's a human body with a deer skull for a head.
Speaker 1: It's the Skeletor model, but otherwise body skeleton head yes, but otherwise he acts like a nice professor You know very powerful and wise mage who obviously has a lot of secrets and possibly evil ones in his past.
Speaker 0: Meanwhile there's this girl who?
Speaker 0: Has sold herself into slavery for reasons right.
Speaker 1: so basically in the first episode It's really structured.
Speaker 1: quite strangely is that they show you the present and introduce these characters But they don't really introduce something to sort of show them right.
Speaker 1: like this is the living situation.
Speaker 1: She lives in a house with this wizard guy and this other thing and this servant Person who's cooking clearly a fairy and this dude who turns into a dog or dog who turns into a dude?
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, right who seemed cool, but you don't know anything about him anyway.
Speaker 1: And then that episode and I guess also the second episode Basically are just a flashback to show you like her early life.
Speaker 1: It doesn't actually show you how she ended up in this situation It just shows.
Speaker 1: you like her origin story of like you know going from orphan to entering the world of magic ness.
Speaker 0: so the Show itself.
Speaker 1: you know we watch a bunch of episodes so we can review this the way we typically have seen until this episode Where they go to the dragon land which is I'll be three I think or four maybe at most.
Speaker 1: on one hand I think it's three.
Speaker 0: It's if you describe the plot naively.
Speaker 0: it has a few warning signs in the sense of This mage buys a woman out of slavery.
Speaker 1: Very young clearly less than 18 year old girl 15. okay to be his wife.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the wife is in the title of the show, but there is.
Speaker 1: I've not seen any wife activity in the show.
Speaker 0: What he said.
Speaker 0: I want you to be my wife someday.
Speaker 0: He says this to her like ten times, I don't remember that.
Speaker 0: we just watched it.
Speaker 1: I don't remember that part.
Speaker 0: Okay, okay anyway anyway, so uh That aside while that is in the show it does not go in the direction that that might imply.
Speaker 0: It's more like a slice of life show about Really in human beings interacting with each other in parallel to humans in a world where magic is slowly dying Which is very similar actually to the world of Little Witch Academia.
Speaker 1: There's also a conflict going on between apparently some evil magic and some good and some not evil magic.
Speaker 0: But it's not really clear what all that is the show.
Speaker 1: It's very mysterious like this.
Speaker 1: something's like a dark blobby thing.
Speaker 1: That's you know obviously evil attacking some nice library, and you know messing with shit, right?
Speaker 0: Well, I guess what you learn about the world you learn from the mage the same way that this girl learns it.
Speaker 0: yep and a lot of the episodes just seem to Introduce over time all these various fantastic like fairies and dragons and other mages and other beings.
Speaker 0: you're not really sure what their deal is and You sort of just see them all interacting and stuff playing out.
Speaker 0: and the thing I think it does very well.
Speaker 0: That I'm very pleased with because this is something that eccentric family did even better is There are inhuman characters who clearly have inhuman sensibilities and do not act like humans.
Speaker 0: the fairies are appropriately dangerous Mm-hmm in the way that a fairy would be expected to be based on the actual fiction about fairies.
Speaker 1: the dragons are dragon e Yep, the super old dragon keeping guy.
Speaker 1: He's a super old dragon keeping guy.
Speaker 0: Yeah He reeks a little bit of the kind of character I would play in the D&D game though, yes Yes, he is.
Speaker 0: everyone has pointed that out.
Speaker 1: the only real negative thing I want to say about this show is that is kind of slow, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, it has a little bit that slice of life feel like we're gonna go to the land of the dragons And it seems like oh, it's not gonna be a good thing.
Speaker 1: It's not that it's slow, and then nothing happens, right?
Speaker 1: It's like I watched one episode and they were.
Speaker 1: I learned about dragons and a lot happened and the plot concluded.
Speaker 1: It's like a thing happened right?
Speaker 1: It's just that you'll get these shots and some people can see this as a positive, but I don't Where I see it as a positive actually when it occurs in anime movies where you got a lot shots where it's just like alright look it's a picture of the dragon land and we're panning across a Landscape and listening to noises and some dragons are flying over Right and it's like you're just watching like scenery and setting a mood Right and it and that you stay in that on those sorts of shots for like a good 10 20 seconds something like that.
Speaker 1: Right, you know and in anime movies those shots are great.
Speaker 1: You got to open your movie with those, right?
Speaker 1: I love an Evangelion, you know, like they'll have the elevator scene.
Speaker 1: shit Like.
Speaker 1: well, no shot the ones that all I always remember from evangelical shot.
Speaker 0: You hear the crickets.
Speaker 1: Yes crickets They're cicadas.
Speaker 1: They show the outside the school in the summer and you hear cicadas for a good like five seconds And then they cut inside the school or inside the apartment right after that.
Speaker 1: right it's like this show is loaded with shots like that where just Things are physically moving slowly.
Speaker 1: They're showing you things happening second by second and creating these, you know We're not plot is not advancing and you're sitting there watching but ostensibly atmosphere is being created.
Speaker 1: Right, you're watching for like a good 20 seconds to a minute and nothing.
Speaker 1: No one says anything No one does anything and that happens a lot.
Speaker 1: So like the first two episodes could have been done in one episode if you cut out some of those scenes.
Speaker 0: right and that I guess Atmosphere like that kind of atmospheric setting is very common in anime.
Speaker 1: and oh, yeah.
Speaker 1: But I think in this show it like I. it is common in anime I expect it and like it.
Speaker 0: but in this show it was to the extent where I felt it, you know dragging a little bit well because in this show unlike say eccentric family, which does very similar things I Compare these two shows a lot because there's a lot of interesting comparisons to make.
Speaker 1: eccentric family has the fun characters.
Speaker 1: This show does not have any characters that I really liked other than the old dragon guy.
Speaker 1: Yeah well I guess we're not the dragon person the actual dragon.
Speaker 0: when Eccentric family who wanted or other or other great anime that I never feel bored at any second watching them Even when they have atmospheric setup shots like that the atmosphere Ties into the allegory or the story of the episode very neatly Or there's some sort of very nice interconnected artistry to it in this show.
Speaker 0: It almost feels like we need atmosphere here it is, but it doesn't tie into any sort of overarching real story Relation or allegory or like.
Speaker 0: it doesn't intertwine.
Speaker 1: those shots in Evangelion with the cicadas are reminding you that it's summer Reminding you that there's nobody left here.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right They're like they have a purpose.
Speaker 1: if you see it right the ones in this show don't really have a purpose.
Speaker 1: They're just sort of like you're sort of like wait like you're just like alright now.
Speaker 1: She's walking towards the library.
Speaker 1: Can we get to the library already?
Speaker 0: No, I think part of that is that the as Interesting as the show is again.
Speaker 0: I like it.
Speaker 0: I'm not saying it's a bad show.
Speaker 0: It definitely feels very shallow in that.
Speaker 0: the thing the themes that are being explored the stories everything Doesn't feel like there's that much under them.
Speaker 1: No, it's pretty much just like okay.
Speaker 1: What's the best?
Speaker 0: Oh you went to the dragon land?
Speaker 0: Oh, here's the dragon life cycle.
Speaker 0: Yep, and now we're leaving.
Speaker 0: Yep, and that's kind of it.
Speaker 0: So you get this very long atmospheric scene with this feeling of pathos and Understanding for this old dragon and the life cycle.
Speaker 0: and but at the same time You just met all these characters and it's a throwaway.
Speaker 1: I also created a Chekhov's gun where he's like, oh you're gonna make a branch for me You're gonna take one of my branches to make a magic wand one day and you know that it's some later episode She's gonna come back and make the wand and use it to solve something.
Speaker 0: But because these can these dragons were all introduced in this episode and then I'm leaving them in this episode.
Speaker 0: I didn't really have any real investment in the life cycle.
Speaker 0: That was repeatedly Telegraph by those children child dragons and just really shallow and kind of hamfisted.
Speaker 1: Yeah Well, I mean it's really the main problem is that I just don't like or care about any of the characters.
Speaker 1: I actually cared more about that story where when she was an orphan and the parents broke up because she was like draining on Their family and that mom was all upset like I think something much more tragic happened there that we're gonna.
Speaker 0: we haven't learned yet.
Speaker 1: No, I'm pretty sure it's just that the mom, you know, the the the problems between those two parents were Exacerbated and revealed by them having to actually, you know deal with this problem that they encountered.
Speaker 1: I never see those parents and kids again in this in this.
Speaker 0: I suspect we'll see more in flashbacks of that.
Speaker 1: I don't see.
Speaker 1: I think we'll see them again.
Speaker 1: But the point is I care about them more than I care about the the main girl The guy with the skull head like this terrible secret of space.
Speaker 1: Like why does he have a skull head the main girl?
Speaker 1: I don't care that much.
Speaker 1: I'm like every anime has this terrible secret of space like that.
Speaker 0: The main girl has no Real personality and are only defining characteristics.
Speaker 0: are she's the super powerful thing that we're gonna have a proper noun for yep, and Her past is tragedy.
Speaker 1: Yep and there are some characters who seemed like they cool and might have a good personality like the Dragon-keeping guy and the guy who turns into a dog or dog who turns into a guy.
Speaker 1: I can't tell what the Where dog or dog where I don't know but it's like all they do is show you them for like a few seconds.
Speaker 1: They don't really give them the serious attention to make you like them or give you any info.
Speaker 1: I'm sure they'll get their episodes.
Speaker 1: But you know It's like you.
Speaker 1: look at some other anime that has a cast of characters and they introduce a lot more characters a lot sooner and actually Introduce them.
Speaker 0: Yep, but that's it.
Speaker 0: It moves slow It has a lot of slice-of-life elements and the actual world building and character development are both actually Pretty shallow and they don't feel like they're all tying together into a deeper Overarching allegorical narrative.
Speaker 0: I feel like it's going to be a very direct non allegorical narrative.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like usually.
Speaker 1: My gut feeling is that when you have a terrible secret of space thing, right?
Speaker 1: Why does he have a skull head?
Speaker 1: What's the deal?
Speaker 1: and you if it's going to be revealed?
Speaker 1: well And you're actually gonna March on this plot that you'll have episodes that March on the plot.
Speaker 1: Right when you get these slice-of-life life episodes It feels to me like it's gonna be one of those not actually ending.
Speaker 1: you're never gonna learn anything, right?
Speaker 1: Well part of that is just backdrop cuz cowboy bebop has a lot of slice-of-life type episodes.
Speaker 0: But a big difference too is that those episodes the plot didn't advance but the characters did.
Speaker 1: Well partly because the characters change even if the world the characters You don't need to know what the terrible secret is.
Speaker 0: But in this show the characters haven't really don't really change in any deep way at least not quickly.
Speaker 0: Nor does the world change.
Speaker 0: you're just getting a reveal of.
Speaker 0: here's the deal with this world.
Speaker 0: But that aside the animation is great.
Speaker 0: The the show is beautiful Soundtracks good.
Speaker 0: the opening themes good.
Speaker 0: I like the opening theme.
Speaker 0: it it reminds me of some older anime Mmm, I like the opening and closing animations.
Speaker 1: Nah, I don't like the.
Speaker 1: the song is just sort of like a Kind of like the opening song.
Speaker 1: it's not something I'm gonna jam to.
Speaker 0: well, no, I mean if you want a jam You gotta watch Gundam seed.
Speaker 0: Yeah But I guess I'm gonna keep watching it for a while and it's only 12 episodes.
Speaker 0: I think so I can finish it.
Speaker 1: You tell me if you find out why he has a skull head and then tell me why he has a skull head and I'm gonna Watch something else.
Speaker 0: I'll keep watching until I get.
Speaker 1: it's not a bad show It's just.
Speaker 1: it's not a show that I'm gonna spend my time When I got all this stuff I can do.
Speaker 0: it uses these scenes that are clearly meant to set an atmosphere And then make you feel a very strong emotion about something that's happening.
Speaker 0: But that strong emotion is not deserved by the show for what it has shown you up to that point Mm-hmm, so it acts like this is a very important moment and this is very somber and you should feel this.
Speaker 0: but you don't feel it intrinsically because They're telling you to feel it and showing you a thing as opposed to making you feel it through the actual evolution of character And story.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: That's pretty much the harshest thing I can say about a show that I still kind of like All right.
Speaker 1: Yeah I mean compare the way they you know They.
Speaker 1: they basically literally tell you what the dragon's deal is and the dragon talks and says what his deal is.
Speaker 0: I've never been a fan of right.
Speaker 0: Here's the thing.
Speaker 0: What's the deal?
Speaker 0: deal is explained.
Speaker 0: end of episode.
Speaker 1: That dragon is really similar to for example the robots from La Pita.
Speaker 1: now compare how you feel about robots from La Pita to this dragon guy.
Speaker 0: So don't even talk because I've seen both Nao Chica and La Pita in the theater very recently.
Speaker 0: I have some very.
Speaker 0: that's a very good point to make about those robots because the robots in La Pita Get very little actual screen time.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah almost none.
Speaker 0: Their origins are not explained in any explicit way Explicit enough.
Speaker 0: No, no, no No.
Speaker 0: So the beauty of La Pita is that the characters are pretty on know worthy like they're just sort of all there to set the world.
Speaker 0: the entire movie The entire movie is this beautiful case study in environmental storytelling.
Speaker 0: You've just the places the characters visit the things that are in the world around them tell this epic story of the rise and fall of civilizations and technology over the endless ages.
Speaker 0: and the story of those individual characters is almost just a way to experience that.
Speaker 0: and the robots have a Very a very complex implied story, but no character says these robots were made for X And this is why why happened.
Speaker 0: but ancient magus bride is literally Dragons work like this and this is why this dragon is turning into a tree.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: So yeah, I'll keep watching for a while.
Speaker 0: It just happened.
Speaker 1: He turned into a tree while you were here.
Speaker 1: Aren't you lucky?
Speaker 0: Well, I mean isn't that the Galaxy Express of every planet you're getting to is having its existential crisis just at the moment that the train arrived?
Speaker 1: Well a lot of times it's the existential crisis is Not something that's on the planet.
Speaker 1: It's oftentimes.
Speaker 1: It's a small like.
Speaker 1: it's not something that's a planet-wide thing.
Speaker 1: It'll be like they encounter a character who's crying in the street and that's you know It's a small crisis.
Speaker 1: that true honor or them coming is the catalyst for the crisis.
Speaker 1: That is also true showed up on the planet.
Speaker 1: therefore trouble.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's alright.
Speaker 0: I enjoy it.
Speaker 1: Okay if you you know If you're the kind of person who watches Animes that aren't a plus animes then watch this one because it's probably better than most of the other ones.
Speaker 0: Also, a lot of people are talking about it.
Speaker 0: So watch at least one or two episodes So you'll know what they're talking about.
Speaker 1: It's not something you need to go run out and watch.
Speaker 0: the manga has been recommended to me a lot over for a while So that was part of why I was feeling that a manga would give you more plus.
Speaker 1: you could read it a lot faster.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but the animation and the color and everything is really great in the anime.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: It looks nice.
Speaker 1: Yes It's nice to look at the mod.
Speaker 0: the monster like the dragons and the fairies are just really well animated and cool feast for them eyeballs, especially like the library scenes.
Speaker 0: So Here is the audio from our judge anime by its cover segment on this exact show.
Speaker 0: So, let's see.
Speaker 0: All right, we were No, yum.
Speaker 0: Oh, this is that wife of the magus bride.
Speaker 1: Anyway, this description for this one Chisei has lived a full life full of neglect and abuse Far from the warmth of family.
Speaker 1: then all hope is lost.
Speaker 1: a fateful encounter with a man with a beast head wielding strange Already.
Speaker 0: it's not just a beast head.
Speaker 0: It is a beast skull head.
Speaker 0: It is Skeletor face.
Speaker 0: It's Skeletor.
Speaker 1: this Reminds, but it's hot Skeletor.
Speaker 1: I mean it a little bit of.
Speaker 1: you know.
Speaker 1: Just based on that only a little bit of goo and saga.
Speaker 1: right goo and saga is about the guy with the cheetah head.
Speaker 1: Yeah, or there's a leopard head.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: He's some sort of dangerous.
Speaker 1: You know cat head right and in goo and saga and here you have a dude with a day a mysterious skull head, dude Rescuing some girl.
Speaker 0: I feel like this might be.
Speaker 0: it says fantasy, but this might be in monster boy genre.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but it's not a boy.
Speaker 1: It's it's a girl.
Speaker 0: right monster mysterious man who I will romance?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: Okay, he acquires her through a slave auction.
Speaker 0: Her life will never be the same.
Speaker 1: Yeah something something's up here that you know, it doesn't seem completely, right.
Speaker 1: It seems like on the one hand you might have this fantasy thing going on.
Speaker 1: That might be cool.
Speaker 1: But on the other hand you got this creepy dude plus little girls Action, that's not good.
Speaker 0: It looks I don't know.
Speaker 0: It looks more high concept and tasteful based on this single.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it has a little bit of vampire hunter.
Speaker 1: D feels as well Right because the the dude is all with his cape and whatnot.
Speaker 0: I would give this one episode.
Speaker 0: All right, you give it your one.
Speaker 1: it's above the line.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I never heard of wit studio though.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but you know what?
Speaker 1: That's just we don't know.
Speaker 0: studio hot Skeletor monster boy.
Speaker 1: All right, that's your guy.
Speaker 0: Move on this has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Speaker 1: crew comm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 0: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 0: But unlike those other late shows It's actually recorded at night and the patreon patrons for this episode of geek nights are Ellen Joyce, Heidi me nickel Amanda do shadow shimmering Ruby obelisk hanging in the sky.
Speaker 0: my state calm.
Speaker 0: Will you Jeremy minor a genuine bonafide like five six car monorail Sean Yeager Matthew Smith?
Speaker 0: Nicholas Brando captain Chinguak is he Rebecca Dunn for two one creations?
Speaker 0: No, I never ever wonder why we're here's number five bitch Shervin but horror rarely.
Speaker 0: Val James David White Rochelle, Monta Nona superboy rim says something funny here.
Speaker 0: sailor Vista Don't like a jar tofish and Joe Shiro Joe stars Sam Cordery Clinton Walton written from New Zealand Ryan Perrin drope and Lander Brian Cidron II Finn Chris mid give Chris Knox Daniel Redmond John Klein Chris Reimer and Thomas Hahn.
Speaker 0: it's November.
Speaker 0: No more spookiness.
Speaker 0: So now I just leave you.
Speaker 0: Then it starts to rag down Louisiana ice skater bench.
Speaker 0: Louis Bédard along with Paducah Bédard now being hammering on the benches well over now, this is just getting out of hand here is Paducah's been hit by the Louisiana ice skater bench and he's ready to go after the entire bench.
Speaker 1: I'll tell you what there better be some big-time penalties handed out here as Louisiana on their player bench.
Speaker 1: We're punching but do.
Speaker 1: And now wine gardeners gonna get a hand in lunch by Louis Bédard through center and Paradise holding his man back.
Speaker 1: You got to love that.
Speaker 0: And now Louie and wine gardener, they're gonna go at it.
Speaker 0: They owe a big flap a big right by wine gardener.
Speaker 0: He's starting to get hammered by a Louis.
Speaker 0: Louis is just hammering wine gardener.
Speaker 0: Oh my it's both tires gotta move in now Louis gonna.
Speaker 0: right now spolt are off the bench comes an ice skater.
Speaker 0: It's Piziak off the bench.
Speaker 0: now Paducah he just hammered Piziak from behind.
Speaker 0: It's just hammered Piziak.
Speaker 0: and now Garris comes off the bench and he's gonna hammer another ice skater.
Speaker 0: He's just hammering him with the right and a left.
Speaker 0: It's McEwen and this thing's gone out of hand as boy.
Speaker 0: Oh boy We've got three bouts going on.
Speaker 1: Garris came off the bench to take McEwen.
Speaker 1: now Paducah is just roughhousing.
Speaker 0: And Now it's a Paducah.
Speaker 1: we've got two fights going on.
Speaker 1: It's Garris and McEwen along with Piziak and Paducah.
Speaker 0: Now Paducah throws down Piziak and he's gonna start hammering them with the uppercuts.
Speaker 0: the ice skaters be feeding all over the ice As they're flat on their backs and the tiger sharks.
Speaker 0: This is straight out of swap shot.
Speaker 0: Oh my Paducah.
Speaker 0: one right after the last left right on top of the ice skaters as they are getting beat up physically There's nothing they can do.
Speaker 0: and now McDonald.
Speaker 0: McDonald is hammering a tiger shark's bench.
Speaker 0: and here comes Melanson to go.
Speaker 0: after McDonald Paducah gets free.
Speaker 0: This is an all-out war.
Speaker 0: now Landry hammering Melanson.
Speaker 0: I can't stay up with it.
Speaker 0: Oh my Unbelievable one fight.
Speaker 0: after the next breaking out here comes Shedden and Christensen.
Speaker 0: They're ready to go at it.
Speaker 0: the cold tenders.
Speaker 0: McDonald meanwhile great darling bonner.
Speaker 0: It's an all-out war.
Speaker 0: Here we go.
Speaker 0: It's bench against bench.
Speaker 0: Oh my this ain't getting out of hand.
Speaker 1: There's woods.
Speaker 0: and now the two benches confronting each other right out in front of each other.
Speaker 1: Well, Louisiana boy.
Speaker 1: Oh boy Being taught a lesson by the tiger sharks.
Speaker 1: We've never seen this before in this building.