Speaker 1: It's Monday August 21st 2017.
Speaker 1: I'm rim.
Speaker 1: I'm Scott, and this is geek nights tonight.
Speaker 1: We're talking about all the Monday topics that you the listener wants.
Speaker 1: Let's do this Pretty bit.
Speaker 1: we're good to go.
Speaker 0: All right, so you ever been to the pond cotillion home?
Speaker 1: I ate there today actually Okay.
Speaker 0: Anyway, if you don't if you don't live in a place that has those it's a chain restaurant.
Speaker 0: That's sort of Is kind of unique ish.
Speaker 0: it has French ish food and yet you can sit at the big table.
Speaker 1: Yeah, good fresh.
Speaker 1: They used to have a lot of good like takeaway lunch sandwiches But they really cut back on that to try to get you to pay way more money.
Speaker 1: Yeah for basically the same food sitting down.
Speaker 0: They sell the big cookie there.
Speaker 0: There's like a thousand calories.
Speaker 1: I got something I shouldn't have gotten.
Speaker 1: they had a thing they called a cookie a french cream donut and it was - yo tart.
Speaker 1: it was basically just a fried pastry filled with like Vanilla cream.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so it's a place and when I go there usually they had to sit this tartan.
Speaker 0: That's really good.
Speaker 1: All those tartans are so good.
Speaker 0: It's like ricotta cheese on a piece of bread and then they put prosciutto and fig and aruba.
Speaker 1: I used to get the one that had like salmon and dill And they put honey on it, right?
Speaker 0: It's good stuff.
Speaker 0: So I was like, you know what I Was like thinking about it.
Speaker 0: Like I kind of want one of those.
Speaker 0: and then I was like, wait a minute That requires no cooking No cooking whatsoever.
Speaker 0: You can just buy bread Yeah, and a tub of ricotta cheese and I have honey and you buy a thing of prosciutto.
Speaker 1: so Discovered the ability to make your own lunch.
Speaker 0: you can make this thing and like five minutes for way less money than they charge.
Speaker 0: The bread I got at the grocery was not as good as the bread they have but I guess I could have bought a bread There or made a bread.
Speaker 0: I mean you can buy just baguettes there Yeah, but it you know, they make it on that tartan bread, right?
Speaker 0: No Yeah, but you know the bread from the grocery store wasn't bad.
Speaker 0: It just wasn't the same bread, but it Tasted basically the same.
Speaker 0: So that was a good time.
Speaker 0: I was like, oh and now I have like, you know The I have enough to like.
Speaker 0: make it again like, you know, like twice before I go to PAX.
Speaker 0: at least That's not too bad.
Speaker 1: We're picking up a CSA tomorrow.
Speaker 1: So we got a cook every night starting tomorrow to use up all that food, you know, if anyone out there it's like think you know.
Speaker 0: when you go to a restaurant or something and you think about The things you're paying for there that cost a lot of money.
Speaker 0: It's like some of those things like you have fancy steakhouse.
Speaker 0: They make a fancy steak.
Speaker 0: It's like you could do that But like there's actually.
Speaker 1: that's a way easier to do than a lot of the other things.
Speaker 1: It's pretty simple is easy to do.
Speaker 0: But even if I have the instructions on how to do it just doesn't you want to make a steak like in those places?
Speaker 1: Just sous vide it like it's gonna be fine.
Speaker 0: I'm just saying it's like the way they made.
Speaker 0: it's like I even if I try really hard and follow lots of internet instructions I just can't get it to taste the same way.
Speaker 1: I look at it more like something I do with like cocktails, but I never order a cocktail.
Speaker 1: That's really easy to make.
Speaker 1: I order the ones that are a pain in the ass to make because I don't want to make.
Speaker 0: There are some things that you might be buying at places that for a lot of money like computers that you could make very easily Like computers, right?
Speaker 0: You couldn't.
Speaker 0: you couldn't make a video card easily.
Speaker 1: No, but I can buy.
Speaker 0: The recipe for the guac at Chipotle is on the Chipotle website.
Speaker 0: I've made it.
Speaker 1: it's ridiculously easy Yeah, but guacamole is pretty easy to make in general.
Speaker 0: I'm just saying you can get the even.
Speaker 0: it comes out even better than what you get at Chipotle when you buy it there because It's fresh.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it just goes bad real fast.
Speaker 0: So I hope you have a lot of friends in a party to eat it.
Speaker 1: So I went out to watch the Eclipse and everyone went out to watch you.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the streets are all blocked in Midtown like our streets weren't blocked.
Speaker 0: Everyone was but there's I guess in the Times Square tourist zone There's lots of pedestrian walk.
Speaker 0: Yeah areas and the sign part was blocked by a lot of tall buildings.
Speaker 0: So people were huddled in masses in the areas where the Sun shone through.
Speaker 1: Yep Meanwhile shadow walkers like people just actually trying to get somewhere.
Speaker 1: We're like walking in the shadow between all these people.
Speaker 1: I was trapped in Bryant Park.
Speaker 1: I actually jumped a fence to get into the subway and then I walked through the subway to get out on the other side to Get away from the crowd.
Speaker 0: Oh, I don't have that problem.
Speaker 1: But the craziest thing was that you know, New York like strangers don't interact.
Speaker 1: when a stranger interactions You they're either trying to rob you or they're crazy Or they're all.
Speaker 0: in return is when there's a reason to interact It's like but they don't if there's no reason.
Speaker 0: they don't even you know, you don't acknowledge each other's existence.
Speaker 0: But once you have a reason, you know, which takes some doing but then you interact with them.
Speaker 1: Yeah And I watched a lot of people just like interacting and more importantly there weren't just like interacting and like talking about the Eclipse.
Speaker 1: people were like sharing and passing around their different Eclipse viewing glasses and it was like a big old block party.
Speaker 1: and So I actually the watch.
Speaker 1: I looked at it through a bunch of different kinds of glasses after checking them to make sure they weren't Fake.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: I saw easily two dozen people seriously hurt themselves looking at it without glasses.
Speaker 0: I saw people looking at the sun.
Speaker 1: I saw literally there's this husband and wife.
Speaker 1: They're kind of standing behind me and I hear the wife go.
Speaker 1: man I wish I brought my sunglasses and the guys like mine are working fine and I turn around and they're clearly regular sunglasses And I feel like that guy's gonna have a real bad day.
Speaker 0: There are a lot of tweets showing stupid people looking at the Sun.
Speaker 0: my favorite though was those one That was like our own president looking right up ahead.
Speaker 0: It was a Twitter search for the words Hurt my eyes my eyes hurt.
Speaker 0: Yes, and there was a lot of results.
Speaker 0: and then there was another one.
Speaker 0: This is the really good one.
Speaker 0: It was just clips from neo gaff discussion.
Speaker 0: And oh, I saw that one too and it was like a bunch of people like before the Eclipse saying like it's a bunch of bullshit.
Speaker 0: Yeah, my mom's eye doctor says, you know People are getting crazy for no reason.
Speaker 0: and then a whole bunch of boats like oh my god.
Speaker 0: No, they weren't.
Speaker 0: It's like I'm a fucking moron.
Speaker 0: Why did we not believe?
Speaker 1: But it was pretty cool.
Speaker 1: I'm glad I took the time to go and just sort of enjoy it because it didn't get crazy dark.
Speaker 1: I mean, we got like 70% in New York.
Speaker 0: I mean, I look it didn't get dark, but it's like I looked at it enough.
Speaker 0: I had brought my welding glass.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I already owned and was.
Speaker 0: apparently I was like, oh I have a welding glass.
Speaker 0: I wonder if that's sufficient.
Speaker 0: I went to the NASA safety website Yeah, and NASA was like you need a welding glass of 12.
Speaker 0: But some people for some people 12 is still not good enough.
Speaker 0: They you should get 14. mine was 12 and I'm like, well, they said it's safe with 12.
Speaker 0: So I looked at it for like a fraction of a second even with the glasses that seem legit.
Speaker 1: I only looked at it for like 10 seconds.
Speaker 1: I was like, okay, I saw it yeah, but I was more impressed by looking at the Dappling through the trees in Bryant Park.
Speaker 0: cuz it made a million little crescents all over the ground Reflections off the buildings like Buildings, but I also I brought made a box of the hole in it this morning.
Speaker 0: It took like one minute Yeah, and then I looked at my box of the hole in it and then I was like, okay I'm still amazed at how many people today seem to have no idea.
Speaker 1: an eclipse was happening Like how do you how do you live your life?
Speaker 1: It is not no stuff.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: How does that happen?
Speaker 0: I feel like my feet has been nothing but people talking about the eclipse Also, I think a lot of people don't respect the box of the hole in it.
Speaker 0: Yeah box of the hole in it is real good Camera without a film or a sensor.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you don't get the color aspect of it.
Speaker 0: Hey, dude, why not?
Speaker 1: I'll debate which poll because usually when people make the pinhole they use it to make the dapple effect and get the outline on The grounds.
Speaker 0: no, I made a box of the hole in.
Speaker 0: it is basically just a camera.
Speaker 0: You can look.
Speaker 0: you can like look at anything through it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know just you basically lets you look at stuff behind you as long as it's bright enough because it's a tiny pinhole.
Speaker 0: So you need a lot of light to see anything, right?
Speaker 0: Something behind you is real bright you can just see it in there.
Speaker 1: So anyway, that was fun and the next one will be a while from now.
Speaker 0: And I think the best thing I saw you could fly around the world to see a different one.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the best thing I saw was someone showed during the eclipses path.
Speaker 1: they took a Google or whatever one of those traffic sites and you can see the path of the eclipse in terms of where there were traffic jams When you're zoomed all the way out from the u.s.
Speaker 0: But I did.
Speaker 0: is I only looked at the eclipse a little bit because I figure I can see better Images of it on the internet.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and I can't.
Speaker 0: and why risk my eyes even with protection?
Speaker 0: Yeah, so I spent most of my time taking pictures of the people.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know I saw a lot of people doing being really into it and cheering and people were again hurting their eyes and yelling.
Speaker 0: a lot of People were like a lot of people are trying to take a picture with their phone And then I had mobile.
Speaker 1: people ask me just randomly like why aren't my pictures turning out?
Speaker 1: I was just like what's wrong with you?
Speaker 0: Some people are putting their you know, they're protective glasses in front of their camera work.
Speaker 0: Okay Good luck exposing it properly.
Speaker 1: I watch someone do that.
Speaker 1: They held it and they took their little like glasses.
Speaker 1: They held it in front of their phone.
Speaker 1: They held their phone up and then they went.
Speaker 1: ah because they looked right into the Sun with the realize because they were holding their glasses, yep.
Speaker 1: So in some news Intel is launched in their 8th gen core CPUs.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they've been going real slow.
Speaker 0: But I think is AMD with their rise ends actually pushing.
Speaker 0: I don't know what's going on.
Speaker 1: No, I'm honestly I'm not.
Speaker 1: it's really sure.
Speaker 0: schedule.
Speaker 0: I don't know the deal is.
Speaker 1: I'm not really sure if this is Nvidia pushing if the AMD Leap forward is going to be sustained or is even really relevant or not.
Speaker 0: a joke in the long run.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 1: uh, we'll see how this all goes.
Speaker 0: but anyway, the point the thing is this new a gen is Mobile only laptop only.
Speaker 0: so this is gonna be a big boost for like surfaces and Mac books and the.
Speaker 0: you know All the things we were complaining like the last MacBook is sucky.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Well, it's now when you get these chips in there It'll you it'll be significantly better, right?
Speaker 0: But the desktop is not upgraded yet, but it's coming.
Speaker 0: apparently.
Speaker 0: Yeah But it's not really.
Speaker 0: I don't think it's gonna be a major upgrade for the desktop area.
Speaker 0: really unless you're the kind of desktop That's like got an Intel CPU with no GPU.
Speaker 0: if you're that kind and maybe oh, yeah Then you're good.
Speaker 1: That's like the best use case for this.
Speaker 0: if you want to make a Tiny tiny computer that can play like 4k video, but if you are just if you have a GPU in there I don't think this is gonna be better.
Speaker 0: So I'm gonna build a new computer when the ninth gen CPU comes out.
Speaker 0: Yeah, whether it's the the what's I think this is what I don't not sure.
Speaker 0: There's like they want to talk about.
Speaker 0: there's like gonna be.
Speaker 0: the 10 nanometer is a 10 the next number.
Speaker 1: So.
Speaker 0: and then there's another one they talk about like coffee something.
Speaker 0: so I don't know which one of those is right now like.
Speaker 1: we're gonna wait and see which one of those is the good one by ridiculously fast like Crazy CPU on my new computer is running it like a little over a gigahertz right now.
Speaker 0: Yeah, my computer is actually just fine.
Speaker 0: I just you know, even the thing is Again, right?
Speaker 0: It's it's not nearly as bad as it was when I had that shady hard drive.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah That was crashing you but it's still got some some slight weird issues, right?
Speaker 0: so for example Like I'm not even near the computer and like it detects that like headphones have been connected in a dialog box.
Speaker 0: What?
Speaker 1: What?
Speaker 0: That's that's weird.
Speaker 0: It's not like before.
Speaker 0: it was like blue screening with some consistency But there was one blue screen like I came home from going out and those blue screen once and I'm like, huh?
Speaker 0: I want no blue screens.
Speaker 1: That is part of why I upgrade cuz my computer was way older than your computer.
Speaker 0: Yeah like Older, but it wasn't bad about maybe heat issues.
Speaker 0: So I'm definitely gonna get you know, it's like I could just buy a computer now with super cooling But that's stupid when I have a perfectly good computer.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but I gotta say like haven't gotten my new computer.
Speaker 1: It's just so nice that it's basically silent.
Speaker 1: It's so fast.
Speaker 0: Also somebody published this Google Doc.
Speaker 0: I can give you the link for it.
Speaker 0: That has.
Speaker 0: it's basically just a spreadsheet.
Speaker 0: It's read-only but someone's keeping it up to date and it has all of these small computer cases available Oh and all their stats in one big spreadsheet.
Speaker 0: so you can be like Oh.
Speaker 0: So I could find one that lets you put the GPU in sideways and also allows water cooling and I can get these a really Tiny computer.
Speaker 0: that's also godlike.
Speaker 1: Yeah, not too shabby.
Speaker 1: Maybe because when my current htpc finally dies That's the route I'm going there's gonna be like a tiny CPU and a tiny motherboard with a tiny m2 drive and like one RAM stick no video card.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I got a tiny Htpc, but it's got a 1070 in it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so I think I got a.
Speaker 0: I can play all the game.
Speaker 1: I think I still got a 460 in the htpc.
Speaker 0: I play all the games actually a better video card in the htpc than in my desktop.
Speaker 0: because you know Yeah, there's some games over there.
Speaker 1: So in some other news, this isn't really news I just want to point it out because it's kind of funny and I'm surprised this is being talked about as much as they.
Speaker 1: But if you didn't see it There's this dude who basically complained that he did something with Visual Studio and it deleted Like all the code he's ever written.
Speaker 0: I know this is weird cuz just the you know.
Speaker 0: Well a while ago we were talking about someone who was like an intern or just a new hire or at something at a company following the docs to set up their environment and yeah leading the production database, right and You know, it's like we blamed the company, right?
Speaker 0: This guy's deleting his own work and we're gonna blame him.
Speaker 0: How does that work?
Speaker 0: Well, it really just comes down to who was responsible for having backups.
Speaker 0: Yeah, their intern wasn't responsible for making backups.
Speaker 0: So, you know and he was following documentation, right?
Speaker 0: This is someone who installed a piece of software on their own.
Speaker 0: probably wasn't following any documentation written by anyone else Just doing things without knowing what they do independently One hard drive and has never backed anything up ever leading their own data and not having a backup.
Speaker 0: so they're responsible, right?
Speaker 0: It's you know, just the circumstances.
Speaker 0: but yet again, we can't.
Speaker 0: I mean we remind people all the time But we can't remind you enough if your data is not backed up.
Speaker 0: You might as well just delete it now.
Speaker 1: Yep, if you're if you couldn't survive Literally reaching your computer right now pulling the hard drive out from the running system and smashing it with a hammer You're not backed up enough And you should back your stuff up.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean like if you did that to me right now I'd lose data for sure.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but it's not any data I'd give a shit about.
Speaker 0: all the data I give a shit about is it is a back it up very nice Caught fire.
Speaker 1: My computer is up and running and I lost maybe a few hours worth of the work I'd done like in the two days before it caught fire.
Speaker 1: Otherwise, I was fine Mm-hmm, if every hard drive in the room, I'm sitting in now died.
Speaker 1: All of geek nights is still online Mm-hmm and backed up in a couple different places.
Speaker 1: so yeah, but in much more important news, especially considering the Times that we live in in the u.s.
Speaker 1: In particular iOS 11 is adding a very important feature.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so the thing that you know is like we talk about really good passwords, right?
Speaker 0: And I won't lie the password to unlock my phone.
Speaker 0: It's not one of those stupid swipey things like Android and it's not some crap.
Speaker 0: Oh four digit pin It's a real a password.
Speaker 0: Yeah Which by the way iOS has a mode where you can force a real password to unlock your phone.
Speaker 0: The problem is if you make that real password a password of any length of any significance You got to type that shit in on his iPhone Keyboard and type it in once in an elevator and the security company that works that elevator has it now exactly.
Speaker 0: So that kind of sucks.
Speaker 0: So typing it is really annoying.
Speaker 0: So what you want to do is you want to use, you know, the fingerprint scanner, right?
Speaker 0: So that you don't have to type it in all the time.
Speaker 0: The problem is at least legally in the United States as of today and we're not lawyers, right?
Speaker 0: As far as I'm aware They can't force you to reveal your password if they say arrest you and question you and I believe that comes down to the Fifth Amendment.
Speaker 1: yeah the Fifth Amendment and they can't prove you didn't forget it.
Speaker 0: So exactly.
Speaker 0: but if you have a fingerprint thing enabled they can force you to touch it.
Speaker 1: They can't.
Speaker 1: you can't say I lost my finger and I don't remember where I put it.
Speaker 0: You can chop your finger off and set it on fire.
Speaker 1: Yeah that might wonder if that would count as Tampering or something.
Speaker 0: I don't know but I'm not about to chop my finger off to protect my phone.
Speaker 1: It would depend on what I just done What I was worried they would find on my phone anyway.
Speaker 0: So but how do you get the convenience of the fingerprint sensor, right?
Speaker 0: Plus it does add security, right?
Speaker 0: I mean if you try to use the fingerprint scanner ten times my phone's just gonna erase itself.
Speaker 1: I just thought of something.
Speaker 1: actually one way you could do it make a rubber finger.
Speaker 0: By the way, I don't give a shit because I have backups.
Speaker 1: make a rubber finger pad That has a pattern that you just draw like an illustrator or something and then you printed.
Speaker 1: you use that.
Speaker 1: don't like your phone.
Speaker 1: No, you just know.
Speaker 1: just tear it off your finger and throw it away.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: But anyway, uh, So they're adding a new feature supposedly we don't know.
Speaker 0: this isn't for sure.
Speaker 0: We'll find out when iOS the next iOS actually hits but it seems pretty confirmed.
Speaker 0: They're adding a new feature where you can disable the fingerprint.
Speaker 0: So I think I read something along the lines of like you push the power button like five times fast or something.
Speaker 1: Yep, I got a quote here from a slash shot headline.
Speaker 1: this presents you with the emergency SOS option Which you can swipe to call emergency services.
Speaker 1: It prevents your iPhone from being unlocked without the passcode.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: So you basically hit the power button five times.
Speaker 0: like what are there five?
Speaker 0: and now you need the passcode?
Speaker 0: The fingerprint sensor has been disabled until you re-enable it.
Speaker 0: So now you like you're about to go to the airport go one of your five and then don't unlock your phone until you're through all the security bullshit and on the plane.
Speaker 0: I feel like what then when you're getting when you're heading towards the customs in the other Airport go one of your five and So forth and now even if they try to search your phone, it's like good luck assholes.
Speaker 1: Now what I would really want is a step beyond this.
Speaker 1: However, I realized that if they made what I want.
Speaker 1: a lot of people use iPhones would fuck up and do this to themselves But I want the option where if I put in a different passcode or like I swipe a different finger It immediately just wipes the phone.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, like this my real password and then there's another pass.
Speaker 0: Yeah, maybe the password should be delete my phone and press enter.
Speaker 1: But what I do what it would do is one it should immediately log in to a like pretty generic Interface with no accounts blank iOS screen.
Speaker 0: That looks like you just set up iOS with no data whatsoever And meanwhile while it presents that screen it is deleting everything.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: That's that's what I would like.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm kind of like in certain cut, you know, the thing is everything on the phone is already encrypted.
Speaker 0: So deleting it is it's it's like alright, whatever.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and if you're not gonna trust Apple who seems to actually for all we can tell they seem to actually care about the privacy.
Speaker 0: Oh, where was it?
Speaker 0: I read someone they were using to help unlock the dude's phone.
Speaker 1: Remember I think someone claimed I have a proof of concept of Compromising the security coprocessor on iOS like a reason.
Speaker 0: anything is possible.
Speaker 0: But the point is Apple seems to care Even though there may be Vulnerabilities.
Speaker 0: I think we can trust them at least on this one aspect also based on the pressure They've been under I get the fact that they would develop this feature earns them credit.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right not they're not a hundred percent trust No one is but it's like, you know If you're not gonna trust Apple after all they've done at least in this one area You just I guess you just paranoid nutjob might as well just make your own computer with the soldering.
Speaker 1: Well, you know we talked about this a long time ago.
Speaker 1: You gotta trust someone yeah, or if you're not gonna trust anyone you're gonna live a real hard life.
Speaker 0: I'll trust someone who makes this feature and fights the FBI, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I'm glad this feature is coming.
Speaker 1: So yeah, but anyway things of the day.
Speaker 1: I think I've seen people tweet like panels from this comic before but someone finally linked me to the comment.
Speaker 0: This is one of those things where it's like you don't realize it's a continuing webcomic.
Speaker 0: as you see it tweeted occasionally But you don't follow.
Speaker 1: I usually would see the one where this rabbits just sitting there and he's like, oh man What a fucking beautiful day.
Speaker 1: Look at that flower.
Speaker 1: Holy fuck.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 0: I've seen that one.
Speaker 1: Yep So this is the comic falls knees and it's basically that and I basically went through the whole archive.
Speaker 0: I didn't haven't read webcomics in so long.
Speaker 0: I gotta like get back on that train.
Speaker 0: you do.
Speaker 1: you're missing out on a lot.
Speaker 1: I mean, dr.
Speaker 1: Me ninja like is completely done.
Speaker 0: I know I haven't had to find I had to get back on the webcomic train.
Speaker 0: catch up and you cover quest Escalated Come request in print.
Speaker 0: I've have.
Speaker 0: I have a bunch.
Speaker 0: I have like at least three volumes that I've only read the first one.
Speaker 0: You don't even know.
Speaker 1: like nightmare nights deal I have to restart it.
Speaker 0: I basically forget it.
Speaker 1: You know what I could read the whole thing again.
Speaker 1: It's pretty good Order.
Speaker 1: the stick has been escalating rapidly.
Speaker 0: I'm sure it has.
Speaker 0: I haven't read any webcomic in over a year, too.
Speaker 1: What was the last thing you remember happening in order of the stick?
Speaker 0: There was like they were at this like.
Speaker 1: is anyone a vampire?
Speaker 0: Yeah, the dwarf was a vampire.
Speaker 0: No, the dwarf is dead inside a dwarf vampire who was at the meeting of all the cleric, okay You're not as far behind as I thought you were.
Speaker 1: that's when I stopped reading webcomics, but there's good stuff going on in there now.
Speaker 1: SMBC xkcd.
Speaker 1: Penny arcade today was actually plenty.
Speaker 0: arcade is one of the comics that I still haven't.
Speaker 0: I probably haven't read all of them since I stopped reading webcomics.
Speaker 0: By the way to start reading webcomics wasn't intentional.
Speaker 0: it was just like an accident.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and now it's like too daunting to catch up.
Speaker 0: But penny arcade will tweet like new comic and I'll click it and I'll read.
Speaker 1: so the one today was pretty good Yeah, but false knees is just cute.
Speaker 1: And if you want to see animals just just read it.
Speaker 1: It's it's hard to describe why I find it funny.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: So here's a my thing of the day.
Speaker 0: is this trailer for a movie and I think it's an independent movie Or is it British?
Speaker 0: I don't know where who's made it Doesn't seem like a Hollywood production, but it's a dark comedy about what a rims favorite not good people the style Joseph Stalin bad guy, so basically, the movie is about Stalin dies.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like in his office alone.
Speaker 0: I like the beginning and One.
Speaker 0: there's a whole bunch of other people who then freak out But it looks like an all-star cast.
Speaker 1: It's like it's like the Arrested Development slash Curb Your Enthusiasm Slash best in show kind of it looks and the way the trailer is set.
Speaker 0: It looks like the opening to snatch where they're like the Sun.
Speaker 0: Yeah the politician It's like.
Speaker 0: oh so you got all these, you know The cast of characters all getting all mixed up because Stalin just died and somewhat seriousness But also mostly comedy.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I I legit laugh.
Speaker 1: just watching like half of the trailer like this looks really good.
Speaker 1: It looks way good and bonus points for the fact that it is a movie made in English Set in Russia and instead of having everyone talk in fakie Russian accents.
Speaker 1: They just talk like themselves.
Speaker 0: Yeah, no one's trying to do a fake Russian accent, which is nice.
Speaker 1: Yeah that counts for a lot, but this movie looks Real up my alley.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so check out this trailer.
Speaker 0: is the movie out.
Speaker 0: Yeah I don't know anything about the movies release.
Speaker 0: You're gonna Google that yourself.
Speaker 1: I'll have to type it into IMDb.
Speaker 1: I'm not even gonna do that right now.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so in the moment the booklet book apparently is still dune.
Speaker 0: So it's the fifth element.
Speaker 0: I started reading it.
Speaker 1: I'm on the nice website and it says book club.
Speaker 0: I started reading the fifth season by NK jemisin on the train just now on the way here I'm in the prologue way.
Speaker 1: I was gonna do that But then I finish.
Speaker 1: I read the false son on the way to work.
Speaker 0: You know what?
Speaker 1: I realize I read the other other story on the way home.
Speaker 0: I realized recently I've made I found a way to make a simple but significant life improvement, right?
Speaker 0: All right, I finished basically playing race for the galaxy on my phone.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I win about 66% of the time now.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and I think I can literally not do better.
Speaker 0: But anyway, I was done.
Speaker 0: I'm like, all right I'm done playing race to the galaxy on my phone and I started trying to play war bits which is advanced wars.
Speaker 0: But the problem is it's not easy to play.
Speaker 0: I got the levels got more complicated.
Speaker 0: I couldn't play them in one train ride or one poop or anything anymore because they're real levels now.
Speaker 0: Right, they have like airplanes and stuff and not even boats.
Speaker 0: yet too much.
Speaker 0: So and I'm like got two opponents.
Speaker 0: Oh my god.
Speaker 0: So I'm like, I'm gonna get a new game and I went through the app store to look for a new game And I didn't really see much worth playing even stuff that caused money.
Speaker 0: There wasn't real.
Speaker 0: and you know, I'm like You know what.
Speaker 0: I'm not gonna play phone games anymore.
Speaker 0: It's gonna read.
Speaker 0: I'm just gonna read.
Speaker 0: I'll use the Kindle app and set all those games.
Speaker 1: It's not a bad idea.
Speaker 0: So whenever I feel like playing a phone game just open Kindle app read pages.
Speaker 1: once it's so winter again I'll start.
Speaker 0: I can just do that.
Speaker 0: I'm just gonna do that forever.
Speaker 1: I'm done with phone games because when I'm not a police of the short time in my life rather than reading what I usually do Is listen to podcasts, but when I listen to podcasts, I pretty much listen to Pseudopod and podcasts like it like short contemporary fiction.
Speaker 0: Hmm That's not to say I'm not gonna play any phone or mobile games.
Speaker 0: You're just only gonna play significant meaningful ones You know like yeah, like hey, let's play a carcass own while we're waiting.
Speaker 0: or hey I'm gonna play this war bits for serious or I'm gonna play Hearthstone, but I don't want to sit at the computer.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well playing race for the galaxy is just wrote at this point.
Speaker 1: So yeah.
Speaker 1: So yeah, the fifth season will be the book club book and well, I'll probably read it to and from packs.
Speaker 0: This is a soup a relatively new Super award-winning.
Speaker 0: Oh my god awesome book and the game won the Hugo Award two years ago or last year and the sequel to this book won the award this Year and the third one in the series just came out.
Speaker 0: So I'm probably actually just gonna read the whole series But we'll do the book club book after reading just this first one.
Speaker 1: Multiple people who are already fans of this stuff have come out of the woodwork in the forums to be excited.
Speaker 1: So I'm actually getting more and more.
Speaker 0: So I picked it because it's like the biggest deal and the sci-fi fantasy novel world right now.
Speaker 1: And now that I sort of you know My momentum of reading the prince of nothing kind of over and into me literally reading the entire appendix Like I know there's a lot of entries that are just men of the tusk died on this date in this battle.
Speaker 1: I read that entire fucking thing I didn't read.
Speaker 0: I only read a few choice entries.
Speaker 1: So some of the ones that don't look like they're gonna be choice that are like a paragraph but they seem like a lame heading.
Speaker 1: Pretty choice.
Speaker 0: when you read I'll tell me what those ones are.
Speaker 1: Yeah, here's the rule Just skip anything that starts with man of the tusk because those are the only ones that are just like.
Speaker 0: alright What if it's man of the tusk and you skip it.
Speaker 0: and then meanwhile that second sentence was like, you know Oh cuz I read a journey to Ayana and because I read the ball Oh, you even read the man of the.
Speaker 1: the only one That was gave me any pause and I don't know if it was a mistake was that it did not list a death year for Confess.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: So I read that I Really want to see confess come back.
Speaker 0: every other people who thought were dead came back.
Speaker 0: So why the fuck not?
Speaker 1: and also conferences greatest moment in all those books is your boy was when nayer Bent him over his knee and spanked him.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: I'll never forget that.
Speaker 0: see good old spank.
Speaker 1: That was a real good scene.
Speaker 0: also met a moment, right?
Speaker 0: We if you're I mean you're either watching this on YouTube or you're listening to this podcast somehow.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right.
Speaker 0: That means you must really be.
Speaker 0: I mean that you shouldn't be do wasting your time on that Just like I'm not wasting my time on phone games.
Speaker 0: But I guess if you that's what you want to do You should know that there are other ways to interact with us on the internet.
Speaker 0: They're probably more worth your time like Twitter Facebook Etc, etc.
Speaker 0: You can just search Google for geek nights or search for geek nights on whatever your favorite social media service place is.
Speaker 0: We're probably there already.
Speaker 0: We even have an Instagram That we only used one time, but we'll try.
Speaker 1: if you take you guys into Google at this point We're literally the entire first page.
Speaker 0: I'm trying.
Speaker 0: I'm thinking you know, it's like my instinct is there's a TV tropes article about geek nights.
Speaker 0: Yes, there is.
Speaker 0: I don't know who wrote it.
Speaker 1: But anyway, there's more in here than I expected right?
Speaker 1: So one lazy person one sad person wrote we used to have a Wikipedia till that crazy guy Positioned to the.
Speaker 0: we're not notable.
Speaker 0: So we shouldn't have one.
Speaker 1: Yeah We won the per sec award.
Speaker 0: Sure, whatever.
Speaker 0: That's not notable either.
Speaker 0: Got it here sure?
Speaker 0: What was I saying?
Speaker 0: Alright, I'm like, I'm trying to decide like.
Speaker 0: on the one hand I feel like if we make content we should put the content out on every possible channel.
Speaker 0: That's like sort of in what we tried to do.
Speaker 0: But now I'm thinking like hey Maybe we should do a content on this channel then a different content on that channel and not force people to follow us in all The places right?
Speaker 0: It's like well, let's do an Instagram live stream.
Speaker 0: Let's do a YouTube live stream?
Speaker 1: I thought about that.
Speaker 0: Let's go fracture.
Speaker 1: Like I don't know anymore.
Speaker 0: I don't know either anyway.
Speaker 0: But yeah The most important place you should go that's actually worth spending your time and not a waste of time is our forum Which is at our website.
Speaker 0: So if you go to front recruit calm at the top of the page is a link for forum.
Speaker 0: You could also just go to community that front recruit calm.
Speaker 1: if you go to forum for good I come you'll find the old forum that has like hundreds of thousands of posts that we have archive.
Speaker 0: it is read only but it is public and will be maintained like Han solo, but not unfrozen.
Speaker 0: But the current community is community our front recruit calm.
Speaker 0: you can come and hang out there.
Speaker 0: if you register It's gonna ask you to type in the reason you are registering.
Speaker 0: someone registered today and was like share ideas And talk with like-minded people early a porn spam bot something like that.
Speaker 0: They wrote.
Speaker 0: that is not a good reason.
Speaker 0: that is not gonna get you through.
Speaker 0: someone else wrote something along the lines of oh Some people on the podcast told me to type something here.
Speaker 0: I hope this is gonna get me in and I'll get you.
Speaker 0: I was like, yes, they got you in cuz.
Speaker 0: now there's no way that that is generic.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that is someone who clearly heard this message.
Speaker 0: There you go.
Speaker 1: So yeah, and our forums kind of rocking.
Speaker 1: so you go to you check it out.
Speaker 1: There's cool stuff in there.
Speaker 0: We have said this for a few episodes now and people took our words Heated our words and have joined and have thus increased the forums potency.
Speaker 1: So you can add to that potency by following and last and certainly not least There won't be much geek nights next week meaning there won't be any Next week and maybe not even the week after.
Speaker 1: but there may well, yeah Cuz actually I'll be out of town the entire next week as well.
Speaker 1: I'll be in.
Speaker 1: I'll be in Park City, Utah.
Speaker 1: Yeah mountain biking.
Speaker 1: so that should be fun.
Speaker 1: last time I went I Say I flipped over on a ridge and landed on a tree stump and got a bruise Size of like a softball.
Speaker 0: This is the last episode of unique nights.
Speaker 0: It's big.
Speaker 0: I know the last episodes.
Speaker 1: Maybe one more episode.
Speaker 1: We're doing DuckTales on Wednesday.
Speaker 0: Yeah, Wednesday will be the last episode of unique nights.
Speaker 1: So You know not gonna lie mountain biking is more dangerous than skiing, but it turns out.
Speaker 1: I'm really good at mountain biking.
Speaker 1: But anyway We will be at PAX West and Emily and I will be at also PAX dev.
Speaker 1: We will be in Seattle for at least eight days.
Speaker 1: Gotta be there for like six days.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna get there Thursday and leave on Tuesday.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we're gonna get there Monday night Tuesday.
Speaker 1: Wednesday is dev Thursday all day.
Speaker 1: It's just all sticking around in Seattle and then pack starts the next day.
Speaker 1: So yeah, I guess.
Speaker 1: well, how late are you getting in on Thursday?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 1: We'll check that later.
Speaker 1: We always get dinner or something.
Speaker 0: I'm sure I'll definitely probably be there for dinner better.
Speaker 1: Getting there super late cuz we're thinking of it We might go hang out outside of the places We normally hang out like hang out with her own Jeremy or something.
Speaker 1: We'll see cuz we're just around all day and there's nothing.
Speaker 1: packs dev ends a day before PAX West starts.
Speaker 1: But on Sunday at September 3rd at 6 30 p.m In the Hippogriff theater Hippogriff starts with H so you can assume it's in the Hyatt.
Speaker 0: It's in the Hyatt.
Speaker 1: We're doing the rage of the quitter.
Speaker 1: We're talking specifically Specifically about people who quit games at a butthurt rage.
Speaker 1: why and how they do that?
Speaker 0: I think it'll be pretty fun All right, so we were gonna talk about this last time We did a Monday show, but I guess we forgot like a minute after we said we were gonna talk about it.
Speaker 0: But we're having trouble with the Monday show ideas, right?
Speaker 0: It's it's not easy to come up with them partially because Like technology it's like technology moves fast But it's not moving as fast as it did and also we're less into it than we were before.
Speaker 0: And most of the things that change are small like, you know Intel CPU increased degeneration.
Speaker 1: Well, here's a good example.
Speaker 1: There was a time when which motherboard you chose had a huge impact on how well your computer worked.
Speaker 1: We are way past that point.
Speaker 1: It usually doesn't matter.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the other thing is like, you know consider like anime is like.
Speaker 0: it's always new anime series coming out I'm watching.
Speaker 0: it's always news now It's always new games to talk about and the gaming show but it's like what it's like.
Speaker 0: there's not new Technology to talk about.
Speaker 0: the technology show.
Speaker 0: that much really it's you know, well there is.
Speaker 0: there was something it's like.
Speaker 0: think about it.
Speaker 0: It's like when early days of geek nights It was like oh my god this.
Speaker 0: iPhones now versus now where it's like the seventh iPhone is here.
Speaker 0: It's different from the previous existed.
Speaker 1: now.
Speaker 1: smartwatches haven't changed, right?
Speaker 0: So it's like they got worse.
Speaker 0: pebbles got all the other show ideas for tech We've already done and would come up with new ones.
Speaker 0: So, uh, I don't know what's gonna happen.
Speaker 0: We might have to change we haven't Early.
Speaker 1: I just wanted to.
Speaker 1: I was thinking about changing the format of Monday to and while it seems like a semi lame I know we can change a format to whatever we want.
Speaker 0: No one's paying us to do this.
Speaker 1: We've said this for 12 years.
Speaker 1: We've never changed the format of anything ever, right?
Speaker 0: Well as the thing is like we're our original intent was to keep changing the format to find something that worked But I guess we're not using any metrics to judge what works.
Speaker 1: Well also man, but it's I've never even experiment, right?
Speaker 0: So I think we're gonna just start experimenting with Monday because otherwise we got nothing.
Speaker 1: So if you got any thoughts on our Monday show as opposed to the specifically Monday, that's all we care about right now.
Speaker 0: The other shows are fine.
Speaker 1: Then just let us know what you think.
Speaker 1: the best I can come up with is a lot of other tech.
Speaker 1: podcasts tend to just be Basically go through all the slashdot headlines from that day and just talk about them.
Speaker 0: But I found that those people they just do tech news roundup only which is why I don't want to do.
Speaker 0: But at the same time the main reason I don't want to do tech news roundup because Literally just makes us the same as every other tech, but at the same time I feel like we provide a very different.
Speaker 1: We're not Dvorak just not knowing stuff.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we don't know a whole different set of stuff.
Speaker 0: our tech news roundup is better than anyone else's but I don't want to just Do that.
Speaker 0: That's like we're just doing the same show everyone else is doing but at the same time I the format is almost just.
Speaker 1: it's like the Substrate just to give us an excuse to talks.
Speaker 1: what I've learned over the years, especially for the Thursday shows Is that he knows that it's tried.
Speaker 1: when we had a topic that was just an excuse for us to talk for an hour It did not matter what that topic actually was a lot of the early gig nights.
Speaker 1: We never even got to that topic.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so I tweeted out today in the Ignites account I said tell us your Monday tech show ideas are well has run dry and people submitted ideas.
Speaker 0: So we're just.
Speaker 0: we did this for Thursday previously when we were dry on Thursday.
Speaker 0: We are still sort of dry on Thursday But not as dry as Monday.
Speaker 1: Thursday's gonna pick up because there's a lot of movies and things.
Speaker 0: But we did an episode like this for Thursday before.
Speaker 0: we just went down a list of Thursday show ideas and and basically Hit them all real fast.
Speaker 0: So people tweeted Thursday ideas.
Speaker 0: We got a big.
Speaker 0: all these replies to this tweet I'm gonna go through but I just want to also mention some.
Speaker 0: people sent in numerous ideas Like a few.
Speaker 0: like most of these ideas are from like three people.
Speaker 0: one person did way more than everyone else.
Speaker 0: That's a somewhat that guy thing to do.
Speaker 0: You should be sending in like one really good idea not a fucking course.
Speaker 1: If I say you submit one thing to someone and then you look and see that literally no one else is giving them anything Definitely then you fill the void.
Speaker 0: No Then you're like.
Speaker 0: that's even weirder if one person says a whole bunch and no one else is anything.
Speaker 0: at least we got a few People in here.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Well, I guess the other thing is a Quality forgives almost all.
Speaker 0: so if those ideas were all good then all is forgiven Maybe but you know just to save time I'm not going to and also not to call out possible.
Speaker 0: I mean, this isn't like.
Speaker 0: I'm not gonna say if you do this, you're definitely that guy.
Speaker 0: I'm just saying it's like that guy.
Speaker 0: ish thing.
Speaker 0: if to do this I'm soft on sort of like someone who sends too many fan letters right into the fan club Yeah as opposed to the one tasteful fan letter, right?
Speaker 0: But anyway, so I'm not gonna say who tweeted what?
Speaker 0: I'm just gonna go through the ideas and we're gonna judge them on their own merit and not based on the merit of whoever.
Speaker 1: I'm ready to type these into Google because you're gonna see how we do with the show All right.
Speaker 0: So the first one was someone who doesn't I guess has hearing problems and doesn't realize that the fixed protocol is the fixed protocol.
Speaker 1: People in the finance industry don't know.
Speaker 0: that person wrote the fix-it protocol.
Speaker 0: It's fixed as an F I X for you know what it stands for.
Speaker 1: It's a financial exchange protocol.
Speaker 0: I thought it's interchange.
Speaker 1: No financial exchange.
Speaker 1: They use the X because I don't know what's the I. then Don't get me started.
Speaker 1: fine if I financial Fi for financial X for the second letter of exchange because fuck you.
Speaker 0: It's not the fee.
Speaker 1: So wait that they want to learn about the fixed protocol.
Speaker 0: Yeah, now I mean rim really loves time with the fixed protocol That I am a world-leading expert on the fixed protocol.
Speaker 1: There's a fine distinction between Knowing a lot about something and enjoying the fact that you know a lot about something.
Speaker 0: the point is is that?
Speaker 0: It's not really.
Speaker 1: I mean, what do we show it our show on?
Speaker 0: if we do a show about any protocol?
Speaker 0: HTTP TCP any protocol you come up with right?
Speaker 0: It's like as basically just reading documentation out loud at you, right?
Speaker 0: There's really no point to doing a show like that.
Speaker 0: There's not any opinions to add or anything.
Speaker 0: It's literally just here's how the thing works.
Speaker 0: You could make a podcast Fucking protocol of the week and that would be a garbage podcast and people would basically Find the episode on the one they needed to learn about and then they wouldn't listen to it because just reading the documentation is faster And better.
Speaker 1: I think that would actually kind of interesting especially because I work.
Speaker 0: you want to make protocol of the week the podcast.
Speaker 0: That's all you.
Speaker 1: why don't we do a Monday show on API's?
Speaker 1: I Got a lot of opinions about like like soap versus rest and all the different ways people make API's and like how they serialize data and help some things do it well if something's do a poorly is
Speaker 0: Example
Speaker 1: of that's like
Speaker 0: that literally what Monday is and that's not it.
Speaker 0: That's.
Speaker 0: another problem is that is the thing that is very very poorly communicated with audio.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you want to realize without diagram, but without diagram, but I was just using text Diagrams would help a lot.
Speaker 0: I think anyway, the point is I think it's not a good show But I can.
Speaker 1: so I could do a full hour talking about the fixed protocol more more.
Speaker 1: It'd be more like a college lecture though in the sense that even without diagrams or anything I feel like I could provide a sort of like the background like if like, you know The thing of this.
Speaker 1: if someone wants to learn more about something it helps for an expert to at least guide them toward The important broad strokes and like the hot the big picture of a thing.
Speaker 0: Anyway, let's continue.
Speaker 1: I'll give them a brief summary.
Speaker 0: So the fixed protocol is basically this ASCII string to get through a whole bunch of more right things here.
Speaker 1: All right couple sentences.
Speaker 1: ASCII string format to send data between financial institutions or systems.
Speaker 0: We're not actually doing these shows now.
Speaker 0: I don't think you understand.
Speaker 0: We're shooting down these ideas and I think it's fine idea If you go for an hour then do a show on it later.
Speaker 0: We're not actually doing any of these shows now.
Speaker 0: the show is going through the idea.
Speaker 1: Alright fine 35 equals 3 anyway.
Speaker 1: So the next I know the 35 equals 839 equals 3 is a joke.
Speaker 0: So the next one 35 equals 3 would have been a bummer.
Speaker 0: Joe Convention 101 how not to suck at registration system both pre-sales and on-site.
Speaker 0: First of all, it's not a Monday show.
Speaker 0: So there is so that second of all we've done that show.
Speaker 1: I would want to say that topic.
Speaker 0: there is a Monday Component and a Thursday component sure, but we've done this show and is not a Monday show.
Speaker 1: I think they're gonna be a Monday show there pretty easily.
Speaker 0: We've done this though.
Speaker 1: Well when what what episode?
Speaker 0: super wait.
Speaker 0: We talked about convention so much.
Speaker 0: I'm sure we've.
Speaker 0: just we've definitely just.
Speaker 1: we've never talked about registration more than the technology side of it.
Speaker 1: How do you load balance?
Speaker 1: How do you have systems that will concurrently handle all the people attempting to the buying part?
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's that's that's how you can split into two the whole the Thursday party.
Speaker 0: We talked about that, but it has nothing to do even specifically with registration.
Speaker 0: It's just like have compute have enough computers for the number of people that are visiting.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's an overly simplistic way to look at it.
Speaker 0: I that's all there is -.
Speaker 1: no It's not because you most of these systems care about the order that people attempt to register.
Speaker 1: so it can't just be Parallel.
Speaker 0: don't have a stupid system like that.
Speaker 1: So what do you mean?
Speaker 1: don't have a system like that?
Speaker 1: It's just gonna be random.
Speaker 1: when people hit like the penny arcade whatever to get their badges who gets into the queue and who doesn't?
Speaker 0: No, it's just like and you go to the site.
Speaker 0: you buy badges.
Speaker 0: if you click buy after this sold out You don't get them.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: So how do you deal with the giant load?
Speaker 0: You have enough servers to handle the load.
Speaker 0: the people do the queuing systems because they're too cheap.
Speaker 0: They won't buy enough fucking servers, right?
Speaker 0: Just pay for the it's.
Speaker 0: this thing is up for like hours before it sells out, right?
Speaker 0: And if it's not something that's gonna sell out you don't need this to begin with.
Speaker 0: so if you're that big that you're selling out instantly pay the money to turn on because Thousand fucking servers on Oz.
Speaker 0: so you can handle this enormous load.
Speaker 1: How do you how do you how do you architect your thing to take advantage of that massive parallels and turn them all off?
Speaker 1: How do you architect your thing to take care of that massive load balancers?
Speaker 0: It's not a big deal.
Speaker 1: How do load balancers work?
Speaker 1: We've never done a show on that.
Speaker 0: I think we have done a show on load balancers.
Speaker 0: In fact, I don't know.
Speaker 0: That's a good.
Speaker 0: load balancers is a good show if we haven't done it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, cuz actually load balancing is way more complicated than you probably think.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm Like mmm load balancing will fuck up your day.
Speaker 0: But anyway and load balancing plus SSL Anyway Alright, so next next idea Iot, which if you don't know is Internet of Things.
Speaker 0: hype promise scary and reality today.
Speaker 1: So I'll show.
Speaker 0: the thing is internet.
Speaker 1: No Cuz I can answer the whole quest the whole thing And you always say that with utterly simplistic pointless answers that don't actually drive into the root of the problem.
Speaker 0: They do Internet of Things.
Speaker 0: So here's the only question is is a thing an IO device or is it a computer, right?
Speaker 0: It's like I could plug a toaster into a computer in which by USB or something in which case my computer is now controlling A toaster with IO.
Speaker 0: Yeah and controlling turn it on turn it off toast time or whatever the controls are, right?
Speaker 0: And now merely I'm controlling the you know, the controls of the toaster with you know, a digital machine.
Speaker 1: No one cares about that semantic argument.
Speaker 1: I want to talk about my idea of increasing automation.
Speaker 0: if I put a computer into the toaster is the toaster now a computer?
Speaker 0: Right, and if it is continuing on that pedantic nonsense Yes.
Speaker 0: and if the toaster is now a computer because it has its own computer you have to worry about like Updating it and all is I write bullshit But you wouldn't have to worry if it was merely and it's an IO device attached to another computer.
Speaker 1: Nothing you said is the interesting problem the or the interesting question connecting itself to the internet and it's an extra.
Speaker 0: Everything is just like another computer connected the internet and that's not the interesting or controversial part from any other computer.
Speaker 1: The interesting topic there is around one.
Speaker 1: There's the security aspect of how do you secure a world
Speaker 0: which doesn't matter if you don't have your toaster be a computer And you just have it be connected to a computer
Speaker 1: Then the computer still has to be secure
Speaker 0: the same as all security concerns for any computer Which
Speaker 1: have still not been effectively dealt with.
Speaker 0: it being a thing doesn't make it computer.
Speaker 1: Yeah, again, you're hung up on this ridiculous semantic computers the computer.
Speaker 0: There's no such thing as a thing.
Speaker 1: There's a big difference between a very small number of computers or a very large number of computers Spread out among mass.
Speaker 1: consumers don't know shit about computers in terms of where and how you secure them.
Speaker 1: and also the consequences of that security are much more drastic when it starts to increasingly control things that affect your physical meat life like Say the hot water heater or the like shotgun that you tape to your door with a solenoid.
Speaker 1: But the interesting topic there is more around aside from the security problem The uses that are good or bad or how like say we solve the security problems and the ease of use problems.
Speaker 1: There are a lot of really interesting things that could drastically change our lives.
Speaker 1: Yes
Speaker 0: if all the things that you have to control and interact with on a daily basis can be very Improved by being controlled by a computer and not having to be controlled by your hands and your brain constantly
Speaker 1: Yeah, and I think there's a whole topic there and there's a separate topic in the middle of.
Speaker 1: right now most Internet of Things things Don't actually do much and are more trouble than they're worth it's and their automation is counterbalanced by their ridiculous configuration Problems bad UX and in many cases poor failure.
Speaker 0: This is why I'm saying we all of those Internet of Things things should not have their own computer.
Speaker 0: They should not be a computer again.
Speaker 0: I simply be i/o devices controlled by the computer you already have again.
Speaker 1: However, I don't think that is the question.
Speaker 1: Anyone's asking nor is that the interesting question and they're just.
Speaker 0: it's.
Speaker 0: By designating them as things Semantically when they're just more computers I think you sort of create Confusion right where there is none.
Speaker 0: if you just say like when people talk about the cloud if they just instead of saying the cloud Just say someone else's computer.
Speaker 0: It really simplifies the discussion, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah Well, there's a separate problem of like people who know technology on a broad and reasonably deep scale Versus people who have a shallow knowledge versus people who don't know anything.
Speaker 1: all three groups use very different nomenclature and more importantly the Implications of a lot of these words mean a lot of different things like normal people hear cloud and have a lot of really wrong Apprehensions about what that means.
Speaker 0: why I'm saying?
Speaker 0: people say Internet of Things and they have a lot of wrong ideas.
Speaker 0: but I'm saying if you ignore if you Internet of Things means instead of your toaster being connected to a computer your toaster is a computer.
Speaker 1: But I would say though that you tell that you ignore the people who don't understand that and we trust that the listener is Intelligent out there.
Speaker 1: and we talk about the perspective of if computers control everything in my house.
Speaker 1: What the fuck happens.
Speaker 1: Anyway, cuz that's an interesting question right?
Speaker 0: next one top X software thing.
Speaker 0: You can learn to make money but be bored.
Speaker 0: fix protocol like board game protocol database.
Speaker 0: put of your mind in doing so.
Speaker 1: Fix protocol, you'll make a shit ton of money and you will hate it.
Speaker 1: It's so boring.
Speaker 0: You want to make a lot of money?
Speaker 0: You want to basically find a job that pays a lot?
Speaker 1: Enterprise Java development.
Speaker 0: if you're good programmer job searches find a job that has a high salary and they're looking and they're only willing to Hire someone who knows them.
Speaker 0: a specific proprietary thing is it's not like top X. There's like a zillion of these things out there right each industry It is how many industries are there has some really specific thing that they use?
Speaker 0: Right, like?
Speaker 0: I'm sure it gets really like.
Speaker 0: I'm sure like, you know, how many?
Speaker 0: applications are specific to like the pharmaceutical industry or the Manufacturing industry.
Speaker 1: Well, there's the rub.
Speaker 0: I know any industry you can think of has some specific piece of software that they use that you've never fucking heard of.
Speaker 0: if you Are just a programmer You've got to learn.
Speaker 0: if you become a master of any one of those you will have a job in that industry for as long That thing.
Speaker 1: if you're just a programmer You've got to be very good to get a high-paying job.
Speaker 1: if you are an okay programmer I'm very good or yeah, I'd say so or even a mediocre programmer.
Speaker 1: But you also have expert domain knowledge.
Speaker 1: in a non computer field.
Speaker 1: You will make as much money if not more money than the very good programmer anyway.
Speaker 1: So either be very very good at one thing like programming or be good at one thing and passively good.
Speaker 0: I don't understand how many tweets we have here.
Speaker 0: if we want to do them all we had to go faster.
Speaker 1: All right, keep going.
Speaker 1: We can always just stop.
Speaker 0: no We had.
Speaker 0: it's not fair because there's like a lot of the tweets at the top like the same people because they tweeted in groups And I'm going in order of time.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: All right, we'll speed it up.
Speaker 0: set up 2017.
Speaker 0: What your geek nights pipeline looks now.
Speaker 0: open audition push record.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we plan 15 seconds into the future at most on gig night.
Speaker 0: open audition push record talk go home.
Speaker 1: I know sometimes the day we're gonna do a show on G chat One of us will mess with the other one to say what are we doing the show on?
Speaker 0: Next one a review of rim.
Speaker 0: So no speaker.
Speaker 0: I won that in a contest.
Speaker 0: I gave one away to a co-worker because I didn't need it and I gave one to.
Speaker 0: really what?
Speaker 1: Exceeded expectations.
Speaker 0: It's a speaker that you connect to wirelessly, but it needs to connect via Ethernet like to the internet Can't?
Speaker 0: you can't just use it like on the beach or anything and then it plays music and it works real.
Speaker 1: Well, and the speaker quality is really.
Speaker 1: it only plays music though So it doesn't do any of the Alexa things of the Google But I prefer that as opposed to the Alexa thing that's listening to every word I say right and sending it to I assume the government.
Speaker 0: It's good.
Speaker 0: If you have a small room and you don't have a sound system.
Speaker 0: The thing is I have a hat.
Speaker 0: my apartment has two rooms and like three or four sound systems.
Speaker 0: Yeah, no use for this thing.
Speaker 1: But I did not have a sound system in the living room and it is like perfect for playing music while we're cooking.
Speaker 0: How to computer?
Speaker 0: good.
Speaker 0: You should just do what Scott do because I'm the best at computer.
Speaker 1: Uh Use computers.
Speaker 1: Yeah and use can actually try.
Speaker 1: when something breaks learn it like figure out what happened.
Speaker 0: My number one recommendation is when you when you're doing things on your computer Do not customize the computer or the software don't change the settings leave everything as default and instead change yourself.
Speaker 0: Say alright, these are the settings.
Speaker 0: This is how this works.
Speaker 0: These are the keyboard shortcuts.
Speaker 0: Don't change them, right?
Speaker 0: Don't go changing your bash shell to some other shell say like Z shell or something it right say.
Speaker 0: All right This is the shell I have.
Speaker 0: What can I learn?
Speaker 0: How can I better myself?
Speaker 0: What reflex can I build?
Speaker 0: what you know?
Speaker 0: I do to change me to make me better at this rather than trying to make the computer easier And that's how you get better a computer.
Speaker 0: That's what I do.
Speaker 1: I mean, it's hard because the way I actually am good at computers was computers used to be shitting hard to use and I wanted To play games.
Speaker 1: so I had to learn a bunch of stuff I hated just to make the games work and that by default made me go to computers.
Speaker 1: So try to do things with computers anyway.
Speaker 0: Tech of Formula E racing.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: It's a battery-controlled battery-powered f1 car.
Speaker 0: I don't know anything about it.
Speaker 1: Wait, so anyone any showed any suggestion like that that the answer is always the same.
Speaker 1: We don't actually know anything about that and we very rarely are willing to do any amount of research for geek night.
Speaker 0: So if we did that show it would literally be us reading the Formula E like Wikipedia page out loud.
Speaker 0: And that's not.
Speaker 0: that show would only be interesting shows if we got into Formula E Or if we had a guest.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that news which we're lazy.
Speaker 1: We haven't gotten guests in a while.
Speaker 0: Enterprise level software development slash management.
Speaker 0: What the hell does enterprise even mean?
Speaker 0: software is soft.
Speaker 1: no, I got enter.
Speaker 1: so I would say the definition of enterprise software is Very complex software aimed at achieving very complex like user experiences while simultaneously having extremely niche audiences and Necessity.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: So what even counts as an enterprise is like a?
Speaker 0: well I mean, obviously there's no like big does a company have to be before it's.
Speaker 1: obviously there's no Specific line because that would be stupid and that's a stupid art.
Speaker 0: That's what I'm pointing out is that it's stupid.
Speaker 1: But at the same time the way enterprise software beyond a certain point on the sliding scale There's a point beyond which the complexity coupled with the small number of potential customers or users Coupled with the need for that thing because it's a very important niche.
Speaker 1: That's what makes something enterprise software and I Could probably talk for a few hours about that because I've been a product manager of enterprise software for like a decade.
Speaker 0: Anyway, adopt.
Speaker 1: There's a whole show there.
Speaker 0: That's a good idea of ipv6.
Speaker 0: Where is it at?
Speaker 0: Why hasn't it taken off more by now?
Speaker 0: What would be the next major turning point?
Speaker 0: didn't we do this already?
Speaker 1: I'm so long ago that stuff's changed.
Speaker 1: but so when we're at our IT is the quick version.
Speaker 1: ipv6 was like a coming thing and I got space on the six mode to Do a project to like learn.
Speaker 1: our ipv6 works like back before and you know what happened to that class.
Speaker 1: I got bored and I withdrew because fuck it.
Speaker 1: I didn't care and I just died in that space eventually expired.
Speaker 1: and the reality is Ipv6 does not affect normal people at all and it never will it.
Speaker 0: I cannot imagine We've used NAT so much that ipv6 isn't gonna come.
Speaker 1: Well, no, it's just that Normal people in your house.
Speaker 1: It doesn't matter how IPs are assigned.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah It's true.
Speaker 0: If your ISP just switched to ipv6 and it rolled out you wouldn't even know all the technology that you have supports it.
Speaker 0: windows supports It max supports that.
Speaker 0: your router supports it.
Speaker 0: It's a new enough router which it probably is because even in beacon we had routers that supported it.
Speaker 0: But more your ISP just switched you to ipv6 and all the websites in the world switched to ipv6 and everything You wouldn't even fucking know now.
Speaker 1: That's partly because there are some.
Speaker 1: We could do a show on that maybe someday anyway but the world.
Speaker 1: so the problem is I would have to do a little more research because the state of The back plane of the internet and like the way IP addresses are used in the way routers like the way routing tables are structured has actually changed a lot in the last decade or so and I'll be honest my Personal knowledge of that off the top of my head is out of date.
Speaker 1: So I'd have to do a little bit of research.
Speaker 1: college was a long time ago and the protocols I know are literally obsolete.
Speaker 0: Anyway, the next one the fixed protocol.
Speaker 0: we did that already.
Speaker 1: I could do a whole show on the fixed.
Speaker 0: Actually wrote it correctly though.
Speaker 0: Ah, what is wrong with century link?
Speaker 0: I assume that's someone's ISP century link and why do they have outages every goddamn week?
Speaker 1: I've never heard of century.
Speaker 0: I assume it's someone's ISP cuz your ISP sucks home and business.
Speaker 0: Yeah, why?
Speaker 0: where?
Speaker 1: where are they?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I can't figure this out.
Speaker 0: Why 50% of your IT outages are sysadmins making mistakes.
Speaker 0: That's incorrect.
Speaker 0: a hundred percent of your IT outages are sysadmins making mistakes.
Speaker 1: No, ninety nine ninety eight percent.
Speaker 1: the other two percent are legit Coordinated attacks from the outside.
Speaker 0: the point is if you set your shit up You should you can.
Speaker 0: it's possible to set shit up to be absolutely impossible to take down.
Speaker 0: You just cost more money.
Speaker 0: So if it goes down and you didn't it's either because a it wasn't worth Keeping that thing up in the face of attack because it wasn't that big a deal like the nice website is not really protected From a lot of things because it's not worth spending the money to protect.
Speaker 0: it goes.
Speaker 1: If the website goes down at midnight we'll fix it like in the morning, I don't need to be woken up.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like cuz I don't care.
Speaker 0: but if you have something that you actually need to keep up all the time it is possible to spend enough money and Build a system that basically is gonna be up all the time.
Speaker 0: Now the other reality is that it comes that when's the last time Google search went down?
Speaker 1: wait We can.
Speaker 1: I think we could do a real Monday show on uptime Like as a general like uptime itself.
Speaker 1: I got actually I feel a show there.
Speaker 0: Anyway, we're modern.
Speaker 0: tech would be without caffeine.
Speaker 0: It'd be just fine.
Speaker 0: I don't drink caffeine.
Speaker 1: Uh, I drink caffeine.
Speaker 1: I feel like tech would be fine.
Speaker 1: But caffeine is just one of the many tools I have in my tool chest.
Speaker 0: I think that the the culture of It's possible the culture of Silicon Valley startup work crazy hours Might be diminished somewhat because those people wouldn't be able to work.
Speaker 0: those crazy.
Speaker 1: Oh, those people would just use cocaine or something possibly.
Speaker 1: I also feel like The like glorification of caffeine in nerd spaces.
Speaker 1: I've really cuz I've.
Speaker 1: this has been going on since like Mountain Dew since before we were alive.
Speaker 1: before there were energy drinks in office culture But it really picked up in like nerd tech culture.
Speaker 1: I Honestly feel like the reason that happened in nerd tech culture specifically is because nerds are too afraid to do real drugs But they wanted to have a little bit of edge.
Speaker 1: So they talk about like how badass they are drinking the caffeine to stay up all night.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I feel like that's where that came from.
Speaker 0: Anyway, building HVAC and why power losses result in so much heat.
Speaker 1: Ah I could talk about building HVAC.
Speaker 1: That's it.
Speaker 1: That's a show.
Speaker 0: I actually know a lot about it.
Speaker 0: I don't know anything about HVAC.
Speaker 0: I know how air conditioner works.
Speaker 1: What kind of air conditioner?
Speaker 0: the kind you put in your window?
Speaker 1: What's the difference between one that has one?
Speaker 1: So the kind you put in your window, what about the ones that sit in the room and have tubes coming out of them?
Speaker 1: How are they different?
Speaker 0: Isn't that the same thing?
Speaker 0: only instead of sticking out the window?
Speaker 0: It just has a tube.
Speaker 1: What if there's one tube versus two tubes?
Speaker 1: What's different?
Speaker 1: Why is there one tube versus two?
Speaker 0: If there's two tubes, one's in and one's out.
Speaker 1: So how does a one tube one work?
Speaker 0: It just instead of having it in tube, it just is in on the front.
Speaker 0: It's in the room.
Speaker 1: All right And why is that different?
Speaker 1: Why does that matter?
Speaker 0: I don't know because you want to use tubes instead of vents.
Speaker 1: I could do a show on this.
Speaker 1: That's another one too.
Speaker 0: I'm not.
Speaker 0: I don't know anything about air conditioning.
Speaker 0: I'd end up reading the Wikipedia page about it.
Speaker 1: All right, let's see HVAC and uptime.
Speaker 0: We're not talking about this anymore.
Speaker 0: We're moving on SSO, I assume that means single sign-on.
Speaker 0: I'm like.
Speaker 1: so my god I've been dealing with single sign-on.
Speaker 0: You have you basically have one system.
Speaker 0: Just that does logging in and the logging out and then all the other systems instead of having their own logins and logouts talk to That system.
Speaker 0: that's how you can log in with Google on a different site.
Speaker 0: That isn't Google.
Speaker 1: Single sign-on is actually a pretty complex topic.
Speaker 0: That uses OAuth when it's on the web but if you're doing it like locally you might use something like Active Directory or LDAP.
Speaker 1: So Single sign-on is complicated because actually it's been changing.
Speaker 1: It's been changing a lot lately Especially with like websites and web applications.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like the on the high level like yeah It's really simple like you use credentials from one side and you trust those credentials to then let someone access another side.
Speaker 1: but the details of how you do that in a secure manner is Actually really complicated and it's a combination of front-end development, back-end development, APIs.
Speaker 1: That's probably a whole show, but I don't know enough depth about it.
Speaker 0: SSL.
Speaker 0: They're like SSO and the next tweet was SSL.
Speaker 0: I think we did one on SSL.
Speaker 0: We may have.
Speaker 0: The thing with SSL Is that like it's hard to.
Speaker 0: actually it's such a mess that it's hard to learn it for reals.
Speaker 1: SSL certificates July 27th of 2009.
Speaker 1: Right, but it's basically you're just gonna read instructions on how to set it up.
Speaker 1: We might have had a bad opinion back then.
Speaker 1: Tonight on Geek Nights we talk about the SSL certificate racket.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there was a racket where the people selling the certs.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the racket is by the way gone.
Speaker 0: You can now use encrypt Encrypt Anywhere.
Speaker 0: What's it called?
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 0: Let's Encrypt.
Speaker 0: That's the site.
Speaker 1: I feel like because of really Shitty use of those certificates that increasingly people are gonna distrust them.
Speaker 0: You think Let's Encrypt is gonna get distrusted?
Speaker 1: I think Let's Encrypt is gonna get distrusted.
Speaker 0: I think Let's Encrypt is actually legit.
Speaker 1: Oh, I think they're legit.
Speaker 1: I think that people that there's going to be a tipping point the problem with SSL certificates.
Speaker 0: Chrome and trust them.
Speaker 0: So does Starbucks and iE.
Speaker 1: Just I'm leery.
Speaker 1: I have opinions.
Speaker 1: We could do a show.
Speaker 0: The racket has been busted.
Speaker 1: We could do an updated SSL show because 2009 was a long time ago.
Speaker 0: IT heuristics.
Speaker 0: Why you know before everyone else does what the problem is based entirely on your monitoring.
Speaker 1: Do we ever do a show on like monitoring?
Speaker 0: I think we have.
Speaker 1: I think we talked about SNMP.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: Ad-hoc networks.
Speaker 0: I took ad-hoc networking class in college.
Speaker 0: Ad-hoc networking never really took off because it's such a pain in the ass.
Speaker 1: It's the best use case for ad-hoc networking would be at a convention But no one's ever made it work because you need all the devices to play games and like play ball.
Speaker 0: Pretty much the most you're gonna get is like the little airdrop on your iPhone and during a disaster and same problem.
Speaker 1: It's just a. it's a really complicated problem.
Speaker 0: Anyway, Decentralized networks and how you can prepare for providing a network that's really difficult to take down for protests and the like.
Speaker 1: That's basically the same question question.
Speaker 1: So the pirate boxes that we remember we talked about a long long time ago We used to.
Speaker 1: if you watch our old panel videos you see us like you can make mesh networks.
Speaker 0: The problem is it's the physicality of it is so difficult.
Speaker 1: All right modern pirate boxes are way better and they have a lot of embedded software.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so you're not gonna make a mesh network that has a wide radius.
Speaker 1: But you can spin up a localized Wi-Fi and if you overpower it You'll probably be able to do okay to basically have like a 4chan equivalent That's local right there for like organizing within the radius of that thing.
Speaker 0: There's a show modern signal jamming solutions.
Speaker 0: I don't know if you're talking about how to signal jam or how to avoid signal jamming, but I know nothing about it.
Speaker 0: I know get a better and more powerful radio antenna than the other guy.
Speaker 1: I know about that from classes I took at RIT and that knowledge is literally 100% obsolete in the modern era.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: The next one is CRISPR.
Speaker 0: CRISPR is CRISPR could change fucking everything and that is that that DNA thing.
Speaker 0: Yeah Yeah, I don't know anything about it other than that.
Speaker 0: It's a DNA.
Speaker 1: So here's the show we could.
Speaker 0: if we're gonna do a show on that I thought for first I was like are they talking about The DNA thing?
Speaker 0: are they talking about some startup called CRISPR?
Speaker 0: Yeah, so I feel like there's no E in between the P.
Speaker 1: I feel like we could do a show on that but it would be almost like a tech transfer.
Speaker 0: I know nothing about it.
Speaker 1: so no, no, we're what we talk about.
Speaker 1: is the like our opinions on the implications of increasingly directed like genetic manipulation of humans?
Speaker 0: Do it?
Speaker 0: I feel like yeah, but did I point out haven't you watched Gundam new types?
Speaker 1: Yeah, but also haven't you read the Prince of Nothing perhaps?
Speaker 1: Novel genetic experimentation on all of our babies at the same time is not the best idea.
Speaker 1: Listen, uh, while I You need to keep pure my natural stuff and just to regress to the me Nothing fandom is probably greater than my Gundam fandom.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I believe the real world is closer to Gundam that it is to Prince of Nothing I do.
Speaker 1: but remember also the fundamental problem of Gundam especially Gundam seed where that was kind of a big part of the plot.
Speaker 1: is that the consequence of increased genetic manipulation was better individuals who are just better in literally every way coupled with Decreased fertility and long-term consequences that might end their race.
Speaker 0: Anyway, we don't need more fertility because if we're living in space stations, we need less people up there.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but we might.
Speaker 1: the problem is that we don't have a pure understanding and Some traits that are beneficial might be intrinsically linked to traits that are less desirable.
Speaker 1: election pressure on there yeah, but I'm saying it's a very complex thing and we are not smart enough to grasp it and I feel like we'd end up Doing what the Incroy did?
Speaker 0: Wells where does the water come from and how do they run dry?
Speaker 0: poisoned wells differences between modern and medieval wells?
Speaker 0: Hashtag will it end?
Speaker 0: well, this is because I wrote in the original tweet our well has run dry.
Speaker 0: they're commenting on that.
Speaker 1: I know a little more about wells than I should because we have a friend who literally digs wells for a living.
Speaker 0: Yep, we could get him on the show.
Speaker 0: He's got her too.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's basically a family-run business, right?
Speaker 0: There's two people that we know that are awesome nerds in California who have a well digging business.
Speaker 0: They know everything there is to know about wells.
Speaker 0: We could get them on to talk about wells.
Speaker 0: Is that science in tech?
Speaker 1: I know I know.
Speaker 1: I know that I know what an artesian well is.
Speaker 1: I remember that from like seventh grade physical science.
Speaker 1: I Just don't know a ton about wells in detail.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm Yeah, anyway, uh predict the future on tech 2017 to 2019. didn't we do this already?
Speaker 1: Not for 2019.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: Let's do it right now.
Speaker 1: Well, you let's each make one production for something in tech.
Speaker 1: That'll be in 2019 incremental improvements.
Speaker 0: VR won't take off Nothing.
Speaker 0: that's a. I won't take off none of the things that are hyped now or they're all garbage.
Speaker 0: we'll just get incrementally better.
Speaker 0: and I do think that I don't know about Internet of Things, but the definitely be more computerization of you know Things that are not currently computer-controlled.
Speaker 1: I think we're gonna see legit murders and big robberies enabled by Internet of Things security issues in 20 by 2019. and I think I Think AI will like really fuck up gaming and start to win all games.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, I don't.
Speaker 0: I mean I don't mean that like.
Speaker 0: I'm like people think about the AI like in terms of like You know sci-fi AI or the Amazon Alexa AI that kind of stuff like no one wants to like.
Speaker 0: I don't think people really want to interact with Cortana or you know fucking Siri or whatever that kind of AI I do if it's smart enough as bullshit.
Speaker 0: No, I don't want to talk to my fucking computer I would be.
Speaker 0: But machine learning in terms of solving the problems it's good at solving, you know The statistical learning which I don't.
Speaker 0: I don't consider that to be AI because not thinking it's just statistical really highly advanced statistical models.
Speaker 1: I have opinions.
Speaker 1: I'm not gonna get into now because we're running out of time making decisions.
Speaker 1: I just read my problem.
Speaker 1: I just read like three dense textbooks on machine learning and AI and I have opinions.
Speaker 0: But that is going to solve some problems and and also create, you know better solutions to things and Increase efficiencies in many areas that will change society.
Speaker 1: I think specifically the kind these the types the list of the types of problems that machine learning solutions Can solve.
Speaker 1: real expand will expand to a dramatic degree and fuck some stuff You think a computer can do.
Speaker 1: it's gonna be able to do like I think any video game will have perfect a eyes by 2019.
Speaker 0: just maybe all right.
Speaker 0: the Russian hacking scandal election related or otherwise.
Speaker 0: what's real?
Speaker 0: What's not?
Speaker 0: who worldwide might actually be at risk?
Speaker 0: I don't have enough information about it.
Speaker 0: If I did I would be like making some money getting paid off by journalists to give them my good info.
Speaker 1: I could probably give a really good summary.
Speaker 0: I get a lot of yes, but I know a lot of facts.
Speaker 1: I know a lot of facts because I read about this a lot, but there's not too many facts to know.
Speaker 1: There's more than you think.
Speaker 1: there's a lot of interesting information out there.
Speaker 1: That's legit.
Speaker 1: You just don't read those kinds.
Speaker 1: like you.
Speaker 1: don't read all the Washington Post articles about it.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm I got a lot of opinions on that.
Speaker 1: I do show on that.
Speaker 0: tweet this article.
Speaker 0: It's a link to an article.
Speaker 0: I'm pulling up the article.
Speaker 0: Ideal OS rebooting the desktop operating experience.
Speaker 0: desktops are dead.
Speaker 1: next Desktops are not dead.
Speaker 1: desktops have become a professional tool.
Speaker 1: a desktop computer or a desktop operating system in 2017 is the equivalent of the toolbox that an artisan carries with them.
Speaker 1: normal people don't carry toolboxes everywhere But artisans do.
Speaker 0: yeah How does AI even work?
Speaker 1: also Linux desktop like fucking.
Speaker 1: just burn it all and start from scratch.
Speaker 1: had Windows desktop is actually pretty fine.
Speaker 0: How does AI even work in a set of instructions ever be truly alive?
Speaker 0: our meat brains alive?
Speaker 0: We're just a combination of senses solipsism.
Speaker 1: next question Yeah, but there's no difference between meat brains and computer brains in the long run.
Speaker 1: They're just technically.
Speaker 0: wait wait I got a few more.
Speaker 0: This is someone who's submitted a bunch apparently at Debugging device drivers.
Speaker 0: I don't know anything about that.
Speaker 0: I guess a lot of times you're bringing out the oscilloscope to see what your hardware is doing.
Speaker 1: So in terms of the consumer side of that the last time I had to debug device drivers Was when I had some firewire shenanigans for some firewire chipset.
Speaker 1: shit wasn't working.
Speaker 0: I guess I don't know if they're asking about debugging it from a user perspective Like you're trying to set up your drive or you're developing a driver for a piece of hardware you have and you it's messed up.
Speaker 1: So on the consumer side, you know how I solved that I said fuck it I disabled the chipset that I couldn't get to work and I just bought a PCI Express card that Google said would work with the Device I had and that was how I debugged it.
Speaker 0: Yeah debugging distributed systems It's hard because things are on different computers.
Speaker 1: Uh, you know what that turns into.
Speaker 1: we could do a show on debugging like how you actually figure out the root of a problem.
Speaker 0: I feel like that might be a good start one and work the other end process of animation.
Speaker 1: I feel like solve every problem I feel like but like I feel like we could do a few case studies and Like give some examples of like the kinds of tools we use anyway.
Speaker 0: general fun uses for tech skills outside the workplace.
Speaker 0: games.
Speaker 0: Yeah Video games setting up a home lab.
Speaker 0: I don't know what you mean by that.
Speaker 1: I don't do science.
Speaker 1: Why?
Speaker 0: why star Nick's directory structures are exactly the layout They are.
Speaker 0: cuz some dude had an old computer and he had a directory structure And then they had to add a hard drive to it because they fucking ran out of space and they mounted that hard drive on Usr.
Speaker 0: so now there's bin and use our bin because one hard drive ran out of space and then they had another fucking hard.
Speaker 0: Cuz that one ran out of space.
Speaker 0: so they made it var and then because the everyone copied that computer They had the same fucking directory structure Even though they didn't made it more complicated and everyone copied everyone else and all the software is written and coded to these.
Speaker 1: The Unix file system is literally people doing what people before them did because they assume that that's a standard for some good reason.
Speaker 0: now It is and there are Linux distributions that fix it and give you like that directory structures that make perfect sense and use English words like slash software slash home directory slash, you know, whatever.
Speaker 0: but No one uses that shit and you're gonna have a lot of annoyances if you try to use it.
Speaker 1: But at the same time I have annoyances using it because a lot of software doesn't play nice in that space Like especially enterprise software.
Speaker 1: usually just install that in like opt because it's monolithic and it needs its own shit.
Speaker 0: all together All right phone app updates your go-to Twitter verse tweet bot and bullshit likes in timeline.
Speaker 1: So I guess I don't know what the good.
Speaker 1: what a good.
Speaker 1: third-party Twitter app.
Speaker 0: I use tweet bot is great.
Speaker 0: It is another time on the debt.
Speaker 0: It's not free though.
Speaker 0: People always want something that's free, right?
Speaker 0: It's like dude, you're using your Twitter app more than anything, right and you're complaining about things like ads and likes in your timeline.
Speaker 0: They don't belong there.
Speaker 0: It's like just pay for the fucking third-party app.
Speaker 0: It's like three dollars, even if it's ten dollars fifty dollars.
Speaker 0: you're using this every goddamn day multiple times a day.
Speaker 0: It gets no ads.
Speaker 0: No, not no bullshit.
Speaker 0: Your timeline is perfect.
Speaker 0: It was even any of the bullshit.
Speaker 0: do not use the actual official Twitter app and you had no fucking problems.
Speaker 0: I use tweet deck on the desktop.
Speaker 0: No problems and that's free.
Speaker 1: But I guess phone app updates update every app all the time like yep and If an app asks for new permissions decide right then and there if you care about the app enough to let it know that thing Or just delete the app.
Speaker 1: Yep, one of the two.
Speaker 0: But yeah, it's like don't be afraid to fucking pay for apps.
Speaker 0: the pay for apps are a lot of times better.
Speaker 1: Why don't you stop?
Speaker 1: we got over an hour.
Speaker 0: That's the last one.
Speaker 1: Oh nice.
Speaker 0: That's why I was rushing.
Speaker 1: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at front row crew comm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 1: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 0: But unlike those other late shows It's actually recorded at night and the patreon page runs.
Speaker 1: for this episode of geek nights are Alan Joyce, Heidi Mcdinkle Amanda Duchette roundabout MP3.
Speaker 1: my statey calm William I suppose Jeremy.
Speaker 1: minor.
Speaker 1: life and death and love and birth and peace and war on the planet earth.
Speaker 1: a genuine bonafide.
Speaker 1: electrified six car monorail.
Speaker 1: Nicholas Brando captain Chinguacos see Rebecca Dunn for two one creations.
Speaker 1: Even if we were to pull out today and if they would come take our base.
Speaker 1: Sherman van Horl rare Lavell James David White Rochelle, Montanona.
Speaker 1: Superboy Scott has become a character of himself.
Speaker 1: Sailor Vista, Matthew Smith, Don Shleich, Jar Chavish and Jojo Joestar, Shawn Yeager, Sam Cordery, Clinton, Walton Wren from New Zealand, Ryan Perrin, Drew Openlander, Brian Sidroni, Finn, Chris Midkiff, Chris Knox, Daniel Redmond, Sean Klein, Chris Reimer and Thomas Hahn.
Speaker 1: PAX is coming and a bunch of other stuff is going on, but stay tuned for stuff anyway.
Speaker 0: I I think you said In my way It's.