Speaker 0: It's Tuesday June 20th 2017 I'm rim and this is geek nights.
Speaker 0: tonight We're talking about a race to the gala race for the galaxy at all its expansions.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: so as many of you follow me on Twitter saw I uh, I Encountered something that I have literally never seen happen in my entire life.
Speaker 1: I mean, that's a lot of things.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there's a lot of things you haven't seen in your entire life But this is something that I also hadn't seen But it's also know a lot about but apparently didn't know what I didn't know and I learned some more things.
Speaker 0: I won't get into too much detail on the things I learned because I'll do that like on the next Monday's show.
Speaker 0: I'll go kind of in depth.
Speaker 0: but My computer at work like just rebooted like oh shit.
Speaker 0: I had a problem.
Speaker 0: I'm rebooting All right that happens and then there was no boot disk anymore.
Speaker 0: Okay, so I assume well this the hard drive must have died or maybe there's a problem.
Speaker 0: Yeah happens.
Speaker 0: I'm about to go into the BIOS.
Speaker 0: long story short.
Speaker 0: No, the SSD that had my windows on it literally caught fire and fucking burned.
Speaker 1: So you went to the BIOS and then fire started coming out of the computer.
Speaker 0: fire came out.
Speaker 0: It was a combustion.
Speaker 1: so you're in you're in the BIOS and then like a fire just came out the side of the computer.
Speaker 0: Well, I have the window and I see I smell.
Speaker 0: I smell a smell like yeah, what's that smell?
Speaker 0: I look and sure enough There's just a fire in there basically the SATA connector for power that goes into this Appetop as SD.
Speaker 0: We'll get back to the fuck.
Speaker 0: Appetop is My best.
Speaker 0: get it just it burned.
Speaker 0: I don't know what else to just it caught fire.
Speaker 0: it melted like a bunch of stuff including like the entire cable connecting in and Yeah, I had to buy a new SSD.
Speaker 0: Luckily, I lost maybe I don't know Couple hours worth of work meaning like stuff.
Speaker 0: I happen to have just saved to my desktop because it was throwaway stuff I didn't care about.
Speaker 0: my computer is already like completely back to normal because I back stuff up.
Speaker 0: You should also back stuff up.
Speaker 0: if you can't recover like immediately from your main hard drive dying Then you're kind of F because this stuff happens.
Speaker 0: Many of you probably didn't expect to have to worry about a hard drive literally catching fire.
Speaker 0: And my best guess as to what happened.
Speaker 1: Why did you have an epitaph?
Speaker 0: So this was a computer that I bought from New egg, but it was a pre-built computer because it was work.
Speaker 0: And yeah, the SSD that they put in it was by a brand that Matt Morgan said it best.
Speaker 0: clearly They meant to spell potato and failed at even this.
Speaker 0: so this Appetop SSD Probably had a real warranty.
Speaker 0: I don't even know.
Speaker 0: I just threw it away right for the best partly because you can buy a 240 gigabyte like crazy good SSD from Samsung 90 bucks.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the 850 avo 90 a hundred bucks tops 110 if you buy it like MSRP and you actually pay for shipping.
Speaker 0: so on one hand SSDs are actually way more prone to this than spinning discs ever were.
Speaker 0: So there is a danger to your computer if you buy crappy SSDs.
Speaker 0: counterpoint there is literally no reason to buy a crappy SSD because the crappiest SSDs save you like 30 bucks.
Speaker 0: Just buy the better SSD by the one that won't set on fire Yeah.
Speaker 0: so I have a pretty good theory as to why the SSDs seem more prone to this and it comes down to the fact that the barrier to entry to make the shittiest possible Physical spinning disk hard drive is actually really high.
Speaker 0: like you need a pretty complicated manufacturing process to build that machine.
Speaker 0: because an old hard drive remember is actually insanely Complicated in terms of having this like tiny read head skimming over a disk spinning it up to 10,000 rpm Literally flying over the surface not touching it in a tiny like well manufactured box.
Speaker 0: So the crappiest hard drive you could buy in the world was more likely to fail.
Speaker 0: but it also required Significant industrial like stuff.
Speaker 1: well people sold ones that basically didn't work for shit.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they didn't care, but usually those were Leavings from bigger factories like to manufacture a hard drive was a pretty big deal.
Speaker 0: an SSD You can just slap the circuits together and stick a bunch of shitty flash in and you're good to go Mm-hmm, so there are a lot of shitty companies like potato here.
Speaker 0: Who are making?
Speaker 0: Garbage tier SSDs and the barrier to entry is so low that you're gonna start running into problems like this like Some diode or something is just or like the power circuit is just bad.
Speaker 0: Cuz you can send up an amp and a half through those SATA connectors.
Speaker 0: Mmm.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that was fun.
Speaker 0: That's something that's never happened to me before and magic smoke got out Yeah, and no one in the office believed me.
Speaker 0: So I was like guys here.
Speaker 0: Look there was a fire.
Speaker 0: See how it's all burned.
Speaker 1: She's the smoke.
Speaker 1: is the fire extinguisher?
Speaker 0: No I just like basically just unplugged it and I just sort of like kicked at it and I've been.
Speaker 0: the fire went out right away.
Speaker 0: Mmm, it was a tiny fire and it was mostly just like I think I think it was.
Speaker 0: It was simmering for a while and there was mostly heat.
Speaker 0: The fire was only right in like the entrance point there.
Speaker 0: Mmm a lot of smoke and char in the case, though I blew a lot of like soot out of the power supply.
Speaker 0: Mmm, but the funniest thing was The power supply sending bad power.
Speaker 1: I am incredibly confident that I get a new power supply.
Speaker 1: Anyway, isn't one of the power supply ends all burnt?
Speaker 0: No, cuz actually the that end Was an adapter cable anyway.
Speaker 0: Oh and I suspected maybe the cable was the problem, but that does not appear to be the case.
Speaker 0: It looks like the fire originated in the SSD itself.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that was fun.
Speaker 0: But anyway, it's Tuesday.
Speaker 0: This is only tangentially related to gaming because if you're a gamer and you have a PC You probably have an SSD in there and if you're cheap, you probably have an SSD like potato.
Speaker 0: So go check what brand your SSD is if you don't know and if it's potato Recommend you could buy a Samsung like soonish.
Speaker 1: Yep, maybe.
Speaker 0: So there is actually a ton of gaming news.
Speaker 1: well because e3 happens since we did the last gaming show here.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so there's tons of gaming news to talk about most of it.
Speaker 0: We don't give a shit though Yep, but I think the biggest news for me three that I care about is that it's Metroid Christmas.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, we're getting now one but two Metroid Eddie's to Metroid Metroid Prime 4.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah a real game.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's gonna be fun and Metroid Samus returns man.
Speaker 0: Sorry the quote a side-scrolling 3ds game.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: That is that's what I want.
Speaker 0: I haven't played a side-scrolling Metroid in a while.
Speaker 1: Well, I got.
Speaker 1: I don't disappoint you but this side-scrolling Metroid game while I'll probably get it and play it Is guts is questionable, right?
Speaker 1: It's made by oh shit.
Speaker 1: Yeah Okay, it's made by some people who have made some other Not the greatest You know games, right?
Speaker 1: They don't have a great track record.
Speaker 0: I'm looking at a deeper site on this right now.
Speaker 1: It's sort of a redo Moses pretty much just a redo of Metroid 2 for the Gameboy which first comment.
Speaker 0: So this is just a remake of Metroid to the recertive Samus.
Speaker 0: that would explain why Nintendo C and D?
Speaker 0: that am to our fan Game reason.
Speaker 1: Well, no Nintendo C and D is everything even if they weren't doing this, right?
Speaker 1: But this is probably gonna be worse than that fan game was.
Speaker 1: They are.
Speaker 1: you can watch videos to learn all about this game, but you know, I'll probably get it but it don't don't Okay, so there's a way worse indicator here.
Speaker 0: Samus now has free aiming.
Speaker 1: Yeah So don't a fan of that inside scrolling Metroid, I'm just saying don't get your hopes up about this game.
Speaker 0: So is it's just Metroid Hanukkah.
Speaker 0: It's not much right.
Speaker 1: Christmas Matronik is better.
Speaker 0: You get eight days eight days of inferior presence as opposed to one day of blowing your whole low point.
Speaker 1: is Metroid Prime 4 though can't go wrong.
Speaker 1: No cannot go wrong.
Speaker 0: That's just getting played immediately cannot go wrong.
Speaker 1: Did you play Metroid Prime 1 2 3?
Speaker 0: no, I played him a little bit.
Speaker 0: I thought you were okay.
Speaker 1: Just go straight to 4.
Speaker 0: why not?
Speaker 0: Why not?
Speaker 1: I mean, I don't know shit about Metroid.
Speaker 0: I only played like three hours of Twilight Princess.
Speaker 1: You know what it looks like Can't even ice beam, bro What's wrong with you?
Speaker 0: Ah Did I ever?
Speaker 0: I don't think I ever beat Metroid 1 without using a code?
Speaker 0: because oh my god No Because if I died near the end of the game I was unwilling to farm to refill my energy tanks because I just that was lame.
Speaker 0: So I would use codes or things just to start with all that full.
Speaker 1: just play like Metroid Prime Zero mission instead.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, which is actually really good.
Speaker 0: Maybe I'll play that and stream it on your GBA On my emulator GBA.
Speaker 0: Okay, actually I got a bunch of GBA is laying around somewhere.
Speaker 1: I got.
Speaker 1: I got a ton of you got a bunch of GBA's.
Speaker 0: Cuz we got to save those because I got tons of Nintendo portable goods.
Speaker 0: Well, cuz we guess that's the good area to bust out.
Speaker 0: the Crystal Chronicles the old four swords the warrior where?
Speaker 0: That's really the only three news.
Speaker 0: I care about though.
Speaker 0: in Saturn news it looks like at e3.
Speaker 0: a bunch of people saw there's a ton more footage from Nidhogg 2 which is gonna be on the ps4.
Speaker 1: and Uh, we already look at every time I've seen it and I've seen it at pack.
Speaker 1: Less excited is I've never been.
Speaker 1: I was zero excited when I saw the first screenshot and now I'm just like completely ignoring it.
Speaker 1: I'm like, I wrote it off.
Speaker 1: as soon as I saw it at PAX I a hundred percent wrote it off.
Speaker 1: it went from 90 percent to a hundred and Thousand percent.
Speaker 0: I'm down.
Speaker 0: I'm down to negative at this point.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so I'm saying I've written it off over a thousand percents because now I've seen a whole bunch of live gameplay footage and I've heard the Developers and like a bunch of people talking about it and like talking about their gameplay experiences.
Speaker 0: I Don't want to get too deep because this is purely like.
Speaker 0: this is a semi uninformed opinion based on Other people talking and watching video footage.
Speaker 0: I Don't think it is going to be as good as a of a game as Nidhogg one Irrespective of the graphics.
Speaker 0: I am so not looking forward to actually playing this game.
Speaker 1: So don't play it.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna play it cuz.
Speaker 1: I gotta know I'm really not looking forward to doing this thing that I could not.
Speaker 1: I don't have to do but I'm gonna do anyway.
Speaker 0: You gotta know you guys is really disgusting food.
Speaker 1: I'm really not looking forward to eating poop, but I just got to eat it.
Speaker 0: I gotta give the real review.
Speaker 1: Hey, I got a bamboo for you to smell.
Speaker 0: I smelled that bamboo and you know, I did and I push that bamboo and that caused far greater disaster not to me.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna smell the bamboo.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I don't even know what the bamboo smells like.
Speaker 1: I'm Sullied.
Speaker 1: you're gonna be sullied by this.
Speaker 0: Smelled the way stale vomit would taste if you drank it.
Speaker 0: That was the worst vomit smell I've ever smelled.
Speaker 1: You're gonna feel that feel on your fingers and you play Nidhogg - it's gonna say that it's gonna feel like touching stale vomit.
Speaker 0: I'm telling.
Speaker 0: I say what I just said as someone whose bodies like go to.
Speaker 0: Solution to most problems is vomit my bod that doesn't vomit to fix your fire away.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna try that after.
Speaker 0: I I think rebooting will fix it.
Speaker 0: But if that doesn't maybe my body of vomit.
Speaker 0: but yeah, now that I've heard a bunch of like the developers talking about the game and game journalists talking about it, uh Based on which game journalists liked it and what they said that they liked about
Speaker 1: it who liked it,
Speaker 0: uh Well, let's save that but that you can.
Speaker 0: walling to this you can watch.
Speaker 0: there's a 20-minute video here.
Speaker 0: Well, you want to smell the bamboo?
Speaker 0: This is 20 minutes of some in-hug talk and every second will drain Enthusiasm from your soul about this game and there's tons of more e3 news, but there's another important news.
Speaker 1: We got to talk about that.
Speaker 1: We have a lot to say.
Speaker 0: even though it's not the biggest deal Yeah, it's a huge deal to a small number of gamers, right?
Speaker 1: So there's a if you don't know there's a company called geek a chic.
Speaker 0: we talked about them.
Speaker 0: we on gig night.
Speaker 1: We saw them As far as we know the very first time they were on display.
Speaker 1: Was it oh wait?
Speaker 0: or oh no, this was back when special guests.
Speaker 1: I think it was oh nine Special guys.
Speaker 0: the packs used to get their own like pre access.
Speaker 1: We went to the expo hall for one hour early before right anyway, I don't think you can do that anymore Disappeared.
Speaker 1: we went into the expo hall at PAX an hour early and we saw these gaming tables and we were you know Like ten years younger than we are now.
Speaker 1: And we're like, whoa, check out these amazing gaming tables.
Speaker 1: Wouldn't you love to play D&D on this fucking thing?
Speaker 0: Holy shit, like I was so excited and like I really wanted one.
Speaker 1: and on the one hand, you know These tables were not the most attractive tables I really wanted you know modern furniture looking table and not antique furniture looking table at first glance.
Speaker 0: They look good.
Speaker 0: Well, we'll get back to that.
Speaker 0: but it's not even just that.
Speaker 0: they're an older style.
Speaker 0: and well We have multiple friends who actually know a lot about cabinet making and furniture craft and they have all said the same thing These tables are a mishmash of a bunch of different styles and techniques.
Speaker 0: that makes them look like ridiculous Camaro monsters to anyone who knows anything about furniture.
Speaker 1: Yeah They don't.
Speaker 1: there's no like.
Speaker 1: you could look at this table on its own and be like wow Look at that gaming table Like you could.
Speaker 1: it would be so awesome to play D&D on that and then you put it in any room in any house on Earth and it just doesn't match anything.
Speaker 0: It'd be like if you walk into a room that had like art deco tiles But the molding was like 17th century molding and the carpet was shag carpet.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like that's.
Speaker 0: that's what these look like to anyone.
Speaker 0: Anyway, anything about furniture regardless of aesthetics, right?
Speaker 1: I mean you might like crazy mixed-up style, but maybe Aesthetics are just matter of taste, right?
Speaker 1: I've also heard people say, you know that while these tables are you know, they're okay They are not Okay, considering the price for the price of these tables six to ten thousand dollars for like a full kit.
Speaker 1: Yeah the crappiest table they offer is like 1400 and like average like 3500 is really the starting price for a somewhat real table.
Speaker 0: now if you spent that much on a table That isn't a gaming table.
Speaker 0: You're buying like an heirloom piece of furniture.
Speaker 1: You get a mag you get a magnificent magnificent incredible regular table for that price.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right and I mean not the best table but a magnificent excellent table that'll probably last not only your life But like your grandchildren's.
Speaker 0: but a big part of why people were so excited about these I think was that no one else was serving this.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: This was that they basically invented this market, right?
Speaker 1: It was an idea people had.
Speaker 1: there were definitely people on the internet.
Speaker 1: you'd see on slash that or whatever.
Speaker 0: You see me bitching about this all the time.
Speaker 1: people would post pictures of their custom-built gaming tables Like I made one.
Speaker 1: check out how awesome I am.
Speaker 1: But there was no place.
Speaker 1: if you weren't a furniture maker that you could like unless you paid for a custom job from a furniture Person you couldn't get a table that was made for gaming that had things like, you know dice pits or DM trays Cup holders to go off the side where it wouldn't mess up anything.
Speaker 1: or you know insets inlays with felt or or you know The best one was the winner grades.
Speaker 0: You could put the glass on top.
Speaker 0: So it's a normal table.
Speaker 0: You could also inside of it put your giant miniatures, right?
Speaker 1: So you'd put your map right.
Speaker 1: then you put a piece of plastic or glass over the map.
Speaker 1: Then you put the miniatures on top of that and then you could put leaves on top of that.
Speaker 1: So you could didn't have to like.
Speaker 1: you could Turn it back into a regular table eat pizza open it up again The minute minis are still inside.
Speaker 1: you want to stop playing minis and play a board game.
Speaker 1: You could bring up the felt panels by flipping over the wooden panels.
Speaker 0: There's definitely a market for.
Speaker 0: Forget that.
Speaker 0: forget it's practice practicality.
Speaker 1: if you were doing heavy tabletop gaming in a place the practicality of them was excellent and they were the first as far as I know people to manufacture them to set some amount of scale and sell them right to the general public.
Speaker 0: every time we have played D&D or Any role-playing game in our entire lives the physicality of the space has always been deeply suboptimal.
Speaker 0: Yep, like tables suck ass at this.
Speaker 0: I think the only good gaming space we ever had was the pre renovated lounge in Peterson at RIT.
Speaker 1: Even that even that kind of sucked.
Speaker 0: Well, it had the thing that people could sit on sure and then everyone else sat on the floor.
Speaker 1: still wasn't good, right?
Speaker 0: That was for the best.
Speaker 1: I think the best use of these though was at gaming stores.
Speaker 1: if you owned a gaming store Oh, yeah You wanted to have one of these for sure.
Speaker 0: nerds had flipped their shit and people would rent time to like play their game at These things.
Speaker 1: now geek she's been around for a long time like at you know, oh wait at nine at least, right?
Speaker 1: So it's been like six seven eight years a long time and the way their business worked is that you would order the table because Everything was custom ish right customized to some extent.
Speaker 1: you'd order the table and pay and then they would.
Speaker 1: you'd get in the queue and Then eventually when they finished your table because they handmade everything you'd get your table, right?
Speaker 1: And they'd actually drive it over to you and deliver it like like hand deliver it themselves.
Speaker 1: It was like a you know, a fancy kind of operation.
Speaker 1: It's part of why it costs so much money, right?
Speaker 1: Yep So that isn't bad, you know that you're paying for that right but The problem is they went out of business.
Speaker 1: So people paid for tables.
Speaker 1: They're probably not gonna get.
Speaker 1: they've just ceased operations.
Speaker 1: And unless you used a credit card and you cancel the payment or something.
Speaker 1: You just lost thousands of dollars.
Speaker 0: Yep, and because those lead times were so long and nerds are so obsessed But lead times kept getting longer and because they now that we know we're in some financial trouble They basically kept taking those orders.
Speaker 0: Yep to get money.
Speaker 1: So I heard like, you know, maybe I don't know when it was but I read some article that was like Yeah, we brought in like tons and tons of revenues.
Speaker 1: We're actually a hundred thousand in the hole.
Speaker 0: No, so that's already This company like.
Speaker 0: I know a lot.
Speaker 0: like I do a lot of business stuff now and I know more about like.
Speaker 0: I know way More about this kind of stuff than I did a few years ago.
Speaker 0: If you're doing two million in sales, and you only have a hundred thousand dollar loss I You have to really fuck up to not turn that into a really fucking legit company.
Speaker 0: $100,000 loss on that revenue is totally fine Unless like you've got serious structural problems.
Speaker 0: I don't know what you're doing, right?
Speaker 1: But I what I heard is the reason they're going out of business.
Speaker 1: I heard they tried to buy some company or something.
Speaker 1: This is like rumors.
Speaker 1: I didn't see like a story about this, but I heard from reliable people's.
Speaker 1: They were trying to buy some kind of company But the deal was bad and they fucked up this acquisition somehow.
Speaker 1: and then that's where they lost all their monies.
Speaker 0: In this article, I'm looking at.
Speaker 0: apparently they were on an episode of Shark Tank.
Speaker 1: I didn't know that.
Speaker 1: 2013.
Speaker 0: Okay That's how we know about the two million dollar sales and hundred thousand dollar losses.
Speaker 1: Oh, they mentioned it on that TV shop.
Speaker 0: okay, and apparently around that time they tried to sell a equity stake in the company for a paltry $300,000 what like.
Speaker 1: but the revenue is two million and you're gonna give 25% for 300 grand.
Speaker 0: like I would have formed a fucking company and bought you fuckers.
Speaker 1: I hope the good thing you didn't cuz you'd be screwed.
Speaker 1: now.
Speaker 0: No Cuz I if I bought them out.
Speaker 1: for if I bought 25% for 300 grand But with 20% wouldn't be giving you a say in shit and they would have fucked up even if you don't cuz then when they went Super fuck up.
Speaker 0: I would have made sure I had a buyout clause and I buy the rest of the stupid company out of Receivership or what?
Speaker 0: I'd buy the rest of it out of whatever problem there.
Speaker 1: now you'd be in debt if you did that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, no shit, and then I did take some invest.
Speaker 0: I could make this happen Jesus.
Speaker 1: Well, no, I'm not gonna have any of these people.
Speaker 1: who are they?
Speaker 1: you're gonna go work wherever the stupid factory is.
Speaker 0: No I would yeah, I wouldn't do any actual work and hire people to do.
Speaker 0: but I Feel like this company was just deeply mismanaged by people who are naive about business and were passionate about gaming And gaming tables.
Speaker 1: their passion by gaming first and furniture, right?
Speaker 0: I blame them for making this trend where there's a bunch of companies.
Speaker 1: Well, those are actually much more recent the imitators.
Speaker 1: I started seeing imitators in the past two three years.
Speaker 1: maybe they've been around longer, but I started seeing them out in force recently and they're obviously the imitators are Obviously doing pretty similar work.
Speaker 1: I've never seen anything that wasn't equally gaudy.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right and I can't tell if the imitators are higher or less quality But their prices are lower and they're not like hand delivering shit and doing this You know, they're doing business more normally some of them But I don't know if any of the imitators are good or not, but their competition is there.
Speaker 1: now is the point Had to be putting a hurt on them at least to some degree originally going crazy on Craigslist trying to buy Existing geek chic tables for huge huge markup.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah I heard that like origins or Gen Con or something was like, oh my god If anyone has geeky tables, we want to buy them from you dude.
Speaker 0: Someone should just start making counterfeits.
Speaker 1: I mean, why not just order from many of these imitating companies that is out there?
Speaker 1: I'm sure they're not all bad.
Speaker 1: So
Speaker 0: I partly blame that because geek chic one thing that I remember when we talked to them Like way back when we first we
Speaker 1: talked to them when they were super new and the guy was way enthusiastic and cool And you know, but they're good people
Speaker 0: they they emphasized so heavily like the wood grain And the choice the
Speaker 1: same as the guy selling the dice -
Speaker 0: I was getting that there's like a whole
Speaker 1: Nerd.
Speaker 0: a whole bunch of nerds and gaming now are Sort of faux obsessed with different wood qualities in like their dice towers and things Despite not actually knowing anything about it's like the people are really into a lot about wood.
Speaker 0: They oh, no, the people are buying them don't know shit about wood I don't know.
Speaker 1: people buying it don't know but the guy is a wood nerd.
Speaker 0: They get upsold by someone who is a word nerd who basically explains to them how.
Speaker 1: you know That's RPG people right?
Speaker 1: They love to buy like leather bound DM guide metal dice, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, I love like, you know to feel, you know, steampunk people right?
Speaker 1: It's that sort of group of nerds.
Speaker 1: They love you know, the material qualities of things.
Speaker 1: They really get off on that even though they have no idea They can.
Speaker 1: But you know, they spend extra money to get.
Speaker 1: you know leather bound parchment stuff, you know this kind of thing.
Speaker 1: They love that shit.
Speaker 1: So they spend more money on that.
Speaker 1: where I'm just like just give me a d6.
Speaker 1: it doesn't matter if it's plastic or metal It's gonna roll, right?
Speaker 0: I want to see the company that goes the other route and maybe the cool-looking DC makes this shit like IKEA But focuses on functionality and minimalism.
Speaker 1: That's what I want.
Speaker 0: I would buy the hell out of an IKEA style table that had this these features built in.
Speaker 1: Yeah, just uh, You know, why don't you start that company?
Speaker 0: You know, I think that I don't see I wouldn't want to start one.
Speaker 1: It might fail though because the market for the tables are mostly those RPG people who really like that crafty stuff.
Speaker 0: The market is also clearly but maybe that's just live in suburbia because if you live an apartment this shit is literally impossible, right?
Speaker 1: But that's another thing right?
Speaker 1: I wonder if you know, we exist, right?
Speaker 1: But we think like we think that we're the rare person who wants the IKEA silent majority, right?
Speaker 1: could there could it just be a stereotype of RPG people that they like that sort of Aesthetic and that the reality is?
Speaker 1: no actually if you made IKEA style, you know modern You know kind of looking furniture that was useful for gaming that people would eat that shit up.
Speaker 0: Yeah, cuz like if you want to buy a poker table or like card playing tables They're actually shockingly cheap for like really really fancy ones.
Speaker 0: Yeah so some other news.
Speaker 0: a Lot of people were complaining During the reason the new season of overwatch that they appeared to be ranked much lower after their placement matches in the competitive For serious mode.
Speaker 0: then they had been previously.
Speaker 1: change the system.
Speaker 0: It appears that.
Speaker 0: and so basically as far as I can tell they do not.
Speaker 0: the system does not put stock in How where you were ranked previously and sort of starts from at least a semi clean slate every season.
Speaker 1: now I kind of like that.
Speaker 0: I kind of hate that because you're not gonna move between season 5 and season 6.
Speaker 0: There is no way you're suddenly a silver tier player if you were in platinum before.
Speaker 1: Well, I think the the reason I like that is because the game changes a lot, right?
Speaker 1: They add new characters enough to be material or there's new maps and things, right?
Speaker 1: So you might suddenly You know be a lot better due to the rules changes and someone else might have a hard time with those rules changes.
Speaker 1: That might be cause for a reset if you change the actual game.
Speaker 1: But yeah, if you're not changing the game significantly then know that you shouldn't even be resetting at all.
Speaker 1: Why are you even making people do the placement matches again?
Speaker 1: Just keep just keep going.
Speaker 0: Yep I that's what I think.
Speaker 0: I think you should keep going forever hearthstone.
Speaker 1: their ranking system isn't a real ranking system.
Speaker 1: Is this grind into you right?
Speaker 1: We've not gonna talk about that again.
Speaker 1: So they can't.
Speaker 1: they reset it every month every season no matter what you get down ranked a whole everyone gets down ranked.
Speaker 1: And I think no you should only do it when there's new cards.
Speaker 1: as soon as the new cards You should reset everyone to absolutely zero no matter where they were because suddenly it's a new game.
Speaker 1: But if you haven't added any new cards to change the rules of the game or anything, it's the same game.
Speaker 0: Just keep it going Even if you change the rules.
Speaker 0: I feel like you could keep the existing ranking because people just you can.
Speaker 1: time you can but it is a different game.
Speaker 1: So suddenly your rank is partially influenced by playing a different Sort itself out pretty quick if you just keep playing.
Speaker 1: It would may eventually right but it would be quick.
Speaker 0: I think it depends.
Speaker 0: Hearthstone ain't that complicated.
Speaker 1: Imagine if we're playing chess for a month and then in the second month We're playing backgammon, but we're still ranked based on our chess play.
Speaker 0: Yeah But the difference between those two games is more than the combined changes to every quake multiplayer game in history combined.
Speaker 1: I guess when you add a character to an art to an FPS or a fighting game That's not an enormous change like a map or something, right?
Speaker 1: But if you add cards to a card game, it's basically a whole new fucking game.
Speaker 0: But it appears to that the system seems to rank people now Lower than what the real rank is.
Speaker 0: so they'll feel that sense of progress as they catch up to their actual rank.
Speaker 1: So they're not doing it for actual competitive reason.
Speaker 1: It's good in the competitive mode.
Speaker 1: You shouldn't be doing that.
Speaker 0: So I don't have any like confirmation of that.
Speaker 0: But many many very skilled players said that this is what they experienced that as soon as they got into the system with their rank Which was low they immediately rose like cat rapidly through the ranks just by playing matches again
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm,
Speaker 0: so I experienced the flip side of this.
Speaker 1: Well, isn't that also a bad experience for the people who suck getting paired with people who rank getting their asses kicked in a few rounds?
Speaker 1: Well, they yeah as other people grind up on them.
Speaker 0: So I did something I've never done before for season 5.
Speaker 0: I played all my ranking matches, especially now that it's all at once all not all at once but solo Meaning.
Speaker 0: I was just matched with random shit lords and not with your friends.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I didn't play any not not one with any of my friends Mm-hmm, and let me tell you I played a couple matches were like two people on the other team.
Speaker 0: I looked up their stats.
Speaker 0: They were diamond last season and I'm on a team We're like one of my dudes clearly has not played the game for more than like a couple weeks like they did not fly as diva at any point that I could see and So I got ranked the lowest I've ever experienced in my life in the high silvers.
Speaker 0: Holy shit, are people terrible at this game down there.
Speaker 0: Once I got into the main matches I walk around games like a god like I single-handedly can win games for my team no matter how bad they are sometimes.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well, this is crazy.
Speaker 1: This is a fundamental problem.
Speaker 1: Is that I'm not I don't know about the overwatch specifically but rocket League Which I actually just tried to play again and I lost most of my skills just did not having played for a long ass time And I didn't have that many skills.
Speaker 1: I was basically super good.
Speaker 1: if no one can fly which is what everyone can do.
Speaker 1: I've been in overwatch But anyway, all these games team base because you could if you were just single people playing the game on your own Like it was just chess.
Speaker 1: you could just yellow per if you really wanted to right which is what you should do.
Speaker 1: But when you have a team game, it's like alright How do we judge you when you're on a team because like personally right if I'm on a team with good people like who are?
Speaker 1: Good my play is elevated and this happens even in Professional sports.
Speaker 1: you have players like for example this year basketball right basketball this year.
Speaker 1: It's over now Kevin Durant.
Speaker 1: Kevin Durant is a guy who everyone knew was a great player, right?
Speaker 1: He was terrific, but he was on the Oklahoma City Thunder right playing with some other pretty good players, right?
Speaker 1: No, but he never.
Speaker 1: he was known.
Speaker 1: it was his thing.
Speaker 1: Basically you always got to the playoffs in round one and lost.
Speaker 1: get to the.
Speaker 1: that was the thing.
Speaker 1: They're like.
Speaker 1: you can't win.
Speaker 1: shit Kevin Durant.
Speaker 1: If you're so great.
Speaker 1: How come you always lose in the first round of the playoffs, right?
Speaker 1: So this year he split.
Speaker 1: he left the OKC Thunder and he went to the Golden State Warriors the best or second best team there is and He just totally killed it.
Speaker 1: He's you know, that team already had won a championship two years ago, right?
Speaker 1: And you know came really close to winning the championship last year Basically should have won last year right and lost like the last three games of a seven game series and the seventh game.
Speaker 1: They lost right.
Speaker 1: They were ahead three one and then this year he goes to that team and a team That was already that good.
Speaker 1: He was the best player on that team and they just dominated and just they were in.
Speaker 0: they were fat happen I was.
Speaker 1: there was seven game series.
Speaker 1: They won four sweep sweep sweep and then I think the last one there were.
Speaker 1: it was like four and one.
Speaker 0: That happens so consistently in overwatch.
Speaker 1: So if I play on a team with good people, I'm better and if I play at a team with shitty people You're right.
Speaker 1: It's hard.
Speaker 1: Even though we gotta play differently even though my individual skill is the same It's harder for me to get kills cuz like I'm swarmed by My teammates aren't help, right?
Speaker 0: So like if you're on a good team You can blind pass and trust someone will be in their spot.
Speaker 0: on a shitty team You gotta like look first, right?
Speaker 1: So So that's a thing.
Speaker 1: but also all of these games is most of them are using a system that Microsoft invented called Microsoft true skill and you can read all the math behind Microsoft true skill that you want but Microsoft true skill ranks you up and down Based solely on winning and losing.
Speaker 1: it doesn't give a fuck at all about your individual results.
Speaker 1: So you're playing racks if you play rocket league and you're on a team with two Basically people who are afk and you score 20 fucking goals But the other team has three average players and they score 21 goals.
Speaker 1: You might as well have scored zero goals It might.
Speaker 1: the system that ranks you doesn't give a fuck and your rate goes down.
Speaker 1: It gives no shits about your individual abilities.
Speaker 1: It is so unsubtle and all these systems are based on just win and lose.
Speaker 1: They don't look at any of that stuff.
Speaker 1: So the rankings for your team-based gameplay are always fucked up in all of these games because no one has put the effort in to figure out the math to actually subtly look at individual stats and say oh look,
Speaker 0: so Overwatch does track a lot of those individual stats, but
Speaker 1: how are they affected in your rank?
Speaker 1: Is it possible for you to go?
Speaker 1: has your rank ever gone up in a game?
Speaker 1: You've lost?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I don't even look at my rank, right?
Speaker 1: But I'm just saying like it's possible for your rank to go up in a game You lose.
Speaker 0: it may well be using that because they don't.
Speaker 0: I don't think they've published exactly how all this works But I've seen reports of people who say that like if they heal really well even a losing game They've gone up in the season.
Speaker 1: That's what I don't know, but it's very published and I've never haven't played overwatch.
Speaker 1: I don't know what they do specifically, but I'm saying most of the team-based games are you know?
Speaker 0: I say that's fine because these games are four teams.
Speaker 0: if you're playing as an individual You're already doing something weird.
Speaker 0: you play this game as a team No, but it's.
Speaker 1: but your rank is an individual rank.
Speaker 0: right if but if you play as a consistent team of six Then your team you're a consistent team of six.
Speaker 1: They should just use elo and not let you play with other people, right?
Speaker 1: We're talking about when you play on your own with rando people.
Speaker 1: if you're six people who are stuck together You know the New York over watches Then you just don't even need to rank the individual people.
Speaker 1: your team has a ring.
Speaker 0: No, you're right the individual people because one day if they if someone consistently plays on teams that do good Then they are probably a better player if they consistently on teams itself.
Speaker 1: Obviously, that's true that the rank isn't completely.
Speaker 1: and I'm not saying the rank is garbage and worthless, right?
Speaker 1: I'm just saying it's always frustratingly slightly wrong Because it's not paying attention enough to how good an individual is.
Speaker 0: But at the same time how good an individual is is pretty worthless in a game.
Speaker 0: That is so heavily team dependent.
Speaker 1: Well, yeah overwatch is more team dependent than say rocket league.
Speaker 1: one good person on a rocket league team or basketball for that 100% win.
Speaker 1: you just can just carry the team.
Speaker 0: how to strike - if you're really good at like head click flicks And you memorize your corners like you minding on the makeup of the teams You could carry your team and you would rank up pretty quickly.
Speaker 1: But
Speaker 0: like overwatch like if I'm if I'm Reinhardt the big shield hammer guy Which is why main lately if I'm on a good team and we get a pick when we're attacking I will immediately charge a healer or something because I know my team's right behind me because we got the pick.
Speaker 0: if I do that when I'm Playing with randos or like silver tears.
Speaker 0: It's instant death for me.
Speaker 0: So I have to play that completely differently.
Speaker 0: so I have like If I talk to my team before I play with randos to figure out if I think they're shitheads or not And then I play very differently depending if they're shitheads.
Speaker 1: I'm just saying like, you know It should.
Speaker 1: the game should detect right that you're better than shitheads and you should never be playing with them ever.
Speaker 1: Yeah You know just because you might get into a bad streak We're like, okay, even though you're playing with good players, which means you're playing against good players You're gonna lose.
Speaker 1: but it should still know this person is too good for that.
Speaker 1: those people down.
Speaker 0: But I found that the system so the placement matches are all over the place because you're reset.
Speaker 1: So you're playing with like this crazy wide spread, but once I got into the regular enough people playing this very popular game You should never have to be playing with anyone too far away from your own during their matchmaking the initial placement matches.
Speaker 0: you will.
Speaker 1: Oh during the initial placement matches.
Speaker 1: You should be forced to play with like all different ranks You should be able to.
Speaker 1: you should be playing with like pros.
Speaker 1: You should have at least one game with pro people a game with almost pro people a game with the most garbage people who don't Even know how to control the game.
Speaker 1: what I found?
Speaker 1: Then?
Speaker 1: it could do the best job of figuring out where you belong because I clearly don't belong in that ranking.
Speaker 0: My rating has just been going up and up and up and up and up just at a constant rate since the regular game started.
Speaker 0: Yeah, because the people in the Silver's pretty bad But also shockingly really really friendly like I haven't run into the weird like shittiness that everyone keeps complaining about that This season mm-hmm like everyone's complaining about throwers and people freaking out And it's so rare that like it's really notable when that happens to man.
Speaker 1: I don't know why rowers like you lose the game on purpose.
Speaker 0: There's a ton of people who just do that.
Speaker 1: Why no one knows what's the I mean?
Speaker 0: There's usually a reason to do that But just they're jerks the trolls there's no benefit of doing or they're doing it to get a really low Ranking so they can then team up with their high ranking friends and bring their rating down so they play against worse people.
Speaker 0: And one last thing that's also related to not just overwatch of a blizzard in general.
Speaker 0: So twitch and blizzard now have a formal exclusive streaming arrangement.
Speaker 1: Yeah with the two-year term It's not really a big deal because already blizzard was streaming all their shit on switch.
Speaker 0: But they're also officially, but there was also streaming on other platforms.
Speaker 1: I didn't see any streaming another platform.
Speaker 0: this article specifically says that has happened numerous times.
Speaker 1: I've never.
Speaker 1: I'm just saying I've never seen it right.
Speaker 1: twitch has always been.
Speaker 0: I don't watch anything other than overwatch.
Speaker 1: I'm just saying twitch has always been the number one place to watch blizzard stuff.
Speaker 1: So this just sort of makes it more official.
Speaker 0: It looks like a lot of it was on Facebook, too.
Speaker 1: I've never seen that.
Speaker 0: a lot of people watch gaming on Facebook.
Speaker 0: Apparently.
Speaker 0: I don't know why why you do that, but It's interesting that these are the kinds of arrangements that happened in regular sports And you're starting to see these things happen like more and more in eSports.
Speaker 0: This is like one more of those stepping stones on the way to eSports being Super professional just like regular sports are.
Speaker 1: the real news is that if you have twitch prime Which you do because you have Amazon Prime because you buy things on Amazon like a modern person You're gonna basically get the loot for Amazon for twitch prime has not been great Like.
Speaker 1: I've looked at it every time there's new loot in there and it's usually worthless stuff.
Speaker 1: I don't like cosmetic shit for games I'm never gonna play.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so I just ignore it.
Speaker 1: But you're gonna get loot crates for your overwatch guarantee.
Speaker 1: They already decided that but there's gonna be stuff for also all the other Blizzard games.
Speaker 1: You know the Diablos and the hearthstones and the Starcrafts and the whatever.
Speaker 1: So, you know probably get some free hearthstone packs and you'll someone else will probably get some.
Speaker 1: you know Skins for what the heroes of the storm piece of shit.
Speaker 1: I just I hope that some Mounts or something.
Speaker 0: I really want that aspect of eSports to disappear because it just feels like all those shitty panels at cons Where they throw garbage free stuff into the audience to get people to show up.
Speaker 1: Well, the thing is it's funnily enough, right?
Speaker 0: But it is also like what regular sports do.
Speaker 0: you go to a hockey game and they give you a shitty towel.
Speaker 1: in all these other games it's like The loot is like all cosmetic worthless shit, but in hearthstone It's actually because the CCG packs of cards are always are a real thing sort of right?
Speaker 1: Yeah But like part that they also do cosmetic shit.
Speaker 1: in hearthstone They give you like new character skins and card backs and I give a shit.
Speaker 1: Yeah, just even more cards.
Speaker 0: But anyway things of the day.
Speaker 0: this video is pretty good But it's something that I always was fascinated by and this sort of just explains it really succinctly.
Speaker 0: It explains in detail how VHS VCRs work and why is it just analog tape the same as a cassette?
Speaker 0: Yeah, what does that mean?
Speaker 1: It did you take the analog signal that TVs like to input like the one that comes over the air.
Speaker 1: So I record it to an analog already Scott and then play it back To the TV already.
Speaker 0: That's actually a crazy difficult problem because the frequencies involved.
Speaker 0: Okay, this explains in extreme Extreme detail but in probably the level.
Speaker 0: this explains in a level of detail that many of you who don't might find fascinating because the VCRs are actually Shockingly complex.
Speaker 1: and when you back in that of amazing back in the day at a TV station, right?
Speaker 1: If you broadcast a show you would record the show.
Speaker 1: Yeah broadcasting is Incredibly different.
Speaker 1: I'm just saying you would record it to a reel to reel tape and then to do a rerun Play the real tape and brought.
Speaker 0: actually for a long time TV was broadcast live and could not be recorded.
Speaker 1: I know that but I'm saying once they had recorded TV they would just do unreal to real tape and then they would rerun it and just send it or read it from the Recorded tape was already a huge problem.
Speaker 0: because of the frequencies involved It was almost impossible to make a consumer version of this in any capacity.
Speaker 1: That's why VCRs have those modes because it's heavily compressed and they throw out a lot of the data Real to real tape.
Speaker 0: you have no idea how LP AP all the SLP modes work.
Speaker 1: I'm just saying that that isn't that how it works.
Speaker 1: you record an analog signal to a tape and then you play it back Just like a cassette tape only with video.
Speaker 0: Uh, actually not at all just like a cassette tape and this video explains in pretty interesting detail exactly how it works.
Speaker 1: How could it be so different?
Speaker 0: Well, you should watch this video.
Speaker 0: I think you clearly don't know anything about helical recording
Speaker 1: anyway
Speaker 0: but it's just a pretty good video because I even when I was a kid like I knew a lot about like Why SLP worked and what hi-fi mode was probably cuz I was bootlegging movies and like an anime fan subs I know like ripping macro vision out and none of my friends knew like.
Speaker 0: I had a friend who was recording a bunch of stuff and he literally his VCR was an SLP mode and he in it for years.
Speaker 0: He never actually knew what that mode was and what that switch did it does.
Speaker 0: the switch was on SLP More qualities, but less note recording time.
Speaker 0: SLP is shit quality record for it.
Speaker 1: I mean the different modes.
Speaker 1: I don't know which one is which SLP is bad quality.
Speaker 1: Okay, you're choosing either low quality but lots of recording time or high quality less recording.
Speaker 0: There were actually three modes right middle mode Disappeared from almost all VCRs.
Speaker 1: pretty early on all the VCRs ever saw had the three modes.
Speaker 0: They would all play all three modes But very few would record in all three modes.
Speaker 0: interesting if you had one that recorded in all three years either old or super high.
Speaker 1: I'll certainly go to buy blank tapes and some of them were had.
Speaker 1: the ones that were more expensive ones that had more tape in Them yep, so you could record longer, but the ones that have more tape in them also were way more prone to failure.
Speaker 1: I didn't know that.
Speaker 1: I mean how could a tape fail?
Speaker 1: you either break it or you don't?
Speaker 0: you never had a. you never had a Tape.
Speaker 0: get stuck in the VCR more have it on spool.
Speaker 0: That's actually kind of common.
Speaker 0: never had it or the tape would just snap.
Speaker 1: But I did see a lot of jokes like people would that you'd see like a joke like a cartoon.
Speaker 1: you'd see a VCR.
Speaker 1: We're like tape spewing out of it.
Speaker 0: I said that happened to me multiple times.
Speaker 1: I never saw that in real life.
Speaker 0: I saw in real life partly cuz I was bootlegging videos all over the fuck place anyway.
Speaker 1: So here speaking of old TV from the analog days is the recording of some old TV from Japan.
Speaker 1: and usually when you're checking old TV from Japan it's usually something like some wacky show or anime or a commercial for something that you know is Japanese like Oh famous American actor does a commercial for a product in Japan or Nintendo commercial from Japan, but here is something that I haven't seen before.
Speaker 1: this is American products that were sold in Japan like yeah Like you know for kids mostly right like Jack Jack slime Coosh ball tennis thing and oh and much much more Right, but sold in Japan.
Speaker 1: and here's the commercials for those American products that we know from America, right?
Speaker 1: It's sort of the opposite deal.
Speaker 0: It's interesting to see which parts of these are very similar to the American advertising and which parts of them are drastically different.
Speaker 0: Yep Actually remember a lot of the American ads for a lot of these products.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah A lot of them are real simple.
Speaker 1: Anyway, this is really fascinating and fun to watch.
Speaker 1: So check it out.
Speaker 1: And also Why is it always Japan?
Speaker 1: Can we see this like show?
Speaker 1: show me like the I don't know.
Speaker 1: I guess it was to the Soviet Union still existed.
Speaker 1: So there wouldn't be like dude Slovakia and commercials forget stuff is on YouTube.
Speaker 0: I'll make it my thing in the day.
Speaker 1: Let's go watch like the Belgian commercial for gacking slime, right?
Speaker 0: or you know?
Speaker 0: when I found a bunch of that stuff When I was looking for anime openers around the world, I actually found a lot of commercials and things.
Speaker 1: Yeah, was there an Australian commercial for sliming gag?
Speaker 1: Oh, I buy some gag.
Speaker 0: Oh That that I don't know if that's an Australian accent or not.
Speaker 0: I'll try it.
Speaker 1: buy some gag mate.
Speaker 0: Good.
Speaker 0: I good on ya No eyes.
Speaker 0: The book club book is Frank Herbert's, dude, I'm reading it.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna read it next week cuz I'm flying to London and I'm sure I'll be done with it.
Speaker 0: When I get back from London, I'm all spiced up.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna be spiced up and spiced out.
Speaker 0: spice everywhere.
Speaker 0: I'm really just not looking forward to this cuz I just Partly because I got Prince of Nothing on the mind again I want to actually that's.
Speaker 1: I'm reading it now because I want to finish it because Prince of Nothing's coming away soon yep,
Speaker 0: and even if the later books concluding the Prince of Nothing do not have quite the same level of Certain kinds of artistry that the earlier books did I gotta know what happens.
Speaker 0: I gotta know what the deal is with all the biz and I know that these books are gonna wrap it all up because that's Just.
Speaker 0: how are you sure you should do not on our website?
Speaker 0: actually I will.
Speaker 0: I just haven't I've been busy and bored.
Speaker 0: and to do that a busy busy board.
Speaker 0: Yeah Also, I Restarted something that many of you been asking me for.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna be streaming advanced Wars all different advanced Wars games Regularly on YouTube.
Speaker 0: cuz a lot of people are asking for it and a bunch of people watch like I had like 20 30 people.
Speaker 0: It's not.
Speaker 1: there's not a lot of advanced Wars content out there.
Speaker 1: You don't have much competition.
Speaker 0: I went and watched a bunch of the advanced Wars content.
Speaker 0: These dudes suck at advanced Wars.
Speaker 0: Yeah Like I might be one of the best advanced Wars players in the world.
Speaker 0: probably I'm pretty because I got so I can't like I didn't.
Speaker 0: I'm not gonna mod my DS So I just have an emulator.
Speaker 0: so I had to go get a save file that had everything unlocked And the save file I found on the internet is like super master s-rank everything.
Speaker 0: I think almost all my s-ranks are way higher than the save file.
Speaker 1: even so save file Shouldn't the save file just be hacked like nine nine nine nine nine nine scores.
Speaker 0: It's just a regular legit save file.
Speaker 0: Okay, I didn't find any hacked ones.
Speaker 0: I don't think anyone cared enough to hack one But the actual save files on all my advanced Wars cartridges are way better than the save files I have found online so far.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 1: So anyway, I'm also Streaming stuff.
Speaker 0: It's not streaming a lot of stuff.
Speaker 1: I say you play in the woods I'm just streaming whatever right like whatever, you know, I don't have like a plan.
Speaker 1: I'm just sort of like.
Speaker 1: you know what.
Speaker 1: I got something to make a video of.
Speaker 1: it's like lunchtime and I.
Speaker 0: your undertale stream was Hard to watch though because you didn't really get how the game worked and then you quit.
Speaker 1: What do you mean is RPG?
Speaker 0: Why'd you kill your mom the goat mom?
Speaker 1: Why not?
Speaker 0: So you just killing people?
Speaker 1: What's wrong with that?
Speaker 0: You can kill people.
Speaker 0: It's just a very different game.
Speaker 1: If you do that, you see when I put this thing, I'm playing an RPG, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm only interested in like seeing what the deal is.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right and I could tell this game is going for something like oh it wants me to either You know kill all the people or not kill all the people right, but I'm like, you know what?
Speaker 1: I'm just gonna do whatever makes me go ahead in the game fastest.
Speaker 0: You can do that too.
Speaker 0: And actually you'll get different endings and different stuff happens depending on who you kill.
Speaker 1: I just want to get through this game as quickly as possible.
Speaker 1: So I'm and I got to that lady and it's like, okay The way there might be some way to beat this without using the attack part But it's pain in the ass to figure that out and I don't give a shit.
Speaker 1: So I'm gonna use the fight part and get this over with.
Speaker 0: what's really funny Is that the over and over with quickly.
Speaker 0: the overarching theme of the game is that people will do exactly what you did.
Speaker 1: Yeah, just want to get this shit over.
Speaker 0: Yep That is the plot of the game.
Speaker 0: people who think like you in the game and play the game that way that is literally the plot.
Speaker 0: The game only takes like six hours like it's really quick.
Speaker 1: I don't think I'm playing that again.
Speaker 0: Hi, it's so quick.
Speaker 0: How could this take?
Speaker 1: you didn't even use a garbage piece of software and I didn't give a shit.
Speaker 0: it just worked.
Speaker 1: I just played like unlike Prince of Nothing.
Speaker 1: I don't care what happens.
Speaker 0: How about night in the woods?
Speaker 0: Cuz I'm gonna play that real soon.
Speaker 1: night in the woods is actually it's.
Speaker 1: I mean It's not some kind of masterpiece, but it is as a piece of software.
Speaker 1: It is has tiny flaws But not like.
Speaker 1: it's a very well-made game.
Speaker 1: the controller connected and disconnected and reconnect.
Speaker 0: see all these simple games.
Speaker 0: because I strained them I just played them on my keyboard.
Speaker 0: I didn't even try to make a controller work.
Speaker 1: Probably be a lot better actually to play night in the woods with the keyboard instead of a gamepad But I can play it on the couch.
Speaker 1: So I don't want to use a keyboard.
Speaker 0: I mean I because I wonder tale like because the platforming part like all the fighting Way easy if you just use arrow keys May play like DDR.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there are certain rhythm parts in night in the woods.
Speaker 1: That would be way easier with arrow keys.
Speaker 0: I'll probably play it on a keyboard.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I would I would suggest that.
Speaker 1: but yeah, I'm playing with a gamepad which is some parts are bad But other the platforming parts are better with the gamepad, but seriously I wish I was streaming right now because I've noticed something.
Speaker 0: now that we have the patreon and we have the podcast and the forum and the YouTube streams there are people who are fans of us because they saw us at a con and they want they subscribe to our YouTube channel and They just noticed like after years of fandom like recently.
Speaker 0: Oh shit You guys do a party, you know this.
Speaker 1: every panel the first and last thing we say at every time.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott Shit Like I could.
Speaker 0: people are asking me questions in the YouTube channel that imply that they literally have no idea We have ever done a podcast.
Speaker 1: We just said it at the beginning and end of every panel.
Speaker 1: We're just weren't listening to the words We were saying.
Speaker 0: so I'm saying this now because if you listen if you like subscribe to us on iTunes And that is your only interaction and you don't know that we do any other things.
Speaker 1: We are put.
Speaker 1: we put stuff all over the internet.
Speaker 0: type the word geek nights into Google.
Speaker 0: I feel like that should imagine.
Speaker 1: imagine a globe.
Speaker 1: There's the internet and then there's us too and we took some buckets of garbage and we just poured them all over that globe.
Speaker 1: There's no part of the globe that is untouched by us.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like I like type the word geek nights into Google and there's a ton of crap everywhere and no one else.
Speaker 0: the only other thing that uses that word violating our common law trademark is like this semi Defunct group of nerds who meet occasionally in London.
Speaker 1: I think I think it's Oxford ox Oxford geek night and occasionally people use the geek night's hashtag just because they're having like a nerdy good old time and they're like Whoa, it's a geek night.
Speaker 1: Yep, like oh, we're gonna play some.
Speaker 0: Oh, no at this point actually we've even pushed those fuckers off.
Speaker 0: if you google geek nights We are 100% of the first page of results.
Speaker 0: Mmm, and nope The Northampton geek nights number 19 from May 10th is in the middle of the second page of results.
Speaker 0: So I am amazed that people like you exist and you should like look at our other stuff because if you Listen to this you'd probably like our other stuff a lot more.
Speaker 0: So speaking of games we played a lot over the years and just never reviewed.
Speaker 1: I think I really think you're deleting episodes and so we can do it.
Speaker 0: ideas prove it son.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna go.
Speaker 1: I
Speaker 0: think our problem is that there's a lot of things that we all we just always assumed we reviewed Because we have talked about them at length or even reviewed them with friends like oh You've never played race for the galaxy and we like talk about it and our brain just takes that and says yeah That was a geek night's episode.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so race for the galaxy is one of those board games.
Speaker 1: That is well card game actually sort of tabletop.
Speaker 1: It is one of those like staple games.
Speaker 1: that like is cemented itself in the tabletop Board game culture and is like always in every game library.
Speaker 1: Everyone knows how to play.
Speaker 1: it's up there settlers cargosone Dominion.
Speaker 1: right race of the galaxy is like up.
Speaker 1: there is one of those games that will always be there.
Speaker 0: Yeah bunch of expansions.
Speaker 0: There's apps There's role for the galaxy.
Speaker 0: that is basically the same game with dice instead of cards.
Speaker 1: It's not as good.
Speaker 1: I think it's better.
Speaker 1: But anyway, I don't think so.
Speaker 1: Anyway, we're only talking about race to the galaxy today.
Speaker 0: So it's expansions to a degree.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: So the deal with race of the galaxy is it's a lot like Puerto Rico actually, yeah, right every round Every.
Speaker 1: instead in Puerto Rico you take turns choosing what's gonna happen like I'm gonna captain and Scott says well I'm gonna crash right.
Speaker 1: so when rim captains he captains super captain because he chose it but everyone else just regular captains.
Speaker 1: Right in race of the galaxy Everyone chooses at the same time and people can actually choose the same thing as each other.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and you could just choose the same thing over and over again.
Speaker 1: But if you choose trade you do super trading.
Speaker 1: But now everyone else gets to do regular trading if they also chose trading Because two people might choose the same thing.
Speaker 1: Everyone could choose the same thing.
Speaker 0: Yeah, then it's panty ass when that happens.
Speaker 1: anyone who chooses does super version of that task But everyone else gets to do regular version.
Speaker 1: So sometimes you get to do everything because everyone chose something different and sometimes you don't get to do very much because everyone chose.
Speaker 0: Now that's already a huge Huge difference from Puerto Rico because in Puerto Rico I choose a role and then the next player.
Speaker 0: So Scott knows what I chose can't choose that and decides based on.
Speaker 0: so every role you choose Informs the decisions but also restricts the decisions of all the further player in race of the galaxy.
Speaker 1: You're trying to guess who I want.
Speaker 1: I really need trading to happen, but I don't want to pick it.
Speaker 1: I know the benefit of picking trading.
Speaker 0: you have to pick.
Speaker 0: you can't trade unless you pick it.
Speaker 1: Oh, right, right, right, okay.
Speaker 1: I really want to settle right now.
Speaker 1: All right, but the benefit of settling is only a minor benefit.
Speaker 1: It's like a one discount or something, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, like.
Speaker 1: I don't need the discount.
Speaker 1: I'm good I just need to but I do want to settle.
Speaker 1: so I want settling to happen But I really don't want to have to play settle because it would also be nice to produce happen this turn.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I want to use and I hope that Jojo explores rim gonna produce.
Speaker 1: if he produces then I can just settle.
Speaker 1: I need to settle if he produces But if he's I think he's gonna settle which is great.
Speaker 1: So I'm gonna produce and then you really hope you can guess what other people gonna do it.
Speaker 1: This psychological element is the number one fun great thing about race of the guy.
Speaker 0: I played a game that I remember to this day where the game started and in the first two rounds Nobody picked.
Speaker 1: settle everyone picks explore.
Speaker 0: in the early everyone picked explore Develop predict like other stuff to two times in a row except military guy.
Speaker 0: So event even military guy.
Speaker 0: so eventually.
Speaker 0: so two rounds of bad drive military guy No one has settled.
Speaker 0: like couple people built like a development Mm-hmm, and everyone assumes now because everyone's got a pile of cards in their hands It's up one jerk that someone's gonna pick settle.
Speaker 0: No one picks it.
Speaker 1: It kept trying to mooch off someone else.
Speaker 0: We went six rounds where no one picked.
Speaker 1: Well your hands really shitty or what?
Speaker 0: well people like people do developments instead, okay or other stuff.
Speaker 0: But no one settled.
Speaker 0: no worlds were put out.
Speaker 0: on the seventh round everyone pick settle everyone Except one person picked settle the smart a winner.
Speaker 0: But that happens a lot and that is a big fun part of this game the other part of this game.
Speaker 1: But that and it's the most like there's a whole bunch of other stuff going on in the game.
Speaker 1: but that Aspect of that word that part beginning of the term where you choose what you're gonna do and you're trying to guess what the other People are gonna choose.
Speaker 1: that is like more than 50% of the fun Strategy and quality in this game and that's why it's fun to play over and over and over and over and over again Just doing that thing over and over again.
Speaker 1: It's so great.
Speaker 1: Yep I don't get I don't get tired of that aspect.
Speaker 0: and the game is if you look at if you never played it before it looks Terrifyingly Bullshitty complex like it looks like the most ridiculous Nonsense game that you will do anything to avoid playing with some guy at a time.
Speaker 1: The thing is this game isn't actually that complex as far as games go.
Speaker 1: It is come to complex for a complete beginner, but it is not as things go.
Speaker 1: It's not advanced squad leader It's not.
Speaker 1: even it's easier than Eclipse.
Speaker 1: It's easier than a lot of games Right, like.
Speaker 0: it's a game that it takes forever to teach someone who's never played games before right?
Speaker 0: But once you start playing by like two rounds and they're like, oh, right.
Speaker 1: So the main thing is that the cards have so much information on them But the information is coded in all these various symbols and what the symbols mean isn't really that crazy But you have to learn to read the symbols maybe and the graphic design.
Speaker 1: It's like maybe you could do better to make the learning easier, but I can't imagine a way you could.
Speaker 0: I think they've done it as good as they can.
Speaker 0: some of these symbols are shockingly complex But if you really look at them, they actually make a lot of sense.
Speaker 1: Once you look up what a symbol means you're like, oh, that's what that does.
Speaker 1: that makes perfect sense.
Speaker 0: Trade any good for one victory point and one card.
Speaker 1: Right, it's like oh it makes perfect sense.
Speaker 1: So you get to learn to read these symbols and that makes getting into the game a little bit difficult.
Speaker 1: The first times you play it you're gonna be constantly like looking at the book and asking people who know Like what does this card do?
Speaker 1: What does that symbol mean?
Speaker 0: I mean the summary card that comes with the game looks terrifying.
Speaker 1: Yeah, at least there is a summary card which helps you out, right but Once you learn to read the symbols You don't need the summary card anymore.
Speaker 1: The game is almost strangely like a solitaire thing, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah There's you interact at that fun part that I mentioned the good part where you choose the role that you're gonna do that turn or the activity Whatever the action and that's the interactive part with the other players.
Speaker 1: But other than that like once everyone chooses an action everyone just sort of goes Okay, and does their own thing Yeah and like you don't even might not even be paying attention to what the other people are doing.
Speaker 1: you should because then you learn how to.
Speaker 0: you know You can pay vague attention like Scott played another green Windfall world.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: Oh Joey Jojo got a more military.
Speaker 0: I better watch out.
Speaker 0: He might try to end the game quicker, right?
Speaker 1: But it's like, you know, you don't have to like super, you know normally in a game Everyone does their turn and says everything they're doing and you see every action they do and the next person goes and race.
Speaker 1: you can Play fast when everyone knows they're doing because everyone just sort of does their own shit Simultaneously.
Speaker 1: and then you can sort of look at stuff.
Speaker 1: You can look at everyone's boards.
Speaker 1: They're all public.
Speaker 1: You can very similar to see what they did.
Speaker 1: You just need to look at their board state to get all the information you need to make your own decisions.
Speaker 0: It's actually very similar among skilled players to how seven wonders tends to play out.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you you know you pass.
Speaker 1: you look at other people's boards to say, okay, I'll pick this card.
Speaker 1: But then once your turn happens like I'm building this I'm taking these points.
Speaker 1: Here's money.
Speaker 1: Give me money.
Speaker 0: Okay, yep, but the symbology of this game is way better than seven wonders.
Speaker 1: Yeah, seven wonders does have that similar problem to learn the language of the symbols.
Speaker 1: But I find that in seven wonders I have to keep looking things up every time I play hardly because there's too many mechanics that are really weird Especially when he had all the expansion in race of the galaxy.
Speaker 1: They just sort of combining the same Symbolic language over and over and cards that need it just have words on them.
Speaker 1: Yeah, a lot of the fancy development cards just have words on them to explain themselves.
Speaker 1: You don't you know, you don't need to look anything up.
Speaker 1: So I do need to look things up when there's new things or an expansion or the few really crazy cards.
Speaker 1: But it's a lot less common than seven wonders.
Speaker 1: You start off like ah, these leaders got to look them up.
Speaker 1: Yep every time.
Speaker 0: now the game Unexpanded is fun, but it's got maybe Maybe 20 plays right before.
Speaker 0: the game is complete random nonsense, you know There is.
Speaker 0: you don't make any decisions.
Speaker 0: The game is so simple.
Speaker 1: the game Just the core set the race of the galaxy box Doesn't have a lot of cards in it.
Speaker 1: So once you have played it a bunch to the point at which you don't need to look up symbols anymore It just gets really repetitive like you're seeing the same cards over and over again, you know exactly what to do on your turn.
Speaker 1: It's sort of previous.
Speaker 1: You're not making interesting decisions anymore Which is why it's good that that exists so that a new player can get into the game easily like that.
Speaker 1: But anyone who's played this enough or is it playing it semi seriously or is a somewhat hardcore tabletop gamer like us You have to combine a whole bunch of expansions in there to get a whole bunch of extra cards to mix things up and keep It exciting at the replay value.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: It was good because there's a lot of expansions.
Speaker 0: Well, there are two main expansions.
Speaker 0: I don't know what other expansions there are because these are the ones that I've played.
Speaker 0: I haven't played anybody.
Speaker 1: you want at least these two main ones especially but there are other ones the gathering storm and rebel versus Imperium.
Speaker 0: right you.
Speaker 1: now you basically need those like if you're buying this game and you like.
Speaker 1: I recommend not buying it.
Speaker 1: if you haven't Played it right play it.
Speaker 1: and if you like it and think you're gonna play it a lot Buy it and those two expansions all together.
Speaker 0: Yep Now be warned the expansions add more cards and they've actually made the game way better like especially just gathering storm.
Speaker 0: That's the minimum because that makes the game start way less random.
Speaker 0: Yeah Because once you play the original enough The start the random like what you start with determines the whole game and there's almost no way back from that initial set.
Speaker 0: But with gathering storm you have some sort of.
Speaker 0: you can tune what you want to do What strategy you want to go to a small degree when you start the game?
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm The only real bad expansion I think because there's like some goals and there was one that came out that I haven't played too much.
Speaker 1: They had like a board with alien guys moving around on the board or something, right?
Speaker 0: There's a scenario The in rebel vs.
Speaker 0: Imperium that I am not interested in at all And more importantly it adds a mechanic that I think is actually pretty bad Around actually attacking other players and taking their shit.
Speaker 1: Mmm I feel like that that that's not good because then suddenly you can't.
Speaker 1: that whole Solitaire element goes away where you start had to really think about what other people are.
Speaker 0: that is just as bad as Carcassonne expansions that let you knock other people's meeples off the board.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like that is bad news.
Speaker 1: so it's like not all the expansions for this game are good, but the good thing is that a lot.
Speaker 1: even the bad expansion like The one with the miniature board where guys move Cards, it just has a bunch of cards in it.
Speaker 1: so you can buy the expansions and not use all of the rules that they come with and not use all of the garbage in there.
Speaker 1: and Like it's like buying a carcass own expansion and just taking the tiles and not using those like you can buy me about what?
Speaker 1: The tower.
Speaker 0: about the tower.
Speaker 0: don't use the tower.
Speaker 1: We just added a bunch of tiles to the carcass zone.
Speaker 1: Right, so you can buy race to the galaxy expansion.
Speaker 1: You just add a bunch of cards And you're not gonna be able to add all the cards.
Speaker 1: We can even add most of them and get.
Speaker 1: mix up your game and get some interesting things happening Without having to use all of the extra weirdo garbage in there.
Speaker 0: I guess the most interesting thing about this game I mean we didn't get too much into the mechanics is it's better.
Speaker 0: if you just learn.
Speaker 1: the mechanics are pretty simple.
Speaker 1: It's like you're basically.
Speaker 1: you're getting cards cards or planets.
Speaker 0: cards are also currency Are everything right.
Speaker 1: cards are everything.
Speaker 1: so it's like you want to build this planet that costs for will discard for other cards.
Speaker 1: It doesn't matter what they are just cards and you hope you draw when you want to draw cards because drawing more cards gives You a more options, but be more currency to actually play some cards that are more expensive, right?
Speaker 1: And then you plan it's produce things so they get goods on them.
Speaker 1: some do some don't can turn goods into victory.
Speaker 0: Only produce things once when you build them and never again.
Speaker 1: planets are military and then there's Developments which do fancy stuff and get victory points and basically all the abilities on these cards enhance your regular abilities.
Speaker 1: So it's like oh this card has a thing that happens when you produce.
Speaker 1: so from now on every time produce happens You can do the fancy thing on this card and you're basically upgrading your machine and your machine is made of planets and goods and Development.
Speaker 1: so again like when someone reaches a certain number of cards in front of them.
Speaker 0: Well, there's two ways.
Speaker 1: the game is over and also in Puerto Rico.
Speaker 1: There's an n-race to the galaxy.
Speaker 1: There's a pile of victory point shits If you run that out if you run out the chit pile of victory points the game ends and then you see was the highest Score.
Speaker 1: so just like the best machine and got the most points and efficiently in the same number of turns.
Speaker 0: Yep, and In that aspect it's like it's a race.
Speaker 1: it's a race in strategy.
Speaker 0: the strategies of this game are Shockingly similar to the kinds of thinking you do in Puerto Rico as well Mm-hmm, like are you gonna build goods and ship them for victory points?
Speaker 0: Are you gonna build a bunch of fancy planets and developments?
Speaker 0: get your victory points.
Speaker 0: that way you can legit win the game.
Speaker 0: Never shipping stuff and you can legit win the game pretty much doing nothing but shipping stuff and just building.
Speaker 1: Try to end the game quickly by like military especially just getting planet planet planet planet planet.
Speaker 1: if you get a good draw Yeah, just get fill up the you know, victory point condition and just end.
Speaker 1: All right There's a lot of different things you can do in the game deal.
Speaker 1: This is why it's not you have to look at what other people are doing You have to make good decisions.
Speaker 1: and there's also an element that Puerto Rico doesn't have of luck.
Speaker 1: Right if you start with the military world new Sparta and you draw a military world that you can just get right away And then you draw another one that you get you can get right away You can just roll through the game.
Speaker 1: But if you draw a bunch of other kinds of things that military isn't helping you with it's just like you can sit there in Slog where someone else who maybe started with the blue world and draws a bunch of blue worlds to go with it and gets a Hand of full of synergies is gonna take off.
Speaker 1: And so even if you're really good at the game You won't win all the time against other people who are good at the game.
Speaker 0: And if everyone's good at the game It's a card game like the better you all get at the game the more the randomness Influences the winner.
Speaker 1: because the game which is why you want to have more cards.
Speaker 1: because then Even though you think more cards to make it more random it does.
Speaker 1: But more cards also means there's more cards to go around.
Speaker 1: so it's not like oh you got the only thing that I Needed to win because there's only one of those in the game.
Speaker 1: It's like oh now.
Speaker 1: There's a huge fucking deck of cards.
Speaker 1: There's gonna be some other cards.
Speaker 1: I can get even if someone took those ones.
Speaker 1: But I'm not just getting blood skilled players.
Speaker 0: that random is a big factor partly because the game will be shockingly tight.
Speaker 0: I would say oh yeah ten to twenty percent of all the games I play this have at least two players who are tied at the end of the game.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, if people are really who know what they're doing are playing Properly.
Speaker 0: in fact you guys are really really close.
Speaker 0: I was playing the Apple.
Speaker 0: I was pooping a four-player game against the hardest AI.
Speaker 0: it was a four-way perfect tie.
Speaker 0: Like that happens in this game.
Speaker 1: shockingly often even that you think it's like it's so complex all the shit You're doing.
Speaker 1: all over the place Everyone's doing mostly the same actions because they're all sharing the action.
Speaker 1: Oh, and you're drawn from the same decks And you're taking the same exact number of turns So the same number of victory points per turn.
Speaker 1: on average you can get ties Even though you have these complex machines being built if everyone's doing a good job.
Speaker 0: But the game is also so tight that like if you have one again skilled players if you have one turn We're like you did a suboptimal thing like you're behind now.
Speaker 1: You're not gonna catch up.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you're done You're you're out unless everyone else fucks up bad.
Speaker 1: at the same token if you have one mega play like oh my god I somehow managed to build this really amazing development X to trade way early and got like 12 victory points.
Speaker 1: Oh my god I was able.
Speaker 1: I was a Traded and sold this good at like this crazy high price and drew a fistful of cards and a turn where no one else Was able to trade anything, you know, and just like whoa, I guess I'm in charge.
Speaker 1: I'm in the lead now.
Speaker 1: Good luck catching up bozos.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: This game also kind of pushes the envelope in terms of for a tabletop Card game.
Speaker 0: you play a really fast like it and but it it's fast.
Speaker 0: But it also really pushes the limit of the acceptable level of complexity you can have in a game like this.
Speaker 0: It is really surprising how fast it plays considering how complex it is, right?
Speaker 1: It's like you're getting a pretty, you know, it's not super deep But you're getting a significant gaming experience in a short amount of time with a minimal investment of setup because it's just dealing out cards pretty much and counting some chits or whatever, right and That's why this game is a staple of that game
Speaker 0: library Right, especially because once you break it out you put it on the table you play it once You can sit there and play it like six more times before you put it away and like just keep play over and over and Over again, it's so quick.
Speaker 1: And the other thing is it starts out.
Speaker 1: this game will start out when you're first playing it as like the meat game.
Speaker 1: Right, you'll warm up with a spot it and then go into a race to the galaxy.
Speaker 1: But once you get good, you can use this as a filler game in between your eclipses, right?
Speaker 1: It's just like because you can play it so fast.
Speaker 1: Now your filler game is a serious game.
Speaker 1: It's like whoa.
Speaker 1: That's pretty.
Speaker 0: I buy because nursery max is kind of done.
Speaker 0: Like I play I think I've played it a hundred percent out That's but that's another that takes more setup, right?
Speaker 0: You're not doing the digital Yeah, but now that there's a good app on Android for race for the galaxy this is my pooping game.
Speaker 0: I can play an entire fully expanded game of this in one poop like as fast as the nursery max.
Speaker 1: the Next time I need a phone game I think I might buy or see wait for it to be on sale or something.
Speaker 1: It's totally worth.
Speaker 1: I'll make it my pooping game as well.
Speaker 0: But the fact that you can play so many games at the table Let me see how much it is right now and I kind of kind of mitigates the randomness because yeah There's a lot of randomness and the game's tight.
Speaker 0: But if we sit down at PAX, we'll play it five times.
Speaker 0: So the better player is gonna win the majority of those games much more likely even if they lose one due to randomness.
Speaker 0: So this game's got a lot going for it.
Speaker 0: There's a reason it has so much staying power.
Speaker 0: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Speaker 1: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 0: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and in Discriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 0: But unlike those other late shows It's actually recorded at night and the patreon patrons for this episode of geek nights are Nicholas Brando Alan Joyce Heidi McNichol Amanda Duchette and Thomas on my Stady calm William Isen rose Jeremy minor.
Speaker 0: Is there anything that's worth more than peace and love on the planet a genuine bonafide like five six car monorail?
Speaker 0: Captain Chinguacu see Rebecca Dunn the terrible secret of space for to one creations.
Speaker 0: The only reason that we set up a red base here is because they have Shervin Von Horrell Rare Laval James David White Rochelle, Monta Nona super boy.
Speaker 0: I paid five bucks to make rim say pickle sailor Vista Matthew Smith Don Shleich.
Speaker 0: It's our topish and Joe sure Joe star Sean Yeager Sam Cordray Clinton Walton Ren from New Zealand Ryan Perrin Mr.
Speaker 0: Black Brian Cedroni Finn Chris midkiff Chris Knox Daniel Redmond Sean Klein Chris Reimer and Thomas Hahn.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we didn't stream the episode tonight because of an interesting conflict where if I opened OBS It would hang the firewire inputs that the computer was receiving even though the actual channel was fine.
Speaker 0: I suspect it'll require reboots and futzing with the drivers because Firewires fickle in the modern era and yes I still use firewire because half of the professional audio equipment in the world still uses firewire and I have a very expensive firewire mixer that I don't really want to replace and I have yet to find a good USB equivalent that has the same level of functionality that this thing has.
Speaker 0: so anyway now I leave you with My.
Speaker 0: Every day you are with me and every night boy you dance.
Speaker 0: in my dreams We dance United together.
Speaker 0: We are one.
Speaker 1: I'll take you there baby.
Speaker 1: Come go with me Try me out.