Speaker 0: It's Monday October 30th 2017.
Speaker 0: I'm rim.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and this is a very terrifying episode of geek nights because we are.
Speaker 0: it is the premiere of geek nights Eve because Halloween is when geek nights first aired back in.
Speaker 0: Some of you were not even born then.
Speaker 1: And if that's true, are you saying there's 11 year olds listen to eat man.
Speaker 0: I am confident there's at least one 11 year old listening.
Speaker 1: You're less than 12 years old.
Speaker 0: This probably should not be listening to our show.
Speaker 1: This show is not appropriate for you.
Speaker 1: Stop listening.
Speaker 0: Fuck Fuck fuck.
Speaker 1: That's not what makes that's appropriate for all ears and is my opinion.
Speaker 1: There are other things that make it not appropriate.
Speaker 0: We might be providing wisdom to a child who will then come.
Speaker 0: school doesn't matter.
Speaker 1: That's why yeah Grades don't matter.
Speaker 1: unless you want to be a doctor a lawyer some shit.
Speaker 0: your grades matter in so much as you need to Manage them to game the system to get out of school.
Speaker 0: But yeah, we've been already people in this chatter like you're actually gonna talk about batteries this time because we have gone down this road before.
Speaker 0: Yes, we were talking about batteries, but first.
Speaker 0: So I got an open event Sure for the 12th anniversary episode of geek nights because you remember the other day while ago we had a chili party And I made that chili.
Speaker 0: that was better than anyone expected.
Speaker 1: So a long time ago, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, so, uh, I've been experimenting with chili since and I had an idea and other people I'll enter a chili contest.
Speaker 0: No, no, no, no, but I wanted to make a chili Where the base was not onion.
Speaker 0: as I typically do I do onion based chilies.
Speaker 0: Usually is like my core stock.
Speaker 0: I Use celery.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 0: Let me tell you it was real goddamn good.
Speaker 0: Okay, like real good.
Speaker 0: so take any chili recipe and just replace the part where it says onion with a 50/50 split of onion and celery.
Speaker 0: if you're not adventurous, but if you're a if you're a maverick, oh all celery You will not be disappointed.
Speaker 0: Uh-huh You got you got to add some cumin or something to bring back that sort of tangy oniony character actual flavor I got.
Speaker 0: so the other remember when I make a chili the other thing I do is I put like Five cloves of garlic in there.
Speaker 0: Yeah independent of everything else.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: Also the kidney bean Not that pinto bean kidney bean.
Speaker 1: I'm I'm still black bean.
Speaker 1: I like black bean I don't know for a chili black bean.
Speaker 0: But so the recipe I based this on.
Speaker 0: I did not do because this recipe went a little overboard.
Speaker 0: It wanted the kidney bean the black bean and the pinto bean.
Speaker 0: It also wanted both ground beef and ground sausage.
Speaker 0: I want just ground beef and just kidney bean.
Speaker 0: But again, I'm experimenting.
Speaker 0: I'm broadening my chili horizons.
Speaker 0: And if you don't think beans belong in Chile I don't know how you found geek nights or why you're still listening.
Speaker 1: Anyway, I went to cafe my so I give you a cafe Maya.
Speaker 0: I Miss that kind of Mexican food.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: So you got some news on this Monday.
Speaker 0: This is Monday.
Speaker 1: I do have a news.
Speaker 1: what the hell was it?
Speaker 0: the surge of sites.
Speaker 1: and oh, yeah.
Speaker 1: So here's the thing, right?
Speaker 1: It's bad enough that when you go to a website That you got all these ads popping up.
Speaker 1: Of course, you got ad blocker.
Speaker 1: So you're all good, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, and if you don't have an ad blocker get an ad blocker, yeah and way back in the day, you know There was JavaScript they added to browsers because HTML wasn't enough.
Speaker 1: It wasn't just enough to have a website.
Speaker 1: show you something and then have you click links to go to other sites.
Speaker 1: They need to have sites do things that were interactive.
Speaker 1: so you needed some way to code and somehow if you can read about the history yourself JavaScript became the language that's in the browser and In the day people use JavaScript pretty much just for evil like make shit blink and annoy the fuck out of you and make pop Ups and do all sorts of evil with it.
Speaker 0: Like most people who were smart the kind of people who blocked ads either just blocked JavaScript.
Speaker 1: Yeah, people just turn JavaScript off because it was only used for evil nonsense And all these.
Speaker 1: pretty much everyone was like, oh good web developer.
Speaker 1: Don't use any JavaScript.
Speaker 1: Just don't use it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, do not use.
Speaker 1: but then over time People just couldn't help themselves and they had to use it.
Speaker 1: and there were ways and our ways to use JavaScript for good and just about any website you go to these days is using it many ways for good to make the web experience better right and whatnot, but Over time JavaScript is all still been used for great evil.
Speaker 1: And there's one great evil that it is being used for now.
Speaker 1: see for the most part that even though JavaScript can do all sorts of stuff It can't really do anything like outside the web page.
Speaker 1: Browsers have these controls in them such that the JavaScript running on a page can only do certain things and if it tries to do Other things the browser will say no, I'm not gonna let you do that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and unless there is a separate exploit like in the browser or something You're not it's not gonna break out of that box.
Speaker 0: right now There are exploits like that, but it's not really what we're talking about here.
Speaker 1: now It's like, you know It just so happens that there is one very evil thing that it can totally do within the box.
Speaker 1: Because I mean if you visit a website The JavaScript has to be able to get information from the website and send it to you.
Speaker 1: and get information from you and send it To the website.
Speaker 1: that's basic obvious functionality.
Speaker 1: You can the JavaScript can communicate with the website you're visiting.
Speaker 1: It's like duh it needs to do that.
Speaker 1: Well, someone's like well Let's see what evil can be done with just that seemingly perfectly safe and secure technology.
Speaker 0: Do external I/O and access processing cycles.
Speaker 0: That's what I got to work with.
Speaker 1: It basically means that well, there's no limits on how much of your CPU it can use.
Speaker 1: So
Speaker 0: there's a
Speaker 1: lot of websites these days unbeknownst to you that if you visit them without correct blocking and such The JavaScript will completely without you knowing unless you know It wanted to your CPU cycles and notice that when you visit that site your CPUs getting used a whole bunch Start mining some coins and then if any coins get mined by you.
Speaker 1: Well, guess what?
Speaker 1: You don't get no coins.
Speaker 1: the first website you're visiting.
Speaker 1: you're sending all the coins to them whether they be bitcoins or Ethereum's or whatever the fuck coins people using these days doge coins.
Speaker 1: I don't fucking know.
Speaker 1: fuck all them coins.
Speaker 1: and that on the one hand is Great evil.
Speaker 1: you basically stealing my electricity my CPU cycles ruining my computer.
Speaker 1: I didn't give you explicit permission for this except maybe in the site's terms of service.
Speaker 0: You're being all shady which you know About that because of one of the or one of the group one website that is doing this.
Speaker 0: we have some more info about Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: But anyway go on.
Speaker 1: Yeah So on the one hand that's bad, right?
Speaker 1: We don't want that and if anyone's doing that you should block them.
Speaker 1: But on the other hand Right.
Speaker 1: It's like I don't believe in these coin nonsense blockchain bullshit, right?
Speaker 1: That's a bunch of get-rich-quick shady scam artists business.
Speaker 0: There are legitimate Interesting uses for blockchain and blockchain like technology, however Cryptocurrencies themselves have fundamental flaws.
Speaker 1: Back in the day people would just be running like affiliate scams making websites full of casino ads trying to make money for without doing Work on the internet.
Speaker 1: Yeah today those same people are doing coin shit.
Speaker 1: Which is it's like this huge amount of people who are just like I need to make money for without doing a lot of work Website.
Speaker 0: I did this when I saw when I was in like late middle school early high school There's this thing where you use this special web browser and they would pay you like a penny an hour or so But they'd show you ads constantly while you were using the internet.
Speaker 1: No, no, this is see People using that browsers.
Speaker 1: I might be able making that bro.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah But I tried to exploit that browser and I ran a bunch of them on different accounts and had a script that would move my mouse a little bit Anyway, but I made like a couple bucks people all.
Speaker 1: if there's any way to try to make real money without doing anything Just by having computers do stuff people will get.
Speaker 1: this is class of people that get all over it and those people are currently Keeping the coin business afloat.
Speaker 1: That's what they're.
Speaker 1: that's what they're doing.
Speaker 1: Anyway And if you actually insert real money into that system, you are the mark Yeah, then they are all competing with their computers to take your real money.
Speaker 0: Now if you say but I made tons of money on cryptocurrencies Yeah, a lot of people near the top of a pyramid scheme make a lot of money anyway.
Speaker 1: but one Possibly good like aspect of this that I hadn't thought of until someone pointed it out is like well We do have this fundamental problem and that people make content put it online.
Speaker 1: Some people are making legit content and they have trouble making money.
Speaker 1: They got a deal with bullshit YouTube.
Speaker 1: They got to put ads.
Speaker 0: I mean case in point.
Speaker 0: the only reason they got a patreon Geek nice is free because we have money To have covered this shit for so many and it's not that expensive true for us.
Speaker 0: But that's cuz.
Speaker 0: we can do a lot of the expensive stuff ourselves with our brains.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 1: Anyway, um What is it what if we live in a world where you go online and there's just no ads and there's no?
Speaker 1: but everything's great Because everyone is mining coins while you're consuming their content Like you're watching a video on Netflix and while you watch it You know It's happening and Netflix is just mining you and that's how you're paying and that's in Netflix will cause zero.
Speaker 0: Arguably, that is how we pay for a lot of for example, Google services in that they're mining data from us.
Speaker 0: They're not mining bitcoins or whatever, but they're getting data about what we do and that's the actual product.
Speaker 0: That's how we pray Google.
Speaker 1: but see but date mining data about you has like all these privacy implications, right?
Speaker 1: It actually wouldn't be harmful to you really except your electric bill Which is where you'd end up paying which for them to just use your CPU cycles And then that's how you pay them, which is not nothing.
Speaker 1: However, because I'm nothing it's not free.
Speaker 1: It's not actually free but you'd be paying for it in a different way.
Speaker 1: That would actually a It could be good for the environment because you'd you'd be.
Speaker 0: we manufacture all these CPUs and a lot of them are going underused Because modern CPUs clock down and don't like they use less power when they're not fully utilized.
Speaker 1: Yes, but it would still Manufacturing, you know resources of making the CPUs right the silicon and the factory is polluting, right?
Speaker 1: You know Google would end up buying less CPUs for their mainframe, you know They're big data warehouses and whatever because they just be using yours, right?
Speaker 1: I'm just saying it's just.
Speaker 1: that's at least a little something.
Speaker 0: So right that is because coin hive is apparently the big one in this.
Speaker 1: Yeah I've is me.
Speaker 1: coin hive is a company that makes a thing where if you're a website maker or owner You can just get coin hive code and put it on your website.
Speaker 1: Well, and now people visiting your site will mine coins for you And I guess coin hive is getting money.
Speaker 0: to quoting this Ars Technica article coin I've presented service as a white way and users can support sites without viewing online ads.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm Consents yes, you don't know that you're doing this.
Speaker 1: just how how you visit a website.
Speaker 1: they could be showing you ads and using your computer to mine for them and - I Really don't think that Legitimate websites are using this.
Speaker 0: I would bet that it's mostly scammy websites that are using this.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, that's just a guess.
Speaker 0: oh, yeah, and malware blockers have already started just blocking coin hive outright saying yeah We don't care.
Speaker 0: if you think you have a legitimate business you have a quote unquote legitimate business.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, but at least there is.
Speaker 1: it's like it's illegitimate because the cryptocurrency stuff is all shady bullshit Right, but the fundamental the lower fundamental idea just on its own taking away the sleaziness of bitcoins and whatnot is Hey pay for things by letting the thing the person that created the content that deserves to be paid in some way Borrow your CPU cycles to use them for me.
Speaker 1: But then you're not fucking using them.
Speaker 0: they are actually directly charging you that.
Speaker 0: the amount of money that electricity costs Which is gonna be more than people will expect it will be more than you expect Will actually be quite reasonable if you consider how much content you consume.
Speaker 0: Ah, but why in directly like that?
Speaker 1: If I read a webcomic and I end up paying like ten cents on my fucking electric bill for the time It took me to read the webcomic.
Speaker 1: That's a bargain.
Speaker 0: Oh, no, so already I'm pretty sure that a lot of these keep running constantly after you visit them Can't have JavaScript running once you close a tab.
Speaker 0: I rise.
Speaker 0: I was skimming this article.
Speaker 0: I said something about hidden browser window.
Speaker 1: Well, that is shady as fuck.
Speaker 1: Yeah, can't be doing that.
Speaker 1: But also if Most people only use the internet on their phones Yeah, that's a problem because your phone CPU you'd kill your battery, right?
Speaker 1: And well, it's not a good deal.
Speaker 1: a lot of people and some phones.
Speaker 0: It does not make their phone battery running out before they get home might as well be a death sentence.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's not cool.
Speaker 1: Right because there's a battery situation also and there's not much CPU.
Speaker 1: to mine That's a weak-ass CPU even in a high-end phase.
Speaker 0: just kicks a more fundamental problem down the road.
Speaker 1: I found X is really fast but it's not as good as even like an i3.
Speaker 0: the fundamental problem this kicks down the road is That the social that we lack a social contract for how media should be funded in society.
Speaker 0: So the right way to do it now would be for people to pay some token amount directly for their content or to have some other system in place.
Speaker 0: the idea of Quietly using a resource people don't understand causing a bill They don't pay attention to to go up by the amount that they would have just paid directly Removes the visibility to those people.
Speaker 0: the fact that there still is a social contract that is funding content.
Speaker 0: It hides from them the real cost of content and as long as you hide it from them they will never care about it Right.
Speaker 1: I think the way to do this is obviously you have to let the person know that it's happening.
Speaker 1: They can opt in or out and have some other payment method and you know such and such right.
Speaker 1: but there is and the other Question is how do you without sleazy coins convert the person CPU cycles into actual money to pay like into my rent if I'm an Artist
Speaker 0: also, I would argue that for a lot of P I mean PCs are already not much of a market like that, but between laptops and PCs at least Causing a CPU to clock up and stay clocked up for a while and a computer that is probably not well built or well dusted But it also goes hardware failures and such.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean don't have any computer you'll take care of yeah, but again also don't push.
Speaker 1: yes, I'm talking about an ethical and Reasonable way of doing this because obviously the only people are doing it right now are doing it evilly and unethically and yeah Fuck them.
Speaker 1: I mean, I feel like I'm saying there is a whole a small Hope in this story of evil doing of hey Maybe we can solve this problem somehow by mixing this up and changing in this way.
Speaker 0: I feel that direct microtransactions are better.
Speaker 0: indirect Microtransactions just reek of abuse and reek of scams.
Speaker 1: sure But what if there is an honest way of you know, somehow turning CPU cycles into fair real money.
Speaker 1: That's not bullshit.
Speaker 1: and people who say teenagers who don't have money in credit cards can say yes You know, I agree that this thick cut, you know This video site is YouTube video.
Speaker 1: I'm watching can borrow some CPU cycles to pay for me watching this video.
Speaker 1: I'm not using my computer.
Speaker 0: There's an economy if you talk about the environmental cost of that.
Speaker 0: There is an economy of scale in Real supercomputers that if you're distributing that load to a wide array of much shittier machines that are maintained to dubious degrees May end up drawing more energy out of the system than the centralized ones would thus having an indirect and negative Environmental impact.
Speaker 0: Yeah kind of like how
Speaker 1: but you know, but while
Speaker 0: there are efficiency
Speaker 1: losses It's tough to measure the environmental impact because it's like, you know People always talk about like all the environmental impact of driving a shitty car, but it's like versus the cost of Manufacturing an electric car.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like you're better off using the used car that spewing out, you know gas.
Speaker 0: Well, that's the whole conversation of electric cars.
Speaker 0: They have more.
Speaker 1: so it's like alright is running this CPU for and making some heat right and using some Electricity that the CPU already exists.
Speaker 1: How does that compare to making a new CPU at the fab, right?
Speaker 1: I don't know the numbers on this But I'm just saying there's a potential there at least to investigate maybe as good maybe as bad.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'm just.
Speaker 0: I am so Highly dubious of all of that.
Speaker 0: I'm also increasingly dubious of the.
Speaker 1: I mean, yes right now I'm just talking about potential features right now.
Speaker 1: Fuck anyone who does this.
Speaker 1: block them all And also fuck your coins, yeah There's a reason I don't have any fucking coins and hands off my CPU.
Speaker 1: That's the story today.
Speaker 1: That is the story today.
Speaker 1: No buts about it.
Speaker 0: So in a much shorter news because I don't want to get too much into the specifics of Portugal But it appears that at least one Portuguese ISP is Doing the exact thing that all the nerds were warning would happen if net neutrality is not protected by governments.
Speaker 0: They're literally selling packages of oh, you want to watch YouTube videos.
Speaker 0: That's another five currency units a month, ah, you want to watch YouTube videos and Netflix videos.
Speaker 1: Well, you got to get the premium package So you got to pay your ISP and then you got to pay Netflix our YouTube or whoever also because they're not giving out.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and I don't want to get into the details.
Speaker 1: this article The actually the thing that we were worried they would do is try to charge Netflix, but they're not doing that.
Speaker 1: They're just charging the customer saying oh you pay for us as ISP You're paying your ISP bill then you pay Netflix themselves But then you got to pay us.
Speaker 1: if you want to add Netflix to your is piece you getting doubled booked.
Speaker 0: Yep, now the real problem with this is that shift is moving from fighting against an entity that has resources to fight back on an Equal level because Netflix can say go fuck yourself.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm Some random dude in Portugal does not have the power.
Speaker 1: I don't know if Portugal has the local monopolies on the internet a service provider.
Speaker 0: That's why I don't want to get into the details.
Speaker 0: not because I have some higher motive because I don't fucking know anything about Portuguese ISPs.
Speaker 1: no But like in the United States at least if someone were to do this like say I have Time Warner I don't really have much of a choice of anyone to switch to right.
Speaker 1: It's like that's the only one that's connected to my building.
Speaker 1: So I can get I guess shitty DSL from Verizon over the phone line.
Speaker 1: fuck that noise.
Speaker 0: But the higher-level problem and this is why net neutrality is so important.
Speaker 0: and why?
Speaker 0: You as a nerd who's listening to the Monday episode of geek nights Which I assume is the least popular episode of geek nights.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: It's the hardest episode to do.
Speaker 0: Yep But when we care the least about the reason normal people need to care about net neutrality Is that the only reason the cool shit that happens on the internet is happening is because the pipes are neutral So anyone can try to sell a cool service or thing.
Speaker 0: Netflix could not have begun Without net neutrality because Netflix needed to assume the pipes are there and get to everyone to then try to offer a service on top of those pipes.
Speaker 0: It's a series of tubes and we need to protect that.
Speaker 0: everyone has access to those tubes.
Speaker 1: This is a common business model.
Speaker 1: actually even forgetting the internet just in Technology and other businesses also in general is you make something new and you got to compete.
Speaker 1: You gotta they got to compete with something that's entrenched or you're new to market and you're brand new.
Speaker 1: But what you do is you make your product open and relatively free for everyone and it gains Popularity and then once you're big enough you lock that shit down and everyone's locked in.
Speaker 0: but locking down the internet locks down.
Speaker 1: We had this open internet and all these companies were able to use it to get real big Amazon Google Facebook Twitter everyone and now Netflix.
Speaker 1: it's like oh well now we're big, you know Let's lock it down and now we'll stay the Kings forever because you know We already got on top of the hill and it's very telling.
Speaker 1: let anyone new in the same gate that we use to get up To the top.
Speaker 0: there is an opposite direction.
Speaker 0: This could go in that the big companies that have already succeeded in the previously neutral environment if they were evil They would actually be against net neutrality Because a loss of net neutrality locks new competition out of ever competing with them at least in internet businesses.
Speaker 0: yeah, so the fact that even the big a like a Moral giant internet companies are also against very very against it because the ISPs will have power over them because of the monopolies ISPs have.
Speaker 1: if ISPs didn't have a monopoly the Google's of the world would love to get rid of net neutrality And I think ISPs should be basically destroyed and regulated like power companies are.
Speaker 0: yes They should be utilities providing a service.
Speaker 0: That is a Ostensible right to all citizens and at a reasonable and highly regulated price.
Speaker 0: and SLA.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: But yeah.
Speaker 0: So the this is one more example you can use to terrify your muggle friends about why they should at least Occasionally call their senator and say the words net neutrality.
Speaker 0: But anyway things of the day.
Speaker 0: Scott's got a Monday relevant thing of the day.
Speaker 0: So I will go first with my much less inspiring not Monday related thing of the day at all.
Speaker 1: So obviously I got to start by saying that I admit I do not have a lot of knowledge on this topic.
Speaker 1: I only know what you learn about DNA in like high school.
Speaker 1: I Only remember most of it and not all of it.
Speaker 0: I took more.
Speaker 1: something about the helix splits apart and then the RNA comes along and copies and makes the other half and they got Two DNAs right something like that and this ACGT and they match up.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and there's some like polymerase enzyme and some other one.
Speaker 0: I'm just saying proper nouns and linking them to those are definitely the right proper nouns.
Speaker 1: That's all I'm saying.
Speaker 0: Do you remember what the nucleotides are?
Speaker 1: Yeah, ACG and teeth.
Speaker 0: so ending guanine cytosine Yeah, I mean, yeah, you know, which one is not in RNA?
Speaker 0: No, it's replaced by uracil.
Speaker 0: I I've heard it.
Speaker 0: so whatever the point is I just said bounced off of the near bottom of what I remember about biology rice.
Speaker 1: Anyway, here is video of video right video of real-time DNA replication like you see these like lines going across its DNA growing in real time Like you're watching this shit happen Like photons are bouncing off the DNA and hitting this microscope camera.
Speaker 1: I presume Right and you're watching it go.
Speaker 1: It's like holy shit.
Speaker 1: And what they learned from this video is that Shit is not like they thought it was.
Speaker 1: it has something to do with like how the strands coordinate.
Speaker 1: I don't completely understand it But basically a lot of stuff that they thought and taught you in high school or college or ever is not a hundred percent, right?
Speaker 0: So I took AP bio in 1998 and also it just I mean fuck.
Speaker 1: whatever the information is that I understand and probably won't matter to me anytime soon.
Speaker 1: But holy shit, it's a video of DNA replicating.
Speaker 1: They predicted something they couldn't see and then they saw it.
Speaker 1: That's so science.
Speaker 0: I still have my AP bio textbook from 1998 and It's half wrong now.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, cuz I watch SciShow so I get a lot of like.
Speaker 0: here's a current thing about science.
Speaker 0: Holy shit, have we discovered a lot about cellular biology since 1998?
Speaker 0: Holy shit has a lot changed To the point that I Highly dubious that I know anything about how cells work anymore.
Speaker 1: No, but if you want to see DNA with your eyeballs check out my thing a day.
Speaker 1: That's pretty.
Speaker 1: you know about biology and DNA.
Speaker 1: I'm sorry.
Speaker 1: I don't know as much as you do.
Speaker 1: Don't hate me I'm admitting that I don't know and I'm wrong and you'll still love this fucking video.
Speaker 0: So if you are much lower brow and that and that thing of the day terrifies you I just got some YouTube live streamer guy but the lowest brow.
Speaker 0: so I Stumbled upon this channel in this video just kind of randomly.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm, and it was legit Really funny.
Speaker 0: and it wasn't just me because I played it again for Emily and it was legit funny.
Speaker 0: And then I played it for a bunch of other people and it's legit funny.
Speaker 0: And then I figured some stuff out about this, dude This dude has been this kind of crap since the early Newgrounds days.
Speaker 0: Okay, so he's like he's in our clade.
Speaker 0: He's more old-school like he was making.
Speaker 0: you know, those like fuck his head like those nonsense videos We used to watch.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: This dude was doing that stuff back then.
Speaker 1: and is who is the dude?
Speaker 1: What's his name?
Speaker 0: Uh, Video game donkey.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: Is he like a gamer gate or a bad person?
Speaker 0: No, he seems like a perfectly fine person with a vaguely Brooklyn accent.
Speaker 1: Oh, that's my kind You're.
Speaker 0: you'll hear some.
Speaker 0: some hints of.
Speaker 1: you can't hold 10 Pokemon But those are Jersey kids if I'm not mistaken.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but see I can't tell those accents apart.
Speaker 0: a group in the Midwest.
Speaker 0: But this video is just a collection of stuff things that happened in Breath of the Wild and One.
Speaker 0: if you haven't really explored the crazy nonsense You can pull off in Breath of the Wild like making airships or bringing chickens with you.
Speaker 0: It gives you a lot of ideas of crazy crap you can do in this game because the game lets you do a lot of crazy crap like What if you knock the weapon out of a bokoblin's hands and give him a Korok leaf and he tries to kill you with it?
Speaker 0: Is it even possible for him to hurt you with that Korok leaf?
Speaker 0: And the answer is pretty funny.
Speaker 0: So this video is pretty good and I guarantee you will laugh at least once during it and it's only like six minutes long And then at a moment.
Speaker 0: the book club book was the fifth season by N.K.
Speaker 0: Jemisin.
Speaker 0: We did it.
Speaker 0: We done it.
Speaker 0: We did a show on it.
Speaker 0: You can listen to it.
Speaker 1: Oh, you didn't choose a new book club book during that episode.
Speaker 0: I did not and I will choose it very soon.
Speaker 1: It's not the Count of Monte Cristo.
Speaker 0: Now, the Count of Monte Cristo is held out solely as a punishment if I ever get displeased by your book club choice.
Speaker 1: Meanwhile, you seem to like my book club choices better than yours.
Speaker 0: I think my book club choice has been pretty good, too.
Speaker 1: Uh-huh.
Speaker 1: Let's have a poll whose book club choices are better.
Speaker 0: We finally got the archive with book club books.
Speaker 1: Also, I'm pretty sure the last book club book you chose was a stolen choice from me.
Speaker 0: Let's see.
Speaker 0: We did the Prince of Nothing.
Speaker 0: That was both of us Uh Snow Crash Earthsea.
Speaker 0: Then I picked a Fair World Arms.
Speaker 0: You did Cavalier and Clay.
Speaker 0: I did Steppenwolf.
Speaker 0: You did Hitchhiker's Guide to the Galaxy Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: I did Locke Lamora, and I think I skipped one.
Speaker 0: I can't tell.
Speaker 0: I don't remember who picked what in these old episodes Uh-huh.
Speaker 0: I picked the Ear of the Eye and the Arm.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 0: That was really good.
Speaker 0: That's okay Yeah, but anyway, I will pick it soon, but I'm already mostly done with the second book.
Speaker 1: I gotta get started on that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I know a lot about the moon now and I'm very pleased with some things that I learned.
Speaker 1: and The only thing that surprised all those people who smacked down the second book are wrong.
Speaker 0: Uh, I can see why they would say the things they said about the second book so far because some Fundamental truths were revealed very directly and I can see why some people would be disappointed by that.
Speaker 1: But no, I like that as long as there's another terrible secret of space.
Speaker 0: at the same time I was not disappointed by that at all because I Learned to think about the moon and I was a hundred percent right about almost everything I thought about it, but then I learned about the other moon.
Speaker 0: That's a very different moon.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so I got this Technology control room and it's good shit.
Speaker 1: this Saturday October 4th and also 5th is Gamer X East, G-A-Y-M-E-R-X East.
Speaker 1: obviously, even though this is a convention That is mostly for L-G-B-Q-T all the letters.
Speaker 0: I'll be honest I say all the people just because I don't want to get into the argument of how many more letters all the letters.
Speaker 0: I include Everyone.
Speaker 0: L-G-B-T dot star everybody, right?
Speaker 1: It's meh, but you can come even if you're like us just a cishet boring white dude who sucks Still go.
Speaker 1: I guess if you're a homophobe you might not want to go but I mean you're still probably welcome there.
Speaker 1: Yeah, especially if you're in New York City and you like games is a good place to go.
Speaker 1: This weekend Saturday and Sunday is gonna be awesome time.
Speaker 1: You can get the info on their website.
Speaker 0: Yep, we will be there Saturday most of the day just hanging out playing games.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like if you want to play a board game with us, we're just gonna be hanging around this.
Speaker 1: Friday and Saturday is Blizzcon.
Speaker 1: if you care about any games that Blizzard makes.
Speaker 1: oh, yeah There's gonna be championships of all those like Hearthstone world championship and such and such.
Speaker 1: Also Saturday and Sunday if you care about netrunner is the netrunner world championship so you can just stream that shit on Twitch.
Speaker 1: So, you know, you can watch around.
Speaker 1: you can watch if you're not a gamer X. You can switch between the first rounds of the Swiss rounds of Hearthstone and the final rounds of heart Net runs start of netrunner and the end of hearthstone and then on Sunday watch the end of netrunner anyway.
Speaker 1: Also on Sunday is the end of daylight savings time in the stupid place.
Speaker 0: We live daylight saving time.
Speaker 0: There's no s on the end of whatever TP I know about daylight saving time.
Speaker 1: Anyway, it's fast fucking bullshit.
Speaker 1: It's gonna be dark at like 5. fuck that nonsense.
Speaker 1: Also, that is gonna be the New York City marathon, which we don't give a shit about because you shouldn't run marathons.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I run marathons.
Speaker 1: I ran one Saturday before the marathon starts There's an opportunity if you have a bicycle to bike.
Speaker 1: Oh bicycle Michael.
Speaker 1: I'll bike Michael Yeah on the marathon route before people start running and doing stuff.
Speaker 1: if you want to do that ending on the weather I may do that.
Speaker 1: I did it last year.
Speaker 0: Yep I did it last year except I bailed at the Queensborough because I didn't want to be trapped in Manhattan.
Speaker 1: I use the Roosevelt Island sky car to get back.
Speaker 1: I could also use a subway to get back Yeah, like an F train or something.
Speaker 0: So I'll see but a Google, you'll find it's pretty easy to do.
Speaker 0: like you might wonder like oh, well, where do I meet?
Speaker 0: Just like look on reddit and head vaguely where the start is and you'll see a bunch of other bikers.
Speaker 1: But it's not or it's way down south in Brooklyn close to the Verrazano.
Speaker 0: The only thing I'll warn you about because it wasn't we were I wasn't clear on this last year There will still be cars on the route just way less.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: No, it's good.
Speaker 1: The roads aren't closed yet.
Speaker 1: That's why you can do this.
Speaker 1: They're partially closed.
Speaker 1: They'll be barricades up in some places But now the roads are technically still open because the marathon hasn't started yet.
Speaker 1: But they're all setting marathon shit up and there's not a lot of cars out at y'all.
Speaker 1: crackety crack crack as a dawn on Sunday, especially not when there's a marathon going on.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right.
Speaker 1: So there's very few cars and you can just bike along the route and so you get to the part that's actually closed near the Finish line.
Speaker 1: anyway.
Speaker 1: other things the week before Thanksgiving we're talking about November 16 salt 17 18 19 is packs unplugged in Pennsylvania which sucks but it's packed some plug which is great.
Speaker 0: We will be there.
Speaker 0: we will be enforcing.
Speaker 0: we will be doing a two-hour event Where we're gonna teach a bunch of people how to play carcass own.
Speaker 0: we're gonna teach them how to be ruthless monsters at carcass own and then we're gonna put them all in a Basically pub G equivalent carcass own tournament last man standing in a single elimination To see what happens when you make monsters and make them fight each other.
Speaker 1: tomorrow is Halloween.
Speaker 1: Good, you're probably listening to this on Halloween the 12th anniversary of geek nights and in the beginning of January It's gonna be magfest on the 4th 5th 6th and 7th and then pack south on the 12 13 14.
Speaker 0: Oh my god, it's gonna go boom packs.
Speaker 1: It's gonna go magfest packs out 1 2 1 2.
Speaker 0: Also, if you've been wondering why a lot of our side content hasn't been bustling so much.
Speaker 0: It's because of all these conventions I've had to organize and deal with our panels.
Speaker 1: for all this shit's going down.
Speaker 0: meeting into January stuff will really calm down and all our side projects will probably pick up.
Speaker 1: you can't do any of these events.
Speaker 1: you Should still follow us everywhere on the internet.
Speaker 1: We got two youtubes.
Speaker 1: We got twitches.
Speaker 1: We got twitters.
Speaker 1: We got Facebook's.
Speaker 1: We got instagrams.
Speaker 1: We got everything that people have on the internet all those evil places.
Speaker 0: We even got a g-plus.
Speaker 1: Yeah, go to all those places and follow us and you can follow along with all this shit.
Speaker 1: That's going down and I'm like streaming Mario Odyssey.
Speaker 1: Okay, all kinds of contents that you can see there because you're not gonna see any content anywhere else.
Speaker 0: So yeah Batteries.
Speaker 1: so how many times have you tried to do a battery show?
Speaker 0: so only one.
Speaker 0: well So I don't think we've ever done it before.
Speaker 0: I Looked I couldn't find it.
Speaker 1: I feel like we tried to do a battery show way back in 2000 beacon days and It might have either been lost or was part of another show and probably called the battery show.
Speaker 0: There are some early old episodes of geek nights where we literally like blew a load and reviewed like five great board games in one show.
Speaker 0: So we're gonna probably redo a lot of those in the future.
Speaker 0: But when it comes to this stuff there are Two episodes of geek nights ever that were lost to time because I don't remember what they were about.
Speaker 0: neither Do I. so there are two shows that we've recorded and then either my computer crashed or I fucked Anytime.
Speaker 1: rim has a show idea that I felt like we did already, but I can't find in the archive.
Speaker 1: I either believe he deleted it or is one of those shows they got lost.
Speaker 0: You know that's like.
Speaker 0: that's like how I'm still spending that money from when we won in Atlantic City, right?
Speaker 1: Batteries are one of those shows And we tried to do a battery show when recently and we failed for some reason we came up with a better idea at the last Second, okay, but the stream still said batteries.
Speaker 0: So all of you were coming into the stream being like I thought this is batteries WTF All right.
Speaker 1: So the other thing is that I actually don't know that much about batteries.
Speaker 1: I don't know how good a show I can do on them.
Speaker 0: I Think we can talk one, but there's such an important.
Speaker 1: There's such an important thing for all technologies that it's they're kind of worth doing a show on
Speaker 0: Your camera,
Speaker 1: okay,
Speaker 0: so but also we can talk at a high level in the sense that it's very easy, especially for some of you who are younger to Underestimate how ridiculously important modern batteries have been to almost everything you do.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm because when we were growing up The batteries that you are used to today that you just plug into a USB and they just kind of work did not exist.
Speaker 1: right when I was a kid and it wasn't because I only had kids toys to put batteries in it's cuz.
Speaker 1: no literally those are Batteries you could get even like adults of boomboxes had a bunch of fucking D and C batteries to my keyboard.
Speaker 0: I had a keyboard like that I would play on.
Speaker 0: it took eight D batteries and those bet that lasted like a day.
Speaker 1: Yeah Rechargeable batteries were didn't show up till later in my life.
Speaker 1: Childhood like middle and high school in high school is when he had Rayovac renewal batteries and they were garbage.
Speaker 0: They were garbage power a game gear for like 10 minutes.
Speaker 1: I used them in our TI 80 calculators, right and I would keep we constantly be recharging them Like every teacher had multiple Rayovac rechargers and was constantly charging all the bad.
Speaker 0: high school They were like if you use rechargeable batteries, you're on your fucking own I know right.
Speaker 1: it was like they gave everyone real bad little batteries and then he could buy Double-a batteries in class.
Speaker 0: Oh, wow We're like a dollar each ever.
Speaker 1: they gave everyone one full set when they bought their calculator if you bought it from the school.
Speaker 0: But I bought my calculator at the store the store as did I because the store was like $40 cheaper.
Speaker 1: And I got it and I got an 86 instead of 83 like everyone else.
Speaker 0: Yeah, everyone got an 83 but because I came in from another school district I went online.
Speaker 0: I was yet alive.
Speaker 0: I got the 85 because it was superior in literally every six is even more superior in so in many aspects anyway But its memory was actually slower.
Speaker 1: Anyway, it was we had more of it.
Speaker 0: It did have a lot more of it.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so The point is I got the rate the same rechargeable batteries that everyone else had because that was convenient and then I bought even more Of them and during high school.
Speaker 1: I used those exclusively until I got to RIT and I didn't use the calculator anymore really.
Speaker 0: but Batteries like buying batteries putting them in devices and replacing them was a huge part Like of the like daily use of basic technology.
Speaker 1: Yeah They did not have devices that you plugged in and charged themselves with their built-in rechargeable batteries.
Speaker 1: That was very rare.
Speaker 1: Very very rare.
Speaker 1: Rechargeable batteries period were rare and it was only you know Later on like when laptops were actually some of the first things that like had their own cells Attached to them that you could like swap out and such yep, and that was like the first thing that was using like lithium-ion batteries as laptops.
Speaker 1: and then you started seeing like iPods were actually one of the earliest things that charged themselves up right and that was you know, early 2000s.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: So all those batteries that are not rechargeable.
Speaker 1: people were actually like.
Speaker 1: I remember in the earliest days of iPods People were like why the fuck does this iPod not?
Speaker 1: let me like swap out the battery.
Speaker 1: Yeah Bones were also.
Speaker 1: the earliest flip phones were some of the things that had their own batteries And you could swap those out on the earliest phones now.
Speaker 0: part of that was the expectation that up until that point The idea of an embedded battery was not a thing to most people.
Speaker 1: So you assume people would be upset by it.
Speaker 1: people want to be able to swap out the batteries All right, because any other battery technology was so shitty.
Speaker 1: it would die and take a long time to recharge.
Speaker 0: Yep, and also batteries especially back then.
Speaker 1: and if the battery died You didn't want to have your whole expensive electronic device be dead.
Speaker 1: You wanted to just swap out the battery and be good to go.
Speaker 0: and the kinds of rechargeable batteries back then.
Speaker 0: and we're not gonna get into the difference between like Nycad batteries which were in early because we don't know.
Speaker 0: I know a little but it's not relevant Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: I part of the reason I do a little was that I was really into like tape mixing and mixtapes and nonsense.
Speaker 0: So I had a lot of portable cassette audio devices.
Speaker 1: all mine took double-a's.
Speaker 1: even my dis man had double-a's.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: So I actually started getting different kinds of rechargeables for those because they had a physical motor that had to turn Actually needed a lot of power.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's one of the other things.
Speaker 1: I was using my ray of X and was that dis man?
Speaker 0: Yep But I think one thing well that I remember this very specific moment in my life because as a kid got a game gear And I didn't know a lot about batteries obviously But the game gear took six double-a's and that would last like three or four hours.
Speaker 1: Maybe yeah Gameboy GBA Gameboy color They all took double-a's.
Speaker 1: the DS was the one that you would first one that had its own battery.
Speaker 1: That was different.
Speaker 1: You could swap it though.
Speaker 1: I did.
Speaker 1: I did swap the battery in my original DS But I think you can even swap the DS light battery and maybe even the 3ds better.
Speaker 1: I don't know about that But those are the ones where you started to charge itself.
Speaker 1: GBA took two double-a's and as a kid I don't know the SP.
Speaker 1: I think you charge the yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you didn't have two double-a's.
Speaker 1: the GBA you did.
Speaker 0: I never had an SP's.
Speaker 0: I don't really remember.
Speaker 1: I have one now.
Speaker 0: Yeah in the in the drawer somewhere, but so My parents being a kid who didn't have any money They took issue with the fact that I ran these batteries out.
Speaker 0: every time we drove anywhere I basically went through six double-a batteries.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so they want they searched and they found you could buy this like I think it was official this rechargeable battery kit.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, a lot of people had that what it was even bigger.
Speaker 0: it looked I was about to say it looks like a phone receiver like a phone.
Speaker 1: It was like two big wings coming off the side of the game.
Speaker 0: No, no the side one That's not what I had.
Speaker 0: I had this one that looked like the receiver on a telephone which is also as I went across the middle.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it hung from the bottom of the game gear.
Speaker 0: it weighed as much as the game gear by itself.
Speaker 0: It took like eight hours to charge it if I plugged it in and it powered the game gear for like three hours.
Speaker 1: Couldn't you just plug into the lighter on the in the car to keep your game gear going the whole time?
Speaker 1: I know lots of my friends did with it.
Speaker 0: Yeah So here is the problem the the actual device to plug that to plug into the game gear.
Speaker 0: cuz remember devices back then Didn't have a standard power input.
Speaker 1: No It had a interface that basically Mimicked the shape of all the six double-a batteries and went right in there and pretended to be bad.
Speaker 0: There was an AC adapter.
Speaker 0: Okay for the game gear.
Speaker 0: I think the Gameboy had one too.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, there was.
Speaker 0: yeah When I was playing at home, I just plugged in with the AC adapter.
Speaker 0: But the thing that cut the AC adapter plugs into the wall and or into the car Cigarette lighter which is extra funny because that interface stuck around even though that is not used as a cigarette lighter By anyone.
Speaker 0: it hasn't been for a long time Yeah, but and it was just a convenient source of powers like a hack back in the day.
Speaker 1: These cars these days have USB in them a lot Yeah But they usually still have the old cigarette lighter port.
Speaker 0: because I'm gonna say some of them do but some because there's so many devices That use that socket.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: But the plug that you plugged into your device because your device took AC or took DC usually The only devices that are AC were like even older devices that were just motors basically Would have a proprietary connector That would not plug in anything else and took a particular voltage and had particular parameters.
Speaker 0: So as a result, you usually had to buy either a first-party car adapter That was often not cheap or you had to buy a bootleg one which before Amazon kind of hard to do.
Speaker 1: actually Yeah, imagine with no internet, you know e-commerce trying to buy like a Gameboy car adapter thing.
Speaker 1: It's like you.
Speaker 1: better hope the one toy store has them somehow in stock.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean you're getting a first party order from a Nintendo catalog and hope you actually get it.
Speaker 1: Who knows what.
Speaker 0: and thus the problem.
Speaker 0: I had the game gear.
Speaker 0: my brother had the game boy.
Speaker 0: Which one of us gets to plug into the car?
Speaker 1: right anyway, so more battery stuff, right?
Speaker 1: So that eventually right phones iPods laptops.
Speaker 1: That's when the rechargeable battery started to really be in everything.
Speaker 1: Lithium-ion battery was invented and you finally had enough power density a good recharge time That obviously improved over time and also a battery life cycle.
Speaker 0: previous rechargeable batteries the more you cycled them And there's details as to what kind of cycling damaged them the most they wear out they get less and less.
Speaker 1: Yeah, those rail vac ones I was using the TI calculator you recharge and recharge and recharge and recharge them and then eventually they'd last like 10 minutes and Throw them out even though they're rechargeables.
Speaker 1: you can recharge them forever.
Speaker 1: a lithium-ion.
Speaker 1: You can recharge a ton of time and thus this is why ever but a ton of time.
Speaker 0: This is why modern devices have an embedded usually not replaceable battery Mm-hmm because that way they get whatever that whatever the battery is You shouldn't care if it's lithium-ion or some other kind.
Speaker 0: you shouldn't care What?
Speaker 0: Particular method of cycling it or how much ambient power to leave in it if it's not used for a long amount of time and Shoot you deep cycle.
Speaker 0: that is wizard nonsense that no one should need to deal with in the modern era.
Speaker 0: So there is a circuit where the device knows how to manage its own battery to maximize its usability and longevity.
Speaker 1: You would hope you would hope so, right?
Speaker 1: It's like, you know I plug.
Speaker 1: I pretty much believe things plugged in even if they're 100% like a whole all the time and I trust that those devices Are smart enough to manage their own batteries intelligently.
Speaker 0: and kids in the old days.
Speaker 0: That was not true No, and the only rechargeable devices that game gear thing.
Speaker 0: It said when the light turns green fucking unplug it or it might catch fire.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and it's like they're all sorts of like, okay, if you want the laptop even like think pads They'd be like, all right You know the all the always you would have spread rumors around like if you want your ThinkPad battery last the longest you got To let it drain down to 30% then charge it back up to 100 and then let go down to 30.
Speaker 1: Don't leave it plugged in when it's 100 and then once every few months Let it go down to zero and then all the way down to zero like a hundred percent dead and charge it up again.
Speaker 1: It's like what the hell.
Speaker 1: why do I got?
Speaker 1: shouldn't I just want to plug it in all the time whenever I can and only Unplug it when I have to?
Speaker 1: so I use you know minimal battery power Yeah, and I want everything to be good now.
Speaker 0: So in my current laptop now, it's just Windows 10 Like.
Speaker 0: I wiped all the stuff but when I first got it, it had some like IBM stuff on it.
Speaker 0: The battery management software that came with it actually exposed all those details and you basically would choose Whether you wanted the battery to last longer in any given use like how long will the laptop run?
Speaker 0: and you could make it?
Speaker 0: Run a lot longer, but then the battery itself would have a shorter lifetime before it just stopped working.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm and Most devices favor the battery lasting as long as the device is expected to last.
Speaker 1: So during college for a short period of time I had a job working somewhere and one of the things that they made one of the things that they made there Was military like military batteries like batteries that military people actually use like they had a big charger on the back of their Humvee or whatever.
Speaker 1: And if these enormous friggin batteries used to power who knows what?
Speaker 1: or I guess I don't know power suits or whatever.
Speaker 1: And you know, they made like the recharging software and some of the hardware for these batteries.
Speaker 1: So they had them around.
Speaker 1: I wasn't working on them But my friend James did and I think he still works on batteries.
Speaker 1: I guess he.
Speaker 1: well you can't be on the show to tell us all his battery knowledge.
Speaker 1: He's probably so mad if he listens to this at our lack of battery knowledge.
Speaker 0: I remember You and him from our IT.
Speaker 1: those batteries were big Heavy and they lasted a long time and gave a lot of power.
Speaker 0: So everything we just talked about.
Speaker 0: there's a fundamental thing that you really need to know and this is why this is kind of an interesting topic.
Speaker 0: The better a battery is The more energy it holds per unit mass.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the more energy it holds for unit mass the more closely it resembles a hand grenade, right?
Speaker 0: I mean because there's more energy in a smaller space right thing about.
Speaker 1: it's like, okay No matter what battery technology it is chemicals or solid-state or who know whatever it is Whatever mechanism you have for holding energy, right?
Speaker 1: Electrons don't weigh nothing.
Speaker 1: We don't weigh nothing.
Speaker 1: well and if protons weigh even more right and so this you gotta have the protons any electrons in there.
Speaker 1: Uh, and if you want a battery lasts a long time Right, you got to have you know, a lot more energy in there.
Speaker 1: energy is mass.
Speaker 0: I'm shit.
Speaker 0: I make no statement as to everything you just said and I'm going to simplify that to simply say that the more energy density something has the more catastrophic a Rapid uncontrolled release of that energy would be case in point You take that old shitty battery pack for my game gear and shove out an iron spike through it.
Speaker 0: It'll probably go play.
Speaker 0: Well, look at how many people shove an iron spike through like just a raw modern lithium-ion cell full energy and it'll kill you All right.
Speaker 1: Look how many people I got my got my cell phone exploded.
Speaker 1: It's like yeah, cuz you have a battery and there were the insane amount of energy in it And they actually can.
Speaker 1: there is technology out there to make some kinds of batteries that are better in terms of you know Energy than the ones we have but you're not allowed to use them or they won't like people won't mail them and stuff because it's like Well, they're super dangerous.
Speaker 1: There's a lot of energy in a space or they have other trade-offs.
Speaker 0: They're very expensive manufacture very heavy They take a long time to recharge or a lot of them act more like primary cell.
Speaker 0: Like if you have a battery that is not intended to be rechargeable There are ways to make very long-lasting batteries, but then they run out Yeah, and then you gotta get another one and give you an extreme.
Speaker 1: Oh, they don't go nicely into.
Speaker 0: inside of an iPhone case There is actually the concept of a nuclear battery.
Speaker 0: now These are not commonly used except in space and like old Soviet era like remote unmanned lighthouses.
Speaker 1: But a nuclear battery is a battery that weighs more than you can imagine, but it's relatively small Because it's got you know radioactive elements which tend to have really high numbers and are thus heavy.
Speaker 0: But it also needs shielding because it's radioactive.
Speaker 1: Yes is led in the radioactivity is.
Speaker 0: Well, basically, usually they're actually just generating ambient heat which is then some sort of Peltier device.
Speaker 0: there's a lot of ways to get a nuclear battery, but They these are a battery that if you had one it'll output.
Speaker 0: however many volts it outputs You know how much energy it you it provides for like 20 years Depends on the half-life, but yeah fucking long-ass time.
Speaker 0: You have a battery that will last consistently 20 years of constant use Mm-hmm, but if you break that battery open It'll kill you and a lot of other people nearby.
Speaker 0: They'll get the cancer and it'll also way too much to put in.
Speaker 1: say a car Yeah You're not putting even like even it was like a flake imagine like a cornflake worth of radioactive material Right and then putting a whole battery around that and somehow getting that in your phone.
Speaker 0: It's like no Regulators might have a big issue with.
Speaker 1: but even half a cornflake is too much.
Speaker 0: So think of these.
Speaker 0: this is the the boundaries of the idea of a battery and a portable energy or semi portable energy repository.
Speaker 0: You can go from a nuclear battery that lasts forever to a tiny flake that will kill anyone.
Speaker 0: It looks at it crosswise Mm-hmm, and it's just a matter of use cases material science Chemical science and it's a field that needs to evolve further to do the kinds of things We want to do with technology that we can't do today.
Speaker 0: the Tesla like those electric cars.
Speaker 0: It is amazing that there are batteries that can hold that much power.
Speaker 1: Well, there's a also.
Speaker 1: you just use a lot of batteries and it somehow manages to not be too heavy.
Speaker 0: So the motor can actually push the car, but there is a huge number of batteries in there.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, there's like a whole tray of them, right?
Speaker 0: But when you we already you're already breaking down the I how many cells comprise a battery Doesn't really matter to a modern person.
Speaker 0: No, I'm working in the technology.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you don't realize it but like okay you open up your iPhone is it?
Speaker 1: there's like a rectangle battery in there.
Speaker 1: The battery is not a rectangle shape.
Speaker 1: batteries are cylinder shaped.
Speaker 1: if you open that up There's a ton of little cylinders in there.
Speaker 1: You don't care how many or whether they're in series or rows or anything, but that's that's how it is.
Speaker 0: So not all of them are.
Speaker 0: there are other shapes of batteries.
Speaker 0: But the point is unless you work on the internals of batteries specifically the beauty of the modern world is that there is circuitry and electronics Intelligence between you and all that bullshit.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so you don't need to know what's actually going on But yeah, most batteries are actually a whole bunch of smaller batteries combined.
Speaker 1: Yep, right because it's like it's cheaper.
Speaker 1: right you can instead of making some custom battery You can just buy these stock cells and just arrange them to get the voltage you need and the life you need Right and then encase them in something and put a connector on the end.
Speaker 0: So in terms of practical example, it's kind of interesting.
Speaker 0: Remember I bought that weird phone.
Speaker 0: like everyone else has a normal Android phone or an iPhone.
Speaker 1: Are you the Sony thing?
Speaker 0: I have the weird Sony thing and the real deal with the Sony thing is the battery lasts twice as long as any other phone.
Speaker 1: Well, cuz it's not as powerful as the other phones Like the Samsung galaxies are like ridiculous CPU ridiculous screen ridiculous GPU.
Speaker 1: Oh my gosh Yours is much more reasonable like iPhone 5c.
Speaker 0: the batteries we put in phones all pretty much have the same energy density.
Speaker 0: So the only factors in terms of how long your cell phone's battery last can last How big it is how heavy it is and how much your phone uses.
Speaker 0: Yep And thus there's an interesting situation where a larger phone will have a much larger screen that has to be lit very brightly But can also have a much larger battery in it.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Well, you need it to accommodate.
Speaker 0: My tiny phone actually does not have a lot of room for battery But at the same time it also has a much smaller screen with many fewer pixels and a slower processor Right.
Speaker 1: So the other thing is that when you if you're thinking about saving battery life on your phone Keep the screen off the screen uses the most energy.
Speaker 0: That is why we talk so much about how smartwatches are so great because if you have a smartwatch You're not gonna turn your phone screen on as much you'll be shocked at how much longer your phone's batteries last.
Speaker 1: Yeah, because the Bluetooth uses a Bluetooth is very low energy depending there.
Speaker 0: They well, it should be.
Speaker 1: there's also Specifically NFC and Bluetooth.
Speaker 1: low energy is actually a protocol that exists is different from Bluetooth and if you use Bluetooth low energy It's way less energy than turning on your screen.
Speaker 0: Yep, way less So in terms of practical battery stuff.
Speaker 0: modern laptops, you don't need to worry anymore Like I think Lenovo.
Speaker 0: you can still buy like you pick which got the batteries just like they do.
Speaker 1: They do sell as far as I know.
Speaker 1: like you can buy a bigger battery pack because I bought what they're like six cell And nine cell ones you can.
Speaker 1: you can buy a battery that was bigger heavier and lasted longer.
Speaker 0: Yeah, my x230 I bought the Six cell one.
Speaker 0: there was a four cell I think and I forget you bought the new one.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I didn't buy the biggest one because it was really big.
Speaker 1: Oh, I had a normal one and I had one that was big and stuck out the back a little bit.
Speaker 0: Yep So the one I bought sticks down a little bit and the bigger one Sticks down more and also sticks back and weighs so much.
Speaker 0: like I went lifted one.
Speaker 0: I didn't get that one.
Speaker 0: It was too much.
Speaker 0: but Where was I going with that?
Speaker 0: Alright modern laptops unless it's one of those weird laptops like it like it just has a battery.
Speaker 0: Just use your laptop and don't think about it.
Speaker 1: now.
Speaker 1: the one last thing you I think about here is for a lot of things and this is I've encountered this a lot with cameras is People companies want to sell you their specific battery, right?
Speaker 1: So you look at my camera.
Speaker 1: is Panasonic Panasonic sells a battery for it.
Speaker 1: That battery costs a lot of money like 70 bucks or like a tiny like 40 to 60 bucks.
Speaker 1: Alright now they're nice in that they've what they've done, you know Some of the companies do nice things and not nice things, right?
Speaker 1: One of the nice things they did is the gh3 the gh4 and the gh5.
Speaker 1: if you keep using their camera system They all use the exact same battery.
Speaker 1: They haven't changed the battery at all, right?
Speaker 1: So you can you know, they've had the same battery.
Speaker 1: They've been made and it's good for them too because they just keep manufacturing the same battery.
Speaker 1: You don't have to redesign it or anything, right and it's got enough power.
Speaker 1: It lasts a hell of a long time longer than a lot of batteries and other cameras.
Speaker 1: But anyway, the thing is that battery is expensive like 40 to 60 bucks depending on where you get it if you get an official one.
Speaker 1: So maybe you want to get a cheaper one.
Speaker 1: plenty of other people make the same exact battery.
Speaker 1: It's just not the official battery.
Speaker 1: It's made by like wasabi Co.
Speaker 1: which is somewhat legit Yeah, but it's not obviously not official or even shady your bootleg one that says pass anonic on it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I bought a variety of non first-party batteries over the years with a wide array of effects.
Speaker 1: Sometimes you buy a third-party battery, right?
Speaker 1: And that third-party battery lasts five seconds or explodes or sets on fire or is useless or who knows what or?
Speaker 1: Some some devices these days even have like DRM and are like, ah, I see that that is not an official battery.
Speaker 1: I refuse to turn on even though I would otherwise be able to work because I want.
Speaker 1: I want you to buy the $50 battery, but it's interesting.
Speaker 0: my old Panasonic camcorder.
Speaker 0: I have two official batteries and I have like six bootleg batteries I got from.
Speaker 0: I get them from anyway somewhere.
Speaker 0: the bootleg batteries all worked at first just fine But then over time one by one they stopped working and the camcorder would be like this is not an official battery.
Speaker 0: Yeah I've had but I didn't have any firmware update and I figured out what actually was happening.
Speaker 0: is those batteries the bootleg ones were just pieces Of shit and their voltage was fluctuating too much.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Now the wasabi batteries I have are actually, you know they're so cheap compared to the the official ones and Occasionally very occasionally you'll get a message.
Speaker 1: That's like I see that battery is not legit But then you just restart the camera and it works.
Speaker 1: Yep, and it's like it's like that small hassle is worth it, right?
Speaker 1: You're only gonna pay if you are so important Whatever you're shooting with your whatever your door your whatever device you're using camera or otherwise.
Speaker 1: If it's so important that it works perfectly then pay for the official battery.
Speaker 1: If you absolutely cannot deal with an exploding battery and you're so nervous by the make sure you're getting the official one and not a bootleg that looks like the official one or really on Amazon.
Speaker 0: if you Cannot afford to have something go tragically wrong with an expensive piece of electronics that you saved up for.
Speaker 0: Don't if you bought a thousand dollar camera, don't try to save 40 bucks on a battery, right?
Speaker 1: It's like, okay I understand that you don't have a lot of money and you saved a long time for this thousand dollar camera.
Speaker 1: because you don't have a lot of money Save even more money for the good battery because if the thousand dollar camera goes down you're going down.
Speaker 0: I'm like this LED panel.
Speaker 0: I got here that I paid like 20 bucks for.
Speaker 0: I Bought a bunch of cheapo bootleg batteries for those things because if these LED pay if every LED panel I own broke today because the batteries exploded.
Speaker 0: I'm not out that much money because I don't buy good light panels.
Speaker 1: So the new camera I got came with a legit battery and what actually I've been doing is I've been treating it like That battery is actually an internal non-removable battery.
Speaker 1: I just plugged the camera into micro USB at night Right, but I did buy two wasabi batteries for it, which were ridiculously cheap and they work just fine perfectly.
Speaker 1: So that if I'm ever in a situation where I'm out so long that the battery dies I can swap those bad boys in right because and they just they totally were great.
Speaker 1: It was like wasabi.
Speaker 1: is this brand?
Speaker 1: and I'm not.
Speaker 1: I'm not.
Speaker 1: I guess I am shilling for them But they didn't pay me for this.
Speaker 1: I've honestly just like a happy customer of a bootleg battery that you can buy.
Speaker 1: an Amazon that I've had good Experiences with doesn't works almost all the time.
Speaker 1: I've had a lot of recharges.
Speaker 0: I've had good and bad with wasabi, but I've never had exploded bad.
Speaker 0: I've only had it just doesn't work anymore.
Speaker 1: But I've never had doesn't work anymore.
Speaker 0: Like oh my god works.
Speaker 0: They're sitting right there cuz I just haven't dealt with them yet.
Speaker 1: All right, but they always give you a charger and they're so cheap Like you don't even feel bad if they don't work.
Speaker 0: as well as the yeah Charges I've had a couple of their chargers that make Terrifying noises sometimes.
Speaker 0: I haven't had that either but then again some of my light panels make terrifying noises.
Speaker 1: cuz they're yes Yes, I've had those yeah Anyway, but yeah, it's a little shaky.
Speaker 1: Like you hear stories about battery setting on fire and stuff and those are real stories, you know Cuz there's so much energy in the little battery and if it's not well made its bootleg, you know.
Speaker 1: Then they could happen.
Speaker 1: and official batteries, you know that you get from the.
Speaker 1: you know Full price for they're gonna be more expensive But they're gonna be work and they're gonna have a much better chance of being safe.
Speaker 1: Not a guarantee of being safe, but pretty rare.
Speaker 1: It's gonna be unsafe, but Even if you have money, it's just not worth it to buy the official batteries.
Speaker 1: You can get pretty good third-party ones that are good enough now regardless of whether or not as a first party.
Speaker 0: You should definitely treat your batteries with respect In the sense that old kinds of batteries even rechargeable ones They really wouldn't do anything too bad if you disrespected them or were careless with them.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm, but like if I drop a lithium-ion cell like a big one not the tiny ones But like the ones that are on the back of my camera.
Speaker 0: if I drop one one I don't Immediately retrieve it just to make sure it didn't have a problem.
Speaker 0: Like I give it a few seconds like okay It didn't explode and then just inspect your batteries.
Speaker 0: Like if you if something happens to one of your battery if it's inflating a little bit if it inflates even a little bit Like take it outside.
Speaker 1: I have some GoPro batteries didn't play a little bit.
Speaker 0: Yeah If that happens just get them out of your house as soon as possible and put them somewhere Where if they start a fire, it won't burn anything.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm, cuz that is sign number one that a modern rechargeable battery might be about to catch fire and hurt you very badly.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, if your phone starts to expand a little bit That means the foil that the cells are in is expanding and you are fucked.
Speaker 0: Take the phone out of your pocket and put it outside.
Speaker 0: Yeah, um if you get them wet Especially dropping them though because dropping them especially a big battery can very often cause a problem More.
Speaker 1: this is why the GoPro batteries had the problem because you know GoPro the action camera It's getting jostled quite a bit.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: Yeah, have a careful.
Speaker 1: There's one more thing I want to say.
Speaker 0: do you remember what it was?
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, so a lot of people out there like in my work.
Speaker 1: I have this problem a lot of People not recharging the batteries properly, right?
Speaker 1: So when you get a battery as rechargeable, you know It's designed to go with a particular charger.
Speaker 1: the people who made the charger designed it with a particular battery in mind.
Speaker 1: You can't just go putting like eneloop's in the energizer charger.
Speaker 1: No, also people at my work.
Speaker 1: They so dumb.
Speaker 1: They're taking batteries that aren't even rechargeable and just like shoving them in a charger It's like what the hell are you doing?
Speaker 1: That's battery's not even rechargeable.
Speaker 0: So the worst part is there are.
Speaker 0: I remember when I was a kid there were cut.
Speaker 0: you could buy Things that ostensibly would recharge a non rechargeable battery.
Speaker 0: knew those things were bad fucking news.
Speaker 0: So what I did?
Speaker 1: luckily the eneloop charger is smart enough to like.
Speaker 1: not mess around but yeah Recharge batteries in the charger that came with it.
Speaker 1: I'll even have like.
Speaker 1: I have wasabi batteries and official batteries and then I have a wasabi charger and an official charge.
Speaker 0: I don't mix the two.
Speaker 1: I don't mix them.
Speaker 1: I use the wasabi charger and the wasabi batteries and the regular batteries and the regular charger and I don't cross them because you know The charger was designed to recharge that battery and you don't want to confuse it.
Speaker 0: I have occasionally put the bootleg battery in the real charger because the chargers what has the logic?
Speaker 1: I would I usually I might do that, but I will go the other way.
Speaker 0: I will never put a legit battery in this like cheap plastic wasabi.
Speaker 1: That's even scarier Yeah, but I don't.
Speaker 1: I try not to do either.
Speaker 1: but yes one is better than the other.
Speaker 0: Yeah If you have to so for my own personal batteries because remember we could.
Speaker 0: there's sort of two.
Speaker 0: There's three types of batteries kind of the thing we can end on.
Speaker 0: there's portable power bank that has USB holes in it.
Speaker 0: Mmm, I think everyone should own at least one small one because you can recharge your cell phone.
Speaker 1: I have I have one that's like the energy.
Speaker 0: It's nothing so ancient.
Speaker 1: It's so ancient, but it has plenty of energy can recharge my phone several times.
Speaker 1: It can recharge lots of stuff.
Speaker 1: It has enough cables.
Speaker 1: It can recharge almost any device ever has plugs for everything.
Speaker 1: It's not USB.
Speaker 0: my little anchors cuz one.
Speaker 0: my anchor just has a couple of USB holes in it.
Speaker 1: Yes I have a tiny anchor.
Speaker 1: There's like a little cylinder.
Speaker 1: That's one USB.
Speaker 1: It'll try my phone up once.
Speaker 1: It'll charge my phone up like two or three times.
Speaker 0: Oh, you got the bigger one.
Speaker 1: No, I got a free one.
Speaker 1: They sent me for being a good customer.
Speaker 1: I just keep it in my bag at all times.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and if my phone I can always bring it out if I ever need a phone charge and it's rare.
Speaker 1: But it I have it.
Speaker 0: so I have that too.
Speaker 0: I also have a big one that will recharge an iPhone like four times.
Speaker 0: but I only use that for like plugging devices into or Powering my phone if I'm doing GPS tracking over like a really long hike in the wilderness Or like I brought that on the Holland Valley Railroad as my power in the tent.
Speaker 1: Mmm.
Speaker 0: So that's a use case.
Speaker 0: So just you should own one of those if you don't know which one to get.
Speaker 0: just buy like whatever the cheapest anchor branded One is they're fine.
Speaker 0: Uh There's the specialized batteries Which is what we've been mostly talking about just now like the ones you use on an expensive camera or an LED panel And we've talked of that enough for Batteries that are the shape of a double or triple-a battery to use with any old device Which I feel like is increasingly an obsolete use case.
Speaker 0: I mean the only devices I have that use those today are 9 volt batteries.
Speaker 0: go to my smoke detectors Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: Fuck that that is such a pain in the ass.
Speaker 1: I have a whole bunch of 9 volt.
Speaker 0: The only other thing 9 volt batteries seem to be used for is Microphones.
Speaker 0: more wireless microphone devices also non wireless but true pretty much any microphone that needs a battery seems to use 9 But increasingly people seem to be moving toward double-a in there because 9 volt is just an annoying form factor.
Speaker 1: I got a 9 volt in the microphone that goes on top of my camera and I bought a whole pack of them from Amazon basics
Speaker 0: yep, and
Speaker 1: Back
Speaker 0: of them - I
Speaker 1: accidentally left the microphone on overnight and I've used it a whole bunch and I used it like all day At the fucking review.
Speaker 1: con like, you know, it's like and you know what?
Speaker 1: It's still on the first 9 volt.
Speaker 0: Yep I bought a pack of those same 9 volt batteries because all the smoke detectors in our apartment when the 9 volt bed They're powered by real power They have wires But they also have a 9 volt battery.
Speaker 0: as the backups of the powers out the smoke detector still works.
Speaker 0: if a smoke detectors battery fails, it'll make it a really high-pitched annoying chirp at Really short intervals forever and there's no way to stop that short of replacing that 9 volt battery.
Speaker 0: Let me tell you when that starts happening at 3 in the morning and you do not have another 9 volt battery Welcome to hell Especially when the rabbits hear it and they you cannot explain to them.
Speaker 0: So I basically use antelopes now and the inter only Sanyo Panasonic antelope is the best.
Speaker 1: double a triple a CD rechargeable battery.
Speaker 0: if you need C's or D's the fuck is wrong with you.
Speaker 1: What they do if you need C or D is actually these plastic cylinders.
Speaker 1: And you put your double-a antelopes into the plastic cylinder and now your double-a fits into the C or D hole.
Speaker 1: They don't actually make C and D batteries.
Speaker 0: I kept the D hole like the shapes.
Speaker 1: I kept them but I've never used them.
Speaker 0: I got rid of the C's cuz I don't own anything that could take a C bad.
Speaker 1: You never know when you'll find something.
Speaker 1: It doesn't.
Speaker 0: what about a single a or a B?
Speaker 1: Actually the stylus that comes with the Microsoft Surface Pro that I have at work what has a Quadruple?
Speaker 1: a bad.
Speaker 0: I've seen those around.
Speaker 1: I've never seen one before in my life.
Speaker 1: I was like, what the fuck is this?
Speaker 1: Where the hell do I get another one when this dies?
Speaker 1: You don't recharge it like you do with the Apple magic pencil.
Speaker 1: You had to buy a new battery for it Wow.
Speaker 0: Yeah But With antelope, there's the normal ones, but they actually have two Weird use cases and three different antelopes, but and there's different generations of antelope.
Speaker 1: But it's hard to tell the difference between the generations and as far as the users concerned the difference in the generations doesn't really matter.
Speaker 0: But there's normal ones and normally we'll use those.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I want to point out noise.
Speaker 1: You're curious.
Speaker 1: if you don't if you don't know better just take the normal white and loops if you somehow really know what you're doing.
Speaker 1: They have the el cheapo antelopes, which are light don't last as long but are way cheaper and they're way lighter.
Speaker 0: Yes, they weigh a lot less.
Speaker 0: So this is where you like you're putting a camera on a drone and like every ounce counts Yeah, or you know that the device you're putting the batteries.
Speaker 1: It doesn't need a lot of energy.
Speaker 1: It's a really low drain device like a portable radio or something and you want it to be lighter and you know Save some money or whatever.
Speaker 1: You can get the cheapo antelopes that are light and I guess more efficient and whatever.
Speaker 0: There's also an aloo pros and I have eight a double-a and aloo Pro cells.
Speaker 0: They cost way more than a regular one.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they're way heavier.
Speaker 1: Yeah,
Speaker 0: like if you hold a regular one and one of these like it is Interesting how much heavier the the pro one is and also I didn't measure this to be sure They're a little bit bigger like they're skirting the line of actually being a double-a
Speaker 1: Big as a double-a as you can fit into a thing if it's one of those Battery holder mine
Speaker 0: are scraped to fucking hell because they barely fit in the Marantz.
Speaker 0: Like I have to shove them into the Marantz.
Speaker 1: I mean while the regular and loop slides in just fine I use the eneloop pros mostly for not for gaming controllers for those uses regular and loop.
Speaker 0: Yep, I love those for a camera flashes.
Speaker 0: I use the pros for camera flash and I use the pros for the Marantz audio recorders.
Speaker 0: We have hmm, which I have three of them.
Speaker 0: I found another cheap one.
Speaker 1: I use them for things that Can only be double-a.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I absolutely need them to.
Speaker 1: I need to like be guaranteed that they're not gonna like turn off right like a recording device.
Speaker 0: But even then these are not like pay for these expensive batteries and your thing lasts twice as long.
Speaker 0: it lasts like 10 to 20% Longer, yeah, it's not.
Speaker 1: they're not that much better than the regular ones.
Speaker 1: But you only get them if you really have a situation where you must have the more power.
Speaker 1: It's a high-powered.
Speaker 1: but what I would recommend now?
Speaker 0: this might have changed and so you can double-check.
Speaker 0: but I bought several of the eneloop pro Charger because the old regular eneloop charger had a thing where you had to put two batteries in at a time Minimum and it would charge them in groups of two.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: The pro one charges every cell individually.
Speaker 1: Yeah, as far as I can tell all it was just an upgrade of the charger model.
Speaker 1: Yep, so like even if you go today to buy white eneloop and it comes with the white charger It's the same actual model as the charger.
Speaker 1: The clearly charge your pro battery - I don't know They're all it's the exact same model number.
Speaker 1: It's just if you buy the white one of the black one that the plastic is white or black.
Speaker 1: But it's actually the same exact charger.
Speaker 1: There's a okay old one is actually a different model.
Speaker 1: It's way back.
Speaker 1: It's like there's something something 17 or who knows?
Speaker 0: I bought the pros actually a long time ago and it's kind of amazing that these cells still work great so many years later.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I have not had a single eneloop battery ever.
Speaker 1: like not be able to recharge and keep working.
Speaker 1: That's how good they are.
Speaker 1: Of course.
Speaker 1: I do have a ton of them.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean I I don't need to buy any more ever because I have so many.
Speaker 0: I have 24 double A's.
Speaker 0: I have eight pro double A's.
Speaker 0: I have four triple A's.
Speaker 0: cuz I really don't need those anymore.
Speaker 1: I use them pretty much in game controllers and camera flashes.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: That's pretty much it.
Speaker 0: I use them for a little while because my bike has lights on it But now I just use primary cells in my bike lights.
Speaker 1: all my bike lights now are USB charged.
Speaker 1: No, I still have one bike light that takes double a.
Speaker 0: still my take double or triple a. yeah And primary cells are just better for that kind of purpose because there's a lot of primary cells are pretty rugged compared to Rechargeable cells and they will survive things better.
Speaker 0: Hmm.
Speaker 1: Whatever.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: I think we're done.
Speaker 1: I'm hungry.
Speaker 1: batteries.
Speaker 0: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Speaker 1: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 0: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 0: But unlike those other late shows It's actually recorded at night and the patreon patreons for this episode of geek nights are Ellen Joyce Heidi McNichol Amanda Duschetta shimmering Ruby obelisk hanging in the sky my stady calm.
Speaker 0: Jeremy minor a genuine bonafide electrified six car monorail Sean Yeager Matthew Smith Nicholas Brando captain Chinguac asi Rebecca Dunn for two one creations.
Speaker 0: No, I never ever wonder why we're here.
Speaker 0: semper fi bitch Sir Sherman on horrible James David White Rochelle, Montanona Superboy rim says something funny here.
Speaker 0: Sailor Vista Don Shleich Jartavish and Joe Shiro Joe star Sam Gordrey Clinton Walton Ren from New Zealand Ryan parent drew open lander.
Speaker 0: Brian Sidroni Finn Chris midkiff Chris Knox Daniel Redmond Sean Klein Chris Reimer and Thomas Hahn.
Speaker 0: trying to say it slow in a more Halloween II way was Taking way too long and saying it faster actually ended up being easier.
Speaker 0: You might have noticed I read another chapter of worlds of power Castlevania for the patrons and I'm gonna finish that book as fast as I can over the course of the next month and then post It as a full audiobook for all of our patreon patreons to enjoy.
Speaker 0: But anyway now I leave you.
Speaker 0: Usually the blood gets off at the second floor.
Speaker 0: No, no go easy on the wee one.
Speaker 0: his father's gonna go crazy and chop mole into haggis.
Speaker 0: Boy, you read my thoughts.
Speaker 0: You've got the shinin.
Speaker 0: you mean shining Shh, you want to get sued now.
Speaker 1: look boy if your dad goes gaga you just use that Shin of yours to call me and I'll come a running.
Speaker 0: but don't be reading my mind between four and five.
Speaker 0: That's Willie's time Sir.
Speaker 1: Did you ever stop to think that maybe it was doing this that caused the previous caretakers to go insane and murder their families?
Speaker 0: Perhaps tell you what.
Speaker 0: we come back and everyone slaughtered.
Speaker 0: I owe you a coke Cables out.
Speaker 0: think I'll have a beer Not a drop in the house.
Speaker 0: What do you know?
Speaker 0: I'm impressed.
Speaker 0: You're taking this quite well.
Speaker 1: Sorry, don't worry, it's funny I can do to keep myself occupied.
Speaker 0: Maybe I'll check out that axe collection.
Speaker 1: Dad gonna kill us.
Speaker 0: We're just gonna have to wait and see.