Speaker 0: It's Wednesday, February 22nd, 2017.
Speaker 0: I'm rim.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott and this is geek nights.
Speaker 0: tonight We're talking about miss Kobayashi's dragon maid.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: Have you heard of this new subreddit the bird?
Speaker 1: It's a relatively new as far as I know.
Speaker 1: I'm newly aware of it.
Speaker 1: No matter how old it is I will see.
Speaker 0: we'll see.
Speaker 0: cuz.
Speaker 0: I found a few choice subreddits recent and it's called shower orange.
Speaker 0: Yes, I saw this.
Speaker 1: you saw the shower orange.
Speaker 0: first someone posted the rules to that subreddit and then later I went and actually saw the subreddit.
Speaker 1: So I tried to shower orange this morning.
Speaker 0: How'd it go?
Speaker 1: I went to the very.
Speaker 0: that's very Cosmo Kramer.
Speaker 1: I went to the.
Speaker 1: yeah pretty much.
Speaker 1: I went to the grocery last night and bought five oranges.
Speaker 1: and first of all, I gotta say Oranges are a bad deal.
Speaker 1: Orange juice is like expensive orange juice.
Speaker 1: It's like four dollars for like half a gallon.
Speaker 1: right for quality.
Speaker 0: Oh, you want to make a half a gallon of orange juice from oranges right?
Speaker 1: five oranges was four dollars.
Speaker 1: Okay, and these aren't good Florida oranges.
Speaker 1: These are New York oranges that didn't have much flavor, right?
Speaker 1: So I bring the orange in the shower and a. it's convenient because you just wash it right there.
Speaker 1: It's nice and clean, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah - it gives you something to do in the shower beside when you're like maybe waiting for.
Speaker 0: well See the problem is right now.
Speaker 0: I got the waterproof cell phone So for the like.
Speaker 0: while I'm standing there for a few minutes every morning I'll actually just kind of read FARC.
Speaker 0: then I'll get about my business.
Speaker 1: anyway.
Speaker 1: It was a little bit hard to peel the orange.
Speaker 0: I don't have like fingernails and I gotta go to got to do the clementine if you want to peel it with your hand.
Speaker 1: It's wet.
Speaker 1: So, but I did it.
Speaker 0: I'd recommend cutting an incision into the orange before you go into the.
Speaker 1: I don't want to link any.
Speaker 1: I want to leak any shower into the orange.
Speaker 0: No, I mean you're in the shower with the orange.
Speaker 1: you're gonna see if it gets on the outside of the orange.
Speaker 1: That's not a problem.
Speaker 0: But as soon as it gets inside the orange water, what else are you gonna get in there?
Speaker 1: I don't want to eat soap.
Speaker 0: I Imagine you eat the orange like before.
Speaker 0: you're fully soaked up.
Speaker 0: Nah, whatever anyway Actually, we're gonna put a garbage disposal in the bottom of the shower.
Speaker 1: I just took the peels out with me and threw them in the garbage.
Speaker 1: So when I open the orange, oh so this keeps going.
Speaker 1: Yeah, all right.
Speaker 1: So so so when I open the orange I began to understand why people like this.
Speaker 1: because it like the citrus odor just like went.
Speaker 0: And it was like you get that just by spraying like a puff of citrus saw while you're in there.
Speaker 1: Yes, you could but it was.
Speaker 1: it was from a real orange like it was so good.
Speaker 1: But the problem was that I disappeared like in less than a second.
Speaker 1: It was like, oh, it's gone.
Speaker 0: I guess gotta have a steady stream of oranges.
Speaker 1: Yeah, just keep opening oranges one after another on a conveyor belt.
Speaker 1: and then I started eating the orange and I was just eating an orange and eating it in the shower wasn't any different than eating it outside the shower except Because I sort of had to take a shower.
Speaker 1: I kind of ate it in a hurry.
Speaker 1: Well, yeah, cuz always if I'm eating it outside, I'm gonna eat it like oh Like one wedge at a time, right, but I'm in the shower and it's like I have to finish showering.
Speaker 1: so I'm like, oh Right.
Speaker 1: So it changes that the eating part.
Speaker 0: Unless you have time to take a forever shower Which I usually do I kind of make time for that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but this is a morning shower.
Speaker 1: I want to see.
Speaker 1: I usually I've been taking more night showers, but because it was shower orange I took a morning shower on purpose because I figured that's what it'd be more effective.
Speaker 1: Anyway, who wants to eat an orange like late at night?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I already got a message for the stream quote.
Speaker 0: I feel mildly uncomfortable looking at this subreddit.
Speaker 1: So I I ate the orange and then I finished taking a shower and I think The shower orange is not really all it's cracked up to be.
Speaker 1: but I'm withholding judgment because I think if I had I got a good orange from like Florida a fresh quality or a big old like hey one of those heavy feeling oranges.
Speaker 1: Oh, this is I got the right variety of orange.
Speaker 1: It just wasn't fresh and powerful and local and whatnot, right?
Speaker 1: So it wasn't when I opened it like each wedge only had a little bit of flavor.
Speaker 0: now I'm already imagining there might be forget the shower.
Speaker 0: The shower is just a pale imitation.
Speaker 0: You need to be floating in the ocean eating the orange.
Speaker 1: Sure.
Speaker 1: That'd be great But it's just.
Speaker 1: I need an orange that maintains its citrusy power and makes the whole shower Orange flavored and not just you know a whiff of orange flavor followed by a few bites of orange flavor.
Speaker 0: Hey this I feel like an orange cough drop will suffice Possibly yeah, also I could just you know my shower.
Speaker 1: Currently, you know, the the flavor that it has is the flavor of Neutrogena rainbat Much better flavor than orange.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you don't want to drink that.
Speaker 1: No, I don't want to eat it.
Speaker 1: But I mean it when I as soon as I get the soap out That's the whole shower gets that soap flavor.
Speaker 1: and I had love.
Speaker 1: I use luxury hotel.
Speaker 1: So so it right and I don't really.
Speaker 1: if I wanted to replace that with orange I would just get orange.
Speaker 0: So see I use some service.
Speaker 1: They definitely make that.
Speaker 0: Yeah I just use like scentless sort of like sea salty soap soap.
Speaker 1: You haven't tried the rainbat.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Well, I haven't tried the orange.
Speaker 1: Orange is better than nothing.
Speaker 1: But so I guess if I was in a Shower that didn't have like a flavor and I wanted to flavor it up I'd get an orange.
Speaker 1: or if I maybe if I maybe I'd go with the grapefruit.
Speaker 1: if I go Grapefruit is actually one of these.
Speaker 0: it's banned.
Speaker 1: There's a wide variety of permitted citrus and grapefruit is not permitted and I agree.
Speaker 0: cuz grapefruits are awful I feel like I should make the grapefruit only one grapefruit to shower grapefruit.
Speaker 1: First of all this now you're getting the spoon in the shower.
Speaker 1: It's already a problem With your hands, yeah, you can know.
Speaker 0: the only thing stopping you is human decency And the fact that it makes a big mess, but in the shower also it tastes disgusting Amazing.
Speaker 0: It's great.
Speaker 0: Granted.
Speaker 0: I do not like eating raw grapefruit.
Speaker 1: I just drink hydrochloric acid.
Speaker 0: So, uh in the news and there's a bunch of news but I actually I want to talk about this because I caught up 100%.
Speaker 1: we've done this news before though on adventure time.
Speaker 1: We've done this news.
Speaker 0: So I have a geek bite of Reviewing the the miniseries because adventure time is actually only done.
Speaker 0: two of these miniseries that are sort of standalone.
Speaker 1: They did snakes which is Name really a miniseries is what I'm saying.
Speaker 1: It's just a more.
Speaker 1: it's more than two episodes that go together.
Speaker 0: Well, I say more and more.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's a series of episodes But stakes sort of told its own story about Marceline start to finish there.
Speaker 0: And what I think interesting about islands is that stakes just sort of like told this side story?
Speaker 0: Islands is like say adventure time had not occurred up to this point and like the next season adventure time was starting like the beginning of a show.
Speaker 0: Islands is almost like the prequel to that.
Speaker 0: Islands literally is Finn and a few other characters find out there might be humans somewhere and Go off as Susan strong to some islands to find out what happened to the last of the humans.
Speaker 1: It makes sense and it is not a spoiler.
Speaker 1: That's like obvious
Speaker 0: Yeah, but it's deeply tied to the continuity and actually already I noticed some things in the background You know, although like in stakes and all these other things you see like other characters and flashbacks and in the background You see a lot of well corpses and items that indicate the statuses and dispositions and end states of a lot of those people.
Speaker 0: and It gave me a lot of confidence that the last season of adventure time which is not the one that's on now It's the one that airs next year because islands just occurs in the middle of the current season Which just has more episodes that are coming out.
Speaker 1: at some point, I guess I'm sticking with my strategy of I stopped watching and I'm gonna watch again when the final episode comes out.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna go And be done.
Speaker 0: thing is I just started catching up because it's so good and I kind of forgot because Steven universe has been the Hotness lately and I like Steven universe my hurry, but adventure time Has quite a long-standing.
Speaker 0: I don't know you of its own thing and I think adventure time is a top-tier show.
Speaker 0: and Reminded of that by watching a bunch of it again Okay, also it's gonna end.
Speaker 0: so, you know your strategy shoes goose that I missed.
Speaker 1: Ah, I don't think there's any choose goose and there's no reason for me to hurry up.
Speaker 1: I can just wait.
Speaker 0: However, you you say this is your strategy.
Speaker 0: What are you gonna read?
Speaker 0: Dr.
Speaker 0: McNinchy because it is 100% done.
Speaker 1: as soon as I get a chance probably real soon.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you can just blow through it.
Speaker 0: I mean, it's you know, King radical was up to something and you're just gonna.
Speaker 0: Obviously, it's pretty good and it's a hundred hundred hundred hundred percent over.
Speaker 0: there will be never more.
Speaker 1: not even one more page of Dr.
Speaker 1: McNinchy will ever be created.
Speaker 0: In fact, if you go to the site now, it shows the first page of dr McNinchy and it warns you not to click back.
Speaker 0: Hmm All right.
Speaker 0: So you got any any news?
Speaker 1: Oh, I do have a news.
Speaker 1: So You know a lot of people have not seen as much Gundam as I've seen.
Speaker 1: But maybe they're not opposed to seeing some Gundam, right?
Speaker 1: Maybe they're like, oh, you know, I do kind of want to see some Gundams, but I don't know which ones to watch.
Speaker 1: There's so many I don't understand right?
Speaker 1: Well, how convenient Hulu, which I recently Suspended my subscription because at South Park isn't on right now.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: I had also pause my Hulu.
Speaker 0: I got a c-roll going and I got the Netflix going.
Speaker 1: I only have c-roll right now because I'm watching you all paddle.
Speaker 1: I might turn it back on because they just added to Hulu five Gundams and there are five excellent Gundams.
Speaker 1: Gundam seed which is the HD version that does not even have dub.
Speaker 1: It's subtitle only.
Speaker 0: I could almost watch that again.
Speaker 1: Go just go right for it.
Speaker 1: Just go right into that.
Speaker 1: No problem They also got Gundam the origin which I kind of want.
Speaker 1: That's the one I would resubscribe to see because I read.
Speaker 1: I read the all the manga But I haven't seen the anime of Gundam the origin or 8th MS team.
Speaker 1: I got 8th MS team, which is way short.
Speaker 1: How many episodes is it like?
Speaker 0: like 8 not many?
Speaker 1: It's not a lot of episodes.
Speaker 1: You can watch this marathon that crab go watch this shit in a day even though there's actually 12 12 episodes.
Speaker 1: So that's like a one-day show, you know, you can watch it in like a week.
Speaker 1: You watch an episode every day.
Speaker 0: It's like a whole arc of utenna.
Speaker 1: Yeah Just watch two episodes every day and you'll see all of 8th MS team one of the best Gundams there is.
Speaker 1: it's on Hulu Right now.
Speaker 1: all of these are sub and dub except for Gundam seed, which is sub only.
Speaker 1: Gundam wing the one that was on Cartoon Network one that I never watched all the way through in order I only see.
Speaker 1: the only thing I've seen all the way through is the movie with the two mix music.
Speaker 1: I never saw the whole TV show.
Speaker 0: all the way to show also has to mix music.
Speaker 1: I mean if I watched Gundam the origin Maybe I'll actually do that and watch Gundam wing all the way through in order.
Speaker 0: and then what do you think the plot of Gundam?
Speaker 0: Wing is.
Speaker 1: so I'm just curious.
Speaker 1: There's a bunch of kids on a planet and there's some sort of war.
Speaker 1: There's an evil government.
Speaker 0: That's all.
Speaker 0: the good guys are the bad guys.
Speaker 1: kids are the good guys, but some of them are bad guys.
Speaker 1: are they and the kids get Gundams one Gundam per kid and There's that girl who's like, you know, basically Princess Leia.
Speaker 1: she's like in the government.
Speaker 1: She's like as Klein.
Speaker 1: Yeah, yeah, and then there's a dude who's not char, but he's char and they must fight in space.
Speaker 0: Except I think they mostly fight.
Speaker 0: I think they also fight on the planet a lot.
Speaker 1: Yeah, sure They do that every Gundam.
Speaker 1: That's how it works.
Speaker 1: and then this is dramatic part where you go into space and a dramatic part We come out of space.
Speaker 0: I gotta say so.
Speaker 0: if you three entries hell.
Speaker 0: if you have never seen Any Gundam somehow despite listening to geek nice you can.
Speaker 1: that's the best.
Speaker 1: This is what I'm saying.
Speaker 1: Is that all of these Gundams including the one I didn't mention yet Gundam double-o Which I have only seen a couple episodes of but I've never actually seen it.
Speaker 1: So, I don't know if it's any good or not because they've only seen two episodes and those weren't bad.
Speaker 1: Is it any of these Gundams?
Speaker 1: are Gundams that you can just watch right away with no Gundam knowledge whatsoever?
Speaker 1: Yeah, you don't need to know nothing about no Gundams.
Speaker 1: So I pick any one of these.
Speaker 1: You can just start from episode.
Speaker 0: one of any of these I'm not even talking like oh, there's all this backstory.
Speaker 0: That won't matter.
Speaker 1: Like no, you can literally start from episode one of any of these.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: Got him.
Speaker 0: seed introduces the concept of a Gundam.
Speaker 1: Maybe Gundam the origin would be.
Speaker 1: I don't know if it like retails the whole thing or if it's just the parts that weren't.
Speaker 1: I don't know enough about it to say that for sure, but all the other ones Yeah, you can just start watching from nothing.
Speaker 0: if I had to recommend I'd recommend Gundam seed Because it's better.
Speaker 1: but Gundam seed will tell you gonna make the mess team is the best of these that I know of.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but gonna see like accessible Gundam seed is giving you.
Speaker 1: that is what all the other Gundams are Like.
Speaker 1: if you watch Gundam seed and then you go back and watch the original Gundam you be like, hey This is real similar to Gundam seed only like different characters.
Speaker 1: It's like yeah, that's how Gundam is.
Speaker 0: Yeah, wait, there's a mascot.
Speaker 0: what's going on?
Speaker 1: And then you watch Gundam wing you'd like.
Speaker 1: this is really some.
Speaker 1: yeah The same story retold with characters of different names and different looking robots.
Speaker 0: Well, except war in the pocket is just.
Speaker 1: war is sad war in the pockets even shorter than a semester Where the pocket is like one shot.
Speaker 1: It's like a movie basically Yeah, but anyway, but any of these are.
Speaker 1: all of these were like excellent choices to put up on the Hulu.
Speaker 1: So if you want to see Gundams your anime fan sign up for Hulu with the no ad version, you know.
Speaker 1: And then watch a Gundam and then turn it off.
Speaker 1: See you stop paying Cuz you don't want to pay for it even that you.
Speaker 0: So I use Twitter a lot and you keep tabs on Twitter.
Speaker 0: Like I check it pretty much all day.
Speaker 1: I read every single goddamn tweet Yep, and I have done so since I started using Twitter for real Tweet.
Speaker 0: I'm muting for a little while.
Speaker 1: every single tweet If anyone I follow is seen by my eyes and read and if I don't like tweets I unfollowed Aggressively.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: There's probably a bunch of people I follow that never tweet and I don't see any of their tweets.
Speaker 1: I don't unfollow them.
Speaker 1: But if someone tweets badly or too much I unfollow Yep, and I it's tough now because I follow new things very rarely.
Speaker 0: Yep I just followed a new account a new ish account at least that it uses emoji to everyday tweet.
Speaker 0: one like Randomized roguelike dungeon.
Speaker 1: I recently discovered the Darwin Awards this Twitter account that constantly post focus Lou is retweeting that about people hurting themselves.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and they're very funny, but there's too many of them sung and unfollow.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I trust a few I don't need like one of those a day not you know, ten Yep, but so last night around the same time Casey Green and Emi Sisorega Both tweeted these horrific cats.
Speaker 0: I saw these cats pretty much all morning this morning Yep, so I basically went and retweeted everyone in my feed who interacted with this thing and then I interacted with it.
Speaker 0: It is it's a neural network like learning experiment.
Speaker 0: There's a bunch of other practical stuff on this site like this.
Speaker 0: one here is about Identifying the components of facades unlike buildings Like imagine that for like drone delivery, but it's neural networks figuring out what something is or interacting with it from training.
Speaker 0: but this one is trained to look at edges like lines like vector art and Find the cats or in this case what Scott drew the dick.
Speaker 1: Why don't we do this except instead of cats dicks and so usable under porn is the here's edges to shoes edges to hand.
Speaker 1: Why don't we do edges to dicks?
Speaker 0: Why why not?
Speaker 0: Let's learn this.
Speaker 0: Let's see.
Speaker 0: So it uses tensorflow.
Speaker 0: chair We can learn that pretty easily make edges to dicks.
Speaker 0: I read it.
Speaker 1: You want advertisement on it.
Speaker 1: You'll make a fortune.
Speaker 0: I read I read a tutorial on tensorflow.
Speaker 1: I tried to read a tutorial on it and it said dude all this math.
Speaker 1: and I said fuck you You're supposed to do the math for me and I didn't understand it.
Speaker 1: just to dicks?
Speaker 0: Yes It does not yet exist.
Speaker 0: Yes Feel the hatred flow.
Speaker 1: When then it must have a counterpart.
Speaker 1: it just to boobs.
Speaker 0: No, it's just dicks Just dicks also boobs.
Speaker 0: Anyway, if you draw or attempt to draw a cat of some kind into this thing it will use machine learning and the height of modern technology to find the cat in it and This has already taken over Twitter for like three days.
Speaker 0: so you can just go enjoy it and Everyone will forget about it in like a week.
Speaker 1: Okay, is that it?
Speaker 1: That's it.
Speaker 1: So back when we were in college, we went to hockey games.
Speaker 1: Yep, and you know sporting events at colleges, you know, the crowds are smaller The crowds are more rabid and dedicated and well organized and they're more.
Speaker 1: it's the same people every time right who are going to every Single game it's not and sitting in the same place every single game.
Speaker 1: Not like a professional sporting event where there's thousands of people who are mostly there like one shot.
Speaker 1: It's the only game they're gonna see that season.
Speaker 1: your gear ever, right?
Speaker 1: So We used to do all sorts of organized chanting to mess with the goalie of the other team primarily Yeah, and also enjoy ourselves more Skate skate, but this is not unique to hockey.
Speaker 1: It also happens in the baseball and here is the best one I've seen of the baseball And Yeah, it's Texas.
Speaker 1: So fuck them.
Speaker 1: But hey, good job.
Speaker 1: I Enjoy this.
Speaker 1: keep doing it.
Speaker 0: I am amazed Not that they do this because you know, like you said this is a kind of common thing the sheer persistence of this particular.
Speaker 1: I'm not amazed that if we had a thing like that at RIT, would we have persisted?
Speaker 0: But we I mean the corner crew like to get the corner going and you could get.
Speaker 0: it's true.
Speaker 1: They have an entire baseball stadium going which is much larger than a little corner crew.
Speaker 1: Yeah,
Speaker 0: like this this is the kind of thing where you imagine like a mother teaching her daughter like listen
Speaker 1: I also think it's easier to persist when you have that many people because like you can take a break and then someone else takes A break and you get back into it.
Speaker 0: But there's also a fine line where the more people you have the more possibility of fracture.
Speaker 0: I mean look at a Rangers game You can't get.
Speaker 0: let's go Rangers going consistently for more than like two runs of it tops.
Speaker 1: It's very it's not easy.
Speaker 0: Like you started let's go Rangers.
Speaker 0: The dude fucking next to you will be out of sync immediately.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so Texas A&M my head is off to you.
Speaker 0: That's not bad.
Speaker 0: in the meta moment the book club book is Frank Herbert's.
Speaker 1: do not hide it because we've never done a we.
Speaker 0: neither one of us has actually read it all the way through.
Speaker 0: We just know a lot about dune because that's kind of pop culture II.
Speaker 0: but we don't know it that well.
Speaker 0: Like I know way more about the wheel of time than I do about dune.
Speaker 1: So I guess that's true.
Speaker 0: In fact because I've read all of the wheel of time I'm in that club of people who know about the wheel of time and I understand now why those people Always want to talk to other people about wheel of time.
Speaker 1: So you want to join the dune club do know?
Speaker 0: I'm reading the first book of dune.
Speaker 0: I am confident that even though somehow I read all of wheel of time from that first book we did I am confident I will not have the desire to read the second dune book.
Speaker 1: Well, I didn't have the desire to read the first dune book in middle school.
Speaker 1: So let's find out.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so we'll see.
Speaker 0: we're going to be live real soon on Friday Not this week not next week But the following week Friday at 6 p.m.
Speaker 0: In the bumblebee theater redoing a panel at PAX East.
Speaker 0: play dirty to win.
Speaker 0: and Let me tell you that that panel already got to the point where there is a line and beyond that line are additional slides Of winning techniques that even I will not use Panel I think I got.
Speaker 0: I got a Cuz.
Speaker 0: I was like here.
Speaker 0: here's the panel to Scott and Scott was like no no, no, you need to push it You need to go deeper.
Speaker 0: That's right, and we went deeper and it's still going deep.
Speaker 0: The bottom is not there yet.
Speaker 0: I think the bottom might be actually kill your opponent.
Speaker 0: No, like yeah, but like ahead of time so they don't show up to the tournament and you get a bye in the second round anyway.
Speaker 0: Otherwise, you should follow me and Scott on YouTube and we're doing a thing because in the last 12 years We have done a lot of Game nights episodes and a lot of those happen to be reviews of board games.
Speaker 0: However While many people might particularly enjoy our style of board game review I feel like very few people who review games actually go to the depth that we go into or A lot of them are often wrong about things.
Speaker 0: But anyway, I think our board game reviews are pretty good, but they're buried under all that other crap that happens.
Speaker 0: Let's talk about cat dicks and you know edges to dicks and all that nonsense.
Speaker 0: So I'm taking Every single board game review we have ever done and putting them on YouTube with just Slideshows of images of the games and just the board game review and nothing else.
Speaker 1: Why would you want to listen to audio on YouTube when you could get the mp3?
Speaker 1: you just skip ahead?
Speaker 0: So skip ahead to where I don't.
Speaker 0: it's not like there's a time code saying because we could figure it out.
Speaker 1: You listen for the thing of the day part and then you you know, what do you mean?
Speaker 0: listen for?
Speaker 0: that already means like scroll?
Speaker 0: Forward nope scroll.
Speaker 0: Nope.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: Now there's that music.
Speaker 0: They're still talking about dicks.
Speaker 1: Someone wants to do that.
Speaker 1: That's on them, but no one's gonna do that.
Speaker 0: Also, it is difficult to unless I make a separate podcast feed of just the main bits Most people can't be asked and most people don't even realize the podcast.
Speaker 1: Well, that's good.
Speaker 1: They shouldn't didn't waste time?
Speaker 0: No, so YouTube feels like a better way for this.
Speaker 0: Plus that's the kind of thing that'll actually get Shared if someone's like hey play this game They'll actually link to a YouTube but they're not gonna link to.
Speaker 1: you're gonna link to a YouTube that just shows images.
Speaker 0: They seem to be popular already.
Speaker 0: People are said that's how things go.
Speaker 0: So what I say to you is if you like our board game reviews You should check this out and send these to the people, you know, who are too dumb to listen to podcasts.
Speaker 0: I Think that's it.
Speaker 0: We can talk about the dragon show Dragon.
Speaker 0: yeah, I've been watching other anime which Scott hasn't and I'm not watching yo a pedal.
Speaker 1: I'm like a pedal.
Speaker 0: I think I'm.
Speaker 0: uh, I don't have anything else to say about yo a paddle It's nothing.
Speaker 1: there's nothing new to say.
Speaker 1: It's just more of the same.
Speaker 0: I mean, it's like Initial D Like I didn't even watch all of initially.
Speaker 0: I kind of stopped around fourth stage.
Speaker 0: It's just kept going and stop.
Speaker 0: Karen Pons are really good, but you haven't watched any of that stuff.
Speaker 1: So anyway, it's Dragon Maid show.
Speaker 1: So everyone was talking about the Dragon Maid show.
Speaker 1: we got mentioned to me by like multiple people.
Speaker 0: it filled my Twitter feed like to a degree that I was shocked by Like.
Speaker 0: I just out of nowhere for like a week nothing with dragons in my Twitter feed and Then it went away.
Speaker 0: and actually as of now the thing that's filling my Twitter feed is that kimono friend show.
Speaker 1: I don't know what that is.
Speaker 0: But anyway, that's animal people, but it's kind of like a dameko dobe.
Speaker 0: It's the one that we.
Speaker 1: that's a good thing.
Speaker 0: It's the thing that we assumed doing Judge anime by its cover.
Speaker 0: that it was gonna be a worse version of dameko dobutsu.
Speaker 1: is it so?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: But it has got some Twitter staying power and a lot of people are saying no It looks low production value and not that good but stick with it a few episodes and everyone's like flipping out about this show.
Speaker 1: So anyway, Dragon Maid.
Speaker 1: I heard about Dragon Maid from multiple people.
Speaker 1: So I said well ice multiple people have said something and friends are coming over.
Speaker 1: So let's watch this thing because Natalie was already way into it and Judith hadn't seen any.
Speaker 0: so yep I mean I were like, well, I like dragons.
Speaker 1: We watched every episode that was on crunchyroll.
Speaker 1: so the first thing about the show is it's made by the same studio that made lucky star and a bunch of garbage and The show is just like every other show that they've made Right, so
Speaker 0: Now I really I do like lucky star but that that those kinds of shows are not forever.
Speaker 0: Those are the kinds of shows like Excel saga where your friend who's away.
Speaker 1: This isn't as crazy as that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but your friend is way into anime tries to get you to watch it But yet it's really only for people who are way in and it is deaf.
Speaker 0: This show is definitely for only people who are into anime first of all, but this this show Kobayashi So, you know made a dragon is for people who are into monster girls Moe but like edging into moe not like not like current moe.
Speaker 0: This is like it's like one step away from getting into the creepy stuff.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and you also are in The girl the tiny girl dragon, yeah, but at least as far as I only watched the first four episodes they haven't gone.
Speaker 1: So I don't wanna say the show is bad.
Speaker 1: Right because it's like it's.
Speaker 0: it's good enough to where like.
Speaker 0: I kept watching it I didn't.
Speaker 1: it's a. I watched it because that's what we were doing.
Speaker 1: I wouldn't I wouldn't personally wouldn't have gone past episode like two.
Speaker 1: But like it's good at what it is is but what it is is not a thing.
Speaker 1: I want.
Speaker 1: Yeah It's.
Speaker 1: it's like there are some funny bits.
Speaker 1: for example There's the evil dragon guy fat after and it's like he is a funny.
Speaker 1: is his character is a funny joke, right?
Speaker 1: He's an evil dragon.
Speaker 0: He's dark and you know He wants to like in the first episode where she calls him for advice and he's just like kill all the human kill all Who see your treasure trust?
Speaker 0: No one kill?
Speaker 1: It's like he is a play likes to play video games.
Speaker 1: It's like that's a funny character, but that joke gets old.
Speaker 1: It's only funny like two times and then he's not funny anymore.
Speaker 1: He's just did right and there's a lot of boobs and stuff which it's like.
Speaker 1: at my limit of tolerance for boobiness.
Speaker 0: I'm like, alright, it's definitely at the limit like it's at.
Speaker 1: it's like if there's any more fan service I would like burn this with fire, but it's like.
Speaker 1: alright, that's the most fan service I can take without hurting.
Speaker 0: so on one hand it is refreshing that it's two girls But on the other hand it is.
Speaker 0: it is definitely at least 50% male gazey.
Speaker 1: Yeah It's not.
Speaker 1: there is the thing right?
Speaker 1: It would be cool.
Speaker 1: It's cool that it's like a lesbian action right the female dragon and the female human.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I like how she is like.
Speaker 0: the normal girl is kind of just like this nerdy programmer normal person, right?
Speaker 1: The problem is is they at least in the five episodes worth they don't make it explicit, right?
Speaker 1: It's like just the dragon girl is obviously all over the regular girl.
Speaker 1: There's nothing on explicit about that, but the regular girl is not Reciprocating in any way other than allowing allowing her to live in the house.
Speaker 0: She holds your hand a little bit.
Speaker 0: She puts up with their crap when he's holding the hand.
Speaker 1: It's not like who holding the hand like my love story.
Speaker 1: It's holding the hand like come with me.
Speaker 1: Stop messing around.
Speaker 0: They're just really good friends, right?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I mean think if we haven't seen not like I don't know where it goes I don't know if it has like an explicit end, but it's like it's got a They had in order to make that like, you know excusable.
Speaker 1: they got across that line.
Speaker 1: Okay, I will give you the credit now that you you know, set it out loud But if you just sort of keep it on the down-low You're basically, you know, just leaving it for male gaziness and I can't give you credit just for pretending or alluding to Right some Yuri.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you gotta give me you gotta actually give Yuri or you don't get credit for it.
Speaker 0: So there seems to also be an undercurrent.
Speaker 0: I'm looking at kind of what's coming up down the show and also I guess it was better There's some manga that I can look at.
Speaker 0: I'm sure there see where it's going.
Speaker 0: It seems like there is actually a plot around dragons Hiding the dragon world.
Speaker 0: There's some sort of war among the dragons and some nonsense going on.
Speaker 0: So bit by bit these dragons get attracted here, but it might go somewhere.
Speaker 1: Thank you for mentioning the best part of this show.
Speaker 1: much like fancy Lala which has a plot about dinosaurs Dragon maid has a plot about dragons.
Speaker 1: They alert to it showing you that like when the dragon met the maid like she was dying Sort of like Excalibur this big-ass awesome sword stabbed in her and she was wounded and she got healed.
Speaker 1: and she doesn't want to Go back to the dragon world.
Speaker 1: and the dragon world is fully humans, you know magic and fight with dragons and dude.
Speaker 1: Why did you make this garbage show?
Speaker 1: You could have just given me a show about that dragon world a fantasy show and cut out all this maid bullshit.
Speaker 0: if season two were the Dragons come and fuck up this world or You just give me the oh, I'll go back to the other world.
Speaker 1: It's like.
Speaker 1: all I care about is the stuff happening in the fantasy world with the Wizards the Knights and the actual Dragon form dragons breathing fire on them.
Speaker 1: if that was 90% of the show I would watch that.
Speaker 1: but it's only like 1% of this show and that's the part that's like.
Speaker 1: Oh, it's like just give me tidbits of the good stuff.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: It's like someone else is watching the show thinking Oh, man, the boobs are the good stuff.
Speaker 1: No I don't care about that sword business and that's a person who I should take a sword to Get you an anime that can do both.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but this doesn't do both.
Speaker 1: It just pretends to do what right?
Speaker 1: It's like if it did even half the show was about the other dragon world.
Speaker 1: Yeah I'd be down.
Speaker 1: But it's like you get one second if you're lucky of other dragon world in each episode.
Speaker 1: now on the other hand that does and I don't Got I don't got time for that.
Speaker 1: I could just watch an actual fantasy anime.
Speaker 0: Well like dragon half if you if you want dragon girl, I guess layers again.
Speaker 0: Yeah Well, you've never seen the slayers.
Speaker 0: that actually has dragons in it.
Speaker 1: I could I could watch that instead of dragon.
Speaker 1: Actually, I'll be a great choice.
Speaker 0: We should cuz you me and Emily cuz.
Speaker 0: you guys had never seen slayers next and remember.
Speaker 0: so we watched it.
Speaker 0: I've got all of Laura's DVDs still of slayers try which is the next season.
Speaker 1: Let's watch that.
Speaker 0: then you know, the plot is dragon slave the plot of slayers.
Speaker 1: try it kind of like what I try to do.
Speaker 0: Uh, so you find out that for all of slayers up to this point the world they're in There's an edge to it and it seems like it's been surrounded by this magic shield.
Speaker 0: No one can get in or out and the shield suddenly disappears and people fall off the edge.
Speaker 0: Nope, so Lena and all them are like let's fucking go out there in a boat and see what's out there.
Speaker 1: Oh, it's water outside.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and you know what's out there?
Speaker 1: more land.
Speaker 0: Nobody knows magic and everyone's wet mad week.
Speaker 0: Okay, so they're like super powerful and there's dragon plots and stuff.
Speaker 1: No, but the dragons out there.
Speaker 0: Well, there are two dragons who are just in the party.
Speaker 1: Oh, okay.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I Do.
Speaker 0: I do also like how God she's kind of just like Toru is just kind of like big and fat and like weird Dragon derp with her magic powers the business almost gooster.
Speaker 0: Oh, no, I'm talking about mr.
Speaker 0: Coby.
Speaker 0: I went back to Kobayashi's dragon maid.
Speaker 1: Oh, that's Layers that show can use some summer goose.
Speaker 0: They're also kind of Derpy and bubbling bulbous in some sense.
Speaker 0: All right No, we will do that's lovely.
Speaker 0: the next big show.
Speaker 0: watch watch us let's try.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm We'll do a review of it at some point.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm, but I guess think that what makes this show Tolerable is that the joke isn't just oh my god She's a dragon.
Speaker 0: it gets a little like it keeps changing up a little bit.
Speaker 0: it usually seems to center around like like remember when they go to the park to play and It turned.
Speaker 0: basically they're shocked that she doesn't have any powers and they really really overestimate humans at every step of the way Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's a cute light-hearted show about dragon girls and some other character.
Speaker 0: Let's see There's.
Speaker 1: it's not an anime to run screaming from.
Speaker 1: it's an anime to watch if you like this sort of thing Or if you've already watched all the other animes and you want to watch another anime.
Speaker 0: It's like a light-hearted thing to watch while you're eating dinner, but it's not something you're gonna shotgun through like Gundam seed.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I know.
Speaker 1: I don't need to watch more than the five episodes.
Speaker 1: I already watched like.
Speaker 0: here's a picture of tours father.
Speaker 0: Oh Yeah, goblin a bunch of monsters Catch the kawaddle.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I Don't know if exactly where the show goes.
Speaker 0: I just know that according to the manga I don't care other than the higher plot.
Speaker 1: Just tell me what the actual plot is.
Speaker 1: I don't need to watch this.
Speaker 0: something about chaos Dragons as far as I can tell.
Speaker 1: Why is it too?
Speaker 1: It should be way simpler than that.
Speaker 0: I think there's two dragon factions.
Speaker 1: Okay?
Speaker 0: That's all I know.
Speaker 0: there are two dragon factions.
Speaker 1: all the dragons we've met so far are in the same faction.
Speaker 0: Oh, no.
Speaker 0: No, so Elma belongs to the order faction the rival to toru's chaos faction.
Speaker 0: Elma's the kid one, uh Snow kana is the kid one.
Speaker 0: Okay You've already lost all the hair.
Speaker 1: I don't care.
Speaker 0: You don't care.
Speaker 0: You lost it.
Speaker 0: You're done.
Speaker 0: I'm Okay This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat Lee for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 1: be sure to visit our website at front row crew.com For show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 0: remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 1: But unlike those other late shows It's actually recorded at night.
Speaker 0: and the patreon patrons for this episode of geek nights and order the amount of money They give us on a continuing basis.
Speaker 0: Ah Alan Joyce Rebecca Dunn Nicholas Brando Heidi McNichol Amanda Duchette.
Speaker 0: Great job.
Speaker 0: Emoji IP fame.
Speaker 0: I say do I come William I suppose Jeremy water.
Speaker 0: Well, tomato hasn't always been this glam.
Speaker 0: I was a drab little crab.
Speaker 0: Oh Chris Reimer and Thomas on Christian coots Marge is what brings us together today.
Speaker 0: much that blessed arrangement Sure, but horror.
Speaker 0: rarely.
Speaker 0: Val James David White Rochelle, Monta, Nona Superboy.
Speaker 0: I paid five bucks to make rims say baboon Brian Fisher sailor Vista Matthew Smith Don Schleich.
Speaker 0: chart option George George our Tyler Eller Shawn.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you're Sam Cordray Clinton Walton Ren from New Zealand.
Speaker 0: Ryan parent drew open letter.
Speaker 0: Brian's the droney a rodent of unusual size redacted.
Speaker 0: Chris mid give Chris Knox Daniel Redmond Sean Klein Chris Reimer and Thomas Hahn.
Speaker 0: Yep geek nights continues.
Speaker 0: I got nothing particularly inspiring to say right now.
Speaker 0: Now I leave you with something from the princess bride.
Speaker 0: Now marriage marriage is what brings us together today.
Speaker 0: With So treasure you're one.
Speaker 0: skip to the end.
Speaker 0: have you over the wing.
Speaker 1: here comes my Wesley now.