Speaker 0: It's Thursday, June 8th, 2017.
Speaker 0: I'm rim.
Speaker 1: That's good.
Speaker 0: And this is geek nights tonight.
Speaker 0: barbecue Let's do this And I suppose to a lesser extent just grilling because I feel like a lot of people say barbecue when they mean just Literally cooking anything on a grill not the same thing, which isn't even a barbecue.
Speaker 0: I guess.
Speaker 1: Yeah Gonna get mad at people saying About you and they mean Teppanyaki.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: That's why I don't get mad.
Speaker 0: I usually pointed out.
Speaker 0: then I laugh.
Speaker 0: but the problem is I can't call it Teppanyaki because no one will know what the fuck I'm Talking about except in like.
Speaker 0: well actually anywhere but the u.s.
Speaker 0: It's fine.
Speaker 0: So Remember we were in Melbourne and we just googled for what is the best Teppanyaki place in the entire city and we just ate there Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: That was a lot of money Yeah, but it was more money than I had budgeted for in terms of like eating on that trip because I was not a cheap All told.
Speaker 0: but What's crazy is that round-trip flights now cost like a fifth what we paid back then.
Speaker 1: cuz no one wants to fly.
Speaker 0: Well, but so Australia is super cheap But like going to Tokyo not any cheaper for some reason like it's way more expensive.
Speaker 0: go to Tokyo then go to see wanna go There.
Speaker 1: people want to go to Australia - not as much as they want to go to Tokyo.
Speaker 0: But why is it so much cheaper?
Speaker 0: There's so many people going to Australia Back.
Speaker 0: when we went to that first pack saws it just aren't going now like I don't know what's going on.
Speaker 0: Anyway, it's a Thursday.
Speaker 0: It's the lounge on geek nights here.
Speaker 0: We can talk about whatever we want and If you're hearing this new from me right now You are so late to the party that you might as well start looking at PAX West 2018.
Speaker 1: I guess I got some badges.
Speaker 0: you can have your money, so this happens every year and All of all the packs is packs East and packs West are Equally difficult for different reasons.
Speaker 0: packs West is difficult because it is the mothership packs.
Speaker 0: People from all over the world try to get in and as best I can tell you have About two to two point five minutes between when the packs account tweets that badges are live.
Speaker 0: It's not a lot of minutes before the last person enters that queue.
Speaker 0: Who will then buy the last badges at least the last Saturday one?
Speaker 1: I think you can still buy a Monday one.
Speaker 0: There are a small hours.
Speaker 1: It's been hours, and you can still buy a Monday one.
Speaker 0: There is a small number of Monday badges left.
Speaker 1: a lot of people just go there even though Monday's Labor Day They're buying Friday Saturday Sunday badges, and they're not buying Monday's.
Speaker 0: yep I mean I want all four if I'm flying somewhere.
Speaker 0: I'm going to the fullness of the convention.
Speaker 0: That's just kind of high local types.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the thing is I feel like I mean I've heard you're missing that omega-thon finale.
Speaker 1: What's wrong with you?
Speaker 0: Because there's only one of me.
Speaker 0: like they try to replicate the content like there's two Q&A's so like there's more chance to see In both, but the omega-thon nothing gets replicated.
Speaker 0: There's just round round round round tournament and The omega-thon finale is one of my favorite parts of packs, and it's been so consistently, but yeah anyway Yeah, I clicked on the link within like 30 seconds.
Speaker 0: I was sitting at work.
Speaker 0: I had the alert set up for a while.
Speaker 1: Tyco tweeted He's like hey guys You know you can pre buy that you can buy this merch when the tickets go on sale whenever that is.
Speaker 1: and I'm like yeah I was like all right.
Speaker 1: We're on high alert right?
Speaker 1: so I go into the forum like hey everyone remember We're on a high alert and then like a minute later the tweet dang click.
Speaker 0: No, I saw his tweet and for a second I was like that's nice.
Speaker 0: and then the lizard part of my brain said rim you got to start from hitting fucking f5 as fast as you can.
Speaker 0: uh But at PAX East the badges don't sell out quite as fast.
Speaker 0: you have like Dozens of minutes before the main ones sell out.
Speaker 0: not a lot of minutes But yeah dozens of minutes is not a long time when you think about it.
Speaker 0: But the hotels that don't require mass transit or a cab they sell out in seconds.
Speaker 0: They're basically sold out before the badges go on sale because you know exhibitors can buy their better.
Speaker 0: We should you know if PAX ever gets bad enough.
Speaker 0: We got money.
Speaker 0: We should buy.
Speaker 1: It's a million times.
Speaker 1: you're not saying anything new.
Speaker 1: the point is today was the day for PAX OS 2017 tickets.
Speaker 1: I got four full sets of tickets the maximum allowed Ticket purchase.
Speaker 1: the price went way up.
Speaker 1: it cost like $700.
Speaker 1: yep But I'm not using all these.
Speaker 1: so user for friends and in case our panel doesn't get accepted.
Speaker 1: So yeah holding back a set the rule.
Speaker 0: the reality is If you're going to kind of like packs you need to have a pool of friends who are all going and you need to together Coordinate.
Speaker 0: because of our friend group not everyone got into the queue in time to buy badges.
Speaker 0: Enough of us did to get badges for all of.
Speaker 1: so whoever needs the badges you gotta let me know Cuz I need to pay back this money's cuz I cannot And we don't want to scalp them.
Speaker 0: we basically just want to sell them at cost to.
Speaker 1: like a friend I only bought them for insurance purposes in case our panels not accepted and such like that I have.
Speaker 1: no you know I want them to go to someone who's gonna go to PAX and I don't want to put in a lot of effort Trying to find someone who will buy them.
Speaker 1: So it's the face value.
Speaker 0: not hard to do that.
Speaker 1: for PAX West the past one year I just sort of like met people on the street outside packs that I arranged with at the packs pass exchange Reddit whatever.
Speaker 0: also, you know, I'll be in town because packs dev.
Speaker 0: there is some interesting though Thanks dev is actually a day earlier than usual.
Speaker 0: So there's a gap day between dev and Wes.
Speaker 0: So I had I would stay in town basically an extra day But something crazy happened when I clicked on the thing because I went straight hotel and Scott went badge.
Speaker 0: The Sheraton showed up as not booked which is insane.
Speaker 0: The Sheraton traditionally is 100% booked long before badges go on sale.
Speaker 0: Like you just cannot be in that hotel.
Speaker 0: It used to be the hotel that like everyone stayed in every year because it's the one connected to the convention center.
Speaker 0: It's like right there.
Speaker 0: So, uh, I see it I click on it and it totally has a room.
Speaker 0: like there are rooms available.
Speaker 0: so I like Immediately as phallic.
Speaker 0: I'm like, oh shit I start typing my credit card stuff in.
Speaker 0: I hit submit maybe 15 seconds later and I get an error saying the room you're trying to book was booked by someone else before that website Transacted bad website and then it says but click.
Speaker 0: because it says click here to try a different hotel.
Speaker 0: I click there and it says oh your session took too long You got to start over and then it just showed me an error that went forever.
Speaker 0: Every time I went back to the site with that web browser It was stuck.
Speaker 0: I used a different.
Speaker 0: I went in incognito mode and I got back in and By that point all the hotels were booked and I found one at the last second and I got a hotel room.
Speaker 0: The real problem was there were no rooms available at most of the hotels for the gap day between dev and West Mmm, and you can't book two rooms.
Speaker 0: So if you're going to dev you were basically fucked unless you picked like the two hotels That had rooms on that.
Speaker 1: one day you can go through the system book goes to the system and book again.
Speaker 0: I tried that once years ago.
Speaker 0: In fact, remember, you know when I tried to do it?
Speaker 0: remember when we bought John St John a hotel room.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah that time.
Speaker 0: So when I tried to book the second one the system said you already have a PAX room.
Speaker 0: Fuck you You can't get to you scalper piece of shit.
Speaker 1: use a different.
Speaker 0: you can't scalp a hotel room first of all Yeah, but it basically said you're only allowed to have one.
Speaker 1: just you use a different name use it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I've used different name email letters everything.
Speaker 0: So all I did back then is I just booked directly at the hotel.
Speaker 0: max cuz.
Speaker 0: frankly I love John But I didn't care if he stayed further away from packs.
Speaker 1: So but anyway each one full set of packs passes this year.
Speaker 1: They're $48 per day.
Speaker 1: Yeah $192 for a full set and then on top and there's a $10 fee.
Speaker 1: that applies to the whole transaction.
Speaker 1: So if you want to go to a day of packs to all the facts West it will cost you 192 dollars.
Speaker 0: Yep going to change go into the single day badges was partly a ploy to Substantially raise the price of packs without saying they raised the price of packs.
Speaker 0: That's something that happened.
Speaker 1: Yeah, cuz look the price to get into packs to enjoy packs is 48 dollars.
Speaker 1: You just want to experience packs as totally reasonable before it's like.
Speaker 1: well weekend passes are pretty much all anyone's buying.
Speaker 1: So the price to get into packs is to buy.
Speaker 1: one of those is like, you know a hundred and something dollars Yeah, but so, uh, yeah, we'll see.
Speaker 0: There's rumors of other packs.
Speaker 0: is like pax East also becoming four days at some point and see we'll see if that happens.
Speaker 0: that adds That adds to my enforcing burden at pax East but it also means pax East could be a little more chill anyway If you don't already have a fax badge.
Speaker 0: You missed it so hard.
Speaker 0: I don't know what to say to you.
Speaker 1: Hope you got $192.
Speaker 0: yep, send it my way and be ready because magfest is gonna have the exact same problem Like any nerd con that's good is gonna have this problem.
Speaker 0: There's no way around this.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: So you got any news?
Speaker 1: I do have a news.
Speaker 1: a chick take this out.
Speaker 1: It's kind of weird, right and I'm still I'm you know, not being Super hyper educated in this area.
Speaker 1: I got a lot of questions that no one ever answered, right?
Speaker 0: So I'm not gonna pretend I'll pretend that I know the answers but I really don't.
Speaker 1: we all know.
Speaker 1: yeah, of course You'll pretend you know the answer.
Speaker 1: That's what you do for everything.
Speaker 1: So we all know you find fossils and all kinds of places usually in rocks, right?
Speaker 0: But also in precious amber, which I think most of our generation learned that from Jurassic Park, right?
Speaker 1: So anyway some scientists Where was this?
Speaker 1: like Burma or something like that?
Speaker 1: or somewhere far away Malaysia something something.
Speaker 0: I didn't read this order.
Speaker 0: I actually don't know about this news.
Speaker 1: Yeah the location I don't remember but basically they found an almost completely intact bird and I not like a skeleton of a bird like actual bird like its head Part of its wing its feats a lot of skin Right.
Speaker 1: That's some biz Like actual, you know, and it was in amber.
Speaker 1: So oh, yeah Burma's Burmese amber I guess.
Speaker 1: does Burmese amber mean it's in Burma?
Speaker 1: or does Burmese amber that the type of amber that could be in places that aren't?
Speaker 0: I don't even know enough to pretend that I know the answer to that.
Speaker 1: Anyway, the point is this shit is 99 million year old bird.
Speaker 1: This is a bird that lived with dinosaurs.
Speaker 0: Oh, man.
Speaker 0: Look at the reconstruction.
Speaker 0: It's a cute little guy Yeah, so stubby tail thing-a-ling.
Speaker 1: But yeah, he's uh in this amber and they got him.
Speaker 1: They can't get any DNA's from there.
Speaker 1: Apparently they say but you can still learn a hell of a lot Because usually a fossil is a skeleton or an outline of a shape.
Speaker 1: Right, so this is like hope pretty holy shit right here.
Speaker 1: the questions I have is I don't really understand how amber works.
Speaker 0: You know, what amber is?
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's just like tree juice tree sap, right?
Speaker 1: So here's the thing though.
Speaker 1: If you got imagine a tree with some sap.
Speaker 1: right tree sap is thick and slow.
Speaker 1: How does a bird?
Speaker 1: Get into trees?
Speaker 1: have that deep?
Speaker 1: I had to be like the dumbest bird and how does there had to be like a bowl full of trees?
Speaker 1: have somewhere like so much Of it.
Speaker 0: I've seen trees that have so much crazy thick like sap coming out of them Pooling around them.
Speaker 0: I think most of the fossils in amber there are a little tiny guys.
Speaker 1: This is a pretty tiny guy, you know, if you look at that, there's a coin next to the picture of the amber.
Speaker 1: it's pretty small, but it's like.
Speaker 1: How do you mean insects getting stuck in the amber makes sense, right?
Speaker 1: Maybe a leaf getting stuck in the amber makes sense, but even a small bird getting stuck in there to this extent.
Speaker 1: It's like It's like if I got caught in a race by a sloth, it's like it makes.
Speaker 1: it doesn't make any sense.
Speaker 0: I think a lot of them I would guess are Animals that died and fell somewhere where they got stuck in amber, but the amber doesn't flow like a river Does just real slow.
Speaker 1: the bird would decompose a lot by the time the amber covered that much of it.
Speaker 1: I guess this is just the random chance, right?
Speaker 1: That's why we haven't found these.
Speaker 0: I was googling to try to like find like a succinct explanation of this and Mostly what I'm finding are web pages that have bad backgrounds and bad fonts, which is always a bad sign when you're googling for something.
Speaker 0: Yep, so I don't actually know and I can't answer it without pausing the show long enough to read one of these things.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but like I just you know Like I know that things were trapped in amber and once you're trapped in there it gets hard and is preserved for a long time.
Speaker 0: I get the impression that anything I think anything large that gets trapped in amber is a fluke and it's just.
Speaker 0: there's so much history that like There's some place where an entire bird's nest fell in some amber and I got a bunch of birds.
Speaker 1: It's like I couldn't possibly get stuck in an amber.
Speaker 1: I just had to wash my hands a little bit.
Speaker 0: I could get you stuck in some amber.
Speaker 1: How much amber are you gonna get?
Speaker 0: What if I tie you up and just like tie you to a really sappy tree and leave you there?
Speaker 1: How long it would take.
Speaker 1: I would probably just give you even if someone rescued me weeks later if I wasn't dead from Dying of dehydration or lack of food or exposure or something.
Speaker 1: I could probably just peel myself off.
Speaker 0: I don't know depends on a male Like.
Speaker 0: I'd have to tie you up pretty tight.
Speaker 0: just let the amber wash over.
Speaker 0: let the sap wash over you Uh-huh.
Speaker 0: I uh, yeah, all these websites have bad fonts?
Speaker 0: I can't.
Speaker 0: I don't actually know the answer to that question, but I like that little birdie.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's interesting stuff.
Speaker 0: There's some really actually interesting Political news from over in the UK.
Speaker 0: So, you know their elections happening.
Speaker 1: Well, they have elections whenever they want.
Speaker 1: They don't have an election day.
Speaker 0: They just dissolve their government when they give up Normal times have elections and there's ways to call for elections I'm not gonna explain like the UK parliamentary process because it's but it is.
Speaker 1: this is a called for.
Speaker 1: this is a Government.
Speaker 0: the way I'll put it is the.
Speaker 0: a Conservative government came in partly on the heels of brexit and brexit likely happened for a lot of the same reasons that Trump happened in the US.
Speaker 0: So this happened and the conservative government that had a very like narrow Stranglehold on power called for early elections thinking that they could ride this wave and totally take over the government.
Speaker 0: and what appears to have Happened is that I thought it's not counted yet.
Speaker 0: So exit polls are done.
Speaker 0: Exit polls are usually real accurate usually so the exit polls Heavily imply that at best.
Speaker 0: It's a hung parliament meaning.
Speaker 1: Doesn't that mean they need to have another election?
Speaker 0: I know it means that no party has a complete majority and anyone who wants to do anything has to do it in coalition with At least one other party.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: This has some if this is a the read on this is that America is fucked up so much shit since Trump got elected that The forces that were similar to the things that caused Trump to get elected in the US in places like the UK Kind of slammed on the brakes and there's been sort of a regression to the mean or a reaction back toward the left.
Speaker 0: So it's almost like the.
Speaker 0: the bad politics in the US Scared all the dumb people who are you know?
Speaker 0: So-called undecided voters and people who call themselves centrists Into not voting for crazy people.
Speaker 1: That's how that's how democracies have worked for decades, right?
Speaker 1: You see whoever's in power.
Speaker 1: you hate them because you see all them fucking up shit.
Speaker 1: So you're mad at them and you vote for the other guy.
Speaker 1: the other guy gets in power, but they're shitty, too.
Speaker 1: So you're mad at them.
Speaker 1: so you vote for the other guy.
Speaker 1: The other guy is just the first guy.
Speaker 1: you forgot that you hated them because it was so long ago They fucked it up.
Speaker 0: So you vote for the other guy and we've been doing that for like longer than I've been alive But then we broke and voted for like So bad that you don't even know what to do like.
Speaker 0: I mean like our president literally didn't know.
Speaker 0: we have an airbase in Qatar and I mean Do you know where every base is?
Speaker 1: Hmm?
Speaker 1: Do you know where every single base is?
Speaker 0: No, but yeah, everyone knows there's a base in Qatar because it's in the news all the time cuz shit happens.
Speaker 1: Yeah, yeah, I know we have base in Germany in Korea more than one there in Japan.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's true.
Speaker 0: Okay But it's all the exit polls.
Speaker 0: This is actually pretty big news in that it has potential Substantial ramifications for whether or not brexit goes forward.
Speaker 0: We'll see how this all goes.
Speaker 0: The problem is Now it's a hurry up and wait situation because until they actually count the vote which probably won't be done tonight All we have is these I can't they be done tonight with voting.
Speaker 1: We don't take that long to.
Speaker 0: yeah We do.
Speaker 0: we don't actually finish counting the vote for a long time.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but we know what the deal is like, yeah, well partly on enough of them Every.
Speaker 1: how are they voting in the UK with like signal flags?
Speaker 0: I Don't actually know what they do.
Speaker 0: I'm like what kinds of voting machines they use or whatever.
Speaker 0: But this is sort of developing news and even if you don't know anything or care about politics You probably see what's going on in the UK because it'll depress you a lot less than what's going on in the US and a hung parliament might actually be pretty funny and interesting going forward.
Speaker 0: because imagine if that happened in the u.s.
Speaker 0: If instead of just like a swing of either The normal party gets it or the crazy party gets it It would be if you're too close to a 50/50 split then nobody gets anything and the government's just paralyzed for another four years.
Speaker 1: Well, they can just have another election whenever they want and I Rules about what they can't.
Speaker 0: she can't just like immediately call the election right after this one.
Speaker 0: Also, it's still technically a monarchy the Queen can just shut the whole shit down Yeah, but not really because the monarch the monarchy ceded a lot of powers to the parliamentary system.
Speaker 1: take him back.
Speaker 1: Good to be the king queen.
Speaker 1: Yeah king queen Whatever you are.
Speaker 0: Well, I mean it could be weird like, you know, you know Francis system works.
Speaker 0: There's no king of France anymore, but there is both a president and a prime minister, but the president is just like a Person who doesn't do anything Symbolic figure a lot like a US president and the Prime Minister is more like the president of the Congress.
Speaker 0: Anyway, this stuff's all fascinating the Parliament.
Speaker 1: They don't have a kind.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well I said the Congress so I'm trying to analogize it back to what the u.s Is like.
Speaker 0: imagine if we had a president president for like war and like as one narrow area of stuff.
Speaker 0: Then we had another president who like was basically the head of Congress and like represented Congress.
Speaker 0: We kind of have that with the majority leaders But I don't know.
Speaker 0: our government is like the weirdest most complicated version of democracy in the world.
Speaker 1: It's because ours isn't old.
Speaker 1: see as though the u.s.
Speaker 1: Is much younger.
Speaker 0: Ours is the oldest because their constitutional monarchies are.
Speaker 1: we're in many ways pretty democratic long before the u.s Pretty but they weren't like having everyone vote The way we were.
Speaker 0: I'd see what about Athens.
Speaker 1: Athens wasn't around.
Speaker 1: it doesn't exist anymore.
Speaker 1: I'm talking about the oldest one the oldest Democracy that still exists.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 1: Okay that I mean, I guess Greece has voting now, but It's not the same.
Speaker 1: It's not.
Speaker 1: it wasn't a clean line from Athens to the current Greece.
Speaker 1: It's not the same.
Speaker 1: Anyway.
Speaker 0: So speaking of hotels.
Speaker 0: this news been making the rounds everywhere and I've been I've been looking thinking about it a lot in the sense That the hotel industry is having a lot of problems partly because People like us Airbnb.
Speaker 0: Yeah, Airbnb is one problem.
Speaker 0: The other problem is that people like us much like with flights don't really give a shit where we stay.
Speaker 0: We just want to be close to the thing we're doing.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: We're not flexible.
Speaker 0: Like we're going this weekend We literally we are not willing to show up a day earlier.
Speaker 0: We're not willing to show up a day Later, we have a very specific window.
Speaker 0: We want to go anywhere.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm Our only real concern is being as close to the thing we're doing as possible and not having bedbugs.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: So Hotels really can't compete with each other with our prices generation other than on price.
Speaker 0: Remove proximity.
Speaker 1: stop offering all the services that no one uses.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the problem is those services are probably the only way they actually make money and if they don't offer those services They probably just raise their.
Speaker 1: for example, do you have a room service that delivers like $5 eggs to people, right?
Speaker 1: No one's stupid enough to buy five people are.
Speaker 1: well, listen, you're mad at packs.
Speaker 0: You know how many of those trays I see sitting out of people's rooms rich people I don't think.
Speaker 0: I think it's packs people who are just dumb.
Speaker 1: I know the point is if you get if you're selling five dollar eggs and a lot of people buy them you're raking in big Cash.
Speaker 1: and if you're selling final eggs and no one's buying them, you should just close your goddamn kitchen.
Speaker 1: Yeah Well the funniest thing is still sell the $5 eggs and just buy the eggs from like the nearby deli.
Speaker 0: What hurt the most was smartphones been tablets because suddenly people had internet that just worked on their phones.
Speaker 0: They didn't need to pay like 20 bucks a day for internet from the hotel.
Speaker 1: Give me free internet and I might choose your hotel over the one that does not free.
Speaker 1: I say that if I if I have a choice, I've literally never checked.
Speaker 1: Well, because I usually don't have a choice.
Speaker 0: and that first room wherever I can Yeah, that first packs went to you back in a way where stuff didn't sell out.
Speaker 0: The red line was like hey if you stay here and you're going to packs for your Wi-Fi They gave us like a little like tax thing and everything when we checked in back in.
Speaker 0: Oh eight Which was like almost a decade ago.
Speaker 1: I also.
Speaker 1: if I'm choosing a hotel to host an event then I'm gonna be very choosy Yep, but what's hurting hotels?
Speaker 0: what hurt hotels then?
Speaker 0: the biggest thing was that businessmen didn't pay for porn anymore.
Speaker 0: No on the TV networks.
Speaker 0: what's killing them now is that pretty much everyone just books hotels either by going to like Google Maps or like a kayak or something and Just typing in their dates and looking at a list of hotels and pick up what everyone's cheap.
Speaker 1: Same thing we do with airline.
Speaker 0: Yep, except those services for hotels Take a way bigger cut than the airline ones do.
Speaker 1: Oh, they're taking a cut from the hotel.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they take up to 30% according to this article.
Speaker 1: Listen if you want to the hotel should do what the airline does make the room smaller have more rooms.
Speaker 0: So Actually, I would say I would stay in like a capsule hotel if it existed.
Speaker 0: Why not convention?
Speaker 0: because I'm pretty much only.
Speaker 1: I just need a place to put my stuff a place to sleep and a shower.
Speaker 1: I don't need any of the other stuff and I don't use the TV Our outlets to charge my business.
Speaker 0: Antonio uses giant-ass living rooms in the Contessa to play our RPGs because it's quiet Yeah, but you can just if it's a capsule hotel.
Speaker 1: you have you know You know this shared as a shower room and there's a room of you know, tables and you know Common area.
Speaker 0: you imagine how lit a capsule hotel would be at a place like PAX everyone in their little capsule with their switch At night.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: Yeah good times.
Speaker 0: but so this is an article kind of talking about that.
Speaker 0: because uh, I think the hotel industry is gonna go through like a major.
Speaker 0: they're fucked Situation in the next few years.
Speaker 1: buy some cheap hotel and capsule it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the problem actually the.
Speaker 0: so I looked into that like a decade ago and Hotel into why there weren't capsule hotels like in the u.s.
Speaker 0: Laws.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the fire code in the u.s.
Speaker 0: Compared to the fire Japan's fire code as far as I can tell is actually way Way lax.
Speaker 0: I mean you can do some shit that would not fly in the u.s.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean the thing is, you know, Japan unlike the u.s.
Speaker 1: Is way old.
Speaker 0: as you're talking I feel like Japan trusted citizens to exit a building in an orderly fashion in a way that you could People use objects like the kotatsu in every home.
Speaker 0: Scott I was on a bus the last time I was there with Emily and we're going up into the mountains like go to the fancy Restaurant and the bus had its aisle down the middle and had two seats on each side like Rose, right?
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm in the aisle You could pull a thing out of any given seat pull it across entirely blocking the aisle and making another seat So you could turn the entire aisle into you into another set of seats.
Speaker 0: So like another 20 seats or another 40 seats Mm-hmm, that is that would be so illegal that you would go to jail in the u.s Yeah Sure.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I was just stare.
Speaker 0: the whole bus ride I was staring at it like marveling and I like.
Speaker 0: I use my thin internet connection to like Read articles and try to figure out like has that ever caused a disaster?
Speaker 0: Like is that killed people?
Speaker 1: Yeah Yeah, but I mean think about if you've got buildings that are so old and wooden that they're not gonna pass any fire code on Earth but you're not gonna destroy them because historic reasons and also you're not gonna stop using them because they're amazing and whatever.
Speaker 1: Why even bother having a fire code for your new bill?
Speaker 1: You know, it's like.
Speaker 1: well our whole place is already flammable and we're not changing it because we got more important reasons to not change it.
Speaker 0: So but here's what's real different about the hotel situation compared to Airlines and all the other industries is happening to a lot of castles burnt down.
Speaker 0: Airlines have some regulation.
Speaker 0: It's weak weak sauce regulation, but it is regulation where they can't.
Speaker 0: if they just bump you from a flight.
Speaker 0: There's some stuff they have to do to like make it up to you.
Speaker 0: to a degree Hotels can just bump you and give you the finger and you're just completely fucked.
Speaker 0: so what a lot of hotels apparently are starting to do is They'll take the bookings from these like these travel sites But if they fill up, they'll only bump the people who booked from the travel sites instead of the people who booked directly.
Speaker 0: Mmm, and that's happened to people I know a few times and I think it's gonna be a huge problem going forward.
Speaker 0: I bring this up illegal to sell something.
Speaker 1: You don't have yeah, I think period and no matter what business you're in I shouldn't be allowed to sell something if you don't have it.
Speaker 1: That includes kick-starting some product you haven't manufactured.
Speaker 0: I don't have.
Speaker 0: I just have to clear like I have to settle But I can totally put a seller and even if I don't own the stock
Speaker 1: You should you should have to buy it first and then sell it the tie the timing should be
Speaker 0: Chipped around well here with airlines and hotels specifically.
Speaker 0: I think there'd be a very there should be a very specific regulation.
Speaker 0: you can never bump anyone who does not volunteer and You just have to keep raising whatever Accommodation you're gonna offer until someone is willing to take the offer.
Speaker 0: If you have to give someone 50 grand before they say yeah, I'll go stay at another hotel that sucks That totally sucks for you.
Speaker 1: That's effectively the same as just preventing people because if that was the penalty if that was the rule People just wouldn't sell things they didn't have and thus the good.
Speaker 1: back to my room.
Speaker 0: I feel like airlines would because there are efficiencies to be had because a lot of I am always shocked whenever I fly and How many people miss their flights?
Speaker 0: Like every time I'm at the airport There's always like constant repeated calls for people who have checked in who may in fact be at the airport and yet somehow Are not at their gate and are not about to take off on the flight.
Speaker 0: I do not understand to this day how that happens.
Speaker 0: Who these people are like what?
Speaker 0: what happens in your life?
Speaker 0: that you're at the airport and you just like forget to go to your gate?
Speaker 0: but anyway things of the day.
Speaker 0: So this came up on the Tuesday show when I when we were kids both of us watched of an American show.
Speaker 0: It's like a big part of like 80s kid Americana.
Speaker 0: It was a show in America called unsolved mysteries With Robert Stack and I watched this throughout basically my entire childhood up until about high school.
Speaker 1: I only watched it like a few times when it was on and nothing else was on.
Speaker 0: see the thing is, you know I watched it a lot.
Speaker 0: It always happened because we went to our grandparents house like what our dad's definitely watch it at grandparents house at least a few times.
Speaker 0: It was always a grandma's house.
Speaker 1: That was definitely a show that grandparents wanted to watch
Speaker 0: because they were really into it and As a result, they'd always watch it and it was always on around like seven I want to say which is when we were there like after dinners We'd how
Speaker 1: much of old people now believing nonsense on the internet is due to nonsense on TV.
Speaker 0: Because of unsolved mysteries I was a hundred percent sure that aliens literally existed.
Speaker 1: I believed in aliens until like high school times because of all these stupid things on TV.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I was 100% convinced that certain kinds of ghosts existed.
Speaker 0: I was also convinced.
Speaker 1: I didn't believe in good.
Speaker 0: I was also convinced that a lot of the murderers that were featured on this show Totally were in the car next to us on the way home from grandma's and I need dad.
Speaker 0: No, I didn't believe that I was watching this when I was pretty young to be fair.
Speaker 0: I mean the show started.
Speaker 0: what in
Speaker 0: 86? 85?
Speaker 1: Oh alright The other reason I believe in aliens is not just based on TV, right?
Speaker 1: TV wasn't enough to convince me of anything on its own but because like I would look outside And see like, you know, the planes flying or whatever and I you know I'd be like, oh that's a plane cuz you'd see like, you know a white light and then the red light in the back Right, but then occasionally you'd see some lights flying around at night that weren't the same?
Speaker 0: Scott I live next to Selfridge Air National Guard Base fighter jets and nonsense.
Speaker 0: If you're doing bullshit up in the air all the time one time one time this is this isn't true, right?
Speaker 1: But obviously not alien.
Speaker 0: I got a similar story.
Speaker 1: I saw what looked like a plane.
Speaker 1: It was a white light and a red light that looked like they were attached to each other flying in the same direction Across the sky far away.
Speaker 1: No at night.
Speaker 1: I just saw two lights blinking white red You know.
Speaker 1: one was in the front one was in the back.
Speaker 1: So it looked like the red one was on the fin in the back, right?
Speaker 1: And the white one was in the front something like that, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, and he kept.
Speaker 1: it's just going across the sky halfway across the sky.
Speaker 1: The red one starts going down Like it like it looks like it dropped like someone like it was attached to something and someone threw it off the side of the plane.
Speaker 1: and the red ones going down like.
Speaker 1: And the white one's still going straight and I'm like I'm like what the fuck and that you know Things like that, you know, yep.
Speaker 1: Yeah noises you would hear in an old house.
Speaker 1: You'd be like, oh alien.
Speaker 0: Yeah Yeah, similar similar situation I saw.
Speaker 0: I've seen a bunch of weird things in the sky as a kid that at the time at least I was 100% sure it was either aliens or crazy government nonsense.
Speaker 1: I didn't believe in crazy government nonsense.
Speaker 1: Yeah, except for hiding aliens, which now I'm more convinced than ever They'd hide no aliens because the government we have now would definitely be leaking that shit.
Speaker 1: If you think that you still think those aliens now is the last straw has been broken I feel like there's no way that the aliens are still a secret with the government the United States has unless it's some other Government that's keeping him a secret.
Speaker 0: Chinese alien, you know if I hadn't become Ultra internet atheist and you know the modern era of the information age say I remain like ultra naive like well into my adulthood.
Speaker 0: what just what would have destroyed my belief in aliens and ghosts is that as Cellphone cameras got better appearances of both dropped off at a catastrophic rate.
Speaker 1: Oh, how can this?
Speaker 1: never an HD picture?
Speaker 1: It's always some blurry ass VHS camera.
Speaker 1: They don't got no HD DSLR to film them aliens.
Speaker 0: But anyway, the thing about himself mysteries was that they'd like do follow-ups episodes like oh We found the killer check this shit out.
Speaker 0: and like they had a tip number you could call and be like I saw the killer I called I thought the tip number was America's Most Wanted not.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, I might be conflating the two.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't like how I conflate kickboxer and bloodsport way more than I realized.
Speaker 1: I think the only thing I'm our Kickstarter is the one starter.
Speaker 1: He puts a glass all over his hands.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I thought that was bloodsport.
Speaker 1: But then it's.
Speaker 1: it's about kicking.
Speaker 1: kick is in the name of the movie I don't know.
Speaker 1: There's not as much kicking in the fire to put glass on his feet.
Speaker 0: bloodsport is when they throw the sand in the eyes.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I don't remember.
Speaker 0: cuz I feel I've seen bloodsport.
Speaker 1: I've definitely seen a kickboxer.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so if you've only seen one You've seen them all.
Speaker 0: a bloodsport is way better than kickboxer.
Speaker 1: I think Just think just watch actual martial arts.
Speaker 1: You know even cops.
Speaker 0: I probably just throw to blur them all together but unsolved mysteries Robert Stack and cops is nothing like the other Two shows.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I still blur like anecdotes from all together.
Speaker 0: Okay, cuz those are all the shows like we watch at grandma's house.
Speaker 0: but here's a Wikia about unsolved mysteries, which is my thing of the day specifically because uh, They have a whole section on all the cases that were legit solved with like the follow-up story like yeah in 2016. this dude totally got arrested.
Speaker 0: and here's all the news articles and I was randomly clicking on these over lunch at work the other day and reading some of them and A lot of them were like, yep, it turns out there wasn't an alien.
Speaker 0: It was a hoax.
Speaker 0: It turns out that that long-lost relative was a scammer.
Speaker 0: Here's he's in jail, but a couple of them actually were way crazier than the show.
Speaker 1: actually Guess the one I remember the most that I didn't believe even at the time.
Speaker 1: Yeah was there these people and they bought a bunk bed and the bunk bed was haunted.
Speaker 0: I think I remember that we wouldn't like it like it would And the kids were getting sick and all this horrible stuff.
Speaker 0: and then I'm gonna find it right now I'm gonna find it here.
Speaker 1: It showed them like demolishing the bunk bed at like the great at the at the junkyard like it was getting crushed and then like Oh as soon as here it is the Talman house the bunk bed as soon as he got rid of the bunk bed That's it.
Speaker 0: There it is right there.
Speaker 1: Yeah, as soon as they got rid of the bed everything was great.
Speaker 1: and I'm like, that's just sounds like a coincidence.
Speaker 1: There's probably nothing wrong with that bed.
Speaker 0: All right, so Results unsolved.
Speaker 0: there's no further evidence related to this one.
Speaker 1: It was not enough evidence to begin with.
Speaker 0: So the two crazy things didn't hurt.
Speaker 1: anyone is innocent victim.
Speaker 0: So one of them I remembered this one from a kid as a kid I don't remember the name now but I clicked around until I found it and it was basically this really creepy story of a dude was like Driving like he was at a gas station and someone approached his car and like asked him for help and was really weird and was Holding a screwdriver.
Speaker 0: so we got unnerved and tried to get away.
Speaker 0: and then the guy like jumped into the car and Threatened him with the screwdriver and told him he had to drive him somewhere.
Speaker 1: so just a crazy guy.
Speaker 0: so he like fought with the guy and like the whole thing happened.
Speaker 0: and eventually like he ran away from the car and the guy chased him down and dragged him back to the car.
Speaker 0: and then like as the Guy was walking around the car being crazy to get back in because he agreed to drive the crazy guy some random over.
Speaker 0: no, he just drove off.
Speaker 0: good job, but Uh The guy the crazy guy kept wandering around in the area because the guy lived nearby.
Speaker 0: So the guy drove off and drove to the nearest police station.
Speaker 0: Meanwhile, the crazy guy wandered around because he knew the guy that ran away lived in the area found a house that happened to be his house snuck in and brutally murdered the guys like mom or wife and They actually caught the guy and there's like the whole.
Speaker 0: like the follow-up was kind of crazy And the other one was.
Speaker 0: there was a couple that just disappeared.
Speaker 0: It was like this big mystery like they just one day they went out for a drive and they were never heard of never seen.
Speaker 0: Again, you know what happened?
Speaker 1: their car fell off like a ravine or something.
Speaker 1: Basically.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they drove off the road into basically like a lagoon in a farm and the car sank and It was found recently because droughts caused the lagoon to dry so much that the car was visible.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm And I was that say if you were as a kid Bothered by not knowing what happens to unsolved mysteries.
Speaker 0: a Whole bunch of them are solved and you can just go to the website and read like exactly what the deal was.
Speaker 1: Here's something that doesn't take 10 minutes to talk about.
Speaker 1: So some people decided they want to take this tree out in their yard or whatever It's like okay, and they decided to take the tree out with what appears to be like this tiny bulldozer like You know how you go to the store to buy like a drill and there's like this real drills like the whole hog and then It's like the plastic crap.
Speaker 1: Oh drill.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: This is like the plastic crap.
Speaker 1: Oh, you know bulldozing equipment.
Speaker 1: It's got like a little shovel cloth thing on it.
Speaker 1: It's like a tract.
Speaker 1: It's almost like a little John Deere size, but it's not for mowing the lawn It's for you know, like what you like a big construction.
Speaker 0: It's already like.
Speaker 0: I got this on here.
Speaker 0: This looks like shaking hands with danger like what I love.
Speaker 1: here comes the danger Like whatever the hell this little tractor guy is right.
Speaker 1: they use it to try to take down a tree which a?
Speaker 1: If you want to take down a tree just use a saw or a chainsaw or regular saw or something like that Right B. If you're gonna use a motorized vehicle to pull down a tree Don't do it this way.
Speaker 1: You can just tie a rope to the tree and drive and pull the tree and that's well.
Speaker 0: That's much safer than what this more because when you do that, you're pulling the tree directly at your car.
Speaker 1: No, you do it in a certain way one of the trees in my yard was taken down by that method.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, if you know the method I'm saying the kind of person who is trying to sorta Jimmy They knew it they did it so well it like it looked like.
Speaker 1: it was like they were basically like Yokels cuz they like literally tied a rope around the tree and a rope to the back of a pickup truck and started driving.
Speaker 1: But they knew exactly how to do it Like they.
Speaker 1: you know, it looks like actually doing it looked stupid and dangerous like YouTube was about to happen But the tree didn't hit the power lines it didn't hit land on anything.
Speaker 1: I'm right the tree landed exactly where they're like, it's gonna land here and that's where it landed.
Speaker 1: You know, I'm just a guy in the street with a pickup truck on room.
Speaker 0: So, you know there's.
Speaker 0: you see this a lot.
Speaker 1: It's when people yeah, this guy does it stupidly and hurts himself.
Speaker 0: hilarious Watch when people and he doesn't die as far as I can see.
Speaker 1: no But it's still funny.
Speaker 0: the the people who do these kinds of things tend to have a number of tools And then they have a problem and they don't want it.
Speaker 0: they never decide to do research.
Speaker 1: you got a hammer.
Speaker 0: Everything looks like nails and they don't even like go to the internet.
Speaker 1: Like if I want to do it, I don't think they have.
Speaker 1: they must have it in it because they upload it to YouTube.
Speaker 0: But like they have internet my like the grout in one of our showers like moldy's.
Speaker 0: I was good They're the caulking not the grout the caulking.
Speaker 0: I was like, oh, maybe I'll just recall kid No and I imagined to myself if I was dumb like if I just tried to do it with no research how I would do it.
Speaker 0: and Then I went and typed.
Speaker 0: How do you recall a bathtub into YouTube?
Speaker 0: and it was super easy.
Speaker 0: And I watched a tutorial and the tutorial gave very very specific advice on exactly how to do it.
Speaker 0: It's actually like really easy But the technique they tell you is not what you would do if you just tried to figure it out on your own.
Speaker 1: I'd probably just take the tube of cock put it in the cock squeezy thing and just yep squirt it in there.
Speaker 0: No, you got to take the old cock out first.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: If you just put the top all you're doing is putting Something for mold to grow on over a bunch of mold, right?
Speaker 1: Well, I think is I would only be using it not in the to replace moldy cock.
Speaker 1: But I have some areas where there's no cock at all already and I would just be using it to fill in those areas.
Speaker 1: So apparently you don't.
Speaker 0: you don't like put a bead and then like pull the cock gun across like squeezing the trigger.
Speaker 0: Yeah, push it forward Like I watch a video that shows the technique and there's all these specific reasons why?
Speaker 0: So when I was in middle school, I had shop class and shop class at least back then.
Speaker 0: I don't know how it is today if they even have shop class anymore.
Speaker 0: It was pretty legit and dangerous.
Speaker 0: Like it was just a. it was a machine shop.
Speaker 1: We had saws it was wood shop.
Speaker 0: We had like plastics labs.
Speaker 0: Like I had vacuum forming machines and all sorts of dangerous nonsense in there, but a kid in my middle school He did the belt sander is being used by someone else and he didn't want to wait.
Speaker 0: So he tried to sand a piece of wood by turning on the band saw and Russian the wood against the side of the blade genius.
Speaker 0: and Yeah, he cut off at least one finger And we had this whole lesson after that on.
Speaker 0: don't use a tool for a thing that it is not explicitly designed to do Unless you either really really really are a professional and know what you're doing or you're really really hate having ten fingers.
Speaker 1: Oh, you really really really want to get a lot of YouTube views Regardless of the danger.
Speaker 1: Shake hands with danger.
Speaker 1: danger will give you YouTube views.
Speaker 0: shake shake hands with danger.
Speaker 0: So, uh, yeah barbecue gonna gonna give a full.
Speaker 0: I guess them at a moment.
Speaker 0: first The booklet book is Frank Herbert's dude.
Speaker 0: I'll read it at some point.
Speaker 0: My YouTube channel has a whole bunch of stuff on it.
Speaker 0: Scott's YouTube channel has a whole bunch of stuff on it.
Speaker 0: You should subscribe to both because we're both escalating our YouTube content and we're gonna do more and more and more as time goes on.
Speaker 0: Uh, yeah follow us on all our biz.
Speaker 0: and Other than that back to the show.
Speaker 0: so You got any meta?
Speaker 0: No We are not experts on barbecue.
Speaker 0: No, I'm not even gonna pretend.
Speaker 1: I'm an expert on eating bar.
Speaker 0: without looking at Put it in to it and I taste the deliciousness, but if you hand me some barbecue I'm not gonna be able to tell you if it's Kansas style Versus like North Carolina style or I guess Memphis style.
Speaker 0: Like I do not know.
Speaker 0: all I know is that I like barbecue and we're gonna be real wrong about a lot of the details of barbecue and We know well, you don't care.
Speaker 1: Well, listen when I was young, right?
Speaker 1: I thought there was a device called the barbecue which is basically a metal bucket with legs that you would put charcoal in.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you mean a grill?
Speaker 1: Yeah, well you would like.
Speaker 1: we called it a barbecue even though we used it for grilling and not for barbecuing.
Speaker 1: But as you know, I can I didn't know right.
Speaker 1: so it's like we had a device.
Speaker 1: we called it a barbecue.
Speaker 1: We had a barbecue, right?
Speaker 1: We would put things on there.
Speaker 1: So I figured out that's we barbecued those things.
Speaker 1: but no we did not barbecue those things right.
Speaker 1: putting you know having hot coals even if you put them in a barbecue and Then putting meats on there or other things In the fiery area like hot dog hamburger, etc.
Speaker 1: That is not barbecuing.
Speaker 1: That is grilling.
Speaker 1: Yep, right?
Speaker 1: Barbecuing actual barbecuing.
Speaker 1: and it's even worse because you have things like shrimp on the barbie.
Speaker 1: That's not Grilling right, of course.
Speaker 0: I mean in the Midwest like the word barbecue just means grill to 99% of people.
Speaker 1: That's what you know.
Speaker 1: But actual barbecue the genre of food Is When you take things and you put them not in a fire but sort of near a fire.
Speaker 1: You know usually in a very smoky could be sealed container where the fire is quite far from the foods.
Speaker 1: But yet it still gets real hot in there, you know relatively speaking Yeah, but not that hot not as hot as near as directly in a fire.
Speaker 1: But still you ain't putting your hand in there because your hand will cook right hundreds of degrees.
Speaker 1: And That shit the meats you put in there that are far away from the fire and being hit by smoke and such they cook mad slow Mad slow like it takes overnight or even a day or just a long-ass time to cook, right?
Speaker 1: No, no No, why would you start this shit like an hour before dinner, right?
Speaker 0: Why would you cook your meat so slow?
Speaker 1: when you cook the meat so slow like that?
Speaker 1: somehow due to the magic of Science right the deliciousness factor multiplies by like a thousand.
Speaker 1: right the meat is such that it is very moist and Delicious and all the smoky flavors come in there.
Speaker 0: well More importantly it's a meat that if you cooked it another way would be pretty crappy meat and it takes all that hard Grizzle nonsense and turns it into wonderful delicious meat.
Speaker 1: that meat just like slides off the bone.
Speaker 1: Like it's not even attached anymore.
Speaker 0: God I just wanting some barbecue like real bad.
Speaker 1: We're gonna eat barbecue all weekend.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 0: It's the barbecue party in New York.
Speaker 0: so yeah, I didn't you know, I'll read the work of eating right now.
Speaker 0: barbecue or Barbecue informally barbecue or Barbie is both a cooking method and an apparatus.
Speaker 0: Barbecuing is done slowly over low indirect heat and food is flavored by the smoking process.
Speaker 0: Well, gill grilling a related process is generally done quickly over a moderate to high direct heat.
Speaker 0: that hardly produces smoke.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: so Barbecue also comes with a lot of associated foods, you know cornbread.
Speaker 0: Corn bread is literally one of my favorite things on earth.
Speaker 0: Remember at RIT one of them one of my staple foods was that 99 cent that cornbread was garbage But it was better than nothing.
Speaker 0: It was.
Speaker 1: no I was worse than nothing is better than nothing.
Speaker 0: you ate it.
Speaker 0: You ate it when I made it barely.
Speaker 1: You know thing is.
Speaker 0: the cornbread I like the most is the cornbread that's like almost Cornbread pudding like it got like big corns just in it.
Speaker 1: Yeah bean Right big bean.
Speaker 0: Yeah big beans.
Speaker 1: Well, I was about this big beans at the barbecue in New York City from this guy.
Speaker 1: I think he's from Illinois somewhere but like that got those beans might be my favorite food.
Speaker 1: Oh, I'm saying cornbread.
Speaker 0: right beans and cornbread, right?
Speaker 1: You know, but you know, it's like the barbecue is the actual meats, right?
Speaker 0: Cuz you know I was recently in Michigan so and I actually had barbecue with my family in like in Northville, which I haven't done since I was a little kid and No being older and Adult and having experienced the world and had a lot of different barbecue around and actually knowing on some level the difference barbecue and grilling I now know that Some of my relatives when they said barbecue chicken, they meant like literally Slow smoking chicken with barbecue sauce for a long time Because I remember it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, when we said barbecue chicken, it meant grilled chicken wings with barbecue sauce on them.
Speaker 0: Yep, so when I was out sauce and something does not make it when I was out there this branch of the family Their barbecue chicken was grilled chicken.
Speaker 1: It was good.
Speaker 0: Like it was a very nostalgic meal, but it was not technically barbecue chicken It was grilled chicken.
Speaker 0: Now.
Speaker 0: I know the difference.
Speaker 0: Yep to a degree.
Speaker 0: but I'm thinking about barbecue a lot lately partly because when I bike to work and what I think the popularity of barbecue in at least this Geography has increased substantially Over the years.
Speaker 0: two different people when I mentioned barbecue earlier today on social media We're like, oh you thought they'd like.
Speaker 0: they mentioned like this specific like Brooklyn barbecue and like like.
Speaker 0: there's a certain Derision for the like neo barbecue in New York City, okay So I mean like to extent.
Speaker 1: I understand right that like we grew up in New York's like pizza bagel.
Speaker 0: I didn't grow up in New York.
Speaker 0: Don't even don't even talk to me.
Speaker 1: Well good Fuck you.
Speaker 1: then Pizza bagels these sorts of things, right?
Speaker 1: It's like there's a right way.
Speaker 1: in a wrong way, you know some Chicago style is garbage.
Speaker 0: Well, you know what like I grew up in Michigan.
Speaker 0: So Breakfast sausage that means something specific if there ain't fennel in it any breakfast sausage.
Speaker 0: It's just some nonsense, right?
Speaker 1: But you know you go somewhere else.
Speaker 1: They don't have pizza and bagel.
Speaker 1: You're like what the fuck is this garbage?
Speaker 1: and if someone tries to have pizza and bagel there and it's obviously no good Yeah, right, but with barbecue, it doesn't seem to me.
Speaker 1: You know, I have been around and eaten many barbecue in many places Right, including ones that people who are you know, very strict and and you know believe, you know certain things about barbecue, right?
Speaker 1: including those places.
Speaker 1: and Thing is I do recognize that there are different styles of barbecue and I could see if you had grown up with a particular style That you then might you know have a dislike for the other styles.
Speaker 0: You grew up eating real bagels and he goes what would you consider real bagels?
Speaker 0: you go somewhere else.
Speaker 1: But but this is the difference here, right?
Speaker 0: it's not the thing you grew up with.
Speaker 1: a real bagel is Delicious and a non-boiled bagel a steamed bagel is disgusting is inedible disgusting garbage.
Speaker 0: It's not an edible.
Speaker 0: It's just white bread in the shape of a bagel.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's not right.
Speaker 1: But you know if I have some barbecue that is like I don't know which plate with you know Which style is which but like I might have some rib that is like this has all the sweet sauce going on And I might have another rib.
Speaker 1: That's more like the dry kind, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like they are both delicious as long as they're actually barbecued properly and you know The meat is so tender
Speaker 0: Where you grew up though because like
Speaker 1: both of those are great, you know
Speaker 0: Midwest so Chicago style pizza and New York style all the different styles of pizza.
Speaker 0: They all existed around me and I didn't have any like one true pizza Fallacy built into my blood and my genes or my family.
Speaker 0: So I like all kinds of pizza and I think I'm lucky that I grew up in a place where barbecue was not such a like Religion so that like you I can just enjoy all kinds of barbecue.
Speaker 1: There's no one style that I think is just better than others like, you know, they're all just different.
Speaker 1: I like most of them But there is definitely, you know quality highs and lows that I can recognize.
Speaker 1: right, you know Sometimes you get a big bean and it tastes too much like bean and not enough like barbecue, right?
Speaker 1: It's too close to a boiled bean.
Speaker 0: I like how I judge burger joints by.
Speaker 1: sometimes you get a cornbread and the cornbread is all dry and crumbly and not moist and Buttery and hasn't have big chunks of corn in it, right like a good.
Speaker 1: right though.
Speaker 1: Sometimes you get a rib and the meat is like all kind of tough to get off of there.
Speaker 0: Well, that's that's insane.
Speaker 0: If the meat is tough that barbecue fucked up because the whole point of barbecue is to untuff in the meat, right?
Speaker 1: But sometimes you get like, you know or something, you know, there's tons and tons of you know factors that can separate You know good barbecue from bad.
Speaker 1: sometimes, you know the the sauce they make it's like, okay.
Speaker 1: I like the sweet sauce style.
Speaker 1: That's a fine style, right?
Speaker 1: But sometimes they put too much sauce.
Speaker 1: It's just like it's buried in sauce and it's like you're not even tasting meats.
Speaker 1: Even if the meats are good, they're hiding under there.
Speaker 1: You can't taste them because the sauce just well.
Speaker 0: The worst is when someone pours a bunch of barbecue sauce like cold like a condiment over What was all what was previously perfectly good barbecue.
Speaker 1: Yep Yeah barbecue sauce is the thing that you put on before the cooking.
Speaker 1: I don't like it.
Speaker 1: when you put barbecue sauce on After the cooking it depends on what I'm doing.
Speaker 1: It's like it's freaking ketchup or something.
Speaker 0: It's like a pulled pork sandwich.
Speaker 0: I like a little bit sort of like.
Speaker 1: it's okay.
Speaker 1: If the barbecue sauce is room temperature or warmer you can like dip a french fry in there.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, it's real important, right?
Speaker 1: But you know You don't want to add more to the already sauced up rib or pulled pork sandwich or whatever it is.
Speaker 0: So when I was a kid I think my favorite barbecue was like regular like barbecue chicken like beer can chicken that kind of barbecue chicken Mmm, and that is still one of my favorite foods to this day.
Speaker 0: Like that is not change.
Speaker 1: I mean there the.
Speaker 1: there are so many different kinds of barbecued food, right?
Speaker 1: You got your your rib your chicken right your pulled pork But then you got the other.
Speaker 1: you got the brisket which is like, oh the brisket watch out You're starting to get into good territories now, right and I feel like you know the best of the best.
Speaker 1: like the the connoisseurs barbecue item is The burnt end.
Speaker 0: Oh my god.
Speaker 0: So John Brown that the state there's one barbecue place like really near us.
Speaker 0: It's like super super legit.
Speaker 0: There's another one that we haven't like figured out where it is or if it's open yet Like what the deal is with it, but this place has burnt ends.
Speaker 1: This is a new place near me, too.
Speaker 1: They haven't gone to.
Speaker 0: they people have said it's okay and they run out of the burnt ends Like they like.
Speaker 0: they just run out of meat every day like they make their me.
Speaker 1: Well, that's the thing is when it takes food so long to make right your Barbecue device whatever it is.
Speaker 1: Usually a big metal thing outside out back behind your restaurant only holds so much meat.
Speaker 1: So you fill it up literally all the way with meat.
Speaker 1: and If people and then it takes a long time before anything's ready to sell at all Things are ready to sell.
Speaker 1: so you start selling and as soon as a some of it, you know Freeze up some space you can put more in there.
Speaker 1: But it might not be ready until like the next frickin day or something.
Speaker 1: You don't even know how long you know.
Speaker 1: Maybe if people are buying things like early before lunch, maybe you can put some more meats in there.
Speaker 1: That'll be done for dinner.
Speaker 1: But like you have a capacity And it's like that capacity might be enough for like people sitting in your restaurant.
Speaker 1: But if people come in and get takeout It's like there's an infinite number of people can do that and then you're out of food and you it's gonna be time before there's More.
Speaker 1: there's nothing you can really do about.
Speaker 1: so I don't know what.
Speaker 1: I have more more barbecues.
Speaker 0: I don't know if it's just because we're talking about barbecue, but the chat is like lit over here.
Speaker 1: I'm sure it is.
Speaker 0: People are very passionate about barbecue for so Grover's real excited about going to the barbecue thing this weekend.
Speaker 1: Oh, so the bar let's talk about the barbecue thing this weekend.
Speaker 1: So in New York every year and I missed it last year for I don't know what reason but I also missed it last year.
Speaker 1: I've been to it almost I found him about it actually by accident I was biking around one day and bumped into it and then since then I put it on my calendar and I hit it every Year since then except last year.
Speaker 0: I don't know why it's dangerous though If you bump into it biking because you're already hungry from biking.
Speaker 1: So now I but what it is is the.
Speaker 1: it's the Big Apple barbecue, it's in Madison Square Park for one weekend a year in the summer usually June something and For two days Saturday and Sunday barbecue people from all over the country.
Speaker 1: nay world Mostly us though.
Speaker 1: I don't think there might be Canadian ones I don't even know think it's mostly us if not all but from all parts of the u.s.
Speaker 1: They come and set up shop in Madison Square Park right on Friday They get those barbecues rolling and then Saturday morning at 11 out comes the food, right?
Speaker 1: The way it works is you walk up to any booth you want and you shell out like 11 bucks or something.
Speaker 1: They give you a you know, disposable food tray with a little bit of like maybe you know a little bit of rib Maybe like a quarter rack or less, right?
Speaker 1: It might not be rib, you know might be a pulled pork sandwich.
Speaker 1: It might be whatever that place is serving.
Speaker 1: each place serves one or two things.
Speaker 1: You know the side whatever their side is, you know and you walk away and eat it.
Speaker 1: and the popular ones that mad long lines Yep, and the not-so-popular ones you can just walk right up.
Speaker 1: They also sell these VIP passes which are even if you're rich and love barbecue more than life itself You should not buy one of these because they cost hundreds of dollars.
Speaker 1: They entitle you to some like, you know free meals or you know, you're basically paying for meals in advance effectively But you could walk basically behind the booths to where they all have separate checkout lanes So you don't have to wait in line.
Speaker 1: you can go to basically the VIP line behind each booth to get food everywhere and Go like that, but you can only eat it like two or three places before you're full Unless you're.
Speaker 0: well, I mean, so I think that is aimed at the Homer Simpsons.
Speaker 1: Yes, sure.
Speaker 1: So what I do is I go on Saturday at 11 before there's any lines.
Speaker 1: I hit up my guy with his being the best maybe my favorite food on earth Maybe right and then I hit up one that I haven't hit up before because I've hit up a lot of them are repeats year to Yep And I try out to see if there's anything new out there.
Speaker 1: and then I come back on Sunday and I do a little rerun.
Speaker 1: And that's how I do except last year.
Speaker 1: I missed it.
Speaker 1: I don't know why.
Speaker 0: probably just go Sunday this year because we're running that race Saturday morning.
Speaker 1: Well, my plan is to bike to the race say hi.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah bike to the barbecue.
Speaker 1: Yeah eat Bike back home where they got the mural project block party is going on.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 0: I forgot about that.
Speaker 1: And then maybe bike back to you.
Speaker 1: Yeah, cuz we're only hanging out of you and I could I could do all kinds of shit on Saturday and then Sunday My plan is bike to the barbecue.
Speaker 0: No and then You know what?
Speaker 0: I might do.
Speaker 1: There's not a lot of things happening Sunday like there are We'll have our guests over.
Speaker 0: maybe I'll spring for them to get a city bike pass for the day so they can bike over.
Speaker 0: Look, cuz I don't think they want to bring their bikes.
Speaker 1: Oh a whole day.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's not too expensive.
Speaker 1: Well, I'm gonna say Sunday at 11.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna be in Madison Square Park.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I will also be there.
Speaker 1: What time is your race on Saturday?
Speaker 0: Ah, I don't remember.
Speaker 0: It's morning ish.
Speaker 0: I think Well, we'll coordinate our business tomorrow.
Speaker 0: Like what our deal is.
Speaker 0: Mmm, but so the Debate they were having in the chat here was wait.
Speaker 0: So the definitions just low and slow because they were saying what about like Turkish barbecue or the barbecues?
Speaker 0: you like heat some stones And then put it next to the meat and I'd say that's all good If it's not cooked an indirect heat for a long time, there's another component you're forgetting probably with smoking.
Speaker 0: I was about to say smoke is the critical component because otherwise you could argue that a slow cooker is barbecue.
Speaker 1: And then it's yes, and it's uh, then it is some other kind of food.
Speaker 1: right that is not.
Speaker 1: You know in the barbecue smoke is key.
Speaker 0: There's a reason liquid smoke exists as a thing even though it's carcinogenic and it's a preservative.
Speaker 0: I Will take that hit I'll take that risk.
Speaker 0: I love the taste of smoke so much.
Speaker 1: Yeah, barbecue is bad really bad for you, by the way.
Speaker 0: Yeah I We know based on relatively recent research that red meat is bad in ways that we never imagined It's super bad like the fat and like all those pieces of it actually aren't so bad for you.
Speaker 0: What's bad is the red meat part itself?
Speaker 1: It's not as bad as tobacco though.
Speaker 1: No, no, and I'm only how often do I eat it?
Speaker 1: like Two or three times a year at most.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I I eat red meat.
Speaker 1: I think I mean I mean barbecue specifically Red meat I eat maybe once or twice a month.
Speaker 0: Yeah once a month for barbecue tops.
Speaker 0: Yeah tops.
Speaker 1: Well barbecue like maybe once every three months, but red meat once a month.
Speaker 0: Well, if I eat barbecue, I go all out and I usually try to not eat.
Speaker 1: Well, that's what I do is like if you know If I'm gonna eat a red meat or a barbecue, I'm gonna eat the best and I'm gonna go all out.
Speaker 1: I'm not gonna eat some I'm not gonna eat some crap.
Speaker 1: Oh burger, right?
Speaker 1: I'll eat a burger if it is an amazo burger.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you go to the Baroness or you eat a steak somewhere.
Speaker 0: Yep steak burger.
Speaker 0: So what's your favorite of all the barbecue dishes?
Speaker 0: Like what's your favorite that isn't burnt ends?
Speaker 0: Cuz that's kind of like cheating.
Speaker 1: See that actually the thing is here.
Speaker 1: as a Jew pastrami is a deal.
Speaker 1: Now you might be saying whoa pastrami is like a cured thing.
Speaker 1: It's not a it's not a barbecue thing.
Speaker 0: smoke pastrami.
Speaker 1: There are places Barbecue places that are doling out the pastrami and let me tell you I'm into that and I don't care about what purist or Technicality thing you want to count.
Speaker 0: that is so good.
Speaker 0: when I was visiting up in Albany with Pete Nury a while Not too long ago smoke pastrami man.
Speaker 1: I'm down with that.
Speaker 1: That is my deal Right.
Speaker 0: I remember that one time we were up in Albany We're gonna have that party and we decided we were gonna smoke prime rib for the fuck of it and eat that.
Speaker 1: and then we went To the place to buy a meat and the dude talked us out of it.
Speaker 0: He's like.
Speaker 1: he's like you don't want no prime rib.
Speaker 1: Just buy this like, you know buy this brisket You're gonna.
Speaker 0: you're gonna waste that prime rib It's not.
Speaker 0: the brisket will be way better and he did like.
Speaker 0: he Literally like talked us out of this like talked us off the cliff.
Speaker 1: He's told us in the buying something cheaper.
Speaker 0: So like okay, whatever we don't care, but in retrospect, I feel like we should have just smoked that prime rib and gone for it.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean we ate a delicious meat.
Speaker 1: I didn't care what meat it was.
Speaker 1: other people were the ones who cared what meat it was.
Speaker 1: I just really really wanted a delicious meat.
Speaker 0: I gotta tell you though the barbecue like kabob barbecue stuff that I had in Istanbul to this day Like I have never had I mean it's I would say that it is not better than American style barbecue in any absolute sense.
Speaker 0: It's just great.
Speaker 0: I have never had that style of barbecue as good as I had it in Istanbul because I've tried to get it from like every Turkish or like Mediterranean style place I've ever tried in the city never quite lives up.
Speaker 1: Meanwhile, yeah I don't know like how come some foods cuz like there doesn't see.
Speaker 1: people always try to find a reason you can't make a food In a certain place, right?
Speaker 0: Like you can't make New York bagels in a lot of places cuz the water's shitty.
Speaker 1: I don't know about that.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna find out if that's true or not.
Speaker 1: Right, but that's what people say.
Speaker 0: I'll bring you some water back from Arizona in a bucket.
Speaker 0: But
Speaker 1: obviously there's no reason you can't make good barbecue regardless of location because the people who make their barbecue far away Come to New York with their equipment and make the same goddamn barbecue They make in their home place, right and it tastes the same as it does if you go to the restaurant far away.
Speaker 1: so Why is it that like not one Turkish person who can make that good food has come to New York with the knowledge to make?
Speaker 1: It and done so here right?
Speaker 1: It's New York City.
Speaker 1: You've got pretty much every freaking thing right that you can think of.
Speaker 1: someone has come here and brought it here.
Speaker 0: Well, it's partly just that like we're you know Mexico with Mexican food and barbecue.
Speaker 0: when we went to San Antonio we were like, let's find the best goddamn barbecue and the best goddamn Mexican food and the best Mexican food there is about as good as the fancy Mexican food I get New York.
Speaker 0: and So far none of the barbecue places we've tried in San Antonio are better than John Brown smokehouse Which is like right next to our house and John Brown smokehouse is.
Speaker 1: it's pretty good.
Speaker 1: Yeah It's not like the best barbecue ever.
Speaker 0: pretty legit though.
Speaker 0: Apparently that is.
Speaker 0: it is Kansas style.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I like it.
Speaker 1: I like like their cornbread is like ridiculously amazing cuz it's almost like.
Speaker 1: it's almost like a cake.
Speaker 0: It's cornbread pudding.
Speaker 1: It's like a giant cube.
Speaker 1: It's all super yellow.
Speaker 1: It's super buttery and moist.
Speaker 1: It's got big chunks of corn in it.
Speaker 1: It's like the ultimate cornbread.
Speaker 0: It's just so hard that that place is there because it's right next to where we go bouldering and when I bike to work There's starting up like they're doing the smoking just as I'm going to work.
Speaker 0: I smell it while I'm biking to work and I get crazy hungry.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like I want to go in there.
Speaker 1: But even if I just get a job there Yeah, you could just quit your job and grill instead.
Speaker 0: I'm sure that being a barbecue Professional in a restaurant will make the exact same amount of money that being like a Wall Street product.
Speaker 1: I'm willing to bet that the pit master Dudes who put their names all over these restaurants that come to Madison Square Park and will be there this weekend make a lot More money than you do but also more to the point.
Speaker 0: I am pretty confident.
Speaker 0: I would become fat.
Speaker 1: They are all fat.
Speaker 1: I there are mostly fat old white dudes, but not all them.
Speaker 0: Not all now, but mostly I feel like fat old white dude.
Speaker 0: Explo expresses literally 90% of the pit masters I've ever met in my life.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm Occasionally but Yeah, they're all Actually taken note over the years.
Speaker 1: which of the places that show up there are not run by fat old white dudes?
Speaker 1: And they are particularly, you know, I don't know if they're the most delicious ones necessarily because I mean, you know Pretty much anyone who shows up there is great to begin with right?
Speaker 1: They don't have any crappy people there, but their styles are definitely the most divergent, right?
Speaker 1: It's like, you know, they don't.
Speaker 1: all the white dudes are just trying to stick to what you know Just like with chili.
Speaker 0: I like the same thing with chili that it with barbecue like.
Speaker 0: there's all these specific like.
Speaker 0: I got the Wikipedia article up and they're like.
Speaker 0: There are only four main styles of barbecue Carolina, Memphis, Kansas City, Texas.
Speaker 0: And then there's a bunch of like weak sauce sub ones like Alabama, California, Hawaii, Kentucky, Oklahoma, St.
Speaker 0: Louis Virginia and other states.
Speaker 0: has a section I guess but I like fusion food a lot and People who do barbecue techniques but twisted in some way.
Speaker 0: I had not only have no problem with that But that's usually some of my favorite barbecue Even though that stuff would net is there literally an entire article on birth.
Speaker 0: There's an entire Wikipedia page on burnt ends specifically, oh, baby Look at that.
Speaker 0: burn those ends burn those ends and put them right in my mouth and then I die of heart disease.
Speaker 0: All right, I think it's.
Speaker 0: I think I just love barbecue and I'm gonna not eat it tonight cuz I'm gonna be eating it this weekend.
Speaker 0: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at front row crew.com for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 0: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows It's actually recorded at night and the patreon patrons for this episode of geek nights are Nicholas Brando Alan Joyce Heidi McNichol Amanda Duchette and Thomas Hahn.
Speaker 0: mystady.com William Eisneros Jeremy minor that when a girl walks in with an itty-bitty waist and a round thing a genuine bonafide like five six car monorail Roncie Roncivalis Rebecca Dunn the terrible secret space for two one creations.
Speaker 0: seriously, though Why are we out here?
Speaker 0: Sherman von Horl rare Laval James David White Rochelle, Montanona Superboy.
Speaker 0: I paid five bucks to make rim say pickle Sailor Vista Matthew Smith Don Schleicke jar television Joshiro Joe star Shawn Yeager Sam Cordery Clinton Walton Wren from New Zealand Ryan Perrin, mr.
Speaker 0: Black Brian's Adroni Finn Chris midkiff Chris Knox Daniel Redmond Sean Klein Chris Reimer and Thomas Hahn.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna run a 5k race in a few minutes as practice for a more serious 5k race that I'm running on Saturday.
Speaker 1: and Now I leave you with Shit Oh shit Sir you're being stopped by an officer of the New York City Police Department Manhattan district.
Speaker 1: We're doing a hundred miles per hour in a 35 mile per hour zone.
Speaker 1: I see your driver's license and registration, please here You are thank you.
Speaker 0: Wait.
Speaker 0: Oh my god.
Speaker 1: You're Captain Jack.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah I'm so happy to see you my god.
Speaker 1: Thank you Come over here Scott, this is my god, I'm happy to see you.
Speaker 1: Okay, my friends.
Speaker 1: Listen to you Listen to you have to autograph cards for your friends and I have to use my race car cuz I'm late for show.
Speaker 1: So, can you please help me?
Speaker 0: You know, give me a hand, please.
Speaker 1: All right Okay, follow me and I'll give you an escort.
Speaker 1: Oh great.
Speaker 1: Now here's one for your wife, too.