Speaker 1: It's Tuesday, May 23rd, 2017.
Speaker 1: I'm rim.
Speaker 1: I'm Scott and this is geek nights tonight.
Speaker 1: Tumble seed the sequel to ice-cold beer.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: So yeah, there were no shows last week cuz I was in Hong Kong, but if you followed Scott on YouTube There's a bunch of Scott stuff going on.
Speaker 1: was there you were streaming and stuff.
Speaker 1: I saw notifications.
Speaker 0: I guess maybe I think I did less than I plan to do.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you did some.
Speaker 1: Hi, I thought I did more than you did.
Speaker 1: Well, I thought I'd do some podcast while I was in Hong Kong But I was just too busy.
Speaker 1: I also mean tired because it's 12 hours off.
Speaker 0: I also made an appearance on ATW 9k, which I thought didn't exist anymore.
Speaker 0: But no, I just stopped listening to the podcast.
Speaker 0: It totally still exists.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the only podcast I actually listened to is pseudopod and occasionally 538.
Speaker 1: I don't really listen to anything else anymore.
Speaker 1: I actually haven't even listened to Dave and Joel in a while.
Speaker 1: I haven't listened to that in years, but Hong Kong was a fun.
Speaker 1: But also I didn't really get to do anything cool because I was just working and I'm getting to two conventions Back to back days and then I flew home.
Speaker 0: Why were there two conventions at the same time - So they're too fast.
Speaker 0: I seized anime Boston situation.
Speaker 1: So yeah, you know what tends to happen in finance.
Speaker 1: There'll be a big conference like in Hong Kong or Singapore or something.
Speaker 1: So clever people will that same week book another venue in the area and do their own conference and piggyback off of it.
Speaker 0: Well, but why would people go to your thing instead of the big thing?
Speaker 1: People don't go there for just one thing They'll just go to both.
Speaker 1: Mmm They're only one day things.
Speaker 1: these things are the only ones that are multi-day are like trade tech Paris Which I went to once so that the big thing is Saturday.
Speaker 0: You make your thing Sunday.
Speaker 1: Yep, exactly.
Speaker 1: So the big thing was like Thursday.
Speaker 1: So Thompson did a thing on Wednesday and I was there all week.
Speaker 1: So I had to do both Thompson like Thompson Reuters.
Speaker 0: Yep, okay.
Speaker 1: They were there at a conference the same company.
Speaker 1: They ran a conference for the buys.
Speaker 1: people just calm.
Speaker 1: people call them Thompson or TR.
Speaker 1: I Try to avoid using the the jargon of finance because I'm sure you guys really care about that stuff, but People seem to care about shit just because they can't help themselves.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like once they hear a thing exists.
Speaker 0: They need to know everything there is about.
Speaker 1: you know, part of that is it's like.
Speaker 1: it's like, you know If you don't know anything about cars at all But you're near a mechanic and they open the hood and start poking around.
Speaker 1: you got to lean over.
Speaker 0: you want to see like hey If you're that's how you tell a good person from a bad person whether or not they lean over there and look if they have a Curious mind.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they have a desire for knowledge or they anti intellectual.
Speaker 0: If we just got rid of all the anti intellectual DNA, it would be a great world.
Speaker 1: Oh get rid of all the anti intellectual DNA.
Speaker 1: I wonder how that could be accomplished.
Speaker 1: I wonder if there's.
Speaker 1: I wonder if there's any problem with this potential theory that you've got.
Speaker 1: I don't know this.
Speaker 0: I Everyone else who's tried to do this has always used some wrong factor for deciding who to get rid of like You know skin color or something, right?
Speaker 0: If I use I could use.
Speaker 1: I'm following you down this road But at a distance right if we could.
Speaker 0: just you know.
Speaker 0: Let Scott choose who to get rid of Scottocracy.
Speaker 0: and you know, I'm not even gonna murder people We're just gonna send all the dumb people into space space.
Speaker 1: what like to be?
Speaker 0: or arc or send all the smart people into space I think smart and leave the dumb people here.
Speaker 1: You know what that is.
Speaker 1: That's the plot of Gundam seed.
Speaker 0: Yeah We'll have awesome robots and they'll have really shitty ones.
Speaker 1: cuz frankly like in that show even though you know The coordinators kind of also want to genocide the humans back.
Speaker 1: It's easy to pick a side in that fight because the ones are pretty much the worst.
Speaker 0: Well, do you know?
Speaker 0: and the other thing is the humans only stood a chance because they stole the freedom Gundam.
Speaker 0: They didn't make that.
Speaker 0: They didn't make the.
Speaker 1: well, they also outbred the space people because the space people stopped having babies.
Speaker 0: they were too smart.
Speaker 0: they Smart enough to not make babies.
Speaker 1: Except no, it wasn't it that they were.
Speaker 1: they became infertile because of the genetic stuff They did and they basically broke their deal like they broke their genetics.
Speaker 1: Whatever don't make space babies Yeah, or if you're gonna make space babies expect them to replace you.
Speaker 0: your space babies are robots.
Speaker 1: So in some minor news, they got a minor geek bite.
Speaker 1: I think we mentioned this but race for the galaxy, which is a pretty good Light tabletop game been around for quite some time We played the hell out of it and kind of stopped playing it just because we played it a lot.
Speaker 1: I never played it enough to get good at it, but I played it.
Speaker 0: It was good play.
Speaker 0: What there's a PC app that was free.
Speaker 0: I don't know if it's still around but I played that a whole bunch for like a few weeks at one time Yeah, and then I was like, alright, it's enough of that.
Speaker 1: So, uh an Android and iPhone app came out.
Speaker 1: Yeah, official and not only is it official but it is Fantastic.
Speaker 0: This is the kind of game you need an app for because it has.
Speaker 0: if you've never played it a lot Then you have problems like figuring out what the symbols mean and stuff like that.
Speaker 1: and now the thing is if you know the game like the iconography and of the game is Fantastic, like it's really well designed but the learning curve for people who are not freaks like us is Shockingly steep right like what the hell does that fucking symbol mean?
Speaker 1: And they make sense in retrospect.
Speaker 1: But it's also this this game is like the poster child for the bit in our panel on writing game rules about how one Of the best ways for people to learn a game is to have someone else just run the game for them and provide the bumpers Like provide the rails.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but I think we I'm assuming we reviewed race to the galaxy at some point on geek nights.
Speaker 0: I'm not that.
Speaker 1: maybe if we didn't that's an easy Tuesday show.
Speaker 1: Okay, but what I will say is that I Think anyone who listens to geek nights should just buy this app because it is it is.
Speaker 0: how many dollars is it?
Speaker 1: I don't even know.
Speaker 0: I just buy it free.
Speaker 1: It's not free.
Speaker 0: It doesn't come with all the expansions you want.
Speaker 1: It comes with the first expansion.
Speaker 1: I think the other two are not out yet.
Speaker 0: Mmm.
Speaker 0: They're gonna charge you for that shit.
Speaker 1: I don't care.
Speaker 1: all told it'll be less than 20 bucks.
Speaker 0: with like every expansion ever I'm pretty sure you could just buy all those for 20 bucks.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but I cannot play the physical ones by myself while I'm pooping in a public bath, I think I can.
Speaker 1: It's gonna be a Ukraine.
Speaker 1: But the real notable thing about this is that I've played a lot of these apps of tabletop games and a lot of them are real bad or They're pretty good, but their UX has a lot of failings.
Speaker 0: No, this is I mean the teeny ones 90% good.
Speaker 0: the patchwork one is way good.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like the carcass own one is a car.
Speaker 0: This one's real good.
Speaker 1: It's pretty good.
Speaker 1: It's got a few issues.
Speaker 0: It's not issues in that it like it requires you to do more presses than you would like to have to press.
Speaker 0: but but there's a Lot of shortcuts.
Speaker 0: you can skip over some presses.
Speaker 1: What impresses me about the race for the galaxy UX is that this is the first big?
Speaker 1: Tabletop game I've tried to play on a phone since I got a super tiny phone with a tiny lower.
Speaker 0: it like 720p works on the tiniest screen.
Speaker 1: it works on a tiny screen so well that I was shocked I'd probably just playing at my giant iPad.
Speaker 1: But like the things it does UX wise to deal with the fact that my screen is so small that there is Literally no way to read those cards.
Speaker 1: It is just very well designed to the point that I actually want to track down who specifically did the UX And talk to them because it's impressive and I am deeply impressed by it.
Speaker 1: You should buy this if you live the geek nights.
Speaker 1: if you haven't played race for the galaxy guess what?
Speaker 1: You'll have way more fun learning it playing this app than having someone like me or Scott tried to teach it to you and trying To figure out the symbols and the stupid cards and then like you can't show anyone your hand.
Speaker 0: Yeah,
Speaker 1: also I think now that I've played this game Probably over a hundred times since I got the app because I had a bunch of long flights And you know I play it on the subway, and I play it when I poop I can crank out almost two full games during one poop.
Speaker 1: It's like wonder Ashima hex games worth of this.
Speaker 0: It's a real fast game.
Speaker 1: to play This card I think I've gotten to the point to where I gotta count cards And it's pretty much random who wins.
Speaker 0: add more expansions.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I've got.
Speaker 1: I've added every expansion.
Speaker 1: That's currently available But it's super good.
Speaker 1: He got any gaming news.
Speaker 0: What was my gaming news?
Speaker 0: They say we're gaming news was the alright.
Speaker 0: So check this out, so here's a check in a while ago in hearthstone, right?
Speaker 0: There's a mode standard where you can only use the newish cards Which is good because if you just start playing today, and you had to get every card ever even including the old cards How would you do that right?
Speaker 0: It'd be too many fun?
Speaker 0: I'd be like oh you want to start playing magic huh well every one of the stores got moxes what you can do about it.
Speaker 1: That was how it was playing magic before they started doing like draft tournaments, right?
Speaker 0: But anyway, so they have what's called wild which is where you can play any card in the history of hearthstone even one.
Speaker 0: And they don't even sell the old cards anymore.
Speaker 0: like if a car is not in standard They don't sell it and she's got to have.
Speaker 0: you know you can make it with dust.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah I do so.
Speaker 0: you take your extra cards you disintegrate them, and you can make old cards with them.
Speaker 0: But yeah, if you haven't if you aren't if you're a new to hearthstone It's really hard to play wild.
Speaker 0: but anyway no one really played wild or gave a crap about it.
Speaker 0: But they announced like hey, we're gonna do a wild tournament and the people who are like top 64 in each region are gonna like qualify for this tournament of wild Standard I guess because hearthstone is a big enough game to where like you can make a living playing it.
Speaker 0: eSports wise People like invested a lot of fucking time to try to make sure they were in the top 64 at the end of the season In the wild category so that they could be in this tournament that they knew no other information about whatsoever.
Speaker 0: There was no information about the tournament other than basically like a few sentences like we're gonna do a tournament Top64 in each region.
Speaker 1: so considering that I didn't read this article I don't know about this.
Speaker 1: But the the title is how blizzard screwed people for the wild top 64 tournaments.
Speaker 1: I'm assuming this takes a dark turn.
Speaker 0: so there are some people who are in Australia Playing tar stone in the wild trying to try to get into this tournament because they wanted to be in because it you know they Felt like that was you know gonna be beneficial to their Esport career.
Speaker 0: right to be in this thing.
Speaker 1: So in Australia you know blizzard has regions right Asia Europe and North America Yep, which if you play like overwatch you just don't care like it doesn't affect you at all.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but you usually a lot of people have accounts on each region because remember hearthstone is free to play.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right.
Speaker 0: So they'll have accounts on each region and some people like level up in each region every single month and shit like that.
Speaker 0: so These people are in Australia And if you're in Australia blizzard tells you for all their games that you should be in the North America region if you're in Australia.
Speaker 0: but For this tournament the tournament rules just came out suddenly You know after the whole thing was already said and done in terms of who are the top 64 were.
Speaker 0: They put out the full tournament rules and the for the full tournament rules were like oh, yeah if you're in Australia You got to be in the Asia region to qualify.
Speaker 0: and they're like we would have made accounts in the Asia region and done it.
Speaker 1: But we only did it in North America because that's the region we're supposed to play in because it's extra interesting because like, you know I was just in Hong Kong the the acronym for that region is a pack.
Speaker 1: Yeah as in Asia Pacific.
Speaker 1: So I understand why they might have put Australia and New Zealand in North America But like there that is the right answer for 50% of use cases and the wrong answer for 50% of use cases.
Speaker 0: But anyway, the point is is that man they really screwed those people over even though I think it's not they're making a bigger deal out of it than it is.
Speaker 0: It's like yeah, it's like It's a silly tournament.
Speaker 0: It's a tournament for a children's card game, whatever.
Speaker 0: but The vast this keeps happening.
Speaker 0: basically in all these sort of Competitives, you know, we've talked about it and other times that it's happened, but when there's competitive structures or organizations managing competitive tournaments for video games and also tabletop games and these organizations are not Top-tier right even companies that are big relatively big companies that have like departments that manage this shit, you know, like netrunner is fantasy fly.
Speaker 0: and You know like the League of Legends people valve screws shit up, right?
Speaker 0: They got like oh someone used a Cheat and a counter-strike thing.
Speaker 0: There was some something wrong with the map, right?
Speaker 1: But when was the last time the NHL screwed something up, right?
Speaker 0: It's like we see this kind of stuff Constantly when people have their organized play.
Speaker 0: their competitive play Departments are not good enough.
Speaker 0: They just keep fucking up and geek nights will always call them out up But just just like we do on everything.
Speaker 1: That's right.
Speaker 1: No, it's interesting cuz on one hand you might say like we said like well It's the hearthstone like it's not the most important or serious game.
Speaker 1: But on the other hand as soon as you add a tournament structure or competitive play with prizes then supposedly big prizes Even if they're small prizes, you're suddenly saying yeah this this area of this game matters.
Speaker 1: You're basically telling everyone play this one for real play it seriously.
Speaker 1: So you're sort of telling all the players to like step up their game.
Speaker 1: But it's implied like there's a social contract that you also have to step up your game.
Speaker 1: No one's gonna treat quick play in overwatch.
Speaker 1: Seriously if they do They deserve what they get like.
Speaker 0: if you have something in the prize is like tens of thousands of dollars At least if it's if you're.
Speaker 0: even if you have a Competition and the prize for that competition is tens of thousands of dollars or more worth of stuff That means it's worth it to someone's like dedicate their life to it.
Speaker 0: Basically.
Speaker 0: No, that's like a year's salary for a lot of human beings.
Speaker 0: You know that's worth.
Speaker 0: someone quitting their job and spending all their time preparing to compete in that.
Speaker 0: now Right when you reach that level just thousands not enough but tens of thousands.
Speaker 0: now As soon as you have a prize that is that amount you have to be 100% perfect in your competitive fairness and everything because people are dedicating their lives to possibly trying to win this thing I feel like with professional sports.
Speaker 1: the specter of heavy Government intervention and regulation caused them to clean up their acts and be very professional and self-regulate.
Speaker 0: Yeah, because I mean even you know, it's like they're not government organizations.
Speaker 0: But even when it's like steroids or something in the 90s like Congress Is like what and there's suddenly hearings, right?
Speaker 0: So it's like you can't fuck this shit up guys video game.
Speaker 0: right now You're small enough and the the old people in Congress don't have their eye on you.
Speaker 0: They literally don't know you exist, right?
Speaker 0: But you know what in 20 years We're gonna be the kind of people people our age are gonna be in that Congress.
Speaker 0: They're gonna know you exist and you're gonna be the next baseball Don't fuck up.
Speaker 1: I mean based on some metrics more people watch certain eSports tournaments than possibly watch the American Super Bowl and watch anything.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and Like this industry is growing rapidly and the professionalization around it is not growing fast enough And this is a collision course.
Speaker 0: so point You know It's just yet another incident and a thing that always bothers us that we point out every time and we're gonna keep pointing out every Time until stops happening.
Speaker 1: So the listener actually sent us two questions a while ago.
Speaker 0: Didn't we have a separate questions thing?
Speaker 1: Yeah, so I'm actually restructuring that because it was a pain and I'm gonna start that up again soon because that's a patreon driven thing.
Speaker 0: primarily People stop giving him money you're paying for and you're not getting what you paid for.
Speaker 1: But this one but they did just guy did just read on another Castlevania chapter where Simon Belmont and Timothy Bradley had a shared Orgasm over the kill.
Speaker 0: Why would you pay for that?
Speaker 0: You want to pay for him to not do that?
Speaker 0: What's wrong with you?
Speaker 1: So but this was not through the patreon.
Speaker 1: This is just a question that a listener sent.
Speaker 1: that was pretty good.
Speaker 1: Okay, and it was related to our writing rules Lecture.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 1: So what makes an easily confusing highly debatable rule?
Speaker 1: Is it just inconsistent definitions or something else?
Speaker 0: It's just ambiguity of the language, right?
Speaker 0: Your language is not a hundred percent precise so that different there could be multiple different meanings.
Speaker 0: Yep, right.
Speaker 0: So here's a perfect example from netrunner, right?
Speaker 0: Let me find this card.
Speaker 0: you talk about something.
Speaker 1: It was a new card They had to fix so I would say I back up and it's more of a design problem.
Speaker 1: What makes it confusing or debatable rule is very simple.
Speaker 1: It's any time a game designer assumes things about the players of the game without actually writing them down or Encoding them directly into the mechanics of the game itself.
Speaker 1: so like imagine if I designed a trick-taking game, right and I wrote my rules and I play tested it.
Speaker 1: It was cool.
Speaker 1: I released it and at no point did I explain what a trick was Because I just assumed that everyone would know what a trick-taking game is.
Speaker 1: It's that kind of situation.
Speaker 1: game designers, especially tabletop game designers, especially any tabletop game designers will very often make up rules to games and assume that the people playing them have the same basic level of game knowledge that they and all their friends do and it's Exacerbated by the fact that most indie tabletop games are play tested by other indie tabletop game designers.
Speaker 0: Alright, so here's a perfect example, right?
Speaker 0: So there's a new relatively new netrunner card and when this card when we first saw it everyone was like what the hell?
Speaker 0: We don't know how to use this card.
Speaker 0: It doesn't make any sense.
Speaker 0: It says it says a bunch of stuff But then it says use this ability only after a successful run on HQ.
Speaker 0: So wait, so if I make a successful run in HQ with the very first action I take in the whole game.
Speaker 0: Does that mean I can now use this ability any time for the rest of the game?
Speaker 0: Does it mean I can only use it?
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, it is after.
Speaker 1: that's like gremlins feet after midnight.
Speaker 1: Does it want midnight?
Speaker 0: Yeah, does it mean I can only use it immediately after like I've made the successful run?
Speaker 0: now I can use it right now or I can't use it.
Speaker 0: or does it mean like as What time after after?
Speaker 0: it could be immediately after or out to infinity?
Speaker 0: It's not specific enough.
Speaker 0: It's ambiguous.
Speaker 0: So they changed it.
Speaker 0: there's a fact that came out like yesterday that said ah, we're changing the wording on this card.
Speaker 0: It now says immediately after until end of turn.
Speaker 1: so Until you turn is a classic Tabletop card game design.
Speaker 0: So you make it you get your successful HQ run and then between that time and the end of the turn You can use this ability.
Speaker 0: Once the end of the turn hits you can no longer use the ability and then next turn maybe you could make a successful run HQ to reactivate the game.
Speaker 0: and now it is no longer ambiguous.
Speaker 0: It is clear.
Speaker 1: pretty much any games that have action point systems of any kind or like actions You can take tend to have until end of turn effects, right?
Speaker 0: but the point is you can see the difference between language that is not specific enough and Language that is specific enough, right?
Speaker 0: You covered all possible cases so that there are no game states that are do not match the rules.
Speaker 0: Right and no one has to ask any questions.
Speaker 0: we all the players can look at it and go.
Speaker 0: aha I know exactly what this card means.
Speaker 0: We don't have to ask about it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but even in that until yesterday everyone was like this card I don't know.
Speaker 1: the person who wrote that rule made an implicit assumption that of course, it's only this turn I would.
Speaker 1: why would anyone?
Speaker 1: you shouldn't be able to?
Speaker 1: why?
Speaker 1: how could you possibly use another turn?
Speaker 1: They assumed all that there was.
Speaker 0: actually there was a big update that fixed the words on a lot of cards even cards.
Speaker 0: We knew what they meant but had bad words.
Speaker 1: Yeah new the new person who's in charge is much better than the previous I got to admit in the modern era with any Moderately complex card game and up.
Speaker 0: I would never release it physically for these reasons But even by the amount of design in hearthstone They have something like people keep pointing out like cards with inconsistent word on them.
Speaker 0: They refuse to fix them for like various reasons Like if I'm making a card game I kind of want to make a card game that digitally just to show that I can do it better than all even though I Know it won't be successful.
Speaker 0: just to prove that I can do it better.
Speaker 1: You have Toronto who do it.
Speaker 1: You set it up.
Speaker 1: anyone who can run tournaments for your game has a phone number.
Speaker 1: they can call 24/7 to be like hey, we need a rules answer right now, right?
Speaker 0: But I mean, I just want to run a digital card game to prove that I can do it by myself Even better than these giant ass companies, you know, I won't have a fancy user interface.
Speaker 0: I won't have big infrastructure.
Speaker 0: My game, you know, who knows if my game will be any good, but at least I will.
Speaker 0: you know I'll be constantly modifying the game all the time to keep make sure it's fresh.
Speaker 0: I'll be won't have any rules ambiguities.
Speaker 0: Oh, you know all those things I'll get right.
Speaker 1: I wonder how consistent Billy and the Snake Man is probably garbage.
Speaker 1: And the follow-up question.
Speaker 1: What is the best rules argument you've ever had?
Speaker 1: It's actually I can imagine.
Speaker 0: you don't have rules arguments, right?
Speaker 0: It's like we just sort of go.
Speaker 0: what's the rule?
Speaker 0: Oh, oh, let's look.
Speaker 0: if we're not if we can't agree.
Speaker 0: Well, we mean what we look it up And if we can't find an answer online, it's like well fuck we don't know.
Speaker 0: fuck this game.
Speaker 1: Yep, if there's official or out of we follow it.
Speaker 1: if there isn't then unless we throw the game in the guard We either unanimously agree that we will interpret the rule as X forever more or we literally stop playing the game and never play.
Speaker 0: It's like Hellas is like the one we keep remembering a lot because like it was.
Speaker 0: like Hellas was such a promising game.
Speaker 0: You had little Greek.
Speaker 1: It felt so good.
Speaker 0: The two-player game and a tiny box and cards and little figures and a map and they were all Greek dudes.
Speaker 0: Yeah fighting and like that in a - that's a lot of good stuff for a two-player game.
Speaker 0: But this one card is like the most powerful card in the game very important and the rules for it were totally ambiguous.
Speaker 0: We couldn't get an answer.
Speaker 1: and the worst part was we thought well Let's try to play like.
Speaker 0: and that situation came up literally Every game we tried to play because every time we tried to use that card because if you had that card It was so strong.
Speaker 0: You wanted to use it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and it's like well, okay I feel like the biggest rules are can't play this game ever actually had were in those early days of playing D&D Where something hinky would happen and we'd all be fighting about how that was supposed to work out.
Speaker 1: or the big serious games of Illuminati we used to play.
Speaker 1: Because Illuminati has a lot of the rules are not ambiguous But they are complex and they don't map to other kinds of games that people like us often play.
Speaker 1: So unless everyone reads the rule book like within a few weeks I don't think is I don't?
Speaker 0: I mean, I definitely remember arguing playing Illuminati.
Speaker 0: There's no such game as Illuminati without our games are always.
Speaker 0: But now the arguments I remember.
Speaker 0: we're not about rules that are always about like, you know, see you guys need to attack rim Turn what the fuck is wrong with you not arguments like.
Speaker 0: no you can't do this.
Speaker 0: You can't do that.
Speaker 1: I remember a lot of arguments around privileged attacks and when and how they could be stopped and I remember a lot of argument about that.
Speaker 1: Uh I also attack.
Speaker 0: no one can assist he's privileged.
Speaker 1: I also remember having a very long argument about how to score farmers in Carcassonne but that was a long time ago when I brought Carcassonne to a gaming event in Upstate New York and I didn't bring the rules with me because I know that game and People disagreed as to how to score farmers.
Speaker 1: and that was when I learned that there are actually three different Official sets of rules for how to score farmers and base Carcassonne.
Speaker 0: I think you also if you're if you're playing games the people who are arguing about rules Like they insist that the rule is something, you know, either they're wrong or you're wrong, right?
Speaker 0: So it's not.
Speaker 0: it's not like an opinion matter.
Speaker 0: This is a factual matter you can look up and if there's no answer on the internet and Someone is still arguing and insisting that they're right and refuse, you know, it's like just don't play games with that person And don't play that game.
Speaker 1: Yep Well case in point look at board game geek.
Speaker 1: whenever there's a rules question and there's no official answer One of the first responses in that thread will be someone just giving an authoritative answer.
Speaker 1: Then you click on their profile and it's just Joey Jojo Shabba do from like Boise who doesn't know shit about games.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like if it's not an official answer, it's not an official answer.
Speaker 1: So apparently there's some cheating in a speed run, right?
Speaker 0: So generally I think of this.
Speaker 0: I only really pay a lot of attention to the speed running community for a GDQ as GDQ.
Speaker 0: Yep, right cuz I'm not super into it, right?
Speaker 0: You're never gonna catch me investing time in my life into being good at it Right, but I like it.
Speaker 0: I respect it.
Speaker 0: I enjoy it.
Speaker 0: But you know, it's not high on my hobby list.
Speaker 0: It's down there.
Speaker 0: right to tell you I thought about two times a year.
Speaker 0: That's enough.
Speaker 0: That's way more speed.
Speaker 0: That's like.
Speaker 0: I'm pretty big fan of speed running.
Speaker 1: if I'm looking at it twice a year at RIT I remember like I found out about speed runs like like that.
Speaker 1: They were wider community than I thought and I thought you know what?
Speaker 1: I'm real good about a command.
Speaker 1: I wonder if I could and I watched no world record run and then I played it and time myself and I and I was like, okay, could I shave like 15 minutes and nope.
Speaker 1: No, there's no way.
Speaker 0: I generally think of the speed running community as sort of like, you know Noble and good and full of good, you know, nice people.
Speaker 0: You know, there's been a few shitheads even an SGDQ AGDQ, but they just get their asses kicked out right away.
Speaker 1: I think if it like WWE and professional wrestling they are professionals doing performances, right?
Speaker 0: And you know, it generally feels like a pretty good community.
Speaker 0: as far as communities on the internet Go is not one of the bad ones.
Speaker 0: It's definitely far from one of the worst ones, right?
Speaker 0: So you did tend not to imagine there'd be too much cheating, especially since you know how much you know People are paying attention, right?
Speaker 0: They take these records pretty serious.
Speaker 1: I mean if the speed running community is doing a frame by frame tool assisted run I imagine they could figure out if you cheated on some friends.
Speaker 0: I never imagined like, you know Like why would you cheat?
Speaker 0: because someone could get you on it so easily that like when you actually they said All right, do it in front of me like oh you got the world record in that.
Speaker 0: All right well, you're streaming live.
Speaker 0: I've seen people do things like they're streaming right and Like to prove that your stream is not like some pre-recorded trick.
Speaker 0: people in the chat will be like You know put a shoe on your head shoe on the head and like you have to put a shoe on your head when they chat And that way you can prove they'll have like a camera on their hands.
Speaker 1: they'll show.
Speaker 0: Someone had a pre-recorded thing that they put on twitch or YouTube to make it seem like they were streaming live.
Speaker 0: Then you know when you said put a shoe on your head prove that that that you're not.
Speaker 0: this isn't pre-recorded.
Speaker 0: The person who's pre-recorded on the screen wouldn't put a shoe on.
Speaker 1: I watched one guy who actually had one of his webcams was pointed Over his shoulder so you could see the screen that he was streaming from another angle that also had him in it.
Speaker 1: Yep, to see that they're all synced up.
Speaker 1: Yeah,
Speaker 0: you know Peter and it's like imagine It's really hard to cheat, but now apparently people would just like editing videos together You know like cutting it like getting a really good run up to a certain frame and then do another run That's really good after that frame and then come you know Do you know?
Speaker 1: that's actually clever because if someone says show me you're good enough at the game to make a plausible attempt Yeah, and world record runs are rare.
Speaker 1: Like when it happens in a GDQ, it's kind of amazing, right?
Speaker 0: But basically, you know various people have cheated in this way by editing videos together you know right at that one exact frame line to make it look perfect.
Speaker 0: and So they got caught.
Speaker 0: some of the people.
Speaker 0: it is definitely a thing that happened this.
Speaker 1: articles about a famous speedrun.
Speaker 1: I think I've seen this one, right?
Speaker 0: So I think the deal was have I liked it as one guy One guy did it and another guy beat him by a little bit.
Speaker 0: So he went and cheated to like, you know Sort of come back and beat that guy by a whole bunch because he was upset that he lost his deal.
Speaker 0: But you know, you know what that is.
Speaker 1: that's going for the full web.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but he at least you know to Hand it to him.
Speaker 0: He was just like, alright guys, you got me I definitely cheated and you know, he's like just ban me.
Speaker 0: so they banned him.
Speaker 0: So I try thought about as but at least it wasn't like I didn't cheat right.
Speaker 0: that was the right response.
Speaker 0: if you You know if you do a bad thing, well, that's bad Don't do that.
Speaker 0: But you know, at least if you come out and say alright, I did the bad thing Just give me the punishment you receive the punishment.
Speaker 0: That's the way it's supposed to happen right?
Speaker 0: given this advice to people many times You can still at least you know, he got the.
Speaker 0: you're gonna get the punishment either way, right?
Speaker 0: If you would have gone rabble rabble rabble rabble, he would have still gotten bad.
Speaker 0: at least this way He's still like a respectable person, right?
Speaker 0: When confronted with something like this guy's some piece of shit.
Speaker 1: if you're confronted with something where you are wrong There are literally only three possible responses and all responses that you take are Actually just a flavor.
Speaker 1: one of these three one is Stonewall literally never respond to the accusations ever.
Speaker 1: To is deny and double down.
Speaker 1: and three is walk it back slash admit it.
Speaker 1: Yep Those are the only three things you can do, right?
Speaker 0: I think you know.
Speaker 0: something I say a lot is that you know people in the world have problems and problems need solutions.
Speaker 0: But then there are people who are not facing problems.
Speaker 0: They're facing consequences.
Speaker 0: You're facing a consequence, right?
Speaker 0: So it's like a Problem.
Speaker 0: I have no money solution.
Speaker 0: rob a bank.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right Problem I'm in jail cuz I robbed a bank solution.
Speaker 0: Well stay in jail till you're out don't right?
Speaker 1: try to double down.
Speaker 1: break out of jail.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: No don't do that, right?
Speaker 0: It's like it's tough shit already.
Speaker 0: You're facing when you're facing consequences of your own actions, right?
Speaker 0: You face them You don't?
Speaker 0: there's no solution to like making the consequences go away.
Speaker 0: You're beyond that point, right?
Speaker 0: You've already committed the crime.
Speaker 0: now you're paying for it.
Speaker 0: deal with it.
Speaker 1: As a kid in the VHS era like NES era like Nintendo Power and other people would run like contest sometimes where you had to submit a VHS tape of like a feat in a game or like a picture of your TV and The console everything showing that like you did it got a high score or something.
Speaker 1: I Tried to enter many of those contests as a kid by taking screenshots from issues of Nintendo Power with an actual camera and a magnifying device and Send them in because I knew the way these tournaments are.
Speaker 1: these things actually worked was Everyone who submitted who had a screenshot that was plausible was basically put into a raffle.
Speaker 1: So I would fake the screenshots to get into the raffle.
Speaker 1: I figured I wouldn't get looked at too closely and everything was so low resolution and low fidelity.
Speaker 1: back then I figured I get away with it, but aren't those things usually like nothing required to enter?
Speaker 0: You can just send a post self like a postcard or a self-addressed stamp sometimes Yeah, without even.
Speaker 1: but I want to point out I was a kid with a kid brain so I Remember one was like Nintendo Power was like give us a picture of you defeating war mech.
Speaker 1: I think it was the war mekker garland.
Speaker 1: I think was war mech with four white mages.
Speaker 1: But there was a screenshot of someone doing it in that Nintendo Power.
Speaker 1: so I took a picture of that Mm-hmm, even though the names would be the same as the Nintendo Power because I never really thought about the consequences would be if I was caught Which probably would have been nothing cuz I was a jail.
Speaker 0: Yeah faking Final Fantasy one screenshots jail.
Speaker 1: So you know what in one other news related to chief he lashes?
Speaker 1: Pokemon go Though I don't think that many people I know play it anymore.
Speaker 0: I know one person who still plays this game.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean it was fun while it lasted was like a month Not at all, and I'm very glad with my decision.
Speaker 0: I'm glad I played it all.
Speaker 1: I'm glad I played it when I did because me it was.
Speaker 1: basically I played an AR version of Pokemon snap For like a month, and then I just uninstalled it because it's gonna go play Pokemon.
Speaker 1: Sam I'm waiting for.
Speaker 1: actually you want a good a good Pokemon switch that you want a good use of VR would be Pokemon snap.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's like the perfect game for the current level of the.
Speaker 0: actually think What would be really much better than that would be AR where a right now, right?
Speaker 0: Pokemon go?
Speaker 0: no no no so you know I'm Pokemon go You you go on your phone, and there's the picture of the Pokemon in there right composited on the real world.
Speaker 0: No, what if you had a real fucking camera and when you look through it right there'd be Pokemon Instead of a phone?
Speaker 1: for most people a phone camera is a real camera.
Speaker 1: I don't know what a real can understand.
Speaker 0: like imagine if you you know you walk around the woods with a real camera and like suddenly There's like a real Pokemon out there But with the motion controls the switch can make one fucking Pokemon game.
Speaker 0: or if you were in some sort of like AR room and they handed you a you know basically a controller that was Basically the shape.
Speaker 0: well they are room that's installation VR, but the controller was basically a physically the shape of like a DSLR.
Speaker 0: Or was a DSLR or what?
Speaker 0: you know what I'm saying?
Speaker 0: you get the idea.
Speaker 1: But anyway Pokemon go is continuing to struggle with the problem.
Speaker 0: actually in Pokemon snap the actual n64 game you it was.
Speaker 0: you didn't walk Around freely.
Speaker 1: no you're on rails.
Speaker 0: You're on rails in like an amusement park ride.
Speaker 0: You could just make that in one room Right where you sit in a little cart and the screens on all the walls and they give you a can.
Speaker 1: that is why I'm saying It's such a good use case for current level VR.
Speaker 1: Take your chair with an oculus on.
Speaker 0: it could put it.
Speaker 0: You don't need that you could put at an amusement park.
Speaker 0: You can have them literally on rails.
Speaker 0: you ride around and there's Pokemon.
Speaker 0: you take pictures of them with your real fucking cam.
Speaker 1: That would basically be the Men in Black ride at Disney.
Speaker 0: Can you bring your camera on and take pictures?
Speaker 1: Well, no they give you a gun when you're sitting there, so oh Well, I never wrote that.
Speaker 0: I've written like spider-man, but they don't give you a gun or anything.
Speaker 0: You just sit in the spider-man in black
Speaker 1: ride is basically you sit in a car with you through your family and everyone gets guns And you got to shoot aliens while you're going through the ride And you'll and you'll see you'll pass by other cars of families, and if you shoot them it spins around and they lose points
Speaker 0: They actually
Speaker 1: get a score.
Speaker 0: We should do that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's a we Emily I did it when we were down there last year.
Speaker 0: that sounds like good ride.
Speaker 0: It's okay It's pretty good better than you know.
Speaker 0: that like back to the future whatever where you just sit in the car doesn't even move.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but the back to the future felt pretty good back then.
Speaker 0: back then I mean actually like the modern equivalent of that the Simpsons ride, holy shit That spider-man one that I mean that was that's even old by now.
Speaker 1: I went on like 2000 if you ever get a chance to go to universal.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the Simpsons ride is Impressive like it's on the edge of making you nauseous like it's really pushing the limits of that level of technology One where the spider-man one used to be.
Speaker 0: that you think.
Speaker 1: so I remember I rode the old Star Wars one.
Speaker 0: I did that too.
Speaker 0: They're also upgrading that shit.
Speaker 1: Yeah big time, but anyway Pokemon goes always had this problem where People who play the game quote-unquote seriously really quickly realize that it's just a grind.
Speaker 1: and then I'll say so a lot of them Cheats.
Speaker 1: you know I'm making finger quotes here because they cheat by using apps to give them more information in the game or just make the game like easier, so they don't have to literally grind it all out.
Speaker 1: and Niantic you know the company has been trying to catch those people.
Speaker 0: Why what do you give a shit?
Speaker 1: because the people who don't cheat get super fucking pissed.
Speaker 0: How do they even know?
Speaker 1: because they see people talking about on the Internet?
Speaker 1: Okay, and it feels unfair because they worked so hard and that other person just like spoof GPS and got all the Pokemon around the World.
Speaker 0: maybe you should just make your grind less stupid or maybe those people shouldn't care.
Speaker 1: But anyway what Niantic is doing now is basically hell-banning.
Speaker 1: So if they if they flag an account as having done anything that violates their TOS Which is basically almost anything then they just won't show you Like rare Pokemon anymore.
Speaker 1: Those never seem again in the game.
Speaker 1: Just make a new account Yeah, and start over and then get shadow banned again.
Speaker 1: Mmm, so this you'll steal someone else's account that I got.
Speaker 1: I'm telling you the way.
Speaker 1: the way to play Pokemon go now Is to legit be Team Rocket.
Speaker 1: go to Pokemon go meetups and parks at night and literally steal people's cell phones.
Speaker 1: Mmm, cuz that's Team Rocket, right?
Speaker 1: They steal Pokemon.
Speaker 1: You can literally mug a kid and steal his Pokemon in the real world.
Speaker 1: Thanks to Pokemon go.
Speaker 1: You can just steal someone's DS, too Yeah, but kids didn't wander around holding their DS's out like this like walking around a park at 3 in the morning Like they do with Pokemon go.
Speaker 0: I don't think anyone's doing that with Pokemon go anymore.
Speaker 1: I feel like that community has shrunk substantially and I feel like the people who continue to play are crazy and are going to double down on the game forever.
Speaker 1: but anyway things of the day.
Speaker 1: So Scott insisted this was the thing of the day in the past.
Speaker 1: I could not find any reference to it.
Speaker 0: This is old.
Speaker 0: I've seen it before.
Speaker 1: It's one year old.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's about the year.
Speaker 1: It's almost as a little past the one year anniversary of this video.
Speaker 0: I've seen it before.
Speaker 1: It's a gamer grognard looking, dude Telling you why hero quest is so great.
Speaker 0: hero quest is not so great.
Speaker 1: That is the point of this video.
Speaker 1: the format is the best thing about hero quest is something and he'll talk about that for a while and then he'll just say the best thing about hero quest is something.
Speaker 1: and I can actually imagine a kind of person who would watch this video not realize that it's making fun of them and hero quest and Agree with it.
Speaker 0: I think there was that there's a thread on reddit for this video and I'm pretty sure most of the people in that thread were Totally like like hero quests.
Speaker 1: Yeah I think you the moment you have to realize he's taking the piss is the best thing about hero quest is rolling for movement Because that is not the best.
Speaker 0: Well, actually it is as the number one thing that makes your request back.
Speaker 0: That is
Speaker 1: the number one thing that made hero quest great when we ruined it when we played it once as adults and agreed That I would literally roll and do nothing until we all until I rolled a six And then we would play our turns
Speaker 0: and this guy's a million views.
Speaker 1: So hey, yeah, it's a pretty funny video 32,000 likes 339 dislikes not too shabby.
Speaker 1: He's got more views than my entire YouTube channel on this video.
Speaker 1: Yeah That's what he got.
Speaker 0: Oh, so we've talked about Japanese wood joining before because it's way ridiculously awesome And there's like this.
Speaker 0: we talked about this Twitter account that had like Animated gifs of you know wood joining join.
Speaker 1: the Twitter account is so good, right?
Speaker 0: This is a guy who does wood joining as a hobby And he's got a YouTube channel and the whole YouTube channel is videos of actually doing wood joining and not just you know gifts of specific joints.
Speaker 0: And the videos in particular are like ultra relaxing like the way they're well On.
Speaker 1: the channel even says this is not a how-to video.
Speaker 1: just sit back and join me on my venture to find beautiful joinery.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so this could replace Bob Ross for you.
Speaker 0: If you've already watched the entire Bob Ross archive You know if you want to do some joining Don't watch this because he doesn't teach you how to do it.
Speaker 1: you're just watching a guy doing it and it's I do not want to do joining because I I Anticipate how complex it is and I had trouble like painting shitty miniatures as a kid.
Speaker 0: I mean, this is what you know.
Speaker 0: This is just on a list of all those zillions of awesome nerdy hobbies that I totally want to do but wouldn't invent.
Speaker 0: You know, yes enough time into to actually do like it's.
Speaker 0: like you see stuff like RC cars and paint.
Speaker 1: This is a hobby I would take up if I was Independently wealthy and bored.
Speaker 0: a skydiving like I would ever ruin my house even right But even then this would not be high rank high enough amongst all those other hobbies and I probably wouldn't do it.
Speaker 1: No, I would do it at the same level that jet black did bonsai and cowboy bebop, right?
Speaker 0: It was actually.
Speaker 0: we interviewed a guy today where skydiving is like his number one hobby.
Speaker 0: Oh skydive like, you know without a no tandem or anything.
Speaker 0: Oh, that means you like you do like seven or eight times a year.
Speaker 0: He goes skydiving.
Speaker 0: So you want to go skydiving?
Speaker 0: Yeah, but not seven or eight times.
Speaker 0: One time is enough.
Speaker 1: we go bungee jumping instead.
Speaker 0: That's even easier.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you don't have to know anything.
Speaker 1: There's literally.
Speaker 1: there's literally no skill.
Speaker 1: You can learn to make bungee jumping more exciting.
Speaker 0: you jump Or you get pushed if they if you won't jump or they don't push you and you just go back down the stairs.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like a baby In the meta moment the booklet book is Frank Herbert's dune.
Speaker 1: I began in So maybe I'll read the book now.
Speaker 0: I haven't played a Zelda.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna go back to it after some other games and so I got a lot to say about Zelda.
Speaker 1: Now that I've played the whole thing I mean, I didn't get I didn't 100% it and I'm never going to.
Speaker 0: I don't think I will either.
Speaker 0: Anthony 100% of it Every Korok seed.
Speaker 0: Yeah, what is it?
Speaker 1: So yeah, I learned spoilers as to what happens.
Speaker 1: It's actually kind of great and I will not spoil.
Speaker 1: do not spoil for yourself the deal of the Korok seeds Because if you get all of them you learn something about the world of Zelda.
Speaker 0: Oh, really?
Speaker 1: You legit learn a thing.
Speaker 1: This is cannon the thing you learn.
Speaker 0: I didn't think you got anything for getting all the Korok seeds.
Speaker 0: I thought it was just alright Korok seeds.
Speaker 1: You learn something very specific about the canonical world of the Legend of Zelda Breath of the Wild about Korok's.
Speaker 1: Like you learn a thing.
Speaker 1: There's a revelation that happens.
Speaker 0: Let's just look it up.
Speaker 1: I'm saying it's almost better if you never look it up, but I'm not getting 900 Korok seeds in my.
Speaker 1: I got 107.
Speaker 0: I just didn't care and I don't know how many I have.
Speaker 0: it's enough and I don't need more slots.
Speaker 0: I think I did 87 shrines.
Speaker 1: I want to say I don't know how many shrines I did though The last run I did before I just said fuck it and killed Ganon was.
Speaker 1: I even tied Island.
Speaker 1: That was a pleasant surprise.
Speaker 0: I told you to go to event at island.
Speaker 1: I see it over there and I'm like, huh?
Speaker 1: I bet there's stuff.
Speaker 0: No, I told you go to it like ten times.
Speaker 1: Yeah No, I saw it a bunch of times.
Speaker 1: then you were like you should go over there and I was like, okay so I finally went over there and stuff happens over there.
Speaker 1: that was tight island was there was unexpected and The high knocks was that was the cream on that cake.
Speaker 1: because I was like, okay I can deal with the thing that is happening to me.
Speaker 1: and then I saw the high knocks.
Speaker 0: I'm like, ah fuck I got a traveler's sword and then it breaks.
Speaker 1: Oh my god That was some good stuff.
Speaker 1: but Ganon goes down like a chump.
Speaker 1: I highly recommend if you're at all Burning out like if you at any point feel the slightest hint of boredom was not to the wild Just go kill Ganon and then put the game aside and pick it back up after a break because Ganon's way Way easy.
Speaker 0: I haven't even gone to Goron land at all.
Speaker 1: I killed Ganon pretty much just with ancient arrows for my 5x line elbow.
Speaker 0: Well, I mean that's a 5x line elbow.
Speaker 0: I had like ancient arrows that you're really strong.
Speaker 1: I have like 80 ancient arrows because I just bought them all because why not?
Speaker 0: I made ancient armor instead of ancient.
Speaker 1: I did not get the ancient armor because who cares?
Speaker 0: I want to be able to go up to ancients and be like can't touch Me, brah.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm so strong.
Speaker 1: I just go up to ancients anyway.
Speaker 1: You know what?
Speaker 1: I wear.
Speaker 1: I wear the Zora suit or the climbing suit all the time and I only wear the snow quill when I'm in like Hebrew anyway, anyway, it's good stuff.
Speaker 1: otherwise Scott's YouTube channel my deep channel the utenna shows starting up again soon because I just finally got time to work on that stuff and I will link to it in this episode.
Speaker 1: You should definitely check out because on my youtube channel I am taking literally every tabletop review we have ever done.
Speaker 1: I'm taking just the review itself out of the longer geek nights episodes and putting them on YouTube is like Just reviews of the thing.
Speaker 1: So if you have joined geek nights Sometime later than 12 years ago and you want to see our review of like some old tabletop game And you don't listen to an hour-long bad episode of geek nights from like nine years ago This is your source for just the reviews.
Speaker 1: so tumble seed.
Speaker 1: We were at PAX Prime packs West while last year was a year ago, right?
Speaker 0: It wasn't the most recent is I think it was two packs West's ago?
Speaker 1: Maybe it was one or two packs West's ago because if you haven't been to PAX West in a while Like it is expanded and sprawled Across Seattle into places.
Speaker 1: You would have never thought pretty sure.
Speaker 0: we talked about it on the podcast.
Speaker 0: We talked about that packs us.
Speaker 0: But anyway, there's a cards against humanity area that we had ignored the year before and we went into it this time Way big.
Speaker 0: it was way bigger than I thought and I had a bunch of rooms and not all of it was cards against humanity.
Speaker 0: There were lots of demos of indie tabletop and video games in there in addition to the cards against humanity store.
Speaker 0: I think they had like 10 bajillion copies of secret Hitler for sale.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but anyway One of the things we saw in there that really, you know It was very very memorable was the demo of the pre not released yet game called tumble seed and we saw it.
Speaker 0: Holy shit, that game is ice cold beer but a video game, but it looks cute.
Speaker 0: Oh my god That is a game for us.
Speaker 1: I mean we literally we walk in the room and we're looking at it We don't say anything.
Speaker 1: and I was looking at each other and scouts like ice cold beer and I'm like, it's ice cold beer It's I.
Speaker 0: so if you don't know ice cold beer is a game that we discovered the first time we ever went to mag fest.
Speaker 0: It was a big deal at that mag fest.
Speaker 0: They still have it at mag fest But it doesn't seem to be a big deal there anymore.
Speaker 0: and what that game is is an arcade machine and the arcade machine has Vertical piece of wood with a bunch of holes in it.
Speaker 0: So it's like you're looking straight on at a piece of Swiss cheese.
Speaker 0: Yep, and as a metal ball a smaller than a pinball, right?
Speaker 0: It's just small bearing and it's on a metal bar.
Speaker 1: so it can roll to the left or to the right and the metal bar Is sort of it's articulated like like I was about to say an antenna on a car.
Speaker 1: But no car antenna looks like that.
Speaker 0: You have two joysticks.
Speaker 0: one Joystick will raise the left side of the metal bar up and down and the other joystick will raise the right side of the bar Up-and-down.
Speaker 0: So if you move both sticks in unison up, you will lift the ball that is resting on this bar Straight up and if you bring both sticks down, it'll go straight down.
Speaker 0: If you put the right stick down The ball will roll to the right and you put the left stick down the ball roll to the left and you want to get The ball from the bottom to the top without falling through any of the holes in the Swiss cheese.
Speaker 0: and it's hard as balls.
Speaker 1: Yeah, everyone is.
Speaker 1: everyone is that year that first year.
Speaker 1: We saw this at mag fest.
Speaker 1: when we started going to mag fest all of us were like that.
Speaker 1: game looks cool and one by one on our own we all went over there and played it and discovered that it is As hard as you think it's gonna be.
Speaker 1: it is so much harder than that that it is beyond description.
Speaker 0: Now, of course, there are people who are masters at this and do it.
Speaker 1: I watched a dude at mag fest.
Speaker 1: just go all the way to the top first.
Speaker 1: try like just like I guess he memorized it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, he's such precision in the hands.
Speaker 1: I just learned himself looking at the Wikipedia.
Speaker 1: It's a title game.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but It was released in 1983.
Speaker 1: It was re-released in 2003 by a different company with a Ticket dispenser and LEDs and all this new biz, but it's otherwise the exact same game.
Speaker 0: Yeah, why not?
Speaker 1: The only other time it's ever been re-released was in 1984 when Taito released an identical game But they called it Zeke's peak.
Speaker 0: I've seen that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it doesn't have beer on it.
Speaker 1: You know Zeke is Uh No, he's the main character in another title game zookeeper.
Speaker 1: Oh Love me some zookeeper keepers some hot shit.
Speaker 0: But anyway, yeah The other cool thing about this if you have one of these arcade machines You can just get a piece of wood and drill your own holes in it and make your own board and sort of swap them Out.
Speaker 0: I don't think there's any official thing for that.
Speaker 0: But you could.
Speaker 0: there's no reason you couldn't.
Speaker 0: it's just a piece of wood with Holes in it.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: But also this game was like like I guess you'd see it mostly in bars and like non-traditional Arcades, it's definitely a thing to eat your quarters, right?
Speaker 0: Cuz like you're really you go to it.
Speaker 0: You see how it works.
Speaker 0: It's kind of fun.
Speaker 0: It's got a physical ball rolling around in there.
Speaker 0: You really want to beat it and as you keep putting quarters and you get better and better and better with more practice and
Speaker 1: it Has a performative aspect where other people see you doing it and get excited
Speaker 0: Especially if you're getting close, right but you
Speaker 1: watching other people if you don't play it It kind of draws you into wanting to play it same like DDR would do the same thing.
Speaker 0: I'll see you a lot of money to practice enough to be able to be good at it.
Speaker 1: I never even conceived of.
Speaker 1: hey someone should remake this kind of game.
Speaker 0: No So we saw this as someone made a video game version of it.
Speaker 0: and not only that but it was really cute your little seed tumbling around on a vine.
Speaker 0: that's a basically the metal bar.
Speaker 0: and You know suddenly there's a whole bunch of interactive stuff going on because it's not just a piece of wood It's a video game.
Speaker 1: and then to go one step further the next piece of information We learned about this game later was that not only is it those mechanics?
Speaker 1: But it's a roguelike.
Speaker 1: what the Roguelike?
Speaker 1: X ice-cold beer?
Speaker 1: That's the kind of crazy idea.
Speaker 1: We come up with randomly in a panel and people like wow That's a crazy idea and someone just did it.
Speaker 0: So the game finally came out.
Speaker 0: I've been I was I saw I subscribed to like.
Speaker 0: the email me when the game is out thing.
Speaker 0: I'm not seeing it effects and it came out.
Speaker 0: and Because of the timing when it came out It was originally gonna be on like we use steam whatever and I would still probably recommend the steam version.
Speaker 0: Except I got a Nintendo switch and they just put it out on switch.
Speaker 0: Yeah so I paid but 15 bucks or whatever it is.
Speaker 0: and why did I do that instead of getting the steam one or waiting for the steam one to Be cheap?
Speaker 1: because the switch is literally the perfect medium for this kind of game.
Speaker 0: It's so portable.
Speaker 1: Well portable but also if you play the switch like handheld the two controls are on the sides of the screen Just like.
Speaker 1: yeah, the bar is like it feels.
Speaker 1: really it feels right.
Speaker 0: also the switch pro controller is so good.
Speaker 0: It's not it the Xbox controller that I'd be using if I played on the PC not as good.
Speaker 1: So yeah, it wouldn't feel.
Speaker 1: plus that I honestly the you know that the fancy rumble in the switch Really works with this game.
Speaker 0: The switch has the most advanced like rumbling of any rumble any controller that exists.
Speaker 0: So it feels like there's a physical ball bearing rolling.
Speaker 0: It takes between.
Speaker 0: They take the maximum advantage of that HD rumbling.
Speaker 0: You can actually feel that ball Just like even more so than you could feel it if you're playing the real ice-cold beer.
Speaker 1: So if you couldn't guess this game is hard as balls, right?
Speaker 0: I didn't realize that I thought it was gonna be like oh a kid looks so cute, right?
Speaker 0: Don't be deceived if you're looking but it's based on ice cold beer.
Speaker 1: That's like saying a game that's based on Dark Souls and assuming.
Speaker 1: Oh, it's cute.
Speaker 1: It'll probably be easy.
Speaker 0: Don't be full.
Speaker 0: This game is not for people who like cute seeds and bugs and things.
Speaker 0: that if you like what it looks like That is not enough reason to pay.
Speaker 0: don't just keep your money right.
Speaker 0: you only buy this if you're the kind of person who likes Super hexagon or something.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if you like insanely difficult Dexterity games.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's when you should buy this game.
Speaker 0: So like.
Speaker 0: I've gotten to the point where I can beat level one pretty reliably But level two if I'm if I beat level one really strongly Then I can do level two and then if I get to level three, it's just like oh fuck you instant death, right?
Speaker 0: So here's how the game works.
Speaker 0: Not only is it the the Swiss cheese, right?
Speaker 0: But there's also enemies that come around Yep, a lot of the enemies are just basically moving holes.
Speaker 0: You can just dodge them.
Speaker 1: not a big deal But some of them have active like if they see you they hit you some of it.
Speaker 0: Well, some of them will chase you the fuck down which means you must kill them, right?
Speaker 0: You have no or move real fast.
Speaker 0: Good luck with that.
Speaker 0: You have hearts so you start with three hearts.
Speaker 0: you can get more with difficulty and if you get hit without fault without Like dying then you lose hearts.
Speaker 0: If you actually if you fall in the holes in the in the Swiss cheese, but only do you lose hearts you don't actually Just lose a heart.
Speaker 0: Yeah You fall down and the farther you fall the more hearts you lose to you.
Speaker 0: if you fall from a great height You lose a whole lot of hearts and die instantly.
Speaker 0: So yeah, it sucks.
Speaker 0: So you also have crystals.
Speaker 0: you start the game with one fucking crystal and you can get more crystals by picking them up off the ground.
Speaker 0: Killing enemies sometimes will drop enemies Always pretty much but you get crystals.
Speaker 0: then you can.
Speaker 0: there's plots on the ground that are diamond shape.
Speaker 1: now This is what's clever.
Speaker 1: They they basically I imagine the developers of the game said we're gonna make an ice-cold beer roguelike I assume they.
Speaker 1: they saw ice-cold beer, right?
Speaker 1: So you but they they explored it as much as possible.
Speaker 1: so they don't just have holes to kill you.
Speaker 1: They have plots to attract you, right?
Speaker 0: so you want to go on these plots and what happens is you can switch which seed you are and you with four seeds and you can get more or check cash a man and get different seeds, but each seed is an ability sort of like curvy and When you roll over a plot based on what seed you have selected and you could change your seeds anytime from the ones that you have That is what will happen when you roll over the plot.
Speaker 0: So the flag flag seed is the one you sort of start as and what that does is for absolutely free.
Speaker 0: When you roll over a plot it puts a flag there checkpoint And if you die by falling in a hole you will come out at that checkpoint where you put that flag.
Speaker 1: I try to avoid using that because I'm not a baby.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you don't want to use it.
Speaker 0: But like if you're in level two or three and you've made it quite a distance you put down a flag.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so well think of it like, you know in Like games where you like a shovel knight or you could destroy the checkpoint to get some loot or use the checkpoint.
Speaker 0: But anyway, the next one is the crystal see.
Speaker 0: the crystal see you want to sort of avoid using because it sucks But sometimes you have to use it.
Speaker 0: It's remote.
Speaker 0: I think of yeah The way the crystal one works is you when you've hit one plot nothing happens.
Speaker 0: you get the second plot Nothing happens, but when you hit the third plot with the crystal seed two crystals come out.
Speaker 0: So you pretty much only use this when you're desperate for crystals because once the game is starts going and you're like getting halfway Through level one.
Speaker 0: You should have a ton of crystals and not really need anymore, right?
Speaker 0: So usually I cash in that crystal seed and get a different seed.
Speaker 0: The third seed is the spike thorn seed and what this does is you roll over a plot you lose a crystal and you know cut and you get a thorn that now like spins around you right and you can make a whole big shield out of Thorns.
Speaker 0: and when you bump into bad guys You can kill them with your thorns.
Speaker 0: and if a bad guy shoots guns at you and they hit you.
Speaker 0: if they hit a thorn You just lose the thorn.
Speaker 0: You don't get hit.
Speaker 0: if you can, you know, sort of did So like these are your weapons and also your shields.
Speaker 0: That are the basic ones a melee weapon.
Speaker 1: and then there's well a bunch more that are way increasingly crazy and complex.
Speaker 0: Well, there's the other non complex.
Speaker 0: was the heart?
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, if you get the heart seed you go one.
Speaker 0: It costs you a crystal to go to a plot with a heart But once you've done four plots with four crystals, you actually increase your life by one heart total.
Speaker 1: Oh, uh cold guy confirmed that the guys the designers of this game were ice-cold beer pro players.
Speaker 0: Okay, so that's why they think it's easy.
Speaker 0: Yeah So you try to avoid using the crystal seed.
Speaker 0: I use the heart seed a lot But I guess if you're really good, you don't need to really.
Speaker 1: they were in an ice-cold beer league.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you don't need to use the heart seed either if you're really good, right?
Speaker 0: So but What?
Speaker 0: the thing that makes this game even harder than like it's a freaking ice-cold beer.
Speaker 0: There's a million holes in the board.
Speaker 0: The bad guys are coming at you like crazy is that if you get hit.
Speaker 0: when you lose a heart you lose all your thorns.
Speaker 0: Yep, all of them.
Speaker 0: It's like I've been in situations where I got like a fuck ton of thorns and a bad guy hits me and I just lose them All.
Speaker 0: and now the real resource in this game is not the crystals.
Speaker 0: It is the plots.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I felt I fall backwards.
Speaker 1: I have to climb back up to where I've already used all those plots.
Speaker 0: All those plots are used.
Speaker 0: There's no more plots and I'm running out of hearts and I'll fuck me.
Speaker 0: I'm basically done even though it's like it's not actually a one-shot kill But it might as well be just reset.
Speaker 1: now does some nice stuff Like if you fall in a hole it turns that hole into a plot big deal so you won't die Fucking fly.
Speaker 1: It's subtle, but it's there.
Speaker 0: Yeah, whatever.
Speaker 1: Whatever That's how you solve some of the puzzles in the puzzle.
Speaker 0: The other thing is you can get more seeds with more abilities, right?
Speaker 0: But the problem is the vast majority of these extra abilities you can get are just gonna fuck you over.
Speaker 0: There's one that's like, okay Projectiles are now bigger.
Speaker 0: Also the bad guys project doesn't happen.
Speaker 0: There's one that you think could be like the best possible one is the magnet power.
Speaker 0: It sucks crystals into you if they're lying on the ground because sometimes the crystal will be like on the edge of a pin Right, so you don't have to roll over there and get it.
Speaker 0: So now you can just sort of casually go safely up the board and get a lot of crystals without having to put in A lot of effort and that's super good.
Speaker 0: But you know what?
Speaker 0: There's a few crystal shaped bad guys that will.
Speaker 0: you'll suck them into motherfucker and they're all over the motherfucker.
Speaker 0: They're all over the place.
Speaker 0: there's like almost no ability.
Speaker 0: There's an ability that's like oh you get a friend who bounces around the screen dealing damage.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that guy's not your friend.
Speaker 0: He does around the screen dealing damage to bad guys, but also to you.
Speaker 0: Good luck.
Speaker 1: So I mean this this game is great Qualified with you either have to be really into dexterity games really into ice-cold beer specifically.
Speaker 1: Uh That's it like that's who this game is for.
Speaker 0: I can't really say like.
Speaker 0: I've been playing this game and I you know Despite it being so hard and annoying like I haven't yet given up on it Like I'm still playing it like once a day twice a day or whatever.
Speaker 0: like, you know It you know and this there's a daily thing where like everyone gets the same Board because it rent.
Speaker 0: it's procedurally generated.
Speaker 0: It's a roguelike, right?
Speaker 0: No, it's different.
Speaker 0: every time you play I have a decker dancer has that to the daily challenge.
Speaker 0: I haven't reached the top yet But there's a daily challenge and even on the switch it connects to the internet and downloads the daily challenge properly.
Speaker 1: So that's that's a pretty cool thing you can do, but I would say that if you are an enthusiast of games not just like a gamer who plays games like you're interested in game design or you care more about like the Theory of games or anything like that.
Speaker 1: You should get this game just because there's literally nothing else like it.
Speaker 0: No, this is absolutely 100% unique game.
Speaker 1: This is in a genre where there are literally only two entries.
Speaker 1: There is ice-cold beer and there is this and roguelikes.
Speaker 0: Yes, but is this rogue and ice-cold beer?
Speaker 0: But this is the combination of the two.
Speaker 0: and yeah, a lot of people are doing the combined two games thing lately But no one's done to combine these two games.
Speaker 1: Yep, right in this kind of way It's just kind of amazing that it came to pass and it's clear.
Speaker 1: you know that they.
Speaker 1: they clearly took a very simple concept and tried to Add as much depth and complexity and interesting situations as they could while never Straying from that core mechanic.
Speaker 0: The only thing I would say is that you know when I look at how far I'm getting up The mountain before dying.
Speaker 0: I'm actually like kind of halfway or even more than halfway up.
Speaker 0: It just gets ridiculously hard I think they.
Speaker 0: I would have liked it if they would have made the mountain taller and Had more of a curve of difficulty like why not go back to ice-cold beer?
Speaker 1: ice-cold beer is easy easy And then it just goes from impossible to more impossible.
Speaker 0: I know this exponential curve of difficulty.
Speaker 0: No, this goes from immediately hard and then impossible and then like even worse than doom nightmare mode impossible.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's just like I would have liked them to stretch out that curve a little more to be more linear and less exponential.
Speaker 0: So it's like start off ridiculously easy get challenging Right and then get hard.
Speaker 0: and you know, let me enjoy the game more before you brutally kill me.
Speaker 0: I'm not saying don't brutally kill me.
Speaker 0: I'm just saying give me like one or two more.
Speaker 0: You know climbs worth of space before, you know, cuz like at the beginning of like level two.
Speaker 0: It's like they send a snake and a guy after you who shoots at you constantly And if you don't already have enough spikes or weapons to take them out you're dead.
Speaker 0: And also there's a million holes right there.
Speaker 0: Good luck dodging the holes and those guys.
Speaker 0: It's just like level two starts.
Speaker 0: Good luck.
Speaker 1: You're dead, but at the same time there's only so much you can do with this.
Speaker 1: We have to start to level three, so I appreciate the fact that it escalates itself rapidly to be a more succinct experience much like A good example of other games they've done like Jenga babies play safe moves for a long time.
Speaker 1: pros Destabilize the tower as much as possible as early as possible.
Speaker 0: I just want to enjoy my $15.
Speaker 0: I spent more.
Speaker 1: I'm playing it for the experience.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the experience is gonna be one minute long.
Speaker 1: Yeah I was trying to play it last night.
Speaker 1: It was just five.
Speaker 1: I did better when I Threw caution to the wind kind of like in Mario games like especially 2d Mario's like the older ones.
Speaker 1: The more you just went for it the better you tended to do.
Speaker 0: I tend to alternate between being careful and going for it Right, you know and what ends up happening.
Speaker 1: usually if I get hit not in a hole I'm just like fuck it.
Speaker 1: Go go go go go go go go.
Speaker 0: The situation that usually kills me is when there's too much going on and like I'm like one bad guy comes He's a really dangerous.
Speaker 0: So I try to carefully take care of him and like when not a lot is going on It's a little safer then I can sort of go for it.
Speaker 0: But when like multiple hazards all at once It's like I'm forced to go for it, but I'm not I can't.
Speaker 1: I can't even beat ice-cold beer.
Speaker 1: I played that game a lot and there's no bugs in there unless there's I guess termites in the cabinet.
Speaker 1: There's literally just the holes.
Speaker 1: you can take as long as you need These two quotes.
Speaker 1: I've never really looked at the site for the game much before but I'm looking at these quotes here.
Speaker 1: So Jerry Hawkins a game about moving laterally in a world that hates you.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm and Adam Selzmann says the Dark Souls of marble rolls.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there is some sort of lore in this game.
Speaker 0: Like you can talk to kids.
Speaker 0: It's RPG roguelike, right?
Speaker 1: This character like going to talk to the elder.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you can talk to people.
Speaker 0: they say stuff and there's some kind of.
Speaker 0: there's like us.
Speaker 0: occasionally you'll enter like in the middle of The map.
Speaker 0: there'll be like this you can go.
Speaker 0: It seems like an abandoned hut with a lab that got destroyed or something and there's some sort of plot of mystic shit going on.
Speaker 0: But I'd have to be able to reach the tap to know what's going on with it.
Speaker 1: I'm on the website.
Speaker 1: I never.
Speaker 1: I never went to their website quote originally inspired by the forgotten arcade classic ice-cold bear.
Speaker 1: yeah, Tumblesee is made by five people in Chicago Benedict Greg Joel David and Jenna and a bunch of their friends and published by iowoo.
Speaker 0: Okay so I if you hate yourself if you hate yourself and you own a Nintendo switch or you can just plan steam I Get it on ps4 or you can get it on like, you know anything just it's.
Speaker 1: uh it's refreshing that a game like this was able to be made and came out because like The the lineage of this game is kind of insane when you think about it.
Speaker 1: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Speaker 0: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 1: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows It's actually recorded at night.
Speaker 1: and the patreon patrons for this episode of geek nights are Nicholas Brando Alan Joyce, Heidi McNichol Amanda Duchette and Thomas.
Speaker 1: on my state calm William Isen rose Jeremy minor Hey, llama llama red pajama reads the story.
Speaker 1: with who?
Speaker 1: with his mama a genuine bonafide electrified six car monorail, Rebecca Done this terrible secret of space for two one creations want to talk about it sure run horrible rare Laval James David White Rochelle, Montanona Superboy.
Speaker 1: I paid five bucks to make rim say pickle sailor Vista Matthew Smith Don Schleich jar topics and Joshua Joe starts Sean Yeager Sam quarter Clinton Walton Ren from New Zealand Ryan Perrin USA.
Speaker 1: Okay, Brian's Adroni the space-time vector of an african-european smaller carrying kiwis redacted.
Speaker 1: Chris midkiff Chris Knox Daniel Redmond Sean Klein Chris Reimer and Thomas on.
Speaker 1: and now I leave you with Something your buddy's mind gonna tell you.
Speaker 1: right you should show your face in the broad daylight.
Speaker 1: I'm telling you how I feel gonna hurt your mind.
Speaker 1: Don't shoot to kill.
Speaker 1: Come on.
Speaker 1: Come on lay it on me.
Speaker 1: All right, I'm giving you one on the count of three to show you stuff or let it be.
Speaker 1: I'm telling you just watch your mouth.
Speaker 1: I know you game.
Speaker 1: What about you?
Speaker 1: Well, I say this guy's a limiting to me.
Speaker 1: That's really true But my friend you see nothing.
Speaker 1: just wait like it because I'm bad bad.
Speaker 1: Come on.
Speaker 1: Come on that bad really really bad.
Speaker 1: You know, I'm bad.
Speaker 1: I'm bad.
Speaker 1: You know it, you know very bad really really bad.
Speaker 1: You know, I'm bad I'm bad.
Speaker 1: Come on.
Speaker 1: Come on, you know bad bad really really bad and the whole world is the answer Just right.
Speaker 1: Just tell just tell you once again who's bad.