Speaker 0: It's Tuesday, November 7th, 2017.
Speaker 0: I'm rim.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott and this is geek nights.
Speaker 0: tonight We're talking about the 2010 board game Luna in the domain of the moon.
Speaker 1: priestess Let's do this.
Speaker 0: So it's definitely too late for any of you who are listening to this.
Speaker 0: So rather than telling you that you should go vote if you didn't vote Mmm Eat on it.
Speaker 1: A lot of people listening to this don't even live in the United States.
Speaker 1: Maybe whatever country they live in their voting day is today Or maybe someone's listening to this way after the day we recorded it in.
Speaker 1: their voting day is today.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, that's possible.
Speaker 0: But if it is if it is 2017 and it's only in the United States for you vote in the second Tuesday in November And you're an American citizen.
Speaker 0: So we have elections every four years that like half of us vote in and we have elections every two years That are just as important that like a quarter of us voted and then we have elections every year that like
Speaker 1: in the no-one
Speaker 0: Vote say yeah
Speaker 1: those in-between years.
Speaker 1: It's like in New York.
Speaker 1: It's basically like one year which is this year you vote for like mayor and shit And then the next year you vote for governor and shit and then the year after that you vote for like state Represent.
Speaker 1: it's all mixed up.
Speaker 1: You basically keep voting for different people in different parts of government every year.
Speaker 0: Many layers most Americans don't vote in.
Speaker 0: really any of those except the president won.
Speaker 0: Yep, so yeah, if you didn't vote you really should have voted and if you're in New York You probably should have voted against having a constitutional convention.
Speaker 0: No, probably.
Speaker 1: I mean that one wasn't really, you know, the biggest deal either way.
Speaker 0: Nah But I guess my mother the only point I want to make is I don't want.
Speaker 0: this isn't a politics episode and because there's no Way, you'll listen to this before the voting.
Speaker 0: We'll already know why.
Speaker 1: the time you hear this will already know what happened.
Speaker 0: yep, but what I will say is that You should vote even in the small elections where someone is running uncontested because even they're Casting an actual ballot and being a member of a party.
Speaker 0: when you cast that ballot It does.
Speaker 0: one thing that's very important in the?
Speaker 0: u.s Is a clear signal to that party that you will show up in the next year's election And they will use that data accordingly.
Speaker 0: if they know you're reliable and you're going to show up They're much more likely to listen to what your little district cares about a little bit in a way that they will not Certain causes in the u.s Tend to not get a lot of traction because the people who care about those causes are not the kind of people who vote
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: if there's some tiny election and someone's running uncontested and like, you know, you know in some tiny town 10,000 extra people come up and just vote yes for that uncontested person.
Speaker 1: They go.
Speaker 1: Oh, I got these 10,000 people.
Speaker 1: Yes for me no matter what.
Speaker 1: so then when rich guy says hey politician Why don't you do some evil evil?
Speaker 1: They say I don't need your money.
Speaker 1: evil, man I can do what I believe in because I got these 10,000 people who vote for me.
Speaker 1: when I'm on contested I'm not afraid of being not elected again.
Speaker 1: Get your ass out of here evil person unless they are an evil person in which case contest them.
Speaker 1: if they're just greedy and they're taking the money and listening to the rich person and not to you that they know You show up They know that you're paying attention and showing up to vote and then you know If you're all staying at home, they go.
Speaker 1: Ah, these people staying at home.
Speaker 1: They're ignoring my evil ways.
Speaker 1: I can continue my evil ways unpunished And that's what they do.
Speaker 0: But that aside we got a bunch of gaming news before we talk about this Luna game Which I didn't realize was as old as it is because I didn't really.
Speaker 1: how old is it?
Speaker 0: 2010.
Speaker 0: That's not that old seven years Anyway, anyway, so in the news, this is such a minor thing, but it's pretty funny.
Speaker 0: Scott Pointed this out to me.
Speaker 1: It's barely a news.
Speaker 0: Yeah But there's a casting call in New York for people who play netrunner to be on a Showtime show Where they need ten people playing netrunner.
Speaker 1: So our local netrunner community organizer person I guess was the point of contact for this and was like hey He spread the word about it And like I'm I can't figure out the whole deal.
Speaker 1: But basically there's gonna be some scene in this show called billions, which I've never watched.
Speaker 0: I've never even heard of.
Speaker 0: I have heard of it because how how have you heard of it?
Speaker 1: so the show billions is about it's it's a Obviously fictional is like Brewster's millions.
Speaker 1: But no, it is a fictional adaptation of real life events involving former US Attorney Preet Bharara.
Speaker 1: And I listen to former US Attorney Preet Bharara's podcast And he was like he mentioned on the show how his parents were so proud there's gonna be a TV show about their You know awesome lawyer son.
Speaker 1: And then they started watching the first beginning of the show and it's like some sexy garbage trash TV scene.
Speaker 0: Well, it is Showtime.
Speaker 1: and then he's like well done with that garbage.
Speaker 1: Which is why a major reason one of the many major reasons I don't watch live-action.
Speaker 0: Are they gonna kiss?
Speaker 0: are they gonna fight any?
Speaker 0: are they fighting over that girl in the middle?
Speaker 0: Is that what's going on?
Speaker 1: It's some garbage us live-action drama crap.
Speaker 1: You don't need to watch this show except for the netrunner scene.
Speaker 1: That will be on YouTube for sure but it's like To do this thing.
Speaker 1: apparently the details are still sparse, but you get paid like $250 for a day of work Which ain't bad.
Speaker 0: Yeah, especially if you don't have a high paying job or you're like, that's pretty good.
Speaker 0: You're a punk kid?
Speaker 0: Yeah, go for it.
Speaker 1: That's pretty good money.
Speaker 1: There are people who know how to actually know how to play netrunner and the fact that they know how to play netrunner I guess is important.
Speaker 1: shows that the game will somehow feature in the show and not just be a backdrop, but they're.
Speaker 1: Apparently there's some scene and the setting of the scene is a netrunner Tournament or event and therefore they need to create this scene and which is why they need these extras to play netrunner there.
Speaker 1: And apparently it's not in New York City.
Speaker 1: They're getting people from New York to get on some mode of transportation.
Speaker 1: Wait what and take them to the Hamptons where the filming will occur way that that is definitely for a very long period of time.
Speaker 1: I think you get on it like three or something and they'll take you there and you'll come back like way late.
Speaker 0: That is definitely a murder cabin.
Speaker 1: No one's coming home from Thursday night through, you know, Friday morning.
Speaker 1: Who knows when you'll get back you getting paid money good money for it that amount of hours of work.
Speaker 1: Well, you know if I play netrunner So I know you can complain about if I didn't have anything better to do that would be an experience.
Speaker 0: I
Speaker 1: just I hope that they Obviously, it's too much hassle for me to do it Even though the money is even okay for someone who has money like me, but I'd have to take off work, which is a problem Yeah,
Speaker 0: but the
Speaker 1: I don't
Speaker 0: wanna go to my boss and be like, yeah, someone's paying me to play a card game in the Hamptons.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the thing is I don't trust some garbage TV show to portray geeks who play netrunner and a positive correct light.
Speaker 1: You know, I expect it to be some horrible bullshit like Big Bang Theory, which is you know, basically You know as offensive to nerds as you know Racist things are to people of color.
Speaker 0: I would I would say that the latter is a bit more offensive.
Speaker 1: I mean, it's more.
Speaker 0: I see where you're going fence.
Speaker 1: It's saying it's in.
Speaker 1: it's.
Speaker 1: obviously Racism is a much worse.
Speaker 0: No, I see where you're going with that.
Speaker 0: I just would not make that comparison.
Speaker 1: No, listen, it's racism is a much worse problem.
Speaker 1: that harms people much much more than any sort of Discrimination against nerdy people.
Speaker 1: nerdy people are much much much.
Speaker 1: I can't have enough.
Speaker 1: much is less persecuted than people who are not.
Speaker 0: why you get those qualifications out there?
Speaker 1: Yes, but right it is the same type of thing where you're create.
Speaker 1: you were putting out some incorrect Stereotype right causing people to have bad views of a group.
Speaker 0: So in other news Blizzard overwatch and I'd still play a lot of overwatch.
Speaker 0: There is a lot of toxic behavior there because all gaming has a lot of toxic behavior, yes Especially competitive gaming and Blizzard has been attempting to and they've been doing more than a lot of game come.
Speaker 1: Yeah, pretty much the League of Legends company riot and Blizzard are doing the most of anyone which is still not enough.
Speaker 0: I mean remember in our panel we did on quitting like Blizzard is pretty clear.
Speaker 0: Jeff Kaplan was like if you're gonna quit games Rather just ban you from overwatch completely.
Speaker 0: There's no point in you even having the game.
Speaker 1: Yep, so they're People still quit the game.
Speaker 0: So actually since the hardline penalties on quitting have been coming into the game.
Speaker 1: There's much less.
Speaker 0: I have not seen someone quit a competitive game.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: Not one.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm, and That's kind of amazing actually to me.
Speaker 1: It's happening.
Speaker 1: You're just not.
Speaker 1: it's just in a games.
Speaker 1: You're not playing it.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, but I'm saying it used to happen in a high percentage of the competitive games I was in and it has happened in none of the competitive games.
Speaker 0: I've been in for a while.
Speaker 0: They are actually Escalating.
Speaker 0: you can read the details here but they're escalating their punishment because one thing that they appear to be doing that is very good is that they are looking at Data in terms of when they try a new thing like punishing people.
Speaker 0: in a certain way?
Speaker 0: Does it actually affect the bad behavior or not?
Speaker 0: in some quantitative fashion and A thing that a lot of games do if someone is being shitty in communications is cutting off their communications Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: The problem they have discovered is that that actually seems to drive shitty people into more aggressive forms of harassing and griefing Because if they can't say their racist stuff on the voice chat, they're gonna throw the game instead.
Speaker 0: They're gonna harass people with the actions of their characters instead.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: So it seems like the thing they're doing Primarily.
Speaker 1: it's like you ever see someone in the street who's mad and then the cops try to arrest him and they get even more Mad like, you know, like.
Speaker 1: they're just yelling at someone but then the cops are we're gonna arrest.
Speaker 1: you know, what?
Speaker 1: Right, they explode even more.
Speaker 1: that's that same phenomenon Yeah.
Speaker 0: So they're actually straight up going to start banning people Even for the things that previously they would just punish them for.
Speaker 1: they don't want someone to do.
Speaker 1: my plan Which is you take everyone's credit card and if someone misbehaves you charge them a fortune of money And if they don't pay then debtors prison, I think a compromise solution would be you buy overwatch.
Speaker 1: It works in like the professional sporting leagues.
Speaker 1: If you don't you you become you know You join and if you break the rules you get a fight or something you punch someone in the face.
Speaker 1: We find you a few thousand dollars.
Speaker 0: How about this?
Speaker 1: One's gonna say a racial slur.
Speaker 1: if it cost them ten thousand dollars watch cause about 40 bucks.
Speaker 0: So right now in games like counter-strike when people get banned they buy another account which creates a sort of interesting Scenario where you're basically milking money out of racists by continually banning them And still they're not charging enough money.
Speaker 1: The fine should be a fortune.
Speaker 0: Well, no well So what they should do?
Speaker 0: because they if if you buy the game for 40 bucks and you get banned for one One of those kinds of reasons if you try to buy the game again Unless they just don't let you ever buy it again, like you're just banned as soon as they figure out it's make
Speaker 1: another account.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but they've.
Speaker 0: a lot of these companies are getting better at Identifying when someone makes a new account because they had to use a credit card somewhere to buy it Yep, and just banning them again after they take their money, which I think is really funny.
Speaker 1: So I'm saying take a lot of their money.
Speaker 0: No, so put him on a list.
Speaker 0: Oh, you were banned for this reason to buy the game again.
Speaker 0: It's now $400.
Speaker 1: No, you should get.
Speaker 1: you should have to pay the $400 and then not be able to play the game again.
Speaker 1: That's how it you know, it's like oh you buy the game for 40 bucks because we need money, right?
Speaker 1: And if everyone behaves we need some money, right?
Speaker 1: Oh, you said a racial slur.
Speaker 1: That's it.
Speaker 1: We're taking $10,000.
Speaker 1: go to hell eat shit and die and you can never play the game again Sorry.
Speaker 0: So anyway, what overwatch is doing I'm talking about is that they're not doing things like Hell-banning toxic people into their own hellscape.
Speaker 0: Nope or any of that stuff.
Speaker 0: They're just they're taking the very direct.
Speaker 0: well your band forever approach sounds good, so we'll see how this goes.
Speaker 0: and The problem with overwatch is that with the competitive scene that is appearing I'm laughing because people in the stream saw the headline of this tab.
Speaker 0: the tab just said sex.
Speaker 1: What a great headline.
Speaker 1: so they're like, what's the?
Speaker 1: that's a headline is gonna get you some clicks.
Speaker 0: good You're a tab from the left dare.
Speaker 0: I ask.
Speaker 0: so overwatch is for real competitive professional league has not even begun games yet and yet already a Sexual assault scandal.
Speaker 0: I may a staff member of one of the teams.
Speaker 0: It wasn't.
Speaker 1: it wasn't our New York team.
Speaker 0: I don't think it's a really shitty name as far as I remember appears to have sexually they're allegedly Sexually assaulted as twitch streamer and was fired over it.
Speaker 0: There's a whole article here.
Speaker 0: You can read.
Speaker 1: That's a someone you can definitely find there.
Speaker 1: It's an athlete in a sporting league.
Speaker 1: You can find them for sure and not slightly jokingly like I was just talking about.
Speaker 0: finding seriously find them Oh my god, and yet so the see also just the middle of this article is also jail Starcraft player Drunkenly harass women on stream gets banned.
Speaker 0: You can see why this is such a big problem.
Speaker 0: They can't they can't even avoid this kind of thing happening in a league that has not yet started.
Speaker 0: That is the extent of this problem.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: So in other news, this is Scott's news, right?
Speaker 1: So there's actually a bunch of news.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna combine all them.
Speaker 1: one's a little bit older and that is that there was a studio at EA.
Speaker 1: EA bought this game studio.
Speaker 1: It's a called visceral games or something, right?
Speaker 1: Is that what it's called?
Speaker 1: Yep Yeah, and basically this is like a week or two ago.
Speaker 0: I think now this was really funny.
Speaker 0: Scott.
Speaker 0: Scott was like yo at EA shut down some game studio Star Wars game.
Speaker 0: So I googled for EA Star Wars layout and you found an old story.
Speaker 0: The top two articles are from right.
Speaker 0: now like October this year EA shuts down visceral games Star Wars game.
Speaker 0: moving to other thing the second link is After a thousand layoffs EA finds itself short-handed for Star Wars games from 2013.
Speaker 1: That was when they were starting with the Star Wars games.
Speaker 1: Yes, right.
Speaker 0: So basically environmental storytelling via Google.
Speaker 1: They had this Studio that also had some famous gaming people working for it Like what's her name Amy?
Speaker 1: something like they made Dead Space I think and some other says face the battlefield.
Speaker 0: I don't feel hardline which I never played kind of games that Scott doesn't care about.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but they were still really.
Speaker 0: They're currently working on Uncharted with Amy Hennig, right?
Speaker 1: The point is that they EA had the studio and they were making a Star Wars single-player kind of Experience game like Uncharted.
Speaker 0: it was only Star Wars and this studio is known for critically acclaimed triple-a game.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't personally enjoy but there's still big-time games and they shut that shit down, right?
Speaker 1: so on top of that right, it's now only a little while later.
Speaker 1: and Runic games the people who make torchlight.
Speaker 1: they're done Rest in peace.
Speaker 0: Yep, GG.
Speaker 1: and also in the news telltale games the people who make all those little adventure games like the Walking Dead and the wolf among us and I think they got today as a Batman.
Speaker 0: I think yeah Which I don't know anything about their sales numbers, but they seem to be doing well.
Speaker 1: They got some Game of Thrones.
Speaker 1: They make adventure games.
Speaker 1: They seem to have like a huge fan club and we were at PAX.
Speaker 1: We got that telltale like mega pack of like every game that had been released up to that point.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah Because I don't that's not my thing really but I so I said to him I thought I'd play them like on my laptop while I was traveling.
Speaker 0: No, cuz that's the perfect thing to do.
Speaker 0: on like a 20-hour flight I ended up just playing Civ 6 and like every flight I had.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and that's part of the point I'm about to make anyway, but They just laid off like 20 25 percent of their staff.
Speaker 1: It's a basically big-time layoffs.
Speaker 1: now all across video game history.
Speaker 0: They at least that we again.
Speaker 0: we can't get into the details of all these but they did say something interesting and the subtitle of this article Delivers it succinctly.
Speaker 0: They're gonna focus on delivering fewer better games, right?
Speaker 1: No, here's the real story right?
Speaker 1: the story that is not written in the in the text But in the subtext or perhaps the sub subtext, it's called subtext.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Okay, what's happening?
Speaker 1: Here is because you think these people are making video games holiday seasons coming up, right?
Speaker 1: Your game should be coming out real soon.
Speaker 1: Get you big money, right?
Speaker 1: No, what's actually going on here?
Speaker 1: is this the habits of people who play games these days?
Speaker 1: Right?
Speaker 1: are the for the people who play a lot of games like video game people, right?
Speaker 1: The kind of people who would play a Star Wars game.
Speaker 1: These are all serious game companies.
Speaker 1: Right making games are nerds not phone games for everybody.
Speaker 1: Yep The Single-player games are not making the bank or at least they're not making enough bank.
Speaker 0: This is why so many games are moving toward loot crate bullshit.
Speaker 1: All of these companies are making single-player one-time Experiences.
Speaker 1: right the the adventure games from telltale or episodic, but there's still.
Speaker 1: buy it play it done with it.
Speaker 1: torchlight Even though it has some co-op and stuff is.
Speaker 1: That Star Wars game is a single-player thing.
Speaker 1: that was gonna be buy it play it done with it Right.
Speaker 1: the way the behaviors of gamers these days self rim everyone I know include
Speaker 0: Specifically PC gamer
Speaker 1: right especially but even console people is that you have some game That's or game or games that are the ones that you go back to and they are almost definitely multiplayer games that have some sort of Microtransaction or something that keeps you putting money into it forever, right?
Speaker 1: You got your overwatch over there rim.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you got your sit you got your sieve over there.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's the game you can just keep going to with this multiplayer for you can keep playing it forever except I also play the single-player, but the single-player is an experience that is Effectively infinite unless you're crazy, right?
Speaker 1: But the single-player games?
Speaker 1: you go to them like a Mario Odyssey or a Zelda.
Speaker 1: you play them and then you done with them Yeah, and then you put them on the shelf and then you unless you're a speedrunner or something You go back to where you came from.
Speaker 0: maybe a year a few years down the road You're like, I'll play through some Zelda again, but that's not me.
Speaker 0: But even that that would be even worse if when I when the clock rings to play a single-player game.
Speaker 1: Getting more than 50 bucks at you or 60 or whatever is for that Mario.
Speaker 1: That's the end of it right?
Speaker 1: how much money would the overwatch get at you if you were a loot crate buying person?
Speaker 0: yep, and the thing is and I actually read a couple articles about this like this this topic is being discussed all over gaming circles, but It doesn't seem to be being discussed that much in like the games press.
Speaker 0: It's not the big games press, right?
Speaker 1: So what's gonna happen here is you're gonna see that Star Wars game is gonna come back and when it comes back It's gonna look a lot more like destiny and a lot less like Uncharted right Those telltale games.
Speaker 1: I don't know what's gonna happen with them in the long run.
Speaker 1: We'll see how if they can hold up.
Speaker 1: I feel like the novelty of them has worn off a lot and only the core fans are really sticking with those.
Speaker 1: If I was them I would go mobile and sell them for a lot cheaper and make them a lot shorter.
Speaker 0: and those kinds of Games like like.
Speaker 1: there's what there's one on mobile.
Speaker 1: It's like I even play it.
Speaker 1: It's like the stupidest game where it's like.
Speaker 1: It's almost like an escape room, but not quite.
Speaker 1: It's basically a lot of puzzles where you just manipulate stuff until you right It's just.
Speaker 1: it's just like they'll be a weird object and you manipulate it a whole bunch and find all its secret Compartments and everything and then it lets you go to the next one Or Monument Valley.
Speaker 1: Monument Valley they came up with a sequel.
Speaker 1: Geniuses did exactly the things that Scott always says to do don't announce a release date Don't even tell you when you're working on it.
Speaker 1: Really, right?
Speaker 1: They just boom.
Speaker 1: They said Monument Valley to out today out of nowhere.
Speaker 1: Put it on the store making a ton of money.
Speaker 1: everyone where the phone buys it plays it and is done with it But it caused nothing to make a fucking Monument Valley, right?
Speaker 1: Unlike where it cost probably millions to make that Star Wars.
Speaker 1: Well, this is where it doesn't matter that everyone just paid five bucks and went on their merry way.
Speaker 0: The area that is in the most danger is the triple-a Single-player expensive game that can't bring in money forever.
Speaker 1: They can only bring in money in one shot.
Speaker 0: So a small single-player game from an indie studio has much more chance of breaking even than a triple-a single-player experience.
Speaker 1: yeah, and I think this is only going to continue because look at look at torchlight right and now look at el diablo.
Speaker 1: el diablo is Somehow even though it's still a single-player game that you can just play over and over They just keep blizzard.
Speaker 1: Just just keeps As much money.
Speaker 0: you can look at how many people every strike.
Speaker 1: every single blizzard game is a lifestyle game.
Speaker 1: They squeeze as much as they can to keep getting money out of.
Speaker 1: even Starcraft 2 just went free to play.
Speaker 1: So they can.
Speaker 1: it has loot boxes in it now so they can keep squeezing money out of every stone they got.
Speaker 0: Yep, you're also seeing more and more mobile games that there's almost no actual game there.
Speaker 0: They're not quite just a clicker, but they're more like that fire in the game.
Speaker 0: But there's actually not much going on.
Speaker 0: Yeah but they're tied to an IP that people are fans of but that IP where it traditionally made its money from a Single-player game by the expensive fire emblem game sales on those games.
Speaker 0: I don't think are going up either.
Speaker 0: There's way more money to made with Psychologically addicting loot crate bullshit.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so that's that's what's going down And it means that if you are working in the video game industry on like fancy triple-a 3d single-player games You might want to go find someplace to work.
Speaker 1: that is making the.
Speaker 1: you know The multiplayer kind that is lifestyle.
Speaker 0: or be sure the game you're working on if it's a triple-a Single-player experience is the one that people are gonna play every couple months like a Mario or a Zelda or much Nintendo only.
Speaker 1: Of course, I'm burning through Really fast.
Speaker 0: Resident Evil actually sells a bunch like with almost no effort and very little time I've gotten like a hundred and fifty moons and just kind of blown through a huge chunk of the game.
Speaker 1: I played it a whole bunch in like two shots and got a zillion moon dude last night.
Speaker 1: I got.
Speaker 1: I basically beat the donkey Town Donkey Kong town.
Speaker 1: I beat the fuck out of New Donk City Yeah, and then I'm gonna go back to it probably pretty soon, especially during this little Thanksgiving.
Speaker 0: but the trouble that was funny is I was basically a New Donk City and In the time between the second about a New Donk City ending part.
Speaker 0: Oh my god.
Speaker 0: That was so great.
Speaker 0: Oh good That was when that song starts playing and I go into that pipe and everyone's chit.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it was good stuff.
Speaker 0: That's good.
Speaker 0: But at the same time in the time between the second period Coming soon to get nice near you.
Speaker 0: the second period ended of the Rangers game And I was playing Mario until the third period started.
Speaker 0: So like 20 minutes or less.
Speaker 0: I got like 20 moons Like you can.
Speaker 0: just I got to use paper.
Speaker 0: He looks like moon moon moon moon moon moon like Korok seeds.
Speaker 0: But yeah I basically only play The best single-player game.
Speaker 0: that's in my queue at the time and once I beat it Then I go back to overwatch and counter-strike for like months until suddenly my brain is like you should play a single-player game and I go back to my queue and I literally pick what is The best game I have access to in the entire world right now And that's the one I'll play.
Speaker 1: since I'm all old and I can't do fast accurate movements of my hands anymore I've been sticking to card games as my go back Scott I found I found by continuing to play twitchy games.
Speaker 0: I'm actually maintaining my skills to a good degree.
Speaker 1: I lost the skills and I don't know how to get him back.
Speaker 0: Gotta just play.
Speaker 1: I didn't maintain them when I had the chance.
Speaker 1: Scott.
Speaker 1: now they gone.
Speaker 0: You got to just play counter-strike again And you know what?
Speaker 1: How am I gonna get the skills back at counter-strike.
Speaker 0: if I just get shot in the head immediately every time cuz the skill ranking will push you down there with the wood tiers.
Speaker 0: and So in my experience in overwatch, at least what if I'm less than woods here?
Speaker 0: Scott in overwatch the wood tiers I am literally neo the god walking around killing and not killing at my whim alone.
Speaker 0: They are I am invincible and I they die.
Speaker 1: in my rocket league.
Speaker 1: skill went down.
Speaker 1: I was but I was better at that than people.
Speaker 1: I knew just not better than people actually knew how to play.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and even that I tried to play it again and I was like hurt.
Speaker 0: But anyway things of the day.
Speaker 0: So what was my thing?
Speaker 0: All right Remember, I don't know the context of this video in that I do not know how it was made.
Speaker 0: I assume this is not a human but someone wrote a simple program to do this.
Speaker 0: I would guess if I had to guess that this is not a neural network or anything.
Speaker 0: But either a human did this themselves, which means godspeed to you.
Speaker 0: Good, sir.
Speaker 0: That is amazing or They wrote a simple script because I'm pretty sure the bombs are 100% deterministic in this game.
Speaker 0: Once you get to the end state and this is just be a three hour 18 minute and 15 second long video of a camera pointed at a CRT that has kaboom on the 2600 running until the score hits.
Speaker 0: It is hypnotic to watch and I have nothing else to say about it.
Speaker 1: Is the only person alive who still loves kaboom except for that one other person I was about to say who also loves kaboom.
Speaker 1: If you want to know why I made this video if you want to know people love kaboom rim that guy and the person who?
Speaker 1: Made this video if you are sure the person who made this video, isn't that guy?
Speaker 0: Pax makes me diamond hard and the reason that is is because the first packs ever went to.
Speaker 0: Among many things that happened to us.
Speaker 0: that packs was that moment where they had an Atari 2600 and I've thought boom was in it And it was running and I out loud news.
Speaker 0: Wow I wonder if anyone else in the world is good at this game and there was a dude standing there who is Good at that game and is just as obsessed with it as I am.
Speaker 0: the odds of that are zero and yet it happened.
Speaker 1: I mean are in fact one.
Speaker 1: Well, yeah one point.
Speaker 0: Oh the odd happened.
Speaker 0: I thought the odds were zero.
Speaker 0: what I underestimated was the power of fucking packs.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm So what do you got?
Speaker 1: so I got actually high quality thing of the day.
Speaker 1: that shows You know yet again that I'm the best picker of things of the day.
Speaker 0: Good God This is an amazing thing of the day.
Speaker 0: I can't I can't even argue can't even argue with this shit.
Speaker 0: So how'd you find this?
Speaker 1: cuz I'm good at finding shit on the internet.
Speaker 1: So Something you don't think about often is grave diggin real-life grave diggin cuz it's pretty morbid.
Speaker 1: You don't think about it except that one time you go to the cemetery and there's people dig in a grave and it's like these laborers that don't talk and stay out of the way and Maybe you think for a second what their lives are like and then you don't think about them anymore.
Speaker 1: It's like how many people know someone who's like a grave digger just like as a friend or like, you know Someone with that profession.
Speaker 1: I sure don't.
Speaker 0: I usually think about grave diggers in the constant in the context of Willie from the Simpsons digging graves.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but even his job was school janitor and not grave digger.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but anyway Grave digger is that sort of like outcast from society kind of profession, right?
Speaker 1: It's not something people think about or whatever and if you do think about it It's like you know, you wouldn't want to associate with someone who's a grave digger.
Speaker 0: Well, they get again though.
Speaker 0: Remember this is the like.
Speaker 0: there's like I would but I'm saying in general Feeling when we used to listen to Penn's podcast Did they do?
Speaker 0: you talk a lot about like when someone is circus or not?
Speaker 0: Like if you're if you're a circus person, then you know all this circus crap that normal people just have no idea.
Speaker 0: I feel like people in the death industry.
Speaker 0: This is just part of that.
Speaker 0: Are you death you into death?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I know death.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's obviously so anyway in Slovakia.
Speaker 1: There are some people who are grave diggers And in the death industry, you know funeral homes casket selling etc.
Speaker 1: undertaking and You know, they were like, hey, let's try to like put on a different face on our work so that we're not so you know looked at with the creepy eye and People can see that we're actually real people and not just that You know sort of labor that you don't want to talk to when you're at a funeral.
Speaker 0: Chris points out in the stream.
Speaker 0: That is I think that's an outcast life path in burning wheel.
Speaker 1: Is it probably?
Speaker 1: Yeah So what they did here in Slovakia is they set up a an annual?
Speaker 1: Grave digging championship and made grave digging into a sport.
Speaker 1: It's can you dig the grave who can dig it fastest and also good enough and then refill.
Speaker 0: That's a real good grave.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like they you dig the grave as fast as you can with your team of people Right using only the normal tools shovels and strong arms, right?
Speaker 1: They check your grave to make sure it's it's legit.
Speaker 1: It's deep enough long enough wide enough Properly shaped, you know structurally sound and then you fill that shit back in as fast as you can and they give out trophies and stuff to put a good a good face on this thing and also make a pretty good sport.
Speaker 1: that happens to have ties to Death which are unsettling but you know, maybe you can get over it if you watch this video.
Speaker 0: This is pretty good.
Speaker 1: And next time you go to a cemetery look at the gravediggers of the different eye.
Speaker 0: So in the meta moment, the book club book was the fifth season and we read it.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna pick the new book soon.
Speaker 0: I am almost done with the last book of the trilogy from the fifth season.
Speaker 1: I haven't even started reading the second book.
Speaker 0: Uh, I see why some people are disappointed with the second and third book, but I want to be very clear.
Speaker 1: But you're not among them.
Speaker 0: I am NOT.
Speaker 0: so far everything that the that the second or third book has revealed is the kind of thing that I wish.
Speaker 1: You know a lot more about sockets than I do.
Speaker 0: I know.
Speaker 0: so here's the thing in say the like later Prince of Nothing books.
Speaker 0: They'll be like by the way, here's a whole bunch of shit Like.
Speaker 0: here's the answer to a big thing in this book.
Speaker 0: when that happens when you get a big info dumb.
Speaker 0: There's more questions - no no, it answers questions Authoritatively in a really interesting way yet somehow leaves intact other Interrelated mysteries without raising new questions.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: So but everything I've learned so far has just made me Happier and more invested in the trilogy.
Speaker 1: Hmm.
Speaker 1: Like it's all you want to do some fifth season RPG.
Speaker 0: it's all ghost in the shell like There's.
Speaker 0: there's cool cyber punky nonsense going on.
Speaker 1: They can't leave anything out.
Speaker 1: It's got to be everything right.
Speaker 0: we get had the fantasy and the sci-fi you get some flashbacks to like pre-season societies And I know exactly what orogeny is and it's great nice But I don't know though I still don't know anything about warrant and what that place is.
Speaker 1: is the ghost in the shell stuff related to the Guardians I imagine.
Speaker 1: uh, not just the guy but but they had their cyber implants, right?
Speaker 0: Book two goes into that in detail.
Speaker 0: good Shafa is I think my favorite character.
Speaker 1: Yeah, no, he's way good, but he's not a sexy pirate captain.
Speaker 1: No.
Speaker 0: Well, no, I said favorite character not best character Not my husband.
Speaker 0: We were at game.
Speaker 1: I want to do sexy pirate captain fan art.
Speaker 1: send them to geek nights.
Speaker 1: We have a forum by the way Community dot front row crew.
Speaker 1: calm you could come there find the thread for the book club and upload your sexy pirate captain fan.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if you happen to know anyone who looks like that character and acts like that character just send photos of your sexy pirate captain.
Speaker 0: So our next convention is going to be PAX unplugged.
Speaker 1: it's like a week or two away.
Speaker 1: It's super soon.
Speaker 1: How soon is it said November?
Speaker 1: 17th 18th 19th in Philadelphia 10 Goddamn days for it by the time you're listening to this less than 10 days.
Speaker 0: This is the inaugural Tabletop only packs, but it is a full packs just aimed solely at tabletop.
Speaker 1: It's gonna have a megathon.
Speaker 1: it's gonna have a keynote.
Speaker 0: It's got a main theater just like normal packs.
Speaker 1: from that I think the guy who's in charge of watsy right how I mean if you're a tabletop gaming person How can you not hear what that person has to say?
Speaker 0: so Saturday at that in tabletop tourney 3 30 to 5 30 p.m We're doing an epic Carcassonne event.
Speaker 0: We're gonna teach a bunch of bunch of monsters how to be monstrous at Carcassonne and then make them fight with each other.
Speaker 1: It's like giving everyone a perfect strategy guide to a multiplayer game and then they all fight.
Speaker 0: It's gonna be good stuff and see who is the best and otherwise we're just gonna be there playing games and enforcement.
Speaker 0: It's gonna be awesome.
Speaker 0: So, uh, yeah and otherwise follow Scott on YouTube because a lot of our stuff is there.
Speaker 0: follow me on YouTube.
Speaker 0: A lot of stuff is there our patreon.
Speaker 0: I'm still reading that Castlevania book.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna finish that entire thing by the end of this month.
Speaker 0: And if you want a really really Weirdly homoerotic audiobook about Castlevania.
Speaker 0: That's then gonna be the final output of what I'm doing in there.
Speaker 1: We also got twitch.
Speaker 1: we got to Instagram.
Speaker 1: So you got the Twitter's.
Speaker 1: we got the Facebook's.
Speaker 1: we got the Google+ we got pretty much Every kind of internet that there is.
Speaker 1: Geek Nights is even posted on LinkedIn.
Speaker 1: Geek Nights is there.
Speaker 1: You can find it.
Speaker 1: go and do so.
Speaker 0: and at ReviewCon Which is what we're calling a thing where we get together with our hardcore friends and play hardcore games We played a lot of board games.
Speaker 0: We're trying to review all of them before we forget about them.
Speaker 0: Yes, and one of the games we played was entirely new to me.
Speaker 1: I'd never seen it before in my life.
Speaker 0: I had never seen it, but I never played it.
Speaker 1: The box was appealing.
Speaker 0: It is just called Luna But apparently as an alternate name.
Speaker 0: the full name is Luna in the domain of the moon princess Which I guess is definitely accurate.
Speaker 0: It's been published by a bunch of different companies, but it was the man at one point.
Speaker 1: This is not a apparently very successful game.
Speaker 1: It's never became a big hit.
Speaker 1: I don't think.
Speaker 0: if you ask most board game people about it only the super nerdiest would know and My shortest possible assessment of it is that I have not encountered a game that is specifically like it combines.
Speaker 1: It's definitely a unique game.
Speaker 1: It can buy it is not so Amazing and to make it.
Speaker 1: it's like a great game that you want to play a whole bunch, but it's also not a bad game.
Speaker 1: It's not like oh this poopy game.
Speaker 1: It's just like it's not super great amazing game like say power grid or some Puerto Rico or something.
Speaker 1: Yep It's a game that I want very unique and therefore worth can't worth pay playing.
Speaker 1: if you're someone who cares about board games Now you that's your TLDR you can stop listening and then now we'll talk about the actual game.
Speaker 0: but I would play it again because and I would play it again an interesting thing about it is that having played at once the interrelations between the purely deterministic actions of the players is More complex than one might expect.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah meaning Playing it again.
Speaker 0: I may take Drastically different actions from the first time I played and despite that despite that complexity the first time we played it The scores were pretty close and people develop wildly different directional heuristics that seem to converge.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so first of all, this game is fascinating and that it is a perfect information game.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there is there's no cards in your hand.
Speaker 1: There's no secret.
Speaker 1: There's no deck of things flipping up.
Speaker 1: There's no nothing.
Speaker 0: It's literally just like all right, everyone move your dudes Yep, move them around on these islands in a right a crook.
Speaker 1: So worker placement game in the middle of the map.
Speaker 1: in the middle of the game is this big hex map thing Which contains the moon princesses castle.
Speaker 1: the moon princess never goes there Yeah, but you can go there to pray to the moon princess and get a lot of victory points.
Speaker 0: Apparently and all around the moon princesses castle are these islands, you know It's funny because that middle part reminds me of the castle from Kalis in that it's the most prominent thing on the board and it seemed to be the true endgame Once people are reasonably skilled.
Speaker 1: Yes, all around the castle are these islands and each island has a different purpose, right?
Speaker 1: it's like an observatory and I forget what all the different islands are.
Speaker 1: there's a bunch of them and so they all do something different Physically separate islands with a token.
Speaker 1: that's actually separate little cardboard islands that are you know.
Speaker 0: And on each island there is a token that is specific to that island that you can basically spend an action to take and Then you'll be able to use that later to do something.
Speaker 0: independently of that There is a moon priestess who moves from island to island in a deterministic fashion Having more dudes on an island when she's there is worth victory points.
Speaker 0: And there's also this jerk who's going around the other direction and you don't want to be on the island when he's there.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm And you basically on your turn you allocate what he's on the island with the moon princess.
Speaker 0: Well, that was an interesting situation that caused everyone to scatter to the winds priestess princess.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the theme like the tying the theme to the game is pretty thin Similarly to how the theme of village seems like it fits the game mechanics But doesn't really when you dig into it, so I basically ignored the theme.
Speaker 1: So the first thing about this game that you'll I noticed right away as soon as the rules were explained that I didn't even need To play one turn of the game to realize this is that you get some meeples and moving them is a pain in the ass.
Speaker 1: Yeah huge as soon as they explain the rules I'm like goddamn it's gonna be hard to move these guys around.
Speaker 1: the whole game is gonna be really About moving these guys and getting them moved to where I need them to be.
Speaker 0: So think of it kind of like when two people are having a fistfight in that if they're high-level martial arts masters.
Speaker 0: The act of moving your body in a way to then punch someone is itself a telegraphing of What direction you're like what kind of thing you're about to do?
Speaker 0: You got to set up moves well in advance in a public space where everyone can see what you're setting up.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so like you want to you want to move your meeple?
Speaker 1: You can move it barely and it caused like a whole action and it sucks and then everyone sees what you did and goes Huh?
Speaker 1: The guys like spent and the meeple can't do anything anymore because you moved it, right?
Speaker 1: You can move them way better if you get a boat.
Speaker 1: But to get a boat you got to go to the island that has boats on it and take a boat tile.
Speaker 1: And now everyone sees that you took a boat tiles.
Speaker 1: You're basically really when you do that you're just delaying your action to get a better action later.
Speaker 0: No I did find that a useful heuristic was by having Amy tile in front of you kind of scared other people from committing to actions that tile could fuck up.
Speaker 0: Yes, and that became so posturing became a big part of the game Which is why even though they are So different that I would not compare them otherwise and I don't want anyone to get the wrong impression from this comparison.
Speaker 0: But this game shares that very strongly with Hansa toy tonica in that The game is you can make very incremental actions on the board at significant personal cost meaning there's a very limited number of actions you can take.
Speaker 0: yeah and The mere act of positioning something gives other players a ton of information about what you're trying to do Things that they can do now.
Speaker 0: Yep, but then when someone else put something down it definitely informed.
Speaker 0: So like when I see Scott still got two guys He could put out and I want to get the majority on the priestess, but Scott could put the guys there.
Speaker 1: You don't want to make a move if someone else still has the ability to disrupt that move you wait until your move is invincible Unthreatened and then make it.
Speaker 1: but if everyone waits that then otherwise if you commit your two movements to go see the moon priestess And then someone else commits three and now you committed your moves and you got nothing for it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but at the same time you gotta move somewhere like you got to do stuff.
Speaker 0: You can't gotta play your hand not do anything.
Speaker 1: They can't just posture forever, which you can pass and take a candle But then what happens is like sure the board can go or if no one else passes It'll come back to you and you can do something you can.
Speaker 1: you don't have to keep passing.
Speaker 0: you can unpack now This passing mechanic and I can't stress this enough.
Speaker 0: It is very rare that when someone does something weird with a Generally agreed upon mechanic in games.
Speaker 0: Usually that's bad like in ground floor.
Speaker 0: Yep, I kind of like this candle mechanic, but I guarantee if you're not careful, you're gonna explain it wrong or do it wrong.
Speaker 0: I was not properly educated on this rule when we started and I which was your own fault because it was explained like five times But it was.
Speaker 1: it's a non-standard passing mechanic Which is why I said my eyes didn't pay glazed over when it was being explained.
Speaker 1: But basically this four or five candle tiles how many?
Speaker 0: some number one, two, three, four five.
Speaker 1: Okay, it might be the number of players I don't know.
Speaker 1: But anyway, if you are four four four if you pass you take a candle tile and the candle starts to burn out Right, and then you wait.
Speaker 1: if the game gets her back around to you and the candle still hasn't burnt out You can obviously pass again.
Speaker 0: You could also take an action but passing again takes another candle.
Speaker 0: So it's not like most games.
Speaker 1: if they have this kind of mechanic Usually when you pass you're out out out come for the rest of the round or something.
Speaker 1: Nope, not in this game.
Speaker 1: as long as this candle you can keep going now.
Speaker 0: the other alternative way that goes is people can pass and If they're not permanently out they can unpack.
Speaker 0: and the other way games tend to do this is the round only ends if Everyone passes once in a row.
Speaker 1: Nope There just needs to be.
Speaker 1: the candle has to burn out.
Speaker 1: one person could take all the candle pieces and that would burn it out.
Speaker 0: So I pass, Scott takes an action, Chris takes an action, I pass again.
Speaker 0: now everyone goes.
Speaker 1: Oh shit, right It's like you can basically take candle burn the candle out as your action to sort of threaten people and to realize oh shit I might not get another action now.
Speaker 1: Crap, the candle has burnt this much.
Speaker 1: We didn't learn that so much later in the game.
Speaker 1: But knowing now what I know.
Speaker 0: You keep saying we it was just you you were the only one confused.
Speaker 1: Better the next time I play this game.
Speaker 1: There's gonna be a lot of rounds.
Speaker 1: I'm just like candle.
Speaker 0: That's fine All right, go especially because if you take candle early, it just it sort of puts a timer on everyone else.
Speaker 1: Yeah It makes them take an action for me to respond to instead of me taking the first action to putting myself at this advantage.
Speaker 0: So there's this worker placement game which has a part of the reason why we're not getting into the specific mechanics of all these.
Speaker 1: I forget them.
Speaker 1: I played the game once and it was a while ago.
Speaker 0: They're kind of immaterial to the review And there's a lot of them and they don't make sense unless we literally teach you the whole game.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but basically each island has a tile.
Speaker 1: the tiles can do things But you have to sort of move a guy to a place get a tile then use the tile.
Speaker 1: It's very slow and you're telegraphing Everything that you can or might do.
Speaker 1: the main thing is the middle of the board of the hexes are I would say we say The main thing but really it's more like the end game sort of.
Speaker 0: it's the goal.
Speaker 0: But really the goal is victory.
Speaker 0: point.
Speaker 1: get these treasures by claiming them and then you put them into the middle and they're worth points And you can also bump people out of the middle that are adjacent to you by attacking.
Speaker 0: that is not what the fiction is.
Speaker 0: I don't care what the fiction is.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the mechanic of this is pretty unique.
Speaker 1: You can also lock your guys in and prevent them from being bumped.
Speaker 0: so you've got a yeah, but that's one of those tile actions.
Speaker 0: yep, so basically you've got this hex area and There is a limited number of the treasure type things where the numbers just count up.
Speaker 0: There's higher and higher numbers and all deterministic and you can only.
Speaker 0: But you can spend actions to claim one and spend actions to put them into the castle.
Speaker 0: If someone puts a higher numbered one next to one of yours with a lower number your guy gets fucked.
Speaker 0: basically Yep, he's kicked out and he goes to a special place where you can't even do normal movement.
Speaker 0: He has to use one of those boats to get out.
Speaker 1: Yeah You have to use a crappy move.
Speaker 1: you have to get an extra action and like use a bunch of resources to rescue that guy Now because he's stuck on the dock of the castle.
Speaker 0: It's real bad.
Speaker 0: Yeah if it happens to you But you can only take numbers so high.
Speaker 1: there was a notable turn where I saw rim was in a vulnerable position And I basically was just like waiting and hoping rim would do this many.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I did it All right.
Speaker 0: So remember the Provost in Calis that would sort of move along to sort of set boundaries for what you can do.
Speaker 0: Yep, so there's there's a mechanic like the Provost and then every turn this thing moves further down this track Activating more of the treasure.
Speaker 0: Yes unlocking higher numbers of treasure bringing you closer to the endgame.
Speaker 0: The earlier you move in you can get points for moving in but now you've got guys that are vulnerable.
Speaker 0: They could be kicked out for the end of the game.
Speaker 1: I'm moving in late is hard.
Speaker 0: One of the worker things you can do is get a tile that will let you skip one level ahead of that Provost.
Speaker 0: yeah, and All that combined makes a pretty complex mechanic that you could build an entire game around Mm-hmm, and yet this is the sub game of getting victory points within the game of doing stuff with these islands.
Speaker 0: So Pretty much if I
Speaker 1: hadn't
Speaker 0: read these rules and played this game This game reeks of a game that would fail in the way that ground floor failed in that it has Multiple mechanics that are like known mechanics, but are crooked in a way that is not commonly known meaning They're easy to mess up coupled with having multiple significantly complex mechanics in the same game that are not Obviously indirectly interrelated and yet they work pretty well together.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's weird.
Speaker 1: There's a lot of games like this out there.
Speaker 1: I remember playing a lot of them back in like the RIT days.
Speaker 1: We're like these really sort of semi unique euros that have things and mechanics that are like really Different from every other kind of game.
Speaker 0: like village is actually a recent example of a game that felt that way.
Speaker 1: Yeah village with the people dying and going in.
Speaker 1: there's no other game that does that right?
Speaker 1: And that sort of makes me personally want to play them But it doesn't make me want to like.
Speaker 1: it makes me want to play them a few times right and then sort of like that novelty is.
Speaker 1: that is the thing the game has going for it because really the game to Play is mostly kind of frustrating with all these limited actions, but it's not like a super fun time.
Speaker 0: But like to call Mexico Java have that same thing.
Speaker 0: What was the joke?
Speaker 0: we always said the way they figure out how many actions you get in those games is to Keep reducing the number by one until a fistfight breaks out in the playtesters right and then add one and leave it there.
Speaker 1: But yeah, it's like it's not a super fun to play and the theme isn't that exciting even though moon priest is pretty cool Right, but but it was intellectually stimulating and difficult and I enjoyed my experience such that I want to play it again.
Speaker 1: Yeah I want to play it a few times But I wouldn't want to buy it or play it a whole bunch or make it my favorite game or give it.
Speaker 1: it's not like A great game that deserves awards or anything like that.
Speaker 1: You know, it's just like it's totally unique weird still good thing that someone who is way into board games Should definitely check out for a you know different experience.
Speaker 1: But you know obviously doesn't have the mass, you know, I don't want to say it doesn't deserve mass market.
Speaker 1: You know, I guess sales, but it doesn't have mass market sales.
Speaker 1: So it has what it deserves, but it feels very.
Speaker 0: I felt good about the decisions I was making decisions I made mattered a lot most of the time.
Speaker 1: You don't get a lot of them.
Speaker 0: That's why yep But the one thing it lacks is that because it's got some fairly complex mechanics all sort of interoperating It doesn't have the sort of I don't know simplistic elegance of Hansa toy tonic, which has a very similar reactive and posturing component.
Speaker 0: So I want to play this two or three more times and it's possible that I would enjoy it beyond that.
Speaker 0: But I'm not sure because I don't know if the game will lock into either a degenerate strategy among significant analysis or a Sort of very steady state like there is only one clear way to win and everyone's just racing to do it.
Speaker 0: So we'll see.
Speaker 0: but I liked it and I haven't played a game like it and I think you should at least if you see it at a con You should definitely take it out of the library and play it, but I would not buy it sight unseen.
Speaker 1: No, I definitely it's one of those games you receive in a convention library You can like.
Speaker 1: what the hell is that?
Speaker 1: And if you ever say that about a game play it at least one time.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there's that mermaid game in the PAX library.
Speaker 1: I don't know what the hell that is, but I really want to play it one time.
Speaker 1: But I guess this game I think it actually might have gotten cold I don't know.
Speaker 0: This game has a lot of meat to it more meat than you might expect and Despite having the trappings of the kinds of things that make me very wary of a game.
Speaker 0: It actually Executed on those things.
Speaker 1: also, it's a perfect information games that don't neglect that fact.
Speaker 1: There's not a lot of perfect information games out there.
Speaker 1: and the ones if you want a game that has no randomness No secrets, no bluffing and really, you know a lot more like chess only obviously more euro style.
Speaker 1: This is one to look at because there aren't many in that category.
Speaker 0: the perfect information games that have these kinds of mechanics tend to Devolve very rapidly into.
Speaker 0: this is the only clear path to her.
Speaker 0: Usually they're abstract like oshi Yeah, but this one I'm really curious if after two or three more plays there is a very clear sequence to victory.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah I don't know other games that I have played that I would have made the same sort of question about Definitely devolve very rapidly this one at the end of our first play.
Speaker 0: I didn't have a path yet And that is notable to me because usually I find that path and I don't ever want to play the game again.
Speaker 0: I actually do want to play this game again, and you know us on geek nights.
Speaker 0: Wanting to play a game again is one of the highest pieces of phrase we could ever give to a game.
Speaker 0: It's like play once play more than once play forever.
Speaker 0: Those are the three levels you got.
Speaker 0: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at front row crew.com for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 0: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 1: But unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night.
Speaker 0: the patreon picture on.
Speaker 0: for this episode geek nights are Ellen Joyce Heidi McNichol Amanda Duchette a shipping Ruby obelisk hanging in the sky.
Speaker 0: my state calm Jeremy a minor genuine bonafide like five six car monorail Shawn Yeager Matthew Smith Nicholas Brando captain Chinga waka see Rebecca Dunn for two one creations.
Speaker 0: No, I never ever wonder why we're here.
Speaker 0: Semper fie bitch Sherman von Horrell rare Laval James David White Rochelle, Monta Nona super boy room says something funny here Sailor Vista Don Schleich chart option Joe Shiro Joe star Sam Cordray Clinton Walton Ren from New Zealand Ryan Perrin drew open Lander Brian Citroni Finn Chris midkiff Chris Knox Daniel read me Shawn Klein Chris Reimer and Thomas Hahn and a whole bunch of people who are giving a dollar which frankly giving a Dollar is totally fine.
Speaker 0: Like I said, I'm gonna try to finish that Castlevania book as fast as possible and then start doing a lot of the other patreon stuff we've been talking about.
Speaker 0: we've been really delayed by the fact that there's so many conventions at the end of this year coming into the holiday season and We've been way busier than we've probably ever been.
Speaker 0: and for those of you who know me in person I have a job that I actually have to do work in which is making these even more difficult, but stay tuned.
Speaker 0: Everything's coming bit by bit right after pecs unplugged, which is less than ten days from now.
Speaker 0: But anyway Now I leave you before we adjourn.
Speaker 0: gentlemen I have one last matter of utmost importance.
Speaker 0: I need to send this parcel with the profit projections to Pete Porter in Pasadena and it Absolutely positively has to be there overnight.
Speaker 0: Hey Porter, pass it on Pasadena promptly.
Speaker 1: package of parcel processing pronto Break up.
Speaker 0: render gas.
Speaker 0: profoundly pressing.
Speaker 0: package of power plant.
Speaker 0: profit projections for Pete Porter in Pasadena priority.
Speaker 0: Here's your package mr.
Speaker 0: Burns.
Speaker 0: My name is the return address.
Speaker 0: you senseless thunderpate smithers, who is this nincompoop?
Speaker 1: I've worked here for ten years and my boss doesn't even know my name.
Speaker 0: Well, that's gonna change right now.
Speaker 0: My name is Homer J snip out Sounded large when I ordered it.
Speaker 0: I can't make hide nor hair of these metric booby traps.