Speaker 1: It's Thursday September 28th 2017.
Speaker 1: I'm rim.
Speaker 1: I'm Scott and this is geek nights tonight.
Speaker 1: We're talking about desks.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: So on Saturday, I was biking around looking for sports to photograph.
Speaker 0: Whatever.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: What was I doing on Saturday?
Speaker 1: I went biking on so I went for a run.
Speaker 1: on Saturday.
Speaker 0: I came across some roller hockey and the thing is I started taking photos the roll hockey But then it ended.
Speaker 0: it was the third period of the last game.
Speaker 0: Ah So I barely I got like me not even any photos But that roller hockey was way like serious competitive intense like they didn't have a name for the league But like it was super organized and like this one guy running.
Speaker 0: It was the most New York guy I ever seen.
Speaker 0: So he's I said when should I come back?
Speaker 0: He says they play Saturday morning and Wednesday night.
Speaker 0: So I'm like, oh I got nothing else to do Wednesday night.
Speaker 0: That sounds more productive than sitting on my ass at home.
Speaker 0: so I went over there and Basically, they play short games like it's still three periods, but they're short maybe five ten-minute periods that makes and there's no stopping for Commercials, there's.
Speaker 0: no it doesn't look there's any hitting any time.
Speaker 0: I saw anyone handy when there was a penalty, right?
Speaker 1: So the reason that makes sense is when I played roller hockey as a kid The one thing that was very apparent is that you never had enough kids for line.
Speaker 1: So you were basically on.
Speaker 0: the one team had no subs, but they like kicked ass.
Speaker 0: one team had like two subs.
Speaker 0: They were like borrowing.
Speaker 0: they had goalies that were like like hey, does anyone want to stick around?
Speaker 0: we're short We need a goalie.
Speaker 1: so I'm curious because I've seen two styles of air hockey.
Speaker 0: Roller hockey did.
Speaker 1: were the goalies also wearing rollerblades or they just have shoes?
Speaker 0: Oh, the goalies are wearing rollerblades, but they all said full goalie equipment.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you got a Playing with a plastic puck or the ball.
Speaker 0: It was a plastic puck.
Speaker 0: on the surface at this rink is some kind of plastic surface, but oh, okay I know I know what kind of it was like.
Speaker 0: it was like these plastic tiles, but man, they were flying like whoa.
Speaker 0: It was like.
Speaker 0: you didn't even realize it wasn't ice hockey, you know, obviously not NHL speed but like damn so modern.
Speaker 0: They were even keeping track of like who got the assists and stuff.
Speaker 0: modern and rollerblades are Dangerous linesman refs the whole deal, but they were just like the teams were like so shoddy like six dudes roll up And they're like they're putting their clothes on right next to the as the other team is finishing up.
Speaker 1: and Scott Let's form a team and join the league.
Speaker 0: We would die.
Speaker 0: Also.
Speaker 0: I can't skate of any any kind.
Speaker 1: I could teach you That's not that hard.
Speaker 0: I cannot skate anyway.
Speaker 0: So that was kind of awesome.
Speaker 0: If anyone wants to do roller hockey I suggest going to Brooklyn Bridge Park Wednesday night or Saturday morning and you know You can definitely play some.
Speaker 0: but it was serious and competitive like they were keeping score on paper.
Speaker 0: They said they play The whole year no matter what the temperature is no matter what?
Speaker 0: Yeah, right as long as it's not raining because apparently the roof there is kind of leaky.
Speaker 0: But it was lit up at night and also the random fireworks.
Speaker 1: were they Checking or no checking.
Speaker 0: No like that.
Speaker 0: No one is hitting anyone.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: I said that already but When you say I assumed that was like they're not fighting and so it was no fun.
Speaker 0: there was no fighting either but there was.
Speaker 0: there was like a great deal of a Verbal assaults.
Speaker 0: Anyway.
Speaker 0: Also, just the tiny news right at the office today They gave out free flu shots to everybody who wanted one.
Speaker 1: Oh my old company two companies ago Used to do that and three companies ago was the hospital.
Speaker 1: So they of course also did that.
Speaker 0: But anyway, we had to wait in line like everyone's waiting in line for that goes with one person giving out shots.
Speaker 0: Everyone's waiting in line, but I just want to say anyone out there Blue shot if you I mean first of all, we all know the way the flu shot works.
Speaker 0: Is that the smart doctors I assume CDC doctors or someone else?
Speaker 0: Figures out.
Speaker 0: Hmm.
Speaker 0: These strains of flu are probably gonna be making the most evil this year.
Speaker 0: Let's get dead ones of those and put them in this here vaccine and test it.
Speaker 0: and that's the flu shot for this year.
Speaker 0: And that's how it works.
Speaker 0: right and every year is different Which means if they're wrong?
Speaker 0: Yeah, you might still get the flu.
Speaker 0: It's possible Right, but it doesn't matter.
Speaker 0: right you want to go back to the day when like the flu killed millions of people?
Speaker 0: No, no, you don't and that's why you should go get jabbed.
Speaker 0: It's like oh no you got jabbed.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well, even if it hurts and even if it sucks and even if you're a big baby you pass out.
Speaker 0: Would you rather have millions of people die from the horrible flu?
Speaker 0: No.
Speaker 1: Well, it's even more important that even if you're just selfish You don't care about other people.
Speaker 1: Getting the flu shot reduces your chance of getting the flu and has almost no consequences for you and likely no Consequences other than possibly avoiding the flu.
Speaker 1: if
Speaker 0: you
Speaker 1: haven't had a legit flu in a while Like if you've had cold haven't
Speaker 0: had one in like so long
Speaker 1: and you forget I haven't
Speaker 0: even been sick in so long
Speaker 1: the actually if you have an actual influenza it is Way worse than you probably remember it being if you haven't had it in a
Speaker 0: while.
Speaker 0: Also is that when you're an adult right?
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah Getting sick is way worse than getting like.
Speaker 0: when I got sick as a kid like I felt bad But like I was kind of happy.
Speaker 1: I never go to school.
Speaker 0: I mean not to go to school, but also it didn't feel so bad that like I minded too much.
Speaker 0: Well, here's so I could still like, you know watch prices right and play Nintendo like fine.
Speaker 0: If I get sick now with the same sickness, I'm like, it's the same thing with falling Like if I fall I like.
Speaker 0: when I was a kid I fell down the stairs.
Speaker 0: as my memory tells me I fell down the stairs on numerous occasions Yeah and jumped off of like porches that were you know a story above the ground with no problem whatsoever.
Speaker 0: and I think about doing that now and it's like I would just die.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I remember one time as a kid I was just in my bedroom.
Speaker 0: If I fell down a stair like a few stairs right now, I'd probably blink a bone.
Speaker 1: I was in my bedroom and I just was like looking out the window and then my kid brain was just like you could totally Make it.
Speaker 1: I just fucking jumped out of the second story Landed down in like the garden and then I knocked on the front door and my parents like what the fuck?
Speaker 0: Yeah, so Getting sick is the same thing.
Speaker 0: It's way worse when you're an adult.
Speaker 0: So get it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, cuz kids with shitty immune systems they can't be getting a flu shot that'll give them flu.
Speaker 1: but the main difference between the Like I'll just be in sick and having the flu is when you're just sick and you stay home from work.
Speaker 1: You'll just sit there and play video games and feel shitty.
Speaker 1: Well the last time I had a legit flu I couldn't hurt too much to play a video game.
Speaker 0: You can't go take photos of roller hockey.
Speaker 1: No, you're gonna sit well.
Speaker 1: so Emily came home while I had that flu like I Didn't go to work and she went to work and she comes home and I was apparently I don't remember this that while I was Sitting in the living room and all the lights are off The TV wasn't on.
Speaker 1: it was just silent and I was hunched over Sitting upright with a blanket covering me like a shroud not moving and I didn't react.
Speaker 1: when she came home.
Speaker 1: Yeah, she was like, are you okay?
Speaker 1: And I was like no no Obviously not.
Speaker 1: you want to go to bed?
Speaker 1: and I was like it hurts too much.
Speaker 0: go to the hospital.
Speaker 1: Thing is I had a flu and I'm an adult.
Speaker 1: I'm healthy.
Speaker 1: The hospital wasn't gonna do anything Depends it was just a flu.
Speaker 0: They might have been able to tell you like maybe you're dehydrated didn't realize it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm pretty on top of that.
Speaker 0: I could think IV you.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah Morphine that'll make you feel better.
Speaker 0: get sleep right away.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they give me the morphine for that.
Speaker 1: I probably not.
Speaker 0: I feel like tell them how it hurts.
Speaker 0: It hurts.
Speaker 1: All I got to ten Man when I got the food poisoning that one time in New York That was an eight that like that was the number I told them.
Speaker 1: on that scale I think that was the worst pain I've ever experienced in my life.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm Yeah In some news, you probably noticed that some people are tweeting entire essays.
Speaker 0: now This is my news.
Speaker 1: you stole it, okay, I introduced it.
Speaker 1: you can just know it's Scott's news.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so Twitter which can't do anything right ever except I guess do the bare minimum to keep itself from dying completely and have enough momentum that people can't abandon and even though there's better things out there has Decided that some people are gonna be able to tweet 280 instead of 140 characters.
Speaker 1: eventually everyone will.
Speaker 0: I guess I can't but whatever.
Speaker 1: Well, you can.
Speaker 1: there is a way for anyone.
Speaker 0: it's on the one right.
Speaker 0: on the one hand this is Annoying because I feel like people are gonna be.
Speaker 0: I'm already pissed off when people tweet a thread.
Speaker 0: if you want to tweet a Thread what you should be doing is writing a blog post and tweeting a link to the blog post.
Speaker 0: That's what you should be fucking doing.
Speaker 0: Don't give me this thread bullshit, right?
Speaker 0: The whole point of Twitter is that you can say everything you need to say in less.
Speaker 0: There have been many occasions where I myself I'm making a tweet and there is literally no way to include everything I want to include and it.
Speaker 0: you know I take out all the cruft and I can't get it in 140 because I'm including like a link and an image and Three hashtags plus the description of what it is, right and that just doesn't fit.
Speaker 0: so it's nice to get the 280 for those rare cases, but Letting everyone 280 all the freaking time is like oh people are just gonna write a bunch of useless crap and that now they had The space they're gonna fill it in.
Speaker 0: that's what people do.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if you give them an inch you can take a mile, right?
Speaker 1: So is at least in English 140 felt like I was a pretty good number.
Speaker 0: This is this is not something that will improve Twitter and it's it's very disparaging because at the same time are discouraging.
Speaker 0: Yeah, not despair.
Speaker 1: I'm going to disparage it.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: I did.
Speaker 0: It's because I am discouraged by Discouraging because there are things Twitter should be doing that they could do.
Speaker 0: That I guess would be more work than doing this.
Speaker 0: to do this all you got to do is change like one number in the code and press enter right, but The things you want them to do they know.
Speaker 1: do what I want to do.
Speaker 0: I want rid of Nazis.
Speaker 1: get rid of Nazis.
Speaker 1: Uh, That's pretty much number one.
Speaker 0: That's pretty much it.
Speaker 0: Yeah Get rid of threads.
Speaker 0: make people tweet a link to a blog post if someone wants to write something because the threads don't get in my way because Usually the ones.
Speaker 0: but the thing is people are writing.
Speaker 0: actually I'm not.
Speaker 0: the thing is the content in most throughout Angle is high quality content that I do want to read.
Speaker 0: It just really sucks to read that content when in Twitter thread form, right?
Speaker 1: Regardless of which Twitter reader you use especially when they mess it up and like their thread turns into two threads, right?
Speaker 0: It's like let force give people of something where if they go over the 140 what it should do is it you turn their tweet It's like a link with it with a short description That's under 140 and then that link take you to a page that has the whole fucking essay written out somewhere Like a blog post.
Speaker 1: I feel like normal people just don't write blogs anymore.
Speaker 0: They just I mean, yeah people aren't gonna start a WordPress just so they can do this, right?
Speaker 0: Well, you have to.
Speaker 1: I would I should yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's what you should do.
Speaker 0: But uh, the Twitter should provide the long blog because Twitter was originally called microblogging.
Speaker 0: No one calls it that anymore.
Speaker 0: You need to provide the macro blog to go with the microblog, right?
Speaker 0: And not everyone has a tumblr WordPress or medium or whatever it is to do this.
Speaker 0: Provide something for the people who are only tweeting so that they can tweet a long essay.
Speaker 0: I feel like making more than one tweet.
Speaker 1: hosting content on the internet has had this Like this dichotomy that's only increased over time where there's two completely separate classes of people.
Speaker 1: there's people like us who have platforms that we invest in or build or run and Audiences and all these things.
Speaker 1: so like I have a lot of ways to take things I want to say and put them on the internet and I don't think about it.
Speaker 1: There's no friction in that process.
Speaker 1: But most people don't use really any services at all and create very little content.
Speaker 1: So when they want to create some content, they don't have any like pipeline or process to distribute that.
Speaker 1: so the only avenue they have is the like Facebook and Twitter updates that they can post.
Speaker 0: there is so much content on the internet that is in a place it does not belong because The person who was posting that content is such a limited, you know view of the internet.
Speaker 0: their scope is so small.
Speaker 0: I saw a post on the board game reddit the other day that was like there is this Skeezy dude in our board game group who's like, you know It's actually harassing me and grabbing me and the other people won't kick him out, right and it's like yes
Speaker 1: one Everyone in that group is bad except you.
Speaker 0: that's true.
Speaker 0: We already.
Speaker 0: everything that to say about that issue has already been says a panel that we did at packs.
Speaker 0: Yes, the point is is board game reddit the right place for that.
Speaker 1: No, no, it's not not at all.
Speaker 1: Well for that the right place for it is a police report.
Speaker 0: That's exactly right, but I see me will write like essays as like a Reddit post in a subreddit.
Speaker 0: It's like.
Speaker 0: don't you have a blog for that?
Speaker 0: You know, it's like.
Speaker 0: no one has a. you know It's the only place that person could think of to know that content one hand.
Speaker 1: There was a time when I would do that kind of thing, too But that time was the 90s and the reason was back then.
Speaker 1: I was young and the internet was a very different place and I Carefully cultivated different personas and different parts of the internet and did not link them.
Speaker 0: How many people like make a video and put it as a tweet when they should be making a YouTube video and then linking to?
Speaker 0: It with a tweet.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like you gotta post your content in the right place.
Speaker 1: All I'm gonna say is the way my hand is is one on my phone.
Speaker 1: now I'm using a Twitter client that just doesn't show me the other people's likes.
Speaker 0: yeah, I ever see.
Speaker 0: I never understood why people complain about this so much because you should not be using the default Twitter client ever not on The web not on your phone on in your tablet not on your nothing.
Speaker 1: I like going to come because it's the easiest.
Speaker 1: just here we go Please.
Speaker 0: there is tweet deck is free.
Speaker 0: It has no ads and also has no bullshit and is also officially made by Twitter because they bought it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's been around for years.
Speaker 0: I've never used the official Twitter website ever except to like change my Twitter password or something.
Speaker 0: There's no reason to ever use official Twitter app or official Twitter website.
Speaker 0: they have ads and they're way worse than everything else and The other things are free.
Speaker 0: And in fact, if you pay for some of the ones that aren't free It's like you're using Twitter.
Speaker 0: First of all, it's like I think tweet bot is what like 10 bucks or something an iPhone?
Speaker 1: Well, hey the 10 bucks.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna often.
Speaker 0: you're using Twitter constantly all day and that's like three bagels.
Speaker 0: But I mean, come on you're doing this way more than three breakfast sandwiches To get rid of all ads and have no complaints.
Speaker 1: Well, though so here's an interesting problem that occurs.
Speaker 1: It's the same thing with ads in the 90s.
Speaker 1: in the 90s I would say the same thing and whenever anyone saw an ad I'd be like how Why would you ever see an ad on the internet?
Speaker 1: Do you want my hosts file?
Speaker 1: But as a result people who were smart enough to recognize that ads were toxic just blocked them.
Speaker 1: So there was very little UX pressure to deal with ads getting more and more toxic Because the people who saw them were the kinds of people who wouldn't complain or would just suck it up.
Speaker 1: And I feel like Twitter is in a similar boat where all the people who know better have ways to avoid the worst UX decisions that Twitter's making and Regular people get fucked by them and at the same time don't have enough under like they'll get mad at Twitter But they don't understand what changed that made them matter at Twitter.
Speaker 1: So they can't effectively complain about it and Twitter seems to do literally the worst job on earth and actually finding out what people want to use their platform for or They do know.
Speaker 1: this is what I actually suspect.
Speaker 1: Twitter knows exactly What people want to use their platform for and they don't want you to use it that way because they can't make as much money.
Speaker 1: They want it to be a platform.
Speaker 0: How do you make it money to begin with?
Speaker 0: They're not?
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's understand.
Speaker 1: now I'm confident I could make.
Speaker 1: I could personally make Twitter like just this service Something that made more money than it costs without ruining it.
Speaker 0: However, I think that Twitter you might think Twitter's so big It can't be replaced or whatever.
Speaker 0: But look My space got killed by Facebook and Facebook also will die at some point.
Speaker 1: So there is stuff's all really different though nowadays Like that was still kind of an early pioneering error of the Internet.
Speaker 0: things will die It can't last forever and also nothing even close to credible has appeared for Twitter, though You just need to get some people on there.
Speaker 1: Yeah, who remember?
Speaker 1: Hello that lasted a minute.
Speaker 0: It can happen.
Speaker 1: It's I'm pretty dubious of that.
Speaker 0: I'll make one then.
Speaker 1: The only way it would happen is if someone set it up to basically ride on Twitter's coattails.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think you can do it.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I don't think so and it could be done.
Speaker 1: people settle and then they're done.
Speaker 1: We'll see.
Speaker 1: But I feel like the real problem here is that Twitter as a company or at least the people who want to make money off of Twitter what they actually want is a platform where People are creating Content just to get other people to read it.
Speaker 1: But the real product is that most people are only following celebrities who tweet sponsored things at them.
Speaker 1: They don't actually want like you and me just to add each other because they don't make money off of that.
Speaker 1: Well anyway in some other news Another one of those somebody gets dragged off of a flight.
Speaker 0: situations happen Which happens often a lot of how those happening lately or maybe they were always happening But people didn't record the video of them with their phones and then put it on Twitter.
Speaker 0: Yeah, which is now what's happening.
Speaker 1: So now we're learning about them more often, but this one's a little bit interesting because I'm pretty much a hundred percent on the side of the airline in this case.
Speaker 1: Yeah, um in terms of dragging this woman off the plane.
Speaker 1: So the deal is you know, you fly on an airline and they give you peanuts sometimes and sometimes they don't give you peanuts.
Speaker 1: and usually when they don't give you peanuts either they're one of those weird no peanut airlines or Somebody who's gonna be on the flight registered in advance and said I got a dangerous peanut allergy.
Speaker 1: Don't let any peanuts be on my flight and they'll take care of that for you.
Speaker 1: Now there's the whole aside about how a good percentage of the people who claim to have peanut allergies probably don't.
Speaker 1: but that's a whole separate Discussion.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but that's fine.
Speaker 1: That's that's the thing.
Speaker 0: This woman got our people who do have deadly peanut allergies.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's not like.
Speaker 1: that is the thing that does not exist, but it is a thing that is over reported.
Speaker 0: Obviously many things are over reported.
Speaker 1: So this person got on a plane and There was someone else had a dog with them on the flight which happens.
Speaker 1: That's totally fine.
Speaker 0: There were dogs on my last flight.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like I love it when there's a dog in my flight.
Speaker 0: Everyone's petting them in the in the gate while waiting to get on board.
Speaker 1: It's good stuff little dog.
Speaker 1: I know I believe this dog was actually a service dog too, which made it even more interesting.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm because this person Claimed once the once they saw they already got on the plane and they were settled and once they saw that there was a dog On the plane they flipped out and demanded that the dog be removed the plane because they claim to have a deadly dog allergy.
Speaker 0: Okay, so why didn't?
Speaker 0: how come you're not already dead?
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'd I literally Believe that that is a lie.
Speaker 0: I don't think that deadly dog allergy is Thing but I've never heard of deadly dog allergy.
Speaker 0: it could exist.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: I could be wrong but even so How come you're not dead?
Speaker 0: didn't you see the dog in the gate area?
Speaker 0: like?
Speaker 1: the whole thing doesn't make a lot of sense Ah, but even more important the person who's on the plane.
Speaker 1: The dog is also on the plane.
Speaker 1: The person is not dead.
Speaker 1: the person demands that the dog be removed in the air.
Speaker 0: on the plane is very not circulated.
Speaker 0: Well, you'd be already in bad shape.
Speaker 1: The airline is like do you have a doctor's note or anything?
Speaker 1: and of course this person does not because they're clearly making it out and The airlines like well in the interest of your safety Will remove you from the plane and put you on another flight that doesn't have dogs on it.
Speaker 1: and that's when this person Super freaks out and ends up getting arrested Because they wouldn't get off the plane.
Speaker 1: and that's the funny part.
Speaker 1: This person refused to get off the plane That had a dog on it that if they weren't lying would kill them.
Speaker 1: They refused to get off when given the chance to remove themselves from the deadly thing that will kill them.
Speaker 0: Someone has a legit peanut allergy and I pull out a pea jar of skippy and start unscrewing it.
Speaker 0: they run.
Speaker 0: That's how it works.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if they weren't running they must be lying Or they cray.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they got a death wish.
Speaker 0: I don't know But if I'm allergic to if you break if you come up with some poison ivy and you're like, hey Scott, okay I'm gonna run the fuck away.
Speaker 0: Right, I mean I might go to the airline gate and be like yo.
Speaker 0: someone on the complaint got poison ivy.
Speaker 0: Try to rub it on everyone and then they'll arrest you though an ivy man, sir.
Speaker 0: But do you have?
Speaker 0: I'm not hanging around your wrist.
Speaker 1: you rub it, sir Do you have a doctor's note saying that poison ivy is dangerous to you?
Speaker 0: Yes, yes, I do.
Speaker 0: Let me show you my leg where the rash is currently growing.
Speaker 0: I'm again
Speaker 1: But I will say that I have encountered a very similar situation at multiple points in my life and it always boils down the same way and that's kind of why I was interested in this story is Because and I've seen this happen a lot at restaurants especially in states that allow animals and restaurants like not this not this there's no states that say oh you have to let animals that Are not service animals in your restaurant.
Speaker 0: There's a lot of rules saying use even if you want to let animals in your restaurant You can't because hair gets in the food.
Speaker 0: That's not.
Speaker 1: and that was actually even though Arguably the restaurant owner should be as long as they make it clear should be able to make that choice.
Speaker 1: New York I think recently passed a law saying that I might get a B instead of a outdoor Restaurants can if they wish to allow patients to have dogs with them.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 1: No, I don't have to really.
Speaker 0: I thought Outdoor was totally okay.
Speaker 0: Was the problem?
Speaker 0: because that's where the foods being prepared.
Speaker 1: Nope So no because the food preparation area is separated from the dining area.
Speaker 0: You're eating outside Right, it's like dog in New York.
Speaker 0: the amount of fecal coliform Is the least of your worries getting on the food.
Speaker 0: if you're eating outside They're just cars blasting exhaust particles onto your food.
Speaker 0: if you're eating inside outside About some dog hair ever been outside and smell some poop in the distance homeless man walks past your you know Restaurant while you're eating there and gets you know, who knows what particles right?
Speaker 1: Particles it's always food particles.
Speaker 0: I agree an inside then your food could be relatively safe from you know.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so the law that changed was that if a restaurant wants to allow it They are allowed to allow it and if you don't like it somewhere else, that's there and it's still dog and cat cafes and stuff.
Speaker 0: They just have to keep the animal area separate from the eating area.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I really really occasionally I've worked at places where people just brought their dogs to work every day and I miss that.
Speaker 0: that's totally cool in an office.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's not a food preparation office or a kitchen but I've grown into a slab.
Speaker 0: It's just the office of desks and chairs.
Speaker 0: You can totally bring a dog.
Speaker 1: I've run into many situations in my life Most of when I was younger and living with my family and having dogs where there are places where it is Okay for pets to be.
Speaker 1: but there are people who just don't like animals and try to complain to get said Animals removed from the area not because they're causing a problem because they don't like pets and they don't like people who have pets.
Speaker 0: There's people who you know, there's a nimby attitude.
Speaker 0: I don't like that thing that someone else is doing so I want to impose my will on them with my HOA or my whatever And that's basically just the worst person there is.
Speaker 0: Someone's a bad person.
Speaker 1: I am like 99% confident that that is the situation here that this person just doesn't like dogs.
Speaker 0: Whenever I see anyone trying to impose their will on someone else just because that person's doing something They don't like you know, turn off that loud music.
Speaker 0: That's not actually keeping you awake You just don't like my music.
Speaker 1: stop killing all those people Scott.
Speaker 0: Okay, but I mean that's actually hurting other people.
Speaker 1: It's not hurting you though.
Speaker 1: So what do you have to complain?
Speaker 0: Loud music, you know, my party music isn't hurting anybody.
Speaker 0: My dog isn't hurting anyone yet.
Speaker 0: It might hurt you though There's a by rim dog.
Speaker 0: There is a threshold above which party music can hurt you Sure, but if I'm under the threshold and you just you know, you didn't care when that neighbor was having the disco party But suddenly I'm having a hip-hop party and you mad.
Speaker 1: What I do think though he's oh here's a side.
Speaker 1: one thing we definitely need to ban is loud vehicles.
Speaker 1: There is no place for that in the mind They are.
Speaker 0: there's ordinances pretty much everywhere about how loud your vehicle can be just they don't enforce it too much.
Speaker 1: Yep, cuz the other day we were down in Brooklyn and there was a lot of motorcycles farting around.
Speaker 1: super loud Yep, and then I finally figured out cuz I biked home most a lot of motorcycles just illegal in New York Perry.
Speaker 0: in New York City There bikes at least.
Speaker 1: oh my god the dirt bike thing that's like that's like such a New York specific problem.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean cuz dirt bikes are legal in most places.
Speaker 0: It's just not New York City and the cops love to basically confiscate dirt bikes.
Speaker 0: Ah, but there's part and then make videos demolishing them all.
Speaker 1: but part of the reason for that Cuz I just a waste of resources.
Speaker 0: really.
Speaker 0: they should auction those off upstate.
Speaker 1: So I've encountered The dirt bike menace before.
Speaker 1: basically what happens in New York Like kinda regularly is a whole bunch of teenagers and young adults who have these illegal dirt bikes Will sort of have a flash mob somewhere and then there'll be hundreds of them just without license plates Screaming around on streets going the wrong way on roads and on sidewalks and blocking traffic and hurting people and causing trouble.
Speaker 1: Yep, that happens like that flash mob of dirt bikes.
Speaker 1: I've seen it twice.
Speaker 0: I've seen it Way more than twice.
Speaker 1: I've seen it twice in like giant mob that I called 9-1-1 about and I've never called 9-1-1 on them.
Speaker 0: But I go.
Speaker 1: hey, no, they're they were they.
Speaker 1: so they were going in.
Speaker 1: You know how the Pulaski has the one way and then the other way and then the bikeway.
Speaker 1: They were riding in one direction on all three of those.
Speaker 1: They're going against traffic on the Pulaski and with traffic and screaming through the bike lane.
Speaker 1: And it wasn't just dirt bikes.
Speaker 1: There were some three-wheelers in there like the off-road three-wheelers as in literally never ride one of those.
Speaker 0: They're one of those dangerous illegal to ride in New York City.
Speaker 0: Also dangerous to ride anywhere ever.
Speaker 1: Yeah for ATV four-wheel fine like that.
Speaker 0: Those are safe to ride them in appropriate, you know.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there is no safe place to ride a three-wheel ATV.
Speaker 1: Those things are just pure death but anyway things Of the day.
Speaker 1: What do you got?
Speaker 0: So geek nights has a long tradition of using a Soviet and Eastern European awesome artworks as things.
Speaker 1: Oh, I think there's a theme because my thing of the day is also Soviet related.
Speaker 0: That's how we do here And we haven't done any of those in quite a while Right, not since like I guess one of those Tetris thing or something.
Speaker 0: Who knows anyway.
Speaker 0: So this is something that's really interesting because back in the day when people Poisoned themselves more than they do now when it was socially acceptable Right now it's really not.
Speaker 0: when people when lighters were not as common people used matches to light their you know Deadly tobacco poison.
Speaker 1: Maybe they use that oil lighter like the guy who burned his house down on the live stream
Speaker 0: and people had you know match books and match boxes and match books and match boxes were for all their negatives were very useful and that they provide a venue for the displaying of Advertisements and also artwork.
Speaker 0: So here is a collection of match box Advertisements and artworks from Eastern Europe and Soviet Russia and these are so great.
Speaker 1: I want a table top.
Speaker 1: board games Uses this aesthetic.
Speaker 0: right and the aesthetic is awesome especially the outer space related ones.
Speaker 0: also the camera related ones and the family related ones and the Everything.
Speaker 0: some of them look sort of like the glory to Rome black box artwork.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 1: So look at these ski ones.
Speaker 1: How about?
Speaker 0: there's an ice hockey, you know sports related.
Speaker 0: It's pretty much all great and It's like I kind of wish there was.
Speaker 0: you know as we move to the digital realm Which is great, obviously and away from smoking which is even better perhaps We're not generating these physical artifacts anymore without fizz.
Speaker 0: without physical artifacts There are less physical places for the displaying of art that you can encounter and collect in.
Speaker 1: so the thing that used to be that no longer be is If you were reading a book in public anywhere people could see what book you were reading Which might start a conversation or something.
Speaker 1: now that just a back of a black Kindle You could.
Speaker 1: what if you put another screen on the Kindle?
Speaker 0: I think there was.
Speaker 0: there was something like that.
Speaker 1: I feel like there was.
Speaker 0: yeah, but that kind of thing.
Speaker 1: We got to make did?
Speaker 0: they're actually on Kickstarter.
Speaker 0: It's way too much money.
Speaker 0: They're selling an e-book that contains the entire fist of the North Star manga and you can read it in Japanese or English.
Speaker 0: We've never been in English.
Speaker 0: It's very very expensive But it's one e-book and you can't like put other books on it.
Speaker 0: It literally only reads fist of the North Star.
Speaker 0: you open it up and there it is two screens one left one on the right Just like a real manga But it's only fist of the North Star.
Speaker 0: You can't load a different e-book on it.
Speaker 0: You can't unload fist of the North Star Nothing.
Speaker 0: It's just that one book forever and in the bat.
Speaker 0: And it looks like a book because the back of it is a cover because it you open it up and there's two screens.
Speaker 1: Oh my god.
Speaker 1: So I don't want it.
Speaker 1: you buy it and I'll read it, you know, we should do we should do up we should kick-start.
Speaker 0: We'll buy very expensive.
Speaker 0: It's like hundreds of dollars.
Speaker 1: We kick-start it and Everyone who buys in we just make a list and we pass it around like Radioactive Man number one.
Speaker 1: Sure, everybody reads it and passes it to the next person.
Speaker 1: You got ten bucks for me this and the more money you give the higher up in the list you go.
Speaker 1: who gets it first I'll give you maybe 20 and if you break it I kill you.
Speaker 0: because what are you gonna do with the batteries run out on it?
Speaker 0: Okay, if you charge, I don't know how it fucking works gotta be ice.
Speaker 1: What if it breaks?
Speaker 1: No, if it broke that Radioactive man number one.
Speaker 1: I'm just saying so in my Soviet thing of the day, I don't think any of none of us have flown on a Concorde.
Speaker 1: That was kind of before.
Speaker 0: I have never been on a Concorde though I have seen one in person because it's on the intrepid.
Speaker 0: Yes, that one go look at that.
Speaker 1: one used to go inside it But now you can't.
Speaker 0: but I've see.
Speaker 0: I've also seen what another one like at an airport just sitting there.
Speaker 1: But the Concorde is pretty cool.
Speaker 1: And I don't want to get too deep.
Speaker 0: It's also way smaller than it looks in photos.
Speaker 1: Well, most things are like fighter jets, you know, you look at a real fighter jet and it's so tiny.
Speaker 1: It's almost shocking.
Speaker 0: Well, it only needs to hold one or two people.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but the Concorde held a reasonable number of people.
Speaker 1: But if you're too young to even know what the hell the Concorde was it was a super jet developed by Europeans that Could fly between New York and London in a shockingly short amount of time.
Speaker 0: So yeah There are only a few routes you could take on it and there are mostly transatlantic flights.
Speaker 1: The reason is a lot of money had nothing to do with technology was mostly protectionism NIMBYism and fear of a sound problem due to the sonic booms.
Speaker 1: that may or may not have been as bad as people implied.
Speaker 0: Right, but I've never heard the sonic boom from it.
Speaker 0: So I don't know.
Speaker 0: so I but I have heard fighter jets fly over and that sonic boom is annoying.
Speaker 1: I spent much of my life living next to Selfridge Air National Guard base.
Speaker 1: F-16s in formation would fly over my house like multiple times a day And occasionally they drop the afterburners and sonic booms would happen and it was kind of amazing.
Speaker 1: amazing But also really really really annoying.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but also planes used to just be louder like.
Speaker 1: don't get into that.
Speaker 0: But anyway cars used to be louder too.
Speaker 1: So Europeans made the Concorde and Soviets and the Americans got Jealous and were pulled a me too as in.
Speaker 1: they wanted to prove that they have the ability to also develop something like that.
Speaker 1: The American Concorde was garbage, but I'm not talking about that.
Speaker 1: I think of the day is a video Titled why you wouldn't want to fly on the Soviet Concorde.
Speaker 0: I wouldn't want to fly in the Soviet anything.
Speaker 1: Tupolev tu-144 story.
Speaker 0: I learned everything I need to know about Soviet.
Speaker 0: You know aerospace Not the space part but the arrow from aerobids cheapest and the crappiest place in aerobids.
Speaker 1: if you Started in the Soviet Union you could you could buy Soviet planes But you didn't start in the Soviet Union because shit sucked over there.
Speaker 1: And if you started anywhere else in the game, except like Iraq you uh, you could buy any planes from like Airbus or Boeing But you couldn't fly.
Speaker 1: so via
Speaker 0: body
Speaker 1: if you went and you have McDonald Douglas the MD 80 I played a lot of that game, but if you tried to buy the Soviet planes, they'd be like, sorry you can't buy from Eastern Bloc countries, but if you played in the right era eventually perestroika would happen and Eastern markets would open up and you could go buy those planes.
Speaker 1: and then suddenly you could go talk to the representatives from Ilyushin and Tupolev.
Speaker 1: And the first thing you realize is that those planes Were pieces of shit and you literally never ever wanted to buy them under any circumstances.
Speaker 0: No, you could.
Speaker 0: you could profit by putting them on some shitty route except they use so much gas and were so unreliable.
Speaker 1: They ended up costing too much.
Speaker 0: They're so cheap to buy.
Speaker 1: They weren't actually that cheap.
Speaker 0: and as long as you only need them for a short amount of time just to get a little bit Of profit so you can buy a better plane.
Speaker 0: Or so we're Soviet Russia and you can't buy another plane.
Speaker 0: Yeah Pretty much.
Speaker 1: the only reason you use those as you started in Russia because you hate yourself and you wanted the game to be impossible.
Speaker 1: The only other crazy place to start was Iraq because you could start in Iraq and then the Iraq war would break out like two Years into the game and just ruin you.
Speaker 1: So, yeah Don't think you wanted to fly on the tu-144.
Speaker 1: And then at a moment the booklet book is not the first or the fourth or the third or the sixth But the fifth season one two or five.
Speaker 0: Yes five seasons is the first book of the Broken Earth trilogy By NK Jemisin and I finished reading it in its entirety.
Speaker 0: I started reading the second one a little bit But actually I stopped because a I'm playing Metroid on my DS and now I don't want to mess up my thinking of the first Book too much because the blinds will get blurred.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna read it.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna read through it pretty quick because book two starts pretty much immediately at the end of book one.
Speaker 0: I almost feel like the first book was actually shorter cuz I didn't couldn't tell how long it was with Ebookness and the fact that the end of the book doesn't end when the Kindle says a hundred percent it ends before then.
Speaker 0: So I did, you know sort of cut out to me.
Speaker 0: It really feels I don't know how long book two and three are But just from book one It feels like really all these three books are one book that happened to be chopped into three Yeah, even pieces because it just picks up right where the first one left off like immediately.
Speaker 1: But yeah, if I don't finish it by the next Thursday show I'll definitely have it done a month from now because I'm just gonna read it real soon.
Speaker 1: Problems my commute so short.
Speaker 1: I literally can't read fiction on my commute.
Speaker 0: There are other times of the day where reading is fine Ah, but the weather's been nice and I've been creating content like before you go to bed and immediately when you wake up.
Speaker 1: Yeah before I go to bed.
Speaker 1: I'm playing overwatch.
Speaker 0: Well, don't do that.
Speaker 0: No, I don't do that.
Speaker 1: Did you should I read overwatch?
Speaker 1: It's still.
Speaker 1: overwatch is so up your alley.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's all those feels of those old quick mods I'm killing some metroids right now.
Speaker 1: Well, we can play some PUBG together because we'll both be equally bad at it.
Speaker 1: I think.
Speaker 0: maybe I don't think it matter.
Speaker 0: I don't think I care if I play PUBG if I don't think I'll care about winning or losing so much.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I feel like and I feel like if I die, I'm not gonna wait for the next round to start I'm just gonna join a different server.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna try to play it enough until I win once and then I'll just quit.
Speaker 0: It's not it's too much money for that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I feel like I'll never win it.
Speaker 1: So we'll see.
Speaker 1: I Feel like it's easier to win a counter-strike gun game than it is to win a PUBG.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there's a lot less competition.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So, uh Otherwise, if you follow me on YouTube, you should also follow Scott and if you follow Scott on YouTube You should also follow me because we just put up two big pieces of content on both of those.
Speaker 1: So on my youtube channel, you can see our newest pecs panel about rage quitters and butthurt rage.
Speaker 1: If you go to Scott's YouTube channel You can see the first episode of our new series based on the anime Boston panel.
Speaker 1: We used to do judge anime by its cover where we review next the next season's anime Before it comes out because we're good at that and we're usually right.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm You should also go to all the other places on the internet that exist like Twitter Facebook.
Speaker 1: It's everywhere, you know, we don't have a myspace.
Speaker 0: We set up geek nights everywhere that we could set up shop for geek nights even like Instagram account Google Plus.
Speaker 1: There is a Google Plus for us.
Speaker 1: you know.
Speaker 0: if there's a place that you want us to set up shop on the internet and we're not there tell us I Google+ still exists.
Speaker 0: we could we could upload our content to you porn.
Speaker 1: I guess we could.
Speaker 1: So, yeah desks, I can't believe whatever.
Speaker 1: did a show on this.
Speaker 0: we did a show about furniture.
Speaker 0: Yep, which how many?
Speaker 0: Thursday.
Speaker 0: we should change Thursday from being everything to being food and furniture.
Speaker 1: the FF No only things to start with F.
Speaker 0: Okay Friedman freeze games.
Speaker 1: Yeah food furniture freedom.
Speaker 1: No, that's the next Friedman freeze game.
Speaker 1: food and furniture.
Speaker 1: Sure, it's a dexterity game.
Speaker 1: You're trying to eat at your desk without spilling food into your keyboard.
Speaker 0: I fail.
Speaker 0: I just banged out my keyboard today.
Speaker 0: So many seeds from everything bagels came out.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah I uh once a month I take my keyboard and I do the hold it sideways and do the tap tap shake.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm and Horrors emerge.
Speaker 0: Yeah, pretty much but for me mostly everything bagel seeds, so desks.
Speaker 1: It's a way way back.
Speaker 1: We did a show on chairs because Scott and I both spent a lot of money to each buy a really really nice office chair And it turned out to be a great great investment.
Speaker 1: I'm sitting in the same chair that I bought in that geek nights episode at my apartment.
Speaker 0: I have the same chair and even though the armrests on it got busted once I emailed the company and they sent me brand new Even better armrests to swap out for free.
Speaker 1: if I had continued to buy cheaper office chairs I probably would have had to buy like four of them.
Speaker 0: and people buy those horrific gaming chairs Look like a race a chair from a race car that on wheels, which is.
Speaker 0: I don't know what the hell people find.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they don't even look that comfortable.
Speaker 1: Actually.
Speaker 1: I know now.
Speaker 0: No, I've sat in them at packs.
Speaker 0: They're not comfortable.
Speaker 1: They're about as comfortable as a cheap office chair.
Speaker 0: However, if I was still a kid in high school instead of buying the $50 chair at Staples I would have bought that chair instead.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but I I love the hell out of this chair.
Speaker 0: I was born earlier, so I didn't have to have that chair.
Speaker 1: But if I had to list the Things that I interact with that are furniture or the things that could affect my life the most in terms of number of hours I'm forced to interact with them.
Speaker 1: desks are like Almost a hundred percent Venn diagram overlap with chair.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you mean you're sitting in that chair for X hours a day every day and you sit and you're sitting at that desk.
Speaker 0: So isn't the desk almost as important?
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's almost like an extension of the chair because if I'm not at my desk I'm not sitting in my chair.
Speaker 1: I'm lounging on a couch Or I'm at a table.
Speaker 0: So there's so many desks these days come at so many varieties since people added the standing option.
Speaker 1: Yep So at my new office the most of the of the desks because there's a cool kind of a cool thing There is that everyone is the exact same desk layout no matter what like no matter what their job is 100% identical everywhere.
Speaker 0: There's no offices or anything really even even Even Bloomberg just standing there in a field of people.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Well you can you can have that desk.
Speaker 1: That's a little more isolated, but it's still that exact size and shape.
Speaker 0: He doesn't have an office with a door.
Speaker 0: No one seems to not even Bloomberg himself.
Speaker 1: It doesn't seem to be.
Speaker 1: I don't work in his office I don't 100% know.
Speaker 1: I've gone over there.
Speaker 1: I'm just like strolling but like hey, what's up?
Speaker 1: Oh but anyway Most of the desks now have the big two monitors on a thing that you basically Lift it and now it's a standing desk.
Speaker 1: But because I joined recently mine does not have that so I do not have a standing desk.
Speaker 1: in fact I've never had a standing desk.
Speaker 0: kind of want one.
Speaker 0: Oh at my work basically if you ask for a standing desk They get you this thing that's like basically a little elevator that they put on your regular desk.
Speaker 0: Oh, and then you put your stuff on top of that and then you sort of have to like pick it up And then put it.
Speaker 1: that has two positions You grab your monitor and you just go and it's up and it brings the keyboard up with it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I have no interest in standing desk unless it's the kind where I push a button.
Speaker 0: It goes.
Speaker 1: see it goes some sort of motorized situation right You know, there's all those studies like if you sit too many hours a day your chance of death from all causes increases.
Speaker 0: You know, I've seen all these different studies and I don't know what to believe because I've seen some that have been that say that's bullshit But those are paid for by big chair and a big chair.
Speaker 0: and I see ones that are say You should stand and those are paid for by big standing desk And so I don't know who to believe.
Speaker 1: I found a meta study that actually might explain that.
Speaker 1: All right, this is recent.
Speaker 1: like I I'm gonna talk about this in the forum.
Speaker 1: I want to link to it like make a thread about it.
Speaker 1: I read this a couple days ago.
Speaker 1: Also.
Speaker 0: I already invested in big chair.
Speaker 0: I don't.
Speaker 1: So there are studies that show if you sit too much your chances of death just increase.
Speaker 1: like that's just a thing.
Speaker 1: That's there's a correlation.
Speaker 0: But is it actually the sitting or just the fact that you're not doing anything?
Speaker 1: There is a almost identical correlation for people who stand all the time who stand equivalent amount.
Speaker 1: people have standing job.
Speaker 0: It's just not moving is the problem.
Speaker 1: Uh People who have jobs where they move but they're on their feet also have a higher chance of death.
Speaker 0: Oh, I guess moving is not the solution.
Speaker 1: then a bit It appears that the only way to eliminate to reduce that chance of death in these kinds of situations not working is to sit and Stand.
Speaker 1: I'll be in about equal amounts over the course of your day.
Speaker 0: That's what I do.
Speaker 0: Anyway, even though I don't have a standing this.
Speaker 1: Yeah most people do not do that.
Speaker 1: but There is a caveat that it might be that most jobs that involve standing pay shit and low money Correlates to low bad life outcome.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm And also those kinds of jobs tend to be more stressful.
Speaker 0: It could be just that boring job.
Speaker 0: sitting at a desk also kills you.
Speaker 0: No true just because it's regardless of whether you're sitting or standing at the desk The point is you're stuck at a desk all day and therefore you are dying.
Speaker 0: Yep inside.
Speaker 1: So, uh, what kind of desk do you have at home?
Speaker 0: I have this desk from IKEA.
Speaker 0: Before that I did the piece of wood on cinder blocks at RIT just as good but it was too big for a New York Apartment.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I got an IKEA desk.
Speaker 0: That is basically Three pieces of wood two vertical ones and a horizontal one and that's I love.
Speaker 0: just having a big ass Flat generic space that I could then arrange things on.
Speaker 0: no weird tears.
Speaker 0: No, I used to like in college I think I had one with like a bit that went up a bit and then that wasn't good.
Speaker 0: I switched to the flat piece of wood.
Speaker 1: See I really like Desks that have tears and spaces on them all over the place.
Speaker 0: I do not need the tears and spaces I want a big flat thing.
Speaker 1: But the best desk I ever had was just because we lived in Beacon I took the master bedroom because you got the walk-in closet.
Speaker 1: So I just got the giant ass bedroom instead.
Speaker 1: That bedroom was so big that I had one of those Gigantic L desks.
Speaker 0: All right, the desk was L-shaped Yeah Yeah.
Speaker 1: And it also had and on the side the long side a tear with like more space for shit.
Speaker 0: Yeah, L-shaped is nice because it's basically, you know, you only can have two contacts in one space.
Speaker 0: It's just a more more flat area.
Speaker 0: Right because normally even if I get the biggest and flattest piece of wood I get like a Warhammer table.
Speaker 0: It's like well, I can't reach the whole thing.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but an L-shape was like, ah now I can reach even more flat space But I'm a big fan in my life.
Speaker 1: like this is.
Speaker 1: one of those things that I actually put a lot of thought and investment into is that I like the idea of having separate spaces or separate Contacts for different kinds of tasks because it causes better focus.
Speaker 0: if I had more space to work with I definitely would be doing that.
Speaker 0: I'd have a different desk for like, you know, make it a. you know playing games or you know.
Speaker 0: I found a picture of my old desk.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know a different desk for like working on models and stuff.
Speaker 0: You know different desks for computing.
Speaker 1: Look at that toricon poster.
Speaker 1: It's an old fucking picture.
Speaker 0: Anyway 2007 this picture.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but the point is, you know, yeah, so it more desks is always better.
Speaker 1: A giant house.
Speaker 1: I'd have a room that was just the podcasting media streaming room.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: I'd have a separate room.
Speaker 1: That's the I'm gonna play some fucking games room and the tabletop room would probably be even another room.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm I loved when I was a kid like the fact that we had a dining room that was separate from the eating like the food Preparation room.
Speaker 0: I mean most people are probably like but I have that.
Speaker 0: well You don't live in a tiny apartment where you suddenly don't have that and it's like I was able to get a dishwasher But I wasn't able to get a dining room.
Speaker 0: You know how much a dining room cause.
Speaker 1: yeah I can't afford that or even just little things like when I lived in sterling heights.
Speaker 1: We didn't really need a formal dining room.
Speaker 1: So instead we had a library.
Speaker 1: So we had a room in the house.
Speaker 1: That was the library.
Speaker 1: I need a library and the great part about it was that I could sit in the fit in the living room If I was gonna like watch TV or we were all gonna watch a movie together.
Speaker 1: that kind of context.
Speaker 1: but I'd go to the library if I wanted to either talk to people with no distractions or Like read a book.
Speaker 1: anyway, we got away from desks But so at the L desk I could face one way and have context one like working on shit But then I can just turn to the right and have a different context Despite only having one desk.
Speaker 0: my desk at work is l-shaped.
Speaker 0: And I've got you know, I've got the keyboard sort of in the cornering area and to the right of that I have like, you know some stuffs.
Speaker 0: and then to the left I have like a little decorative area.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right, you know, but if I need to switch tasks, I just move.
Speaker 0: I use actually a pat a pax branded CCG card gaming mat as like my mouse pad is like takes up a whole area.
Speaker 0: Just to the left of that.
Speaker 0: I can do some writing and you know, whatever.
Speaker 1: So I do the thing where cuz my desk at my current job has a. it's kind of it's like pretty big actually But it's like a straight on but it's wide enough to where.
Speaker 1: it's big enough for two people to sit at it.
Speaker 1: But it's just me.
Speaker 1: So what I do is I have an area to the right which like keyboard mouse and like no Computering and if I scoot to the left, I got an open area where I have like my drawing tablet and paper.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I have an area to the left.
Speaker 0: It's just I put chat keys there.
Speaker 1: Yep I uh, I don't have that here.
Speaker 1: actually the current setup I have for the geek night studio like the desk I'm sitting at right now Not the greatest setup because I have too much shit that I use on a regular basis and there's not enough space to put it All that is also well organized.
Speaker 0: Now let's talk about something else.
Speaker 0: the desk has going on below which is some drawer action.
Speaker 1: I want more drawers on my desk, right?
Speaker 0: So that's the thing is like on the one hand, right?
Speaker 0: It's like I kind of like not having anything under there because moving around becomes real easy.
Speaker 0: But the fact is that when you get the big piece of wood, like I enjoy just a big flat area There's a more and more area on top for shit to accumulate.
Speaker 0: the more area There is on the bottom and that area while you want to have it open so your legs can be there It's also pretty much a wasted area.
Speaker 0: So you may as well put some kind of storage down there.
Speaker 0: You got to put something, you know, you're.
Speaker 0: otherwise you're wasting space which in a tiny apartment is a problem.
Speaker 1: Well, I get a big house like who cares that room was so big?
Speaker 1: I could put like six more desks that size, right?
Speaker 0: So if you don't have a space elsewhere and plus it's easy to get stuff if it's there if you put your stuff far away.
Speaker 0: Now you got to go really far away to get your stuff.
Speaker 0: So you want to put handy things you're gonna need while you're at your desk in drawers underneath the desk.
Speaker 0: nice filing cabinet action.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know all that kind of stuff.
Speaker 0: So the drawers I have are actually it's.
Speaker 0: it's actually a go.
Speaker 0: It's like a set for my key.
Speaker 0: It goes with the desk.
Speaker 0: But it's like a free rolling file cabinet that has two drawers and then one file drawer and I can take it out and roll It around if I want.
Speaker 0: but it just fits perfectly in that in the desk part.
Speaker 0: But I can move it if I have to to the left to the right wherever.
Speaker 0: So it's pretty good.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but if I got an even bigger desk, I can get another one of those, right?
Speaker 0: But if I got a second one now, I wouldn't have enough legroom under there.
Speaker 1: So yeah, like right now I have enough legroom to stretch out, but it's literally just as wide as my legs.
Speaker 1: Yep, cuz my computer's down there for reasons of venting heat and there's nowhere better to put it.
Speaker 1: Yep so I Wish I Cuz then I could have a tiny computer that I would just like tape to the bottom of my desk And like just it would just be hanging from the desk and I'd never have to touch it or interact with it.
Speaker 1: Is that the USB hub like sitting on top?
Speaker 1: Yep, but the reality is that's not true.
Speaker 1: I have a giant computer So I need that space down there for the computer to sit.
Speaker 0: Cuz you can't actually put my computer next to the desk.
Speaker 1: I don't have room for that here.
Speaker 1: Actually.
Speaker 0: I barely just enough room for that.
Speaker 1: yep, so I really Really really always want my desks to have the keyboard tray that is under the desk and comes out over my legs.
Speaker 0: No, I am against this.
Speaker 0: I want the keyboard to be on the desk and that's why I need the big open space because the keyboards and the mouse are Taking up some of that space.
Speaker 1: Look I can roll it out and deploy like my stuff on this nice area.
Speaker 1: That's at the exact right height.
Speaker 0: No Exact right height.
Speaker 0: it needs to be higher.
Speaker 1: Why would I make higher?
Speaker 1: It's the exact level of my own rest.
Speaker 1: Too low, how is this too low too low?
Speaker 1: gonna be typing like this like up?
Speaker 1: Why would you?
Speaker 1: why would you do that to yourself and type all the way up here?
Speaker 0: That's that's not.
Speaker 0: first of all, you're talking about a two inch difference, right?
Speaker 1: That's a big deal.
Speaker 0: And second of all your arms are short.
Speaker 1: My arms are longer than your arms.
Speaker 0: Also when I sit in my chair whenever I get in a chair I always adjust it to a be reclining as much as possible.
Speaker 1: cuz like Why don't you get a lay down desk?
Speaker 0: That would be great.
Speaker 0: Also I make the elevation of the chair as high as possible.
Speaker 0: So even though you're saying oh, that's the right height for you as to love my knees be bumping into that shit.
Speaker 1: Uh, my knees do not bump into this.
Speaker 0: is your air on chair as up high as it goes?
Speaker 1: Of course not.
Speaker 1: my air on sure can go way higher than I possibly would ever need it to.
Speaker 0: that's the thing.
Speaker 0: is I if I Had that chair output at maximum height?
Speaker 0: Why there is a?
Speaker 0: that is my most comfortable position is what I would if I could.
Speaker 1: this is why you have a hump.
Speaker 0: I would have my chair be up like so I could kiss giraffes on the lips.
Speaker 1: This is why you're gonna be a hunchback when you're old because you sit weird and it seems like it's not just your backslouch But it's every aspect of your being.
Speaker 0: Gotta be up high.
Speaker 1: The plebs got to be a pilot.
Speaker 1: So when you're sitting in your chair like working on stuff are your feet?
Speaker 1: Dangling touching the ground or flat on the ground?
Speaker 0: It depends on where I am because I have different chairs at work and home.
Speaker 0: But I would most prefer my feet to be dangling and floating in the air like dangling.
Speaker 1: So I ever dangling is bad news.
Speaker 1: dangling is not great for you Who cares?
Speaker 1: it also decreases comfort over time unless you're weird and I guess the hunch is giving you like.
Speaker 0: I love it when you Go to like a restaurant and they have those really tall stools only if they got the platforms You can hook your feet around the snow platform and you're gonna go.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you could spin around in a circle and hang the feet on the platform.
Speaker 0: No, no platform.
Speaker 1: I want my feet to be planted flat on the ground No on my thighs to be facing straight forward.
Speaker 1: So my knees are like this 90-degree angle.
Speaker 1: That is the perfect way to sit.
Speaker 0: The only benefit that I must admit of the keyboard drawer is That when your keyboard is hidden away in the keyboard drawer You can eat at your desk without food getting in it.
Speaker 0: I would not have a million everything bagel crumbs Yeah seeds in my keyboard, but that is a small price to pay for having my keyboard out on top You know in the right.
Speaker 1: so for the longest time I've always been a fan of if I have to get a desk that isn't a gigantic L then I like the Compact computer desk that have a bunch of vertical space in them to use that space up.
Speaker 0: See, I'm I don't.
Speaker 0: well I'm not super against having the vertical stuff because I do like more storage space.
Speaker 0: right and just an empty wall is not Restored.
Speaker 1: I use it for active things.
Speaker 1: Like the the compressor is literally like mounted on my desk up there.
Speaker 0: It's storage But it's.
Speaker 1: it's more like a control interface.
Speaker 0: it's used to say it's it's a thing it's being stored there.
Speaker 0: I you give your didn't?
Speaker 0: you couldn't store that on an empty wall.
Speaker 1: Well, then by that logic a desk is just storage - it is what we're talking about is separately.
Speaker 1: It is because it's also a workspace It's.
Speaker 0: it's just a shelf that you interact with the things on more.
Speaker 1: so access its access more than storage.
Speaker 0: It's a more easily accessed shelf.
Speaker 0: It's a shelf you can access while sitting.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I would say that but I wouldn't go so far as to call it storage.
Speaker 0: It's storage.
Speaker 1: Is it stowage?
Speaker 0: No, yeah, it's just story.
Speaker 1: but the problem.
Speaker 1: so this was great Through most of my life and computing but now we're in an era Where I can get really fucking gigantic monitors that don't fit in the spaces that exist on those deaths.
Speaker 1: So right now the vertical part on this desk was great until I got a really big monitor And now the monitor has to be in front of that.
Speaker 0: It is really strange.
Speaker 0: how like I had 17 inch monitors, right?
Speaker 0: And then as time went on people are getting 19 inches and I looked at that.
Speaker 0: I'm like, it's too big I don't need that big right?
Speaker 0: I don't want more.
Speaker 0: I want more resolution smaller pixels better screen But I don't anything bigger than 17 now.
Speaker 0: My monitors are 24 inches.
Speaker 1: They're 16 by 10 and I'm looking at even bigger one.
Speaker 0: I see I see 27 inch monitors and I'm like those aren't too big and I see people buying 34 inch monitors I had at one time.
Speaker 0: I currently have a 40 inch television as My television and I don't need a big.
Speaker 1: I have a I have a 52 and I would never go bigger than that.
Speaker 0: No, 50 just too big.
Speaker 1: but well for your apartment It would be.
Speaker 0: I only have a 40 inch TV because the 37 inch that I replaced They couldn't get another 37. but 34 to 37 adds a really small difference.
Speaker 0: Yeah But it's like yet.
Speaker 0: They don't there's not a lot of furniture out there.
Speaker 0: They can like accommodate these bigger monitors, especially in the small apartment, right?
Speaker 0: I have two 24 inch monitors on my desk now on arms That are mounted to the back of the desk.
Speaker 0: But like if I had to go to bigger monitors, like I couldn't I need to basically stick with 24 inch monitors.
Speaker 1: Yep So the only way to fit two monitors on this desk is right now.
Speaker 1: my secondary monitor is a shockingly ancient 4x3.
Speaker 0: That's at the 17 that I had in like 2002.
Speaker 1: But also that number is different because that number if you measure something diagonally a rectangle is a very different profile Depending on its aspect ratio.
Speaker 0: Even if you want to measure it the area is way small.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but if I get a bigger monitor than what I have now I cannot have a second monitor unless that second monitor is very much to that monitor.
Speaker 0: 1280 by 1024.
Speaker 1: No, this one's higher than that.
Speaker 0: No the 17 inch one.
Speaker 1: Oh that one is 1280, right?
Speaker 0: I think so.
Speaker 0: And this other one is 1600 by or 19.
Speaker 0: This one's 1920 by 1200 1200.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Oh my god.
Speaker 1: I found this picture.
Speaker 1: I was looking at pictures of my old desk.
Speaker 1: So I've got the 19 inch CRT.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm, and there's magic in this picture.
Speaker 1: You see the old mixer.
Speaker 1: You see my old flip phone before smartphones a Neal Stevenson book the shittiest raddest ass They the keyboard shelf with my old Logitech keyboard down there.
Speaker 1: And you can see in this little screenshot that I'm running.
Speaker 1: Katie it looks like Good old times.
Speaker 1: but yeah, the problem with the vertical space now too is that The vertical stuff was really useful in the previous places I had lived up until now in my entire life because the ceilings weren't that high.
Speaker 0: They made the most use of that space and putting shelves on the wall just kind of is hard and sucks.
Speaker 1: But now that I live in a Finding and like modern luxury apartments have really high ceilings compared to the average ceilings in most of America Like that's been the trend if you get a fancy house now, you'll get like 13 14 foot ceilings.
Speaker 1: The highest vertical desk there's still like five feet above the desk that I'd still have to put shelves in.
Speaker 1: I can't have a desk that will use up all that space.
Speaker 1: So it almost be easier to just put shelves in all the way up in the first place then bother getting the vertical desk.
Speaker 1: But I already have the vertical desk and I don't want to just replace the desk.
Speaker 1: that's even more of a pain.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so I do want to talk about like a lot of deaths like the IKEA desk.
Speaker 0: I have it's fun, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah But it's like.
Speaker 0: You know when I was a kid the desk I had that came with like the children's furniture that then lasted me all the way to high school Was actually made of like for serious wood.
Speaker 0: like.
Speaker 0: it had three drawers and not a lot of space.
Speaker 0: But I was able to get my you know 15 inch CRT on there with my computer on the floor, you know with my Pentium 3 for a couple years.
Speaker 0: It wasn't.
Speaker 0: it worked, you know, it managed.
Speaker 0: but like it was serious furniture like wow This is solid super wood.
Speaker 0: It lasted all that time.
Speaker 0: You could easily move it to another house or sell it to someone.
Speaker 0: no problem, right?
Speaker 0: The IKEA desk I bought in college like disintegrated the first time I tried to move it.
Speaker 0: That's the rule and that's why I switched to cinder blocks with a plank because that didn't fall apart.
Speaker 0: It did but you could put it right back together again.
Speaker 0: And the IKEA desk I have now while just fine actually had a bunch of peeling going on.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah Look look at all this like cosmetic damage that's accumulating right and if I have to move basically just got throw it out and recycle.
Speaker 0: It's completely on.
Speaker 0: it's because it's so shitty and chintzy.
Speaker 0: now I do see people who still have fancy desk these days with serious wood usually like executive desks and I do like those In one hand, but they tend to waste a lot of space, right?
Speaker 0: Because they're so big and ah, and so solid which is good But they're pretty much worse than every other way.
Speaker 0: besides bigness and solidness often They have weird shapes and they're ornate and they're not uncomfortable to sit under and they're not made designed with computers in mind.
Speaker 1: So When we first moved to this apartment, we got bookshelves.
Speaker 1: We got these like really nice leaning bookshelves for the bedroom.
Speaker 1: I really like that aesthetic and they hold off crazy ton of books, too Like this is really nice and they go right up flush against the wall.
Speaker 1: There's a lot of reason I like these shelves.
Speaker 1: But there was an option because they're modular you can get them as many segments of these leaning shelves as you want.
Speaker 1: You could replace one of those segments with a really minimalist desk.
Speaker 1: Uh-huh, and then the shelves go up.
Speaker 1: and If I didn't have all this audio mixing equipment nonsense because I like.
Speaker 1: I do stuff that normal people don't do with their computers.
Speaker 1: I Because what I'd have is like a Microsoft Surface Book or something or a laptop of some kind to be my primary computer and I would just set it there on this really minimalist desk and it would be great.
Speaker 1: Like that would be almost the ideal solution.
Speaker 0: Well, I think you know if you had like two living places, right?
Speaker 1: So like if I that's the desk I'd have.
Speaker 1: we bought a house upstate to store stuff in.
Speaker 0: right if I'm a big house Somewhere we're actually like, you know, like workshops and things or I have they might.
Speaker 0: my New York City apartment Just becomes this minimalist You know place just to live while in the city and then it can have really tiny stuff like that because who's no one's gonna Have a desktop computer in such a minimalist place.
Speaker 1: or if I had a bigger house What I do is like there'd be shelves like that in most of the rooms because that's what you do.
Speaker 1: I probably just have a little minimal desk along the wall in almost every room because if you're just in a room and you want To like do some work.
Speaker 1: It's a nice thing.
Speaker 1: I like having workspaces and other places again just to give myself a better way to change contexts.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm Alright, but yeah, it's.
Speaker 0: it's sad that desk these days are hard to come by made of high-quality materials that you you know are actually a serious piece of furniture, you know as opposed to You know some chintzy basic plank.
Speaker 0: I mean, you know who knows what kind of particle crap.
Speaker 1: So actually this one is real sturdy.
Speaker 0: Otherwise, I mean mine is mine is sturdy because it's only three pieces of whatever it is.
Speaker 1: But it this desk I'm pretty sure I don't move without it breaking.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I could probably take apart the three pieces and put it back together.
Speaker 0: I think it does actually have a fourth piece or just like some sort of backing plate.
Speaker 0: That's not necessary Yeah, and maybe provide some structural integrity, but not really.
Speaker 0: it's real thin But it's like you wouldn't you would.
Speaker 0: just you're better off just getting rid of it because it's so cheap.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think the biggest constraint I have on desks is that For a variety of reasons.
Speaker 1: I have a large number of control surfaces to which I need access and peripherals like drawing tablet The knob two keyboards one for gaming and one for typing the giant ass mixer the compressor the streaming crap And then now like all these USB chargers everywhere.
Speaker 1: So I have all these like extra Constraints that mean it's almost harder for me to find a desk than just a normal person using normal computers for normal things.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: But I wonder what are the people?
Speaker 1: Who don't have computers?
Speaker 1: do they just not have desks like the people who just have an iPad or their phone?
Speaker 0: I see, you know when I go to people's houses like
Speaker 1: I don't see desks
Speaker 0: at least from what I remember of going to people's houses like people have their computer does like in the 90s when I you know, it goes either in
Speaker 1: the kid like in the
Speaker 0: Other people's houses and everyone had a different weird situation for their computer desk Like even ours was like, you know, I had mine in my room But like the family computer was like in the kitchen on this weird like non desk table
Speaker 1: It was like real calm.
Speaker 0: It's like people's houses weren't made to accommodate a computer.
Speaker 0: so everyone in the 90s like found a place that was so random and to like shove a desk that was covered in papers and CD-roms and a printer Right and except the computer on it and it like it made me in the basement.
Speaker 0: Some people it's like all over the place my aunt
Speaker 1: and uncle I remember I was always jealous because I had a bigger house than us when I was really young and they had a den And that room became the computer room and there were a bunch of computers in there.
Speaker 1: Also, they were nerds and they were.
Speaker 1: they were computers.
Speaker 1: I wanted to have their computers too Because we didn't have computer right away.
Speaker 1: And when we did it went into the dining area, which was connected to the kitchen.
Speaker 0: I do think though nowadays more modern people's if you don't need the big computer I think a lot of people don't need the desk because everyone's got tablet phone whatever.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and the desk is going away.
Speaker 1: They sit at the table or you know what.
Speaker 0: you don't need a desk because there's a thing.
Speaker 0: back in the day You would have a desk.
Speaker 0: it's like do paperworks and things But now you don't do those anymore because you do everything on a computer.
Speaker 0: Yeah now your computer isn't a computer anymore.
Speaker 0: It's just your phone or a tablet or something or a laptop.
Speaker 0: So you just do on the couch and use a coffee table or whatever.
Speaker 1: Yeah, or you get it to get a TV tray or one of the.
Speaker 1: I see a lot of people get those Trays that you sit over you like a breakfast in bed tray But it's just for a pillow with a piece of wood attached to it that thing That or more substantial ones that are actually a tray with legs.
Speaker 1: that's like a mini table, right?
Speaker 0: But like if you're not if you don't need a desktop computer, you don't need a desk in the year 2017.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah a top computer even though it's under my desk.
Speaker 1: Yeah, because the world changed.
Speaker 1: so it's a desk under computer Mm-hmm, and I'm one of those people who uses desk under computers.
Speaker 1: So I need a desk to put it under And that's that.
Speaker 1: I still can't believe you don't like the the tray that comes out for the keyboard.
Speaker 0: I don't like the key that comes out.
Speaker 0: I just also it's.
Speaker 0: it's just in practice.
Speaker 0: I mean a lot of them are obviously yours still functions But many people have a get a flimsy one that just fall
Speaker 1: in a flimsy keyboard tray is worse than no keyboard tray Mm-hmm kind of like if you go on an old airline and you open the tray and it kind of just sags.
Speaker 0: You can't have sag.
Speaker 1: if there's sag just tear the thing off.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: All right that killed an hour.
Speaker 1: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music Can't leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at front row crew comm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 1: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 0: But unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 0: It's actually recorded at night.
Speaker 1: And the patreon patreons where this episode of geek nights are and Remember I say these in one take every time no edits.
Speaker 1: No pauses and it is harder than it sounds.
Speaker 1: Alan Joyce Heidi McNichol Amanda Duchette a shimmering Ruby obelisk hanging in the sky.
Speaker 1: my state calm Jeremy minor genuine bonafide like five six car monorail Matthew Smith Nicholas Brando captain chinga waka see Rebecca Dunn for two one creations Even if we were to pull out today and if they would come take our base.
Speaker 1: Shervin von Horl rare Laval James David White Rochelle, Monta, Nona Superboy rim says something funny here sailor Vista Don Shleich jar tovish and Joe show Joe star Sean Yeager Sam Cordery Clinton Walton Ren from New Zealand Ryan Perrin drew open lander Brian Cedroni Finn Chris midkiff Chris Knox Daniel Redmond Sean Klein Chris Reimer and Thomas Hahn.
Speaker 1: I Slowly settling into my new job and back into actually getting stuff out.
Speaker 1: You might have noticed I uploaded a board game video.
Speaker 1: There's gonna be more of that to come but now that is neither here nor there because now I leave you.
Speaker 1: I'm see.
Speaker 1: no say God.
Speaker 1: Oh I thought Doreen just last night.
Speaker 1: What's wrong?
Speaker 0: You Say that the sun's lower kimita.
Speaker 0: to kokoro Shinken Yugi say that's a town.