Speaker 0: It's Wednesday April 5th 2017.
Speaker 0: I'm rim.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott and this is geek night tonight.
Speaker 0: penny arcades Lookouts comic.
Speaker 0: may we die in the forest and such.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: So I yeah a couple nights ago.
Speaker 0: We did the show and he might notice that I only uploaded that show yesterday.
Speaker 0: So actually the people who are watching the live stream were the only people who got to listen to that show right away.
Speaker 0: We did all the recording.
Speaker 0: Scott left and I was dicking around and I went back to actually upload the show and I was watching.
Speaker 0: It's always sunny in Philadelphia at the time And then I go to the geek night's website and it's down and then I look and my internet's not working.
Speaker 0: So I'm troubleshooting this but it didn't quite Sink in right away that my internet was actually down because websites weren't working.
Speaker 0: But I was watching a TV show that was still playing and it actually kept playing because of Netflix caching for like 15 minutes until it finally petered out.
Speaker 0: the internet had been down for at least 15 minutes at that point But I basically had to reboot the FiOS thing in my wall Okay to make it work again.
Speaker 0: But the cool thing is the way that works is you log into this Verizon website and you can kind of control that thing remotely.
Speaker 0: So I logged into the Verizon website.
Speaker 1: How did you log into the Verizon website if it wasn't working and you couldn't get any internet?
Speaker 0: So that I could have done it from my phone just by going downstairs to get LTE signal.
Speaker 0: good idea, but uh I was too lazy for that.
Speaker 0: So I waited till I got to work and I did it from computer the next day.
Speaker 1: Oh, okay, so you couldn't.
Speaker 1: No, wait, it doesn't have its own web service.
Speaker 1: You can't just visit like one nine two one six eight No, because it present basically the router.
Speaker 0: my computers all connect to a switch.
Speaker 0: the switch Connects to other switches and the router.
Speaker 0: the router connects to via a coax line the FiOS box.
Speaker 0: So it treats the the coax line Kind of like the upstream slash ISP layer and then so it connects to it and then the FiOS box Connects to Verizon.
Speaker 0: so the link between the FiOS box and Verizon work.
Speaker 0: But for whatever reason the FiOS box just wouldn't respond to my router anymore.
Speaker 0: So I had to reboot it.
Speaker 0: I think I could have just powered it off and powered it back on But I don't like messing around in the physicality of that box.
Speaker 0: So I did it through the interface.
Speaker 1: shockingly You know since I got whatever the last time they changed my cable box itself the physical cable box.
Speaker 1: Yeah, time Warner for me has been effectively perfect.
Speaker 0: The only problems with it is that oh This is my third FiOS outage in the entire time.
Speaker 0: We've lived here.
Speaker 1: Yeah, is that I'm still obviously paying too much for too little.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I got like a hundred down and like 50 up.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I have a hundred down and only ten up.
Speaker 0: remember how I used to sometimes pay for more ups.
Speaker 0: more than once I wasn't paying attention and I'm careful about this now.
Speaker 0: I uploaded the WAV file instead of the mp3 to our website Which causes a whole bunch of problems for a lot of reasons?
Speaker 0: But it uploads so fast that I wouldn't notice so.
Speaker 1: But I mean even that it's still even the hunt.
Speaker 1: even a hundred.
Speaker 1: a hundred is Slower than the RIT days.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Well, that's kind of cheating cuz one.
Speaker 0: the internet was way different back then.
Speaker 1: That's true, too.
Speaker 0: We were on.
Speaker 0: we had an OC 3 connected to the internet and we had an OC 3 a separate one connected to Another internet that most of you do not have access to.
Speaker 1: I don't have access to.
Speaker 0: I don't have it anymore.
Speaker 0: I wish I did.
Speaker 0: I don't think it works quite the same way, but Back then internet 2 was basically just software and media piracy Mm-hmm invisible to the RIAA.
Speaker 1: it might still be it might still be but those are what the status of internet 2 is Actually Is it using IP?
Speaker 1: I bet it's using IPv6 like for reals.
Speaker 0: internet 2 isn't exceptional yet still exists as far as I can tell.
Speaker 0: I had an account.
Speaker 0: we were at RIT on the six bone.
Speaker 0: That was the IPv6 like testing network.
Speaker 0: I had a whole.
Speaker 0: I got my personal allocation of I of IP addresses on it For a project that I was supposed to do for a class that I then bailed on before the date.
Speaker 0: You know the six weeks in because I didn't care and the class was too much work.
Speaker 0: So I just bailed on it.
Speaker 0: I don't know whatever happened.
Speaker 0: I assume that allocation went away.
Speaker 0: I assume the six bone is gone.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: But uh, yeah, it's when.
Speaker 0: yet six bone was the test bits gone.
Speaker 0: so my thing is gone.
Speaker 1: that's a shame.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So, uh, there's a bunch of news.
Speaker 0: actually Wednesday shows, you know Anime manga comics pretty easy to do these days.
Speaker 0: a lot of stuff is happening.
Speaker 0: So we used to make a much bigger deal about mocha fest.
Speaker 0: I mean we would go every year.
Speaker 0: We would like interview all the people with tables.
Speaker 1: Okay fast used to be a much bigger deal.
Speaker 0: Yep, it used to be a kind of different deal - it's morphed a lot in the years since the Society of illustrators Gracefully took it over which not to knock them.
Speaker 0: I'm thankful they haven't destroyed it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, because The museum that mocha fest supported went under right?
Speaker 1: So mocha fest was a indie comics mostly indie comics festival that Existed in order to be the fundraiser for the Museum of comic and cartoon art Which is a mocha is and that museum was very tiny and didn't have a lot of money But they were able to survive with the funds from this one festival per year.
Speaker 1: The festival started out in the puck building.
Speaker 1: It may have been somewhere else before that but we didn't go then.
Speaker 1: and then it moved to the armory Which is and it was basically this big-ass festival.
Speaker 1: You would go there for like a day and look at all the tables.
Speaker 1: They're only a handful of panels, but they get a lot of creators.
Speaker 1: They're big names.
Speaker 1: You know, it was a big deal is crowded.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we used to dedicate entire episodes of geek nights just to what we saw at mocha because there would be so much stuff there That you had to see enough stuff to fill a whole geek nights episode and maybe even more.
Speaker 1: But then the Society of the mocha couldn't stay afloat anymore and the Society of illustrators took it over.
Speaker 1: So like the museum is now inside the Society of illustrators They rescued their stuff and they still have the festival every year and I'm sure they still make some amount of money on it.
Speaker 1: But it is much much smaller.
Speaker 1: It only cost us five bucks to get in.
Speaker 1: So I guess they're keeping the price reasonable.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and it still has some big name type people there, but it's not the mega thing It used to be like.
Speaker 1: we took instead of taking like multiple hours.
Speaker 0: We saw every table in like an hour Yeah, but I like spent time at every table.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like looking at like in two hours, you'd be like, all right I seen everything there is to see here.
Speaker 0: I also bought less and part of that is that there's a lot more Zines that even if they have a good cover they are just a bunch of unrelated illustrations, which I guess Society illustrator.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there's a lot of stuff there.
Speaker 1: That is like way awesome to look at but I don't know a lot of stuff.
Speaker 1: That's way awesome to buy and take home and like a mini stapled together comic.
Speaker 0: That's like a 10 page tiny comic.
Speaker 0: I'm all about Mm-hmm, but I have a lot of them in a box a mini stapled together series of ten illustrations by ten artists nine of which I haven't Heard of even if they're fantastic illustrations.
Speaker 1: I buy them and then what?
Speaker 0: Yeah, exactly.
Speaker 1: So I only the only things I usually when I see something like that I'll take someone's card and go to their website.
Speaker 1: Also a lot or if I was in the market to hire an illustrator I got a whole bunch of cards.
Speaker 0: I can go look at a lot of New York comic artists that I know Who are big were not there.
Speaker 0: Yep, and it was very small was there.
Speaker 1: Yeah, he's always there.
Speaker 0: I talked to him for a little bit.
Speaker 0: He was losing his voice.
Speaker 0: I was like, dude, let's talk when you're not like dying here.
Speaker 0: I'm not gonna ruin what little of your voice is left But yeah, like a lot of the big names.
Speaker 0: I know who live in New York We're not there.
Speaker 1: It used to be a thing that was big enough that was worth traveling to New York to go.
Speaker 0: do not come to New York To go to mocha fest.
Speaker 0: go to mocha fest if you already are in New York, right?
Speaker 1: However, they we now have both SPX and t-caf.
Speaker 1: So if you want the I've been to SPX.
Speaker 0: It's a lot more like what mocha fest used to be and Emily has been to t-caf, right?
Speaker 1: so if you want to go to a Indie comics festival and not you know a wizard world or a New York comic-con or what?
Speaker 1: That is the places you should go to in the Northeast US Canada technically Toronto area.
Speaker 0: Yep The thing is even they're like traveling to those things like.
Speaker 0: the problem is if you traveled to mocha fest back in the day At least you're in New York.
Speaker 0: There's more to do than just it.
Speaker 1: But some things to do in Toronto.
Speaker 1: the snakes and latte.
Speaker 0: is there stuff to do?
Speaker 1: SPX is not the as nothing to do is literally nothing there.
Speaker 0: Like if you don't bring a car there's nowhere to even walk to eat food.
Speaker 0: Nope, like you're just in this hotel and Imagine going to an anime con.
Speaker 0: That's just an artist alley and the con stops at like six and unless you know the artists and go to their private hotel room Parties you're just alone in a hotel for the rest of your trip.
Speaker 1: Like that's the kind of thing that you would go to if you could drive there do it and drive home Yeah or you know.
Speaker 0: if you know people and you go to one of the hotel parties and like it's like it's a con if you're in That culture and know those poor if you are an artist Yeah, or if you like I did.
Speaker 0: the one time I went to SPX I got the presidential suite and threw a giant ass party and invited everybody to it by accident And that was when Caldwell came with us and slept in that giant room with all the statuary Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: That was a weird convention.
Speaker 0: But yeah the only significant thing I bought because remember I did we did that podcast where me and Andrew and Scott talked about the Weimar Republic and like the rise of Nazi Germany and All that.
Speaker 0: there was a compilation of all these cute newspaper comics from the Weimar Republic and this dude like in 1934. these comics are just like a dad who's kind of mischievous and his son who's kind of mischievous and they're like short wordless newspaper comics and They give me a little bit of a Calvin and Hobbes vibe and they're really really great.
Speaker 0: and it's extra tragic Knowing the story around the people who made it.
Speaker 0: Well the person who made it, you know rise of Nazis, etc.
Speaker 0: But yeah, it was a really interesting book that I would not have run into had I not been at mocha fest.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm Yeah, there's a lot of stuff I see at mocha fest.
Speaker 1: that's like stuff I'm gonna buy too cuz like there's all.
Speaker 1: there's a few big publishers there right like Fanta graphics is.
Speaker 1: they are running, you know.
Speaker 1: But it's like the books they got.
Speaker 1: there are books.
Speaker 1: I could buy on Amazon cuz they're real publishers.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and they're like that you already bought on Amazon and I'm gonna borrow from you.
Speaker 1: and really it's like so this.
Speaker 1: so I'm not Gonna buy those at mocha fest.
Speaker 1: So the only books I'm gonna buy there are books like that.
Speaker 1: I know I could not ever find anywhere else ever.
Speaker 0: Also in the old mocha fest there was more stuff like.
Speaker 0: there were big panels and there were.
Speaker 1: there are panels.
Speaker 1: The panels are in another building.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there's only like there are.
Speaker 1: they have the same number of panels They used to which is like six per day in two rooms.
Speaker 1: Yeah which isn't many but those panels actually have huge names on them because like it used to be they got a ton of huge names and Some of them would be on the panels and some of them just at their tables all the time.
Speaker 1: But now it's like they bring in some huge names and those are the people on the panels and not really a lot of other Names come.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: So in other news that goes to the shell movie.
Speaker 0: That was terrible.
Speaker 1: I haven't seen it.
Speaker 1: Yep, but I don't plan to see it.
Speaker 0: I There is a scenario had I not known things that I knew about it where I might have considered going to see it.
Speaker 0: But knowing the things that I know I'm definitely not gonna go see it and it was a huge box-office disaster so far.
Speaker 0: Now make money domestically.
Speaker 0: it is not looking like it's gonna make its money internationally, right?
Speaker 1: So, you know, I've heard a lot of things about it But since I haven't seen it, I can't confirm or deny them.
Speaker 1: but the one thing I did see that I do want to comment on is I think like someone from the studio that Produced it was like, uh, you know, he was basically complaining like yeah because these fanboys made a thing.
Speaker 1: It didn't you know, he's busy blaming the fanboys in whole or in part for the failure of the movie.
Speaker 1: Yep, and it's like maybe if you had, you know, and the sort of discussion that happens from that is like, you know.
Speaker 1: It's like hey, you know, it's not.
Speaker 1: maybe your movie just sucked.
Speaker 1: Maybe just no one cared about it, right?
Speaker 1: That's sort of thing.
Speaker 1: but the thing I'm he's basically the guy was presenting this sort of scenario where it's like They had to change it to make in a way that made fun boys upset To appeal to the mainstream to make enough money to pay for it.
Speaker 1: But the argument that I'm presenting that no one else seems to present is that like you are vastly Underestimating the number of people that are fanboys By pissing them off is why you made no money.
Speaker 1: if you would just appeal to them.
Speaker 1: There actually are the mainstream and so also there's a so total side There is that you have no idea how many fanboys there are.
Speaker 0: What does he mean by fanboys?
Speaker 0: because there there's the fanboy of.
Speaker 0: it must be exactly like a shiro's comic in every detail.
Speaker 1: You made it crazy shiro style.
Speaker 1: it would have done crazy.
Speaker 0: Well, there's the people who do who think they're fanboys But don't know who shiro is and want it to be exactly like.
Speaker 0: oh, she's stuff for Kamehameha stuff.
Speaker 1: I would have been great would have made money, too.
Speaker 0: But there's the other set of people who independent of if they are fanboys or would have cared about Adaptation because standalone complex is a hugely Deviant adaptation of the comics.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm The movies also are pretty deviant from a lot of what the comics would do.
Speaker 0: They're already all these adaptations the superfans of ghosts in the shell pretty okay.
Speaker 0: with adaptation.
Speaker 0: the people who were mad and vocal were mostly the people who are mad about all the whitewashing nonsense and The fact that the whitewashing nonsense was once we learned what the plot was Way worse than like anyone could have expected.
Speaker 0: Like the plot was she got whitewashed.
Speaker 1: the point.
Speaker 1: someone pointed out something on Twitter today.
Speaker 1: I forget the exact details, but they were like look this kimono friends thing.
Speaker 1: Kimono something like that Gets an average of like 75,000 retweets right.
Speaker 1: yep the president of the United States Matt is like ceilinging at around 25k.
Speaker 1: read Okay, so if you had just made something with nerd appeal You can.
Speaker 1: it doesn't have to be exactly like the original any of the existing ghost in the shell universes because they don't match each Other.
Speaker 1: it just has to be a non whitewashed real ghost in the shell things.
Speaker 0: the thing if they're gonna blame the fanboys I saw.
Speaker 1: oh there are tons of it.
Speaker 1: There are more fanboys are the mainstream.
Speaker 1: He's the.
Speaker 1: don't believe in this sort of false dichotomy between like oh you have to sell to the mainstream Versus nerds like no nerds of the majority.
Speaker 1: That's why you're investing in ghosts in the shell because there's a lot of nerds out there.
Speaker 0: Also We're not complaining about deviations from the canon of ghost in the shell.
Speaker 0: I saw almost no one credible complaining about that.
Speaker 0: the people were complaining about all the racist nonsense.
Speaker 0: Yep That was the pre-release Controversy the fact that the movie appears to be kind of bland and the plot was kind of dumb.
Speaker 0: That didn't come out until the movie came out.
Speaker 0: Like I did not see anyone talk about that until after the movie was out.
Speaker 0: the damage was done by the racist stuff way in advance.
Speaker 0: And you know that controversy I mean that started what when they cast it?
Speaker 0: that was a long time ago.
Speaker 1: point is Maybe all you keep trying to do the same thing and he's failing.
Speaker 0: and you remember that Dragon Ball movie They may be.
Speaker 1: we're right.
Speaker 1: You know nerds aren't nerds who complain about things are usually often wrong like Counter-Strike players complaining about.
Speaker 0: you know the AWP But I know a lot of non-nerds Shit out of Akira to this day.
Speaker 1: That doesn't mean that they always wrong.
Speaker 1: This was a time when the nerds are right and you should have done what the nerds said and you make a lot of money.
Speaker 0: If you did, yep The problem is I worry that Hollywood is gonna learn the wrong lesson and they're gonna believe that it was negative pre-hype Coupled with some like dumb crap about maybe can't have a female protagonist Or maybe they'll learn.
Speaker 1: maybe the lesson they'll learn is huh turning an anime into a live-action movie doesn't sell which is a fine Lesson for them to learn.
Speaker 1: stop doing it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, stop doing it and maybe in the future someone will do it, right But I don't think it's ever happened.
Speaker 1: Has there ever been a good one?
Speaker 0: has there ever been a Western live-action adaptation of an anime?
Speaker 1: not direct but there have been many sort of you know indirect for example, yeah, right, uh you know you have Like the matrix right?
Speaker 0: It's not directly Adapting anything borrowed from things but I'm talking adaptation kind of like how people say video game movies are bad.
Speaker 1: I'm like magnificent.
Speaker 1: magnificent.
Speaker 1: seven is Not as good as seven samurai, but it is an adaptation of seven samurai and it's good and it's not bad.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's a good movie, but I don't think that has ever happened with anime.
Speaker 0: I Mean well, I'm also as though she ever made a lot a good live-action movie.
Speaker 1: But I mean seven samurai is a Japanese movie.
Speaker 1: that's better than any anime movie Also all Japanese but Best Japanese movie there is.
Speaker 0: I can't.
Speaker 0: you can successfully adapt that any live-action anime anything in the West ever.
Speaker 0: That's been good or even watchable.
Speaker 0: Mmm.
Speaker 0: I am really hard-pressed.
Speaker 0: No, no listeners got nothing.
Speaker 1: people don't hate That.
Speaker 1: the thing with the robots the thing with the robots What's it called Pacific Rim?
Speaker 0: Yes, that is So like it borrowed from Evangelion, but it is so far removed from Evangelion.
Speaker 1: I'm not saying like.
Speaker 1: I've seen part of it most half ish of it and it is not like.
Speaker 1: I'm not gonna say it's good But it's not bad.
Speaker 1: It's it's gotta be better than what I'm hearing about this ghost in the show.
Speaker 1: I don't get.
Speaker 0: that doesn't count though because it's not in any way related.
Speaker 1: But the point is you can go down that road at least some of the way and not completely fail.
Speaker 1: So there are plenty of other cyberpunk robot people Movies that have come out from Hollywood that are quite excellent.
Speaker 0: Well, the thing is I also read a review that said that even if you forget And Terminator.
Speaker 0: Yeah forget any other problem with this movie.
Speaker 0: they said the plot was like really simplistic and boring and Doesn't really go anywhere and barely seems to have anything to do with ghost in the show.
Speaker 0: Mmm also, apparently Characters will speak Japanese, but then all the other characters will speak to them in English.
Speaker 1: I mean that makes sense in cyber land where everyone has translators in their brain.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but if the movie is set in Japan But you're not used like either have the whole thing be in Japanese or have the whole thing just be in English and do That is weird.
Speaker 1: If someone is pretend it's all in Japanese like but it's really who's talking in Japanese and who's talking in English.
Speaker 0: Yeah, apparently there's things where character Aramaki will say stuff in Japanese and everyone responds to him in English.
Speaker 1: My responding to him in English, uh other Japanese like Toga said who's a Japanese person.
Speaker 0: They had some tweet where he was like I think was my tool.
Speaker 0: someone in my Twitter feed was like I gotta replace our maki's Speech and treat him like Chewbacca because that's basically what they do with Japanese in this movie.
Speaker 1: I mean it makes sense if say like, you know an American agent came to visit or something.
Speaker 1: They spoke English because they knew there was mega translators because everyone is so high-tech.
Speaker 1: but if you're it would be weird if that person came.
Speaker 0: and When you're making a movie, you generally have everyone speaking English.
Speaker 1: also in a site, you know If you're releasing it in America, the other thing is inside something.
Speaker 1: it goes in the shell period.
Speaker 1: in cyber world You don't really need language.
Speaker 1: Everyone can just transfer bits between their brains doesn't need to actually communicate with a written human language Spoken one.
Speaker 0: even in the Ghost in the Shell manga Most people communicate was effectively spoken thought language, right?
Speaker 1: That always bothered me because I'm like a in cyber land where everyone communicate with just brain-touching.
Speaker 0: That's a plot point of all of Ghost in the Shell.
Speaker 1: the idea that you can't just send the direct data Anyway, that's they talk to each other over the great distance with what's effectively telepathy.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but they still send symbols as opposed to raw data because those symbols are still interpreted by parts of their brain.
Speaker 0: It's not a complete.
Speaker 0: There are very few beings in the Ghost in the Shell universe who communicate Directly on that low level because it's arguable that they're not even human anymore.
Speaker 1: The point is if and we had that story with me on this I'd be communicating in at least see And at least see.
Speaker 0: yeah, I got different libraries now.
Speaker 0: I'm little Indian.
Speaker 0: What are you gonna do?
Speaker 1: Don't be little?
Speaker 1: Internet is big Indian.
Speaker 0: The network is little Indian anyway.
Speaker 0: So there was some news that there's going to be a.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: by the way This is a Monday topic.
Speaker 1: I don't know whose decision it was to make the internet big Indian.
Speaker 1: when x86 processors are little Indian X 86 came first.
Speaker 1: No way.
Speaker 1: No, it didn't.
Speaker 1: Internet came first.
Speaker 1: Internet's from 1969.
Speaker 1: O86 didn't even exist then right?
Speaker 1: Whoever decided to make x86 little ideas at a big Indian.
Speaker 1: Fuck you.
Speaker 0: Should that be our next Monday show?
Speaker 1: No, there's nothing else to say.
Speaker 0: Every computer should just say doubt that Most of the people who are listening to this have any idea what we're talking about.
Speaker 0: That's fine.
Speaker 0: In fact, because I am NOT a computer scientist.
Speaker 0: I have only a conceptual understanding of this Oh, I can tell you it's really so well.
Speaker 0: The problem is you say you can say that the fact that you don't know why network stuff is the way it is Means that complete.
Speaker 1: as far as I know it's a completely arbitrary decision.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so you send bytes sequentially over the internet.
Speaker 0: which bytes are more important, especially in a network where performance might matter?
Speaker 1: You're really gonna start routing when you've seen half the bits.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we'll talk about that anyway.
Speaker 0: So there was an announcement that I saw all over the place that there's gonna be a squirrel girl TV show.
Speaker 1: That's I mean, first of all, that's great.
Speaker 1: cuz squirrel girl is the best Yeah, but I'm not gonna watch it.
Speaker 1: cuz not watching any TV shows.
Speaker 1: But how is that gonna be?
Speaker 0: don't watch any TV shows?
Speaker 0: What about anime?
Speaker 0: you watch anime, right?
Speaker 1: I'm not watching a you know superhero garbage, but nothing.
Speaker 1: I Can't imagine that this would actually be good unless right is Ryan North writing it.
Speaker 0: So I was a little bit interested but apparently no the actual news was freeform.
Speaker 0: We'll get back to what the fuck that?
Speaker 1: I don't know what the hell that is ordered.
Speaker 0: not squirrel girl, but new warriors.
Speaker 0: They're making a new
Speaker 1: Right, so I saw this headline and I thought that what the headline was saying was that there's gonna be a new new warriors comic because I don't think there's been a new warriors comic since like maybe the 90s or I don't even remember when the last Time there was a new warriors comic and squirrel girl was gonna be on the team which makes perfect sense
Speaker 0: Yep, but no it's a new warriors show that may or may not actually have squirrel girl in it.
Speaker 1: Okay, and by the way, it's girl girl had never had anything as far as I know never had anything to do with the new Warriors, yeah, but the new warriors is just like what teenagers right?
Speaker 1: I think she was like into speedball and maybe speedball was a new warrior.
Speaker 0: I think speed I don't know all the new I so I've never read new warriors.
Speaker 1: new warriors is basically some buyers.
Speaker 0: Yes, people speedball is totally one of them.
Speaker 1: Yeah new warriors is a Marvel boy.
Speaker 0: Namorita the hell's namorita the Morita it's namorita.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 0: I don't know that is now.
Speaker 1: more is the.
Speaker 0: basically they're fighting the juggernaut.
Speaker 0: now more I don't know other than speedball.
Speaker 0: I have no idea who any of these people are.
Speaker 1: Okay, so night Thrasher I don't know who that is.
Speaker 0: I've seen fire star.
Speaker 1: Yeah fire start.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I've run into fire star before but anyway namorita, you know namor the prince of the sea.
Speaker 1: He's the Aquaman.
Speaker 1: He's the Aquaman of Marvel.
Speaker 1: Okay only he's way more badass and actually serious and not a joke Like.
Speaker 1: I'll come in.
Speaker 1: Okay now Morita is basically Teenage girl.
Speaker 1: now more store doing here.
Speaker 1: Thor That might be Thor.
Speaker 1: I think that's Thor.
Speaker 1: I don't know But Nova's cool.
Speaker 1: I like Nova.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: Nova's good when he's doing space anyway.
Speaker 0: So people kept saying freeform ordered it freeform ordered it and I literally didn't know what freeform.
Speaker 1: I never heard of freeform before today.
Speaker 0: So I looked it up.
Speaker 0: a Freeform is the name of the television network that has Continued to evolve since the last time I knew about it when it was the family channel.
Speaker 1: So why would there be a Marvel superhero TV show on the family channel?
Speaker 1: Wouldn't this be on like it says?
Speaker 1: Disney owns it?
Speaker 1: All right, so wouldn't it just be on ABC or would it be?
Speaker 0: Oh, this is so complicated.
Speaker 0: So the history of freeform goes back to 1977.
Speaker 0: All right, holy shit is this cable?
Speaker 1: there was cable in 77 so there was TV in 1977.
Speaker 0: all right, but what is freeform today was actually one of the first satellite distributed television networks.
Speaker 0: It was one of the first cable channels Mm-hmm, but it was originally Originally as far as most people would know The family channel.
Speaker 0: most people who watch TV and grew up in my era Was the family.
Speaker 1: you heard of the family channel and I've never watched anything.
Speaker 0: The family channel was a channel that if you were a kid and you're as old as we are We got it on cable, but we didn't watch it.
Speaker 0: Well, because it was as old as us in the early 80s the family channel came to existence.
Speaker 0: It was a standard cable package channel So anyone who had cable that was just one of the channels I get at other people's houses.
Speaker 1: some other kids watched it But we didn't watch it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know, she was Nickelodeon and MTV.
Speaker 1: We watched Viacom channels in our house.
Speaker 0: the boring kids who came from families that wouldn't let them watch good TV Like super Christian families tended to watch the family channel because it was inoffensive.
Speaker 0: pablum.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we watched Viacom channels in our house.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so I did not know this until I was looking into this but the family channel spun off from CBN.
Speaker 0: Alright had Robertson's Christian Broadcasting Network.
Speaker 1: I mean that makes sense.
Speaker 0: That was like Televangelical scams, but I don't remember there being any Overt, you know Christian stuff on the family chair was but they played in the hours that you probably weren't watching.
Speaker 1: Okay, I mean I was watching it either.
Speaker 0: They.
Speaker 0: basically it evolved into being the channel that like ultra Christian families would force their kids to watch because they locked out all the good channels.
Speaker 0: Mmm This is like old-school TV network stuff, which is difficult to put into useful context quickly.
Speaker 0: But basically this channel got bought and bought and moved and sold and moved and moved and moving forever And I think Disney and ABC both own a chunk of it.
Speaker 1: Disney owns ABC.
Speaker 0: So Disney, but I don't know if Disney owns it directly or if Disney owning ABC causes them to own it indirectly.
Speaker 0: I can't.
Speaker 0: it's all the same company.
Speaker 1: Disney Marvel Star Wars Muppets ABC.
Speaker 1: they're all the same company.
Speaker 1: ESPN all the same company.
Speaker 1: It's all just Disney.
Speaker 1: Disney is all that.
Speaker 0: so if best I can tell did Marvel was taking bids for who would get this show?
Speaker 0: and Free form like the thing that they were taking bids for?
Speaker 1: who would get the show.
Speaker 1: How does that work?
Speaker 0: Fuck if I know.
Speaker 1: why would you?
Speaker 1: why would you're auctioning off what you're making a TV show and auctioning it off Like I don't.
Speaker 1: how does work?
Speaker 0: I barely knew how does this TV business work?
Speaker 1: What's those God?
Speaker 0: I barely knew how this works.
Speaker 1: How do you make money with that?
Speaker 0: back in the well?
Speaker 0: Back in the old day because this network has made other shows before.
Speaker 0: you might have heard of baby daddy or no teachers.
Speaker 1: No, they have shows.
Speaker 0: All right, and I guess freeform.
Speaker 1: How do they make money by making shows if no one?
Speaker 0: Well, I'm not getting into that.
Speaker 0: There's way Longer topic that we get into but gay freeform as far as I can tell has never made anything That I would care about and thus I have very little confidence that this show is going to be good.
Speaker 1: Well, how would it be good?
Speaker 0: and that is my opinion on that.
Speaker 0: okay things of the day.
Speaker 0: so, uh, I am NOT a member of this community, but I am a member of a similarly important community because Internet culture as you know it today is driven way more than you realize by the combination of FARC 4chan in the early
Speaker 1: days
Speaker 0: and something fucking awful something awful If you have no idea what that is.
Speaker 0: it was basically just a form of people in the like in the early days of the modern internet like after the original Doc and it was a really typical forum like a V bullet in PHP VB style kind of thing.
Speaker 1: It wasn't a fancy forum at all.
Speaker 0: But it just for a lot of reasons that uh, you should read this because you might learn a thing or two.
Speaker 0: But if you were if you don't know anything about something awful This is a sort of interview oral history of what something awful was and why it was the way it was.
Speaker 1: the interviewing low-tax is the Basically every big name.
Speaker 1: Yeah, this is low-tax is the guy.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but there's other guys.
Speaker 1: Yeah, sure But something awful is way important to the internet and and unlike other things that are way important Well the way not terrible.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's not some horrible.
Speaker 0: It doesn't have any ickiness on it As well, it has the same level of ickiness that everything on the internet does right.
Speaker 1: but the people running it weren't pieces of shit.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they're not like scumbags.
Speaker 1: They need to be.
Speaker 1: you know Not saying that side has not had its share of problems, but by and large you have a big internet community of shitty people in it, but the the the Governance and such the people running the show are not bad now.
Speaker 0: I'm a member of the fart community, which was parallel to this and Similarly strong and probably similarly important.
Speaker 1: Yeah, Drew Curtis isn't bad guy.
Speaker 0: No, he's actually.
Speaker 0: he's been doing a newsletter kind of like your newsletter For geek nights.
Speaker 0: Hmm.
Speaker 0: It's real good.
Speaker 1: I haven't done my newsletter only because I usually do it at work and even busy at work.
Speaker 1: I've been doing other stuff instead.
Speaker 1: So I'm you know, I don't have like a whole day at work of doing nothing to write a newsletter.
Speaker 0: I've actually been really busy at work lately, too Which is what you might.
Speaker 1: I've been tweeting you last which a lot of you I keep like every day I look at my to-do list is like newsletter But then I get to work and it's like can I do nothing today except newsletter?
Speaker 1: No Yeah, I have to do a thing today.
Speaker 0: Also, honestly Breath of the Wild Killed all my discretionary hours.
Speaker 0: Well, I wasn't gonna write a newsletter when I'm at home Yeah, but I play Breath of the Wild in lieu of a lot of other things, but this is so fascinating.
Speaker 0: You have to read this.
Speaker 0: Okay, it's real long too.
Speaker 1: So my thing today is Maybe is fascinating but very short is a little tiny video of us of a nice Nick.
Speaker 1: Let's Nick.
Speaker 1: I like snakes like snakes So this snake is not too bright.
Speaker 1: We don't see what actually happened which would have made this video like an all-time great video But we get to see an aftermath in this video.
Speaker 1: It's even in the thumbnail I don't even see to watch the video, but I think I'm sad.
Speaker 1: I think it's in Brazil.
Speaker 1: this stupid snack Attacked a pork you pine and he got.
Speaker 1: what happens when you attack a porcupine?
Speaker 1: And it got me thinking I was talking to rim before the show.
Speaker 1: like you think of the biggest baddest animals that are still existing and not extinct on earth.
Speaker 1: you think of like gorilla and human and great white shark and Elephant right or lion right and you don't think about porcupine.
Speaker 1: It's not as something you think about too often like you know about porcupines.
Speaker 1: You've heard of them You've seen them, but it's not an animal you think about too often unless you're like a big porcupine fan Or that's your zoologist in the porcupine part of the zoo.
Speaker 0: I mean if you're if you're deep into evangelical, and you think a lot about hedgehog hedge is not a porcupine.
Speaker 1: No, I'd even related.
Speaker 1: I think they're just similar with their defensive functions.
Speaker 1: But the point is porcupine fucks up lion porcupine fucks up elephant porcupine fucks up shark porcupine fucks up gorilla.
Speaker 0: What is the difference between a hedgehog and a porcupine?
Speaker 0: right porcupine answer they're very different species WTF?
Speaker 1: Yeah, they have nothing to do with each other.
Speaker 1: porcupines fuck up humans, right?
Speaker 1: So all the biggest baddest animals that you normally think of.
Speaker 1: maybe an elephant could just stomp one But I bet its foot would get fucked up.
Speaker 1: Maybe a lion could just sort of like squat one real good to send it flying You know.
Speaker 1: But it's like that lines gonna get some thorns in the paw.
Speaker 0: look at this.
Speaker 0: pork is a fable about that.
Speaker 0: Three lines are looking at this porcupine.
Speaker 0: the porcupine is like I give zero fucks.
Speaker 0: I'm just hanging out.
Speaker 0: Yeah, four lines.
Speaker 1: Oh for lion and porcupine clearly beats neck right.
Speaker 1: the snake just got owned.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and it's a. snakes are pretty dangerous too, especially if they're poison.
Speaker 1: so well if they're venomous porcupine The most dangerous animal on earth is it like the king of all?
Speaker 1: Species that really exist?
Speaker 0: no because they have a super high defense stat But they do not have the highest like attack stat.
Speaker 1: What do you mean?
Speaker 1: it puts its spikes out and comes at you.
Speaker 0: you're gonna run the spikes mostly run in those spikes.
Speaker 1: How is that not offense?
Speaker 0: So if he's coming at me you have to stop and turn around like butt into me.
Speaker 0: I can run faster than a poor.
Speaker 1: He's got spikes in all directions.
Speaker 0: I can run away faster than a porcupine.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you can get away, but if he gets you yeah, he can do aerial deny.
Speaker 1: He can make you go anywhere.
Speaker 1: He wants you to go or he can make you not go anywhere He doesn't want you to.
Speaker 0: he can definitely do area denial But he could not like he could not displace me from my small shack home.
Speaker 1: It's some of them like shoot their quills like pee pee pee.
Speaker 0: I know that is not a thing Spiders, it's only a video.
Speaker 0: spiders can do that.
Speaker 1: It's only a video game like tarantulas.
Speaker 0: Fun fact if you have if you ever meet a tarantula Don't put your face right up in his biz because he doesn't like you.
Speaker 0: he can shoot his tiny spines into your eyeball and guess What.
Speaker 0: there's basically no way to fix that.
Speaker 1: You'll just be blind forever.
Speaker 0: Well, there's very.
Speaker 0: it's very difficult to remove these thousands of tiny spines from your eye So they'll have to just work their way out on their own.
Speaker 0: and if that doesn't sound fun, guess what?
Speaker 0: It's really not fun.
Speaker 1: Why are you putting your face close to a tarantula case?
Speaker 0: You don't know.
Speaker 0: like maybe you might not know.
Speaker 1: I mean, I guess you could do it if it's in an aquarium or something.
Speaker 0: tarantulas are pretty cute and cool I guess terrarium.
Speaker 1: It's not full of water.
Speaker 1: They would drown the spider in the meta moment.
Speaker 0: The book club book is Frank Gerberts Doon Doon with the spice and the Arrakis we're gonna be at.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna be a Zenkai con doing some panels at the end of this Month, I'm not.
Speaker 0: I'm also gonna be in London and Paris around the end of this month I'm not.
Speaker 0: I'll be in Hong Kong for a conference that I know none of you are going to I'm not.
Speaker 0: and Not too long after all that there's gonna be Connecticut packs packs and packs.
Speaker 0: we got all that Coming up packs Australia packs West packs unplugged.
Speaker 0: And guess what?
Speaker 0: He ignites is gonna be at all three of these motherfuckers.
Speaker 1: Hopefully they could decide to start rejecting us.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if my panel gets rejected the packs awesome, probably not gonna go you don't say but we've never been rejected.
Speaker 1: I can't.
Speaker 1: I'm very kind.
Speaker 1: I'm like 99% confident.
Speaker 1: We're in packs unplugged.
Speaker 1: You know prime they gave me giving us the one every time.
Speaker 0: sometimes do still I'm.
Speaker 0: it's not like the old days where we do like four at paxi.
Speaker 1: I'm still worried about.
Speaker 1: you know, maybe prime will say no cuz it's so big I'm always worried but I'm going to prime no matter what.
Speaker 0: even if packs told us never come back I would keep coming back to prime.
Speaker 1: Yeah, of course.
Speaker 1: Why wouldn't I?
Speaker 0: Yeah, cuz I got a dev - it's a whole week.
Speaker 1: Might have normal bum badges.
Speaker 0: I don't know what I would do.
Speaker 0: that would be the end of an era.
Speaker 0: but packs unplugged is a thing and I feel like You need to bring it up and call attention to it because a lot of people are asking me about it Like I know anything more than the internet does.
Speaker 0: well We do know you kind of know a little bit more than the internet.
Speaker 1: I think that packs does not expect packs unplugged to be super popular.
Speaker 1: They have announced that the tickets will go on sale on May 3rd, May 3rd Which means they're not expecting a scalping because they thought scalping was gonna happen.
Speaker 1: They wouldn't reveal such guys.
Speaker 0: The Philly Convention Center is big.
Speaker 0: It ain't that big Yeah, and also Philly is a like day trip train ride away from New York City from a lot of places.
Speaker 1: So a lot of people are in range of those bags.
Speaker 0: little dinky Anime cons and comic cons that are in the outskirts of Philly sell out get thousands of people.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like way more people than you think.
Speaker 1: this is tabletop only But it's still a packs.
Speaker 1: May 3rd the tickets go on sale.
Speaker 1: if you are within range of Philly and you want to go to packs unplugged You better buy them on May 3rd.
Speaker 1: Get your Twitter thing ready to let you know the moment they're gonna go on sale.
Speaker 1: And also it's gonna be midnight while hotels will be opened up.
Speaker 1: wider hotels are open up now.
Speaker 0: Well, they're not fully open as we got.
Speaker 1: we got a room already.
Speaker 0: I got another room just in case.
Speaker 0: that's good because you got a room because way back We were planning on me not going and I got a room with Tracy.
Speaker 0: But now it's very likely that I'll be going.
Speaker 0: so I got a room just in case.
Speaker 1: where'd you get your room?
Speaker 1: in a loft?
Speaker 0: I went the a loft.
Speaker 1: we got the.
Speaker 0: a loft Is connected to the Convention Center.
Speaker 0: as far as I can tell that's good But the the other hotel the Marriott is like one block away Mm-hmm, but supposedly more rooms will open up in these blocks once the badges go live.
Speaker 0: That makes sense, but you can totally book rooms right now If you think you're gonna go to this, I highly recommend you do so.
Speaker 0: one of them is already sold out.
Speaker 1: I also recommend going to this.
Speaker 0: Yeah, this is gonna be a good packs.
Speaker 0: It's gonna be.
Speaker 1: it's gonna be so much dice and RPG and wooden cube action like.
Speaker 1: yeah You're gonna not want to even see a wooden cube or a dice ever again For like a week after you go to this, but it is going to be.
Speaker 0: Don't even started on the number of cards.
Speaker 1: You're gonna see.
Speaker 1: you're gonna see so many cards.
Speaker 1: Like if you see another card, you guys like burn it, but seriously guys This is going to be a real magic show and just walk out.
Speaker 1: cuz too many cards.
Speaker 0: like.
Speaker 0: they're narrowing the focus But they've made it very clear.
Speaker 0: This will count as a packs.
Speaker 1: Like it is a packs the things you expect panels Omegathons keynotes, we don't get to have all we we don't know for sure.
Speaker 1: We expect it to have all of the usual packs things except for video games except for video games that are digital Implementations of board games.
Speaker 1: Nope.
Speaker 0: I could see I could see like Hearthstone being here.
Speaker 1: Maybe yeah, absolutely Cuz.
Speaker 1: that's the fact that's a tabletop game Virtual table table.
Speaker 1: up by the way Hearthstone major expansion comes out tomorrow.
Speaker 1: Un'goro dinosaur cards All right, so let's talk about some lookouts.
Speaker 1: so way back in the day, you know the penny arcade the hulkins and krahulik team You know, they've made a lot of other properties besides, you know, just penny arcade itself.
Speaker 0: A lot of them have been like concepts or like short ideas.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they got the Automata now is a real thing and the sand one with the desert whatnots, right?
Speaker 1: But lookouts was one.
Speaker 1: it's sort of in this sort of Ironwood universe that also includes the thorn watch and you know The daughters and whatever.
Speaker 1: but you know, the lookouts is basically like Boy Scouts Except fantasy world full of fantasy stuff.
Speaker 1: Plus it's super dangerous and for real and not a joke, but like real Boy Scouts May we die in the forest.
Speaker 0: and definitely from those early comics you got this vibe of Every time every time an adventure happens somebody doesn't come home, right?
Speaker 1: So these were comics that were originally posted on you know, the actual penny arcade website, you know Like they would do a whole a few weeks or a couple weeks in a row and they would tell a little tiny story Right.
Speaker 1: And yeah, you definitely got the idea That's like oh they're Boy Scouts and fantasy land and shit happens to them.
Speaker 1: Like they get turned to stone or eaten by a monster.
Speaker 0: Great concept and it was.
Speaker 0: it was a concept.
Speaker 0: It was like an X like a pilot almost.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, it was.
Speaker 1: and because you know, they did I think they did more than just that.
Speaker 1: I'm sure there's tons of material they've made that I've never even looked at.
Speaker 1: also especially like in their game everyone at PAX Always trying to play the throne watch game.
Speaker 1: I never even bother putting in any effort into that, right?
Speaker 0: Well, I mean, I don't.
Speaker 0: I have not played Fine.
Speaker 0: I've not played more than 5% of the library of indie RPGs.
Speaker 0: I've.
Speaker 1: The point is this this universe that they thorn watch universe They've created and this lookouts property in particular is very popular.
Speaker 1: people really weigh into it.
Speaker 1: I remember being way into it when it was a thing I was like.
Speaker 1: I was waiting every day for that new comic to be posted to see that right?
Speaker 1: It was good stuff Very good stuff.
Speaker 1: people are asking for more.
Speaker 1: So what they made at some point, I don't know exactly when is A an actual comic book you could buy in the store called lookouts.
Speaker 1: It came out in multiple issues and now you can just buy the whole thing in one hardcover And I'm sure they'll be a trade.
Speaker 1: if you wait and you don't want to pay I'm sure you can get it digitally also.
Speaker 1: so the deal here is that I'm not sure exactly how much involvement Kraulik and Hawkins Mike and Jerry Had with the creation of this comic because they have their credited.
Speaker 0: what with created by right?
Speaker 1: if you look at the credits It says it was created by them and under story It lists four people Ben McCool Corey Jones and them.
Speaker 1: But they are not listed as they're not the writer.
Speaker 1: the writer is Ben McCool.
Speaker 1: They are not the artists.
Speaker 1: You're right.
Speaker 1: The pencils are done by Rob Momertz and the inks are done by Mike Norton who I know is really good.
Speaker 1: the colors by two other people.
Speaker 1: letters Tom All right, they didn't do.
Speaker 1: but the art Mike did do one variant cover artwork this one right here.
Speaker 1: But the main cover artist is the same guy Rob Momertz, right?
Speaker 1: Someone else did variant cover.
Speaker 1: So They you know how.
Speaker 0: here's the here's the Rob cover, right?
Speaker 0: It's like well, you know what.
Speaker 0: if I had to guess if I just looked at those two I might have guessed that the opposite the people who drew which one I would have gotten it wrong, right?
Speaker 1: So their involvement with this how much is questionable?
Speaker 1: obviously more than nothing, but you know They were not the primary creative.
Speaker 0: I would assume they have significant Creative direction.
Speaker 1: I'm sure they reviewed it right and we're like, oh you should change this change that right?
Speaker 1: Who knows?
Speaker 1: We could ask them they test tell us probably yeah, this was published by of all people.
Speaker 1: you think Oh What comic company did?
Speaker 1: this was IDW?
Speaker 0: is our car right now like that?
Speaker 1: Cryptozoic the people who publish lots of crappy board games based on intellectual properties publish this comic book And they did a good job.
Speaker 1: Apparently I learned from the credits here.
Speaker 1: the president and chief creative officer of cryptozoic is Corey Jones.
Speaker 0: He wrote a pretty nice little forward in the book.
Speaker 1: He's one of those four people in the story credits.
Speaker 1: Yeah, he's also the editor of this book.
Speaker 1: So there you go.
Speaker 1: Corey Jones had a ton of creative input on this thing.
Speaker 0: I think the moral is that it's such a solid concept that Penny arcade put together the right team of people to make this happen because it's great Like.
Speaker 0: I really like this comic so look forward to more.
Speaker 1: how many issues did they make they made?
Speaker 0: Because we read a hardcover trade.
Speaker 1: you read the hardcover.
Speaker 1: so I'm not sure exactly how many issues there are total Let's see.
Speaker 1: One, two, three four.
Speaker 1: It might be six seven eight issues something along those lines But anyway, it's a comic book.
Speaker 1: It tells us a continuous self-contained story about a group of lookouts In the thorn watch.
Speaker 1: I would universe.
Speaker 1: it also contains little pages from like the lookouts Handbook and like how to earn different merit badges.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: It also contains lots of concept arts and bonus junk Around and you know extra illustrations all the covers all kinds of other good stuff.
Speaker 1: So it's like you buy this hardcover or the softcover that eventually is gonna come out and you will get the whole picture.
Speaker 1: So What is the first thing I say about this comic the artwork?
Speaker 1: Mike didn't draw this yet.
Speaker 1: You could show it to someone and maybe believe he drew it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like you can sort of tell it's not exactly on.
Speaker 1: it's like you look at it and it's like it's totally in his style.
Speaker 1: You know, like the way the skin is drawn on the people is the way he tends to color skin on Noses in particular, you know The line work is very similar to his.
Speaker 1: a lot of the.
Speaker 1: the way the mouths are drawn with like the one big tooth Block, you know that he does right?
Speaker 1: It's like it really is.
Speaker 1: They were definitely trying to keep it in his style, but they're not him.
Speaker 1: so you can see that it's slightly off But it's still great because people are still great artists and also like the.
Speaker 0: it's definitely set up the work.
Speaker 0: because if you get the world of lookouts was interesting because from the pilots like what I knew coming into this comic was What you could know if you just are a fan of penny arcade and listen to what they have to say and have read their Comics.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: So it's a very Loosely defined setting where there's obviously a lot of stuff out there and you're seeing these tiny views into it and this comic Definitely keeps that going.
Speaker 0: The only thing you know about this world is that this forest is real dangerous.
Speaker 0: There's weird shit out there that maybe some of its good some of its bad, but mostly it's just the cruelty of nature.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm, like it's just out there like this Sphinx is just it's a thing.
Speaker 0: It's there It's the force of nature and we deal with it.
Speaker 1: The main thing that tips you off that is not Mike.
Speaker 1: doing the art is like how much stuff there is in the background Detailing filling out the world which you kind of need in a fantasy world and you're telling a story like this.
Speaker 1: You need to really fill that environment in.
Speaker 1: you can't just leave sort of like a blank Background all the time to tell your joke in the front.
Speaker 1: So that's one key.
Speaker 1: that sort of tips you off.
Speaker 1: The other thing is that I actually say like the coloring is Actually, usually way sort of more detailed and maybe in some ways better than what he usually does Like.
Speaker 1: it doesn't stand out and sort of pop off the page as much as penny arcade does.
Speaker 0: It's more like shadery comic-y.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but you know, it's it's like it's.
Speaker 1: it's definitely highly advanced, right?
Speaker 1: Someone put a lot of work into this thing for you know However many issues it is more work than you see usually from a little comic miniseries definitely.
Speaker 0: Well, the Sphinx is great.
Speaker 0: Like I really like the Sphinx.
Speaker 0: I'm very happy that I mean won't spoil it because you can just read this thing, but It all got resolved in an interesting way.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so like the story was good Yeah, so the story here is.
Speaker 1: you got these kids who are lookouts in some town and You know, they sort of have a lookout scout leader guy who you know helps them out and tells us what to do.
Speaker 1: But there's also the town elder who I don't trust at all.
Speaker 0: Yeah anymore like I do not trust that guy.
Speaker 1: No, and it's something up with him and you know the town elder I guess is where they get their missions from.
Speaker 1: and the town Elders like yo, there's a Sphinx nearby terrorizing people.
Speaker 1: No one can trade with these other town because the Sphinx is guarding that path.
Speaker 1: No one can get past it.
Speaker 1: You know, you guys are lookouts.
Speaker 1: That's the kind of thing you deal with.
Speaker 1: It's a Sphinx you.
Speaker 1: all you're gonna have to do is solve its riddle or whatever.
Speaker 1: So go do that.
Speaker 1: so they go to do that.
Speaker 0: and And it's structured a lot like an RPG Which makes sense because this setting is basically become the setting of an RPG.
Speaker 0: sure because there's the game.
Speaker 1: I think the game is from what I've heard is become slightly more board game and slightly less RPG But it still is structured in the in the fashion of a gimme RPG.
Speaker 1: indeed there is there's a sort of.
Speaker 1: there's an encounter along the way with a troll before they go to the real encounter.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know this, you know, there's fighting versus parlaying decisions to be made.
Speaker 1: There's different characters in the party that you get to learn about and each have their own different quirks and backstories.
Speaker 0: and the quirks and backstories are interesting because this world and on a surface the world looks like There are humans.
Speaker 0: It's a lot like the torchbearer setting.
Speaker 0: humans are in their isolated communities fearful of the crazy nonsense that exists everywhere else.
Speaker 0: but yet at the same time the backstory of almost every one of these characters is no humans are actually just as crazy and Fit into this world very well because every one of these characters or most of them have some sort of supernatural connection to the natural order of this magical crazy world.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and you look as you go through each issue.
Speaker 1: It's like you learn about.
Speaker 1: you know one of the lookouts and what their deal is and each one has a crazy cool deal.
Speaker 1: That's pretty unique and interesting.
Speaker 1: It's like it's like.
Speaker 1: none of them were like.
Speaker 1: super strong characters are like that's my guy.
Speaker 1: I'm down with that one.
Speaker 1: You know that person But they were.
Speaker 1: each of them were so interesting that I still wanted to know like even more about what their deal was and see What happened to them?
Speaker 1: Because None of them had like a typical story that you would expect.
Speaker 0: but the plot at least so far and if it continues in this style Seems to not focus on any of them in terms of their motivation.
Speaker 0: so much as how does that eclectic group of people?
Speaker 1: Solve a problem in a very gamey sense Yeah, but also each issue sort of you know goes even if not in the story itself But in in the little handbook page Gives you like a really sort of not super deep but deep enough.
Speaker 1: dive into some aspect of this world Like there's a part that talks to you about like the two moons.
Speaker 1: Yeah The world has two moons and here's the deal with that and if you learn too much about them it messes you up and then It's like oh by the way the world has vampires in it.
Speaker 1: There's no vampires in this story, but you sort of learn about oh this world does have vampires, and it's like okay What's up with those right?
Speaker 1: You know it's like whoo there's this stuff going on here, right You know what's a and you know the Sphinx is a Sphinx in this world.
Speaker 1: That's supposed to be a Greek thing, but now the Sphinx is.
Speaker 1: what's their deal?
Speaker 0: Yep, and what little I know about their deal based on this trade that we read.
Speaker 0: It's pretty good deal.
Speaker 1: Yeah, this is dry ads and shit in this world.
Speaker 0: frankly that Sphinx is totally within his rights Oh sure, but it's a kind of dicks to him.
Speaker 1: I think the thing with this world that makes it so cool is that it has all this stuff from typical expected fantasy worlds.
Speaker 1: right.
Speaker 1: I'm sure there's minotaurs and dragons and all the things you'd expect but none of them are exact They don't.
Speaker 1: they're not the expected D&D stereotype.
Speaker 1: They have some kind of eh some kind of twerky twist that makes them different than all the other fantasy worlds And they sort of putting those all together in the same basket.
Speaker 1: You know everything normal.
Speaker 1: each thing gets one twist But that's a lot of twists piled on top of each other when you mix them all together in the same bag Which for a game side or for a story is really good compared to say fuck out to the round, right?
Speaker 1: You have all the familiarity like.
Speaker 1: I know what a Sphinx does.
Speaker 0: it blocks you with it, but you don't know it's full deal, right?
Speaker 1: It's like I've seen a vampire before.
Speaker 1: I've seen Dracula, but you don't know it's full deal.
Speaker 0: So yeah, but like any D&D ish setting in the world I know pretty much the full deal of when to use cold steel on somebody.
Speaker 1: and of course that one thing that or a few Things that you're missing from the full deal Interact with the story in a way that makes it way interesting like whoa Shit, son.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: How's that gonna go down?
Speaker 1: plus the the fundamental?
Speaker 1: Emotional thing that ties the whole thing together is basically kids being in danger gonna die.
Speaker 1: Yep, right and like that holds everything together because it's like oh my god These are still kids who even if they're badasses don't die.
Speaker 1: Oh my god I wasn't little and they can and do.
Speaker 0: I'll admit that was a little disappointed in How neatly they wrapped it all up in the sense that from the original comics the pilots I really had this idea that the way to make this super interesting was that like somebody always doesn't come home.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it does it almost.
Speaker 1: it's like it definitely goes there.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but it doesn't go bokurano, right?
Speaker 1: And I feel like it was originally.
Speaker 1: they sort of pulled it back from the bokurano ledge a bit You know to publish this which I guess, you know I guess they have their reasons, but it's still there enough that you don't feel like they're going too easy.
Speaker 0: true Right.
Speaker 1: It's a dangerous world and it didn't cover everything with squishy pillows.
Speaker 0: I mean look those kids are in danger from whatever these rules are that the town elder has.
Speaker 0: Yeah, whatever the rules are of the lookouts.
Speaker 0: Yep, the forest itself.
Speaker 0: And there are two challenges both the ogre or that the troll is.
Speaker 1: a troll is gonna bridge He's a troll and that dark wizard.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we learn about along the way just out there.
Speaker 1: So like, you know, you can just read this and it's done and I haven't heard of any more being made.
Speaker 1: It doesn't say volume one on it.
Speaker 0: I would just read any more of this that came out.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm kind of disappointed that there isn't a volume - it's like Cryptozoic.
Speaker 1: You're bad at making games.
Speaker 1: Stop making games just publish, you know, but you're fine at publishing things, right?
Speaker 1: You never you know, you can make stuff.
Speaker 0: I've heard good tell that you're good at arts and stories for this is good at being what it is intended to be.
Speaker 1: I'm sure it is.
Speaker 1: I've never played it.
Speaker 1: So who knows?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I've read through some of the rules.
Speaker 1: It's not bad But if you are a person who's a fan of fantasy Comics penny arcade stuff if you're one of those people who always goes to PAX and is like Where do I sign up to play thorn watch?
Speaker 1: Yeah, and you haven't and you haven't read this.
Speaker 0: This is like a great example of that adjacent output to of.
Speaker 0: you know Dave and Tycho can't do everything on their own.
Speaker 0: they have a lot of cool ideas and the fact that they have made an organization and a group of friends and all these like all these structures are in place to where they've taken a bunch of their cool ideas like this and made separate works that can sustain.
Speaker 1: Make this.
Speaker 1: someone else made this right their input to some degree.
Speaker 1: That is unknown, right?
Speaker 1: People are always at you know asking questions Like when are you gonna make this when you're gonna make more stuff there?
Speaker 1: keep asking them to make more stuff.
Speaker 1: They made a thing or someone else made a thing with their IP.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and is good and worth your time and money.
Speaker 0: why you know, you know why you know and everything else I have to say about this.
Speaker 1: I mean I could if you buy digital.
Speaker 1: that makes sense.
Speaker 1: if you wait for the trade, I can't make sense.
Speaker 1: I can't expect people to buy a hardcover.
Speaker 1: I actually think I mistakenly thought it was gonna be a trade and got a hardcover.
Speaker 0: hardcover is really high quality.
Speaker 0: It's fine.
Speaker 1: I mean, I just don't like hardcovers.
Speaker 0: If you take off its book jacket though, it's got a really nice like golden boss.
Speaker 1: They just take up too much space.
Speaker 1: Oh that does look nice.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like really tasteful.
Speaker 0: Anyway, really good-looking book.
Speaker 0: Like if you're the kind of person who wants the bookshelf of these things It's a really good-looking book.
Speaker 1: Yeah hardcover is good comic.
Speaker 0: you read my only Critique at all.
Speaker 0: It's not a masterpiece.
Speaker 0: My only my primary critique is simply that I don't want I don't want to say the dialogue is over raw Cuz.
Speaker 0: that's kind of a crappy critique to give.
Speaker 0: the dialogue is a little Stilted in the way that people who are role-playing speak.
Speaker 1: sure But that is definitely not.
Speaker 1: it's definitely not natural dialogue, right?
Speaker 0: It's like Jeff Lemire did not write the dialogue.
Speaker 1: No, it's.
Speaker 1: it's.
Speaker 1: it's more along the lines of like, you know, the kind of dialogue you get in like a superhero comic You know with less less crazy words for things because it's a fantasy world.
Speaker 1: It's not the way normal people talk to each other.
Speaker 1: and The other thing I'd say is like.
Speaker 1: actually, you know, I think it's a little bit rushed You know, you know the story-wise the pacing and the pacing is still just fine.
Speaker 1: It's like you don't?
Speaker 1: you're not gonna feel like it's going too slow or too fast when you're reading it.
Speaker 1: But it's like I read the whole thing pretty quickly Yep, and subway rides and I felt like you know It didn't feel like it was going fast when I was reading it, but it also when I was done.
Speaker 1: It's like man, they could have fit more in there.
Speaker 1: I would have liked to see more, you know, slow it down a little bit and but you know and fill it in.
Speaker 1: Don't slow it down.
Speaker 1: And so I wonder because they're like you take the same material and drag it out over more pages.
Speaker 1: That's not gonna work.
Speaker 1: That's gonna be too slow because associated with it could have put in more stuff.
Speaker 1: that would happen You know like add another encounter on the adventure add more Interactions, you know, but I can see an angle that the things I'm most interested in Like.
Speaker 0: I want to know what the village elders deal is.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's the kind of stuff you could have fit in right?
Speaker 0: You know girls why death penalty right violated.
Speaker 0: you could you could add a scene with the village elder You could add a scene telling us Answers to the questions that I am asking are the kinds of things that are supposed to remain central mysteries of the setting.
Speaker 1: you Can but I feel like when you have central mysteries of a setting like that You have to answer or partially answer one of them per product that you put out.
Speaker 0: the alternative is to have some of them be present in every single story and Cause tension and problems so that it's always this ever-present like.
Speaker 0: but what the fuck's the deal with that?
Speaker 1: Well, you can eventually Tell the backstory of what the fuck the deal with it is.
Speaker 0: Yeah, then you try to forgotten realms where everything has this overwrought forever back story.
Speaker 1: But you could still while telling the backstory of why things are the way they are still not resolve them.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so that they continue to be there.
Speaker 1: you just know why they're there.
Speaker 0: now in my head I feel like this is literally the exact same world as torchbearer.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it fits real.
Speaker 0: Well, maybe torchbearer That's setting the implied setting of torchbearer.
Speaker 0: if you just read the rules and don't like try to read other things that you know those people who put together It's just yeah dangerous weird magic filled world out there and you're a jerk who's porn.
Speaker 0: you got into it.
Speaker 1: I think that but the lookouts aren't going out to find treasure.
Speaker 1: No They're not just looking to defend the normal people who live in the dangerous fantasy world about the normal people in the torchbearer world Who are going out adventuring?
Speaker 1: Yeah, the torchbearer people are trying to go out and get loot.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but the torchbearer world is that they're the crazy ones.
Speaker 0: everyone else stays in the village Dangerous out there.
Speaker 1: That's true.
Speaker 0: Anyway, it's good stuff this book.
Speaker 1: it exists.
Speaker 1: You might not have known about it But now you should and you could buy it and then give cryptozoic your money for this but not for their games.
Speaker 0: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Speaker 1: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 0: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 0: But unlike those other late shows it's actually recorded at night And the patreon patrons for this episode of geek nights are in order.
Speaker 0: the money was on a continuing basis.
Speaker 0: I already see a bunch of crap down there Rebecca Dunn Nicholas Brandau Alan Joyce Heidi McNichol Amanda Duchette great job emoji mystati.com.
Speaker 0: William Eisneros, Jeremy Monner kiwi wo kiwi wo aishiteru kokoro de mitsumete iru the Cronenberg Interdimensional geek nights fan club.
Speaker 0: four to one creations.
Speaker 0: I mean are we the product of subcosmic coincidence?
Speaker 0: Sherman one horrible.
Speaker 0: James David White Rochelle, Montana Superboy.
Speaker 0: I paid five bucks to make rim say carburetor sailor Vista Matthew Smith Don Schleich chart option Sure sure sure.
Speaker 0: star Tyler Eller Sean Yeager Sam Cordery Clinton Walton Renford, New Zealand Ryan Perrin bring back.
Speaker 0: Sheriff Lobo Brian Cedroni.
Speaker 0: I've had a bit of a tumble redacted.
Speaker 0: Chris midkiff Chris Knox Daniel Redmond Sean Klein Chris Reimer and Thomas Hahn and now I leave you is something Something like hard-boiled eggs from patties.
Speaker 1: bar green eggs says patties on them.
Speaker 0: You keep them on your desk and when you go to work Who's gonna want to keep a hard-boiled egg on their desk at work?
Speaker 1: Oh, all right.
Speaker 0: Then you put it on your dashboard of your car.
Speaker 1: It's just a jumping-off point.
Speaker 0: Frank keeping hard-boiled eggs on your desktop or the dashboard of your car is not a jumping-off point.
Speaker 0: Well, you get the hell out of here.
Speaker 0: All right, let us concentrate on doing the merchandising idea.
Speaker 0: Clearly you don't get it.
Speaker 0: So I don't I don't get it.
Speaker 0: You don't get it.
Speaker 0: I don't get it.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah We'll see who doesn't get.
Speaker 0: okay.
Speaker 0: Yeah