Speaker 1: It's the geek nuts book club, and we are back on this spooky Thursday October 26th, it's scary because we read the book club in a reasonable amount of time.
Speaker 0: who's So?
Speaker 1: it's interesting That the fifth season is the fourth way.
Speaker 1: Why?
Speaker 1: because at the very end we find out that the moon eats your soul?
Speaker 1: What's the leather?
Speaker 1: I Spoilers the book club.
Speaker 1: We are assuming you have already read the fifth season by NK Jemisin.
Speaker 1: If you have not read it, you're gonna want.
Speaker 1: you're gonna be confused until we're gonna spoil everything.
Speaker 1: I suggest you read it.
Speaker 1: There are many other geek nights book club episodes that we have done such books as the Wheel of Time and the Prince of Nothing Right, so I chose this book because I'd heard a lot about it.
Speaker 0: You know, this is it happens a lot.
Speaker 0: I say this often but I'm gonna keep saying it.
Speaker 0: You hang out in nerdy communities.
Speaker 0: You hear something mentioned over and over and over again.
Speaker 0: Just keeps getting mentioned and mentioned and mentioned.
Speaker 0: you're like, oh this thing keeps have.
Speaker 0: Oh gabbo gabbo It's like I keep hearing about this.
Speaker 0: I should check it out at some point and then the book club is like well I have to pick a book.
Speaker 0: Hey, how about that one?
Speaker 0: I keep hearing about.
Speaker 0: oh, what's that?
Speaker 0: It won the Hugo award and the sequel won the Hugo award the year after.
Speaker 0: Interesting and I saw the author at gamer X's last year and she was cool talking about Dragon Age or whatever.
Speaker 0: and it's like Alright, this seems good to me.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: So I really enjoyed this book like straight up and I'm gonna read the other the next two.
Speaker 0: Yeah, this is a fantasy sci-fi novel of high quality.
Speaker 1: It did not disappoint and I like I did very much enjoy.
Speaker 1: and again last chance.
Speaker 1: We're gonna spoil it.
Speaker 1: We're gonna assume you read it.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: Enjoy the fact that it starts with the end of the world.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: Well, there's a lot of world.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it starts with the end of the world.
Speaker 1: It starts to set the the idea of what does it mean for a world to end?
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm, and then it jumps into all these different stories that are actually just different parts of the same story.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's the.
Speaker 0: I think that is the number one genius part of this book right is that we saw?
Speaker 0: we already read Hyperion which did a Canterbury tale Situation and here you think you're sort of getting that right?
Speaker 0: You've got these different stories of different characters, you know even Prince of Nothing does the same thing where you Different every chapter.
Speaker 0: it goes to a different part of the story focused on a different character and just like snatch, you know At some point they're all gonna crash into each other.
Speaker 1: So do I know spoiler here, but if you ever watch Westworld the new one, which is one is fantastic Does the same thing.
Speaker 1: it does something very similar.
Speaker 1: that is It's very similar and very well done and amazing.
Speaker 0: So in this book, I got a little suspicious early on because the stories really didn't fit with each other.
Speaker 1: well Well one of them fit with the other two one fit.
Speaker 1: one of them was the world's fucking end.
Speaker 0: right.
Speaker 0: one of them It's like there is a season happening and the other ones people are just like hey, what's up?
Speaker 0: And I'm like, how could I'm like?
Speaker 0: is the season really far away from them?
Speaker 0: Like I went to look at the map and try to figure it out because basically you have this world Where they've got spring summer winter fall, but they also have what they call our seasons or the fifth season Which is just apocalypse world.
Speaker 1: the RPG guard your gates.
Speaker 0: There are different Apocalypses that happen randomly throughout history and they always end up winning in the end and they don't completely wipe out humanity But they do a bunch of damage effectively erasing civilization.
Speaker 0: well, and you can see the remnants of the previous civilizations densives which makes you and that's how you know that your sieve is at Least better than theirs because they if they were better than you they would they wouldn't be alive.
Speaker 0: and well at the same time It's still being alive proves that you're doing better than them.
Speaker 1: It's how you quote unquote.
Speaker 1: know because it's very interesting to see this overarching theme that Over time a world like this because at the end of the book you get the appendix that later on a world That's super dangerous.
Speaker 0: It reminds immediately reminded me of the end of game.
Speaker 0: a player of games.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, but the warrior planet with the fire planet.
Speaker 0: This is a ring of fire going around and burning it over and over again.
Speaker 0: They could they live on the planet as soon as the fire goes away And then they wait a long time and the fire comes back and they run away.
Speaker 1: I think the fire is going in a ring.
Speaker 1: They just always stay ahead of the ring like in that moving castle or whatever.
Speaker 0: Yeah, whatever, but that totally reminded me of that Immediately,
Speaker 1: but the conventional wisdom of this world is interesting because there's definitely this very strong idea At least from our main character and all the schooling that brought her to the point that she was at that
Speaker 0: any
Speaker 1: remnant of Any civilization any calm anything that didn't survive a season is clearly worthless because they're dead and we're still alive.
Speaker 1: therefore Anything that is old and didn't survive is worthless and you should avoid it.
Speaker 1: and over time you have the society that is increasingly Hyper-static and hyper focused on these very narrow avenues of success.
Speaker 1: But then you look at the time scales and the actual time frame between these seasons Can be thousands and thousands of years
Speaker 0: and then somehow this stone lore has lasted, you know Even though they don't care about old things This stone lore is somewhat old enough that they like know about these old seasons Even if they're so old, but they don't know about like these Obelisks that are flying around.
Speaker 1: Ah, but they don't care about the obelisks because the obelisks are clearly a relic of a sieve That didn't make it therefore.
Speaker 0: It doesn't matter what the stone lore is a relic of a sieve that didn't make it do.
Speaker 1: no Because the stone lore is passed down among the sieves that survive Anyway, but they literally they ignore the relics especially the obelisks at least ostensibly.
Speaker 1: and the argument is the obelisks are a relic of Society that failed.
Speaker 1: therefore whatever they are should be ignored because the people who didn't didn't ignore them didn't make it.
Speaker 1: So what the fuck did they be?
Speaker 0: who made them didn't make it.
Speaker 1: but obviously That is kind of false reasoning
Speaker 0: Obviously, especially
Speaker 1: in light of the fact that these seasons can be thousands and thousands of years apart and this other overarching theme that Whether or not any individual civilization survives a season Seems to come down to not really stone lower but luck because sometimes just get fucked.
Speaker 1: The reality is that these seasons are by and large caused by things beyond the understanding and control of anyone involved.
Speaker 0: It's just a super super fucking dangerous world where all this awful shit happens all the time And it's everything sucks.
Speaker 0: So a better more dangerous than the earth We live on like and like if the cow Aren't you like them super caldera out in Yellowstone or whatever that everyone's always afraid of?
Speaker 0: Yeah imagine if that blew up and like that was a Constant fear.
Speaker 0: like actually that people actually worried about that all the time and there were many other things like it and not just that One.
Speaker 1: but imagine if they were afraid of that all the time and the last time it blew up was 10,000 years ago.
Speaker 1: and yet 10,000 years later Everyone still is prepared for that exact same bullshit.
Speaker 0: But other horrible things like it are also on.
Speaker 0: the could happen at any time.
Speaker 1: But I guess the fundamental reasoning of that civil is there.
Speaker 1: those people is our main character in relation to Ignore the dead civs.
Speaker 1: They clearly didn't make it.
Speaker 1: I feel like the overarching story of the next two books will be how false that reasoning is.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so the the book starts to lead you on with this Canterbury tale focusing on different characters and yet then it pulls a switch I've never seen before.
Speaker 0: I mean it's it's it's sort of like.
Speaker 0: it seems like an obvious thing that someone could have done.
Speaker 0: Maybe someone did but I've never seen it before where haha.
Speaker 0: It's all the same character at different points in their own life.
Speaker 0: It's just that that character's life was so Different at different points in her life the main character her childhood her upbringing her old light or meet a middle-aged life.
Speaker 0: We don't see her old life.
Speaker 0: It was her life was so different and she changed her name so many times And became a different person so that the three different stories really seem like different people and then you realize it's all the same person Gradually, like I Scott suspicious, but it's like how could it be?
Speaker 0: These worlds are so different.
Speaker 0: This one's in a season and this one's not.
Speaker 0: and this one You know, it's like how could this can't possibly be the same, you know, and then eventually it's like no It is exactly what I suspected.
Speaker 0: good move well played well played.
Speaker 1: so in light of everything I said before there's another point that the book makes repeatedly and very explicitly that the most interesting story about a thing like a history of people or whatever is to notice the things that are Conspicuously lacking.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm that you wouldn't think about.
Speaker 1: like is there something that never gets brought up?
Speaker 1: What's the elephant in the room and The?
Speaker 1: this point is reinforced gradually as you see things like no one cares about the stars because why would you ever look up when?
Speaker 1: All the dangers below you.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm Like she don't even our main character doesn't think about the stars until she's out on an island Which she didn't think people lived on.
Speaker 1: and there's people out there.
Speaker 1: No one talks about islands cuz clearly people don't live on islands.
Speaker 0: islands are hella dangerous.
Speaker 1: But then there's these people on this island who appear to have been living there for a long time.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm And when she was in the stone Lord and you just try you have faith in the stone Lord cuz that's what's keeping you alive.
Speaker 0: But well, there's people who don't know about her doing just fine.
Speaker 0: There's a world outside Outside of the occurs, you know, yeah the mind trap that has been made for you by the society The society is really restrictive right?
Speaker 0: It's like they have these use casts, right?
Speaker 0: It's like you're in a particular use cast.
Speaker 1: Yeah Your last your last.
Speaker 1: your name is basically your first name.
Speaker 1: how you why?
Speaker 1: why you are useful Scott what city you live in Scott?
Speaker 0: Computer person, New York.
Speaker 1: Yeah rim computer person, New York, right?
Speaker 0: It's like.
Speaker 0: so It's like and that that's what you do in life and you obey the stone lore.
Speaker 0: and the stone lore you just take as granted.
Speaker 0: You're not really questioning anything take it for granted.
Speaker 0: Yeah You know and you just try as an origin joke.
Speaker 0: You're just trying to survive in this awful world.
Speaker 1: and but all these little things around that that point of what is missing Like what is not talked about and there's subtle things like the stars of the islands like she literally islands don't exist because why would?
Speaker 1: I would live on them.
Speaker 1: and then oh there's people on the island and it sort of makes sense because Even if people settled on that island right after the previous season they could live there for thousands and thousands of years Before another season.
Speaker 1: Yeah, very few civilizations on a real earth have made it thousands of years, right?
Speaker 0: That's another thing is that this is trope.
Speaker 0: I see a lot that we I talk about a lot where of the sci-fi thing where the people are trapped in physically trapped right in the dome like or Logan's run.
Speaker 0: Yep, or What's the one we did for the book club where they were underground with it with the helmets?
Speaker 1: Oh Already forgot, you know the one yeah, but I already forgot with that book.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but anyway There's a lot of these sci-fi fantasy books or whatever, especially sci-fi where the people are sort of physically trapped in some location.
Speaker 0: They don't know about the outside world.
Speaker 0: anime does it a lot where there's a wall around the society or something, right?
Speaker 0: You know big O is sort of one of those the inside and outside the dome situation.
Speaker 0: But here there's no physical trap really, right?
Speaker 0: Even though many of the the soul as well.
Speaker 0: Well, that's the one, you know wool over your eyes, right?
Speaker 0: We should have figured that out.
Speaker 0: But Here instead of doing a thing like Logan's run where they're physically trapped in some horrible dystopian society underground they can Physically freely roam everywhere, but the origins can't.
Speaker 0: the origins are effectively trapped sort of but there's no There's no physical wall around all of society.
Speaker 1: People could just get on a boat like that island I Island where they keep pirating like no one went and got them because no one.
Speaker 1: everyone assumed that it was some other local calm.
Speaker 0: but the point is is that there's still this mental wall around the society and thus a lot of the same things that happen in Stories that follow that trope happen in this like oh We've discovered this hidden society of people outside of the society civilization that we were aware of.
Speaker 0: Oh, you know we learn things that you know.
Speaker 0: There's actually this whole other way of life and other things going on that were kept secret from us all this time.
Speaker 0: Right as all those same things happen in the fifth season Even though it doesn't have the same premise of the trope.
Speaker 1: Nope So in terms of those absences again Uh, the moon is never mentioned at any point in the book the nail of heaven.
Speaker 1: and then actually the North Stars Yeah, and then the moon is Literally the last line of the book of you ever heard of the moon?
Speaker 0: Yeah, and it's like what.
Speaker 1: so I saw that coming from Pretty early out like almost after.
Speaker 1: after that long explicit bit about like look for the absences And then all the bitch with stars and everything I realized and I started paying attention to about a third of the way through the book that the moon was never mentioned ever.
Speaker 1: She was outside looking up and talking about the stars like the idea of the moon never really came up ever.
Speaker 1: and then there was another bit where the they start talking about.
Speaker 1: why is the evil earth so pissed?
Speaker 1: and They no one really remembers, but wasn't the oral legend something like the people of Earth killed his son?
Speaker 1: Who could be the son of the earth?
Speaker 1: perhaps the moon in a world like this?
Speaker 1: And then also there was a point where they said that maybe it wasn't his son But some people say that they destroyed his favorite glass knife.
Speaker 1: They destroyed the earth's favorite glass knife and near the end Reinforcing my idea that the moon was gonna be evil earth's son when the alabaster shows up after he destroyed the world Really started the destruction.
Speaker 1: There's that big glass knife and leaning on the wall and she's like what's that?
Speaker 1: and he's like.
Speaker 1: And there's nonsense about it and it seems to be tied to the same thing.
Speaker 1: that's tied to him bringing up the moon.
Speaker 1: Pretty sure.
Speaker 1: the whole rest of this is about what's up with the moon and why there isn't a moon anymore.
Speaker 0: There's definitely the secret past that I didn't think we're actually gonna see a lot of that, you know Terrible secret of the past.
Speaker 1: I think we're gonna see it all.
Speaker 1: I think the Guardians know a lot.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, but then they're no good.
Speaker 0: then as soon as we went to that place In that the Guardians had with like the room with a socket the socket It's like as soon as you saw that it's like shit son there is a terrible secret of space and I
Speaker 1: gotta know that was one of my favorite scenes because Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: You there's a secret you went from not even knowing about it.
Speaker 0: Usually it's like this is looming terrible secret of space like ooh, what's in the thing?
Speaker 0: We're not gonna tell you to like chapter 10.
Speaker 0: It's like we're gonna reveal you the thing exists and go there right away.
Speaker 1: I'm like, oh snap, not only that but they reveal it They don't tell you what it is and then immediately like that Guardian shows up and that other nonsense happens.
Speaker 1: And then that Guardian takes her aside and she thinks always gonna kill me or she's gonna kill me Like I'm done and that Guardians I'm getting killed instead, but instead the Guardians like so did you touch it and she's like what?
Speaker 1: Did you touch it?
Speaker 0: That's important because the Guardian thought she knew more than she knew.
Speaker 1: Yep, and then you learn a bunch but you don't learn enough.
Speaker 1: and then the other Guardian comes in and pulls the chip out of Guardians brain and yeah, this is something it's like.
Speaker 0: the Guardians are like the most fascinating thing right?
Speaker 0: because okay So you got normal people then you got origins which are as powerful as wizards in the Prince of Nothing or they are Like in Dune where all the magic is based on the spice And the ecology of the planet Arrakis in here in the fifth season.
Speaker 0: All of the magic is based on rocks and geology.
Speaker 1: Yep, right to the point that they don't they call scientists Geomasts because all science is rooted in the earth because that's the most important thing right?
Speaker 0: Everything is about geology here.
Speaker 0: The magic is powered by geology.
Speaker 0: Everything's geology and the people who practice wizardry, right?
Speaker 0: There are some of the people just you know, they're pretty much just born.
Speaker 0: Oh crap.
Speaker 0: I'm born a wizard.
Speaker 0: I have magic powers.
Speaker 0: I'm dangerous.
Speaker 0: They're basically treated like x-men, you know, there's the obvious allegory of you know, racism and persecution that's going on.
Speaker 0: They have a racial slur for them.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's.
Speaker 0: it's pretty much the same story as x-men.
Speaker 0: People are born with powers and then they're shunned by their families.
Speaker 0: Some of them are made useful Through training at Professor X's Academy and some of them are killed and some of them are horribly tortured.
Speaker 1: Professor X's Academy seems more like magnetos.
Speaker 0: Yes, it does.
Speaker 0: It's not the greatest but it does teach you skills and you get to go on missions to help.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but there's where the Guardian is the most.
Speaker 1: it because they're so unnerving and there's all these moments Where a guardian appears and you expect a certain sort of interaction to happen reading the book like alright this Guardians here They're right.
Speaker 0: It's like these Guardians are presented as these people who run really running the show are even stronger than any origin Right there.
Speaker 0: They can kick any x-men's ass with their magic powers, right?
Speaker 0: Everyone's super subservient to them no matter what you get.
Speaker 1: little things like alabaster tells her do not let him touch you with his skin.
Speaker 0: Right, they constantly have this like question of like who's who's the ball?
Speaker 0: who is the boss of the Guardians?
Speaker 0: and you don't know.
Speaker 0: It's a super mystery.
Speaker 0: It must be God or something who even knows.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so Guardians are super scary.
Speaker 0: Yet even though some of the Guardians act in a super scary way Some of the main one is like super cool and he doesn't.
Speaker 1: well, it's more most of the time They're inscrutable.
Speaker 1: the actions that they take Take me as the reader by surprise.
Speaker 0: like that one shows up when alabaster They don't follow any pattern of what you would expect from that kind of character in any other story.
Speaker 1: Yep Well the one that shows up in the town that gets destroyed by the volcano it just immediately tries to kill them Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: There's the one the the main one who shows up again after he.
Speaker 0: so he's like the super cool character I just like him so much.
Speaker 1: Oh, he's a great character.
Speaker 0: It's like.
Speaker 0: that's the character It's like.
Speaker 0: please go back to the character, please.
Speaker 0: Please they're so awesome.
Speaker 1: the best character in the entire book However, is the sexy pie is the pirate captain.
Speaker 1: Oh that character.
Speaker 1: I agree is the sexiest Person I have ever read about in fiction.
Speaker 1: Like I I am hard-pressed like.
Speaker 1: this is occhio level but not evil as far as I can tell.
Speaker 1: he's just great.
Speaker 0: He's just awesome pirate guy.
Speaker 0: You see it's like it was like a BK was sexy.
Speaker 1: Yeah, he seems to have no character flaws.
Speaker 0: He's bisexual he's polyamorous He is hotter than God and a pirate and a good pirate.
Speaker 0: Yeah, he's kinda wizard.
Speaker 1: He's great at pirating, but he's also a good person.
Speaker 1: Basically, everything about this guy is great.
Speaker 1: It's like the one person you just want to win and then want to have sex with.
Speaker 1: yep Yeah, yep, pretty much.
Speaker 1: I love that bit where because obviously alabaster is Probably pretty gay and does not you know, there's probably he's the most gay.
Speaker 0: 99% again 999% again.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and they're doing there.
Speaker 0: I knew that from like page two because it's like.
Speaker 0: she said the main character is sent to go like have sex with this Dude, right.
Speaker 0: He's like because they're likely to have awesome wizard babies because they're both awesome wizards and She like doesn't want to do it because he also doesn't love it.
Speaker 0: But then he also doesn't want to do it.
Speaker 0: I'm like, oh he's gay.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: He's gay.
Speaker 0: Oh, I'm right.
Speaker 1: but then when the pirate captain like.
Speaker 1: They both want him and the pirate captain wants both of them and the way that resolves into just okay.
Speaker 1: They're all together now.
Speaker 0: Well, baby.
Speaker 1: That's just how it goes.
Speaker 0: sexy sexy.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: though along those lines in general - in terms of aside from origins the way the rest of the world is presented is very interesting from a just like modern fiction perspective because There's trans characters there's gay characters skin colors all over the place and a lot of these attributes are very casually used and it's just I'm happy to see Interesting representation across a broad spectrum.
Speaker 0: I mean this book is written by a nerdy black lady from Brooklyn.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so I mean, I don't know what you expected.
Speaker 0: I mean It's so not par for the course with fantasy fiction except for like Ursula K Le Guin or whatever.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right?
Speaker 0: So, you know, there you go Caradad Caradad torch.
Speaker 1: Yep, but I very much enjoyed that aspect of these books a lot.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm, but that pirate captain We can't get away from sexy pirate.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like I started reading it because Emily's the only bad thing about sexy pirate captain He doesn't show up till later in the book and then he doesn't make it.
Speaker 0: Oh, no.
Speaker 1: Yeah He goes down in a pretty pretty awful way.
Speaker 1: Oh, no Well, I mean the way he goes down Room tells us exactly why you don't want one of those Guardians to touch your skin with their skin.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: But now I read.
Speaker 1: I really want to know what the secrets are and I want to know.
Speaker 1: I wanted everything.
Speaker 1: I want to read the rest of these.
Speaker 0: I've heard from some reliable people that book two and three are not on the same levels.
Speaker 0: book one But it's like.
Speaker 0: I don't understand how that could be.
Speaker 0: book two also won the Hugo award and I don't know.
Speaker 0: book three just came Out super recently and it's like how could that possibly be bad?
Speaker 0: I can't even imagine but I'm gonna find out for myself.
Speaker 0: I held back on reading more book two so that it wouldn't taint this episode of geek nights.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I don't got a hold back anymore Except Mario Odyssey is coming out like this.
Speaker 0: Yeah Is there anything else to say about the fifties?
Speaker 0: Oh one thing I do want to say now about the is that even though this is I seem a three book series, right?
Speaker 0: I Really actually feel like someone negative about the book.
Speaker 0: I feel like you didn't really get your money's worth with book one.
Speaker 0: in terms of length I feel like it.
Speaker 0: five hundred twelve pages sure, but it feels story wise.
Speaker 0: it feels like essentially the way it ends.
Speaker 0: it feels like it really is just like Is the three books could have been one book, you know, it doesn't feel like a three book Even though I haven't read book two or three.
Speaker 0: It doesn't feel like book one of a set.
Speaker 1: it feels like the first chunk of a one complete book got ripped out but at least it ended on a Huge revelation and a coming together of all the ideas it did and it ended on a good beat of.
Speaker 1: have you ever heard of?
Speaker 1: something called the moon?
Speaker 1: Yeah, but meanwhile other books that had like Wheel of Time books just kind of stop and then the next book just starts like but They're so enormous.
Speaker 0: They're tired at the end and that's why it feels like a complete thing.
Speaker 1: They also all the later Wheel of Time books do not feel like a complete thing.
Speaker 1: Okay, the ones I literally like book eight Or something like I hit the end and I hit next and I was like, oh shit It's done.
Speaker 1: and I just opened book nine and just immediately hit next.
Speaker 0: Okay Because the ones that I read all of them built up and eventually ended on a major Confrontation between the main character and the major evil, right?
Speaker 1: And then you think that all of that gets resolved so much so early in those books, right?
Speaker 0: But I'm saying is that all the books I read in that series.
Speaker 0: That's what happened like four or five something like that.
Speaker 0: But like the end of the book was always a confrontation with major evil Right.
Speaker 0: and the same way that like Star Wars Episode four ends with a fight with Darth Vader.
Speaker 0: It's our.
Speaker 0: episode five ends with a fight with Star Wars episode six Darth Vader.
Speaker 1: if this the thing is this I wonder what if the next book will continue telling all these three stories as they come Together further or will it now just pick up from this moment where alabaster asks her to continue the apocalypse?
Speaker 0: I hope it does continue from that part because I don't think there's too much more from the past.
Speaker 0: We need to learn about the minute, you know, say night or I guess that's a night But I can't pronounce.
Speaker 1: she's not sure what name she wants to use because she it's interesting how.
Speaker 0: that's why I just keep saying main character.
Speaker 1: well because the Book is structured in such a way that you see these three different people and then it's revealed that they're the same person at different Stages in their lives which sort of lines up with the like child woman crone Thing that is done in literature.
Speaker 1: but simultaneously She has this self-awareness of Not caring about the overarching plot and is very conflicted about who she really is Because the reality of these three different lives is a very important part of her character and spinning is The really crazy thing.
Speaker 0: is that like, you know, she's obviously because you're reading a book, you know This in the meta that she's like a central character in like this the whole world Picture but she as a character is only focused on going to get her child.
Speaker 0: Yep That's all she cares about at least in that one present timeline.
Speaker 1: Everyone around her present especially the stone eaters are like you were the chosen one and she's like I don't give a shit Yeah, she doesn't care like that.
Speaker 0: It's like stone is like.
Speaker 0: this is the great mystery of the stone eaters.
Speaker 0: Don't give a shit.
Speaker 1: gonna get my child like when a stone eater shows up I'm like, oh my god my kid go like she finds anything interesting.
Speaker 1: I'm like, let's find out push that lever do a thing follow up.
Speaker 0: and she literally she's like, oh, I just want to find my baby.
Speaker 1: She cares about the opposite of what I care about, which is interesting cuz she didn't care about her first baby.
Speaker 1: Well She did.
Speaker 0: sort of not as much she cares about the one now.
Speaker 1: Well, because there's nothing to do for the first baby.
Speaker 0: Sure.
Speaker 1: I mean she did everything she could for that first baby kinda From her perspective.
Speaker 1: That was the best thing for that baby.
Speaker 1: hmm, hmm because she lived through the fulcrum training and she lived through her life at that point later and She definitely made her decision that death is preferable to slavery.
Speaker 0: Hmm, and I thought especially after seeing the the the nodes or whatever.
Speaker 1: Yeah the nodes of the problem I that that's a great moment before you know what the nodes are where she's like blah blah blah.
Speaker 1: I don't want to get stuck in some back.
Speaker 0: That's another situation where like they talk about nodes and then like the chapter or two later you go in the node and get the Whole deal.
Speaker 0: you don't have to like wait for the mystery of the node But the way we are still waiting for the mystery of the socket.
Speaker 1: So there's that moment where she says like like she's sympathetic to what she believes the person in the node is doing.
Speaker 1: She's like, yeah, I guess we should help them out.
Speaker 1: and then alabaster pauses.
Speaker 1: He's like you've never been to a node Have you?
Speaker 1: nope, you've never been to the West Indies.
Speaker 1: Nope so shall we go and How?
Speaker 1: he doesn't really need to explain it.
Speaker 1: You just get this very like the slow reveal like obviously they go in they see what happened They leave but the way that chapter is written is almost like someone coming into a room and just looking bit by bit at all the things at the room.
Speaker 1: and then Environmental storytelling does its thing and the full gnosis is revealed Just by seeing the remnants of an event that happened.
Speaker 1: That was a very well-written scene.
Speaker 0: I was the alabaster right is like.
Speaker 0: He's way cool And it's sort of like it just.
Speaker 0: it's just fun to have that kind of character around who's Ridiculous insane powerful like having a level 20 wizard in the party.
Speaker 0: Yep It's sort of fun and just sort of that raw nerdy kind of way like oh my god This guy's so strong.
Speaker 1: It also makes you feel like together.
Speaker 0: They're invincible, but They hold it in check and don't just ruin everything because you got this guardian situation going on, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, he can't just go and do whatever he's got to actually sort of do his job.
Speaker 0: But because he is so powerful can sort of get away with a lot.
Speaker 1: But that's it.
Speaker 1: The power of the origins is revealed to be ridiculously ridiculous Right away and the more you learn about it the more ridiculous it seems.
Speaker 1: and you start to wonder more and more like wow Why does alabaster put up with any of it?
Speaker 0: Why did the x-men put up with this stupid US government always trying to make sentinel program?
Speaker 1: Yeah, but then bit by bit like every new thing you learn about the Guardians makes you realize why?
Speaker 1: They're in power despite the origins.
Speaker 1: all being gods.
Speaker 0: The Guardians got some sort of cyber implant of awesomeness.
Speaker 0: But also it freaks out and is being controlled by some sort of central AI.
Speaker 0: who knows what?
Speaker 1: I do also appreciate how the storytelling the narrator uses the second person a lot and Who the narrator is sort of gets revealed later?
Speaker 1: And I thought that was really interesting because the the writing style is very Conversational and very.
Speaker 1: it definitely has its own beats that I've rarely encountered.
Speaker 0: It didn't fully pull out to a princess bride level to where you see who the narrator is talking to or anything like that.
Speaker 0: It gets close.
Speaker 0: It gets close because the narrative will be like It'd be like Princess Bride if you saw a grandpa, but you didn't see what's-his-face.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah So Yeah, I have other thoughts that I kind of want to just reserve until I see how this all.
Speaker 1: There are threads that I don't know if they will be meaningful or not And there's allegory that I don't know if I'm reading too much into it or not.
Speaker 1: But I'm hyper focused on this.
Speaker 1: What is not described because that is a very powerful story tell storytelling mechanic to tell someone Hey the things that aren't said are the important parts and then to tell a story and not say things Which this book is doing very much.
Speaker 0: so I mean, I'm focused mostly on of course, you know the x-men Persecution story because that seems to be like the central obvious one.
Speaker 0: It's pushed really hard and then obviously I'm focused on Secondarily.
Speaker 0: the tower was eager to space because I'm Scott Reuben and I like to tell in this case the terrible secret of the moon the socket the other side of the world the Obelisks the stone eaters what their deal is anything like that.
Speaker 0: I got to know the deal.
Speaker 1: Yep I'm just mostly invested in the the fallacy that dead civs are dead for a reason and the idea that not everyone has control over the Extrinsic disasters that might befall them.
Speaker 1: Yeah Like there are things that can happen to you like if a cosmic ray Came in and killed me somehow in this room.
Speaker 1: There is literally nothing I could have done to prevent that and thus there is no value judgment To be made based on that fate to any decision I have ever made in my life.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: So I just want to guess what the terrible secret to space is.
Speaker 0: My guess is that on the other side of the world like the moon just fucking crashed into the earth because some orogene badness Probably and that's why this seasons all the time because the earth is all fucked up because there's a moon smashed into it And the socket is probably from like a piece of moon that landed there and the moon is what you know gave people Powers and
Speaker 1: I think the socket is what was used to strip.
Speaker 1: I think it legit that manufactured Obelisks and the obelisks are something very specific.
Speaker 0: Oh, that's good.
Speaker 0: That's good.
Speaker 1: That's what I think something like that.
Speaker 0: But yeah, the stone eaters in the obelisk like flying it around.
Speaker 1: I don't know if the stone eater was trapped in the obelisk or if he was using the obelisk.
Speaker 1: Maybe people play and play God.
Speaker 0: Really good part of the book.
Speaker 0: It's like one of those short in-between the chapter things.
Speaker 0: That's sort of like an aside Yeah, and it's like.
Speaker 0: it's like well, it's a good you know, it's like oh, yeah this world this and that and people are like This.
Speaker 0: well, it's a good thing that people aren't the only intelligent life on this world.
Speaker 0: And I was like, oh, that's so good It's okay.
Speaker 1: I do wonder if evil earth will actually be a Person like a thing of some kind other than just literally a planet.
Speaker 1: it's the moon, I don't know cuz the implant that the Guardians get Appears to be able to fail in a weird way because that Guardian went crazy, right?
Speaker 0: I think that it like it.
Speaker 1: The implant you tapped into something that's there.
Speaker 1: Yeah, almost like cuz in creating some sort of connection with something and like the radio signal in wool Which I think I can say cuz this Soul or demon or something in there?
Speaker 1: Yeah something along those lines like it's almost like maybe there's a radio transmitter somewhere That's transmitting crazy bullshit and the Guardians plug that into their brain and they're barely holding out of their sanity using it.
Speaker 0: I don't know something some nonsense like that.
Speaker 1: Anyway, also I want to see what Tonkis deal is like.
Speaker 1: I want to see Tonkis.
Speaker 0: Oh, you mean the scientists, right?
Speaker 1: I like the scientists a lot.
Speaker 0: I love how that character that totally got me.
Speaker 0: I didn't see that coming.
Speaker 1: I did not see that coming at all.
Speaker 0: Well, you actually had asked you would you discuss something about it?
Speaker 0: and I was like, oh because I had already read it I got up.
Speaker 0: I was right before the point where Yeah, and you started talking to me about it and I'm like, well you don't know the deal do you?
Speaker 0: and you're like, oh And I'm like, oh I was like Tonki seems cool.
Speaker 1: I wonder what her deal.
Speaker 0: she seems a lot like an anime character to me one of those characters.
Speaker 0: Yeah Who's you know, like ooh, I got to learn all the stuff.
Speaker 0: I'm the science girl with a whole bunch of papers trying to learn everything And then the fact that that character was actually came back in the other timeline and bumped into the main character again is like whoa.
Speaker 1: And also I like how she's that kind of tinker character who will Obviously is hiding a lot.
Speaker 0: She's like guns from Chrono Trigger the girl you meet with the.
Speaker 0: You know the mechanical girl Luca.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like Luca.
Speaker 1: I could see that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's that kind of character.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so yeah well I'm gonna read at least the second book and If the second book would have to somehow be really bad for me to not read the third How could it be?
Speaker 0: I can meet people.
Speaker 0: some people said it's not good, but I can't imagine it being well.
Speaker 1: So the people I've who seem to have said that didn't really say it's not good.
Speaker 1: They said it's not Great, like it's not as good.
Speaker 0: Well, we'll see.
Speaker 1: but at the same time like I've read a lot of if I eat a Perfect steak and then I eat a steak.
Speaker 1: That's only 80% as good as that steak.
Speaker 0: That's still a good steak Yeah, but yeah I think this shows the the.
Speaker 0: all the hype that I heard for many moons.
Speaker 0: the moons about Jamison was true hype.
Speaker 1: So You see many moons.
Speaker 1: I feel like there's between zero and one moons remain.
Speaker 0: probably can't go wrong reading any other Novels by NK jemisin based on this one.
Speaker 1: I could definitely fall for that.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm For the opening.
Speaker 1: music can't leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Speaker 0: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 1: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 0: It's actually recorded at night.