Speaker 1: It's Wednesday July 12th 2017.
Speaker 1: I'm rim I'm Scott and this is geek nights.
Speaker 1: tonight We're back and we're talking about one of the most delightful anime.
Speaker 1: We've seen in a while eccentric family season 1 too many words.
Speaker 0: you could have just said Let's do this.
Speaker 1: It could be complicated though cuz season 2 is on like right now, and I'm actually halfway through it.
Speaker 1: It's real good and actually I was talking to Yuko and Judith both at Connecticut about season 2. they both said it is way more serious and probably better than season 1 and I'm really curious to see all that now.
Speaker 1: I really like season 1 a lot.
Speaker 0: Don't you save your talk about the main bit for the main bit all right?
Speaker 1: So you got any news about anime or animation comics?
Speaker 0: You're not even gonna talk about the Connecticut that we just went to.
Speaker 1: that was gonna be.
Speaker 1: I was gonna make that my news Good.
Speaker 0: the new news is ways the opening bit.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah opening bit, so I just biked home from work And it's like 88 degrees, and I'm sweaty cuz it's super hot out, and I biked real fast.
Speaker 0: I think it's kind of a little bit cold out right now.
Speaker 1: It actually got a lot chillier while I was biking home.
Speaker 0: It could be warmer.
Speaker 1: Yeah over lunch.
Speaker 1: It was like way hotter, and then it cooled off.
Speaker 1: But yeah, we were at Kinetic on and I was in London like the week before that and I was in Hong Kong not too long before that.
Speaker 1: so we've had a lot of Weeks where we didn't do shows and it's real hard to do a show the day after we come back from a convention.
Speaker 1: That's why Monday didn't happen.
Speaker 1: cuz I asked I also.
Speaker 0: I came home on my.
Speaker 0: you know I basically went to work straight from Connecticut Monday morning, so I was like I need to go home I can't spend another hour not at home and frankly I gotta go take care of my shit.
Speaker 1: well I could have said something like oh that means we won't do a show.
Speaker 1: what I thought in my brain was yes Fuck the show.
Speaker 0: I have no idea for a Monday show anyway.
Speaker 1: I do actually I want to do a show on AV tech in like panel rooms and halls and things like that.
Speaker 0: we done that.
Speaker 1: I don't think I did a Tentative search.
Speaker 0: video output goes to the video display thing.
Speaker 0: make sure the input is selected.
Speaker 0: audio output goes to the sound system.
Speaker 1: Go there's a few more components.
Speaker 0: You got some microphones mix them nicely.
Speaker 0: There's.
Speaker 1: there are a few more components to that.
Speaker 1: Anyway, also I saw I noticed some things people are having problems with and actually they have the right adapter.
Speaker 0: Also, we told everyone VGA, but all the rooms at HDMI.
Speaker 1: now They also had VGA, but people kept like kicking it under the table, okay?
Speaker 1: Well a lot of the rooms HDMI cables just stopped working and it looked like it's because they were just literally too long Mmm.
Speaker 1: They're all all those kinds of issues.
Speaker 0: I thought it was because people had adapters that like weren't any good.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it wasn't just the adapters.
Speaker 1: There's more to it than that anyway.
Speaker 0: So his is anime news ready crunchyroll the place where I watch 90% of the anime that I watch.
Speaker 0: that's new And one of the only I guess the video streaming service that I cancel the least because I've said this before But just in case anyone doesn't know my strategy is because you get Netflix.
Speaker 0: you got who you got crunchyroll.
Speaker 0: you get all these freaking shows out things out there and You know if you pay for any like.
Speaker 0: if you pay for Netflix monthly, it's like, okay This could be months where that's worth your money is me months.
Speaker 0: You don't watch Netflix at all.
Speaker 0: And what the hell did you just spend money on right?
Speaker 0: I feel the same way about Adobe.
Speaker 0: There's like months where I'll make three videos and months or I won't even edit a photo and it's just like I paid 50 bucks for nothing that month anyway.
Speaker 0: But you can't you have to do that yearly.
Speaker 0: You can't do it month to month with the Adobe thing easily, which is fine Cuz I'm using it literally all the times.
Speaker 1: I don't care.
Speaker 0: It just feels comforting to know that at any time I have the full power to edit any Sort of digital content.
Speaker 1: Yep and that comes in handy when I want to make a sudden meme out of nowhere and I need to like bust open any kind of Digital content video audio image website anything I have full power at a whim so that's worth paying for.
Speaker 0: but anyway.
Speaker 0: But video streaming services.
Speaker 0: if you pay for crunchyroll some month and you don't watch a single goddamn anime episode You just threw money in the fire like right but crunchyroll I use more than you know.
Speaker 0: Cancel Netflix.
Speaker 0: when I got no Netflix shows I cancel Hulu and I got no Hulu shows.
Speaker 0: I pretty much only subscribe to Hulu during South Park season but crunchyroll almost always on.
Speaker 0: so Crunchyroll is going down the path of the Netflix's and the Hulu's and the Amazon Prime's and that they realized hey You know just showing shows that someone else makes is pretty good, but to really get people to subscribe and pay We gotta make content that only we have.
Speaker 0: if we stream something that someone else has it's like all right.
Speaker 0: You know if we stream something that's like a temporary exclusive lice It's like people can wait it out and watch it somewhere else.
Speaker 0: But the reason all these people are making their own content is because that way it's like if we make something good You gotta pay us to see it.
Speaker 0: Otherwise the end is nowhere else.
Speaker 1: you will ever see it ever Yep, and also as soon as you own it You can do the kinds of things that a lot of licensers will not let you do sell merch.
Speaker 1: Look at look at Netflix with their offline mode.
Speaker 1: You'll notice that most stuff does not work in offline mode and the things that do work are the things that Netflix paid for themselves Right.
Speaker 0: So anyway Crunchyroll has partnered because obviously crunchyroll doesn't have anyone who can animate on their staff right there.
Speaker 0: But they partnered with NBC Universal Entertainment Japan Which I didn't even know existed.
Speaker 0: who is previously?
Speaker 0: they have previously produced animes such as fruit of Grisaia Starm you - I guess they didn't make starm you one.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I know starm you is.
Speaker 0: it's a Pokemon, right?
Speaker 0: Drifters, is that related to Tokyo drifters or is it different?
Speaker 0: Berserk that's an anime.
Speaker 0: I know that's a real anime the first real anime.
Speaker 0: Yeah, as seven mortal sins don't know what the hell that is, but I guess they can produce anime.
Speaker 0: They produce berserk, right?
Speaker 0: Okay So crunchyroll is partnering with them and they're going to produce anime that are yet unnamed.
Speaker 0: But we'll have international appeal, of course And then they're gonna put them on crunchyroll only and we're gonna watch them.
Speaker 1: it'll be interesting because this is kind of a big deal.
Speaker 1: but a big part of why Netflix is able to have so much success with this is their unlimited bucket of money.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm and NBC Universal Japan, I'm sure has money.
Speaker 0: also anime that you make in Japan and pay With slave animation labor is inexpensive.
Speaker 1: That is actually probably the biggest factor that if you just take the existing Like studio system in Japan and just pump money into it and Commission anime I feel like it'll be real cheap to make a lot of content But at the same time that does not actually help the people in Japan.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm I hope that you know.
Speaker 0: the one thing I hope that comes from this actually is that they make some Original anime and not anime based on manga or sequels to exist it, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Well, I think there's a real bigger issue here.
Speaker 1: Well not an issue but the idea of what is anime versus what is just animation is gonna get increasingly blurred.
Speaker 0: I mean people are arguing about this Castlevania show on Netflix, which I watched.
Speaker 1: I don't think anyone from Japan was super involved in like.
Speaker 0: no, it's not Japanese at all It's.
Speaker 0: it's.
Speaker 0: it's in English is the primary language.
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 0: It's not dubbed It's it.
Speaker 0: I mean it's dubbed in the way that dubbing means toss, you know voiceover But ADR style the original language of voice acting is English, right?
Speaker 0: It is made by an American studio and mostly and no not Japanese really right it.
Speaker 0: but it you know has a Visual style that is not often seen in things that are produced.
Speaker 0: You know, obviously anime comes in many different styles and you know animation comes in many different styles regardless of nation of origin.
Speaker 0: but the style of this is more like a lot of you know, generic not interesting anime styles and is not very much looking like you know a American, you know style animation.
Speaker 1: Well, I think what it'll be is that there was you know, the anime.
Speaker 1: Even though like we said there isn't really a particular style the kinds of shows and the things that came out of anime are going to start increasingly being adopted by just animation globally and the idea that something is anime because it came from Japan will be a lot like a Particular film movement like via our films from a certain era.
Speaker 0: Yeah well Todd we'll talk more about the Castlevania show.
Speaker 0: one's room watches it cuz only four episodes.
Speaker 0: it's like 20 minutes each.
Speaker 1: the next the only thing big nights.
Speaker 1: We will review it.
Speaker 0: But the only thing I want to say about it now is that when I was watching it It's like it was really the one thing that was really disappointing.
Speaker 0: the most disappointing about it was that it felt like It should have been.
Speaker 0: it was like leaning towards a Yoshitaka Amano style, but was so far away from it And obviously had no involvement with it whatsoever.
Speaker 0: that like I just really wanted like they just should have had him do it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I really just want an animated feature a new one.
Speaker 1: That is just his crap.
Speaker 0: Yep It's like they would have just hired Amano to do the arts on that show would have been like like the greatest thing ever.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so yeah the Castlevania thing is kind of a missed opportunity and I'm not gonna talk about it too much because like I said We're gonna literally review it on the next Wednesday show of geek nights.
Speaker 1: So this past weekend as you know, we were kinetic on which is not an anime convention.
Speaker 1: It is just a convention.
Speaker 0: It's a nerdy convention of all nerdy things comics tabletop games video games You know an amaze everything nerdy is there and there's very little like it out there.
Speaker 0: cuz most There's a lot of everything cons.
Speaker 0: They just a lot of them don't have the balls to call themselves everything con.
Speaker 0: Well, a lot of everything cons to are super tiny and a lot of it ain't that small and and they are not run as Well, it might be one of the better run everything cons that we know of.
Speaker 1: Yep, but we were there, you know We're.
Speaker 1: if you don't know we literally like run the entire panels department there And as always because we scheduled a whole bunch of panels and like random and had like the counts and everything I noticed a lot of interesting trends about Like what is popular and not now.
Speaker 1: and one thing I can say pretty definitively based on three years of trend data The pony fandom has all but vanished from the convention.
Speaker 0: No, I mean I saw plenty of pony action.
Speaker 1: keep pony action in that people will wear merchandise about my little pony.
Speaker 1: There'll be tons of art in the artist alley.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm, but there is almost no interest in attending Pony related panels.
Speaker 1: No, and there's almost no one submitting pony related panels.
Speaker 1: No, meanwhile, you know, it came back in a big way.
Speaker 1: I got a shit ton of Hetalia.
Speaker 1: ask a nation.
Speaker 1: submissions really gone for years.
Speaker 0: I only saw one Hetalia with my eyeballs, but I saw actually a big two scoops full of homestucks.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, there were.
Speaker 0: it wasn't like the homestucks back in the heyday But there were like two nice scoops worth of homestucks that I saw.
Speaker 1: but in terms of submissions like Hetalia submissions We're up in a big way.
Speaker 1: I think we're way down.
Speaker 0: I think the reason for that is.
Speaker 0: I don't think it has anything to do with the popularity of Hetalia itself.
Speaker 0: I think is that the Hetalia community is a community that knows how to submit panels.
Speaker 0: I think that is more so than other pet communities regardless of size.
Speaker 1: I think cosplay related panels.
Speaker 1: I got more submissions for that than literally anything.
Speaker 0: That's the biggest thing at the gun.
Speaker 1: But most of them still are.
Speaker 1: I am a cosplayer and and they don't really have anything going on in the panel.
Speaker 1: so the ones I scheduled were ones like I am a pro and here's a technique.
Speaker 1: or Here is some like real information on plus-size cosplay and like how to do it right and stuff like that like real technical panels.
Speaker 1: I'm not interested in how I make dozens of dollars with my youtube channel about cosplay photography.
Speaker 1: Nope But yeah, we ran our channels and what was really interesting is that Kineticon is one of those cons like Zenkai Con or like all the cons that are in a place Where the people who live in that place don't tend to travel to other conventions.
Speaker 1: that much Nope, so you'd have people for whom that convention is their first and or only Convention.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm meaning we being lazy take all the content We've run it like five packs is and just recycle it at like Zenkai Con and Kineticon.
Speaker 1: but when I ran for an anime openers, which is something I've run like years and years this everywhere I ran I pretty much filled the room and I think 90% of the people in the room.
Speaker 1: never heard of me never been to a Kineticon before But didn't have any idea about any of this stuff and I'll for a lot of them I'd say half the room.
Speaker 1: It was their first convention ever.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: So all I want to say is that that German Naruto shtick?
Speaker 1: I had to pause and rewind.
Speaker 1: people were laughing so hard.
Speaker 1: They could not believe it.
Speaker 0: Seen a German Naruto before they'd never.
Speaker 1: the the foreign anime openers concept was already pretty crazy.
Speaker 1: The Italian pony thing kind of kind of lost him.
Speaker 1: They were.
Speaker 1: I had to back up and replay parts of that because they were making so much noise.
Speaker 1: but uh, yeah, uh The other trends I see is that there are fewer and fewer anime related panels being submitted and more importantly Almost all the anime panels are people who have submitted them in the past And or who I see it.
Speaker 1: other kinds like anime Boston or like Charles Dunbar and No one seems to have any interest in talking about most recent anime.
Speaker 1: It's all panels about old anime submitted by people who are around our age.
Speaker 0: Maybe I'll do a eccentric family panel, huh?
Speaker 1: Like.
Speaker 1: I think I only have like 35 minutes of content though.
Speaker 0: Well now if we get a second season in there.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah Seasons do some research about.
Speaker 1: so here's how hell is portrayed in this painting and how that relates to.
Speaker 1: I could be a fun panel.
Speaker 1: Actually, hmm.
Speaker 1: I'm suddenly feeling a be like maybe we should make a new set of anime panels.
Speaker 1: Is that a recycling over and over again?
Speaker 0: I could do your pet old panel.
Speaker 0: Yeah I could do a big you off at open.
Speaker 1: The problem is the anime have the most to say about her.
Speaker 1: still the old ass anime.
Speaker 1: There's almost.
Speaker 0: I'll mostly talk about biking.
Speaker 1: Yeah But anyway things of the day.
Speaker 1: so remember that channel that we're a fan of.
Speaker 1: it's the woman who?
Speaker 1: makes Helper robots that are just awful Like they'll chop lettuce really dangerously with knives flying.
Speaker 0: Oh, I saw one just the other day.
Speaker 0: I don't know if it was this channel But it probably is.
Speaker 0: it was chopping a bread from the a loaf of bread from the top really poorly not.
Speaker 1: So this I just found this kids YouTube channel like ran it randomly and this clearly looks like a dorm room in a college campus.
Speaker 1: And basically he did a project where he used facial recognition technology to make a tiny robot and what that robot will do is Track any human face it sees and try to shine the laser pen in their eye And the video is pretty good because he tied.
Speaker 1: he talks a lot about like why he made it and how it seems like it's Gonna be a really good thing.
Speaker 1: but then he's you know, it's obviously like a school project and showing off the code and then he goes to demonstrate it and Literally he turns it on and he starts to talk and it gets him right in the eye and he's like, ah shit.
Speaker 1: And then he does the rest of the video trying to like Avoid it hitting him in the eye while he talks about how it works and it's way funnier than it has any right to be.
Speaker 1: Up there got him again.
Speaker 0: Just close your eyes, bro.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if you get hit in the eye with a regular laser pen and you close your eye, you can still see it.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm And the related videos to this seem to mostly be people making dangerous weapons with laser pens or Diodes, but this video is actually really funny and I laughed out loud.
Speaker 1: So So what do you got?
Speaker 0: Oh, so this is a illustrator based out of Tokyo that I follow on Twitter Because their arts are way awesome and they're called utomaru.
Speaker 0: I think they that Twitter account itself was the thing of the day way back.
Speaker 0: But anyway utomaru has been doing the album art for this idol person named Oresama for I think like a couple albums, right and Oresama, I guess it's just some generic J-pop idol person or whatever, right?
Speaker 0: Anyway, so Oresama now has like a Is.
Speaker 0: I got a major label now and they just had a new music video that came out just now And it's generic J-pop.
Speaker 0: It sounds like an anime opener.
Speaker 1: Yeah My brain is literally.
Speaker 1: I'm listening to it with Scott before the show and I'm like, oh this sounds exactly Like.
Speaker 1: and my brain is every anime opener ever not all of them all the ones from a certain era Sure Cuz you know.
Speaker 1: like the late 90s anime openers have a particular sound to them as opposed to like the mid 2000s anime.
Speaker 0: anyway, we don't we don't care about this song.
Speaker 0: What we care about is that utomaru's amazing illustrations are all over this music video.
Speaker 0: So just like watch the music video.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you've retweeted.
Speaker 1: I've seen you've retweeted this cat hour before.
Speaker 0: Yeah Just watch the video and you can mute it if you want and just you can see like so much Illustrations were done and put all over this music video.
Speaker 0: I guess the song is called that bat back there.
Speaker 1: It's a good bat.
Speaker 0: yeah, it looks like a drakey from Dragon Quest.
Speaker 0: yeah does but yeah, the song is called trip trip trip Whatever.
Speaker 0: and it has like this RPG theme kind of going on while also has like a vacation traveling theme combined.
Speaker 1: That could be a good manga.
Speaker 1: It's visually Stimulating like that's how manga you're reading at the beach that I gotta borrow and read about the people in the dungeon delicious and dungeon.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's alright.
Speaker 1: So in the moment the book of book is Frank Herbert's do not and we both read it and I got a lot to say.
Speaker 1: So the next Thursday episode of geek nights will be a week from tomorrow.
Speaker 0: Yes We're gonna talk from today.
Speaker 1: for most of you the geek nights book club is gonna talk about Dune which I had never read all the way through in my life until recently and To give you a preview of what we're gonna say about that book.
Speaker 1: It is way Simpler and more straightforward than the internet and people I have talked to over the years.
Speaker 1: that led me to believe I'm gonna even know the spoiler.
Speaker 0: Nowhere in the book do the words quote the spice must flow appear.
Speaker 1: Yeah, was that in the movie?
Speaker 0: It might be in the movie.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna have to go watch the movie I think so I could add it into the conversation.
Speaker 0: Well, I went and read even though I've heard bad things about the movie and I believe them but I gotta watch it anyway.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I could watch it.
Speaker 1: Now.
Speaker 1: What I really want to do is play the Dune board game again.
Speaker 0: I have played the food dude.
Speaker 1: I have played it, but I have not played it since I read Dune.
Speaker 0: Sure.
Speaker 1: Ah Never before has an intellectual property been applied to a game So literally and yet still been an actually good game.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm like.
Speaker 1: It's kind of amazing and I'm actually like legit shocked by that and I feel like we could do a whole episode on that Concept on a Tuesday.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm, cuz it's nuts.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm I feel like you could do the same thing with Game of Thrones But I don't know if anyone will because the Game of Thrones game is not that I played it.
Speaker 1: Of course.
Speaker 1: wasn't there a second edition that we didn't play?
Speaker 1: that fixed some issues?
Speaker 1: I don't remember.
Speaker 1: Hmm That was in our recess back when we used to go to those in the meta moment.
Speaker 1: other than the book club.
Speaker 1: We gonna pick the next book club book which we'll do at some point.
Speaker 1: I think Scott said he has an idea so I'm able to go with that If you do have an idea.
Speaker 1: if you listen to this because you her found us at Connecticut And you're somehow still listening all the way to this point.
Speaker 0: Whoa One what's wrong with you?
Speaker 1: I'm amazed that you figured out we do a podcast because a lot of our fans like seem to not realize that.
Speaker 1: Like we have fans on YouTube who don't know about the podcast and vice-versa.
Speaker 0: Even though you're now putting the podcast on YouTube It doesn't help.
Speaker 1: that is starting to help a lot.
Speaker 1: I see my seal.
Speaker 1: I've actually seen an uptick because I've been watching the Libsyn cuz.
Speaker 1: I'm trying to like now that I'm paying For it directly.
Speaker 1: I'm trying to tune what we pay for and tune my bit rates and all that stuff.
Speaker 1: But anyway, I've seen an uptick and I think they're starting to help in that way.
Speaker 1: I've also noticed something interesting.
Speaker 1: the Thursday shows get the most live streams.
Speaker 1: the Wednesday shows get the least live streams.
Speaker 0: Maybe this is because the day it might be.
Speaker 1: I don't know if it's the content of the day or what but If you found us at Connecticut and you wanna and you like want to know more about any of the panels.
Speaker 1: we did Little little fun fact to three of the panels that for four of the panels We did a Connecticut are already on YouTube from other conventions.
Speaker 1: And if you watch them on YouTube They're just better more polished versions of what we have as Lee did a Connecticut.
Speaker 1: So that's the secret And otherwise like you should follow all our stuff on the internet.
Speaker 1: Scott's YouTube channel has a lot of live streams like you were live streaming Like us running the panel's department at Connecticut.
Speaker 1: No, they're pretty interesting videos.
Speaker 0: I watched the one I was using.
Speaker 1: I watched the one with you and Kate and I watched the one of you walking around.
Speaker 1: they were entertaining.
Speaker 1: I was legit entertained.
Speaker 1: All right, I feel like we should do that more.
Speaker 1: I think we should live stream a random crap from conventions.
Speaker 1: We go to way more often because it totally works and like it's moderately entertaining.
Speaker 1: uh What else do we got?
Speaker 1: nothing really?
Speaker 1: I guess the only important thing is because a lot of you are emailing me about this or posting random comments.
Speaker 1: I'm like random videos on my channel about this.
Speaker 1: So one now the Connecticut and all that travel is done.
Speaker 1: We're resuming all the projects that were on hold.
Speaker 1: So the convention we're trying to start.
Speaker 1: we're working on that now.
Speaker 1: The utenna geek nights presents show.
Speaker 1: we're gonna put an episode up real soon.
Speaker 1: We're gonna produce it like I got my shit together.
Speaker 1: All those other like the game show all that crap we were talking about.
Speaker 1: We have time to work on that now.
Speaker 1: The only thing that will get in our way between now and October is that if it's really nice outside, we're not doing shit.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm and also the packs.
Speaker 0: the next convention is real packs.
Speaker 0: labor day weekend in Seattle I always forget until like cuz I'm always focused on my next summer when summer ends Real packs arise.
Speaker 1: I mean we've got to the point in our lives.
Speaker 1: It's kind of fascinating.
Speaker 1: the conventions We go to no matter what now are magfest Packs West packs East packs out packs Australia packs unplugged packs dev.
Speaker 1: There's there's a pattern there.
Speaker 1: Yeah Thank icon And we pretty much dropped almost everything else.
Speaker 1: we'll see Boston now that I'm inspired to do some.
Speaker 1: I only
Speaker 0: skipped anime Boston one time
Speaker 1: Yeah and I feel actually kind of refreshed by skipping it because this year was just a busy year that we might be able to bring an A-game to the next anime Boston because we're not missing good weather if we go to that.
Speaker 1: Mmm, but packs West is The packs and me and Emily are gonna be in Seattle for nine days.
Speaker 0: It's a lot of days.
Speaker 1: Yeah it is.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna be there for less days.
Speaker 1: Well, cause you don't go to pecs dev.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna arrive Thursday and leave Tuesday.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna arrive I think Monday Sunday night or Monday and then we're gonna leave like the following Tuesday.
Speaker 1: I think I'm gonna fly Delta though.
Speaker 1: I think it might be done with the jet blue.
Speaker 0: Mmm I already got jet blue tickets.
Speaker 1: so I want to say the majority of my flights to or from packs for the past few years have been late and I don't think I've been on a single late flight might have been and I was looking as I fly a lot and actually Jet blue.
Speaker 1: is this really like dropping in the on-time performance?
Speaker 1: Domestically and their fleet is aging pretty badly and the Delta tickets are actually cheaper.
Speaker 1: So We'll see.
Speaker 1: thing is if I do jet blue partly I got a ton of miles So I gotta like blow them all I get for free flights.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't know how many true blue points or whatever I looked never used my points.
Speaker 1: I've only yeah me there so I got a shit ton of points.
Speaker 1: Mmm, you know we could do though if I don't use them on packs Maybe we should just use them to go down to like Puerto Rico or something and like yes Let us go to a tropical place.
Speaker 0: No other reason then let's go to a tropical place.
Speaker 1: actually cuz I'm not the whole crew can do that But maybe like you made Emily's just do that like take a long weekend and just like pop down there use up all our miles.
Speaker 1: Let's do it.
Speaker 0: I'm actually I'm feeling that that's that's my idea.
Speaker 0: You're stealing my idea the idea that I keep saying and everyone else is me.
Speaker 0: Well, because not everyone every time every time it's like where do we go?
Speaker 0: I'm like, let's go to a place where the water is blue Why not like this guy could do both and everyone's like meh and I'm like, what is wrong with you?
Speaker 0: Let's go to a place where the water is so clear that you can see the fishies.
Speaker 1: Part of well The thing is that the thing about going to the Jersey Shore is that the place of the water is black.
Speaker 1: that place but all Our friends can go because there isn't the barriers to entry of taking a bunch of time off work and or flying and or like.
Speaker 0: Let's go to a place where our anime will be anime of our lives will become island episodes.
Speaker 0: Let us go the island episode.
Speaker 1: We haven't.
Speaker 0: let us go to that place.
Speaker 1: Actually, I'm uh, I'm looking for an excuse to go back to Costa Rica cuz I want to visit Emily's family down there.
Speaker 0: Cuz what color the water they got?
Speaker 1: Uh, it's it's colorless cuz you can see all the way to the bottom Even when you swim way out there.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and it's super except the only.
Speaker 1: the only drawback is if you go to give those beaches.
Speaker 1: The sand was so hot that if you tried to walk across the beach without sandals You would literally burn your feet to the point of blisters.
Speaker 0: I mean that happened even in Jersey.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah I remember running and feeling really bad about myself at Sandy Hook last year in the last trip we did.
Speaker 1: Also, I think I got a minor sinus infection from the bacteria in the water on our last Sandy Hook.
Speaker 1: So yeah, maybe some clear water might be a good idea.
Speaker 1: I don't have a problem.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I swam a lot more than you.
Speaker 1: I also got a bunch of water at my nose cuz I kept swimming underwater.
Speaker 1: But yeah, I'm just I'm feeling beaches.
Speaker 1: Maybe we should go to Sandy Hook this weekend.
Speaker 1: Mmm every weekend.
Speaker 1: Just keep going.
Speaker 0: It's a lot of money together.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm still looking at Airbnb's - maybe we can go down to like Jersey Shore but further north and just rent a house and we don't have to deal with you know Restrictions or people.
Speaker 0: why don't we at least go to?
Speaker 1: I mean at least go to Virginia Beach, which is nice thing Yeah, but it's way easier to just rent a car and just drive down the Garden State like an hour.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: So you might recall we do our judge anime by its cover.
Speaker 1: when we do go to anime Boston and stay tuned We might just start doing that as a YouTube show because I think it's really good And I also like doing it and it's shockingly low effort because we're not even allowed to research the shows.
Speaker 1: But one of the shows we reviewed based on one screenshot and a few sentences was the eccentric family.
Speaker 1: And now we've both seen the entire first season.
Speaker 0: I've seen about half of this.
Speaker 0: I could have swore you I've watched this a long time ago, but I'm re-watching it now.
Speaker 0: I just finished re-watching the first season anyway, because season two just came out.
Speaker 1: Season two is real good.
Speaker 0: I haven't watched even any episodes of season two because yet just yesterday I finished re-watching season ones.
Speaker 0: I've seen the entirety of season one two times very and once very very recently as in yesterday.
Speaker 0: So and I could have swore we did an episode about this show after only watching a few episodes.
Speaker 0: But I guess you didn't find it doesn't matter because we're an eccentric doesn't even show up in the back end.
Speaker 0: search Yeah, and we definitely have not done An episode on it.
Speaker 1: I'm pretty sure what happened is we might have completed We might have mentioned it like as we both watched a couple episodes.
Speaker 1: I think we just mentioned it in like the early part of an episode.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm, and that's probably it.
Speaker 1: so Sport knows we'll we'll save spoilers to the end and we'll warn you.
Speaker 1: So don't worry because season one alone does not really deserve a like Full final thoughts cuz it's not like Trigun where there's a lot.
Speaker 0: There's not a lot to say even though It's got a lot of eccentricities.
Speaker 1: Yeah Alright, this is my favorite show of last season like hands down Sure, cuz one punch man came out before that.
Speaker 1: Yes, it did.
Speaker 1: Uh, oh do I like this more than one punch man?
Speaker 1: I feel like.
Speaker 0: well, no, this isn't even a show of 20 of the last season.
Speaker 0: This is a show from years ago 2015.
Speaker 1: yeah, you're right.
Speaker 0: He's in.
Speaker 1: one is old season two is right now.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think I like this and here's neither season came out the same time.
Speaker 1: as one bunch I like this show and one punch man equally for very different reasons.
Speaker 0: No, I want one more.
Speaker 1: I think I like them equally.
Speaker 0: he who punches only once yeah, but bent and Sama and whatever.
Speaker 1: so the gist of this show is that it's set in modern-day Kyoto and It's based on a novel.
Speaker 0: The first novel came out 2000 something 2007 and then that first season of the anime covers the first novel.
Speaker 0: but then Another novel a sequel novel came out much more recently.
Speaker 0: So then they once that novel came out they guess they went into production with another anime.
Speaker 0: There's
Speaker 1: also a manga which I haven't seen even one screenshot from yeah
Speaker 0: Yeah, and it this seems like it's the kind of thing that was like made out of like, you know Just because and wouldn't be that popular but apparently was popular enough to like just make another anime.
Speaker 0: So well, I'm very happy that like people like this so much that they keep making more so.
Speaker 1: the gist of the story is that in modern-day Kyoto the beasts and creatures and mythology of Japan is Alive and well and it just continues to coexist alongside humans just like it did in ancient times, right?
Speaker 0: So there's a huge.
Speaker 0: the human society is perfectly normal But there's also like Tengu's and tanukis and these sorts of.
Speaker 0: you know Mystical things, you know and they're combined in the same place and it's sort of hard to tell right?
Speaker 0: is it's like on the one Hand?
Speaker 0: are these things?
Speaker 0: You know, is it like?
Speaker 0: do the people see these tonic ease and things?
Speaker 1: They definitely do occasionally because one of the a good a nice point of the show like a plot point.
Speaker 1: Is that one of the tonic II?
Speaker 1: Him and his dad one of their favorite things to do was he would shape-shift Into a particular tram that runs into used to run in Kyoto Yep, and just careen down the street scaring the ever-living shit out of drunk people late at night, right?
Speaker 0: So it's weird because on the one hand people can obviously See human beings can obviously see and interact with the Tengu's and the tonic ease and things like that because sometimes the tender good Tengu and tanuki are fucking dangerous to those humans.
Speaker 0: Sure.
Speaker 0: But at the same time like when humans talk it's like they don't seem to know that like tonic ease Transform and like they think tonic ease are just animals in the woods
Speaker 1: which makes sense because you know to a modern person else you in less than a tonic II like Middle by transformed in humans
Speaker 0: are having a festival and is like boats flying in the sky That are clearly Visible and they don't seem to be reacting or giving a shit.
Speaker 1: The show sort of sets up that like.
Speaker 1: there's definitely this like liminal separation between the worlds because a lot of times Characters go to a place.
Speaker 1: That's like a it's not.
Speaker 1: It's not a physical place in the same sense as like the rest of the area that they're in like they'll enter basically some sort Of like TARDIS like space all the time.
Speaker 0: But I just think it's really an interesting way of avoiding those sorts of questions like you know about the boundaries between the worlds By just sort of being like man, you know, we'll just we'll just do whatever is convenient scene to scene.
Speaker 1: It fits more with like.
Speaker 0: this is not sturdy pots.
Speaker 1: It fits more with my sensibility my understanding of like Japanese Sensibility toward mythology in that these are things that sort of exist on the edges of your perception Like you see something weird.
Speaker 1: Maybe that was a tonic II like you don't know.
Speaker 1: So it sort of fits into that like the humans who interact with these things.
Speaker 1: It is brief transient interactions that Startle or surprise them usually right?
Speaker 0: So anyway, it's called eccentric family and it's about this family of tanuki.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and they live in like a temple or whatever and they have powers to transform because they're tanuki.
Speaker 0: there You can do.
Speaker 0: they're in the little cute animal form But they also can turn into many other forms.
Speaker 1: The cute animal form is super cute and different.
Speaker 0: Yeah, different different tanukis have different amounts and varieties of transformation power, right?
Speaker 0: So the oldest brother can transform into a tiger and fucking bite the hell out of you.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but he's way high strong Little bait.
Speaker 0: the kid who's you know, I guess he's elementary school age.
Speaker 0: He isn't so good at transforming Electricity.
Speaker 0: Yeah, he has electricity powers.
Speaker 0: He can recharge his phone just wherever he is.
Speaker 1: season two.
Speaker 1: He keeps reading like books on Maxwell like he's gonna be dangerous someday.
Speaker 1: I think sure.
Speaker 0: But anyway, you have this family and the story is that their dad was like the best tonic II Into an entire fucking mountain to fool some Tengu who are super powerful.
Speaker 1: Yeah, cuz Tengu are.
Speaker 1: Tengu are like one step below gods in this world.
Speaker 0: So this guy was basically like the legendary god tanuki and this is his wife and and his idiot for idiot son.
Speaker 1: And he's also an idiot.
Speaker 1: Sure.
Speaker 0: You're all idiots as far as we can tell right, but this family especially Inherited the idiot blood from their godlike tanuki.
Speaker 1: He's a blood into four idiot types among his own combined his four children.
Speaker 0: you get him basically But you only have the four children left and they all have different aspects of him and the story mostly focuses on Isaburrow, yep.
Speaker 0: Oh, it's hard to remember all their names because they're all wide Japanese.
Speaker 1: I was the main kid and why?
Speaker 1: what I like the most is that and this sort of is a theme throughout the entire show It is very rare to see non-human characters in fiction who Legitimately are portrayed as having non-human sensibilities.
Speaker 1: Usually you see oh, it's animal people, but it's just people.
Speaker 1: but like the way these characters interact with magic and death and The things around them is very clearly and very specifically Non-human like what happened like oh, yeah dad messed up and the Friday fellows Just cooked him and ate him in a hot pot and like yasaburo is friends with one of the people who murdered his dad and Ate him in a hot pot because that's just a thing that happens sometimes.
Speaker 1: and Then this is sort of exemplified in this character because he's sort of like a laid-back lazy.
Speaker 1: Like my only goal in life is to just get into trouble have an interesting life yep, but as so he just will randomly be a girl for no reason just because like he doesn't really care like gender doesn't really Mean much to him and he's a tonic.
Speaker 1: Yeah, he don't transform into whatever.
Speaker 1: That's just what he can do.
Speaker 0: But yeah, the thing that I like a lot about the show also is that you know, he's the main character, right?
Speaker 0: But usually in an anime a stereotypical generic average anime The main character will always be sort of the character that doesn't have any character.
Speaker 0: They'll be sort of just a generic.
Speaker 1: Why would a room?
Speaker 1: Oh No is like the the perfect archetype.
Speaker 0: the main character is a generic Nobody and all the other characters are interesting and quirky and you care about them.
Speaker 0: But the main character is blessed a full metal Alchemist.
Speaker 0: right Edward Elric is kind of average adventure guy.
Speaker 1: But then you got King Bradley and you're like, what's his?
Speaker 0: do right, but all the other characters are really cool.
Speaker 0: or You know, what's another good example?
Speaker 1: Like almost any Rishi boyo almost milk toast boring, dude And everyone around him is like a crazy dangerous goddess.
Speaker 0: any mecha show The main pilot of the mech is boring generic person and all the other mech pilots and villains are totally awesome.
Speaker 0: So in this show, however There is no boring generic character.
Speaker 0: right every character is wacky and crazy and interesting.
Speaker 0: So It's like you care about all of them, right?
Speaker 0: I care about this main character.
Speaker 0: Usually the main character is the person you care about the least.
Speaker 0: I can't say I care about the main character the most But there's no characters.
Speaker 0: I don't care about.
Speaker 0: there's no characters.
Speaker 0: Like I hate and want to go away.
Speaker 0: Yeah It's like they're all you know, even the annoying bad guy brothers with your kaku and king kaku.
Speaker 0: Normally they would be super annoying like oh my god, they're basically Starscream one and Starscream -.
Speaker 0: Normally you're like get the fuck out of here, but actually it's like, okay, they're kind of funny, you know, they're not the worst.
Speaker 1: I love all their sisters.
Speaker 1: I was like, oh, there's such pieces of shit.
Speaker 1: But then if anyone else calls them pieces of shit She's like, hey don't make fun of my brothers.
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 1: but Non-human sensibilities so like the.
Speaker 1: The gist of the show like the core of it really is that this family is partly blood relatives and partly just friends of the family like the old Tengu who threw his back out and can't really Tengu around so much anymore.
Speaker 1: and They face the same sort of Nuanced and complex problems that real families do except everything is sort of twisted with this Weird fantastic element like the one.
Speaker 1: brother is depressed But the way that expresses itself is that he transformed into a frog to sit in the bottom of a well because he's depressed and can't face the world anymore.
Speaker 1: and yet he literally like forgets how to Unshift from being a frog and that is like a point of drama in the family.
Speaker 1: and the mom has like a deep phobia of Thunder and dad was murdered by these people who still live in the city and just hang out there.
Speaker 0: and There's kind of really complicated relationships with all the characters way more complicated than anything in Dune Yeah, and like even though you know, they have these sort of complicated relationships that are you know?
Speaker 0: It's like they just still like sort of hang out and talk to people.
Speaker 0: what's like.
Speaker 0: there was a. there was an episode where there's been ten.
Speaker 0: who is the human?
Speaker 0: who a Human who is abducted by a Tengu and got Tengu powers and she's real danger and she's ridiculously powerful.
Speaker 0: And she seems like she's evil.
Speaker 0: and I just like she's so mysterious like what's her deal?
Speaker 0: You don't even know and they don't tell you explicitly.
Speaker 1: the show is all about this sort of like Incidental storytelling, right?
Speaker 0: But then there's a part where like you Saburo Runs out of town for like a year long period of time to run away from her because she's so mad at him Theoretically, he's afraid
Speaker 1: she's gonna just kill him and eat
Speaker 0: him and now when she finally catches him It's just sort of like man.
Speaker 0: It's sort of like this really tense scenes.
Speaker 0: It's a tense episode.
Speaker 0: Well, it's because we're like what's gonna happen here.
Speaker 1: I don't know these characters like.
Speaker 1: it's a world.
Speaker 1: It's a fantastical world.
Speaker 1: So some of the characters like the the Tengu even the old one are Real dangerous to be around.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm like there's a moment where the Tengu goes on kind of a rampage later in season one and Like I feel like some of the people who are in those cars that were nearby might not have made it maybe
Speaker 0: But like they're just hanging out like, you know, there'll be ones like one minute They'll like be getting drunk with this dude and the next minute like they're running away from because he's so dangerous.
Speaker 1: So the problems and like the relationships are very much non-human and mystical But at the same time they evoke all the feelings that real families have with the real family drama Like, you know, you've got your brother who's depressed and you've got your other brother who's like running for office But he kind of sucks at it and he needs you to help him But you don't want to because you're busy with your own stuff.
Speaker 1: and then your old the friend of the family grandpa Who's in love with this woman who's actually really bad for him and all that kind of stuff like it's.
Speaker 1: it's real family drama But it's a bunch of tonic II and Tengu and the family drama is all tonic II and Tengu drama.
Speaker 0: The only thing that makes me uncomfortable in this show is the arranged wedding to the cousin which I guess if you're a tonic II you can get with your cousin, but They're in human form and that's kind of gross.
Speaker 1: I don't think that's so bad.
Speaker 0: That's so that is cousin fucking.
Speaker 0: not so bad Books array, but it in the books.
Speaker 1: rim says cousin fucking not so bad is arranged cousin marriages and things like that are not that uncommon Even today around the world.
Speaker 0: I'm saying that's not a good thing Even though it's true.
Speaker 1: There was like a sideshow recently that was talking about how actually the danger of cousin is way low.
Speaker 1: rim.
Speaker 0: I guess rim has some hot cousins.
Speaker 0: He's looking Also Who's in favor of cousin screwing?
Speaker 0: Not Scott?
Speaker 1: I point out a big part of that anti cousin romance the eccentric family.
Speaker 1: You know the the the shimo gamo family that we're talking about is like the the known idiot branch of like the greater family and their related family the Ebisugawa who are all they're like the more noble like they have real jobs and things family and there's sort of this weird fighting family Rivalry like.
Speaker 1: they're two Important bloodlines that are tied in ancient times and that was like an arranged marriage to combine them again.
Speaker 1: But then it broke up because the father was dead and there's a whole bunch of plot around that too.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm I liked out the girl cow.
Speaker 1: Oh, what's her name?
Speaker 1: There's just so the girl who was a cousin.
Speaker 1: Yeah, who was pledged to be married to ya Saburo Won't let him see her.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: He has never seen what she looks like and there's some great scenes.
Speaker 1: We're like, they're in a bathhouse like on opposite sides yelling at each other and fighting But she won't let him see her at any point.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm, but they're still friends.
Speaker 1: Like everyone's even the enemies are relatively friendly Except where there's a few points where there are some enemies who are not friendly.
Speaker 0: But that's right and they can go from being friendly to like.
Speaker 0: is this huge range of interactions between?
Speaker 1: Characters cousin marriage are legal and considered totally normal in Japan.
Speaker 0: in quotes in the chat great Sure, that's that rims moving to Japan to get with this Japanese cousin.
Speaker 1: But uh Yeah, I don't want to spoil anything cuz I mean the.
Speaker 1: really this is a review, right?
Speaker 1: You should just watch this show.
Speaker 1: It is one of the best anime to come out.
Speaker 0: Not only is the show Good enough to be worth watching.
Speaker 0: I won't put it as a plus anime.
Speaker 0: I'll just put it as a anime.
Speaker 0: It's not a legendary all-time show, but not only is it so great It's not animated like in a special way It's just well animated like the arts and the character designs especially are so good.
Speaker 0: You know between all the different forms the katana keys take and things like that and people are wearing different clothes and different scenes.
Speaker 0: It's like y'all.
Speaker 0: they put effort into this thing, right?
Speaker 0: It's never like.
Speaker 0: there aren't a lot of garbage animation mistakes and things.
Speaker 1: All those scenes were like Benton is dragging that one drunk guy around on the roofs.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like.
Speaker 1: they're all just deeply Japanese and beautiful.
Speaker 1: and if you've been to Kyoto it that is Kyoto like one.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, everything is just taken from actual real.
Speaker 1: No, like a lot of the places you see in the show like we've been there Yep, but the number one reason to watch this show is simply that it's unique.
Speaker 0: There's no animes like this besides this one that I can think of.
Speaker 1: not that we're good.
Speaker 0: Yeah, this is the only anime that is like this and that alone makes it worth watching even if it were bad.
Speaker 0: But guess what is good?
Speaker 0: So watch it.
Speaker 1: and season two is on crunchyroll and season one was re-added to crunchyroll.
Speaker 1: So you can get.
Speaker 0: season one was temporarily removed from crunchyroll, but now is back.
Speaker 1: So one annoyance though, they changed the translation direction in season two.
Speaker 1: Oh real.
Speaker 1: so they so like in season one the their dad.
Speaker 1: he had a title that nice a Mon Yep in season two.
Speaker 1: They actually just translate that literally to what to like tricksters I forget already.
Speaker 1: But it's like there's a set of Japanese terms that are translated literally and a set that are translated That are not translated and you just get like these Japanese.
Speaker 0: I mean philosophically it should be Translating to English, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, but in season two They saw that you're just used to seeing nice a Mon because they did a bad job in season one.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but now you don't know what they're saying.
Speaker 1: in season two Some words that were translated are now not and some words that were not translated are now translated.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and they also they'd stop calling the Friday fellows and call him the Friday Club.
Speaker 0: I Think actually I remember Friday Club seems closer.
Speaker 0: Well, no, I remember hearing with my ear.
Speaker 0: So yeah, the word club boo as someone was talking.
Speaker 0: So, I don't know where the Friday fellows part came from.
Speaker 1: Yeah I also really wonder what their deal is cuz it seems like it's just a bunch of schlubby humans.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it seems like that's the one scary old guy except for the scary old guy who seems to have some kind of power.
Speaker 0: It seems like it's just a you know a human meetup group that no different than like anything else on meetup.com like it's just some people who hang out and Making a hotpot once a year is just a thing they do and they don't have any sort of well
Speaker 1: Like when yasaburo is sort of trip forced or tricked into performing for them and he does a bunch of transformations And they don't seem to really understand that.
Speaker 1: that's legit real magic.
Speaker 0: No, well the get.
Speaker 0: then again, the old guy wasn't there at that time true The old guy who seems to know anything so besides Benton.
Speaker 1: Uh, the one thing I can say about that old guy is I noticed something.
Speaker 1: that old guy is the only person I have ever seen Benton in any way Respect.
Speaker 1: Yep, which implies that he is way dangerous.
Speaker 0: He definitely was the only person in the show Character in the show where you're like, whoa, that dude is actually evil bad guy or at least like dangerous.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like watch out for him.
Speaker 1: But you know, I keep saying subtle but the show is super subtle in that It has.
Speaker 1: it has a lot of really big funny moments and everything.
Speaker 1: It's just a great show all around but so much of the story and so much of the nuance is just sort of Like the show doesn't come out and tell you thing.
Speaker 0: Everything in the show is completely unspoken for anything that matters is like not said out loud.
Speaker 0: You know it just you have to watch it to understand and show.
Speaker 0: but it's not like.
Speaker 0: it's like easier to follow than like utenna.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but it's they don't.
Speaker 0: no one says.
Speaker 1: but utenna is like allegorical and obtuse on purpose to make these meta points.
Speaker 1: This show is just.
Speaker 1: it trusts you to be paying attention while you're watching it.
Speaker 1: Because if you pay attention you can figure out a good chunk of Benton's backstory.
Speaker 1: You can figure out a lot about why the family's the way it is.
Speaker 1: and I just really like Media that respect the audience to figure shit out on their own.
Speaker 1: and especially because the stuff you can figure out isn't super important You can enjoy it Even if you don't notice those.
Speaker 0: and knowing that it was originally novels I would really like for the novels to be Translated.
Speaker 0: a lot of stuff is always like light novels and like.
Speaker 0: I have no interest in those but like actual novel I want to read dead.
Speaker 1: So briefly I will say that not only the show great But I've watched half of season two.
Speaker 1: It is also great.
Speaker 0: It just keeps me sure it is.
Speaker 1: I've never watched any season two though season two has a lot more serious dangerous stuff a lot of jikoku like hell and Love me some hell and all sorts of nonsense starts appearing at a call doom guy get your hell problem.
Speaker 1: Oh my god rock us.
Speaker 1: All I'm gonna say no spoilers.
Speaker 1: here.
Speaker 1: a character Ends up in hell.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and Hell is great, of course it is.
Speaker 1: hell is like super great.
Speaker 1: Of course, I can't key taro's hanging out down there But you see the hell stuff it is.
Speaker 1: it is exactly what you Scott want it to be.
Speaker 0: It is so perfect demons dancing and having a good time that are all freaky Yeah, but also like no.
Speaker 1: seriously, this is hell.
Speaker 1: This is a good place.
Speaker 0: real bad people getting set on fire because they were so bad.
Speaker 0: They deserve it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but maybe not everyone there deserves also Satan's a total badass who loves metal.
Speaker 1: So, I guess That's it Like.
Speaker 1: we're gonna talk to a few spoilers because I don't want to talk about some like the whole season so you can come back After you've seen the show, so I don't know.
Speaker 0: I don't really have anything else to say.
Speaker 0: we want to spoil.
Speaker 1: All right, I won't spoil it.
Speaker 0: We already spoil some stuff.
Speaker 1: my favorite scene in season one is there's a trope that you've seen in some movies and TV shows but you know the trope where there's a bunch of characters with a bunch of plots and then They all end up in the same restaurant.
Speaker 0: You mean like snatch?
Speaker 1: Yeah, like snatch where everyone just happens to be in the same place at the same time when the car accident happened and then Everyone realizes what's going on and all hell breaks loose.
Speaker 1: That's kind of how season one ends and the scene with a bunch of tanuki Scattering.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm is one of the funniest things I've seen.
Speaker 0: We can make all the hot pods we want like that scene.
Speaker 1: I was laughing so hard during that scene.
Speaker 1: I like.
Speaker 1: I guess it's get like how when you like you watch a lot of anime that aren't that great you kind of forget What a great anime is like.
Speaker 1: and then you see a great anime again like when we were watching a bunch of crappy shows.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'm just watching like generic your pedal, which I'm not gonna stop watching.
Speaker 1: It's good, but it's not.
Speaker 0: it's not something That's memorable.
Speaker 1: watching cuz there's bikes in but then you watch like a random episode of Ava and you're like, oh shit Right and real anime exists.
Speaker 0: It's out there.
Speaker 0: Just doesn't come around too often.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so if you're looking for some great anime to watch you should watch eccentric family.
Speaker 1: It is so good.
Speaker 0: My favorite scene and part is the bathhouse.
Speaker 0: There's a whole episode.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there's a whole episode in a bathhouse and it's awesome.
Speaker 0: There's so much going on in that one.
Speaker 0: like almost most of the episode happens just in the bathhouse.
Speaker 0: There's that iron underwear that they had and they keep the iron underwear going.
Speaker 0: Yeah, all this stuff keeps coming back.
Speaker 1: You two pieces of shit you not on.
Speaker 1: did you not realize the failure of your underwear plan?
Speaker 0: the Fujin Raijin fan from the very beginning of the show comes back at the end of the show, right?
Speaker 1: There's also this song that'll play in the back cuz it does pretty good soundtrack.
Speaker 1: Like it's kind of nondescript doo doo doo doo doo That one.
Speaker 1: but no there's there's the one that's kind of jazzy that whenever it starts Shenanigans are about to follow and it's gonna be the tonic use fault Mmm, and that song you start to recognize it.
Speaker 1: cuz the season do they keep that up.
Speaker 1: stuff will be serious serious.
Speaker 1: And then the song starts playing.
Speaker 1: and the next thing, you know tonic explosion tonic everywhere.
Speaker 1: Mmm say I watch the show and Don't let the drunk.
Speaker 1: old Tengu drink all the port wine if the tea kettle that's letting your flying ship continue to fly Also needs port wine to keep flying.
Speaker 1: That is like the moral.
Speaker 0: they just bring more.
Speaker 1: part one they did and he drunk it.
Speaker 1: No You notice they had another box that was like behind a bunch of stuff and there's a shot where you see that that box is Also all drunk.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean they could have just brought yet another box.
Speaker 1: I get another but I think they brought twice as much as They needed three times as much.
Speaker 1: Like I feel like that.
Speaker 1: Tengu could literally drink.
Speaker 0: also, why is that guy hooked on port so much?
Speaker 0: doesn't he like anything?
Speaker 0: Well, he also likes us really really really long cigars Mmm, I mean if you're a Tengu fine, it's not gonna hurt you, right?
Speaker 0: If I and if I was some sort of mystical being I'd be doing all kinds of dangerous drugs and shit.
Speaker 0: I also enjoy the joy the sort of subtext that yes Alvaro is definitely like if I see someone smoking and I say man That's gross.
Speaker 0: Stop that shit.
Speaker 0: You're poisoning yourself to death and say actually no, I'm magical and this doesn't hurt me at all.
Speaker 0: I would say damn I'm jealous.
Speaker 0: I would do that if I were you.
Speaker 1: but that cigar is like more than a foot long.
Speaker 1: Listen if I saw someone who looked like him smoking a cigar that was a foot long I would I'd be more impressed than angry.
Speaker 1: Mmm.
Speaker 1: But I do also like the sort of really complex relationship specifically between the main character.
Speaker 1: Yes, Alvaro and Benton because He's afraid of her.
Speaker 0: She's dangerous.
Speaker 1: He's also kind of in love with her.
Speaker 1: He's also trying to like understand her and those are three different threads going on in his character And they don't resolve.
Speaker 1: they just continue to increase the tension that he has around her and season two keeps that going in a big way.
Speaker 1: Say I watch the show.
Speaker 1: It's great.
Speaker 1: I'm super hungry.
Speaker 1: So I think we're gonna have the show right here.
Speaker 1: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Speaker 0: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 1: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays and a comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 1: But unlike those other late shows It's actually recorded at night and the patreon patrons for this episode of geek nights are Ellen Joyce, Heidi McNichol Amanda Duchette and Thomas Hahn.
Speaker 1: mystacey.com.
Speaker 1: William Isenbroughs Jeremy Minor life and death and love and birth and peace And war on the planet Earth a genuine bonafide.
Speaker 1: like five six car monorail Nicholas Brando Captain Chinguacu see Rebecca Dunn the terrible secrets of space for two one creations over there is because we have a red base here.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's because Shervin von Horrell rare Laval James Avery white Rochelle Montano to Superboy.
Speaker 1: I paid five bucks to make rim say pickle sailor Vista Matthew Smith Don Schleich.
Speaker 1: It's art option.
Speaker 1: Joe Joe Joe star Sean Yeager Sam Cordray Clinton Walton Ren from New Zealand Ryan Perrin.
Speaker 1: and What's this layer of ozone?
Speaker 1: Brian's the droney Finn Chris mint give Chris Knox Daniel Redmond Sean Klein Chris Reimer and Thomas on Stay tuned also on the page around because we're gonna have a bunch of rimbly reviews and I got a bunch of rims rants all Around heuristics that are coming up real soon now that we're back from all this travel and all these guns.
Speaker 1: and now I leave you Somebody.
Speaker 1: Somebody once told me the world is gonna roll me.
Speaker 0: I ain't the sharpest tool in the shed.
Speaker 1: I ain't the sharpest tool in the shed.
Speaker 0: Somebody once told me the world is gonna roll me.
Speaker 0: I ain't the sharpest tool in the shed.
Speaker 1: Somebody once told me the world is gonna roll me.
Speaker 1: I ain't the sharpest tool in the shed.
Speaker 1: I ain't the sharpest tool in the shed Somebody.