Speaker 1: It's January 19th 2017.
Speaker 1: I'm rim Scott and this is geek nights tonight and the geek guides book club.
Speaker 1: Rebecca.
Speaker 1: finally Rebecca Let's do this.
Speaker 0: Well you seem to like my recommendations lately.
Speaker 0: maybe you'll take like I suggest.
Speaker 1: I got some books I want to do anyway.
Speaker 0: So Emily was just cleaning out some stuff in the kitchen and she found some old wasabi powders.
Speaker 1: She was like when is this from guess?
Speaker 1: and I'm like few years.
Speaker 0: She's like beacon yeah Seven years old almost as old as podcast.
Speaker 1: It's amazing cuz you know it was probably old ish even in beacon and it's one of the because I packed some kitchen stuff and like Brought it when we moved.
Speaker 1: so I guess we brought.
Speaker 0: so I got home from magfest and I go over you know I'm sure and usually when I leave to go somewhere for more than two days.
Speaker 0: I always clean the hell out everything Right.
Speaker 1: so in the very least I do a quick check at the fridge of.
Speaker 1: is there anything that'll be rotten by the time I Get back exactly?
Speaker 1: and is there?
Speaker 1: is there anything in my garbage bag?
Speaker 0: so I go over and you know I got back from magfest And I go over to the corner get a banana Because I just bought some banana on the way home to put it right because I obviously got rid of all the banana And I noticed is like some goop heart sticky goop on the counter that was not there when I left.
Speaker 1: oh I get terrified when that happened.
Speaker 0: It's sort of in between the toaster in the fridge And it's sort of brownish like like what the hell is that?
Speaker 1: what did you find another banana?
Speaker 0: What the hell is it?
Speaker 0: could it could have been banana juice?
Speaker 0: I've been potato.
Speaker 0: it could have.
Speaker 0: who knows what it could have been.
Speaker 0: I'm like what the hell is that?
Speaker 0: where did it come from to come inside the toaster?
Speaker 0: was it like they come from inside the somehow the top of the fridge?
Speaker 0: So my god, I guess it came from the cabinet, but like the cabinet is full of dry goods How could it come from the cabinet?
Speaker 0: so I opened the cabinet, and then I realized what had happened.
Speaker 0: I?
Speaker 0: Don't know which can.
Speaker 0: it was oh a can exploded Botulism.
Speaker 0: I don't know what happened, but one of the cans of stuff was no bueno and I realized I've never had that happen in my entire life.
Speaker 0: I never seen that happen ever.
Speaker 0: I didn't think it could happen.
Speaker 0: So I looked at the cans and like many of them were goopy, but none of them were like broken obviously right.
Speaker 0: yeah I think it might have been this black bean can because it was at the top.
Speaker 1: How old were the black beans?
Speaker 0: all of these cans were probably beacon old?
Speaker 0: And I realized why the hell am I keeping any of these cans?
Speaker 1: and clearly haven't used them in all this time.
Speaker 0: I haven't used these cans and all these years.
Speaker 0: I'm not going to use them.
Speaker 0: their best buy dates are long fast gone.
Speaker 0: they're probably still edible, but I Haven't used them, and I've never think to use them.
Speaker 0: Why do I have at least perishable things?
Speaker 1: they hit this point of no return?
Speaker 1: We were like.
Speaker 1: this is an edible.
Speaker 1: I know it.
Speaker 1: I can feel safe throwing away.
Speaker 1: If you look at a can you're like it's still technically good.
Speaker 0: So I have to clean my cabinet, but I also reclaimed a bunch of cabinet space.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so as a win-lose situation.
Speaker 1: So this is the geek nights book club.
Speaker 1: if you're not familiar you should go check out the other book club.
Speaker 1: But things but the.
Speaker 0: it's about reading.
Speaker 0: you should read books because you're an intelligent person and not one of those people who says I don't read which means you're a bad person I have no respect for cuz I have to say we've had friends who used to not read and you know what.
Speaker 1: when they started Reading they got a lot smarter right?
Speaker 0: so if you don't read read, and if you do read You don't got to be told to read.
Speaker 0: But it's fun to read a book that other people also read like case in point and talk to them about it.
Speaker 1: It's nothing books.
Speaker 1: I like them a lot But the only reason they're so like weirdly dear to my.
Speaker 0: if I couldn't make a joke about you know breaking horses Why would I read that book?
Speaker 1: what do you see?
Speaker 0: yeah if I was all alone They would just be horrified.
Speaker 1: But it was because a bunch of our friends all read that book at the same time by accident And then another bunch of our friends all read the book at the same time thus Rekindling the purpose and then we kept these embers going.
Speaker 1: there's something fun about consuming media altogether.
Speaker 1: So you can have that like don't worry about spoilers like have a real conversation about a thing that you're all familiar with.
Speaker 0: so we're Suggesting a book for you to read that you know is gonna be good And we read it together and has a fun time.
Speaker 1: so we read Rebecca the novel that the famous Alfred Hitchcock movie is actually really closely based on.
Speaker 0: right.
Speaker 0: so I had you know I love me some Alfred Hitchcock movies and This is you know rear window is like my number one favorite movie.
Speaker 1: We know so good.
Speaker 0: It's the best movie.
Speaker 0: There is and Rebecca was like the second.
Speaker 0: it was not the second best movie there is but the second best Hitchcock movie.
Speaker 1: If you ask me yeah It's tough though because I like some of the like older weirder ones like that like the spy ones from his earlier career I mean, but they're not.
Speaker 1: yeah, I mean like they've got problems, but like the Lady Vanishes is pretty great.
Speaker 0: It's a good movie, and I mean there's not a lot of bad ones or anyway.
Speaker 0: So I did not know until recently that It was based on a book even though when you watch the movie the first thing it shows on the screen is based on the book by.
Speaker 0: I Did not know that and as soon as I found that out I said Oh, I guess that's my book club Vic and so it was Daphne du Maurier If nice French lady, so this is extra weird because I when Scott said this is gonna be the book.
Speaker 1: I wasn't sure if I had seen the movie Rebecca or not.
Speaker 0: I have only seen it like two times in the past and it was long ago, and I rewatched it after reading the book and You know The memory of it is like now all tangled up.
Speaker 1: Oh even worse.
Speaker 1: so I wasn't sure if I'd seen the movie.
Speaker 1: I was pretty sure I'd seen it.
Speaker 0: I had a hundred percent definitely seen the movie.
Speaker 0: I was not wrong like oh like you were.
Speaker 1: but here's the problem.
Speaker 1: I saw a lot of these movies when I was very very young because my mom was really into gothic horror.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well the movie is made in what like 1940 something We were born in 1980.
Speaker 1: so my age was definitely single digits when I saw Rebecca And I conflated it with this other movie picture mommy dead.
Speaker 0: We're not even close.
Speaker 1: Actually There's a bunch of it hits a lot of the same notes to where you could see like aesthetically why they could be.
Speaker 0: it's black and white and it's old.
Speaker 1: yeah, but Reading Rebecca After I got about a third of the way through it like I suddenly like very vividly remember seeing a scene I'm reading in a movie, and I remembered all these sit like the scene where mrs.
Speaker 1: Danvers is trying to convince her to kill herself like I suddenly was like oh shit the skull-faced lady.
Speaker 1: I remember this movie.
Speaker 1: Oh my god.
Speaker 1: So I remembered all these scenes But I couldn't quite link them together.
Speaker 1: And then I sort of remembered the movie in the course of reading the book.
Speaker 1: and then now I want to watch the movie again.
Speaker 0: You didn't watch the movie again.
Speaker 1: I didn't watch the movie again.
Speaker 1: Oh, I did because I wanted to make sure that the book reading was as little polluted by the movie as possible.
Speaker 0: I just watched.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna tell you all the things when we do this episode that are different in the movie.
Speaker 1: yep But last warning we're gonna spoil both of them, so I hope you've read the book.
Speaker 1: otherwise We're gonna assume that you read it.
Speaker 1: We're not gonna explain to you what the hell this book is about.
Speaker 0: well one other thing is that you know this People talk about like gothic romance like gothic.
Speaker 1: This is like the gothic horror fiction.
Speaker 0: It's like, but it's like.
Speaker 0: I did it.
Speaker 0: you know I'm not gonna lie I didn't really a hundred percent understand what that means.
Speaker 0: like.
Speaker 0: what does it mean like gothic?
Speaker 0: It's like.
Speaker 0: this is nothing to do with goth kids You think about that kind of goth?
Speaker 1: Before not before I read the definition of gothic stories and like all this stuff.
Speaker 1: Here's what I always imagine there's going to be a fancy masquerade of some kind.
Speaker 1: yeah There is.
Speaker 1: there are dramatic moments where people are introduced and stuff happens.
Speaker 1: there are scenes and gardens around a manor house And it's spooky and it's night sometimes right.
Speaker 0: so what it would it mean?
Speaker 0: It's basically a collection of you know certain tropes that make something gothic.
Speaker 0: so it's basically like vaporwave Spooky mansions right like you think about the movie Beauty and the Beast.
Speaker 0: right don't go to the West Wing.
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 0: It's like that's where Rebecca's hanging out right exactly.
Speaker 0: It's like Beauty and the Beast is a gothic romance kind of thing.
Speaker 0: or like you know any kind of Edgar Allan Poe Action right where it's like oh, he's in the spooky house, and there's the Raven right and it's like whoo.
Speaker 0: So if it's also a tale of romance it usually includes You know medieval kind of theming.
Speaker 0: you know like hint even if the medieval stuff was way in the past.
Speaker 0: Right you know that kind of stuff.
Speaker 1: or like you know here's a more modern take.
Speaker 1: so there's a. there's a sub-genre that I did Know about because again my mom was really into it.
Speaker 0: southern gothic Which is basically set in the American South right instead of being in a European castle is in like you know a big old plantation House.
Speaker 0: yeah, but it's the same kind of thing like.
Speaker 1: I think the best example of this is probably Midnight in the Garden of Good And Evil which is a fantastic I've heard of.
Speaker 0: you never seen it Maybe but I don't remember.
Speaker 0: it is also based on a book.
Speaker 1: okay We could do.
Speaker 1: this is the next book club to stick with a gothic theme for a while.
Speaker 1: But the movie it's your pick Men in the Garden of Good and Evil was the first movie I saw that featured Kevin Spacey where I was like god damn that guy's a good actor.
Speaker 1: Like I just like that movie.
Speaker 1: Later.
Speaker 1: actually I think I saw this first fun fact.
Speaker 0: I saw the usual suspects for the first time in chemistry class.
Speaker 1: Nothing better to do But it is a gothic tale, and it is like it is that to a T. It is like you know that vaporwave video.
Speaker 1: that is like yeah, that's vaporwave.
Speaker 1: Look at this movie or this book and like yeah, that is a gothic romance.
Speaker 1: So the only question I have for you the listener What is the main character's name?
Speaker 1: Because it is not said at any point in the novel or the movie.
Speaker 0: no well it is it's mrs.
Speaker 1: Dewan's doing sir, but what was it before she got married?
Speaker 1: It was just mrs.
Speaker 0: Miss something the girl who is hanging around the fat old kind of horrible lady Well, I mean almost the entire thing is is from her mrs.. Dewan's perspective.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right, so it's not.
Speaker 0: it's it's me Right.
Speaker 0: it's or her or you know I?
Speaker 0: yeah, not her right It's I or me because it's from her point of view almost everything that happens.
Speaker 1: much very Stark and made.
Speaker 1: I think that is one of the big tone differences.
Speaker 0: So you know like you don't say your name right if I'm telling a story.
Speaker 0: I'm never like oh Scott.
Speaker 0: Did this yep, right?
Speaker 0: I'm only gonna say my name if I have to narrate the dialogue of somebody talking to me and that person is gonna say mr.
Speaker 0: Ruben.
Speaker 1: well We also know it was intentional because I'm because the author apparently had to continuously respond to Fan letters saying why did you do this?
Speaker 1: and she would always say that she thought it was an interesting technical device And it was very much intentional and it served a purpose Independent of it kind of making sense looking at the book being from the perspective of mrs.. Dewan sir mm-hmm I really like the book, but I was I guess Startled by the difference when you find out in the middle that he just fucking shot Rebecca.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like that.
Speaker 1: then literally I was reading the book and I was like all right.
Speaker 1: kind of remember this kind of remember this.
Speaker 1: and then He's tells his wife like oh, yeah I killed her and I literally stopped reading like wait what?
Speaker 0: no you didn't know that was happening.
Speaker 1: I didn't know that he murdered her.
Speaker 1: It's an Alfred Hitchcock Thing Memory from the movie of her like falling down the stairs or something now.
Speaker 0: so in the movie actually right because that's the thing right.
Speaker 0: so You sort of have this dual situation going on where you know the story is being told from the perspective of Mrs.. Dewan sir.
Speaker 0: right and you're sort of on her side like she's the good person.
Speaker 0: and you know mrs.
Speaker 0: Danvers and Rebecca they're evil from the the dark right.
Speaker 0: it's like they're the ones who are bad.
Speaker 0: right and Mr.. Dewan sir is like he's sort of mysterious, but he's you know he's still good right?
Speaker 0: it's just you know he's not enough information coming out of him to get the whole story, which is what makes the story work and You sort of her on the side of you know mr.
Speaker 0: And mrs.. Dewan sir and against Danvers and Rebecca.
Speaker 0: yes, right.
Speaker 0: And then it's like oh, no actually we shot Rebecca.
Speaker 0: And if you read the book Based on who you are as a human being in the real world if you're me suddenly you're like oh Well, I mean mrs.. Danvers is a little creepy.
Speaker 0: Rebecca was totally fucking awesome.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you got your piece of shit who murdered her.
Speaker 0: But then it was like I would like to.
Speaker 0: and now you're evil.
Speaker 1: But at the same time it also sort of twists in that I mean you don't that the thing is.
Speaker 1: a big theme of this Book is that you don't know what other people remember have experienced have been through.
Speaker 1: you don't actually know their perspective If you only know by communicating with them.
Speaker 0: right well because your first half of the book because it's for the perspective of mrs.
Speaker 0: Dewan sir And she doesn't ask about anything that happened before so she's just filled with like her Assumptions about the past of like this world that she's entered.
Speaker 1: But not just that she's filled by like her perceptions of everything like your half the first the entire first half of the book is her Sort of fantasizing about what might be happening, and she's sort of like.
Speaker 0: she doesn't know anything.
Speaker 0: And it's also she's guessing and she's guessing assuming the worst.
Speaker 1: yeah, she always seems the worst.
Speaker 1: It's very like depressive Ideation of like.
Speaker 1: oh well they must hate me.
Speaker 1: everyone thinks.
Speaker 1: I'm horrible everything I must be so bad.
Speaker 0: It's a good read because I know people in the real world who think that way.
Speaker 0: it's a very common sentiment.
Speaker 0: But and even people in the real don't think that way all the time think that way some of the time, right?
Speaker 0: It's like you don't know if someone likes you or not.
Speaker 0: So you think they must hate you, but then the big reveal.
Speaker 1: one of the big reveals now even more so I think than the murder is When mrs.
Speaker 1: De winter reveals to her husband that she thinks he doesn't love her and that he's still in love with Rebecca.
Speaker 0: Why didn't you have the balls to say anything about that earlier?
Speaker 1: But then he turns around and reveals that he assumed completely different things about her like his.
Speaker 1: Imagining about her motivations and her desires and her happiness was also a hundred percent off.
Speaker 1: He was looking at her actions from his assumptions and making this really wrong conclusion.
Speaker 1: She was looking at his actions from her assumptions making this really wrong.
Speaker 1: They were both like a hundred and eighty degrees away from the reality of each other's situation.
Speaker 0: Now usually this is one of those cases where it's like if only you would have just said something Everything and it's like one of the usually when that happens in a story.
Speaker 1: It's like a bad story.
Speaker 0: It's it's just bad.
Speaker 0: It's like oh if only you had just talked you could have sorted this out from the beginning, right?
Speaker 0: It's like he would have been happy to tell you he wouldn't have told you he murdered her But he would have told you that he didn't like Rebecca.
Speaker 0: but he assumed you're on the start.
Speaker 1: He assumed you were aloof and unhappy and he thought like he thought you heard like he was like.
Speaker 0: well this marriage doesn't go Right, but you could have discussed that when you're still in Monte Carlo and you would have at least known He hated Rebecca and not been all insecure her all this time.
Speaker 0: However There's a really good reason.
Speaker 0: they didn't say any of these things to begin with and that's because they have this plot device of.
Speaker 0: she Thinks perhaps correctly, so he doesn't want to hear about Right.
Speaker 0: You want to talk to someone about their dead spouse?
Speaker 0: That's really uncomfortable.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right You don't like.
Speaker 1: you want to bring that up like one of the most tense scenes in them in the book.
Speaker 1: is when?
Speaker 1: She chases the dog off to that like Marina house in the cove.
Speaker 1: Yeah Cuz the whole like.
Speaker 1: the whole description is.
Speaker 1: he is like I don't want to go over there and he's obviously like really freaking out.
Speaker 0: It's he doesn't want to be reminded of Rebecca.
Speaker 0: so from your perspective knowing that you know, this guy's wife died.
Speaker 0: It's like you're trying to avoid that topic as much as possible.
Speaker 0: But you're also need to know what happened in the past to lose your insecurity.
Speaker 1: that scene is tense because you the reader pick up on the fact that max is really uncomfortable.
Speaker 0: and Well, I mean, but it's understandable his wife died there.
Speaker 1: Well, mrs De Winter who doesn't have the same knowledge that we have as the reader like we can see a lot more because we're sort of this Perspective.
Speaker 1: she sort of is putting that all of her head and is focused on just like chase after the dog.
Speaker 1: She's not thinking about it.
Speaker 1: So you see her going headlong into this and meanwhile all the descriptions around it are just setting this really ominous tone To where you're almost afraid about what she's gonna find in there Like you have expect to find a body in there in that early scene.
Speaker 0: Well, there's also a creepy guy right the creepy guy down by the beach Yeah, who basically to me, you know, he's not as significant a character, but he feels a lot like Boo Radley.
Speaker 1: Right, it's always like that weird mysterious guy who knows up something, you know the things he'd say right, but he was interesting because When you first meet him, she has this perception of him in a certain way.
Speaker 1: but was it Frank?
Speaker 1: someone says and during the book that he's not nearly as in like Incapacitated as he lets on incompetent.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like he he is way more together than he is acting Yes, and different people have different perceptions of his capabilities Which again is like that's the driving theme of this book is you can't know you only know what people say.
Speaker 1: So when max tells the story of how and why he murdered Rebecca It's a weird situation where like yes, you shouldn't have murdered her.
Speaker 1: But you also understand sort of if everything he said was true why he would have because he's a piece of shit.
Speaker 1: Ah, but this so think about a play devil's advocate from the perspective of society at that time.
Speaker 1: She basically threatened to cuckold him or ruin his life did well well Did she didn't actually have a child?
Speaker 0: I guess not.
Speaker 1: and the fur the final revelation at the end like knowing at the end that she just had cancer and couldn't have Had a child.
Speaker 0: Mmm.
Speaker 1: It is implied that she was trying to get him to kill her.
Speaker 1: Mmm that that was suicide by max sure but at the same.
Speaker 1: but but he she was basically threatening.
Speaker 0: Right, but there's this whole right.
Speaker 0: The book tries to convince you that like Rebecca was somehow a bad person.
Speaker 0: But actually she was just a fucking Incredible person right?
Speaker 0: It's like she was partying.
Speaker 0: She was getting it on.
Speaker 0: Yeah, she could run that mansion like nobody's business.
Speaker 0: Oh, she's only.
Speaker 1: she knew she could decorate way.
Speaker 0: Awesome.
Speaker 0: It's like she was just like this awesome incredible person.
Speaker 0: You're like everyone loved.
Speaker 0: it's like so.
Speaker 1: did the conversation that him and Rebecca had and Monte Carlo Take place the way max remembers it?
Speaker 1: did she at the beginning of their marriage say listen I fucked you and now I own this shit and I'll blackmail you so you got to play along or I'll ruin everything?
Speaker 1: Well, you know that happened as said or is this again?
Speaker 1: Is this all max?
Speaker 1: reading into things and being jealous or is it max?
Speaker 1: because he obviously lives in this world of High society at that time in place where Rebecca's actions in that perspective are seen as abhorrent and unforgivable?
Speaker 1: Cuz they're too managed even though in a modern sense Rebecca would be seen in a much more modern and positive light Unless she was literally blackmailing him.
Speaker 0: Well, I mean, you don't really know it's a very, you know, it's a sexist kind of issue, right?
Speaker 1: You know, it's like but it's complicated on the fact that we don't need.
Speaker 0: the name of the mansion is Manderley and that's not an accident right?
Speaker 0: is?
Speaker 0: you know?
Speaker 0: Manderley is the land of men.
Speaker 0: Well, it's a patriarchy like it's a Ancestral home and Rebecca was max and Rebecca was running that shit and she wasn't no man Right, and that's how Max couldn't stand for that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but at the same time she may have been running it under Very dubious pretenses.
Speaker 1: Hmm But again, we can't know because we only have one perspective and that is mrs De winters.
Speaker 1: max's perspective is his telling of what happened.
Speaker 0: You can go by mrs.
Speaker 0: Danvers story of what Rebecca is like, right?
Speaker 0: She's awesome.
Speaker 0: So in the novel you definitely understand versus fitting is mrs Danvers, even though like she may be right in that Rebecca was way awesome, right?
Speaker 0: Miss Dan, it doesn't help your perspective because mrs.
Speaker 0: Danvers herself even is obsessive and insane, right?
Speaker 0: She's like the lady in perfect blue spoilers.
Speaker 0: Yep, right It's like all these characters.
Speaker 0: obviously these characters were here first, right?
Speaker 0: You could.
Speaker 0: it's the other way around right?
Speaker 0: It's like keep saying like Oh to kill a mockingbird came way after this.
Speaker 0: I'm pretty sure it did.
Speaker 1: This is published in 1938, right?
Speaker 0: I'm pretty sure to kill a mockingbird is a newer book and I'm a hundred percent sure perfect blue is newer 1960s.
Speaker 1: the yeah, right.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so there you go.
Speaker 1: Yep, but so mrs.
Speaker 1: Danvers Based on the book.
Speaker 1: I am convinced that Rebecca was bisexual and straight-up seduced Mrs.
Speaker 1: Danvers at some point probably to draw her into this sort of sapphic fascination.
Speaker 1: So she basically made mrs.
Speaker 1: Danvers her.
Speaker 0: Yeah, Rebecca was also super good at sailing.
Speaker 0: Yeah, all kinds of others.
Speaker 1: She basically had mrs.
Speaker 1: Danvers wrapped around her finger like she like she had her she was a thrall.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean mrs Danvers like took care of her since she was like small right.
Speaker 1: so according to some of the liner notes in this book for this Book in the movie that had to be toned down because one of the rules of I guess the brain Commission is you weren't allowed to show lesbian Romance in cinema.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: No stop.
Speaker 0: So a lot of.
Speaker 0: so.
Speaker 0: the movie is like Surprisingly close to the book while also key.
Speaker 0: things are different, right?
Speaker 1: He didn't technically murder her because you're not.
Speaker 1: you weren't allowed to show his spouse murdering another spouse.
Speaker 0: I don't know if that was about being allowed But it was more like look if we show if that's the story in the book in the movie, right?
Speaker 0: Nobody's gonna go for that.
Speaker 1: There appears to have been a censorship rule.
Speaker 1: It's where you weren't allowed that the liner said something that the fact that it's possible.
Speaker 0: But also it's just like you couldn't if you put that in a movie, right?
Speaker 0: Nobody would go for that.
Speaker 0: They'd be like, whoa, what?
Speaker 0: No, they would turn on right?
Speaker 0: It's like you can't have the main character suddenly become the bad guy Like people would be hating the movie and throwing tomatoes at the screen or whatever right, you know, so yeah though again.
Speaker 1: So it's interesting to look at also To kill a mockingbird again.
Speaker 0: The thing ends with like court scenes In court with judges and shit, right?
Speaker 0: It's like come on Yep So the plate the movie the both of the movies actually those scenes are very similar in the way they play out.
Speaker 1: So an interesting aspect of that moment too of when he reveals to mrs De Winter that he murdered Rebecca is that from that point forward like the whole time?
Speaker 1: our main character is unsure of herself and Basically never takes decisive action on anything and second guess is literally everything.
Speaker 1: And then from that moment on she's just like all right.
Speaker 1: Well, let's cover the shit up Let's go like do this.
Speaker 1: and this is like she starts Consoling him and giving him the stone-cold advice of a professional.
Speaker 1: to go back to master Keaton.
Speaker 1: This book has that theme again be like the master versus the professional.
Speaker 1: So like she was a normal human being she was young and naive But that's also what made her interesting.
Speaker 1: But she didn't realize that and even max notices that as soon as she started acting the way she you know Quote should have acted from his perspective.
Speaker 1: Suddenly he's like wow, you've changed your old now.
Speaker 0: Well, cuz suddenly your eyes suddenly Rebecca's ghost wasn't haunting her anymore, right?
Speaker 1: But then to to to kill Rebecca's memory.
Speaker 1: she basically had to become to some degree Rebecca.
Speaker 1: She had to fall into in the movie.
Speaker 0: it's even more that there's a scene in the movie that I don't think is in the I don't remember being in the book where she goes into the morning room right and there's all like Rebecca's stationery with the letter R on it on the table and He tells mrs.
Speaker 0: Danvers like throw all this shit out and she's like, oh, but these are you know, you know Mrs.
Speaker 0: Dewinter's things and she's like, I'm mrs Dewinter.
Speaker 1: now she has a dream where she basically does that at the very end of the novel in the car ride back, right?
Speaker 0: No, but in the in the movie That's a scene where she's like, yeah miss Danvers making you throw Rebecca shit out But she like looks in the mirror and it's like sort of sees Rebecca there because she you don't know what Rebecca looks like.
Speaker 0: You get descriptions of it You don't know.
Speaker 1: but she on one hand is afraid of Rebecca because she needs she needs to replace Rebecca or she won't feel comfortable.
Speaker 1: but at the same time she's kind of envious of Rebecca because Rebecca seemed to be this very strong perfect figure and She's not living up to any of that Like she wishes.
Speaker 1: she was a sailor and a horseback rider and a hunter and ran these fancy balls, right?
Speaker 0: But look, but look it's like that's.
Speaker 0: you know, Max, you know He was married to the awesome person and he didn't like that.
Speaker 0: He wanted the you know, the woman who wasn't capable, right?
Speaker 0: You know.
Speaker 1: so he could be the man at the same time sort of resentful.
Speaker 0: He didn't want the adult woman and he's like, ah shit I got the adult woman again.
Speaker 1: But he was also sort of resentful of the new mrs.
Speaker 1: Winter because she seemed very unhappy and unsure of herself all the time.
Speaker 0: He wanted someone who was happy and light-hearted and you know.
Speaker 1: But he also wanted a professional Someone who could like like during the ball the ball incident where she comes down wearing the dress because mrs Danvers totally fucking set her up.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like brilliantly And you see it coming the whole time and then she walks downstairs everyone freaks out like.
Speaker 1: that's what my favorite scenes in the book, but He being a professional just like puts on a face and does the dinner party like no sweat Mm-hmm, and she hides in a room and even Beatrice is like listen You got a fucking hardened up and come down here and do this thing.
Speaker 1: yeah, like just just put on the fucking dress and come down and play your part and we'll deal with this tomorrow because that's what Professionals do.
Speaker 1: but she wasn't capable of doing that.
Speaker 1: So max was obviously kind of angry at her for not being capable of doing that Despite the fact that to be capable of doing that she would have had to be more like Rebecca.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm He wasn't that mad though, right?
Speaker 0: Most of it was.
Speaker 0: she just thought he was mad at her but he actually wasn't like.
Speaker 0: the next time they're together He was mad.
Speaker 0: But again, he's mad for a short time and he gets over well.
Speaker 1: He was also mad for a very different reason.
Speaker 0: Yeah Hmm, that's another reminds me of another small difference.
Speaker 0: It's not really meaningful Yeah, but in the book at the costume party, right?
Speaker 0: What's the name of the the sister?
Speaker 0: again Beatrice Beatrice and her husband, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, I like.
Speaker 1: Beatrice seems awesome.
Speaker 1: She is awesome.
Speaker 1: Derpy.
Speaker 0: He is derpy.
Speaker 1: It's like awesome and derpy.
Speaker 0: Yes, that is correct, but in both in the book and I'll be but in the book their costumes are like racially insensitive Yep, and in the movie they are different costumes Which is nice because this movie was made at a time when you could be racially insensitive and no one would give a shit.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think in the in the book.
Speaker 0: He's like an Arab guy Which is not good with like, you know with paint on his face is I guess it's you know, not blackface.
Speaker 1: good But you know, you sort of you might argue that that was the even.
Speaker 1: the author may have been portraying the Accurate racist sensibilities of the upper class at the time on purpose maybe but in the movie he's a caveman and he's got or like a.
Speaker 0: He's wearing like a leopard print sort of like one shoulder Fred Flintstone kind of thing Yeah, and he's got a barbell with.
Speaker 0: he's like good and good and it's on both ends of the barbell.
Speaker 0: It's inflated and as a joke really bounces it off the ground.
Speaker 0: But he's derpy right.
Speaker 0: and yeah Beatrice but this you know as awesome as Beatrice is right the movie is very condensed.
Speaker 0: so you lose a lot of those things like, you know times just hanging out with Beatrice or Going to visit the you know, the old lady grandma screaming Rebecca Rebecca Rebecca.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's not in there.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know like a lot of those things are cut out right to save the time.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so the court scenes I think were super well-written like they were coursing intense.
Speaker 0: I mean court scenes are always the highest drama.
Speaker 0: That's why it's so.
Speaker 0: that's why it's so easy to make law and order.
Speaker 0: This drama is gonna be so easy man, I could write this in my eyes closed.
Speaker 0: Yeah I can write 10,000 episodes my eyes closed because court is the most dramatic place on earth before the boat guy is.
Speaker 1: But there's something that's weirding me out and I just want to tell you and then the prosecutor like the boat expert Yeah, and then the prosecutor raises eyebrow like yes, and then max is like, oh fuck me.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: And especially because at that point like mrs Nose and she knows the full details so she starts freaking out and then faints, right?
Speaker 0: I just actually really like how Even though I kind of want I want him to lose and be found out and go to jail I also want him to win because the person who's going after him is the biggest piece of shit on earth, right?
Speaker 0: It's like.
Speaker 0: it's so weird.
Speaker 0: It's like this guy Rebecca's cousin is like.
Speaker 0: it's a big piece of shit Yeah, but Rebecca is awesome.
Speaker 0: It's like well, he should get We you know, it's like, you know, everybody's like the clear good or bad guy.
Speaker 1: Frank is a diligent and earnest supporter.
Speaker 0: It's still a murderer right?
Speaker 1: No, no Frank not max.
Speaker 1: No.
Speaker 0: No Frank is fine.
Speaker 1: Yeah, Frank probably knows he knows Frank knows everything but I feel like it's injured.
Speaker 1: I think Frank is the kind of character who knows because he figured it out not because max told him no Yeah, and it's not clear very smart figures out that he actually doesn't know, right?
Speaker 0: I mean, I don't think he tell Frank ever tells max what he knows, right?
Speaker 0: No, thanks things like don't know.
Speaker 0: mr Winter figures out cuz she notices and she she knows that Frank knows.
Speaker 1: Yeah, cuz she confides in Frank cuz you feel like she should have just run away with Frank.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but Frank was like old and he's not that old.
Speaker 0: He's getting old not in the movie But now Rebecca's cousin is a piece of shit, but I guess you know in the movie max is Laurence Olivier.
Speaker 0: So why would you go with anyone else?
Speaker 0: Sure, Colonel Julian suspected heavily Yeah, but anyway the point is the.
Speaker 0: the awesome part is how he's just like.
Speaker 0: oh, alright you're accusing me.
Speaker 0: fine Let's go.
Speaker 0: Fuck you, right?
Speaker 0: It's like he's not like trying to hide it or run like he just confronts it head-on and he's like We're just gonna go explore.
Speaker 0: Let's explore everything.
Speaker 0: Sure.
Speaker 0: You want to see what's in the kit.
Speaker 0: I'll show you everything.
Speaker 0: I'm exposed.
Speaker 0: Here's all the papers.
Speaker 0: Let's go.
Speaker 1: I wonder about that because on one hand he might because his perspective is very different from the cousin.
Speaker 1: I forget that shit heads name.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm, but favel favel favel.
Speaker 1: So favel favel.
Speaker 1: so on one hand from Max's perspective if all the dirty laundry came out that Rebecca was bone and her husband or her Cousin and everybody else on the planet would ruin favel's name and Rebecca's and his it's like I'll tie the grenade to myself.
Speaker 1: We'll all go down.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm, but that's only true from his perspective of being in high society.
Speaker 1: But I will doesn't give a shit about.
Speaker 0: could you imagine like I rob a bank right?
Speaker 0: yeah, and the cops come to investigate and there's Some.
Speaker 0: you know, there's not super strong evidence.
Speaker 0: They can't take me in right away, but there's probable cause.
Speaker 0: they think they're pretty sure.
Speaker 0: It's me.
Speaker 0: they got ideas and they got to investigate because it's it's.
Speaker 0: it looks like there's a possibility.
Speaker 0: So you start to investigate and I just fully cooperate.
Speaker 0: I'm just like yeah.
Speaker 1: Oh my god Scott You know you need to watch.
Speaker 0: you want to see what's in my closet.
Speaker 0: I'm open up all my closets to you.
Speaker 0: cops I don't have to.
Speaker 1: you don't got a warrant, but I'm gonna show you God you have got to watch the Fargo TV show.
Speaker 0: This is someone who does that Holy shit.
Speaker 0: Oh you want to see my bank records here?
Speaker 0: Here's my bank records for the last ten years.
Speaker 1: So here's a perspective on that.
Speaker 0: It might was I on this night.
Speaker 1: That's where I was on this night I'm telling everyone and it might have been max assuming mutually assured destruction like bring it.
Speaker 1: It might have also been Max resigned to his fate cuz he did not right.
Speaker 0: He did not know about the cancer and that he was good.
Speaker 0: He did not know he was gonna like be saved by this investigation.
Speaker 0: right he was even he figured.
Speaker 0: you know He's just like all right.
Speaker 0: They're gonna keep investigating We're gonna go through with it, and they're gonna find out the truth.
Speaker 0: Let's just go.
Speaker 0: Let's just go through with it.
Speaker 0: Yep He doesn't admit it.
Speaker 0: He doesn't like break down and admit it ever.
Speaker 0: But he's just like let's go through with it and see what you can find.
Speaker 0: you know I'll fully cooperate and then he just sort of lucks out.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so I actually reading this I Wondered because Frank basically took the phone call and like arranged all that meeting.
Speaker 1: I actually suspected heavily that that was not a real doctor and that Frank actually set this up Where this fake doctor would pretend to be a retired doctor and pull out this file and be like oh?
Speaker 1: And just like neatly tie everything together, and I thought it was a big ploy.
Speaker 0: Frank did.
Speaker 0: it's not as a real though.
Speaker 1: I suspected that when the scene was happy.
Speaker 0: I think that's too clever, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I see Frank doing something like like the book like the story has stuff, but it that's too much.
Speaker 0: That's like one step too far.
Speaker 1: I was pleasantly surprised that that that did not seem to be the case right cuz I didn't know either.
Speaker 0: How could it right?
Speaker 1: well Frank did know.
Speaker 0: he knew the murder happened no, but he didn't know about the cancer.
Speaker 0: No, that would have been made up.
Speaker 1: It was all made up.
Speaker 1: He told someone to tell this story the end and that would be too much because it was a conveniently retired doctor Not at a doctor's office.
Speaker 0: Documents and shit.
Speaker 1: Donald Trump had a big pile of documents.
Speaker 0: It's not the same Documents documents is that the same?
Speaker 1: cuz?
Speaker 1: also Colonel Julian really heavily leans on favelle like.
Speaker 1: well I don't look into this any deeper.
Speaker 0: that is another thing right?
Speaker 1: is it a little nervous when?
Speaker 1: Julian was the.
Speaker 1: Julian said don't worry if he ever causes trouble for you again The doctor's testimony would be enough.
Speaker 0: One thing seem comforted by that one thing that works in Max's favor Which is I think why he takes the strategy is he knows that Colonel Julian already had is already on Max's side Yeah, and against favelle, so he's gonna.
Speaker 0: You know he's gonna need like imposter like absolute.
Speaker 0: You know no reasonable doubt proved to be convinced and until then is going to come up with some other explanation for the evidence That makes you know.
Speaker 0: yeah, cuz there's basically all that is they keep making up whenever there's evidence that appears like oh this boat Looks like someone murdered her in this boat.
Speaker 0: right and he's like and it wasn't suicide.
Speaker 0: and he's like well Maybe she did do it herself and locked herself in.
Speaker 0: It's like they're.
Speaker 0: basically he's going through because he's on Max's side.
Speaker 0: He's coming up with any explanation He can that where Max will still be innocent up even though the explanation of Max did it.
Speaker 0: is there really the easy?
Speaker 1: Decide because one like don't rock the boat.
Speaker 1: You know society and two he dines with that dude.
Speaker 1: They're both upper-class.
Speaker 0: So you couldn't imagine right that that would even be the case like it's like.
Speaker 0: you couldn't even think that that was like.
Speaker 1: You see favelle's victory in that Julian wouldn't have even like he would have just been like nope this is bullshit.
Speaker 1: But favelle at least had enough evidence to get Julian to say well I guess I got a look into this.
Speaker 0: I mean like imagine if you know like rim died on the ski slope.
Speaker 0: Yeah How much would it?
Speaker 0: how much evidence would have to appear before I would even consider like Emily pushed him off the skis Right like that would not even be considered even you know even though the tons of evidence like right it would.
Speaker 0: That wouldn't even be a possible explanation that would even come to mind.
Speaker 0: I like the point unless there was like a video of it.
Speaker 1: Beatrice is like oh my god.
Speaker 1: I heard they're saying it's suicide.
Speaker 1: That's bullshit.
Speaker 1: and I want to start shit to get people to realize it wasn't suicide and then be.
Speaker 1: and then Max or bet and mrs.
Speaker 1: De winter are like no, that's okay.
Speaker 1: Just let that be.
Speaker 0: Don't worry about that don't rock the boat.
Speaker 1: So yeah, I'm pretty sure mrs.
Speaker 1: Danvers just fucking burn the house down - No, that's oh.
Speaker 0: so that's in the movie, right The end of the movie.
Speaker 0: actually they come up to the house as it's burning.
Speaker 1: Yeah Do it.
Speaker 0: the other book - that's the famous scene in the movie is they're standing in front of the burning Manderley and like mrs.
Speaker 0: Danvers I think is inside burning with it now and they zoom in on the pillow on the bed with Like the famous movie ending right is?
Speaker 0: that's how you know that you've seen this movie and not some other movie.
Speaker 0: That's sort of like the rosebud sled at the end of citizen Kane.
Speaker 0: now It's the pillow with the R on it at the end of Rebecca is like the yeah And then the the the end shows up on the screen while the pillows on fire.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but in the book, it's gonna call like mrs.
Speaker 1: Danvers took all her shit and left and then the house mysteriously set on fire The end hmm.
Speaker 1: Yep, but I like how the book went full circle because remember it started with two basically nameless characters Avoiding talking about anything at all, right, which is like, okay, they didn't get he didn't go to jail, right?
Speaker 0: But basically it's like yeah, they did sort of get.
Speaker 0: you know, these these bad people deserve each other.
Speaker 0: It's like yeah now you have a boring shitty life traveling around alone But at the same time it did.
Speaker 1: that's that you get the impression that that is right after and that they could recover from this.
Speaker 1: Mmm, because they do.
Speaker 1: they both know.
Speaker 1: now like they have a topic they avoid but they both have a full understanding of that topic.
Speaker 0: Mmm, they're sort of you know, but they're like, you know They're sort of back to where max was before he met her.
Speaker 0: only now they're both in it together right traveling around, you know Boring not but the ghost is dead.
Speaker 1: They cannot go back home before.
Speaker 1: one problem for max is that his whole life was wrapped around Manderley the stupid house, so he's away from it.
Speaker 1: wish I had a house, but it's all hot.
Speaker 1: It's like the waterfall house even that shit.
Speaker 0: He did not use that house.
Speaker 0: Well, I Had if I had some kind of man that Rebecca used it right.
Speaker 1: Rebecca was like Yeah, like half the time we invited so many people over.
Speaker 1: people are like sleeping in the foyer.
Speaker 0: If I had an estate, that's how it would go down.
Speaker 0: You gotta be like the Great Gatsby like I wouldn't be letting my cottage on the beach have any cobwebs in it You know, I'd be using that boat every day.
Speaker 1: All right, so a modern point but in the beginning of the book For mrs.
Speaker 1: De Winter Is kind of the is an insufferably boring kind of person that I would avoid because if you don't know her inner universe Which is quashed by society around her like, you know all her imagination like all none of that seems to come out of her into the real world.
Speaker 1: because Even before max everyone in her life up to that point is basically forced her to be meek.
Speaker 1: So she ends up being really boring and cut the kind of person to avoid.
Speaker 1: so you wonder if max sort of wasn't drawn to her use so much as the fact that she Was a she was.
Speaker 1: it would be easy to avoid Anything with her because she would just kind of sit idle if nothing happened.
Speaker 0: I actually kind of like Ms.
Speaker 0: Van whatever name is at the beginning.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah the she's you she is.
Speaker 1: She's like a side character in a musical like in the beginning who's like introducing people and like telling the framing story, right?
Speaker 0: But it's like while she's obviously the kind of person to be like annoying to be with Right and like oh so fake and you know, whatever.
Speaker 1: now, why don't we be like that when we're old?
Speaker 1: Why don't we be the old people who like pull up outside of like packs, right?
Speaker 0: But at the same time where she's sort of that like the annoying character.
Speaker 0: She's also like not stupid.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and also Kind of really capable and is living life, you know, well, it's like she's got a family she's close with them She likes to travel she's spending your money.
Speaker 0: Well, right, you know, she You know lives the good life.
Speaker 0: She's delicious food.
Speaker 1: Well, like she is very insincere but only around these social things to like engender and endear herself to other people.
Speaker 1: But the rest of her life seems pretty genuine, right?
Speaker 0: And then you know, that's him.
Speaker 1: the core of his life is disingenuous.
Speaker 0: now and then when mrs.
Speaker 0: Dewinter is like, oh, yeah I'm leaving by she's like, oh suddenly she gives her like the real advice, you know, she's like, oh good luck Time.
Speaker 1: she was also pigeon-holing that young girl into being nothing but what she was for the rest of her life.
Speaker 1: There was no path for her out of that life.
Speaker 0: Well being married to someone her own age that wasn't?
Speaker 0: it have a horrible mansion and not a murderer.
Speaker 1: But the way she treated her she like.
Speaker 1: I don't think she would ever grow into her own and become an adult.
Speaker 0: You could she could have become an adult just like mrs.
Speaker 0: Van whatever.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's a fate worse than death But it's fine to be that person.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but she wasn't an evil person.
Speaker 0: She wasn't hurting anyone.
Speaker 0: She's just annoying people.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but it better than better than murdering people Murdering also the rich.
Speaker 1: I'm the rich young dilettante who comes to stay in Monte Carlo.
Speaker 0: Actually, you would be you are miss man, whatever you would be like, oh who's staying in the hotel?
Speaker 0: No, I will go get in there.
Speaker 0: Good graces.
Speaker 0: Let me tweet at this famous person incessantly and bother them and hope they will talk to me.
Speaker 1: Imagine Like avoid the dude standing out front.
Speaker 0: You are that annoying old lady.
Speaker 1: I would beg to differ.
Speaker 0: you are.
Speaker 1: Where's my cheese?
Speaker 1: laughs.
Speaker 0: she's.
Speaker 0: basically if the female spoonie bard is right She's only doesn't have.
Speaker 1: she doesn't barge his place cards, which is also what you do spoonie bard, maybe You are.
Speaker 1: she does play cards.
Speaker 0: She's good at it.
Speaker 1: You know what actually a big problem with mr.
Speaker 1: Winter is that she is not good at cards.
Speaker 1: No, like not at all.
Speaker 0: No Yeah, she doesn't have.
Speaker 0: the only skill she has is drawing.
Speaker 0: Doesn't come into play like they keep bringing up that like that's.
Speaker 0: her hobby is drawing.
Speaker 1: No She started saying it's her hobby because she had to say something and while she did she that was their only hobby.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but it was a very idle hobby and it's very noteworthy that she's not good at it.
Speaker 0: But she did it well enough for the dressmaker to make the exact dress true true.
Speaker 1: That is true.
Speaker 1: But otherwise like she doesn't do it like she avoids it in the house.
Speaker 0: It's like she doesn't have other skills.
Speaker 0: She doesn't.
Speaker 0: she can't like any of the.
Speaker 0: everyone else has skills.
Speaker 0: She doesn't have it.
Speaker 1: like she lives there for months and you you just all you can imagine is this fog of her Wandering around in a daze day by day.
Speaker 1: Yeah playing with the one dog.
Speaker 0: It's like she doesn't have.
Speaker 0: she doesn't do anything.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you feel like Mrs.
Speaker 1: Van.
Speaker 1: do whatever would have not let her blossom any more than max would have again.
Speaker 0: showing you.
Speaker 0: Rebecca was awesome.
Speaker 0: Rebecca could do everything.
Speaker 0: Yeah, mrs do.
Speaker 1: she may have only been able to do that by seducing and then blackmailing someone and Threatening to ruin his life.
Speaker 0: better than killing.
Speaker 1: Of course she was gonna die anyway.
Speaker 0: Point is who you want.
Speaker 0: point is we won't hang out with mr.
Speaker 0: Winter.
Speaker 0: one was doing two.
Speaker 1: I would like to be at Rebecca's parties.
Speaker 1: I don't know if I would want to be close to Rebecca Why not?
Speaker 1: That might be dangerous swinging times.
Speaker 1: Yeah You want to you want to share you want to hang out with her and favelle have a good night.
Speaker 0: No, if I would have a good time, I met.
Speaker 1: favelle is gonna be around.
Speaker 1: That's the problem.
Speaker 1: Favelle is the worst character in this novel.
Speaker 0: Hey in those days.
Speaker 0: It was okay to duel people.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think it duel him.
Speaker 1: I Like how even mrs.
Speaker 1: Dewinter is like wow, he's gonna be and I'll go in like ten more years.
Speaker 0: He's busy Biff.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So here's the question Scott.
Speaker 1: if when Colonel Julian and Max are there If max had just shot favelle and the three of them hit his body, but that have been okay I don't think Colonel Julian wouldn't let it go Even like are you shot someone right when max fucking punched him out?
Speaker 1: Colonel Julian just quietly turned his back and stood there.
Speaker 1: Yeah, maybe you cuz favelle is the worst person.
Speaker 0: It's still 1940 something right?
Speaker 0: Yeah Anyway, there's a good book good movie.
Speaker 0: It's good times.
Speaker 1: There are deep complexities here that I'm not really qualified to try to Go into but there's a lot going on for a book.
Speaker 0: That was like originally like.
Speaker 0: oh like a Bad romance novel right isn't.
Speaker 0: and then you know amazing movie right is like thing is.
Speaker 1: it's actually a really good Romance novel about a bad romance.
Speaker 0: I'm just saying is like a book that was originally treated like it was.
Speaker 0: you know Trash right is actually.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah Reception.
Speaker 1: well there was definitely a. there was this line cuz we read the liner notes for this that talked about how Gothic romance was a very like powerful avenue of feminist expression during the era.
Speaker 1: this book was written And it was often written off as trashy romance when actually there's a lot going on right.
Speaker 0: I mean I'm sure you're not gonna be able to make like.
Speaker 0: if you bought some romance novel on the shelf today at the grocery store Right could you make like an amazing movie out of it?
Speaker 0: It's like you know I don't think the Fifty Shades of Grey movie.
Speaker 0: not that I've seen it or read the book But pretty sure it's not even remotely close to being as good as this movie or book.
Speaker 1: Oh, I didn't.
Speaker 1: I did not even catch this.
Speaker 1: I'm just flipping through things here.
Speaker 1: the opening line of the book is an iambic hexameter.
Speaker 1: last night I dreamt I went to Mandalay again, okay There's all these little bits that I'm not gonna.
Speaker 1: you can read the Wikipedia article right.
Speaker 0: it's like highbrow shit But also you can get through it with the lowbrow only.
Speaker 0: That's what.
Speaker 0: that's what makes something good right like the Godfather is the say.
Speaker 0: That's why the Godfather is so great is because if you come to it from a lowbrow perspective Yeah, mobsters.
Speaker 1: Let's go right.
Speaker 0: and if you can also come to it highbrow like wow this man's being destroyed.
Speaker 0: look at this evil Dude baptizing that baby and saying he denounces Satan But he's basically is Satan and will cut to his hitman murdering someone.
Speaker 0: and here he is baptizing baby.
Speaker 1: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 0: be sure to visit our website At front row crew comm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 1: remember geek nights is not one But four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows It's actually recorded at night.
Speaker 1: and the patreon patrons in order of the money money.
Speaker 1: They give us on a continuing basis are Alan Joyce Rebecca dumb Nicholas Brando, Heidi McNichol Amanda Duchette.
Speaker 1: construction noises Ivy fame.
Speaker 1: I stated calm William Eisen rose Jeremy minor Chris Reimer and Thomas.
Speaker 1: on is a false statement.
Speaker 1: Serious time guys.
Speaker 1: Emily is my beard.
Speaker 1: Scott is the true love of my life Shervin but horrible rare.
Speaker 1: Lavell James David White Rochelle, Montana Superboy Abraham links this Aaron's Reese Brian Fisher sailor Vista.
Speaker 1: Pardon me.
Speaker 1: Are you Aaron Burr sir?
Speaker 1: Matthew Smith Don Schleich jar tovish and Joe show Joe star Tyler Eller Sean Yeager Sam Cordray Clinton Walton Ren from New Zealand Ryan Perrin drew open Lander Brian's Adroni Karen if redacted Chris midkiff Chris Knox Daniel Redmond Sean Klein Chris Reimer and Thomas on.
Speaker 1: you might notice that it sounds a bit Different right now and Out of lark.
Speaker 1: I'm recording this using the microphone.
Speaker 1: I use when I play overwatch.
Speaker 1: This is like a typical gaming headset microphone.
Speaker 1: So you guys could all hear the difference between a real microphone and a little baby microphone When it comes to recording audio.
Speaker 1: and there's a reason why Scott and I spent a lot of money on a lot of really fancy Equipment to do geek nights because what you really want to listen to geek nights if it sounded like this.
Speaker 1: But anyway, I leave you now with something.