Speaker 0: It's Thursday March 30th 2017.
Speaker 0: I'm rim I'm Scott and this is geek nights tonight.
Speaker 0: indoor lighting and possibly also outdoor lighting.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: So I got a little bit of a horror story that I happen to be on the subway yesterday.
Speaker 1: How hard could it be?
Speaker 0: Uh, so it was a situation that I had never conceived that I would be in and I was not sure how to extricate myself from it.
Speaker 1: I mean if you're honest you're on the subway.
Speaker 1: I was on the subway could push the red button and then you're good.
Speaker 0: the red button would have Potentially just made my situation worse.
Speaker 1: the it's the emergency to contact the conductor.
Speaker 0: So I've been taken the W home All right for a while now because the W runs a hybrid route where it goes by my office downtown and goes directly to my Apartment uptown.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and because of the route it runs.
Speaker 0: No one rides it from that far downtown except me.
Speaker 0: I'm like on these empty cars But yesterday there were people on the train like there were.
Speaker 0: some people say I still got a seat.
Speaker 1: I always get to just sit down which I never sit on subway Even if I get an empty subway train and stand.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if it's a half-hour, you know I do I sit down and I'll play games on a portable console and soon I'm gonna start doing that with my switch.
Speaker 0: Cuz I can totally play Zelda.
Speaker 1: I don't like him.
Speaker 1: I do not play Portably with my switch.
Speaker 0: I'm going to bring my switch on the W because I don't have to transfer trains And I mean your commutes a little too short for that.
Speaker 0: mine is exactly 30 minutes Which is like a perfect amount of time.
Speaker 0: do a little bit of like walking around.
Speaker 0: Bust up a camp of those boblin little guys.
Speaker 1: Well, you haven't got anywhere.
Speaker 1: Nope.
Speaker 0: I was fighting the high knocks yesterday.
Speaker 0: I bumped into one of them.
Speaker 1: Tell me to see a line.
Speaker 1: Oh, I watched a Lionel's combat video today.
Speaker 0: I think I watched the same video.
Speaker 1: someone posted thing that were like Hey, this guy was beaten Lionel with basically tree branch and I'm like Jesus Christ.
Speaker 0: Yeah Yeah, I got one really big ass sword that I save for like critical blow against scary.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that sword you you have you think is big ass is probably like a tree branch compared to what I.
Speaker 0: yeah So my my best sword has 38.
Speaker 1: It's not bad.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I Got swords.
Speaker 0: I literally just found it on the ground in a camp of like shitty moblins.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I got one that's like 50 something.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I got a few special ones that are less than that but are like special ancient technology.
Speaker 1: the master sword is 30 But if you take it out sometimes it'll glow when you're like in a dungeon or around special areas.
Speaker 0: It's like a plus three or higher sword.
Speaker 1: It'll become like 70 because it's the master sword.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so like if you're fighting a bot again in boss with it, it's just like boom I am the good sword now.
Speaker 0: So, uh, I sit down and I always try to sit on the edge and not in the hobo.
Speaker 0: Hobo love seat.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: That's that's how you do in New York.
Speaker 0: So I sit down and there is empty space next to me and then the bar like the vertical bar that kind of blocks people from sitting and then someone Else is sitting.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm a person got on the train at the next stop and most of the seats are filling up.
Speaker 0: This person was Extremely large.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm and Just immediately Plop down next to me.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm to the point that she was actually sitting on.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm, like her butt was on the subway seat But part of her overlapped over my entire right leg.
Speaker 1: It's a stand-up and get away.
Speaker 0: I was trapped by her like there was no way to actually stand up without shoving her out of the way.
Speaker 0: so I sat there for a minute just Thinking about if I force my way up or if I asked her to stand up so I can then stand up.
Speaker 1: So she can then sit down and say excuse me and I'm getting out and get up except I wasn't getting off.
Speaker 0: I had like 12 more stops to go.
Speaker 0: I guess I could pull the game where I excuse me I'm getting off get off at the next stop and just walk to the next car.
Speaker 1: You just say excuse me.
Speaker 0: I'm getting up and get up and then just stand there.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I feel like that would be a. I Feel like the person may have taken that the wrong way or perhaps the right way.
Speaker 1: I mean, I don't.
Speaker 1: this is why I don't sit on the subway.
Speaker 1: Hey, yeah sitting can only bring you trouble.
Speaker 1: I never have trouble by standing elbowed.
Speaker 0: I've had mostly by odd people on the seven who really want to sit down even though I'm not.
Speaker 1: this is why I always Stand even if it's empty.
Speaker 0: you can never have trouble standing But like I had a dude through throw poop in my direction not not at me But like poopers thrown and I was nearby.
Speaker 1: like I've seen you standing.
Speaker 1: you dodge poop But I'm sitting and get pooped on.
Speaker 0: I've seen some shit in my life on the subway But I have never had someone literally just sit on me.
Speaker 0: Mmm, and then Stoneface it.
Speaker 0: Mmm, like I Was dumb.
Speaker 0: part of the reason why I sat there for me to try to figure out what to do is that was kind of dumb.
Speaker 1: Stand up cuz you shouldn't be sitting in the first place.
Speaker 0: I could not stand up without pushing her leg off of me do it.
Speaker 0: So eventually I tried to like make myself uncomfortable against her like I'd.
Speaker 0: basically I had my elbow out So I just move my.
Speaker 0: I just stand the fuck up.
Speaker 1: What's I couldn't you stand?
Speaker 1: Shover stand up.
Speaker 0: should I have shoved this lady say, excuse me I'm getting up and then just stand there and stare down.
Speaker 1: You don't have to stand in that spot.
Speaker 1: You can go stand in the other part of the car.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it would have been real obvious why I'd stood up though.
Speaker 1: It gives a shit.
Speaker 0: Yeah That's what happened to me on the subway.
Speaker 1: Okay?
Speaker 0: Did you have a better opening bid?
Speaker 1: No, but just stand the fuck up.
Speaker 1: It's your problem.
Speaker 1: Also don't sit in the first place.
Speaker 0: I'm not.
Speaker 1: you're young and healthy.
Speaker 0: Why not?
Speaker 0: I'm not taking a seat from anyone else.
Speaker 1: when you're an old man you can sit.
Speaker 0: Why like?
Speaker 0: why should I not sit on the subway if there's no one else in the subways?
Speaker 1: you run into problems like that.
Speaker 1: I'll see you sit all goddamn day at your desk.
Speaker 1: You take some time to stand.
Speaker 0: I was walking around a lot plus It's warm again.
Speaker 0: So I've resumed my thing my running thing.
Speaker 0: So I think I've told this to some listeners off and on because I've run into you and I've done this to you.
Speaker 0: But I have a policy.
Speaker 0: I've been following this for about five years now and it served me really well.
Speaker 0: if I'm ever by myself and I'm walking somewhere and I don't have a good reason not to good reasons being things like it's raining.
Speaker 0: I'm dressed up It's a crowded street.
Speaker 0: It's super dark out.
Speaker 0: I always run everywhere instead of walking.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so you're basically It's like a Kramer thing to do.
Speaker 0: It is.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it really is a Kramer kind of thing.
Speaker 1: That's like.
Speaker 1: that's what that is.
Speaker 0: But I've been doing it being that guy, but I've been doing it for a long time And it's warm enough to do that again.
Speaker 0: So I actually get a lot of exercise.
Speaker 1: You're gonna come that kooky old man.
Speaker 1: Who's like when people when you go by people go.
Speaker 0: Yep, New York Yeah, and because it's got my goal in life is to be that like 90 year old skeletal man wearing under armor That still looks loose Jogging at 5 a.m.
Speaker 0: In December.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's what you're gonna be.
Speaker 1: That's exactly what I'm gonna be.
Speaker 1: That's not what you want to be.
Speaker 0: that is what I'm 90.
Speaker 0: That is the life That is literally my goal in life.
Speaker 1: I want to be that old man who goes in and says hey if I'm everything Vegas, let's go See I'll be a real New York person and not the person that people's like, you know saying whoa.
Speaker 0: so Think the whoa is I'm going to shit on you.
Speaker 0: So the other news that's important before you bring up your news is that it's almost April Fool's Day.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna link to our old episode about it.
Speaker 0: Just like it's fine to be tricked because someone like legit tricked you do not be tricked by the Internet.
Speaker 1: also Don't post stuff that's not even trying to trick people just like an obvious fake news.
Speaker 1: That shit is not funny.
Speaker 1: I've actually you know as like Google like what's the one they did that one time like pigeon something?
Speaker 1: It's like.
Speaker 1: those things not once have ever been funny or entertaining.
Speaker 1: They're all.
Speaker 0: it's gotta be like a legit trick like you go to a site and you read the news and you go what?
Speaker 0: Holy shit.
Speaker 0: Oh, wait, what day is it?
Speaker 0: It's gotta be it's gotta be.
Speaker 0: so it's gotta be believable but yet extreme Yup, or just a legit prank of right kind you can.
Speaker 1: just it's like.
Speaker 1: it's just believable and not extreme.
Speaker 0: So you accept it as real news and then you tell someone and they go Yup, I don't necessarily mind people who just do Generally interesting things like sweat web comics will do their swap and all that like.
Speaker 0: that's fine because it's not a prank.
Speaker 1: It's not like.
Speaker 0: it's not like a go-to-read.
Speaker 0: I don't know mega Tokyo and I'm like, oh my god I guess the penny arcade guys are in this comic now, huh?
Speaker 0: Like you're not.
Speaker 0: I'm not tricked by that but it's usually funny.
Speaker 0: I brought a mega Tokyo because Over the last weekend is it still exist?
Speaker 0: So I decided to play a game and the game was.
Speaker 0: I went to mega Tokyo and the comic was just updated.
Speaker 1: What's the latest update?
Speaker 1: Uh, so yeah, what does the website even look like today?
Speaker 0: It looks the same really.
Speaker 0: it even has the same relax.
Speaker 0: We understand you.
Speaker 0: Oh, no.
Speaker 1: Oh, it does look the same.
Speaker 1: Okay, what's luck?
Speaker 0: What's the Stephen got Piero and guests?
Speaker 1: What's?
Speaker 1: so?
Speaker 1: what's the date on that comic strip?
Speaker 0: This comic went up a Couple days ago, really?
Speaker 1: So art looks the same though.
Speaker 1: It hasn't.
Speaker 0: as it improved Was to start clicking previous until I figured out what the fuck was happening.
Speaker 0: You had to start back when we you know, yeah, uh, not only I don't think the plot has gone anywhere.
Speaker 1: How many readers does this have?
Speaker 0: a lot?
Speaker 0: All I'm saying is that it doesn't look like it is beyond where it was when we were in our IT Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: It looks like it is literally in that exact same part like Largo or whatever is still in the hospital.
Speaker 1: I mean, well, we know what the Piero in real life right the Piero guy we know what he's doing.
Speaker 1: He's making this comic.
Speaker 1: what happened to the Largo guy?
Speaker 0: Yeah, like his Rodney He like showed up at some cons for a while.
Speaker 0: He saw him.
Speaker 1: He was oh at least what little we knew of him.
Speaker 1: He was not the worst now a bad, dude I might be and I just don't know I interacted with him once on like minimal pleasantries.
Speaker 1: No, he was a nerdy person who was a you know, as far as I could tell a human being that wasn't painful to talk to.
Speaker 1: What happened to him?
Speaker 1: What is he doing now?
Speaker 1: I'm curious.
Speaker 0: I'm really curious here.
Speaker 1: Is he a disgusting person now?
Speaker 1: Is he just living a life?
Speaker 1: Is he?
Speaker 1: what's he doing cuz?
Speaker 0: maybe you might forget but I don't understand how fucking big that comic was back then in terms of The all of his six months.
Speaker 0: Yeah Years couple years is a big deal.
Speaker 0: couple years now.
Speaker 1: It's no.
Speaker 0: like it was bigger than penny arcade for a while Yeah, and now it's no deal.
Speaker 0: Yeah Well penny arcade kept growing and like look I keep hitting back.
Speaker 0: This might as this might as well be a strip from when we were at our IT.
Speaker 1: Yeah Looks the same.
Speaker 0: All right, you got any news.
Speaker 1: yeah, so the astronauts are doing the astronaut thing, I guess I don't know what day it is in space.
Speaker 1: How do you tell a day?
Speaker 1: it is in space and you're going around the earth the whole?
Speaker 0: but I guess you just pick a pick.
Speaker 1: You pick just you just UTC whenever empty is just UTC if you're in space, I guess Oh anyway, but says oh here you go at 10 a.m 1400 GMT.
Speaker 1: Oh No 1400 GMT.
Speaker 0: so much space stuff.
Speaker 0: because I know there was the spacewalk that people were talking Did a spacewalk, which is they happens all the time.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they drop something.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah I saw the story about that and that's just hilarious for so even though it's all you know It's probably bad news or it's but it wasn't like such a bad news that like it they're gonna die But it's just like oh my god that drop something.
Speaker 1: well I think that's kind of funny.
Speaker 0: most of the work up there because you know things I've learned just because you know I follow space is that people who stay in space for any long amount of time?
Speaker 0: They get used to being in space.
Speaker 0: So they'll like you hand them a cup and then they get distracted.
Speaker 0: They'll just let go of the cup sploosh, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah But the point.
Speaker 1: so they were.
Speaker 1: basically what happening was I think as far as I can tell they were moving a docking port Which is the port where you know ships connect to the space station, right?
Speaker 1: They're moving it and they since nothing was docked they had to like cover it up.
Speaker 1: So there's nothing would smash into it and mess it up.
Speaker 1: So they had like these basically pads.
Speaker 1: I think they're sort of described as like shields to put over it.
Speaker 1: and When you're installing stuff you basically have everything at all times.
Speaker 1: everything is I you're always keep yourself tied to the space stations You don't float away into space and you make sure that everything you're working with is tied to you or the space station.
Speaker 1: I did so I did and when you're gonna when you're you know You would say if you had a thing tied to you you would tie it to the space station then untie it from you Right afterwards.
Speaker 1: and that's how you you know.
Speaker 0: Anything like you can have like say you're messing with screws you can't just have a bowl of screws.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you can't do that.
Speaker 0: when I was in space camp will face Academy cuz I did the older kid version of it.
Speaker 0: It's not actually but as a kid they made us do a lot of those kinds of exercises Which basically they put you in a suit that's super hard to move in.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: And then they make you like alright Screw a light bulb into that thing climb up climb up this ladder and screw a light bulb into that thing and you immediately break The light bulb and you another one you break that one.
Speaker 0: They hand you another one you get up there and drop it immediately.
Speaker 1: But anyway So in the past astronauts have lost things like someone lost the whole toolkit.
Speaker 1: one someone lost a bolt.
Speaker 0: the toolkit was the first thing that came up when I googled for this.
Speaker 0: Yeah The article is quote spacewalkers lose piece of shielding.
Speaker 0: use MacGyver like plan for patch instead.
Speaker 1: Yeah, basically, it wasn't really MacGyver like pan.
Speaker 1: They just took whatever they had they the remaining shields.
Speaker 1: They shielded the most important bits and took some other stuff They had left over and shielded some other bits barely.
Speaker 1: and it's like, alright, you know You're not as long as nothing's like smashes into it that one spot unluckily.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's gonna be fine, right.
Speaker 1: but It's just kind of funny to imagine someone in space and like they lose something and it floats away and you can't go get it.
Speaker 0: And it's just like fuck especially because imagine it's slowly moving away from you and it's just becomes this white spec.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like, you know, I drop stuff all the time, especially when I'm gaming.
Speaker 1: I'll drop pieces on the ground because I always fiddle with them and Like I just bend down and pick them up.
Speaker 1: Imagine if like you're playing a game and you roll the dice and the dice go off the table and then just go off into space Just like a dice ain't come back You would be fucked in space.
Speaker 1: Yeah Got no dice left guys.
Speaker 1: We can't continue our space RPG so randomly.
Speaker 0: I got a geek bite instead of a news you go on.
Speaker 1: the moon is a bunch of dice.
Speaker 0: Yeah, because as much as I would love to talk about the fascinating things that are happening today in politics I know that Scott literally does not care.
Speaker 0: Some of you might but whatever I have a price there to say.
Speaker 0: Oh, there's a lot to say.
Speaker 0: I have a private Hangout with the small number of people I know who want to constantly talk about this.
Speaker 0: I'm getting it all out of my system in there and I actually just added a new person to that.
Speaker 1: But it is bad the end.
Speaker 0: No, it's more like here's the specific and detailed way in that This particular shit is bad right now and how it is differently bad from how it was yesterday.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I've read that in the news.
Speaker 1: So I don't need to read rim writing it again.
Speaker 0: I don't think you read any of this in the news.
Speaker 1: I read a lot of things in the news.
Speaker 0: Did anything happen today?
Speaker 1: Yeah, like what we're not gonna talk about.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna talk about it cuz the.
Speaker 0: anyone else can also read the news to find out You name on a high level anything that happened today other than the NCAA slash North Carolina thing The ISVs fine thing.
Speaker 0: that didn't happen today When they have happened a couple days ago.
Speaker 1: very sure that was today when they voted.
Speaker 0: pretty sure they voted yesterday.
Speaker 1: It's still news today, that's old news.
Speaker 0: We already knew about that.
Speaker 1: Anyway, uh, anyway point is I read news.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna geek.
Speaker 1: I need you to read the news again.
Speaker 0: Multiple people told me to watch this show and multiple people told me not to watch this show, but it's an old show Not that old.
Speaker 0: I guess it's still going like 12 seasons.
Speaker 0: So going okay Okay, but it's always sunny in Philadelphia is a show that I just randomly was on that.
Speaker 1: Isn't that the show where the guy who wrote Seinfeld is on it?
Speaker 1: Like it's his show.
Speaker 1: So he's the main character.
Speaker 0: the thing most people know about is that Danny DeVito is just on it as a character.
Speaker 0: Oh, I didn't know that hit and he's he's great in it.
Speaker 1: Okay Uh, I mean usually people who are great are great in anything.
Speaker 1: even don't think so.
Speaker 0: It was pretty great Yeah, but basically the deal with this show like I just watched it cuz I didn't really know a lot about it.
Speaker 0: Chase in particular always been bugging me to watch it.
Speaker 0: So I watched a bunch of it.
Speaker 0: That's his kind of thing because I was doing a lot of geek nights like video editing I was working on the pipeline for antenna and making those board game things and it's kind of mindless work.
Speaker 0: so I was actually watching this sitcom while I was doing that work because that work was just super mindless and The show was not quite what I expected.
Speaker 0: and I actually really enjoy it.
Speaker 0: But my geek bite review will be that you have to be a particular kind of person To actually like this show and I would I
Speaker 1: guess there's enough particular kind of people for it to go 12 seasons Yeah,
Speaker 0: so, you know Seinfeld the Seinfeld episode is basically You know the characters.
Speaker 0: like a premise starts like these characters are at a Chinese restaurant or they're gonna do a thing And then the whole episode will basically then just be that thing.
Speaker 0: Well, it's and it ends often with like the Crazy or exaggerated failure climax to that.
Speaker 1: I think the usual formula George's wife is dead now, right?
Speaker 1: but I mean the usual formula is you know, either individual or groups of characters have a thing going on and then Individual or group of characters have another thing going
Speaker 0: on in the B
Speaker 1: And then they there could be even three of these things and then at the end of the episode they all come together.
Speaker 0: But the important part is that it's mostly realistic normal Like that's how self-absorbed people in New York kind of are and then it just it escalates into like a crazy moment at the end.
Speaker 0: It's always sunny has almost the exact same structure except it starts at the crazy thing that happens at the very end of an episode of Seinfeld and just goes way beyond that.
Speaker 0: and Terms of crazy and ends like it's Seinfeld ending are things like literally the entire block burned down or those people are all dead Like.
Speaker 1: so it's about different people all the time.
Speaker 0: No, like.
Speaker 0: not the characters like other people.
Speaker 0: Okay, they've killed a whole family or something.
Speaker 0: Okay, but it's Seinfeld Ian in terms of how it all goes down.
Speaker 0: It's the same writing guy.
Speaker 1: It's just really Escalating.
Speaker 1: I can't remember the guy's name Rob Miguel McElhenny, no, not that guy.
Speaker 0: That's that's the creator.
Speaker 0: who's the other?
Speaker 0: Blya Glenn Howerton and Rob McElhenny?
Speaker 1: No, that's not the guy I'm thinking of.
Speaker 0: who's starring Charlie Day.
Speaker 0: No, then Houghton.
Speaker 0: No, Rob McElhenny Caitlin Olson, who's the guy who wrote Danny DeVito?
Speaker 0: No, I don't actually know.
Speaker 0: you keep bringing this up.
Speaker 1: What's the guy's name?
Speaker 1: This is maybe he's not on the show.
Speaker 1: I'm thinking of a different show I'm looking for.
Speaker 0: I mean the writing team The answer to who the writer is for this is not trivial for me to give you a just a name.
Speaker 1: Well, then Larry David.
Speaker 1: that guy Maybe this is a different show than the one I was thinking of.
Speaker 0: It's very.
Speaker 0: David is not in any way involved in the show.
Speaker 1: What's the show that Larry David is on the Larry David show?
Speaker 1: No There's some other show that he had.
Speaker 1: that was I guess this.
Speaker 1: isn't that show?
Speaker 0: no, no, all right.
Speaker 0: Let's go to Larry David and Wikipedia.
Speaker 0: Let's see active to present.
Speaker 0: What's he working on right now or recently ish?
Speaker 0: I mean, there's curb your enthusiasm.
Speaker 1: Oh, is that the show that was thinking of?
Speaker 0: that's the show you're thinking of.
Speaker 1: I don't watch TV in America.
Speaker 0: Okay As little as I know about TV in America I'm actually shocked at how little you know about TV in America.
Speaker 1: I don't watch garbage American television.
Speaker 0: I think you might actually like it's always sunny because Seinfeld.
Speaker 0: a lot of the problems with rewatching Seinfeld today is that Some of the left tracks laugh tracks and sometimes its jokes are a little bit dated or not quite as like this.
Speaker 0: yeah, uh but the but this show these people are horrible people and the plots but I don't like that begin are Amazing.
Speaker 0: one of them.
Speaker 0: so to the characters come into like the bar that they own I guess and they're having an argument over who shit the bed and What the fuck are you talking about?
Speaker 0: and they reveal that the two of them share an apartment and they share a bed.
Speaker 0: because why are you gonna pay for two beds?
Speaker 0: and The other characters are like, okay, that's weird but go on.
Speaker 0: and they woke up one morning and There was a poop between them and neither one would claim that they were at fault Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: So someone put the poop there.
Speaker 1: It wasn't either of them.
Speaker 0: So the other characters agree that this is a mystery that's worth DNA test.
Speaker 0: so they yeah, they take it to a they take it somewhere like to the police to have them examine it and that goes about as well as you'd expect because Everyone who is not these characters is a perfectly normal human being.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm much like Seinfeld.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so They agree to stay the night and watch them.
Speaker 0: Seinfeld has some not normal non main characters Yeah but they were still within the realm of like.
Speaker 0: I've known people who were like in those the same archetype.
Speaker 0: you knew soup Nazis and I've known people who were that archetype kind of humans.
Speaker 0: I know some fucking Newman's.
Speaker 0: I Know some Newman's.
Speaker 0: I would argue that One of the unnamed people from our IT who shall not be named edged real close to being a legit Newman.
Speaker 0: I mean, there's a those people at our IT guy the guy with the merged earlobe.
Speaker 1: I Know people at our IT who looked a hell of a lot like Newman.
Speaker 0: I also acted like Newman but did not act like him and we've treated him with.
Speaker 0: we gave him the Newman like oh, hello.
Speaker 0: Anyway, I enjoy this show.
Speaker 0: You need to really be okay with watching the show where really horrible people go through a Seinfeldian nightmare from start to finish.
Speaker 0: but anyway things of the day I Literally, this was just recommended to me on YouTube and it's real catching us tuck in my head Diva Miru.
Speaker 0: It's just a Video that someone made where they took all the words that Diva says in overwatch and Autotune them and mix them into a cute and catchy song with a video.
Speaker 1: Why don't we do the same thing with all the sounds people making counter-strike circle around back?
Speaker 0: Ah, we could do that With.
Speaker 0: that is definitely something we do.
Speaker 0: I'll go right in the hopper go go go go go go go go go go go.
Speaker 0: Actually that just turns right into gotta go fast.
Speaker 0: You can mix those together anyway.
Speaker 0: Anyway, but after I liked this video and decided was my thing of the day I realized Way after that the YouTube account it's on is piece of sheets.
Speaker 1: We've done the thing of the day from piece of sheet before.
Speaker 0: I believe yeah, it was some over.
Speaker 0: It was a heart stone thing I'm pretty sure.
Speaker 1: Oh, maybe it was so.
Speaker 0: this channel has twice Become a thing of the day of ours.
Speaker 0: So I'm gonna subscribe.
Speaker 1: when the name of your YouTube channel is piece of sheet And there's a piece of a sheet of toilet paper is your icon.
Speaker 0: Yep Come on still.
Speaker 0: I remember now the last time we talked about this I said wow their videos don't have a lot of views and no one subscribes to them.
Speaker 0: So I subscribed just now.
Speaker 0: There's only 241 people subscribe to this channel.
Speaker 0: What the fuck like?
Speaker 1: Well, we have like five thousand So everyone go check out a piece of sheet.
Speaker 1: Yeah So what do you got so?
Speaker 1: You know usually and you get situations the kids are involved and adults mixing.
Speaker 1: in a competitive environment Adults tend to go easy on them, right?
Speaker 0: or it's like that game of tag We played.
Speaker 1: you know, there's that famous South Park episode where they play hockey against the Red Wings And the Red Wings play like their kids are an NHL team and just beat the shit out of them.
Speaker 1: Right, and that doesn't actually happen in real life.
Speaker 1: That's why it's funny on South Park, right?
Speaker 1: You know in real life if there's like an adult kids t-ball game like the adults sort of soft Toss it or they're like, you know barely hit the ball so the kids can feel the.
Speaker 1: you know, that's how you do.
Speaker 1: Well, apparently there's some sort of event.
Speaker 1: I'm not sure what event this is, but it happens enough times that there's a whole bunch of videos of it that were edited together where professional mascots from NFL teams and I think college football teams Play football against what appeared to be high school football players.
Speaker 1: Clearly not college football players.
Speaker 1: Yeah and Nobody is holding back here.
Speaker 1: And those mascots clearly have you know Professional mascots are athletic adults usually because they can do flips and they can wear that suit for a long period of time and jump.
Speaker 1: And you know, I mean, I guess the gorilla from the Phoenix Suns is the best of all in terms of athleticism But I guess he's not playing football the gorilla.
Speaker 1: Yeah but anyway.
Speaker 1: So yeah in this video It's a bunch of clips from these mascot versus kids games and the mascots play football like they're trying to win and it is Glorious.
Speaker 1: and you said how is this allowed to continue?
Speaker 0: I've not even watched this yet But I just see.
Speaker 1: but as long as it exists I'm not gonna deny myself the joy of watching it, but they should probably stop doing this.
Speaker 0: I just see the thumbnail.
Speaker 0: I just see this kid who looks like he's about to get wrecked and it just says mascots destroying kids Compilation.
Speaker 1: yeah, there's.
Speaker 1: do not destroy the kids anymore, please, but do watch this video.
Speaker 1: So at least they would not.
Speaker 1: the ones that have already been destroyed were not destroyed in vain.
Speaker 1: They can provide joy to the rest of us.
Speaker 0: We can treat it like hockey fights.
Speaker 0: Yeah I'm glad hockey fighting is not as much of a thing and I hope it eventually Would have been even better if it was never a thing.
Speaker 0: But because it was a thing and we have video of it we can enjoy from old videos There is enough video of it to where I can satisfy my need to see hockey fights for the rest of my life.
Speaker 1: I was actually thinking the other day.
Speaker 1: It's like there's a hockey fight Why don't they just like arrest them and put them in jail for us like assault or something?
Speaker 0: I mean some sports they would like depending on the nature of the fight.
Speaker 1: Like if you're in a Fight within the this month where there was like, you know blood on people's faces and shit.
Speaker 0: Yeah Well, I think I was watching that game.
Speaker 0: Answer was like this is some old-timey hockey going on right here?
Speaker 1: They just go to jail and if they Know cuz fighting is part of the rules of hockey, right?
Speaker 1: But I mean as soon as if they put just one set of players in jail, no one ever fight again.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I don't know hockey.
Speaker 1: I guess like in basketball like fighting seems way less Justifiable if I tell you what if I had played hockey and I thought of this and someone tried to punch me in the face I just press charges and like punch me in the face.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know what that might not have worked out.
Speaker 0: So it's the same reason why if you go still I still try and make a big deal.
Speaker 0: if you go skiing and hurt yourself You basically can't sue anybody.
Speaker 1: Yeah, cuz you signed a thing when you bite your lip.
Speaker 0: Oh, no, it's because you don't sign anything It's at your own risk.
Speaker 0: It's basically that there's a legal precedent around this to a lot of them around the idea that there are certain inherent risks that are common knowledge and common and well-known in certain activities and You cannot pretend to be surprised by them.
Speaker 0: Uh-huh fighting is a common part of that sport Especially if you started playing hockey in the old timey days But these aren't the old timey days.
Speaker 0: but yeah When would you have done this?
Speaker 0: if you're you know in the name 1920 someone tried to see.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so what era would you try to sue people for punching you in hockey?
Speaker 1: I guess I was I would have if I played hockey.
Speaker 1: I would have been playing hockey in the years 1990 X through 2000 X I'd probably be getting if I was any good if I was bad, I'd be retired already.
Speaker 1: if I was any good I'd be close to it.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: You might you might be a team the slow team captain.
Speaker 0: Who's not that good on the ice anymore, but still good for the team.
Speaker 1: I mean, you know, we're the same age as Lundquist.
Speaker 1: We could have been goldies.
Speaker 0: Yeah I just I still.
Speaker 0: whenever I look at that man I feel like he's way older than me because he just looks like such an adult that I do not feel like he is an Adult.
Speaker 1: he has mad monies and a better job than we have.
Speaker 1: Oh and he only works part of the year and he's Has a wife and kids.
Speaker 0: He doesn't have a Stanley Cup.
Speaker 1: Now You has as many as you have yeah Same age.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we're tied.
Speaker 0: So great.
Speaker 0: I'm tied with Lundquist.
Speaker 1: He made it.
Speaker 1: He has a president's trophy.
Speaker 0: I don't have that.
Speaker 0: so he's beating me on the president's trophies Aka the.
Speaker 0: they won't.
Speaker 0: you won't win the Stanley Cup.
Speaker 0: Thank you.
Speaker 1: I think he does.
Speaker 1: he have a zena trophy my Anyway trophies and you do in the mad a moment.
Speaker 0: if you just count pretty sure he has Olympic medals.
Speaker 0: Also, if you just count trophies and medals, you don't qualify them.
Speaker 0: I got a fucking crate of medals and trophies.
Speaker 0: My mom's got him in Arizona.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think he has Olympic medals.
Speaker 0: Just counting medals.
Speaker 0: Like yeah, he's how many Olympic medals could he have?
Speaker 0: 10 20.
Speaker 0: I had like a hundred science Olympiad medals his Olympic gold medal.
Speaker 0: In fact, I got probably 30 or 40 science Olympiad gold now and he does have a Visena trophy.
Speaker 0: Okay I don't have one of those I have here.
Speaker 0: I got a trophy.
Speaker 0: I got Two trophies on my dad three trophies third place in a 5k second place in a 5k in my age group and the parsec award that geek nights won way back when there was a category for Us.
Speaker 1: I have that too.
Speaker 0: We both have it.
Speaker 0: but anyway in the meta moment the booklet book is Still Frank Herbert's.
Speaker 1: do not do names.
Speaker 0: We haven't read it.
Speaker 0: We should.
Speaker 0: we'll read at some point.
Speaker 1: The spice is gonna flow.
Speaker 0: Rebecca was the previous one.
Speaker 0: Follow our YouTube channels and if you're so inclined a number of people have been donating their time and their effort to provide closed captions on our more Widely known panel videos because it would be real expensive for me to just pay people to do all that.
Speaker 1: Good job everybody Good job.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like this is this is great like this Everybody wins if we do this.
Speaker 0: I'm do not do this if you have better things to be doing.
Speaker 0: obviously It takes a long-ass time.
Speaker 1: it's way easy, but it takes a long-ass time.
Speaker 0: like I was I'm working on one.
Speaker 1: I did it and I made it through like seven seconds and it took me like a minutes.
Speaker 0: Yep, but this is just.
Speaker 1: I feel fast.
Speaker 0: So there's a forum thread and a Google spreadsheet that I made just so that if you are so inclined to donate your time To provide closed captions for those who could not otherwise experience the joy that is geek nights panels.
Speaker 1: Also, I would recommend to you Instead of doing it for our videos go on YouTube find something for like some really important Yeah, find some educational video that's actually valuable that as accepting, you know It's user-submitted subtitles and captions and do that instead.
Speaker 0: We've had more than a few people ask us for citation information because they included us in theses All.
Speaker 0: any time that happens I just want to be like I kind of want to see the paper to find out Why you're about to lose your doctors?
Speaker 1: Yeah Guys on the internet said really we're gonna be.
Speaker 0: well, I'm gonna be a Zenkai Khan.
Speaker 0: I I assume Scott's gonna bail on it.
Speaker 1: When is it?
Speaker 0: Uh end of the month and the next month sometime.
Speaker 1: There's a new Google Calendar app for iPad.
Speaker 1: I can actually see my calendar properly now.
Speaker 0: Oh you couldn't before.
Speaker 1: What's the date of Zenkai Khan?
Speaker 1: so you can tell the listeners?
Speaker 0: Fuck if I know I don't even know what panels I'm doing.
Speaker 1: Just type in Zenkai Khan right now.
Speaker 0: I am literally typing it, but I don't even know what panels I'm doing.
Speaker 0: I just know I have them.
Speaker 0: I didn't even fill out the form.
Speaker 0: I just like emailed them and I was like, ah, here's a list.
Speaker 1: What day is it?
Speaker 0: It is on April 28th that weekend.
Speaker 1: Nope.
Speaker 1: Not going.
Speaker 0: Not going?
Speaker 0: Why not?
Speaker 1: Nope.
Speaker 1: Why not?
Speaker 0: It's not gonna be nice weather yet.
Speaker 0: I don't think.
Speaker 1: Not gonna.
Speaker 0: You don't wanna go?
Speaker 0: I'm just gonna.
Speaker 0: all I'm gonna do is play board games the whole time.
Speaker 1: Nope, not happening.
Speaker 0: With a small group.
Speaker 0: This is like the board game con cuz.
Speaker 0: what else am I gonna do?
Speaker 1: No, good luck.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it'll be fun.
Speaker 0: I'll hang out there.
Speaker 0: Uh There's PAX Unplugged and PAX Prime and PAX Australia Which it is like 90%.
Speaker 0: sure that I'm going to PAX Australia.
Speaker 0: 90% pee?
Speaker 0: 90% pee That I'm gonna pee in Melbourne during PAX Australia.
Speaker 0: I will be there.
Speaker 0: I will pee.
Speaker 0: But my panel will not be about peeing or panels, but Geek Night is coming back 90% sure.
Speaker 0: Not a hundred percent sure because I haven't actually booked the tickets yet, but it's looking real good For a lot of reasons.
Speaker 0: So, uh When humans started living in domiciles one real big problem is that it's fucking dark inside them.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm like It is way darker inside places that you live than you realize and you might think it doesn't look that dark.
Speaker 0: Get a light meter out.
Speaker 0: It's way darker than you think.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah Your brain your eyes are just pretty good at seeing in the dark more than they're not dwarf good or elf good But they're pretty good.
Speaker 0: but like the more I do photography and like video and like that kind of stuff the more I Notice like this room is actually like a third as bright as I feel like it should be like it's real dim in here.
Speaker 0: It's dark with this one LED light and then like the light for like if I do video like when you see someone filming something And it's ridiculously bright.
Speaker 1: You're like, oh my god.
Speaker 1: Why is it burn?
Speaker 1: It's like because that's how bright it needs to be.
Speaker 1: Yep It's dark.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but when I make when I stream the podcaster, I'm not doing right now.
Speaker 0: the lighting on my face from my monitor is Significant to the overall lighting profile.
Speaker 0: That is how dark it is in this room.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so yeah, it took a long time for us to have any kind of lighting Indoors, right people would make structures with like holes in the roof or no roof or they would just let it be.
Speaker 1: They would barely go inside.
Speaker 1: you go into your cave when you're a caveman and sleep at night And then you just get the hell out as soon as the Sun is up because it was dark at night.
Speaker 0: Don't worry we're not going all the way born at this.
Speaker 0: we're not gonna do the contrived show of lighting through history.
Speaker 1: No, because we don't know anything about lighting through history.
Speaker 0: I know a shocking amount about very specific eras of certain kinds of lighting for unrelated reasons But at one point we invented gas lighting candles Yeah, lamps these sorts of things.
Speaker 0: and then you know in the early 20th century my apartment with nothing but glow sticks I just have my Amazon delivery schedule.
Speaker 1: We finally got us a light bulb and nowadays Lightbulb technology is actually advanced significantly way fast.
Speaker 0: So think of this when we got to RIT it was pretty much incandescent bulbs or Fluorescent like regular old shitty-ass floor.
Speaker 1: There were other kinds of bulbs you could get but for lighting that a normal person would have in their home.
Speaker 1: They're home not dark.
Speaker 1: You wouldn't really use those.
Speaker 0: what other kind of bulb other than incandescent or fluorescent.
Speaker 1: Well this halogen Incandescent is it really?
Speaker 0: that's the scene.
Speaker 0: all incandescent is a very.
Speaker 0: it's a very simple concept of halogen is just different kind of incandescent.
Speaker 0: Mmm, there's still a filament in there.
Speaker 1: So fluorescent that isn't is an incandescent.
Speaker 0: Nope.
Speaker 0: Fluorescent is different.
Speaker 0: Is it fundamentally different concepts?
Speaker 1: I thought fluorescent was the same kind of thing only it was filled with fluorine instead of.
Speaker 0: nope, you know, so Basically incandescent bulbs are.
Speaker 0: there's some sort of filament that's burning and you have electricity going through it which heats it up.
Speaker 0: So it gives off photons Usually tungsten.
Speaker 0: right tungsten tungsten or there's other things that people use.
Speaker 1: tungsten lasts a hell of a long time is usually why right?
Speaker 1: Yeah gives up a ton of light.
Speaker 0: I'm digging this article right here to see because there's.
Speaker 0: they use the cold filament.
Speaker 0: Okay, this article is way too big.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you can read the Wikipedia.
Speaker 1: you put electrons on the tungsten or whatever and it lights up.
Speaker 0: now There's cool stuff about these.
Speaker 0: so I I've always been an advocate for a long time Even though RIT banned them which was annoying.
Speaker 0: but I like torsion lamps because they provide the most and demand best diffuse lighting For a mid cell like the kind like a living room sized room, right?
Speaker 1: Cuz what the way they work is.
Speaker 1: they shoot light up at the ceiling and your ceiling basically becomes a giant reflector.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that reflects light and since it's so much light it reflects the light evenly and softly down.
Speaker 1: So you just get even lighting almost everywhere in the room.
Speaker 1: That's you know It's like having a really giant weak light bulb instead of having when you really don't have one.
Speaker 0: So if you had a halogen bulb just pointed like down in your room It would be it would.
Speaker 0: it would be horrible burning Sun that you would hate all the time And it would also be really hot like you'd feel its heat.
Speaker 1: But imagine if you had the Sun in a bowl and then the Sun shot the ceiling and then the ceiling was actually the light Bulb effective.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but uh When we were at RIT if you wanted really bright lighting that wasn't like terrible fluorescence.
Speaker 0: You pretty much had to get halogen bulbs Which are super hot and there's.
Speaker 0: that's why RIT banned them because they assumed that stupid college kids would literally burn the dorms down.
Speaker 1: You can if you get if you go to like a construction site You know at night and you see they have like these giant lights out there.
Speaker 1: Or you go to a baseball stadium and like they have these lights that is lighting up the whole fucking thing like daytime Even though it's night.
Speaker 1: Yeah, those things like a bajillion degrees.
Speaker 1: Don't touch those.
Speaker 0: Yeah, last night Actually, we had the spot on cuz we were playing a game on the floor and Natalie stood up and bumped ever So slightly into the halogen like where the bulb was and burned herself.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: Don't do that.
Speaker 0: Yep so like they have cages around them and That was pretty much as good as you could do.
Speaker 0: you buy a nice expensive halogen lamp and you would use that to light like an apartment and I that's what I still use in the living room you can.
Speaker 1: Halogen bulbs can also like.
Speaker 1: it's weird.
Speaker 0: You can get some that are ridiculously small, but then the brightness is like ah, yep Xenon is probably better, but that's mostly used in like car headlights because it's not as hot But it's way more expensive and just as bright as far as I know.
Speaker 1: Yeah, car headlights also go to the store the auto shop and look for like replacement car bulbs.
Speaker 1: They tiny.
Speaker 0: Yep, but When we were at our IT if you want normal light bulbs are incandescent and you kids might not even remember at this point.
Speaker 0: But in gas above used between 60 and 100 watts.
Speaker 0: Like they used a lot of power and they were kind of shitty and they cost like 20 cents.
Speaker 1: Yep used to actually you'll get him for free.
Speaker 1: they used to be zero dollars.
Speaker 1: Oh, you just get him from the power company for nothing.
Speaker 1: and then eventually they were like, hey It's I would be profiting from this.
Speaker 1: so then they started selling them.
Speaker 0: But then the compact fluorescence came out and the idea was that they would replace these Ridiculously power inefficient lights with far more efficient light, right?
Speaker 1: So it used to be that fluorescent bulbs were just like the long tubes you would put in the ceiling in like a classroom.
Speaker 0: Yeah, or maybe you get the complicated ones that would have like a weird coily tube, but they were still normal fluorescence.
Speaker 1: right the compact Fluorescent was a great invention because instead of having the two hookups on the side You could have the it could screw into a normal socket where the incandescent used to go.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they would have the master whatever building into it.
Speaker 0: but
Speaker 1: since the design still had to be a long tube, they just made one long coily tube that was eventually bulb shaped and Basically you instead of having one long thing you had one sneaky thing in a very small ball shaped area and it's like aha we did it and That meant you could have the fluorescent bulb and a normal socket and it worked and you got the advantages there.
Speaker 0: But I guess where what I'm getting to is.
Speaker 0: what's really interesting Is that CFLs appeared and at first a lot of people complain about it?
Speaker 0: Most of those people are just dumb because the color is slightly different people.
Speaker 1: There's people just hate change, right?
Speaker 1: Oh, you know like Twitter made a change today We've talked about this and geek nights many many times people hate change Even if the change is for the better and you know anything that's different is bad and that is a bad attitude.
Speaker 1: Anyone has the attitude fuck that.
Speaker 1: but people also complain because they would not to say that all change is good Just to say you should not dislike something just because it is a change.
Speaker 0: they were expensive Like they were expensive, but you had to replace them less often except actually you had to have it replace them a lot Because most people were buying the cheapest bulbs they could get Which burned out like real fast and were real shitty.
Speaker 1: They didn't burn out as fast as incandescence, but they still burned out.
Speaker 1: I have had.
Speaker 1: you know I remember reading like when I bought compact fluorescence originally in the beacon days About how they would last for like years and years and years and they would if you bought the expensive nice one from the good name.
Speaker 1: But I have had some at least a few burn out and still most of my bulbs are Compact fluorescence from those days that are still going good.
Speaker 1: Yep, but my new ones are LED ones.
Speaker 0: But it's interesting how that technology was very much an interim technology and it's already kind of obsolete Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: because LEDs which back then like I saw like people sold like very special like LED light bulbs You could put in a lamp like a normal lamp and they'd be like 50 bucks.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean we had we've always had LED.
Speaker 1: we haven't always had LEDs.
Speaker 1: We've LEDs for a very long time right.
Speaker 0: bright white light your remote control and you're affordable, right?
Speaker 1: I mean like every electronic device had little red lights that lit up and eventually blue ones or white ones, right?
Speaker 1: You know and those are LEDs But no one can make one that was bright enough to like light up a fucking room or using a flashlight until Somewhat recently, you know.
Speaker 1: and now you got LED flashlights LED everything.
Speaker 1: Everyone's replacing every light with LEDs because they don't really burn out so much.
Speaker 0: Yep, and now we'll get to the practical stuff and use a lot less energy.
Speaker 0: CFLs I'm actually I've replaced almost every CFL I've got with LEDs now.
Speaker 1: Well, should I replace?
Speaker 1: the CFL is still working.
Speaker 1: that feels bad.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so I. so I haven't done that yet But I'm going to do it.
Speaker 0: You know those two box lamps.
Speaker 0: I got in the living room.
Speaker 0: They have CFLs that I bought when we moved into this apartment and they're not that bright and part of that's because you know those those lights.
Speaker 0: I'd like them to be brighter not sun bright, but brighter.
Speaker 0: an LED that would go into one of those because they basically don't generate any Significant heat could be about twice as bright and use less power than the CFLs.
Speaker 0: But then I'll have to have these two perfectly good CFLs.
Speaker 0: I would basically have to Keep in my apartment until the next amnesty day probably and then take them over to the special recycle, right?
Speaker 1: That's the main thing.
Speaker 1: CFLs for all their good benefits of energy usage and long-lasting this they have a very small amount of mercury in Each one and so if they break They're very dangerous and you have to sweep them up properly.
Speaker 1: and even if you want to throw them out You have to dispose of them properly by taking them to like Best Buy or to your local recycling.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna say if you can't just throw them in the trash like an incandescent which is you know, but even throwing away incandescent It's still pointy glass.
Speaker 1: So you throw it away carefully.
Speaker 0: But yeah, if you throw CFLs away in your garbage, you're a bad person.
Speaker 0: Yeah I really deeply disrespect you.
Speaker 0: you're very bad.
Speaker 0: do that and The reason I disrespect you is because I had a fucking box of CFLs that every few months I take to a place and deal with.
Speaker 0: it's a giant pain in the ass Because I don't want to break them while I'm transporting them.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and cuz I don't have a car I transport them usually by biking with them in a backpack.
Speaker 0: Yep so, uh Lighting your apartment's dark.
Speaker 0: So what are you gonna do about it?
Speaker 1: I'm gonna get more lights.
Speaker 1: That's what I'm gonna do.
Speaker 0: What kind of like is you used to always complain about torsiers?
Speaker 0: whenever I talked about a torsier style lamb and this happen on geek Nights many times you would bitch about them and complain about them and tell me I was dumb for liking them.
Speaker 1: I don't really like the style.
Speaker 1: It's not a good style.
Speaker 0: So what's a good style?
Speaker 0: What do you what is the style you would use to light say this rumor.
Speaker 1: and now well I mean depends how much money I got.
Speaker 1: right.
Speaker 1: if I had mad moneys, I would just buy only Tiffany lamps Right, you know with the colored glass and shit, right?
Speaker 1: See if I had I can't afford.
Speaker 1: I can't even afford one Tiffany.
Speaker 0: I would do the thing we were talking about before the show where I would get the LD light bar of LEDs like around the ceiling like the diffuse LED bar.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean that's the thing is like.
Speaker 1: because I'm renting this tiny apartment I feel like there's a lot of things that I would do if I say owned a house that I wouldn't do even if they're Simply because I'm renting.
Speaker 1: I don't make like a.
Speaker 0: that's something that's always That it was like.
Speaker 1: I really like you and lights are built into the ceiling and you switch which is how it is in my Kitchen, but I can't add those over to the living room area.
Speaker 1: good.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but I mean, it's not.
Speaker 0: Here's the thing.
Speaker 0: when I was a kid in Michigan every house I lived in every house my friends lived in every room had ceiling lighting of some kind built in Mm-hmm, and then when I moved to New York, I basically stopped encountering that New York.
Speaker 1: Because New York houses are older right and no one's modifying their house And they already have lamps.
Speaker 1: because they live in New York's they buy lamps so that you know.
Speaker 1: So only new places have that old grandparents house had it only in certain rooms.
Speaker 0: But because there was a giant party house They built like giant house with like a bar in it and like living room family room like an entertaining room everywhere.
Speaker 0: But they the living room was giant and they had like this area where there's the TV and then like an L big l-shaped couch And they'd have lamps lighting that area up.
Speaker 0: But when we were visiting unless there were a bunch of people around They would not turn on lights anywhere else in the house.
Speaker 0: So you'd be in this like lit area bounded by the couches and it would be dark dark Like you could barely see the wall bowed before the saving electricity.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, of course they were.
Speaker 0: this is when I was a kid.
Speaker 0: Yeah, yeah, but it was weird as a kid to go to grandma's house at night because the house was so dark.
Speaker 1: I mean, it's a habit.
Speaker 1: I mean, it's you know, I if I have it when we had more than one room It's like when you're going to other parts of the house You're not using some parts of the house turn off the lights in the part You're not using.
Speaker 0: well when you have one big room and you turn off the lights in like half the room.
Speaker 1: That's weird.
Speaker 1: It was a big room.
Speaker 1: Whatever room I'm in all the lights should be on.
Speaker 1: Yeah But uh, unless it's watching a movie or so.
Speaker 0: So the only overhead lights I got is there's a bunch of halogen spots in our kitchen Which are really nice and then we have separate fluorescent lighting for the fill.
Speaker 0: I have spot and fill in all the parts of my apartment that have built-in lighting.
Speaker 0: like even the bathroom has a fill light like a fluorescent on the top.
Speaker 0: and then I have the like the lights on the Mirror that are xenon for some.
Speaker 0: well, they're not xenon anymore.
Speaker 1: I just replaced them with LEDs, but they're xenon and that provides like my bathroom has like these four giant bulbs that are circles You know, they're like they're like orbs.
Speaker 0: I hate that style of light bulb.
Speaker 1: They're above the Above the mirror and that's what the house that's the apartment came with.
Speaker 1: that was there.
Speaker 0: So the halogens the spots kept burning out Like every few months one would go.
Speaker 0: so I replaced one of them with a CFL that was in the form factor of a halogen spot and It wasn't as bright and eventually after about a year It started not turning on all the way and it would like turn out all the way later if you left it on.
Speaker 0: I eventually I bought like $20 like fancy LED spotlights and replaced every one of them.
Speaker 0: They've been perfect ever since.
Speaker 0: they're way brighter than the halogens and they generate like zero heat which is just fascinating to me.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the heat is actually a big deal right because incandescents like you'd want to change the bulb and it'd be all hot and shit.
Speaker 1: Yeah LEDs is like no problem.
Speaker 1: You can just touch them all day.
Speaker 0: Yeah But also means that I have light fixtures that have a wattage limit like no more than 150 watts in this thing.
Speaker 0: You know, you don't start a fire.
Speaker 0: But if you put an LED in that old fixture You can ignore that and you could get a hundred and fifty watt quote unquote equivalent.
Speaker 0: Or just get whatever light bulb you want and like as bright as you want because it's not gonna use that many watts.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there's.
Speaker 1: it's not gonna use even close to that many watts.
Speaker 1: Yep So if you actually had an LED that used a hundred and fifty watts of actual electricity from the wall You're just like be dangerous.
Speaker 1: It was like burn your face like.
Speaker 1: ah.
Speaker 0: So some lamps too because my apartment's also not bright.
Speaker 1: The problem is that eat, you know, even basic lamps cost a lot of money and not Tiffany lamp, right?
Speaker 1: Just lamps from that are mass manufactured or not cheap if you want ones that aren't garbage Yep.
Speaker 1: Now Joe and I see even IKEA like a lamp could be like 50 60 bucks or something.
Speaker 0: Yeah Well, it's a 50 60 every time.
Speaker 1: that's really kind of low-end lamp - every time I've got.
Speaker 0: yeah Here's the IKEA lamp 20 bucks stand upright.
Speaker 0: Oh Takes a standard socket up top so you can put a CFL in there.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's a really cheap.
Speaker 0: Oh, this is the lamp we have in the bedroom.
Speaker 1: That's a cheapo lamp.
Speaker 0: It is a cheapo lamp, but it probably works.
Speaker 0: It wouldn't be that bright super cheapo.
Speaker 0: But when I've gone to like a store and looked at lamps, I've seen really nice lamps to do exactly what I want.
Speaker 0: They're like three hundred dollars.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: Let's see.
Speaker 1: IKEA has 97 floor lamps.
Speaker 1: That one's 50 bucks.
Speaker 0: Okay, so the last 90 by the last time For lamps.
Speaker 0: well two times ago I ended up buying like I did a lot of research and the most of the lamps for sale on Amazon.
Speaker 0: We're really garbage and we're from manufacturers who looked like they made nothing but garbage.
Speaker 0: Yep And those are all still here.
Speaker 0: but increasingly there's this company bright tech that I noticed and I still think they're making cheap stuff.
Speaker 0: but it looks like they Make fixtures that just take LEDs that are just built into them and they've gone kind of crazy with the form factors.
Speaker 0: And I feel like when I get a new lamp, I'm gonna get one of these like weird form factors.
Speaker 1: It's a really weird kind of lamp.
Speaker 0: Well look like this one.
Speaker 0: It's just a disc on the top of a stick.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that looks really stupid.
Speaker 1: That's like you look any different than this.
Speaker 1: that also looks really stupid.
Speaker 0: Why does it look stupid?
Speaker 1: It looks stupid.
Speaker 0: Why how would you design a torchier lamp?
Speaker 0: That doesn't look stupid.
Speaker 1: I wouldn't use a torchier lamp because it looks stupid.
Speaker 1: I've put a lamp for the shade like a normal lamp like a normal person.
Speaker 0: what like just Sticking up way high in your ceiling just like a lamp shade?
Speaker 0: No, just you know, like what we'll find an image of what you think you want.
Speaker 0: cuz I don't think it exists.
Speaker 1: What do you mean?
Speaker 1: I have it.
Speaker 1: what here it is.
Speaker 1: It's a normal ass lamp.
Speaker 1: Yeah, see it's a stick and at the top of the stick is a bulb with a shader.
Speaker 0: That's that's not gonna provide enough diffuse light because that lampshade is gonna prevent our diffusion.
Speaker 0: That's why your apartments dark.
Speaker 1: Yeah, cuz I have a normal looking lamp.
Speaker 1: That's it's not supposed to be crazy.
Speaker 1: How bright do you want it?
Speaker 0: plus honestly until relatively recently?
Speaker 0: I had never in my life seen a tall lamp that had a traditional lamp shade on it.
Speaker 0: all lamps are there Torchy air?
Speaker 0: or if it had a lamp shade it was a lamp that was on a table.
Speaker 0: That lamp does not look great.
Speaker 0: I don't think okay.
Speaker 0: That's not a good style of lamp.
Speaker 1: It's a perfectly normal land.
Speaker 0: I think torch air provides.
Speaker 0: See that's your problem.
Speaker 0: the kind of lamp you Aesthetically seem to want is not in any way going to provide enough light for you to not say your apartment is too dark.
Speaker 1: Just get more of them.
Speaker 0: How many I think you would need?
Speaker 0: like six of those.
Speaker 0: I think you would need six of those.
Speaker 0: your apartment is pretty dark like darker than my living room Mm-hmm and my living rooms just got that big torch air.
Speaker 0: and then the two really dim box lights.
Speaker 1: Yeah, box lights are a weird thing right cuz I like to shooting light sideways and down ways.
Speaker 1: It's like you know.
Speaker 0: yeah, I got these.
Speaker 1: I bought the box lights partly because yours only have the box at the top.
Speaker 1: I seen ones that are box all the way down.
Speaker 1: I'm like how many bulbs are in there?
Speaker 0: I don't like those.
Speaker 0: is it bulbs all the way to hate way more than the what the box lamps that have multiple boxes are Those Boston style ones that just have a bunch of like shitty spotlights hanging off at weird angles.
Speaker 1: Oh the one that looks like a tree like yeah like that.
Speaker 0: Those are the wars those are the ugliest.
Speaker 1: so those kind of lamps It's like I can actually understand one of those in one situation All right You got a big-ass living room in the suburbs all right And you got a reclining type chair or the at the side of a couch where you're gonna sit.
Speaker 0: Ah you put it like between and you put that.
Speaker 1: you put the lamp right behind the couch or next to the chair So that one of those sneaky arms can be like a reading lamp so you can see your TV.
Speaker 0: Oh, no You're thinking of like.
Speaker 0: you're thinking of this nonsense that has the lamp and then like the thing hanging off exactly one of them.
Speaker 1: one Of them is aimed at you for the TV guide reading and one of them is aimed at the whole room.
Speaker 1: But be it you put it next to you because that way you can control both of those lights while you're sitting there watching TV Like a lazy ass.
Speaker 0: I agree with you.
Speaker 0: That's the only other.
Speaker 1: that and the one the one that has three arms is just a variation of that where?
Speaker 1: You know one of the arms sort of shoots somewhere.
Speaker 1: one of them shoots up and one of them is down.
Speaker 0: You say that but every time I've gone to someone's apartment, and they have that tree like Boston style lamb.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that kind it.
Speaker 1: one of them is aimed at you Anything in particular.
Speaker 0: they're just using it to try to fill light the whole room.
Speaker 0: But because it's they're kind of low and no light is going upward.
Speaker 0: They actually make the room way darker.
Speaker 1: Yeah, those they're not effective at lighting a whole room.
Speaker 1: They're effective at lighting like you know.
Speaker 1: You like certain areas right.
Speaker 1: so you could.
Speaker 0: you got to aim the three of those Suburban house and you want accent lighting on some thing that I guess you could use some.
Speaker 0: right.
Speaker 1: you got to put it.
Speaker 1: It's like one of those shoots down at you.
Speaker 1: one of them shoots like over near the TV Okay, so you get up or like shoots like at the coffee table Yeah, and one of them maybe shoots like to the back wall or something you know.
Speaker 0: so I really like Modern torsiers because now that they're using LEDs like the one I got here They don't need to have the giant cage over the top So you don't accidentally start a fire if you knock it over.
Speaker 0: They don't need to have the glass shield to prevent UV radiation from giving you a sunburn in your own house.
Speaker 0: And they're actually way way brighter like this one here and are in the studio.
Speaker 0: There's only three tiny LEDs in that whole thing Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: they sell one that has like a whole ring of LED.
Speaker 1: I mean, I have a flashlight with an LED, and he says like it.
Speaker 1: You know freaking blind people that thing.
Speaker 1: yeah I am.
Speaker 0: yeah fine my druthers I would definitely put ceiling or at least like if you have a high ceiling maybe on the sides like I'd ring the room with LED driven light bars Because I don't like track lighting like track lighting just feels really 80s like late 80s early 90s yuppie house in the affluent suburbs And it doesn't feel like it's practical because it makes too many spots and too many like too many hot spots and too many cold spots.
Speaker 0: Like you've got all these individual little lights pointed in different places up there Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: so what are you gonna do?
Speaker 0: What are you gonna buy?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna probably just get two.
Speaker 1: I think I just get two identical lamps that are good because right now I have one lamp to the left of the TV right.
Speaker 1: yep I'm gonna move that lamp back into this space near my desk where I have some room if I get rid of some stuff And then I'll buy two identical lamps and put one on each side of the TV.
Speaker 1: Here's the problem though that is that the light switch for turning on lights only controls this one outlet Even though there's outlets on both sides of the TV.
Speaker 0: I have extension cords plugged into various ways to extend that to control multiple labs from all my but it's like it's so annoying though.
Speaker 1: Right it's like should.
Speaker 1: maybe I can get some sort of like home.
Speaker 1: You know like I don't really want to use all this stupid home automation system.
Speaker 1: things cuz my.
Speaker 1: I have one room two rooms.
Speaker 1: Yep, it's not necessary, but maybe I can just get like one component from that kind of system to use To turn on all the lights and turn off all the lights without having a bunch of wires everywhere.
Speaker 1: I've thought about that because just use it just use it for on/off switch and nothing else.
Speaker 0: yeah I just don't trust any of those systems.
Speaker 0: is the main reason why I have not gone down that road?
Speaker 1: No, I mean you know I mean I guess if I own the house I would also get the thermostat one, but that's about it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I've heard a lot of people have the thermostat one.
Speaker 1: It's not great though, so no I'd probably get like you know the extra nerdy one, but I just made.
Speaker 0: do Arduino yourself maybe but uh.
Speaker 0: So I'm thinking about getting for it because I need a one more lamp in the living room I think because if we play games on the table I don't have a light that's directly shining at the table Which would not be a concern except German board games like you really need a real light pointed directly at the game.
Speaker 0: it is actually kind of hard to deal with board games and even like a Generally well lit normal like kitchen or bathroom or bathroom or a living room that most people have in their houses.
Speaker 1: Another kind of light that I don't see are the ever these days is the chandelier.
Speaker 0: Ah My grandparents house had huge ornate chandeliers in both dining rooms, right?
Speaker 1: So that's the only place you really see.
Speaker 1: them is like above a dining table, right?
Speaker 1: It's like that's the only place.
Speaker 1: yep But I like me a chandelier.
Speaker 1: I don't know when you go to the theater and have like this fucking enormous ones.
Speaker 0: It's like oh shit, son I guess I've always felt that the ones I encounter in houses feel really cheap because they are really cheap usually.
Speaker 1: But you know some people have not cheap ones.
Speaker 1: the thing is You know a chandelier is is pretty cool because not only like.
Speaker 1: is it a thing?
Speaker 1: and it like means you don't have some boring Ceiling.
Speaker 1: you actually have something going on up there.
Speaker 0: They're really effective at lighting up the whole fucking room usually not nearly as effective as a light bar or a modern way of doing that.
Speaker 1: But you go in a place that has a chandelier Right like a big one and you turn it on and turn it off and you be like, oh, yep So here's here's what I know about chandeliers.
Speaker 0: based on the fact that there were a bunch of my grandparents house and my mom Explaining to me in great detail why we did not have any in our house one You're gonna hit it and knock it and break it all the time.
Speaker 1: Well, that's why they're usually above tables.
Speaker 0: Ever move your table.
Speaker 0: You're fucked.
Speaker 1: Yeah, don't move your table three.
Speaker 0: You gotta dust that shit like every couple days.
Speaker 1: Yep, that's all depends the design of it.
Speaker 0: But yes, there's almost no design.
Speaker 1: I can imagine you want to talk about dusting right the cousin of the chandelier.
Speaker 1: and this is the thing is a lot of people Replace their chandeliers.
Speaker 1: They had ceiling fixtures where a chandelier would go.
Speaker 1: Yeah But in the 80s and 90s Maybe in the 70s They replaced them with spinning fans with lights under them covered on the top with dust that they forget about until the summer.
Speaker 1: That's right every year.
Speaker 1: That's what.
Speaker 1: that's why there's a lot less chandeliers because those places in old houses got replaced with fans.
Speaker 0: They said everyone they always put their fans in wrong.
Speaker 1: So the fans wobble some of them but some of them get them installed, right?
Speaker 1: But the point is those fans actually the lights on the bottom of the fan usually have like four bulbs aiming different directions And if the room is small that usually lights up the whole Michigan.
Speaker 0: every room of every house had a fan and had those lights.
Speaker 1: Oh, we only had one in the kitchen most.
Speaker 0: Wow the kitchens the one room.
Speaker 0: We actually did not have that because the kid the kitchen had a chandelier.
Speaker 1: in the dining room had a shed.
Speaker 0: Oh, see we had a separate dining room.
Speaker 0: We did.
Speaker 1: We had a table under each one But the chandelier in the kitchen was quickly replaced with the fan.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we had fans ceiling fan.
Speaker 0: lots of those houses had fans and light combo.
Speaker 1: I don't know when the fan light combo was invented, but it feels like it was invented, you know Not in the 60s maybe earlier.
Speaker 1: that I think actually I haven't seen any ridiculously old.
Speaker 0: I suspect why there isn't a lot of overhead lighting in these like luxury New York apartments.
Speaker 0: Is that the one of the I guess?
Speaker 0: Displays of affluence or and things like that in modern New York style apartments?
Speaker 0: Is that you gotta have the high ceiling?
Speaker 0: like the higher the ceiling is the more like fancy the building is to a point?
Speaker 0: Which is your thing for old housing like a standard height ceiling like if you're used to the hot tall ceilings Feels kind of like a dank cave When the ceilings right there, so like the our ceilings are way higher than is in any way like reasonable or necessary
Speaker 1: Ceilings feels about normal.
Speaker 0: This is what 14.
Speaker 0: This is that this is considered like high-end luxury ceiling height.
Speaker 0: Most apartments will not be this high.
Speaker 1: This is about a high - right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, you're you're a similar.
Speaker 0: like luxury class apartment Apartments are a foot.
Speaker 0: see.
Speaker 1: when I think of high ceiling I think of like whoa Has two stories like.
Speaker 1: no Well, that is high but I'm talking high like you.
Speaker 1: let a balloon go and now you can't get it back.
Speaker 0: So as a kid we had that because for a while we lived in a ranch house that had the art the steeple ceiling.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's what I'm talking about.
Speaker 0: So live there was at least every month or two.
Speaker 0: There was a helium balloon stuck up there for a while Mm-hmm, and there was a fan up there and no one ever wanted to dust it because it's a pain in the ass.
Speaker 0: There was a time forget.
Speaker 0: there's a word there's a like house building word for that, but I forget.
Speaker 0: Anyway, where was I going with my onion belt story?
Speaker 1: Is the style?
Speaker 0: time was the style at the time.
Speaker 0: I completely lost my train of thought there.
Speaker 0: so it's gone.
Speaker 0: All right to make the ceilings higher.
Speaker 0: Notice how it's just the slab with some spackle paint a lot of the ceilings.
Speaker 1: There was no drop thing under it with.
Speaker 0: yeah And to get the ceiling a foot or at least a half a foot higher.
Speaker 0: There's no drop ceiling in most apartments anymore, at least fancy apartments.
Speaker 0: So the only drop ceiling I have in my apartment is in the area directly over the kitchen.
Speaker 0: So I have all the spotlights in there.
Speaker 0: that's the only end the hallway.
Speaker 1: That is the same as my apartment.
Speaker 1: the ceiling above the kitchen is slightly lower because this room is basically there.
Speaker 1: put lights in there Yeah, and then the ceiling Everywhere else is slightly higher than that.
Speaker 0: So there's literally no way you could mount a light or anything there because there's not much space between that slab and the next apartment.
Speaker 0: Yep, I guess there's the soundproofing or whatever because I don't hear anything.
Speaker 1: I heard almost nothing.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I never hear anyone which is good.
Speaker 1: If I open the window I hear a lot from outside.
Speaker 0: So I'm looking at some of these fancy form factors, and I'm really thinking about getting this weird curved lamp.
Speaker 1: How does that light that only see that feels like a lamp that shoots down and is good for like putting next to your chair Like in that picture?
Speaker 1: so like yeah, you can read, but it doesn't look like it's good for lighting a whole room.
Speaker 0: So there's another one where the LEDs are on the back of it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it only has light in the whole room.
Speaker 0: I think it might because these are way better off with the flying saucer thing.
Speaker 0: Yeah, oh, there's the crazy flying saucer thing.
Speaker 0: It's like a ring LED and then another ring LED.
Speaker 0: so it forms almost like a sphere of light.
Speaker 0: So lights going up and down and left and right and you put it in the corner of the room And it lights the whole room.
Speaker 0: crazy Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: the problem is there's no way for me to tell how well any of these weird form factors actually work in a real apartment Because there's this not like this company like this is Amazon.
Speaker 0: I'm pretty sure Amazon is the only place you can buy this stuff.
Speaker 0: Like if I go to the lighting store in New York, it doesn't have this shit.
Speaker 0: It has the $400 completely different lamps that I'm not gonna buy.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm Did we kill enough time?
Speaker 0: is the show done?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 0: got anything else to say about indoor lighting?
Speaker 0: No, cuz we didn't get home to our lighting.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna say this I hope there's someone out there listening and it's almost definitely someone out there listening knows a lot more about indoor lighting than we do And corrects the hell out of us.
Speaker 1: and yeah gives us some advice.
Speaker 1: That's usually how these shows go.
Speaker 0: is your house or apartment adequately bright?
Speaker 1: Is it actually adequately possible to be too bright?
Speaker 1: What is the brightness that it should be there?
Speaker 0: is possibly too possible to be too bright for me too bright is you know?
Speaker 0: Sometimes you go to a store Especially some Duane Reade's down and they have like the makeup section and it's like way Bright in that retail area.
Speaker 1: Well, I think that's because you really need to see colors properly.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but it's also like I get uncomfortable and my eyes start to hurt if I'm in that kind of room for more than like a half-hour Like that level of bread.
Speaker 0: There's some lobbies in New York that are like that.
Speaker 0: They're like ultra ultra crazy bright in your face.
Speaker 0: That is too bright because it's like perfectly diffuse light coming from a whole bunch of light bars all over the place.
Speaker 0: Strategically placed.
Speaker 0: that is too much But I would like this room to be about twice as bright as it is now 90% more light.
Speaker 0: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Speaker 1: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 0: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 0: But unlike those other late shows It's actually recorded at night and the patreon patrons for this episode of geek nights are Alan Joyce Rebecca Dunn Nicholas Brando Heidi McNichol Amanda Duchette Great job.
Speaker 0: emoji Ivy Faye my stady comm.
Speaker 0: William Eisen rose Jeremy minor.
Speaker 0: Every guy here'd love to be you guys and even when taking your lumps I owe nine nine nine nine.
Speaker 0: Kajar Tava shin.
Speaker 0: Do you ever wonder why we're here?
Speaker 0: Matthew Smith redacted Brian Fisher Chris Reimer?
Speaker 0: Joshua Joe star Ren from New Zealand.
Speaker 0: We got a you Daniel Redmond Sherman von Horrell Don Schleich Rochelle, Monta, Nona.
Speaker 0: Nothing shows up for that one.
Speaker 0: Chris Knox Chris midkiff rare Laval is Pronounced with an O Rar Laval.
Speaker 0: I paid five bucks to make rim say Cabbages Tyler Eller Clinton Welton Ryan Perrin Brian Cedroni had Thomas Hahn Sam Corddry Sean Klein Christian Koontz, James David White and Sean Yeager was a cop-out show today I know but we're working on a lot of stuff.
Speaker 0: So stay tuned.
Speaker 0: You see all those board game videos are going out.
Speaker 0: I got a pipeline for that.
Speaker 0: I got a pipeline for the Utena stuff.
Speaker 0: I got a whole pipeline of rims.
Speaker 0: rants that I just got a record as soon as I get a chance But I've been really busy lately.
Speaker 0: So stay tuned.
Speaker 0: stuff's coming.
Speaker 0: Don't worry.
Speaker 0: And now I leave you with Something I like talking to you.
Speaker 0: However, flare on is the only fully evolved fire type Pokemon that cannot learn solar beam.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'm working on a medley of all 17 Pokemon through the songs.
Speaker 0: Oh I can't not fuck him.