Speaker 0: It's Monday September 18th 2017.
Speaker 0: I'm rim.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott and this is geek nights tonight.
Speaker 0: We're not talking about portable electricity.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: So yesterday kind of something Emily and I started doing is every fall give or take.
Speaker 0: it's kind of random exactly when we do it.
Speaker 0: But we head upstate to a place called breakneck Ridge, which is not named after a hiker who broke his neck.
Speaker 1: It's named after a bull who broke its neck By falling off the cliff just like a hiker is likely to do so.
Speaker 0: the as the legend goes The people of Cold Spring.
Speaker 0: there was a bull that was terrorizing the farmland.
Speaker 0: So they got a bunch of farmers together and they chased it up breakneck Ridge and off breakneck Ridge Killing it and then they named breakneck Ridge breakneck Ridge.
Speaker 1: Why not kill bull Ridge or falling bull?
Speaker 0: Well the boat the mound on the other side of the river It's called Mount Taurus I believe not on the other side of the river.
Speaker 1: Storm King is on the other side of the river but everything on the other side of the river is based on animals bear Mountain bull mountain.
Speaker 1: Yeah horse mountain, but So what we usually do is we get off the train mountain.
Speaker 0: Metro North in New York has this cool thing where there's a couple of stations that aren't an actual full strain station They're just a wooden platform.
Speaker 0: That's like not even that big and some trains will stop at these little wooden platforms usually request No, you don't.
Speaker 0: actually it's for a long time.
Speaker 0: In fact at the stand of the exact right door Yep, and they they announced when the trains about to leave like where it is.
Speaker 0: but anyway So breakneck Ridge is one of those stations and it used to be.
Speaker 0: There'd be like two trains that stop there on the way up and two trains that stop there on the way down only on side.
Speaker 0: It's Saturday and Sunday But when we went this time and we do this all the time like this is a regular trip we do There were like six trains instead of the usual to a lot of people going.
Speaker 0: yeah so a lot of people are starting to do this way more than used to.
Speaker 0: Like tons of people get off at breakneck Ridge to the point that now there's all these porta-potties set up like at the station.
Speaker 0: There's like a tent set up at the trailhead with like maps and it's only sure there's a Metro North ticket machine.
Speaker 0: No, but you can just buy tickets on the train.
Speaker 0: So obviously bless who buys tickets.
Speaker 0: You have a smartphone app.
Speaker 0: I'm amazed how many people I see like in beacon frantically buying tickets at the station before the train comes.
Speaker 1: Hilarious when I'm in Grand Central and there's a line of people on the weekend at the ticket room with all the machines.
Speaker 1: Yeah and right next to the entrance to the ticket room is a giant sign that says buy your ticket with this app and it has the URL to go get the app and everything and you see someone standing with a smartphone waiting in line with the sign next to them.
Speaker 0: It is trivial to buy a ticket on the app.
Speaker 0: it just works.
Speaker 1: though, there's a woman supports Apple pay.
Speaker 1: Just go.
Speaker 0: there's a weird bug with the app that I found it has not affected.
Speaker 1: Did you find a way to get a free ticket?
Speaker 0: No, so whenever I buy a ticket right now and I show it the time it shows on the app for what time it is now and when I bought the ticket is In the Utah time zone.
Speaker 1: Oh, cuz you're stuck in the wrong time zone.
Speaker 0: No, but my phone is not in that time zone.
Speaker 1: now my phone is definitely in the right time So my phone does not have this problem.
Speaker 0: Uh, yeah, so my phone shows the time the correct time.
Speaker 0: only the Metro North app shows the wrong time.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well iPhones don't have this.
Speaker 0: no other Apple.
Speaker 0: You don't know that you haven't been to Salt Lake City.
Speaker 1: I've been to Seattle.
Speaker 0: Yeah So have I. and when I went to Seattle because I've used this app before it did not happen.
Speaker 0: It only happened after I went to Salt Lake City your phone your phone has been touched by Mormons.
Speaker 0: Yeah, something like that.
Speaker 0: It's weird.
Speaker 0: But so we did the hike and it's a metro north.
Speaker 0: It's an extremely strenuous and difficult hike and it takes us about six hours.
Speaker 0: if you do the Schofield Ridge it takes like three hours if you don't just go field Ridge because Schofield Ridge is actually way.
Speaker 0: it's a Surprisingly difficult hike over there.
Speaker 0: But anyway, we did the hike and everything was fine.
Speaker 0: We went back to Beacon and The place where I once almost it was an abandoned building.
Speaker 0: There's a lot of abandoned factories all over Beacon that I broke into almost all of them.
Speaker 0: Most of them have been turned into fancy loft apartments now.
Speaker 1: that makes sense Gentrification.
Speaker 1: we were there before it was cool.
Speaker 1: We left before it was uncool.
Speaker 0: now It got cool like way cool, but Beacon just in the last like six months Gentrified to a degree that is surprising.
Speaker 0: even knowing that they already built all these crazy lofts and all those old fact.
Speaker 1: It was slightly gentrifying when we were there.
Speaker 1: Like they started opening up more restaurants and stuff as we left.
Speaker 0: So so many people get on the train to go from Beacon back to the city on a Sunday evening that the train completely filled Mmm, and even the conductor was like, yeah, this has been a problem.
Speaker 0: I don't know what to do.
Speaker 0: Good luck.
Speaker 0: Have fun.
Speaker 0: You're gonna get to stand.
Speaker 1: probably good move moving.
Speaker 0: and on Main Street now There's a giant apartment building being built where like on Main Street used to be right in the middle.
Speaker 0: No Main Street is like way different from what you remember.
Speaker 0: It's all fancy bars fancy restaurants.
Speaker 0: Like when we lived in beacons a sushi place still there.
Speaker 0: Yeah, of course it is All right, what was a floor?
Speaker 0: was an upscale or were there even upscale restaurants in Beacon?
Speaker 1: There was the sushi place that was not upscale.
Speaker 1: It was for a while.
Speaker 1: There was cafe Maya, which was again not upscale.
Speaker 0: That was just nice.
Speaker 1: the suko Thai.
Speaker 1: Fuck you suko Thai.
Speaker 0: Fuck you.
Speaker 0: They're still there.
Speaker 1: Fuck you, but was there The.
Speaker 0: was there a restaurant in Beacon that you would consider fancy Like?
Speaker 1: what level of fanciness I mean?
Speaker 0: because the sushi place wasn't unfancy, uh, like any of the places in Vernon Jackson?
Speaker 1: No, not not it was.
Speaker 1: there was no place that was like, you know a place that someone wear nice clothing - so You could wear nice clothing suko Thai if you wanted to but fuck now.
Speaker 0: now We only if you wanted a fancy like quote-unquote upscale place.
Speaker 0: He went to like fish kill or something.
Speaker 0: There's like three upscale restaurants in Beacon now, they're building so many apartments.
Speaker 0: the craziest thing There's a giant construction going on right now right next to the train station big apartment building.
Speaker 0: It looks like where we're next to the train station Like, you know when you go up the road toward where we used to live and there's all those like old Like condos those white condos right there Like in a place that was just woods before.
Speaker 0: it's just gigantic apartment building.
Speaker 1: Okay, so yeah Someone bought the woods I feel like I Got.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna look at some real estate prices in Beacon because of all the upstate places Beacon actually has the most investment value.
Speaker 1: That is a little late.
Speaker 1: You could have you missed your chance on that one.
Speaker 0: See while I think it is late it's still not too late because the buildings they're building is like Gonna add 20% more housing to Beacon.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I was thinking like further out cheaper, but also larger.
Speaker 0: So Beacon will larger than Beacon name a town that's larger than Beacon not the town being larger the property that we buy.
Speaker 0: So anyway, I realize if you want to say if the house isn't next to a metro-north station It's also on a lake and unless it's next to a metro-north station.
Speaker 0: It's worthless and I'm out.
Speaker 1: I don't care if it's worth listen.
Speaker 1: It's I want to store stuff.
Speaker 0: No, it's not useful.
Speaker 0: If I can't just take a train to it I don't care.
Speaker 1: I can get a car.
Speaker 1: if I have a house I have a car and go there.
Speaker 0: We're gonna keep the car down here.
Speaker 0: you can leave it there leave it there.
Speaker 0: So how are you gonna get to the house to then use the car?
Speaker 1: Amanda has a car.
Speaker 0: Ah Yeah, it's all you.
Speaker 1: if you don't want to be in a town that has metro-north If you're a town that has metro-north it cost too much money and that defeats the purpose.
Speaker 0: But it still cost way less than you think Cause way too much money.
Speaker 0: How much is too much money?
Speaker 1: Like too much money.
Speaker 1: All right more.
Speaker 1: I sought to continue to pay New York rent if I didn't right.
Speaker 0: cuz that's check That Pete sent us a link to was still like a hundred and fifty.
Speaker 1: That's really cheap.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but it's a shack.
Speaker 0: It's a cabin in the woods with generator power, but it has an enormous amount of land.
Speaker 1: I've seen houses with two stories and Sewer, well, maybe not sewers but electricity and phones and internet and whatnot on a lake for 150.
Speaker 1: No, they were just dilapidated crappy houses, but they were still houses.
Speaker 0: So but beacon is Gentrified and growing to a degree that was shocking to me who already had the impression that it was gentrifying rapidly.
Speaker 0: Something changed in the last like three to six months.
Speaker 1: Oh, what's what's we instead of going to beacon?
Speaker 1: Think about what's gonna be the next beacon?
Speaker 0: I think it's gonna be it more like town has just gentrified with his.
Speaker 0: here's what I think is gonna happen.
Speaker 0: Beacon is gonna fuck like cold spring and all the towns near it.
Speaker 0: That because they don't have local economies like vegan does Cold spring I don't think can be fucked.
Speaker 1: It's got money.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but cold air is in his super mansions.
Speaker 1: They don't give a shit.
Speaker 0: Cold spring is like just commuter town as a put.
Speaker 1: like people people who live there They're giving you say about the train.
Speaker 1: Why not croaty croaty croats?
Speaker 0: Hey Curtis not that nice.
Speaker 0: There's not there's nothing there.
Speaker 1: It's not about what.
Speaker 1: you're only going to your own house Doing anything else there.
Speaker 1: No, we're at a beacon house that do stuff going to just to go to your house.
Speaker 1: If I want to do stuff, I live in New York City.
Speaker 1: I don't need to go somewhere to do stuff.
Speaker 1: I'm going somewhere to put my stuff.
Speaker 1: so my apartment in the city could have no stuff.
Speaker 0: So anyway, we got any.
Speaker 0: tech news is Monday.
Speaker 1: There's tons of tech news because we delayed because Apple was inconvenient with their timing this this Apple day Yeah, and so Apple Day was like two weeks ago, but geek nights is today.
Speaker 1: So we held on to the Apple news and somehow did not forget it and also didn't use it on a non Monday.
Speaker 1: Good job us.
Speaker 1: All right, so let's let's go Apple news real quick.
Speaker 1: Number one new Apple TV does 4k.
Speaker 1: fuck the Apple TV TV.
Speaker 1: I break its back.
Speaker 1: make it humble.
Speaker 1: It sucks chrome cast and it still sucked.
Speaker 1: the Apple TV Costs more than all the competing products like Chromecast and fire stick and I think the fire sticks actually be canceled.
Speaker 0: but yet it does less.
Speaker 1: it does less than all of those and It's big.
Speaker 1: you can just get a computer that does a raspberry pie is like cheaper and better than Apple TV and does more.
Speaker 1: Right, there is no reason to buy Apple TV for anyone even I guess if your whole life is Apple and you only do Apple things and you're only interested in doing things Apple TV does then you're paying more to get a Maybe nicer user interface.
Speaker 1: Well like on it If you're the kind of person who's buying movies on iTunes, then maybe Apple TV is good for you.
Speaker 0: That's everyone I knew used FaceTime.
Speaker 1: then that would be a better if it's literally the only thing connected to your TV because you don't Right, but the thing is I always use this analogy and I'm gonna keep using this analogy because I still believe in it, right?
Speaker 1: Here's someone who lives in a town and you never leave the town.
Speaker 1: So you say who needs a car?
Speaker 1: I never need to leave town.
Speaker 1: I've never left town.
Speaker 1: Why would I buy a car?
Speaker 1: Right?
Speaker 1: I only need to do things in the town.
Speaker 1: I'll stick with my bicycle and then one day someone forces you to leave town And you realize what you've been missing.
Speaker 1: and now you see why it was stupid to not have the car and leave town Right?
Speaker 1: That's what an Apple TV user is like.
Speaker 1: I only do things that Apple TV does.
Speaker 1: I'm never gonna need to play emulated games on my computer.
Speaker 1: I'm never gonna need to watch a video on my computer that the Apple TV won't watch for some reason.
Speaker 1: I'm never gonna need to do this.
Speaker 1: and that because I only do the Apple TV things.
Speaker 1: if you did the other fucking things Because you use something that wasn't Apple TV you'd realize how shitty the Apple TV was.
Speaker 1: now It doesn't fucking do anything.
Speaker 0: All right, so the Apple TV, so I watch three will.
Speaker 0: Really once Scott gets his then we'll talk about it.
Speaker 1: I ordered it so I get to go get it on Friday But as far as I don't want to talk about it too much.
Speaker 0: But the main reason the only feature it has is you can put a SIM card in it, right?
Speaker 1: Well, no, it has an electronic SIM card built into it.
Speaker 0: Okay, so I can have a SIM card in it.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 0: It has its own data plan, right?
Speaker 1: Well, it uses your own.
Speaker 1: it uses your data plan.
Speaker 1: you pay ten dollars extra a month in the u.s.
Speaker 1: But actually in every other country it cost more than yeah.
Speaker 1: But anyway, so yeah The main reasons I got it were it's not they didn't redesign it and make it thinner and better Which is sad right because that's what I was really waiting for.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but you know the pebble not supported anymore.
Speaker 1: Go.
Speaker 1: Bye.
Speaker 1: Bye And it's not.
Speaker 0: pebble still working a lot better.
Speaker 0: But I've noticed online just sort of a. this is purely just a sampling like self-selected sample people I know who use primarily iPhone.
Speaker 0: their pebble has been degrading or working less and less Well has always worked less with iPhone than with and with but on Android it's still working like a champ, right?
Speaker 1: But like there are lots of notifications.
Speaker 1: I'll get that won't be on my watch and then suddenly I'll get a notification on my watch.
Speaker 1: It's very inconsistent.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'm not now I'm having no problems like that.
Speaker 1: Anyway, but I mean my pebble time still works.
Speaker 1: if anyone wants a pebble time, let me know.
Speaker 0: It's pretty much the second best smartphone in the world the best one being the pebble time.
Speaker 0: steal our watch my watch anyway.
Speaker 1: So the other thing with the new Apple watch is they added this supposedly?
Speaker 1: Advanced better heart monitoring something now.
Speaker 1: I don't know if that's bullshit or not.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna find out and let you know.
Speaker 1: No, of course I don't even know if I'd be able to tell because I'm not a doctor.
Speaker 1: But if it has any merit whatsoever Right, you got to figure.
Speaker 1: heart disease kills the most people of anything in our part of the world.
Speaker 1: That is the number one killer.
Speaker 1: more than car accident.
Speaker 1: more than anything.
Speaker 1: Of course a lot of the heart disease deaths are from smoking which I don't do.
Speaker 1: But besides the point it's still the thing most likely to kill Scott is heart disease.
Speaker 0: pretty much.
Speaker 1: So if this Apple watch can in any way Even remotely provide any sort of valid information that may help to detect heart disease early and keep me alive somewhat longer right then the five whatever four or five hundred dollars it cost is Basically, that's too cheap.
Speaker 1: But also if it's true It could just be bullshit.
Speaker 0: forget your life.
Speaker 0: even an exact even like the fact that I you know I wanted the new pebble.
Speaker 0: that never came out because pebble is gone.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but it had a heart rate monitor.
Speaker 0: I don't even want Necessarily accurate information.
Speaker 0: I just want consistent information from the same source to use in my stat tracking because if you use Strava or something for exercise like when I Bike and ski and you can you can start and stop.
Speaker 1: your Strava runs from your Apple watch Of course, which I can do from my pebble.
Speaker 1: my pebble doesn't do that.
Speaker 0: Wow iPhone and pebble does really didn't work with me which me?
Speaker 1: well no it works It's just the iPhone just worked on.
Speaker 1: my pebble like iOS does not Have all of the Bluetooth things like open.
Speaker 0: I always doesn't have all of the NFC stuff like if you want to use a separate External security token like a yubikey NFC on your iPhone.
Speaker 0: It just won't work.
Speaker 0: It only works on Android.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they don't.
Speaker 1: they don't really have NFC.
Speaker 1: that they you know, they don't allow that.
Speaker 1: Yeah Cuz they want to charge you for making Apple accessories and we want you to use Apple stuff, right?
Speaker 1: You like they didn't even do Bluetooth headphones anymore.
Speaker 1: They got like their Apple X headphone thing, which is admittedly better than Bluetooth headphone.
Speaker 1: But you have to buy headphones that use it.
Speaker 1: You can't just buy any.
Speaker 0: so the trouble is on one hand like I like my smartwatch partly because it makes it easy for me to do sports like when I'm running and The having a smartwatch.
Speaker 0: even the old iPhone - I watch - would do this but you start to carry your phone with you That had independent GPS.
Speaker 0: you could theoretically get the data without the watch.
Speaker 0: the problem You're like you don't need the data plan.
Speaker 0: You'll get the GPS data because you don't need the data plan for GPS, right?
Speaker 0: The problem is Emily's tried that and the GPS and the I've watched appears to suck ass Mmm, like it's way less accurate and shitty if you don't have an iPhone with you.
Speaker 0: I wonder if the iPhone 3 I watch 3 has improved the GPS.
Speaker 1: I wonder we'll find out.
Speaker 1: I've never used the GPS.
Speaker 0: I think oh, I just want to carry my watch but when I go for long runs runs I actually want my phone with me because I might take a break and I want to read the internet The internet and I watch yeah on that tiny ass screen.
Speaker 0: No, thank you.
Speaker 1: Hey Siri, tell me what the news is.
Speaker 0: Yeah, do you actually do that?
Speaker 0: Or do you want to just read Twitter on a real screen?
Speaker 1: I watch my might want to do it instead of yeah I'm the you know Cuz.
Speaker 0: I just just leave my head if you regularly read long parts of a timeline or long news articles on your watch?
Speaker 1: Well, I imagine if I'm biking I could just like hey Siri read me the something.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but that's not what I do.
Speaker 0: I stop after running like 10.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so I don't run.
Speaker 1: Running is tiring.
Speaker 0: or I stop in Rockaway after I biked and I want to just sit and read the news while I eat a hot Dog, you know that on your watch also I like to look at a large map to navigate and plan if I'm running somewhere.
Speaker 0: I've never been before.
Speaker 1: Anyway, we'll find out how good it is, right?
Speaker 1: I still need to.
Speaker 1: you know I still need the functionality the pebble gives only better.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and the iWatch is gonna give that.
Speaker 0: so I don't think the iPhone 8 Does anything like.
Speaker 0: I guess I don't know.
Speaker 1: I think what they realize somehow is that like cuz he I bought the iPhone 3g The four the five the six and the seven right every two year and I realized aha this these s phones are bullshit.
Speaker 1: Why would you pay money to upgrade from like five to five s?
Speaker 0: Ah, but isn't the iPhone 8?
Speaker 0: even this article is like it feels like it's just the 7s, right?
Speaker 1: It's barely better.
Speaker 1: So then they went from six.
Speaker 1: I don't think they made success, right?
Speaker 0: It was six seven if I don't even remember.
Speaker 1: there might have been success, but they went from seven to eight.
Speaker 1: There's no 7s, right?
Speaker 1: They realized what I they they trying to fool me.
Speaker 1: They're like, ah, haha Scott won't know if we don't put the s that this is just a minor increment and not an actual upgrade.
Speaker 1: But you're not fooling anyone.
Speaker 1: you release the iPhone X at the same goddamn time.
Speaker 0: So so meanwhile the iPhone X. here's the thing that I gotta get out before I get anything out.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: I don't like the Continued.
Speaker 0: let's make a weird aspect ratio or have weird no-go areas on the screen for you.
Speaker 1: I don't really care about that so much.
Speaker 1: from a design The way I see it is the phone is not.
Speaker 1: any bit is just the right.
Speaker 1: It's basically the regular size of iPhone 7 which is only slightly too big.
Speaker 1: Yeah Yet the screen is as big as the iPhone 7 plus screen true because it's the whole fucking thing.
Speaker 1: You got rid of those other areas.
Speaker 1: So you're getting the giant and normal screen without the giant and normal phone.
Speaker 1: That's a good.
Speaker 1: the screen is better.
Speaker 1: It's ridiculous.
Speaker 0: Sane resolution two different UX articles from people who make iPhone apps talking about how that bar area and Slightly changing aspect ratios is increasingly.
Speaker 1: the bar area of course drives designer people crazy.
Speaker 1: But like how much do I really care?
Speaker 0: I guess why is that there?
Speaker 1: It's because it's basically that bar at the top is basically a Kinect.
Speaker 1: It's a Microsoft Kinect in there.
Speaker 0: But why not just have the bar go all the way across the top?
Speaker 1: Instead of as you get that really useless screen You know because by pushing the time and the symbols out of the way now that you gain that much more space.
Speaker 0: right True except for full-screen apps and I have to deal with it.
Speaker 1: See that's the thing I don't understand is the full-screen apps like.
Speaker 1: why should the full-screen apps even be allowed to intrude into those little areas?
Speaker 1: Those little ear areas should always contain the time and the symbols no matter what and they should only option should be to make it Black to hide them if you want like watching a video or something.
Speaker 1: that is the correct answer Should only be able to go into the space below.
Speaker 1: Why should apps be able to creep into those two notches?
Speaker 1: I guess you could if you wanted to make a cute app that does something up there like a game.
Speaker 1: No, no, but then how's that?
Speaker 1: What's that app gonna do on a regular iPhone?
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's it.
Speaker 0: None of you were clever enough to use that thing.
Speaker 0: Well what Scott suggested is the correct answer.
Speaker 1: But I guess if you're on the lock screen it can put like nice.
Speaker 1: your picture can extend up.
Speaker 1: there is kind of nice.
Speaker 0: That is dumb.
Speaker 0: why I mean just it's bet you know, oh, yeah Well, I guess the only things you should be able to use that area are the iPhones direct notification status bars itself Yeah, or apps that appear on the lock screen Probably controlled by Apple.
Speaker 1: I mean just your lock screen literal your actual lock screen background up there.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right or whatever.
Speaker 1: But yeah, it's like hell.
Speaker 0: I know that aside.
Speaker 0: the other thing I'm gonna complain about is that people are kind of talking about the pricing in a rude way because it's $1,000.
Speaker 0: No, no, no, it's not.
Speaker 1: It's like 11 or 12 hundred.
Speaker 1: It's a $1,000 for the 64 gigabyte worthless one that no one should buy because 64 gigs is not enough.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna quote this verge article because this article exemplifies what I'm talking about.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna read a sentence.
Speaker 0: It'll come in two storage configurations 64 gigabytes in other words never by for $999 and 256 gigabytes too much for a whopping One thousand one hundred forty nine dollars now 149 dollars as an incremental increase in price between 64 gigabytes and 256 gigabytes is not whopping.
Speaker 0: No $149 is default.
Speaker 0: You should not buy the small iPhone X at the same time.
Speaker 1: How much?
Speaker 1: what's it?
Speaker 1: What's a 256 gigabyte SD card go?
Speaker 0: I don't even care about that.
Speaker 1: Apple's always been that way as I'm saying, but that's the biggest deal as they still are way overcharging for the storage.
Speaker 0: There should be my Android phone.
Speaker 0: I can stick that arbitrarily sized micro SD card in there.
Speaker 1: that larger size 256 gigs cost Apple basically nothing extra to make.
Speaker 0: You're missing the port.
Speaker 0: forget that one.
Speaker 0: Apple's never gonna let you put your SD card in.
Speaker 1: No, no No, I'm saying they should have a single configuration.
Speaker 1: No Or a thousand dollars, you know how I me.
Speaker 0: the designer freaks out about those pixels on the top.
Speaker 0: So here is why app.
Speaker 0: in my opinion Apple has the 64 gigabyte so they can advertise a lower price.
Speaker 0: It exists solely so that their marketing media can say the iPhone X starts at 999 dollars.
Speaker 1: why not make those smaller one 128 so that it's actually you can buy that one.
Speaker 0: It probably because if it was 128 256 I just buy the 128 because if they make it 64 gigabytes Then a much higher percentage of people will buy the bigger correct sized one for the extra hundred forty six is actually too Much.
Speaker 1: you don't need all this space Yeah.
Speaker 0: But I literally think they just made the 64 gigabyte one nine nine nine so that they can have a price point that is under $1,000 because muggles still don't understand what smartphones actually cost because of like a decade of phone price subsidies.
Speaker 1: I have the iPhone 7 and when I got the iPhone 7 I got the upgrade plan because I was hoping for iPhone 8.
Speaker 1: That was a significant upgrade right now.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and I pay for the iPhone 7 $37 a month and that includes the best Apple care and everything.
Speaker 1: and now basically at any time starting now ish I can go and give them my iPhone and get a new one and pay the monthly fee for that and Do not have to pay 37 a month anymore, right?
Speaker 1: Pretty much all the iPhones worth getting.
Speaker 1: the old which is the iPhone X that's big Costs 50 something plus a month.
Speaker 1: Am I gonna pay $20 more every month to get that phone?
Speaker 1: It's like that's to get those pixels up there to get some extra pixels and some better cameras.
Speaker 1: It's like no for $20 more a month.
Speaker 1: I could just go spend that on plenty of other good shit.
Speaker 0: Well, I wonder where Apple might be losing some momentum.
Speaker 1: and iPhone 8.
Speaker 1: It's like, okay I could go get the iPhone 8 but it's not better in any significant way.
Speaker 1: that matters to me compared to my iPhone 7 and And it will cost me more money.
Speaker 1: so why would I do that?
Speaker 0: Apple is increasingly having trouble marketing iPhones like new versions that come out as Game-changing and revolutionary whereas Android there's no marketing around.
Speaker 0: this Android phone will fucking change your life with the keynote, but smartphones have hit sort of a plateau.
Speaker 0: Where there aren't new life-changing features that are capable of being added until battery technology or processor You could just stop overcharging.
Speaker 1: people put out that iPhone X at a lower profit margin and people will buy it like Insano and they'll kick all the Android phones asses.
Speaker 1: I don't know but Apple has never been concerned in doing that.
Speaker 1: like Ferrari could sell cars at a low profit margin and kick all The Ford's asses, but they don't do that either.
Speaker 1: It's a luxury brand.
Speaker 1: That's how they do.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but there's no.
Speaker 0: there's no way to market cutting-edge features when there's nothing new in the smartphone world.
Speaker 1: That screen is pretty new.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but it's so.
Speaker 0: it's 2436 by 1125 but by how many inches?
Speaker 0: 5.8.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: That's right the best screen on earth.
Speaker 0: That's more pixels than this fucking monitor I'm looking.
Speaker 1: that is the best screen that a consumer can buy.
Speaker 0: that is more pixels than the Dell ultra sharp I'm literally looking at right.
Speaker 1: That's why it's $1,000.
Speaker 1: Yeah for the screen alone.
Speaker 1: I would pay but not $1,000.
Speaker 0: So in other news and again, we're gonna talk about this in more depth later, but just in case you didn't notice Equifax got hacked.
Speaker 0: and normally when someone got hacked
Speaker 1: and someone got their password guessed
Speaker 0: Well, no, no No, so when someone got hacked and database got released like company got hacked not individual and information got released Usually it's
Speaker 1: SQL injection the
Speaker 0: salted rainbow table of rainbow the salted table of like password hashes Yeah and usernames, but this one's different.
Speaker 0: So if you've been ignoring this hack, the reason it's different is that the data that was breached was ahem first names last names birthdays Social Security numbers Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: That means you're fucked if your data got hacked and everyone's data is in there.
Speaker 1: If you're a United States person with credit, yeah, these companies my data is I haven't even looked Didn't they release like a thing where you can show?
Speaker 0: So I am just I so according to the reporting on this issue because I'm we're not a primary source here The website they gave out where you could check to see if you got hacked Provides random results that vary based on what browser you use to submit the exact same information.
Speaker 1: Oh, really and even I didn't check.
Speaker 1: I just assumed my stuff is in there because I read it.
Speaker 0: the click-through agreement if you check says you can't sue them.
Speaker 0: Ah So they're just evil and this is real fucking bad.
Speaker 0: I know the click-through agreement for not suing them was like if you pay for their credit No No, apparently the click-through agreement - if you use the site that would tell you if you were hacked you agree to not sue them Uh-huh.
Speaker 0: And apparently that website just returned random results according to a whole bunch of reporters who put the same data into a bunch of different Places.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: This is real bad because in the US your social security number I don't know if you I said for people to understand what Equifax is, right?
Speaker 1: There are these companies called credit bureaus and there's a law the fair credit reporting act that determines how these companies work And there's only four.
Speaker 1: but I learned today five of them.
Speaker 1: Apparently there's a fifth one.
Speaker 1: That's weird.
Speaker 1: Yeah, fourth one is actually also weird.
Speaker 1: The other three are less weird.
Speaker 1: The not weird ones are Equifax the bad one Experian and TransUnion, those are the real ones.
Speaker 1: The fourth one is in Novus.
Speaker 1: That's slightly weird.
Speaker 1: And then the fifth one I learned about just today when I was reading about this is PCR be I think or something.
Speaker 1: we don't worried about that.
Speaker 1: But what these companies do is You're they report or companies report to them Incidences that are related to people's credits like this.
Speaker 0: bum didn't pay this credit card, right?
Speaker 1: For example, the only time I had a negative report is when the hospital in Rochester Right.
Speaker 0: I remember that.
Speaker 0: I remember you bitching about that for like six years.
Speaker 1: So I didn't pay them.
Speaker 1: and if you checked if you get did a credit report on Scott Rubin to see if Scott Rubin is Someone you should loan money to and it would say yeah He's always pays every bill except for this one to this hospital.
Speaker 1: But now that's gone because there's a time limit on those things.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: So now if you look up on the credit bureau or any of them and say should I lend money to Scott Rubin.
Speaker 1: is he?
Speaker 1: Someone who will pay his bills and pay back this loan.
Speaker 1: It says absolutely.
Speaker 1: Yes God is a person who has money.
Speaker 0: these companies really is basically scores.
Speaker 0: Like how good are you at money, right?
Speaker 1: So they're what their information can significantly impact lives of every United States citizen.
Speaker 0: So here's an example if you want to buy a car They check that and if your number is too low They give you a higher interest rate or they won't sell you a car.
Speaker 1: You could try to get a job and because of information at Okofax Someone might decide not to hire you because of what these data that these come.
Speaker 0: that is legal.
Speaker 0: It is totally you you can require.
Speaker 0: try to get you.
Speaker 1: try to rent an apartment and the person renting you the apartment will ask These companies if that's a good idea and if they say no the person won't rent you the apartment.
Speaker 1: yep, your lives are if you're in the United States are extremely extremely impacted by these companies and Bottom and the top.
Speaker 0: so if you have a low credit scar, you can't get the job You need to pay off your bills.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and you can't get a cheap apartment.
Speaker 0: And if you need to buy a car because in America you need to own a car.
Speaker 0: unless you live in New York City You're gonna have to buy a car from a garbage place.
Speaker 0: That's gonna rip you off and charge a lot for a shitty car and give you high interest rate.
Speaker 0: But on the other side if you have perfect credit you get lower interest on everything.
Speaker 1: Yeah Anyway, these companies because they provide this service according to the Fair Credit Reporting Act law Whatever have everyone's fucking data.
Speaker 1: who has money in this country?
Speaker 1: Yeah They just have everyone's.
Speaker 1: it's like it might as well be a government database times four of them or five of them.
Speaker 1: tons of info out there at these companies and Equifax's IT was apparently garbage and all that got leaked.
Speaker 1: Someone just took down took their database all the infos from there about all the US citizens.
Speaker 1: now that would all their monies.
Speaker 0: But it's worse because the data that was leaked first name last name social security number birth date That's enough plus more for oh, yeah plus a lot more.
Speaker 0: and also if you Paid for services with Equifax.
Speaker 1: They got even more monies.
Speaker 0: Well, they also.
Speaker 0: some of the data is for two hundred nine thousand US people.
Speaker 0: They actually got credit card numbers.
Speaker 1: No, I did a. I got.
Speaker 1: I did my free credit report one.
Speaker 0: I did my credits like almost seven hundred.
Speaker 1: Yeah, these companies you have likes.
Speaker 1: you have to pay these companies money for them to tell you information about.
Speaker 0: You can get one a year for once a year for free.
Speaker 1: They have to tell you What your credit score is and what.
Speaker 1: but more than once a year you have to pay if you want.
Speaker 1: you're in to see if Anything happened to.
Speaker 0: actually I still have that old capital one credit card the one I got when I was in high school Mm-hmm, and they started giving me a free credit report like every month.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, Chase Bank gives me a free credit report.
Speaker 1: Yeah, she saw there's other service, but I don't.
Speaker 1: I haven't used it.
Speaker 0: I used them all to see my credit is real good.
Speaker 0: Apparently Mike.
Speaker 1: I did it once.
Speaker 1: my credit was fine.
Speaker 1: Nothing's happened since then.
Speaker 0: My credit is apparently better than someone my age should have only because I got my first credit card.
Speaker 0: I was 16.
Speaker 1: point is someone can go and take this.
Speaker 1: if someone has this data Which they can just go get a home loan.
Speaker 1: They can go get a loan and buy a house in my name.
Speaker 1: I have to find out if they did somehow.
Speaker 1: How would I know if they did?
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: So This is real bad.
Speaker 1: Someone out there claims to be Scott Reuben buys a house has a mortgage.
Speaker 1: It's written down that the Scott Reubens mortgage or living in the house.
Speaker 1: They don't pay it.
Speaker 1: then someone knocks on my door and it's like hey, how can we not paying your mortgage?
Speaker 1: I'm like what mortgage?
Speaker 0: so what?
Speaker 0: one of the things that I'm an expert in is Like sock and I all that ISO nonsense around like how do you do good IT security practices?
Speaker 0: And how do you document that you do them?
Speaker 0: And how do you prove to other people and how do you report if you're an entity that has to report on that?
Speaker 0: Like what you're doing for security.
Speaker 0: I Feel like the fact that this breach happens means that a lot of that was not happening at this company.
Speaker 0: Nope, and the fact that this company has such critical like.
Speaker 0: there's a concept a PII.
Speaker 0: I think it's Personally identifiable or identifying information.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: That kind of data is so much more dangerous and so much more highly regulated than other kinds of data.
Speaker 1: We don't even store credit card numbers at work.
Speaker 1: We just if you try to buy something from us, we use the credit card number take your money and then that's it.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, we don't let you save it or anything.
Speaker 0: You can avoid storing PII in a system that you control.
Speaker 0: it saves you a lot of headaches.
Speaker 1: That's what we do.
Speaker 0: but a company like this Failing so horribly.
Speaker 0: This is a sector that probably needs really heavy-handed regulation Mm-hmm, which is not happening And as far as I can so I looked up to see what the happening at the other three or four major places.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we learned some one of them was running PR to like say how they're not awful.
Speaker 1: Another one was like oh shit.
Speaker 1: We're gonna be worried like doomsday right?
Speaker 1: and the other one was like we're the weird one We're the discoverer of credit reporting.
Speaker 1: Yeah, who knows what's up with that anyway, but Yeah, I wonder because what I heard from eco facts the little that I heard was that their IT was so garbage.
Speaker 1: They were running like Windows Server 2003 and like the person in charge of their IT was not someone who came from an IT background which on the one hand is Perfectly fine because you know my first boss had a philosophy degree.
Speaker 1: Well, my first boss after college my current boss is a journalism degree.
Speaker 1: It's like you don't need to have you know Education in IT to work in the IT industry.
Speaker 0: CTO doesn't mean you make all the technology decisions.
Speaker 0: It means that you're the one responsible for those decisions being made right.
Speaker 0: a subtle difference between those two statements.
Speaker 1: But it still does appear that their IT setup was generally a shit show that had not been updated.
Speaker 1: That kind of old busted Windows thing.
Speaker 1: you can imagine, you know One of those companies that people still have IE 6 kind of deal But that was not the source of the breach.
Speaker 0: according to them The source of the breach was a flaw in Apache struts, which one doesn't matter if you use someone else's software.
Speaker 0: They're not.
Speaker 0: if you use someone else's software, especially open source software They are not responsible for your security.
Speaker 0: You are responsible for verifying their security.
Speaker 1: shows that the people working there were not people who were good at security.
Speaker 0: Also on top of all that Apparently some executives that krafax sold a bunch of stock right before they announced that they'd been hacked.
Speaker 1: So, how did they know that they had been hacked?
Speaker 1: if they're so incompetent IT?
Speaker 1: They must have know had some confidence to know that this had happened.
Speaker 1: maybe someone sent them a ransom note or so or maybe they found out that they were hacked and How would?
Speaker 1: how did they even find out?
Speaker 0: Uh, there's a lot.
Speaker 0: so usually what'll happen is someone will notice something hinky But That's a new word.
Speaker 0: I like that word.
Speaker 0: It's one of my favorite words lately.
Speaker 0: that implausible.
Speaker 0: But something hinky is going on.
Speaker 0: but like some ops person notices something hinky Like that's a weird DNS request.
Speaker 0: like they're looking through some logs.
Speaker 0: So they open a ticket like hey Let's look into this later.
Speaker 0: And then eventually it gets just like my desk if I worked for a company that does the kinds of stuff and I look at And go wait a minute.
Speaker 0: That's there's something up there.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna open a bunch of our tickets to look into this hinky business And then eventually a report goes up the CTO saying something fucking hinky happened.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but you sell your own stock.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I wish I should.
Speaker 1: I wish I could set up a bot that automatically detects when an insider is selling and then also sell.
Speaker 1: Yes, it just insider activity.
Speaker 0: Like if it's got people do that all the time.
Speaker 0: That's that's a common trading strategy.
Speaker 1: How do I do that?
Speaker 1: Because you know, how can Scott Rubin do that?
Speaker 0: Uh, pretty easily I mean so usually and again, I'm not giving financial advice.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm, but Insider holdings are Regulated or controlled to some degree.
Speaker 0: so like if someone who works for a big company Wants to sell a bunch of stock in the company they work for I have to say so Yeah, they make an announce So you'll see things like scheduled like some executives will schedule.
Speaker 0: like every month I am selling this number of shares on this day Mm-hmm, because they you know, they want that to be taken into account by everyone else.
Speaker 0: But apparently these Agra facts executives just fucking sold stock.
Speaker 0: And then like right before this happened and according to the news I'm reading they're now the focus of a criminal investigation.
Speaker 1: Yes You are not allowed to do the insider trading good or bad And unless you're a congressperson in the United States in which case you can do that all you want Because you just you know that a certain law is gonna happen It's gonna affect an industry and you just buy or sell stock in that industry then we could do a job dick about it, but uh Not.
Speaker 1: if you're someone who works at a company so Jail time for you.
Speaker 0: So here's the two takeaways.
Speaker 0: one If you are in any way responsible for information about people in a commercial setting Like, you know all the citizens of the United States.
Speaker 0: you should understand something about Secure our system and organization controls.
Speaker 0: I never remember what sock stands.
Speaker 1: Also other countries because I pretty sure these credit bureaus only apply to the United States.
Speaker 1: other countries Please tell me how credit reporting is handled there.
Speaker 1: Like if you need a loan and say France How do they find out if you're good for it or not?
Speaker 0: Yeah, probably way better.
Speaker 1: word of mouth like hey Oh, oh those does really have the money.
Speaker 0: Well, see there's so many problems.
Speaker 0: The problem really is that the information that was leaked should not be that dangerous.
Speaker 0: the fact that a few numbers Like a social security number is that dangerous to be leaked in the US is the real problem.
Speaker 1: I'm hoping it's one of those situations where the fact that it's fine You know, you had to wait for the egg to be cracked before people do something about it.
Speaker 0: So but I Companies or people who have this sort of information need to do real due diligence on security and Like.
Speaker 0: it's not an easy thing and it's gonna be a lot of work and cost you a lot of money.
Speaker 0: But you need to be doing it because if you're not doing it You're gonna get fucked by something like this.
Speaker 0: But my second takeaway is that if This situation is that bad and so much information is leaked that identity theft becomes endemic then credit scores Start to mean bupkis because they're filled with fake data and garbage.
Speaker 1: credit scores are already Often filled with fake data and garbage.
Speaker 0: So if you have bad credit and actually and the credit that the whole system gets undermined by this you come out.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 1: Well, if you believe that then maybe you believe in that fifth weirdo credit bureau, which relies on self-reported data.
Speaker 0: Ah Hey, I totally paid that bill that one time to that guy.
Speaker 1: Well, I think you have to prove your Reports, right?
Speaker 1: You can't just type in anything you want.
Speaker 1: You prove like your history of paying for stuff and then that's that's what's used for, you know How good you are.
Speaker 0: so really briefly the last news.
Speaker 0: Let's talk about because this is like Real technology news which we always can pull a scout always complains Seal or approval real tech news.
Speaker 0: this just happened.
Speaker 0: So like Dateline 702 p.m.
Speaker 1: Eastern talking about it for years.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but it actually happened.
Speaker 1: It happened is done.
Speaker 0: So the World Wide Web Consortium, these are the band in the consensus.
Speaker 1: These are the people who determine the formats for like HTML CSS?
Speaker 1: what's gonna be in browsers HTTP?
Speaker 1: All you know because the web is like the number one thing you use.
Speaker 1: and they did.
Speaker 1: they decide all the standards.
Speaker 1: So basically it's representatives through a bunch of companies and interest groups.
Speaker 1: They all meet and they all collaborate and decide.
Speaker 1: are we gonna remove the blink tag?
Speaker 1: All right, we're removing it.
Speaker 1: All right, CSS is gonna work like this.
Speaker 1: All right, that's how it's gonna work and they all work together.
Speaker 1: So as far as I know all the Apple Microsoft, you know Mozilla, it's like, you know, everybody's in on this.
Speaker 0: But as far as I know this stuff the consortium has almost always been done by major consensus.
Speaker 0: Yes that they wait for everyone to agree on Like the majority of what they're talking about has their rules for proceedings and voting and appeals.
Speaker 1: But generally the way it works is they all compromise and work and compromise and work together until they decide Alright, that's what the standards gonna be.
Speaker 1: everyone agrees on it and then they all vote.
Speaker 1: Yay And now I am anyone's voting.
Speaker 1: nay, they change it a little bit.
Speaker 0: I am a fan of administration by consensus.
Speaker 0: We run the RIT Anime Club that way the executive board.
Speaker 1: How do you think?
Speaker 1: Did you think you could run a country that way?
Speaker 0: Uh Maybe not a country but I'm talking about like the like local administration like running a body of some kind.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if any because.
Speaker 1: yeah, especially well because you have a small body right you have a small number of representatives in that body.
Speaker 1: It's like if you can't you know each one of those representatives represents a Significant percentage like if you have a hundred people with five representatives if one of them is going and I think you need a consensus Right.
Speaker 1: It's like you're having 20% of your people's happy, right?
Speaker 0: But this is apparently.
Speaker 0: this might be the first time they have ever abandoned.
Speaker 1: This is the first time there was an appeal ever that's for sure and it might be the first time they abandoned consensus.
Speaker 1: 50 what 58 percent agreed to this.
Speaker 0: Yeah, fifty eight point four percent agreed with this.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm It was appealed which has never happened before.
Speaker 1: 42 percent of the web.
Speaker 1: People who have to deal with the web do not want this to happen, but it's gonna happen.
Speaker 0: The appeal was denied Mm-hmm, and the EFF said fuck you and resigned from the organization, right?
Speaker 1: So the EFF is no longer involved in w3c as of today.
Speaker 1: They might rejoin but unlikely.
Speaker 0: So, what is this all about?
Speaker 0: It's whether or not to have a standard way to do DRM on the world wide web.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: I It is a complicated problem because on what he
Speaker 1: talked about this on geek nights before when it was first proposed
Speaker 0: Yeah on one hand if you don't standardize it then Private companies might put their own standards and we might get back into plug-in hell to view proprietary media.
Speaker 1: On the other hand, it's basically people want to be able to watch like beautiful amazing 4k Netflix in the browser.
Speaker 1: But Netflix, you know and the people giving content to Netflix and what and etc.
Speaker 1: We don't want to allow that because if it's through the browser Well, it could you know, you could just pirate all that shit and rip it.
Speaker 1: So because the browser is like this piece of software the users controlling so they want some kind of DRM in there to prevent that.
Speaker 1: Otherwise, they're just gonna force everyone to use like Netflix app and stuff.
Speaker 0: But on the other hand which has the DRM?
Speaker 0: anyway, if you allow it to be a standard that's a formal part of the WWW.
Speaker 0: that sort of like they cut the concept of DRM at its fundamental core is like directly Contradictory to the goals of the world wide web as stated when it was created.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm The idea is that information should always be you have a certain shareable sortable linkable.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you have a server.
Speaker 1: someone sends.
Speaker 1: get with a URI.
Speaker 1: you're supposed to send them that thing.
Speaker 1: You're not supposed to be like, alright, here's that encrypted thing.
Speaker 1: Did you pay money?
Speaker 0: So I am heavily like.
Speaker 0: I'm even fairly ambivalent on the between ideology and pragmatism.
Speaker 0: But in the end, I sort of feel like the fuck you to.
Speaker 0: DRM is more important than the standardization right now.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm Like, you know DRM was like is on the downswing, right?
Speaker 1: It's like all the DRM on PC games are getting busted and you know, making people unhappy.
Speaker 1: You know DRMs and other things, you know app I all the music services like iTunes doesn't have DRM anymore.
Speaker 1: You just download mp3s or ACs in that case, right and they just play.
Speaker 1: they're just file.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right DRM was taking a beating, you know We don't need to see DRM make a comeback and the very least I also don't.
Speaker 0: I don't really want to dilute the like the magic of what the world wide web was Even though we've sort of gone very far from what the world wide web originally was.
Speaker 0: those core guiding philosophies I think are still important and I'm actually very proud that the EFF was willing to walk away from this organization.
Speaker 1: Well, it doesn't help.
Speaker 1: the EFF's representative at the w3c is actually number one anti DRM.
Speaker 1: Well number two anti DRM person after Richard Stallman Corey doctor.
Speaker 0: Oh, so but this is this undermines the authority of the w3c to a degree Because the w3c's authority came primarily from the fact that everybody agreed.
Speaker 0: in the end.
Speaker 1: There's still a lot of questions as to whether like for example Mozilla will implement right and such and such Yeah Or whether like will the Firefox fork on Linux the ice weasel?
Speaker 0: if that's still how they do We don't know what's gonna happen.
Speaker 0: Yes, result of all there are some browsers gonna break from.
Speaker 1: the standard is like what's gonna happen here, right?
Speaker 1: 42% of web things gonna not work right.
Speaker 1: a movie.
Speaker 0: This is the moment of drama.
Speaker 0: We're like the representative of one of the countries in the UN in a movie Like slams their fist on the table and walks away and abandons the UN.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: So what happens next?
Speaker 0: Nobody knows.
Speaker 0: But anyway things of the day.
Speaker 0: so real quick, you know, I'm a big fan of roller coasters and Cedar Point.
Speaker 0: So I found this video while I was looking for another video and it's basically a roller coaster nerd talking about Most of the roller coasters that Existed at Cedar Point over the last hundred years that no longer exist and talks about like what their deal was.
Speaker 1: Are there any that you haven't been on mr.
Speaker 1: Cedar Point fanboy?
Speaker 0: Yes, many of them.
Speaker 0: so I haven't been on this one that was built in 1908 and shut down in 1917.
Speaker 0: Okay, I'm sure okay From 1929 they tore it down in 1951.
Speaker 0: I did not ride that one.
Speaker 0: Okay, but I have ridden Oh jumbo jet which my parents have ridden on Oh, but it was shut down in 78.
Speaker 0: So I was not ridden on it.
Speaker 0: Okay, but Several of these I have ridden on like avalanche run Disaster transport the Wildcat the second while disaster transport is a way cool name.
Speaker 0: It was a pretty cool coaster.
Speaker 1: It's taken down.
Speaker 0: I'd taken.
Speaker 0: so here's I'll tell you the story of this one cuz it's real short.
Speaker 0: There was a roller coaster that was part roller.
Speaker 1: I just like the name good name part flume.
Speaker 0: So the roller coaster was I love me a flume.
Speaker 0: It was on a rail, but not water flume just flume without water.
Speaker 0: Oh, so basically it was on rails But then it would go off the rails into like a halfpipe and then go back onto rails.
Speaker 0: It was really cool.
Speaker 1: If it was a water flume, that would be my favorite ride ever.
Speaker 0: So they got rid of that.
Speaker 0: There was a water flume.
Speaker 0: There was very similar.
Speaker 1: There's a roller coaster.
Speaker 1: That's a log shape and then at the end The tracks and then it goes blue White water line And then they sort of fish the logs back onto the track.
Speaker 0: There was the log ride and white water landing which was also a flume.
Speaker 1: Usually when you do a flume, it's just up and then sploosh.
Speaker 0: There was one like that.
Speaker 0: I think it was called white water landing, but they tore it down.
Speaker 0: I wrote it a lot.
Speaker 1: But anyway, I'm all about the flume.
Speaker 0: they shut down avalanche run But instead of tearing down the coaster They built a building around the entire coaster and they turned it into disaster transport Which was basically a better space mountain.
Speaker 0: Like legit better space mountain And then they tore that down.
Speaker 1: I mean the best part of space mountain is the space and not the mountain.
Speaker 1: Yeah, everyone knows that.
Speaker 0: but yeah, this video is just like a real nerd history and the real crazy takeaway from this video is that There is not a lot of documentation of things like have these roller coasters like one of them that Existed for like 20 years.
Speaker 0: the guys like.
Speaker 0: this is the only known photo of this coaster in the world and nobody Actually knows who built it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, no one was caring or keeping track of these sorts of things like they were historic.
Speaker 1: It was just like some carny amusement park.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so just kind of think of it as like an important thing to you know.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'll leave the dips.
Speaker 0: So anyway, this video is pretty good.
Speaker 1: Okay, so I got two sort of two things of the day.
Speaker 0: So I'm taking a play from the rim handbook.
Speaker 1: Not really the sort of related.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna make them related.
Speaker 1: So I found out today that you can buy on Amazon for like 40 bucks Endoscopes, I don't know if they're safe to shut up.
Speaker 0: You better not be announcing your new twitch channel.
Speaker 1: I don't know if you can shove these up your ass or down your throat safely.
Speaker 0: You've just got you definitely can.
Speaker 0: the question is not can but should?
Speaker 1: I don't know if these are medical endoscopes But the point is they're.
Speaker 1: they're law their cameras at the end of long thin snakey devices, right?
Speaker 1: And they come in both wireless and wired.
Speaker 1: so you could like connect onto your phone and like see what the camera sees.
Speaker 1: We're just holding your phone and the USB ones.
Speaker 1: I assume just work like webcams.
Speaker 0: So I think we don't want to watch Scott's livestream if it suddenly starts.
Speaker 0: three, right?
Speaker 1: So first of all, is it is would you watch you know endoscope videos on YouTube?
Speaker 1: Right, so I figure even if you're not using this for YouTube purposes, okay I cooked on one of these.
Speaker 0: most of the pictures are like I'm trying to fix my air conditioner.
Speaker 0: I shove it up there to see what's going on inside exactly.
Speaker 1: How useful is this thing?
Speaker 1: You can look under the couch without getting your head on the floor.
Speaker 1: You can look behind the stove.
Speaker 1: You can look dude.
Speaker 1: This one has accessories.
Speaker 0: It has a hook extension a magnet extension.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you can look in your throat when you're sick to see if there's anything in there, right?
Speaker 1: You can look at your asshole not I'm not in it but like at it without using like five mirrors.
Speaker 0: Right, it only takes me two mirrors tops.
Speaker 1: It's still two.
Speaker 1: It's still more than zero mirrors, right?
Speaker 1: It's like.
Speaker 1: this is just a really really really useful thing to have.
Speaker 1: I'm not gonna buy one right now But as soon as I'm the next time I'm at my house our apartment I might buy this one.
Speaker 1: I just clicked on and I'm thinking to myself man.
Speaker 1: It would be really useful to have an endoscope.
Speaker 1: right now I'm doing I'm using like two mirrors to look at my asshole at that.
Speaker 1: at that moment I will click go to Amazon.
Speaker 0: Oh this guy stuck it into his wall to help with a cable run.
Speaker 1: Oh, look at that.
Speaker 1: How great is it?
Speaker 1: You can wait.
Speaker 0: wait a lot of why is this?
Speaker 1: Just a picture of a bathroom because a lot of people are using it on the drains of tubs and sinks to see what the Hell is down there.
Speaker 0: But no This is just so.
Speaker 0: the pictures are Like looking.
Speaker 1: so like look down your sink to see if you dropped your ring down there before you take the catch-off to say That's where it actually went.
Speaker 1: How useful is that?
Speaker 1: saves you so much work?
Speaker 0: Oh, I know what I could do the livestream of go to places that like outside a building somewhere Especially in New York and just go up into like weird places that are not necessarily publicly accessible.
Speaker 1: Oh, you know you're walking down the street.
Speaker 1: There's like a tiny hole cut in something.
Speaker 1: stick the endoscope through the hole.
Speaker 1: now You can see everything is going on back there stick it down the great.
Speaker 0: You know all those great in New York City, you'll see greats.
Speaker 0: and sometimes down there It's just like the subway but sometimes like down there like when you used to go to those events down in Mercer those gaming nights at the think cafe you look down a great and it's like 50 or 60 feet deep and there's like a room down
Speaker 1: there.
Speaker 1: I got a fair.
Speaker 1: which endoscope has the best light?
Speaker 1: at the end of it?
Speaker 1: You can't get one without a light.
Speaker 0: this one comes with a mirror a hook and a magnet does have a light.
Speaker 0: I yes, there's an LED.
Speaker 0: You can just turn on.
Speaker 1: That's the important part because you're usually gonna be looking in dark places.
Speaker 1: Anyway, endoscope is thing a day.
Speaker 1: now if you have an endoscope, you know to look at your to look at your backside there You might want to still you know, do something about protecting your front side.
Speaker 1: So here is a typical weigh-in for a boxing match.
Speaker 1: I don't even know who these boxers are But one of the boxers I assume the one on the left brought his kid to the to the weigh-in which is cute and his kid like father like son, let's just say and Yeah, the guy on the right, you know, he's probably got enough money from boxing.
Speaker 1: I don't know if an endoscope will help him.
Speaker 0: I Got these guys come in real quick to break it up.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah, this is this is a the best 42nd video I saw today.
Speaker 0: Okay, it couldn't have been too bad cuz he's laughing at the.
Speaker 1: yeah I mean it was a little kid right but still That's it's not hit.
Speaker 0: Yeah strike.
Speaker 0: That's right in the moment.
Speaker 0: The booklet book is the fifth season.
Speaker 1: I just read a chapter of this book with some terrible secret of earth.
Speaker 0: Holy shit, this book going places and We were at the penny arcade Expo in Seattle And we did a panel on rage quitting and guess what.
Speaker 0: that whole panel is on YouTube in glorious 2k Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: I didn't do 4k cuz that it would have been like a 30 gigabyte export.
Speaker 1: now this week this week We are gonna make a video of.
Speaker 1: I'm saying it some rim has to do it.
Speaker 1: I'm doing it.
Speaker 1: I'm on it cuz you didn't.
Speaker 1: you didn't do it this weekend you went hiking instead.
Speaker 0: We gotta do video, you know what you didn't do it the day.
Speaker 0: I could do it cuz you were hanging out with your mom.
Speaker 1: So well, you know what you're gonna do.
Speaker 0: Hey, what are you gonna do?
Speaker 1: It's raining this week, though.
Speaker 1: Yep, so we're gonna do this video judge anime by its cover and we're gonna do it four times a year.
Speaker 1: So that now it's coming out this week.
Speaker 1: So you should subscribe to our YouTube channels cuz who knows what YouTube channel that video is gonna be on.
Speaker 1: Yeah One of the other whichever maybe both why not?
Speaker 0: So we've already gone 53 minutes.
Speaker 0: I think we just did a tech news roundup.
Speaker 0: No, I don't think we have time to talk about batteries.
Speaker 1: Why not?
Speaker 0: because I'm hungry and we've already gone.
Speaker 0: an hour and ten minutes is not enough time.
Speaker 1: But we didn't even do a main bit at all.
Speaker 0: We just died.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: Do you have a domain bit that only last five minutes?
Speaker 1: Why how do what?
Speaker 1: there's no way we have talked for?
Speaker 0: 54 minutes almost.
Speaker 1: it doesn't feel like that.
Speaker 1: We don't usually don't mess up our timing like this.
Speaker 0: We talked a lot in the front bit.
Speaker 0: How do we didn't?
Speaker 1: we just did two newses?
Speaker 1: Well three newses, oh you did a third news.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we did the third news cuz they're all really big newses.
Speaker 1: Yeah, this is rims fall.
Speaker 1: I do not approve.
Speaker 0: I feel like we just talked about Apple.
Speaker 1: I do not approve next Monday show.
Speaker 0: We'll talk about the iPhone the iWatch I keeps an iPhone do the iWatch and we'll do batteries.
Speaker 1: I do not approve of this Un-eu-serped tech news roundup, it's not allowed.
Speaker 1: This is rim doing this.
Speaker 0: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Speaker 1: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 0: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows It's actually recorded at night and the patreon patrons for this episode of geek nights are Alan Joyce Heidi McNichol Amanda Duchette roundabout at mp3 mystated.com.
Speaker 0: William Eisneros Jeremy minor a genuine bonafide like five six car monorail Matthew Smith Nicholas Brando captain Chinguac asi Rebecca Dunn for two one creations.
Speaker 0: Even if we were to pull out today and if with a word come take our base.
Speaker 0: Shervin von Horrell rarely.
Speaker 0: Val James David White Rochelle, Montana Superboy Sailor Moon Moon Sailor Vista Don Schleich Jartavish and Jojo Joestar Shawn Yeager Sam Corddry Clinton Walton Ren from New Zealand Ryan Perrin drew open ladder Brian Cidroni Finn Chris made Kiff Chris Knox Daniel Redmond Shawn Klein Chris Reimer and Thomas Hahn.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we blew way too much time the beginning of the show talking about a bunch of stuff kind of ad hoc.
Speaker 0: So we will do the battery show on the next Monday episode of geek nights And that'll make up for the fact that we did not talk about portable electricity tonight.
Speaker 0: So now I leave you with.