Speaker 1: It's Monday May 1st 2017.
Speaker 1: I'm rim I'm Scott and this is geek nights tonight Drm because I guess we never did a show on this in the last 12 years.
Speaker 1: I can't Can't find one in the database.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: This is the second time in recent memory.
Speaker 1: one of us said hey Why don't we do a show on X?
Speaker 1: and the other one said?
Speaker 1: We have definitely done a show on X and the first one agreed and then in searching the database There wasn't one.
Speaker 1: there has to be.
Speaker 1: I can't find one.
Speaker 1: if you find a show we did Specifically about digital rights management.
Speaker 1: My head is off to you and I will eat my hat.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm You know all your hats.
Speaker 1: I'm not eating all my heads.
Speaker 0: I will eat a hat which head Have a area.
Speaker 0: I'm sort of small your leather cowboy hat that you from the RIT days.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, that's good hat.
Speaker 1: I like that hat.
Speaker 0: eat it.
Speaker 0: It's right edible.
Speaker 0: It's leathery, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, you drive to boil it.
Speaker 0: Sure boiling is fine.
Speaker 1: I'd probably better off eating that hat than eating the felt hat.
Speaker 0: That's I'm saying.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so remember the last time we did a Monday show I talked about my computer That was blue screen and how I replaced the motherboard and then it still was blue screen in.
Speaker 0: yeah I remember that and I was upset.
Speaker 0: I was like, oh, why did I waste my time updating the motherboard?
Speaker 0: Wasn't actually the problem.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and I was like, oh well, you know, it could.
Speaker 0: what was it was this?
Speaker 0: was it that?
Speaker 0: so I Removed.
Speaker 0: I had two SSDs in my computer the old one, which is the first SSD I ever bought.
Speaker 0: It's like maybe Four years old something like that four or five years old.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: it's old The old one.
Speaker 0: and then there's a newer one that I have that I bought more recently that's the Samsung one.
Speaker 0: that's better right now.
Speaker 0: So that old one is now relegated just being like the scratch drive.
Speaker 1: right that's what I've been doing with my old 32 gigabyte.
Speaker 0: So it's only used when I'm like using Adobe stuff.
Speaker 0: Otherwise, it's not being used at all.
Speaker 0: It's just in there with no data being written to yep or from it whatsoever.
Speaker 1: So, you know I've noticed because I have a my giant like multi terabyte like many terabyte drive.
Speaker 1: I set it up to our only Adobe stuff and static media is on it.
Speaker 1: So it literally if I ever like start an Adobe project I hear that drive spin up.
Speaker 0: The point is this old SSD that was in there.
Speaker 0: of the two SSDs I had I unplugged it because number one I hardly use it except when I'm Adobe ink so it doesn't matter if it's unplugged too much.
Speaker 0: and B Was it really the cause of blue screens?
Speaker 0: Well, I can tell you.
Speaker 0: Since unplugging it two plus weeks ago.
Speaker 1: I have had Zero Blue screens.
Speaker 1: I would not have predicted that.
Speaker 0: Okay, this makes this is new to me, right?
Speaker 0: How can an SSD a drive a storage drive that is merely plugged into a computer that is not being used?
Speaker 0: No data written to or from it?
Speaker 0: How can that cause blue screens so frequently while the computer is doing other unrelated things not even accessing that drive?
Speaker 0: that could make sense if say the SAT a controller on the board was busted.
Speaker 0: that might cause blue screens, but we changed motherboards Yeah, and we were having blue screens on both of them.
Speaker 0: It would make sense if the GPU is causing blue screens and these blue screens were having Various error messages of all shapes and sizes not one consistent error.
Speaker 1: I got some guesses I think but it's all it wasn't.
Speaker 0: My RAM tests were always like a plus your RAM is totally good and my RAM was totally good You know, but I was just because RAM makes more sense for a blue screen.
Speaker 1: It was like the primary cause.
Speaker 0: Take would have made so much more sense for these random blue screens.
Speaker 1: But so here's my guess cuz you gotta use its process of eliminations.
Speaker 0: since that old bud busted SSD has been removed No blue screens.
Speaker 0: I should put it in someone's computer and see if it makes blue screens.
Speaker 1: So it's not data coming on or off of that drive obviously And it's probably not something like physical on the motherboard is one of the odds.
Speaker 1: you have two mother two motherboards are the same.
Speaker 1: Right, so either that drive Way because even though you're not accessing it the SATA controller still like initializes it or whatever.
Speaker 0: Like I'm gonna crash just like rent sometimes for a long time.
Speaker 0: Sometimes a short time.
Speaker 1: So maybe if it has a internal problem where occasionally it'll send spurious voltages up that SATA cable.
Speaker 1: I Could be that's already a pretty like esoteric impossible to troubleshoot.
Speaker 0: probably shouldn't it not cut like.
Speaker 0: There should be some fault detection and protection.
Speaker 1: it should be some protection in the motherboard Protection in the code to say hey don't crash in the half No But you can't put that everywhere because like putting voltage protection one can cause problems with bandwidth, especially like high-speed things uses.
Speaker 1: Yeah old invention uses introduce latency and trouble depending on how they could say they're also big.
Speaker 1: Generally, you only protect like the power in places where you're likely to get weird power situations like from the power supply Yeah, but not from like a SATA cable plugged into a hard drive.
Speaker 0: Oh, it could have been also maybe on the power.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the other thing would be it might have a problem where it over and under draws or just something weird causing the PSU to Have a momentary fault.
Speaker 1: that then causes the system to get unstable.
Speaker 1: Those are both stretches.
Speaker 1: That's weird.
Speaker 1: We should.
Speaker 1: we should put you know what?
Speaker 1: I got a couple extra computers.
Speaker 1: Give me the drive.
Speaker 1: I'll just plug it into my HTTP.
Speaker 1: see out there and see if it blue screens.
Speaker 0: All right, just you got to keep running for a while.
Speaker 0: See you happen.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 0: So cuz the thing is the drive never misbehaved.
Speaker 0: every time I wrote data to it it worked.
Speaker 0: every time I like that drive.
Speaker 1: You had an RIT that had that one sector where you hear the you hear it like have a platter.
Speaker 0: It's an SSD.
Speaker 0: That can't happen.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but that you had an old hard drive.
Speaker 1: Using this drive.
Speaker 0: it appears to be a perfectly functioning 128 gigabyte SSD and it did not cause blue screens until you know, whenever.
Speaker 1: yeah Oh my god Linkiji in the chat had a hard a laptop hard drive that was like plug-and-play key.
Speaker 1: Oh, you can unplug it an external one.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: He would get a blue screen Reliably about an hour after he unplugged it Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: So I don't know, you know, it's kind of an old motherboard in terms of like it's from an era.
Speaker 1: Maybe SATA controllers are a little less for a bus back.
Speaker 0: Well, I mean I'm saying is this drive?
Speaker 0: this SSD is a Corsair brand SSD from way back.
Speaker 0: So I can't imagine this would be a problem for anyone buying new SSDs and you're only buying Samsung ones these days.
Speaker 0: Right, so, you know our Intel ones which are fine But slower.
Speaker 1: because I had an SSD go through the traditional failure recently my old 2009 laptop.
Speaker 1: I had to replace its you know, one SSD that I paid a lot of money for in 2009.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that drive was not cheap when I bought it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, this old 32 gig SSD just like Windows like I go to play a video at a con and then Windows.
Speaker 1: It's just like some libraries are missing.
Speaker 1: So I'm like, okay, that's weird.
Speaker 1: I'll just use VLC.
Speaker 1: I run VLC and the VLC complains about some DLL files having a problem.
Speaker 1: and a little bit more investigation I think half that file system had single bit errors like just littered throughout it.
Speaker 1: scan disk Yeah, and scan disk crash.
Speaker 1: No, I tried it again.
Speaker 1: scan disk crash and I gave up.
Speaker 1: and I just bought a new hard drive FSCK.
Speaker 1: yeah, and when I'm once I put the new hard drive in one.
Speaker 1: modern SSDs are way faster than old SSDs.
Speaker 1: Yes, and to the laptop?
Speaker 1: is this SSD?
Speaker 0: even those old was still six gigabit per second.
Speaker 0: SSDs.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know but there.
Speaker 1: but while they have six gigabit, you know They're they use that standard.
Speaker 1: old SSDs tend to actually have pretty low or pretty high latency Compared to what modern SSDs do like.
Speaker 0: I expect that SSD like, you know fail in the way.
Speaker 0: an SSD fails where it starts running Out of sectors.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and then you start.
Speaker 0: I don't expect it to randomly blue-screen your computer with no indications that it was the SSDs fault In any of the error messages anywhere.
Speaker 1: So what's interesting is in old computers like but like.
Speaker 1: I think the 486 was the end of this era Where like when I bought my first 46 my family about one.
Speaker 1: it came with a manual and the manual actually even went down to Voltages and pin outs and like motherboard diagrams.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's a holdover because before then you'd be buying computers like, you know Coleco's not Coleco's Radio Shack Coco - or a Tandy something.
Speaker 0: or you know Even Apple Apple twos and Amigas.
Speaker 0: they all came with those things.
Speaker 0: even the stereo that I bought It was like, you know, they.
Speaker 0: it was like a piece of furniture that had two giant speakers and a turntable and you know Dual cassette decks were dubbing or whatever.
Speaker 0: that came with a complete circuit diagram.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it was a thing.
Speaker 0: all electronics that you also be able to throw a long up until like, you know early mid 90s Every time you bought some piece of electronics it came with like a complete circuit diagram.
Speaker 0: It was just the thing.
Speaker 1: the physicality of what you were doing with electricity and older computers Was a lot simpler like when I was at RIT, this wasn't that long ago, right?
Speaker 1: one of the early classes we took that was actually interesting was all about signal processing and We spent a lot of time learning about all the different networking standards.
Speaker 1: and like buses like computer buses and the actual token ring physical electrical Signaling like here is the kind of wave like, you know differential Manchester or whatever.
Speaker 1: What is used in modern networking is so much more complicated than that stuff that all of that knowledge is literally worthless today.
Speaker 0: But then I mean gigabit ethernet isn't just the same thing only fast.
Speaker 1: No, no, no, no, no, no No, so yeah, like Manchester encoding is pretty.
Speaker 0: that was that was from the 10 megabit days.
Speaker 1: Yeah Yeah, and we and actually like we're old enough at RIT Literally use 10 base - yeah.
Speaker 1: and token ring.
Speaker 0: so I didn't use token ring.
Speaker 0: I used 10 and 100. but now we're using gigabit.
Speaker 1: Yeah You didn't use the 10 base - with the with the vampire clamps or no 10 bed the 10 base 5.
Speaker 1: There was the one with the thick coax cable.
Speaker 1: You shove these vampire clamps in to make basically a ghetto hub now.
Speaker 1: and then the other one was the tees.
Speaker 1: we get the tea Junctions the back.
Speaker 1: Yes, computer.
Speaker 1: That's 10 base - okay tees You're like twist it in and in and then you got to have a terminator on that last computer.
Speaker 1: I've seen those Yeah stuff's all obsolete.
Speaker 1: But my point is that back then in those classes I took we could literally plug oscilloscopes or other devices into network cables and by looking at waveforms and using like voltimeters Troubleshoot problems.
Speaker 1: I don't think it's feasible to do that kind of troubleshooting on modern computers.
Speaker 1: too much data Yeah and the kind of equipment you would need that would be sensitive enough is probably out of the realm.
Speaker 1: like Flukes are not even cheap and modern flukes are probably way more expensive even Good times.
Speaker 1: So, uh, I was this weekend at Zenkai con.
Speaker 1: I did three panels.
Speaker 1: So if any of you are here because you saw those panels a lot of people were really, you know That's not an audience that typically sees our stuff.
Speaker 1: most of the people in these mostly full rooms No idea who I was and only one person walked out and I think they had to go to the bathroom based on their body Language, so it was a good time, but I got to tell you Zenkai con is great and I have a lot of fun there.
Speaker 1: independent of that Lancaster got a Lancaster.
Speaker 0: That's why I don't go there.
Speaker 1: It is the only city I have been to in my entire life where a City, it's just technically a city village.
Speaker 1: people on the street townies will come up to strangers and have adversarial interactions with them.
Speaker 1: and But they are not actually panhandling.
Speaker 1: They're just being aggressive over nothing.
Speaker 1: I had people just like bothering us and like like random people will come up to you and just say Unintelligible things to you regularly, but none of them are panhandling.
Speaker 1: They're just townies living there accosting strangers who came to town.
Speaker 0: They say uh, she's just walking down the street and someone comes He'll walk up to you and a lot of them would.
Speaker 1: some of them were just asked like what's going on with the freak show What's up with all the costume weirdos, but some of them would just say gibberish like.
Speaker 1: I did not understand What.
Speaker 1: a lot of them is.
Speaker 0: not just crazy, Pennsylvania sticks accent But you know what?
Speaker 1: It might be my guess not not to be.
Speaker 0: Hey, can I get a glass of water?
Speaker 1: If I had to guess to paraphrase someone else who was in our group the spice must flow Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: So I suspect it might have been some spice and or met that was going on.
Speaker 0: That is a problem in much of this country.
Speaker 0: a lot of the people who are People keep talking about how this meth is a problem and I don't want to talk too long about this cuz Monday.
Speaker 0: Yeah, let me just say isn't that a problem that solves itself.
Speaker 1: Really?
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: No because it doesn't.
Speaker 1: so It takes too long to have that super dark timeline outcome that you're alluding to.
Speaker 0: Oh, maybe I should get it on this.
Speaker 0: I Get a long time before.
Speaker 1: Also, like meth is just an amphetamine and amphetamines have their own problems.
Speaker 1: There's a separate problem of you know, unclean meth made in bathtubs or whatever, but I mean we had that problem with cheese, too Yeah, but in general should I avoid cheese?
Speaker 1: in general stimulants like that have a lot of Positive by some definitions effects and a lot of negative by all definitions effects.
Speaker 1: So like, you know during World War two like both us and the Germans and a lot of the armies Just gave meth to soldiers like all the time if he made a YouTube video of doing meth.
Speaker 0: Was that not allowed?
Speaker 0: I do.
Speaker 0: I do not want to try crystal meth, but you were the one who was gonna try it.
Speaker 0: I don't even drink alcohol.
Speaker 0: You're the one who has to do the best.
Speaker 1: But to otherwise the con was great but there was a moment on Friday night It was like midnight and we we went to have some drinks for hanging out.
Speaker 1: So all of us are walking back to our hotel, which is like we're just like north of the train station.
Speaker 1: So we're walking through town and we see these two guys and they see us and they all hey and start running at us.
Speaker 1: so we brace for impact and then they pull up and they're just like the most stereotypical like live-in Philly dudes and The discourse we had with them boiled down to yo you look like you from around here.
Speaker 1: Where the fuck can a man get some food in this country ass town?
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm, and I were they in that country ass town.
Speaker 1: It was their first zenk icon.
Speaker 0: Why were they in zenk icon?
Speaker 1: Cause zenk icon is pretty fun.
Speaker 1: I don't know why you're so down on zenk icon.
Speaker 1: I played more tabletop games with quality people at this zenk icon than I did at the last Pac South.
Speaker 1: Sure We just did nothing but play Pac South.
Speaker 0: you got other shit to do.
Speaker 0: Like what?
Speaker 1: What did you do at Pac South other than play tabletop games?
Speaker 1: We were other than running your panel, which I also did.
Speaker 0: Ate food, walked around an expo hall Played some games that weren't tabletop games.
Speaker 1: Like what?
Speaker 0: Name one Forget the name.
Speaker 1: Yeah that game.
Speaker 1: I remember that game.
Speaker 1: That game was pretty good.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: It was a good game.
Speaker 1: I'll come back to zenk icon next year.
Speaker 0: Oh I remember watching that hearthstone tournament.
Speaker 1: Also Apparently now that Pacs has negotiated to be in the Philly Convention Center I learned from a couple people because I didn't know a lot about that convention center.
Speaker 0: You went there.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I don't know a lot about it.
Speaker 1: Like I know a lot about the BCEC and the BCC and the Hines just cuz like, you know For various research I never knew shit about the Philly Convention Center.
Speaker 1: But apparently the reason building you've been in yeah, but I why would I have studied it?
Speaker 0: I'm just saying.
Speaker 1: You wanna run a convention there?
Speaker 0: No.
Speaker 1: So apparently the reason no one ran conventions there was that the unions would basically just say no.
Speaker 1: like that that convention center was notorious For having the worst possible union interactions you could have.
Speaker 1: Apparently you had to negotiate with five separate unions who all had Required hours and overtime and everything to do anything in that convention center, and that's why nothing is really there.
Speaker 1: so apparently they consolidated that and now you only have to negotiate with one union and Some people have implied to me that it might have been because Pacs sort of like came in with money and said listen guys it's not really clear what happened, but Might maybe some guy could move into that convention center Being downtown grow because they were already outgrowing the shockingly big Convention Center in Lancaster.
Speaker 1: Like since you've been a few years I make it bigger.
Speaker 0: It is it is way big just a Marriott Hotel when I was there.
Speaker 1: No, it's in a full-on convention center like a pretty big one.
Speaker 1: Oh when I was there I mean it's connected to the Marriott the Marriott, but it has a whole bunch of big spaces.
Speaker 1: It's just completely full.
Speaker 1: every hotel in the whole city was full and in fact That's not a lot of hotel.
Speaker 1: when we got to our days in There was a line of people waiting to check in and they were all having drama and trouble.
Speaker 0: I'm blazing at the daisies.
Speaker 1: It looks like most of them were at the wrong days in because they were kids.
Speaker 1: they didn't know how to make hotel reservations And the rest of them were trying to get a hotel in town because they drove to town Not just expecting they could get a hotel room and literally every hotel in the entire city was sold out and they were getting desperate.
Speaker 1: So later that night our hotel put up a no vacanee sign.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: It was spelled wrong.
Speaker 1: So no vacanee.
Speaker 1: Yeah That hotel was the third worst hotel.
Speaker 1: I've ever slept at in my life, by the way Do not ever is worse than the Chai live motor in.
Speaker 1: no Is the third word.
Speaker 1: the Chai motor in is the second worst and the family and I stayed at like 80 miles outside of Gatlinburg.
Speaker 1: Tennessee is probably the worst Child.
Speaker 0: that motor in The family in the door did not lock the child.
Speaker 1: I might be the worst as we pushed a couch up to the door to lock the door.
Speaker 0: You can always go stay in one of the like nightmare cockroach bedbug places in Times Square area for one night.
Speaker 0: You just walk over and stay there.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's only like a hundred bucks a night - yeah There was.
Speaker 1: so you want to read what might be the whitest article anyone's ever written on the internet.
Speaker 1: this like white tech bro Dude blogger wrote a whole article about his adventure booking a room in that hotel and spending the night and how horrifying it was.
Speaker 1: and it is just the Dumbest article you will ever read.
Speaker 1: Hmm, but yeah, it's Monday.
Speaker 1: It's May.
Speaker 1: It's May day, too.
Speaker 1: So Happy eight-hour days workers rights and such.
Speaker 1: but Amazon you also have Labor Day.
Speaker 0: why we need two days Day is fucking five days a week.
Speaker 1: May day covers a lot of things though.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but it's the first Early May.
Speaker 1: all the fun things between now and May 5th is all the fun.
Speaker 0: biz, you know, what starts today?
Speaker 1: Gatlinburg family in has some a-plus meth.
Speaker 1: You get enough people in that chat.
Speaker 1: so anyway in actual tech news, we wasted like 20 minutes talking about this.
Speaker 1: Amazon announced a service that's actually pretty Important I think to the ecosystem of the internet because it's hard to do this if you don't pay someone to do it for you.
Speaker 1: but basically Amazon launched something called a self-service marketplace for subscription providers and it's basically Subscribe with anima at Amazon.
Speaker 1: so if you sell a thing that is a technology subscription like Adobe Creative Cloud would be an example or Access to a website that does a thing or an app or a game or anything like that Then you can sell that just in Amazon store, right?
Speaker 1: They'll just handle it for you.
Speaker 0: This is a thing where anyone there's.
Speaker 0: a lot of people have this business model now of subscription selling right subscribe to Netflix Subscribe to a box of stuff that comes in the mail every month.
Speaker 0: Right a lot of people are using the subscribe business model But everyone who does it has to implement it on.
Speaker 0: that's like code the same code over and over again.
Speaker 0: So it's like that's if you want to do a subscription thing You have to write this code that everyone's already written.
Speaker 0: There's no way you there's no service.
Speaker 0: It just like offers it to.
Speaker 1: you know, all the code really has to do now is interface with payment processors.
Speaker 1: yeah, take customer info and Somehow provide an authentication token of some kind to the actual service.
Speaker 0: Yep So now Amazon made a thing so you don't have to write this code anymore You can just use their thing
Speaker 1: and more importantly It means that your thing is just in Amazon's marketplace Like if there wasn't patreon and geek nights was for money, which don't worry that will never happen.
Speaker 1: You could literally we could be like by geek nights for a dollar a month on Amazon And like I was looking at the docks now it works and I think this is going to Actually hurt some of the services like patreon that many people are using to do this kind of thing.
Speaker 0: if those It's not it's.
Speaker 0: yeah, it's not accessible to pay trans for individual.
Speaker 1: Yeah This is this is.
Speaker 1: this is well in terms of what you need to be able to bring to the table You have to be a step up in that You're.
Speaker 1: you probably need to be a company and more importantly you need to have the development Expertise to be able to use the service because it's gonna let you set up that Authentication token like you still need to make that all happen Easier than developing.
Speaker 1: Yeah So I think there will be a you know would be a good place for this Certain video games that are on patreon right now to give you access to the video game Like.
Speaker 1: that is the.
Speaker 1: that is the use case here.
Speaker 1: the question what I don't know is how much of a big Amazon's taking Compared to other services.
Speaker 1: I didn't dig into that much detail.
Speaker 0: They always take.
Speaker 1: yeah, of course they take but Take and take and take.
Speaker 1: pay attention to this
Speaker 0: rent seeking
Speaker 1: because if This ecosystem I suspect is going to be the primary subscription ecosystem in a relatively short amount of time Because the reality is people trust Amazon and even though there are other e-commerce platforms Lay people do not trust them because they aren't Amazon and that's just the way.
Speaker 1: it is real hard to compete with Amazon Like seamless in Grubhub.
Speaker 1: There's a reason it's so hard to compete with them because even though they don't offer the best services They already exist and people have heard of them.
Speaker 1: Anyway and some other tech news.
Speaker 1: that's actually a big deal and is gonna be a bigger deal later.
Speaker 1: So I'm not gonna talk about in too much depth, but tinder that website to get your fucking on.
Speaker 0: Yeah I'm not even a website.
Speaker 0: I'm pretty sure is just an app.
Speaker 1: Is it just an app?
Speaker 0: I don't think you can swipe on the web.
Speaker 0: I think you can only swipe.
Speaker 1: well I saw someone made an app that will auto swipe through their API.
Speaker 1: Alright, so but essentially another company Used some sort of.
Speaker 1: they use their API to get all the photos that people have uploaded into tinder.
Speaker 1: But you can just pull out of the API.
Speaker 1: I mean stuff's just public essentially and they used it to make a data set for facial recognition.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean someone put out free photos that are all squares.
Speaker 0: They're all.
Speaker 0: you know, it's Thanks, you can read the.
Speaker 0: I know they're all people's faces.
Speaker 0: cuz I don't want to go in too much depth It's on one hand.
Speaker 1: on your own data sets are one of the like like the last frontiers of Monetizing and late capitalism in terms of technology.
Speaker 1: right now like on Wall Street pretty much everywhere Selling data or being a platform are like the places you can still make money without having to do something Like that no one's ever done before.
Speaker 1: like there's a lot of money in making data sets using data sets and a data set like this for like generating machine learning algorithms or doing anything with facial recognition super super super valuable and useful and Arguably violates the terms of service of the website.
Speaker 1: The data was gotten from yeah And the whole cat of worms that gets opened is say there's a website that has information on it.
Speaker 1: Copyright means I can't take that information and just redistribute it without a license.
Speaker 1: That's already covered.
Speaker 1: But what if I take that information and use it myself?
Speaker 1: But don't provide that information to other people.
Speaker 1: I just provide information I generated from that information.
Speaker 0: I mean the only reason we know they scrape tinder is because someone said so.
Speaker 0: if they're just kept their mouth shut it would just Been like hey, we have a facial recognition thing.
Speaker 0: No one would have known where the hell they got it from.
Speaker 0: It's only because they open their big fat mouth.
Speaker 0: And this is the same thing I say to a lot of other people is like a lot of you will make stuff and they upload It to YouTube and it gets taken down or like yep people.
Speaker 1: the dude who made it steward Kolyani released it under a public domain creative right.
Speaker 0: a lot of people will like make.
Speaker 0: it was like a 3d chrono trigger.
Speaker 0: people are making some other who making a Super Metro a Metroid 2 remake and these things get taken down.
Speaker 0: and it's like assholes When you make something and you're gonna put it out there And there's something about it that is gonna stop it somehow because you got your data from somewhere shady Yeah, or you're violating some copyright something while you're generating buzz.
Speaker 1: call it.
Speaker 1: call it Trono Bringer or something.
Speaker 0: Don't take any fucking credit for it.
Speaker 0: So no one knows who the hell you are and just put it up on BitTorrent completely anonymously And don't say where it came from and no one will be able to fucking stop you.
Speaker 0: I scraped tinder to make some database.
Speaker 0: I would just put it anonymously on to BitTorrent like tada Mysteriously.
Speaker 0: this database appeared out of nowhere.
Speaker 0: I don't know where it came from and now everyone has it.
Speaker 0: if you do it where you tell everyone now There's gonna be a big ruckus.
Speaker 1: But it's not only that this.
Speaker 1: the reason this could like I don't want to talk about this too much Is that there are so many interesting issues you could talk about based on this one story like for example right now I'm looking at information in a web browser because that information is publicly available on the internet.
Speaker 1: if a website has terms of service For use but does not have accounts and does not block people from accessing it Are you actually bound to those terms of service?
Speaker 0: especially does have accounts though, but say you don't.
Speaker 1: Especially if you hit a website with a browser Meaning, you know some sort of scraper curl that doesn't actually read the footer of the page that says it has terms of service.
Speaker 1: You'd never even encountered them If I trespass on some land and I didn't actually pass any no trespassing signs at any point because they didn't put them on That side of the property though.
Speaker 1: all those questions are largely unanswerable even my lawyers right now and they've been unanswerable for a long time and Based on the way Congress is going I suspect no laws will be passed in the next 10 or 20 years to deal with this stuff.
Speaker 1: so The upside is if you use tinder your photo is part of this public domain data set of people.
Speaker 0: I mean we always say this anyway anything that you upload to the internet Anything that you put on a device any data you put on any sort of electronic thing that is connected to the internet Even if you check private only share with my friends direct message only.
Speaker 0: It doesn't matter.
Speaker 0: you have effectively, you know shared that thing with the entire Human race.
Speaker 1: let's put it simply there are no sharing controls Except client-side encryption.
Speaker 1: That is the only way you can control data you send.
Speaker 0: and even then if I send something to rimming I know you don't.
Speaker 1: you can't trust me.
Speaker 0: I have to trust rim not to share it with the entire world on purpose or by accident.
Speaker 0: You know now that image is unencrypted on rims phone.
Speaker 0: who knows where it's gonna go next, right?
Speaker 0: Oh, the only way if I take say a photo and I want it to be absolutely private I must a keep it in my house only on non internet connected mediums, and that is it.
Speaker 1: and the last news Surprisingly multiple people I guess goble goble.
Speaker 1: Yeah, everyone knows that I used to spend a lot of time in Turkey.
Speaker 1: So Because that's not a super common thing to do I guess so a lot of.
Speaker 0: I don't think it's the.
Speaker 1: oh Even before it was not the most visited country three different people messaged me to tell me about this or you know As it happened ad zenk icon two different people when I ran into them because I didn't see in a while.
Speaker 1: They're like, oh, yeah, you hear about Turkey and I was like, it's good I heard about it a lot of things are going on with Turkey.
Speaker 1: one thing in particular like oh how they blocked Wikipedia.
Speaker 1: So yes to all of you out there.
Speaker 1: I'm aware that this happened and the irony I mean the fact that Wikipedia is blocked in Turkey.
Speaker 1: I. Well, I don't want to say it's not news because it is news and it's a bad thing.
Speaker 1: But it is probably the least bad news that has come out of Turkey in the last several weeks.
Speaker 0: It's a bad news, but of the bad news is it is the least one.
Speaker 1: I mean if you're not familiar Turkey basically voted in a scam election to Make er to on effectively the Chancellor of Germany.
Speaker 0: Oh Is that how you pronounce his name?
Speaker 0: I thought it was edrogan.
Speaker 1: It's Turkish is interesting in that if the letters like pronunciation and conjugation are 100% regular.
Speaker 1: See now you look at when you learn like Spanish or French like they teach you rules for conjugation.
Speaker 0: I thought My pronunciation was way more Marduk guard a calm than yours was.
Speaker 1: Yeah the way that now I'm disappointed.
Speaker 0: Hey, he's like, I mean he's already not cool.
Speaker 0: But now he's even less cool.
Speaker 0: So you want to learn how to be evil.
Speaker 0: at least be cool evil.
Speaker 1: Here's how you pronounce Turkish words.
Speaker 1: You look up a few rules But basically learn how to pronounce all the vowels and look up the list of consonants that are pronounced and any Consonant that's not on that list.
Speaker 1: Just kind of swallow it as you say the word So like yeah to him just kind of like swallow the end and you'll sound close enough.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so anyway, so funniest thing is that they blocked Wikipedia and perhaps one of the reasons they blocked Wikipedia Is there pages like this which are 2017 block of Wikipedia in Turkey is literally on Wikipedia.
Speaker 0: there's a Wikipedia page about it Wikipedia being blocked in Turkey.
Speaker 0: and I was saying like hey You know, I guess it's not as bad as the Great Firewall of China.
Speaker 0: I'm pretty sure they don't allow Wikipedia either.
Speaker 1: Well, they're making their own Wikipedia.
Speaker 1: Sure.
Speaker 0: That's gonna work out great for them.
Speaker 0: But like if I don't have Wikipedia, that's like I could survive but that's pretty close to not having water.
Speaker 0: It's real bad without Wikipedia.
Speaker 0: Like I don't know anything.
Speaker 1: So yeah with what do I know if I have the internet and Wikipedia?
Speaker 1: I can know basic stuff about everything.
Speaker 1: if I have the Internet but not Wikipedia.
Speaker 1: How is baby formed is the best you're gonna get about most topics.
Speaker 0: What the fuck - I don't know shit.
Speaker 1: Like we really are.
Speaker 1: we're like, why don't we do a show about crabs?
Speaker 1: and I realized that without Wikipedia I don't know fucking anything about crabs.
Speaker 0: and I my first my first thought was actually a stupid thought which is oh go to the Library and get like a tiny book about crabs.
Speaker 0: That's like one of those, you know ones meant for kids or something.
Speaker 0: But like, you know the kind you would do a book report with so you'd actually get more information about crabs.
Speaker 1: That's what you'd have to do.
Speaker 0: But then I was like, wait a minute.
Speaker 0: I can just read the Wikipedia page about crabs.
Speaker 0: No everything there is no yeah without Wikipedia.
Speaker 1: I don't know stuff anymore.
Speaker 0: I see, you know used to be the every year during the holiday times Wikipedia post that thing on all the pages.
Speaker 0: Like give us money.
Speaker 0: Oh my gosh I give the money now and I guess about.
Speaker 0: I guess enough people give the money to keep them alive because they're still there.
Speaker 0: I switched to give it the monthly monies.
Speaker 0: Oh Obviously less monthly money, right?
Speaker 0: But maybe you're paying for the whole thing maybe but it's like, you know that way.
Speaker 0: It's like.
Speaker 0: I don't have to remember to do it, you know at the end of the year Like did I do it already this year?
Speaker 0: I don't remember.
Speaker 0: It's nope monthly monies.
Speaker 0: It's either Wikipedia going.
Speaker 1: it's just interesting.
Speaker 1: I'm curious out there.
Speaker 1: This is like a food for thought for you guys out there the listener.
Speaker 1: How often do you actually go to Wikipedia and do you think about using a percentage of your Google searches result with success on?
Speaker 0: Wikipedia page.
Speaker 0: Yeah and that's where you got what you want.
Speaker 1: because the way my life goes is any time I'm in any Conversation and someone brings something up and I don't know enough about that thing to engage with them that day I just read the Wikipedia page about whatever that thing is.
Speaker 0: I think about half of my Google searches are wiki space something so that I know that I'm gonna basically saying give me the Wikipedia page for this Google because the next answer is gonna be some Yahoo answers bullshit.
Speaker 1: And then after that, it's down into Urban Dictionary.
Speaker 0: Yep Sometimes Urban Dictionary is what you want.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like what the hell does this mean?
Speaker 1: But anyway things of the day I just stumbled upon this YouTube show randomly.
Speaker 1: it's old it's from like 2007 and I can't believe I haven't found this like.
Speaker 1: I never ran into this before Because it's just it's up my alley.
Speaker 0: in a lot of ways this matches up with one of our things.
Speaker 0: It's like, you know, sometimes you have a thing with your group of people like an inside joke.
Speaker 0: Oh, you know some story that's told off in or you know, like a like, you know, the certain things.
Speaker 0: There's things you have, you know I don't know what to call them but like.
Speaker 0: and then you discover another separate group of people local me Right and they have the same or similar thing to what you have and somehow you had this connection with these other people.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I didn't even know like you both make the same kind of joke about a specific kind of board game.
Speaker 1: So, uh, this is a show you can watch called cautionary tales of swords.
Speaker 1: This is episode one.
Speaker 1: quote in this episode, honey I killed our son and swords will cut your fucking hands off.
Speaker 0: that's true.
Speaker 1: all the show is is a dude with an eyepatch answering viewer mail about swords and Cautionary skits explaining why don't ever own swords?
Speaker 1: swords are stupid.
Speaker 1: They will fucking cut you.
Speaker 1: Never own swords.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and there are many episodes when you're in the kitchen with a knife like you're cautious like you.
Speaker 0: This is dangerous.
Speaker 0: I must respect this blade and not cut myself.
Speaker 0: Like people don't hold swords that often and even nerds the olds who hold swords more often than normal people But still not that often.
Speaker 0: a sword is a fucking giant ass knife, especially like a Japanese one.
Speaker 0: Holy shit It is so dangerous.
Speaker 0: Don't fuck around with them.
Speaker 0: But most of the time when we're talking about swords is I'm with the dangers of spending all your money on them Yeah, which if I had money when I would say in high school or middle school, I would have spent it on too many swords.
Speaker 0: Oh, thankfully I did not do that.
Speaker 0: We you know, this is this is our sword thing, right?
Speaker 0: It's like we have this sort like don't buy swords thing and this other group of people make these YouTube videos.
Speaker 0: They have their don't buy swords thing.
Speaker 0: So we have a connection with them.
Speaker 1: Don't don't not buy swords.
Speaker 1: So they will cut you.
Speaker 0: so, you know You know the old trick where like you make it look like you took your thumb off right like this.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, I'm not even doing it that well.
Speaker 0: I'm doing trick.
Speaker 0: How well am I doing it poorly?
Speaker 1: I can see your thumb bent backwards.
Speaker 0: I'm bad at it.
Speaker 0: Right?
Speaker 1: Anyway, I can't even see myself in the video, right?
Speaker 0: the point is You know, it's an old trick, you know when no one gets fooled by that right unless you're like a little kid.
Speaker 0: But this guy on YouTube, I don't even know you could push this trick to such limits.
Speaker 0: I don't even I have to go frame by frame to see how he even does the last part.
Speaker 0: I mean I got an idea but it's like I watch it once.
Speaker 1: he just moves real quick He pushes this trick.
Speaker 0: He has practiced this way too much and it's like god damn.
Speaker 0: I would not be surprised if he legit had like either crazy fingers that like flex and in improbable ways or Literally actual fake fingers.
Speaker 0: that is hyper realistic or something.
Speaker 1: I mean as a kid I got a magic set like one of those box magic sets kids get and it came with a fake thumb and a fake finger.
Speaker 0: Yeah, mine also came with this pink rubbery finger.
Speaker 0: It's obviously fake and you know magic with it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know what?
Speaker 1: I used it for I covered blood and throw it at people instead of using it a magic trick.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's a Halloween decoration a magic trick I did with it.
Speaker 1: That's kind of relevant to my thing of the day.
Speaker 1: it was a magic trick that I just used to scare my grandparents where I'd use that finger and I act like I'm doing this complicated knife trick and then I Accidentally cut my thumb off and have blood spray everywhere.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's a. That's how they do.
Speaker 1: But this is only 16 seconds long and you might think like how far can they push this trick in 16 seconds?
Speaker 0: It's pretty good.
Speaker 0: I think you could.
Speaker 0: the the 16 seconds you spent Listening to us is way more wasted than the 16 seconds you can spend watching this video number 5 on trending.
Speaker 1: Is this trending or something right now?
Speaker 1: Oh, I think people are seeing this.
Speaker 1: Maybe that's how.
Speaker 1: how did you find this?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 1: You don't know.
Speaker 1: it just came in.
Speaker 0: I just I read a lot of internet every day.
Speaker 0: You know how much internet I read.
Speaker 1: there was just a study that was released today saying that the average white-collar worker in the United States consumes 12 hours of Content per day on average.
Speaker 0: I don't think I do that much because I'm only at work for eight hours.
Speaker 0: So that would not be possible.
Speaker 0: You got to subtract the time I'm working sleeping and eating also at eight hours and then when I'm at home definitely not four hours Unless you can't.
Speaker 0: I mean, you know playing games doesn't count as internet content.
Speaker 1: It counts as consuming media.
Speaker 0: I think yeah, but I mean it depends what you count.
Speaker 0: right if I'm reading comics in bed.
Speaker 0: Does that count?
Speaker 1: Let's see.
Speaker 1: Thanks to multitasking.
Speaker 1: Oh, so people, you know people might have two media streams on at the same time.
Speaker 0: I don't do that.
Speaker 0: I don't do that either.
Speaker 1: I do that occasionally, but only when the task I'm doing is rote.
Speaker 0: I'm only doing one one at a time.
Speaker 0: Oh wait, does it count if I have music playing while reading a web page?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I did not read the article.
Speaker 1: Yeah, cuz your slash shot right gonna read the article anyway.
Speaker 1: In the moment the book of the book is Frank Herbert's Dune.
Speaker 1: Don't even talk to us until I beat Gannon, which is coming along.
Speaker 0: I'm I could go begin and I just I only got.
Speaker 0: I could just go to Goron land.
Speaker 1: do that dungeon Right now there's good.
Speaker 0: I have not even entered Goron land ever on purpose and I'm cleaning up shrines and Doing all kinds of stuff everywhere else.
Speaker 0: I'm most upgrading armors.
Speaker 0: I'm getting armors.
Speaker 0: I didn't even know existed.
Speaker 1: I'm doing two things.
Speaker 1: I'm hunting line.
Speaker 0: I got all the rubber armor all the climbing armor.
Speaker 0: I got everything.
Speaker 1: I'm hunting line out and I am forming an entirely new town.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I got to figure out the town thing.
Speaker 1: I heard rumors about that but like someone key toad hinted at me the the start of that whole saga.
Speaker 0: I don't even know where the start is.
Speaker 1: So remember I said you can buy a house.
Speaker 1: Yeah If you buy that house The builders dealing with that house are free to go off and do their show.
Speaker 0: I didn't buy the house cuz I'm saving my money for other stuff first.
Speaker 1: I got like I'm gonna 9,000 rupees.
Speaker 0: so I spend my munt rupees upgrading some stuff but buying some armors.
Speaker 0: But I'm going to.
Speaker 0: next thing has been a rupees on.
Speaker 0: is I found a fairy who upgrades horses.
Speaker 1: What?
Speaker 0: Yeah, why is a fairy fountain?
Speaker 0: that's a 3,000 rupee fairy fountain that I have not opened yet.
Speaker 0: what For horses?
Speaker 0: the horse fairy fountain.
Speaker 0: I got all four regular fairy fountains, but there's a horse fairy.
Speaker 1: I've only got two fairy fountains.
Speaker 1: actually just I got.
Speaker 0: I know you can't upgrade your armors to the fourth level.
Speaker 0: No, I can't I?
Speaker 0: for fairy fountains and the fourth one cost 10,000 rupees.
Speaker 0: But I got the horse fairy fountain, but I need the 3,000 rupees to open it.
Speaker 1: I'm way more excited about the horse fairy than I am about the.
Speaker 1: is it actually a giant like sexy horse?
Speaker 1: It comes.
Speaker 0: I haven't opened it because I need 3,000 rupees.
Speaker 1: if that fairy does not have a horse head I'm gonna be legit disappointed.
Speaker 1: I'm just saying it's gotta have a horse head.
Speaker 1: Otherwise we were.
Speaker 1: I was just at Zenkai Con.
Speaker 1: we did three panels super fun.
Speaker 1: I guess the next con will be out.
Speaker 1: is Kinetic Con exciting?
Speaker 1: and then Pax Unplugged and then Pax West and then Pax Australia.
Speaker 0: I mean if you're listening to this you've already probably found us everywhere On the internet that we are.
Speaker 0: but we are on all the places of the internet that exists particularly YouTube.
Speaker 1: We got in that way many.
Speaker 0: we have many youtubes and Twitter's and we even have Facebook And we got.
Speaker 0: we have a fucking everything.
Speaker 0: if there's a place on the internet that people post things We have a thing there and we post there.
Speaker 0: so go to all the places that you use on the internet and find us rim and me and geek nights and follow all But then don't actually watch any of the content.
Speaker 1: Yeah So in other news meaning the actual main bid we I guess did a show on DRM.
Speaker 1: never.
Speaker 1: I don't know how that never happened.
Speaker 1: I feel like we did it like I almost remember doing it.
Speaker 1: I feel I feel like we've talked about.
Speaker 1: I feel like this was the primary thing I was mad about for like eight years of my life.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and yet somehow we've never talked about it.
Speaker 0: It was a big problem, man.
Speaker 0: It's still a problem, but much smaller one.
Speaker 0: So here's the deal.
Speaker 0: DRM is digital rights management And what DRM is is you have some data and you want to give that data to somebody else?
Speaker 0: Yeah, you want to make it available and so you share it around.
Speaker 0: But you only want people to be able to use read that data if they have permissions to do So.
Speaker 0: for example, I am Adobe.
Speaker 0: I made Photoshop.
Speaker 0: Photoshop is just data.
Speaker 0: It's just an exe file Photoshop that exe and people can just download the fucking thing Right and they if some one person downloads it or gets it on a CD or USB stick They can just give it to someone else.
Speaker 0: It's just data they can copy up.
Speaker 0: It's just a giant number, but they do not want people who do not pay for Photoshop to be able to use Photoshop.
Speaker 0: So they put some special code in there to make that Difficult to use the Photoshop if you have not paid for and that is DRM and there are many mechanisms for doing this.
Speaker 0: But the fundamental idea is that you have a thing I could imagine.
Speaker 0: you have a treasure chest and the Photoshop is in the treasure chest and it's locked.
Speaker 0: So you give out treasure chests with Photoshop inside to everybody.
Speaker 0: But only some people got keys to open it.
Speaker 0: The problem is you're also giving people the keys so they can also copy the key.
Speaker 1: Oh, like there's the key is also data.
Speaker 1: So DVDs and blu-rays right like if you have encryption on the discs so they can only be played in legitimate players.
Speaker 0: So the legitimate DVD players have keys in them and the DVDs themselves are locked treasure chest with movies inside But those keys.
Speaker 0: and if you put the DVD into an illegitimate DVD player that DVD player does not have the key.
Speaker 0: So we can only watch DVDs that are unlocked treasure chest.
Speaker 0: It can't watch ones that are locked except if I buy a legit DVD player Once the keys are in there and I can take them out.
Speaker 1: They might be complicated keys Yeah, but they're still just keys.
Speaker 0: It might be hard to get them out of there, but they're in there and They are.
Speaker 1: there's an angry nerd somewhere who will get the key out of there and put it on the internet, right?
Speaker 0: And that's how DRM works.
Speaker 0: It's like it's never foolproof because the fundamental concept behind it is just Absolutely flawed from the get-go, right?
Speaker 1: The so so arguably, you know when we talk about DRM the kind of DRM that pertains to subscription software Does work more so and also is pretty justifiable.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't have problems saying it's not justified in all case, but it also the main reason it can work.
Speaker 1: Is that unlike most things people talk about with DRM because they're usually talking about Static media like movies or songs when it comes to software.
Speaker 1: There's no analog hole.
Speaker 1: I can't just take a picture of my screen and now I've got a copy of that.
Speaker 0: Oh, that's only one of the flaws of DRM, right?
Speaker 0: the main flaw of DRM is the one we talked about which is that the key is also digital and once someone gets the Key, you're giving people the lock and the key and once they have everything they have everything.
Speaker 0: right now It's making it difficult.
Speaker 0: the other flaw of DRM specifically on media such as a movie.
Speaker 0: It's like, okay Let's say I never figured out the key to unencrypt this DVD and it only plays my legitimate DVD player.
Speaker 0: It still has to send that video to my television and even if you use they do have DRM.
Speaker 0: It's called HDCP on HDMI cables, and that's new.
Speaker 1: it used to not exist.
Speaker 0: So I can't record easily from the HDMI cable itself.
Speaker 0: I can't trick right.
Speaker 0: I can still point a camera at my television and record everything.
Speaker 0: So Congratulations, in fact my grandfather I can't point a camera at my monitor and record Photoshop.
Speaker 1: so my grandfather who is real old was a carpenter and and I'm cabinet maker when he was young too.
Speaker 1: and He in the earliest earliest days when when photocopies existed he immediately would get catalogs of Big enough to just use.
Speaker 1: he was pirating that stuff in the like pre-internet days.
Speaker 0: So their DRM was pretty much make it really small so no one can see.
Speaker 1: yep It's like by the pattern.
Speaker 0: here's a catalog of patterns and it has pictures of the patterns.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there's no tiny thing.
Speaker 0: Why don't you just send them money and they'll send you the pattern, you know at full size.
Speaker 0: But he just take the tiny picture of a pattern make it bigger and now we can see it, but it more technological Even though that not that that wasn't technology.
Speaker 1: We had a fancy camcorder like a really fancy one that the family all share.
Speaker 0: still took VHS tapes.
Speaker 1: It took VHS tapes, but back then full-size ones.
Speaker 0: Not the small ones that you put into the full size.
Speaker 1: It was not easy to copy VHS tapes that had copy protection because there was copy protection on VHS tapes.
Speaker 1: It's this complicated analog thing We've talked about in old episodes of geek nights.
Speaker 0: There's also the little piece of plastic where the VCR VCR will refuse to record onto a VHS tape if that piece of plastic has been punched out.
Speaker 0: and that's a good thing because you won't Accidentally overwrite the Aladdin VHS tape you bought with say an episode of the Simpsons.
Speaker 1: But that macro vision copy protection worked only because it was a signal on the tape itself.
Speaker 1: So my grandpa took the big TV and he pointed the camcorder at the TV And he plugged the audio inputs on the camcorder into the speaker outputs of the TV and that is how he pirated shit Mm-hmm, and that was legit like it worked
Speaker 0: and then for those days you would not be disappointed with the quality nowadays.
Speaker 0: You'd look at that and be like, oh my god, it's unwatchable.
Speaker 1: Yeah but but with with with static media the analog hole exists.
Speaker 1: no matter what I mean right now like Crunchyroll or anything like that if I want to get a clip for a panel I just fire up OBS and record my screen.
Speaker 1: It totally works.
Speaker 1: if I need audio I can literally pipe the music that is being played from the thing no matter how copy protect It is through my mixer and then back into audition.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they've.
Speaker 0: they've mostly given up on copy protection for music these days.
Speaker 0: Yeah, pretty much all that Apple gives you like DRM free, you know, AC files or whatever.
Speaker 1: yep video is interesting because they've definitely not given up on it and People care less because streaming services exist now, right?
Speaker 0: Right, it's like, you know, they made it Spotify Netflix whatnot.
Speaker 0: They've made it to the point where it's easier to not pirate.
Speaker 0: That was the only thing.
Speaker 0: people were pirating these things because it was hard to get it legit.
Speaker 0: now It's like you pay for Netflix.
Speaker 0: It's way cheap and You can just watch everything with one button press and it plays immediately Which is even easier than in Napster days where you would type it in press enter and then double click and it would play.
Speaker 0: This is even less steps Even less steps.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so and even now I pay for music services Even though I used to pirate music to the point that pirating music might have arguably been a distinct hobby unto itself for me.
Speaker 0: Right, but these streaming services are still using DRM Even if you're not paying attention because you're not trying to pirate anything.
Speaker 0: Yeah, Netflix does not want you to be able to download their show and keep a copy of it forever Right, and that's they remove things from Netflix sometimes, right?
Speaker 0: If you could just download things forever that were on there that wouldn't work out too Well.
Speaker 0: when they're trying to remove things so you can't watch them anymore.
Speaker 1: Oh a big example.
Speaker 1: example of a problem was until recently you would.
Speaker 0: you would be in a situation you paying for Netflix for one Month download fucking everything right and then cancel it.
Speaker 1: Days of red octane when I got the maximum subscription plan.
Speaker 1: I rented every single Ps1 game I ever wanted in my life and ran them through the Plex tour as fast as I could.
Speaker 0: in high school There was a. it was a gang not a legit gang But you know a gang of kids.
Speaker 0: and what they would do is they would go to Blockbuster and rent PlayStation one games.
Speaker 0: Everyone would copy them right and so it's cost you like five bucks each, but there were like ten people.
Speaker 1: Ah, but there was a second component to that.
Speaker 1: Everyone's PlayStation had to have a DRM crack in the form of a mod.
Speaker 0: Everyone had that.
Speaker 0: so yeah You would.
Speaker 0: basically everyone would go to Blockbuster with five bucks and that would be like ten people.
Speaker 0: But you basically getting ten PlayStation games for five dollars.
Speaker 0: Right you copied them all and then you returned them all and then you could do it again and get 20 PlayStation games for ten Dollars.
Speaker 0: it just like the math was so great on that for the price of one Blockbuster rental You got the number of friends you had Times number of PlayStation games.
Speaker 0: because you would everyone would make one copy of theirs.
Speaker 0: So thinking I mean all bunch times everybody.
Speaker 0: think about how old plus the price of blank CDs.
Speaker 1: think about how old-style Piracy wasn't that much of an economic impact because of the physical reality of it.
Speaker 1: You know it wasn't as easy and widespread for mass copying and what you guys did was also pretty small scale.
Speaker 1: But when I was doing it with red octane there was an economy of scale.
Speaker 1: I could get someone to mail me all Those CDs as fast as I could copy them right because copy in a PlayStation game back Then like you had to burn that shit at 1x.
Speaker 1: There's a lot of reasons.
Speaker 1: they took a while.
Speaker 0: in the olden days right when technology wasn't as powerful They had other kinds of DRM.
Speaker 0: for example you bought a say an old video game like star control, right?
Speaker 0: Oh, and you would install.
Speaker 0: you could you could copy this game on floppy disks and give it to all your friends And everyone had to copy a star control.
Speaker 0: But when you open up star control you type star con dot exe.
Speaker 0: it would open up and it would be like hello What is the star located?
Speaker 0: and you had this physical star chart?
Speaker 0: It was like a spinny cardboard on a thing and you're just.
Speaker 0: it came in the box with the game And you just spin it around and mess with the star chart and answer the question It was giving you.
Speaker 0: sometimes they'd ask questions like yeah on page whatever of the rule book What is the tenth word on what?
Speaker 1: and it's like quest for glory to did a really clever one?
Speaker 0: There was so many like what are you gonna do?
Speaker 0: photocopy the whole goddamn rule book and give it to every?
Speaker 1: And it's like pain in the ass.
Speaker 1: think about this.
Speaker 1: that was an error.
Speaker 0: make your own star chart somehow perfectly Just like the one that came in the box.
Speaker 1: That was an era when floppy disks and computers were widely available But copy machines were not.
Speaker 0: it was much harder to come on.
Speaker 1: machines are like that.
Speaker 0: stuffs by since Rule books that came with PC games were large.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we're full books.
Speaker 1: And if you end in those days if you wanted to make photocopies It's not like now where you could just go to a photocopy machine to just do it.
Speaker 1: You'd go to like a cake goes and hand them the thing and say here's the copies I want.
Speaker 0: they weren't gonna do that.
Speaker 1: They would run the machine for you.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I went in there a lot of times with D&D books, and they were like nope fuck you.
Speaker 1: Yeah, not helping you pirate that D&D book.
Speaker 1: I know exactly what you're doing.
Speaker 0: I'll copy the character sheet for you.
Speaker 1: They would not actually copy the character sheet really even though it had a disclaimer on it saying you can copy this.
Speaker 1: That was a long time ago.
Speaker 0: Yeah, obviously quest for glory to download a PDF pushprint.
Speaker 0: It was this giant folder that you have.
Speaker 0: use it on your tablet don't even print.
Speaker 1: It was a giant fold-out map of the main town and all the streets and the town is just super complicated.
Speaker 1: And if you did not have a physical copy of that map in color the game worked fine and nothing changed.
Speaker 1: It never asked you for anything, but good luck ever fucking finding anything or ever getting anywhere in that maze.
Speaker 1: I guess you could figure it out, but it would be.
Speaker 1: imagine all three of the Labyrinths in Breath of the Wild and make it about five times bigger than that.
Speaker 1: That's like the size of this stupid.
Speaker 0: You could map it out on your own with a pencil and a paper.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and you know what I feel like if someone did that.
Speaker 1: like good on you.
Speaker 1: You're in that game.
Speaker 0: Well, they like some people like doing that.
Speaker 0: you're like Etrian Odyssey.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I understand the appeal of that.
Speaker 1: I did not make any maps in the in any of the mazes.
Speaker 1: I've done recently.
Speaker 1: I used the the Variant of the left-hand rule mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: He's got to be careful.
Speaker 1: It is possible design maps that have left-hand rule traps.
Speaker 1: It'll take you in loops forever.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: Good maze.
Speaker 1: Yep That's there.
Speaker 1: That's a real good maze if there's more than one of those traps pro pro maze.
Speaker 1: So uh yeah DRM actually was a much more dangerous topic Early well.
Speaker 0: the other thing like before get night.
Speaker 0: the other thing about DRM is like we said is easily broken.
Speaker 0: So it's not like if it was not breakable.
Speaker 0: This would be a really big problem because so much of the culture of the world would sort of be trapped and like you know For preservation for shit.
Speaker 0: for all these reasons, right?
Speaker 0: It's real that could be very harmful, but luckily it's easily breakable, right?
Speaker 0: Yep Here's the thing.
Speaker 0: in the United States at least the DMCA says you may not break DRM Except for these specific exceptions, right like unlocking your phone.
Speaker 0: I think has recently made an exception.
Speaker 0: I think so, but I think I'm not 100% sure.
Speaker 0: but it's like if you if you break DRM Even in order to do something legal you're not violating copyright You're just breaking DRM for some other reason that is technically against the law to do this.
Speaker 1: Yep Now Portugal might be moving down the road of fixing this.
Speaker 1: I saw an article about that a little while ago doing research for the show, but The problem still is it.
Speaker 1: it was way worse earlier partly because are the US government.
Speaker 1: you might Expect that our government's pretty bad about technology stuff.
Speaker 1: but there was this golden era from the mid 80s through the end of the 90s early 2000s where Both parties in our government were equally hostile to media technology and the internet and we're basically both Pushing legislation to ruin everything forever.
Speaker 1: This was the era of the CBD tPA And if you want to know how bad that law was and how dangerous it was.
Speaker 1: I remember that giant acronym to this day.
Speaker 1: Well initialism, I guess it's not technically an acronym.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm, but that law basically said something like
Speaker 0: media
Speaker 1: can Must be tied to legitimate devices and can only be played on legitimate light devices by law like a device that can play media of any kind or even arguably a general-purpose computer was effectively banned under that law unless it had Government mandated copyright controls in it.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: Imagine if you couldn't run Linux Mm-hmm, like that kind of stuff.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: We've backed way away from that precipice.
Speaker 1: That's good And I mean the DMCA.
Speaker 1: it's kind of weak-toothed.
Speaker 1: HDCP was actually broken a long time ago.
Speaker 1: Like people have broken that as far as I know.
Speaker 1: These you know DCSS CSS was broken.
Speaker 1: We've had a lot of luck breaking.
Speaker 0: most of the copyright DRM enforcement regimes that have been actually dangerous to this is less effort on breaking them lately because you don't need to because you can.
Speaker 1: Companies are finally giving you all the content you need but also the Fewer people are outraged about it because back then the outrage was you can't do things that you do today.
Speaker 1: You'll lose access to stuff.
Speaker 1: But now because streaming so easy even though the were the streaming ecosystem is pretty heavily locked down.
Speaker 1: like unauthorized devices can't play streams You can't cash stuff.
Speaker 1: like until recently Netflix had no way to work if you didn't have internet connections.
Speaker 1: and even now Actually Netflix is doing a good thing because their own content they'd let you download in cash locally.
Speaker 0: So yeah, that's partially good.
Speaker 0: But so there's still bad.
Speaker 0: DRM is out there right out the John Deere.
Speaker 0: people can't buy a tractor And then they cannot repair the tractor can't replace the tire.
Speaker 1: You got to get a got to get an authorized tire, right?
Speaker 0: And if they if they were to say try to repair their own tractor They would be breaking the DRM.
Speaker 0: that's in the tractor software and therefore it's against the law to repair the thing you own Which is why a lot of places are trying to make right to repair laws, which say regardless of any DRM bullshit You can repair something that you buy right?
Speaker 0: You can't be doing this bull Someone else to repair it, right?
Speaker 0: You know, you're not licensing that tractor.
Speaker 0: You own it.
Speaker 0: You bought it, right?
Speaker 0: It's yours.
Speaker 1: I mean imagine the alternative a world where if you buy a Chevrolet car You can legally only get it serviced at the dealership.
Speaker 0: You cannot legally bring it anywhere else nor are you?
Speaker 0: If Chevy goes out of business, you can never repair the car ever and if you open the hood you could go to jail.
Speaker 1: Yep, that's what it would be like.
Speaker 1: That's that's the danger of fully realized and effective DRM.
Speaker 1: But replace your car with the collected culture of mankind produced to date.
Speaker 0: Yep So some bad news for Netflix and others, right?
Speaker 0: Google and even you know people you normally think of as not evil because they fight for things like net neutrality, but Even Tim Berners-Lee is on the wrong side of this one.
Speaker 0: There's a thing called encrypted media something Yeah, me encrypted media extensions.
Speaker 1: I happen to have the Wikipedia page up about there.
Speaker 0: make the basically as part of HTTP.
Speaker 0: this is the web only not the internet just the web right.
Speaker 0: the standards for the web like HTML, right?
Speaker 1: Yes, listen to old geek nods.
Speaker 1: you want to know the difference between the web and the internet
Speaker 0: but the w3c the organization that like decides what the standards for the web are gonna be which is then what People who make web browsers have to basically code to those standards to make sure that websites work on all browsers the same way.
Speaker 0: They decided almost certainly By a vote and the vote can only people who can vote or rich people who can pay to be a member like tens of Thousands of dollars to include DRM, you know these EME and the standards of the web.
Speaker 0: So now browsers if they want to be standard will have to include this DRM which would allow You know Netflix and other people to distribute DRM video Into people with just standard web browsers no extra software required.
Speaker 1: now There are some sound arguments on both sides.
Speaker 1: there
Speaker 0: are there are indeed
Speaker 1: I mean the alternative and don't don't say that I'm necessarily speaking for this but One problem is that under the old under the regime where there is no official standard everyone rolls their own and
Speaker 0: everyone's using flash or Other everyone's installing some kind of garbage, you know, there's still.
Speaker 0: they're not gonna distribute their content without DRM, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, they're gonna distribute the content with DRM there But they're gonna make you install some nonsense to do to get the content or you don't install the nonsense.
Speaker 1: So the argument comes down.
Speaker 1: In fact, this article says exactly what the argument is.
Speaker 1: the argument comes down to the alternative is not the web abandoning DRM.
Speaker 1: It's media companies abandoning the web right and going fully proprietary Mm-hmm, which is probably true a lot of them have already.
Speaker 0: I mean that a lot of most people I don't imagine use net watch Netflix things on the Netflix website.
Speaker 0: They're going and using an app.
Speaker 0: Yep, right usually embedded into some sort of No reason that that app has to talk to Netflix itself.
Speaker 0: Netflix is server infrastructure via HTTP.
Speaker 0: it can talk to Netflix using any protocol that they come up with.
Speaker 1: Yep So so on one hand this is like from a pure technology standpoint.
Speaker 1: This is a thing people want to do with technology, so we should have some standards.
Speaker 1: So it works interoperably across platforms across browsers.
Speaker 1: But on the other hand the thing you're trying to do is from an ideological standpoint fundamentally dangerous to culture in the long run even if it has short-term positive economic impact.
Speaker 1: and let the fact that Capitalism say here's hard to make money here.
Speaker 0: the problems here the problems of this particular thing.
Speaker 0: Number one if you just include DRM and browsers like this automatic thing People who are currently distributing things for free might just decide to oh, it's really easy.
Speaker 0: use the standard DRM.
Speaker 0: It's built into everyone.
Speaker 0: Let's just use it.
Speaker 0: and now suddenly all these things are DRM that before were not DRM.
Speaker 0: Yeah, now number two Let's say you make an open source web browser like Firefox or something.
Speaker 0: You cannot be including this DRM shit in this open source product, right?
Speaker 0: That's not gonna work out.
Speaker 0: That's fundamentally like against your license and such or you can't do this.
Speaker 0: You know, that's a problem depending on the license, of course Debbie and is not going to include a browser that has DRM.
Speaker 1: Wikipedia EMA has been highly controversial because a quote places a necessarily proprietary Component into might what is otherwise an open and free software ecosystem.
Speaker 0: Yep Because you have to download the Nvidia driver separately when you install some Linux.
Speaker 1: Yeah Remember how we talked about keys before the.
Speaker 1: the key the code whatever it is that makes us hear it happen is Still just that key.
Speaker 1: so it has to be closed source or it cannot work.
Speaker 0: Yeah If it was open source just included in Firefox.
Speaker 0: You could just read the source code of Firefox and it would basically have instructions on how to break the DRM in it Which is why it won't right?
Speaker 1: I've decided just now I'm oh, I'm for this being implemented and I have a pretty specific reason why.
Speaker 1: If we standardize on one way of doing a DRM you crack one key to crack the world.
Speaker 0: Sadly this DRM does not work that way.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah as many keys You have to crack you'd have to fundamentally break its system.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't think it's.
Speaker 0: this is designed Well, the system was made by Google Netflix, etc.
Speaker 0: It's a whole team effort.
Speaker 0: It's gonna be very very hard for you to do that.
Speaker 0: Well, the other trouble is that the reason a lot of I do not think it is so fundamentally flawed.
Speaker 0: I think you could obviously well.
Speaker 1: the reason why other keys were more easily flawed Is that a lot of the things that consume media or that did DRM in the past?
Speaker 1: Can't reliably have access to an internet and change themselves.
Speaker 0: Yeah, this is for the web.
Speaker 0: It is internet.
Speaker 0: Right?
Speaker 0: Anyway, the other problem with this is That let's say, you know web browsers are like the most important thing right like in terms of software on your computer.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the most it's.
Speaker 0: the number one application of the internet is the web.
Speaker 0: So People are constantly, you know Particularly security people, you know working on browsers.
Speaker 0: if browsers include DRM You might accidentally even though you're not trying to pirate any movies or anything Break the DRM while you're messing around with browsers because that's what you do Especially if you're a security investigator type person trying to find, you know security problems in the browser Security problems in that DRM that could threaten your whole computer.
Speaker 0: someone might use a flaw in the DRM system to just you know, turn your computer into You know some kind of spam bot or whatever.
Speaker 0: Security researchers might have to mess around with this DRM, but doing so is against the law because it's DRM and it's not something else.
Speaker 0: So that's a problem.
Speaker 1: Here's some quotes while backers developers of Firefox were hesitant implementing the protocol for ethical reasons and dependency on proprietary code Firefox's implementation of it uses an open source sandbox to load the DRM modules which are treated as plugins.
Speaker 1: So they have this convoluted way to get around some of the potentially thorny legal Problems.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but basically, you know, the web is a hundred percent open right now.
Speaker 0: And now that this is basically saying, you know what some part of the web is not gonna be open now?
Speaker 1: Yep But the previous alternative was some parts of the web like in websites would be black holes with flash or something.
Speaker 1: Sure So it's replacing Non-standard black holes with standard widely implemented black holes.
Speaker 1: great It's hard to predict what specific impact this might have Because on one hand it might make for an easier proliferation of more streaming services and things like that but it could very easily be used for evil.
Speaker 0: and I think you'll see consumer benefits in that.
Speaker 0: you'll be able to just get like 4k Surround sound Netflix streams right in the browser.
Speaker 0: You'll
Speaker 1: see a consumer detriment in that only Windows and Macs will be able to be used to watch stuff forever after this point Like your Linux box ain't gonna work with any of this stuff probably unless you install proprietary closed-source browsers Depending on your distro by going out of band because they won't give them to you.
Speaker 0: It's gonna be one of those things where like the negative effects are all Even if they're significant or in the tech world where normal people don't see or care.
Speaker 0: But tech people are gonna go like and it's gonna suck ass.
Speaker 1: now The hope will be if it expands into causing the further dangers beyond the expected dangers Like even normal people were afraid of the CBD tPA and like.
Speaker 1: we're able to stop that nonsense?
Speaker 1: Yeah, so we got to make sure that the laws protecting these systems do not become worse than they already are and we need right to repair and right to archive and Right to study and right to research and all these other.
Speaker 0: you start seeing shit like wayback machine can't archive any pages anymore Cuz they're all DRM.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right.
Speaker 0: It's a problem.
Speaker 1: So there's nothing for you out there to do like.
Speaker 1: there's no activism You can do on this cuz.
Speaker 0: yeah, it's already too late The final draft is in and you weren't rich enough to get a vote.
Speaker 1: Anyway, all you can do is keep an eye on this Like be aware that this exists and pay attention to when it starts encroaching.
Speaker 1: That's that's literally all you can do and figure out the line at which you start trying to get non nerds To be angry about it because no one's gonna care.
Speaker 1: right now the the feast at the buffet of streaming is still too great.
Speaker 1: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Speaker 0: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 1: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 0: But unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night and the patreon patrons for this episode of geek nights are Rebecca Dunn Nicholas Brando Alan Joyce Heidi McNichol Amanda Duchette.
Speaker 1: great job.
Speaker 1: emoji.
Speaker 1: mystady.com.
Speaker 1: William Eisneros Jeremy minor.
Speaker 1: But I was going to Tosh station to pick up some power converters.
Speaker 1: a genuine bonafide electrified six-car monorail The terrible secret space for two one creations.
Speaker 1: what I mean, why are we out here in this Canyon?
Speaker 1: Shervin but horror rare.
Speaker 1: Laval James David White Rochelle, Montana Superboy.
Speaker 1: I paid five five bucks to my rim.
Speaker 1: make rim say pickle sailor Vista Matthew Smith.
Speaker 1: Don't you like chart option George?
Speaker 1: You're just our top.
Speaker 1: Shawn Yeager Sam Cordray Clinton Walton Ren from New Zealand Ryan parent OJ morphine Lobo OJ morphine Lobo Brian's droney the space-time factor of an African European swallow carrying Kiwis Redacted Chris mint give Chris Knox Daniel Redmond Sean Klein Chris Reimer and Thomas Hahn.
Speaker 1: I see that patreon did something weird with their podcast feeds.
Speaker 1: So I'm I have some content I haven't uploaded yet because I'm trying to figure out what happened there first.
Speaker 1: It wasn't just me It was everything in patreon as far as I can see.
Speaker 1: Expect a whole bunch of rants and roomly reviews and other stuff to be coming up in the near future Now that I have a long break between conventions.
Speaker 1: and now I leave you with this Oh Leopold Ah.