Speaker 0: It's Monday November 27th.
Speaker 0: I'm rim.
Speaker 0: That's good.
Speaker 0: And this is geek nights in the year 2017. tonight we're talking about how to decide what technology to buy.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: So despite being in the city for a long time I've been in the area of them, but I never actually been to the clusters like I'd never gone inside them.
Speaker 1: I've been there.
Speaker 1: I've been there many a times.
Speaker 1: When I was going I was a kid.
Speaker 1: we would drop.
Speaker 1: when you drove to New York We would go down the Henry Hudson Parkway and see the cloisters out the window.
Speaker 1: Yeah The car and I always wanted to go there because it looks like a castle.
Speaker 1: it is technically a castle.
Speaker 0: It's basically the piece of all these castles and cathedrals and churches.
Speaker 1: right for anyone who doesn't know It's obvious that castles exist in Europe.
Speaker 1: castles don't exist in North America unless you count like Bannerman Castle as tech ruins or you know people who are weird and decided to build a castle even though Castle was now an old style of construction that no longer was necessary anyway.
Speaker 1: So why the hell is there a castle in New York City and the north of Manhattan is?
Speaker 1: Because FDR went and got all these pieces of castles from other places in the world Most of which were just gonna be destroyed or in disrepair and brought them there and made a little museum Which is technically part of the met.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: You don't have to actually pay to go in.
Speaker 0: It's suggested donation and if you Suggestedly donate the ticket they give you also works at the Met right.
Speaker 1: so the main feature of the cloisters is a. it's cool Architecture because it's like a castle.
Speaker 0: it is really cool B.
Speaker 1: It's at the top of a hill in an ice park.
Speaker 0: That park is also really great.
Speaker 1: See it houses many like artifacts of like Christian medieval times yep, which are Shockingly like.
Speaker 0: we're looking at this one painting a lot of Jesus II shit in there Like why is there this Renaissance painting there?
Speaker 0: Then it's like no, this is actually from the Netherlands in the 1300s and holy fuck.
Speaker 0: This guy could draw.
Speaker 1: Yeah And the most.
Speaker 1: the number one reason that people go there is because it houses the famous unicorn tapestries.
Speaker 0: There is a conspiracy around that unicorn tapestry.
Speaker 1: When I was there the last time I was there There was a tour group looking at the tapestries.
Speaker 1: at the same time I was and some moron was like hey unicorns real and everyone laughs But there's like 40 year old dude sort of believed in unicorns.
Speaker 1: for real.
Speaker 0: I Guess it was too soon friend.
Speaker 1: Why is he asking?
Speaker 1: Why is he asking a tapestry expert about cryptozoology?
Speaker 0: I mean one.
Speaker 0: maybe he was just a poorly attempting a joke.
Speaker 0: No, no but uh - I. Well, I remembered a certain person in my high school who didn't seem to know that World War two it happens and this became a As we started studying it and this person did not.
Speaker 0: They expressed incredulity and as the unit went on got increasingly distraught and it became readily apparent.
Speaker 0: They literally did not know about the war in the Pacific Like at all, they thought only half of the war happened.
Speaker 0: like they didn't know that America and Japan had fought a war.
Speaker 0: Alright, and it was.
Speaker 0: it was a fascinating individual I recall.
Speaker 0: but here's the thing.
Speaker 1: I know it's hard You know, this is I don't want to spend too much time in the opening bit but like yeah at what point It's like?
Speaker 1: I wasn't born with that knowledge.
Speaker 1: Yeah at what point of my life Did I know that?
Speaker 1: and how come when I was in history class?
Speaker 1: It wasn't a shock to me.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like I like I don't know.
Speaker 1: It's not like I watched that many war movies before high school.
Speaker 0: I mean we didn't study World War two as like a unit until high school.
Speaker 0: But when I got to like 10th grade and like now's the World War two unit Because I had a Jewish education I was more aware.
Speaker 1: but no other non Jews are also don't have this problem.
Speaker 1: Yeah But I don't know.
Speaker 0: but the unicorn tapestry is notable in that despite growing up in Michigan I knew all about that unicorn tapestry.
Speaker 0: And in fact, there's a picture of it in my Western Civ book my textbook Which I have because I stole it when I left high school.
Speaker 0: and it's over there and there what there's a page that has the unicorn Tapestry.
Speaker 0: well one of the unicorn tapestries.
Speaker 1: it's weird because on the one hand I feel like the unicorn tapestries.
Speaker 1: They're sort of overhyped and overrated, but they're really impressive.
Speaker 1: and on the other hand I really like tapestries and I really like the unicorn tapestries a lot.
Speaker 1: It's almost like the initial D of old arts where it's like.
Speaker 1: I feel like it's not as great as it's not.
Speaker 1: It's not as great as all the hype but at the same time.
Speaker 1: I really like it a lot.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: So, uh The picture in my textbook from Michigan of the unicorn tapestry Was the one that most people see and the one that's on all the merchandise
Speaker 1: where the unicorn is sitting down and there's like a circle And there's a big and the unicorn
Speaker 0: has this look on its face.
Speaker 1: Like hey, yeah, what's up?
Speaker 0: So you want to ride me bro all the other.
Speaker 1: have you had sex with anyone?
Speaker 1: Cuz if you have yeah, I might not talk to you or let you see me or let you ride me.
Speaker 0: So let me describe briefly all that, you know If you've never felt the horn before well, maybe maybe this is an action for that's the tapestry the kids know and are like Yeah, that's that's the great unicorn.
Speaker 0: Look at that chill unicorn.
Speaker 0: He says a bunch of other ones.
Speaker 1: They tell a story.
Speaker 0: Yeah The story is bunch of medieval shithead.
Speaker 0: saw a unicorn purifying water and then the rest of them are them Hunting down and brutally murdering the unicorn to steal its horn.
Speaker 1: Yeah the end Yep.
Speaker 0: And in fact the pillow because you can buy a pillow at the store at the cloister that has the unicorn on.
Speaker 0: it has the nice In the circle, but if you look at it You can see they've kind of removed all the blood that's on the unicorn from his injuries.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm And how do you know you corns a dude?
Speaker 0: Uh, yeah, I could be a lady.
Speaker 0: We don't know.
Speaker 1: In fact industry it could be a transgender unicorn.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we do not know the identity of that unicorn.
Speaker 0: All we know is that those medieval fuckheads murdered it and it's covered in blood in most of the tapestries of it.
Speaker 0: And yet most people who have not been to the cloisters only know this picture of this chill unicorn sitting in a circle.
Speaker 0: They don't know that's a cage.
Speaker 0: There's a chain around its neck.
Speaker 1: Nope.
Speaker 0: But yeah, that was a chill time.
Speaker 0: It was a good time up there chill time.
Speaker 1: I hear what the brutally dehorned unicorn.
Speaker 0: Yeah The tapestry where they got the horn is the worst because the top of it is like all these Spears through the unicorn and blood everywhere.
Speaker 1: If you're if you're nerdy and you want to do nerdy type things related to cloisters and you come to New York once a year They have a medieval timey Ren Faire type thing there that you can go to.
Speaker 0: I'm sure there will be people there who will be more than happy to explain to you everything You never wanted to know about medieval swords.
Speaker 0: We should go there cosplaying as Star Trek dudes in the holodeck a bloody unicorn and a unicorn hunter Perhaps a triptych of different states of the unicorn.
Speaker 0: I'll get a whole bunch of people make I'm into triptychs after being there Too because there's a lot of triptychs.
Speaker 0: It's a Monday, so I guess we won't talk about unicorns.
Speaker 0: we'll talk about technology.
Speaker 0: So here's some news.
Speaker 1: I got it's like a two news.
Speaker 1: is that are really one news, right?
Speaker 1: So the first news is that someone you know did a study and they found out that Pokemon go Right because people were playing it so much Did quite a lot of damage in terms of traffic related incidents for people playing Pokemon go.
Speaker 1: if Pokemon go had not been created There are people who would be less hurt less dead and less cars.
Speaker 1: That would be less damage.
Speaker 0: half a million dollars in additional damage 31 additional injuries two additional deaths.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm Pokemon go murdered two people real people in the real world.
Speaker 1: That's not something to like joke about.
Speaker 1: that's an actual thing.
Speaker 1: the people at the company that makes Pokemon go by writing that software Murdered two people.
Speaker 0: now as a counterpoint before you get to the second in direct your second news that'll tie all this together.
Speaker 0: The mere act of adding bike lanes had similar effects because more people started biking Mm-hmm, even though the bike lanes probably made any individual biker safer.
Speaker 0: It actually increased the number of bike death, but it decreased actual overall deaths.
Speaker 1: Queens Boulevard used to be the Boulevard.
Speaker 1: every study that shown is bike lanes.
Speaker 1: They slow traffic and reduce overall right.
Speaker 1: so it's the total amount of damage Right, even though maybe someone else decided to bike who wouldn't have biked without the bike lane And they died.
Speaker 1: the overall number of people who are harmed or died in all traffic related incidents are reduced when bike lanes are added And there's also a side story for that one person who died to other people were saved at least.
Speaker 0: there's a side story I have to get into about how anyone who's making technology should at least think about the potential ramifications of that technology and make ethical decisions, right?
Speaker 1: so?
Speaker 1: Secondly you got this guy that I didn't know about and he has this spreadsheet.
Speaker 1: It's an Excel spreadsheet That's got like a zillion sheets in it.
Speaker 1: You can actually get the spreadsheet and mess with it.
Speaker 1: Good luck.
Speaker 1: And what it is is it's basically this thing where he tries to take into account all possible factors of New York transit of all kinds and there's a few inputs and you change those inputs and you can go to All the other sheets and basically see what the effect would be on All these aspects of New York transit.
Speaker 1: and then sheets for like you know Buses and like all these different like a you know small things big things.
Speaker 1: It's like oh What would the effect be on this you know.
Speaker 1: so this bridge?
Speaker 1: It's like alright.
Speaker 0: It tells you right and it how rigorous is the science and math behind this?
Speaker 1: I have no idea.
Speaker 1: But it's it's.
Speaker 1: it's pretty impressive.
Speaker 1: I downloaded opened it and was like what the fuck.
Speaker 1: and then I deleted.
Speaker 1: But anyway While you know that aspect of it is questionable, right?
Speaker 1: It's like, you know a lot of the you know If you read the article, it's like oh, well, where did you get the numbers for calculating this?
Speaker 1: And it's usually from like various studies and things.
Speaker 1: it's like oh someone studied that for every X we spend here It causes X so that that goes into the spreadsheet, right?
Speaker 1: it sort of basically combines all these things together and the main purpose of it is to evaluate the effect of Possible, you know congestion pricing which is something's been discussed in New York a lot where we're gonna charge people money to drive a car Below some Street in Manhattan.
Speaker 1: So basically in Manhattan in the busy area the where the big buildings are.
Speaker 1: if you want to drive your car there We're gonna charge you some money and we're gonna use this to pay for trains and buses and all the other good stuff Because no one has the balls.
Speaker 1: just tax rich people and take all their money Or anything like that, even though some people are asking for it.
Speaker 1: No one's actually doing it.
Speaker 1: so This spreadsheet you can use to figure out exactly, you know, well, what have we raised?
Speaker 1: the price too much?
Speaker 1: Oh, it turns out that people just stop driving there.
Speaker 0: That's what I want?
Speaker 1: Yes, you know, but it's like well, what would the actual total cost to society be?
Speaker 1: Right?
Speaker 1: Well, you know what areas would be helped or harmed and whatnot.
Speaker 1: So This spreadsheets really cool.
Speaker 1: the Pokemon go thing is pretty interesting But why are these?
Speaker 1: the same news is because clearly we have reached a point where even though we don't have perfect Information right we have the ability to at least accurately enough estimate I don't want to say predict but estimate the total cost to society of any particular project or policy or whatever.
Speaker 1: yet Almost never do people take in this total cost of anything into account and when they make decisions People like people just start uber.
Speaker 1: they just start companies without thinking about the total cost, right?
Speaker 0: Well, cuz they're probably thinking about their own personal profit, right?
Speaker 1: Oh one of the interesting facts in this in the article from the guy with the spreadsheet is When you drive a car into Manhattan on a weekday you cost The everyone else at least $160 in externalities, right?
Speaker 1: You're basically doing $160 of damage to society if you drive a car into Manhattan on a weekday.
Speaker 1: Why doesn't?
Speaker 1: but we don't charge you 160 dollars.
Speaker 1: You're basically stealing a hundred and sixty dollars from all of society as a whole whenever you do that.
Speaker 1: So Like nobody's charging you 160 bucks to do that and we absolutely should.
Speaker 0: well there was yet another.
Speaker 0: I'm not gonna try to dig it up right now.
Speaker 0: There's another article that I read that was talking.
Speaker 0: It was I think was the New York Times But it was talking about the story of how and why the New York City subway has become so ridiculously underfunded despite being so like Literally and directly crucial to the economy of America as a whole and
Speaker 1: used by a shit ton of people who all pay for it millions
Speaker 0: and millions of people Unarguably, I'm of the mind that the New York City subway should be free for anyone to ride and be funded solely through tax dollars.
Speaker 1: It can be free if you tax people other people enough.
Speaker 1: If you set I think they said the congestion price at like some likes number.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they could make all buses and all subways free forever.
Speaker 0: Yep, but then I see the guy who made this spreadsheet.
Speaker 0: I'm just skimming this article.
Speaker 0: He's something like oh, but then it increases this traveler's amenity Which is like the benefit that travelers get out of the system.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and he already like he seems to make a lot of pro car arguments.
Speaker 1: The point is is that You know, I'm not I'm not vouching for the the reality of the spreadsheet, which is why I use much language like estimate.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right.
Speaker 1: What I'm saying is that in general right people, you know There's lots and lots of people are doing large projects that are all over the news things like Bitcoin.
Speaker 1: It's like well They just fucking do it and everyone starts doing things without considering the environmental impact or any you know Impacts on you know, all sorts of things, right and It's understandable that like back in the day before we had computers that that was a thing because it's like yeah You first of all, I didn't have the knowledge let alone the power to you know.
Speaker 1: Consider what would all the consequences be of doing this large thing?
Speaker 1: but now to at least enough extent we have the power to do that and It must I think is actually morally mandatory when doing any large project To consider the total cost to society.
Speaker 1: hard
Speaker 0: to say though because you
Speaker 1: if you're gonna make Pokemon go You better consider what's gonna happen when you make Pokemon
Speaker 0: go example does not take into account any of the benefits of self to society in terms of all the people that have walked Around who previously were not walking.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean you got to count everything And make it you want to count Pokemon go before you release that shit.
Speaker 1: make a giant spreadsheet if you wanna.
Speaker 0: if you want to count everything then you have to worry about the fact that Quantitative analysis a lot of these things is both one extremely difficult or possibly dubious.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm and two the goals of anything like what thing to optimize for or what counts as a cost versus a benefit is Highly partisan in America.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm I mean certain people would say that anything that reduces the number of drivers is harm.
Speaker 0: Whereas I would say it's a benefit.
Speaker 0: Yep, so that's part of the reason why this isn't so simple as let's just do the calculation because we can't agree on what we're calculating how we're calculating it and how to interpret the output.
Speaker 1: even if Somebody was to disagree with me and say more cars is better, right?
Speaker 1: It would be.
Speaker 1: at least They should at least do some amount of reasonable effort.
Speaker 1: So at least they know that the thing they're doing is going to make more drivers like they want, right?
Speaker 1: As a pull I'd rather have that where they want the opposite thing of me and they're effective and intelligent and going about it.
Speaker 1: Then just doing something they think will have more drivers without even estimating in advance Like.
Speaker 1: it's an interesting example, you know the best The best knowledge available.
Speaker 0: I'm not even so much concerned about this sort of like projecting forward because of all the perils.
Speaker 0: I've noted Hitherto.
Speaker 0: But I'm more interested in the fact that we're not even dealing with the problems where we don't need to project anything.
Speaker 0: We have empirical historical data showing that the solutions we are attempting to problems fail.
Speaker 0: The best example of this is highways and freeways the fact that we add more lanes to highways and freeways to reduce congestion yet empirical evidence over the course of like 60 years shows that that literally Increases top drive times and increases congestion.
Speaker 0: It does not decrease.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: So well, I mean, you know cuz you have a when you making you got to fix the bottlenecks, right?
Speaker 1: Look at George Washington Bridge.
Speaker 1: It's like the bridge still only has so many lanes.
Speaker 1: adding more lanes to it doesn't help.
Speaker 1: You got more lanes going in than there are on it So it's that.
Speaker 0: but look at like LA no matter how many more lanes you add anywhere It doesn't.
Speaker 1: actually there's gonna be a bottleneck somewhere.
Speaker 1: They don't have ten lanes on Main Street.
Speaker 1: So it's handling the freeway doesn't do you any good if there aren't ten lanes and all the other roads.
Speaker 0: It appears that even if they eliminate effectively all bottlenecks like say you got ten lanes from every destination to every other destination What ends up happening in practice is that more people start driving because driving is more convenient.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm The fact that there is congestion is actually just have to have so many lanes to accommodate as many people as you have.
Speaker 1: So if you got you know as many people as New York City just every road should be 50 lanes.
Speaker 1: Cover the whole of Manhattan with just solid pavement and roads and nothing else.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and then we can all drive no problem What was that silly plan from?
Speaker 0: like the Moses did the Robert Moses days of?
Speaker 0: Fill in the East River and put buildings on it and make a big highway.
Speaker 1: Yeah There's also the one where you want to like make a road like a bridge that goes over Manhattan so you could just drive from Brooklyn in New Jersey.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like you'd be up above like 30 something the avenue just like on a bridge going all the way across.
Speaker 0: Anyway, we need more mass transit.
Speaker 0: Yeah So I got a little.
Speaker 0: not really a news news but it's something that might be interesting to you guys because a long time ago back in 2008 we did a show on net.
Speaker 1: 2008 was a long time ago.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Okay network attached storage.
Speaker 0: We talked about the boxes with hard drives that you store files on in your house.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: So where you go listen to that episode, I'll link to it If you want to know.
Speaker 1: I still have the NAS that I bought way back.
Speaker 0: It's still here - mine It's an.
Speaker 1: it's a net gear like readiness and V plus.
Speaker 0: I got the net gear like - it's only got two drives.
Speaker 0: It's a four bay.
Speaker 1: It kind of sucks.
Speaker 1: It's a little flaky.
Speaker 1: Some of the features are a little man, but it works.
Speaker 1: It still works today.
Speaker 1: I can still.
Speaker 1: it still has all my files safely.
Speaker 1: None of the drives in have ever crashed.
Speaker 1: The power supply in it actually failed and I had to get a replacement which I replaced myself and it totally worked.
Speaker 1: I Mean my files are still on there.
Speaker 1: What can I say?
Speaker 1: I feel like I want to replace it, but that's a lot of money and the one I still work.
Speaker 1: So it's hard to justify.
Speaker 0: if you want a goodness and you're someone like us Meaning that you generate a lot of like media content like you have you have workflows that involve big files.
Speaker 0: You're not normal.
Speaker 0: Yeah, because normal people there are very soon.
Speaker 1: You do not need a NAS 90% of the time No, but like if I'm recording fork, I like I'll do it.
Speaker 1: I'm doing a lot of 1080p videos.
Speaker 1: just a 4k is too big.
Speaker 0: Yeah, guys we record in 4k.
Speaker 0: say we have two cameras on a panel of packs.
Speaker 0: That's 16 gigs per camera For one panel.
Speaker 1: and I do like, you know, even if I only video panels and nothing else my whole life That's how many panels do we do a year?
Speaker 1: Oh my god times about 20 gigs each.
Speaker 1: Right if I don't want to delete anything.
Speaker 1: It's like I could just make the video then delete all the raw source material, but that I feel wrong about that Especially because I have gone into my art even though not once ever have I gone back into the.
Speaker 0: I have gone back a couple Times.
Speaker 0: one time I went back to remaster a video Removing a clip that had some copyright troubles and re-render it.
Speaker 1: The main reason I keep all this stuff is because a I feel it's wrong to delete data but also be You know, you can't see stories, you know some old person.
Speaker 1: they go into a you know They die and someone moves into the house and looks in the attic and finds a trove of old something.
Speaker 1: but right I got I got silly but I gotta leave behind that trove So a newspaper article can be written about me after I die.
Speaker 0: Well think about this.
Speaker 1: Like wow, we found this trove of old videos from the early 2000s.
Speaker 0: a lot of the stuff We know about like what it was like in New York City and like the 20s is because of just random photos shitheads took.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like you look at like you see these photos of old-timey New York and you're like, whoa And it's like I take photos like that every day those photos just boring as hell because they're like current day, New York.
Speaker 1: But if I just keep that photo around for 50 years It'll be old-timey New York and that photo will be married a hundred.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like an award-winning photo if I just hold on to it for 70 years 100 years from now Someone finds Scott's b-roll of like some random packs and they're like This is actual video from inside the first penny arcade Expo unplugged before it became the government.
Speaker 1: Yeah, look at like.
Speaker 1: look at like the handful of photos you see from 70s nerd cons.
Speaker 0: It's like oh My I mean, I'm excited.
Speaker 0: There's a picture a super low-res picture of the first I think was the second RIT anime club meeting in the year 2000. that shows me and Scott and pretty much all the friends like our entire crew from that era Sitting in different parts of this room.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm seeing that photo is amazing, even though the photos like 60 pixels across.
Speaker 0: Yeah So, uh, yeah in one 2000 right now, you probably don't need an ass.
Speaker 0: do not do this.
Speaker 0: but if you're like us and you need a Centralized place to put data from multiple devices because if you don't need multiple devices Just put a bunch of fucking hard drives in your regular computer and like raids one them.
Speaker 0: It's totally fine.
Speaker 0: I have five terabytes of raid one Like so ten terabytes rated into five terabytes and that's directly attached to six gig SATA in my computer.
Speaker 0: I'm using like eight hundred gigs of it right now if I don't count like garbage I'm just working.
Speaker 1: Yeah, dad Daz is also not a bad.
Speaker 1: if you don't need the network part of an ass a Daz is not a bad idea.
Speaker 0: Just get like a drobo or whatever that just USB or something USB 3 and plug into the back your computer Fast enough for most of what you're doing.
Speaker 1: What's also good about that solution is if you're maybe gonna switch computers Like you could unplug it from one and plug it into a laptop and that's actually faster than say sending the files over the network.
Speaker 1: Yep, you know.
Speaker 1: so it's not a bad idea to do the Daz based on unless you really need the network part.
Speaker 0: So here's why the simple parameters why I'm getting a new NAS one.
Speaker 0: I Me and Emily together both generate a lot of media.
Speaker 0: So we want a unified backup pipeline for all of our shit meaning it has to be huge.
Speaker 0: so I want a real NAS that I can set up quotas and SIF slash Samba mounts, you know SMB all that nonsense.
Speaker 0: So all our device all our main computers that create media can do fun stuff Like the automatic Windows backup of the entire file system.
Speaker 0: Why not?
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: Keep like three of those Right, you know incremental backups and also to archive to it stuff that I'm not actively working on.
Speaker 0: and then Because I want to I want to have a full pipeline Because it's a real NAS instead of the crappy netgear.
Speaker 0: I got up there.
Speaker 0: I could do something like have it back itself up once a month to Glacier.
Speaker 0: Uh-huh, and I think the best solution for someone in that prosumer Low-level professional workflow is a Synology DS 1517 plus.
Speaker 1: yes, it all G's are pretty good the cute apps I just got feeling the Synology ones you look online it like there.
Speaker 1: that software does like everything.
Speaker 0: Yep No, there's.
Speaker 0: there's multiple levels like Snellie's a lot of devices, but generally there's always two of every kind.
Speaker 0: There's the one that's pretty much only for home people and there's the one that's kind of aimed at small office business.
Speaker 0: The latter one is way faster and more reliable and better in pretty much every way.
Speaker 0: So it's probably worth it to spend the extra money.
Speaker 0: So the 1517 plus has enough horsepower.
Speaker 0: It's like a computer to where I can run like all the internal house services.
Speaker 0: I need.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's another thing.
Speaker 1: These NAS is provide a lot of features.
Speaker 1: Some of them might be redundant with your router like you can use it as a DHCP server or DNS server.
Speaker 1: Some of them have HDMI outputs.
Speaker 1: you can put videos.
Speaker 1: Let's see.
Speaker 1: Oh, you don't have an HD PC.
Speaker 1: You can plug the NAS into your TV Put video files on the NAS and then the NAS can actually play them and send them out to the TV through HDMI.
Speaker 0: I think.
Speaker 0: leave it run dockers.
Speaker 0: I could like put a getter up up there and just have it like run on my NAS I use as a print server.
Speaker 1: I have the printer plugged into the nest because my printer is USB.
Speaker 1: It doesn't have.
Speaker 1: it does not have its own network service.
Speaker 1: So you plug it into the NAS and now you every every device in the house can print.
Speaker 0: I used to do that But now I have a fancy like modern brother laser color printer and it just prints wirelessly and it just works.
Speaker 1: Yeah newer mine is a also, you know as an older black and white laser jet that is not have any network capability.
Speaker 0: Yeah, this crazy printer was so cheap.
Speaker 0: It was cheaper than it was.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Mine was also so cheap.
Speaker 1: I just bought it way long ago.
Speaker 0: Yep I only bought this one because the old laser printer I had The toner ran out and the toner didn't cost that much less than just buying a brand new printer.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so but yeah NAS is do a lot of stuff and not just store your files these days.
Speaker 0: The other reason is I want it to be this separate thing because the danger of modern malware which can get even smart people is that if you get like a crypto crypto locker kind of malware and You have a Daz plugged into your computer.
Speaker 0: Guess what the Daz gets encrypted, too.
Speaker 1: It'll be very difficult for a evil crypto locking malware to get to your NAS.
Speaker 0: Yeah, let alone even if it gets to the NAS sure it's not gonna get to the glacier backup.
Speaker 1: Yeah Well, this is one interesting thing people in talking about recently related to the big news of net neutrality.
Speaker 1: Yeah, which is if we lose net neutrality you might end up in a situation where?
Speaker 1: You got a little.
Speaker 1: you know glacier You're a cloud back.
Speaker 0: I want to download your four terabytes of like every photo of your family for generations.
Speaker 0: That'll be ten grand for that bandwidth.
Speaker 1: It's like it's all.
Speaker 1: that's just metered bandwidth.
Speaker 1: That's not net neutrality.
Speaker 1: But the point is they could block and or slow lane whatever your cloud backup provider is now.
Speaker 1: now what?
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: It's like I think actually backing up.
Speaker 1: if you're doing only cloud backups I think you may want to yup like the new.
Speaker 0: that is another reason why I'm.
Speaker 1: she may want to make sure you have local Backups once net neutrality is gone.
Speaker 0: My previous backup regime was Amazon cloud drive before they ruined it.
Speaker 0: so in the era before net neutrality was under a real threat and Amazon cloud drive existed I could pay 70 bucks a month for Infinite storage and you know what I did.
Speaker 0: I uploaded like seven terabytes of shit.
Speaker 0: I'm pretty sure people like me or why they shut that thing down.
Speaker 0: Yep, but I was using cloud only backup.
Speaker 0: I was just putting stuff on Amazon cloud drive and saying fuck it.
Speaker 0: Yep It's not gonna download seven terabytes of crap and put it somewhere before the end of the year.
Speaker 0: I ain't paying like 400 bucks a month to keep it up there.
Speaker 1: I just want to also say I got you know, a lot of my files are not well organized.
Speaker 1: I'm sure that's true for everyone.
Speaker 0: miners almost really well organized.
Speaker 1: My photos are well organized thanks to Lightroom, but nothing else is.
Speaker 0: so the geek nights archive is Organized by nature.
Speaker 1: I my video is not organized.
Speaker 1: Well, my video file is organized.
Speaker 1: I got my.
Speaker 1: I got Lightroom.
Speaker 1: I mean premier projects like all over.
Speaker 0: I made a point of consolidating that and you know what setting up that pipeline like Making my premier workflow makes sense to anyone other than me and also makes sense to me because yours probably doesn't fully make sense.
Speaker 0: You're like you're trying to open a file and you're like, wait a minute.
Speaker 0: Where is it?
Speaker 0: It took me like two weeks of like every day.
Speaker 1: So I just want to say there's a strategy you can use.
Speaker 1: It's the Scott strategy for organizing files.
Speaker 1: I did this way back in the day with mp3s and then luckily that was the end of mp3 collecting.
Speaker 1: So I was safe folder based subfolders.
Speaker 1: make one folder name it old shit and try to get everything in there.
Speaker 0: Yep, right.
Speaker 1: Don't worry about organizing the old shit.
Speaker 1: organize the new stuff just to have everything in the old shit folder.
Speaker 1: So put the old shit folder on the Nez and now on your brand new computer.
Speaker 1: Organize everything properly from from now on and like, you know come up make a folder for video projects Make one folder for each video you're making and now you're good forever more and all the old shit is in the old chip.
Speaker 0: now The only other rule that's very important any time you use something in the old shit folder put it in the new Place maybe move it first.
Speaker 1: Maybe I mean if you're making a new video project Here's one of the sources for the new project is an old video from the old shit folder.
Speaker 1: Yeah, drag it into that folder for that new project.
Speaker 0: Yeah I mostly organize my media now by.
Speaker 0: where I took the footage like this is from PAX 2016 and then in there there's a folder like this is b-roll.
Speaker 0: This is the panel we did.
Speaker 1: You know, the point is the old the main strategy.
Speaker 1: I'm trying to teach people is the old?
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, but Scott I put everything in the old shit folder strategy.
Speaker 0: Do you have in your old shit folder an old shit folder that might have an old shit folder?
Speaker 1: Because I do.
Speaker 1: I have Only two layers deep of old shit folders my M. Oh, I have an old shit folder and it is mp3s and in that is an old shit folder even older mp3.
Speaker 0: My oldest that's as deep as it goes on earth is my mp3 collection.
Speaker 1: Okay, so anyway, because I did organize it at one point That's why it only goes too deep.
Speaker 0: five bay nazis are the sweet spot right now.
Speaker 1: I got four bay.
Speaker 1: I think four bay is good enough.
Speaker 1: So you can get a big drives these days.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so here's the other thing.
Speaker 1: like you have four eight terabyte drives 24 T. That's good enough for now.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so I'm still living on four two terabyte drives.
Speaker 0: No problem Yeah, I got two five terabyte drives in my current computer and I'm looking at putting five eight terabyte drives in the NAS.
Speaker 0: Because not bad eight terabytes is the sweet spot right now.
Speaker 0: They're like 200 to 250 bucks for a 5400 rpm.
Speaker 0: and yes, you want a slower drive and a NAS.
Speaker 0: don't be stupid.
Speaker 1: What's your hurry?
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's a NAS.
Speaker 1: If they even had they even sell.
Speaker 1: if you're not sure on Newegg Western Digital actually sell NAS drives.
Speaker 1: I think a lot of it is just sort of like no bullshit mark.
Speaker 0: I looked into it.
Speaker 0: So I Think I recommend Western Digital because they seem to be the generally most reliable.
Speaker 1: I mean, no, but I mean I'm time at the everyone all the different drive manufacturers these days are marketing Like these are sick drives that you should use for you're like, no, I learned why this?
Speaker 0: Why I actually know the deal here.
Speaker 0: So and this is not a Western Digital ad but the black drives are the ones that are high performance.
Speaker 0: But the counterpoint is at least on paper.
Speaker 0: They are higher performance.
Speaker 0: Okay They're also louder they spin faster.
Speaker 0: They generate more heat and vibration.
Speaker 0: But but they're faster.
Speaker 0: Don't put that shit in your NAS.
Speaker 0: They have the like blue which is like the normal drives.
Speaker 1: If you don't want to just get a NAS and fill it with SSDs You can think of no.
Speaker 1: but like you think about how much space a three and a half inch drive takes up right now.
Speaker 1: think about how much space an m2 drive takes up.
Speaker 1: I Yes, so why can't I get a little tiny thing?
Speaker 1: That's got like 10 m2 drives in it and that's hide it away in a closet somewhere.
Speaker 1: It's just godspeed.
Speaker 1: Right, but has the IE lanes.
Speaker 0: because the problem is m2 is only useful if you plug it into PCIe.
Speaker 0: If you plug it into SATA, it's not really faster.
Speaker 1: I see someone just make a board that has a whole bunch of PCI ease and a controller chip and a network card.
Speaker 0: Cuz those seep those lanes Lanes lanes back to the lanes.
Speaker 1: Make a chip that's got a thousand lanes on it.
Speaker 0: Anyway, that's we'll.
Speaker 0: we'll talk about that in the future.
Speaker 0: Sure.
Speaker 0: So Where's it?
Speaker 0: cuz?
Speaker 0: I want to wrap this up.
Speaker 1: gotta go to the metamoment.
Speaker 0: The deal with the five with those drives is that the NAS drives Western Digital splits into two kinds of NAS drives.
Speaker 0: They're the red ones.
Speaker 0: There's the regular ones and the pro ones.
Speaker 0: the pro ones are louder Hotter and you probably don't want them.
Speaker 0: In fact, you most definitely don't want them.
Speaker 0: They also cost a lot more money.
Speaker 0: The only reason you'd ever get those so-called pro Western Digital Reds for a NAS is if the NAS has more than five bays.
Speaker 0: the reason for this Ostensibly is that up to about five bays the vibrations from all these drives acting in sync is reasonable.
Speaker 0: if you have eight drives all in a giant as and they're all doing that of the same things you like raid five or eight six then Not only are the consequences of multiple failures more devastating the consequences of multiple failures are more likely because multiple simultaneous failures are more likely and Drives are prone to that synchronized vibration.
Speaker 1: Why not have the bays like individually like floating or something or Offsets.
Speaker 1: they're not all in the same position.
Speaker 1: or they're at angles or have half of them are vertical and have them horizontal.
Speaker 0: There's a lot of reasons for that But the way they are today, that's how any NAS you're gonna see is gonna be.
Speaker 1: I wonder how big data centers handle that problem.
Speaker 0: Uh, they buy good drives and they use specialized harnesses or just use SSDs like you this to you unit where you just go SSD SSD SSD SSD you put like 32 of them in a row.
Speaker 0: Yeah Can I get one of those if you got like out like 80k?
Speaker 0: Yeah, let's do it.
Speaker 0: It'll be so loud We couldn't talk next to it.
Speaker 0: SSDs are loud or just the fan cooling Yeah, but anyway eight terabytes the sweet spot for three and a half inch drives right now.
Speaker 0: And ten terabyte is too much money.
Speaker 0: for how much you get?
Speaker 0: twelve terabyte is way too much money.
Speaker 0: It's good for a PC, but not for a NAS.
Speaker 0: the expensive Pro Red Western Digital NAS drives have Extra vibration dampening and extra environmental stuff to protect them from this stuff.
Speaker 0: The only other thing is you do RAID 5 or RAID 6 with a lot of drives because RAID 6 protects you against two failures.
Speaker 1: My NAS has like its own custom RAID which is It's some sort of RAID 5 and I just said okay use whatever RAID you want.
Speaker 1: This is okay and it works.
Speaker 0: so here's the problem.
Speaker 0: if you have a lot of bays if a if a disk goes into NAS and you're using the equivalent of RAID 5 then if another drive goes before you You're only safe with one drive going down.
Speaker 0: But it's worse because when you put a new drive in to replace it now all the existing drives Have to work overtime to rebuild the array into that new drive Correct increasing the chance that one will fail before it finishes Because those are the drives.
Speaker 1: I feel like you're still pretty safe with a RAID 5.
Speaker 0: So I would go with RAID 6 if I had the 5 bay if I weren't gonna do this backup strategy to glacier.
Speaker 0: If the RAID 5 the worst case scenario is in I lose a drive.
Speaker 0: I immediately put in the cold spare.
Speaker 0: the array fails before the cold spare finishes.
Speaker 0: I lose at most 30 days of data.
Speaker 0: as I go back to my glacier backup.
Speaker 0: I'm willing to take that risk and that that gives daddy 32 terabytes of redundant storage for about two grand.
Speaker 1: if my crappy NAS.
Speaker 1: That's a piece of junk that only had a power supply fail has kept me safe without even one failure.
Speaker 0: I've had two drives fail in that thing over the last.
Speaker 0: I'm feeling pretty good.
Speaker 0: I've had two drives at the same time not at the same time.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: It's a two drive with RAID 1.
Speaker 0: So if I lost both, yeah So yeah, I'll link to the forum thread where I say exactly what I'm about to buy.
Speaker 0: But this feels like the sweet spot.
Speaker 0: and again, you only need this if you're like us.
Speaker 0: But anyway things of the day What do you got?
Speaker 1: so, you know, this is this is sort of genre of video article whatever where people like to Debunk experts at things particularly subjective things and the one that always comes to mind is like wine experts Like get some wine experts and they'll give them some wines without telling them what they are like.
Speaker 1: Oh, can you tell?
Speaker 1: and they can sort of not tell.
Speaker 0: it's sort of best I've seen is there are some people who can tell but they'd like they're specially trained and they seem to not actually enjoy wine.
Speaker 1: Point is is that they're exposing the amount of bullshit.
Speaker 1: Yeah is sort of outright.
Speaker 1: But anyway here I saw a link to this video today Where there was a cheese expert who is going to try to identify the more expensive cheese.
Speaker 1: and it's like I Thought at first is gonna be one of those videos where they're like, you know showing you that like cheese expert is bullshit or something.
Speaker 1: But actually first of all, it wasn't a completely blind thing.
Speaker 1: the cheese expert looks at the two cheeses a and B with their eyes and then taste the cheeses and then tells you which one is more expensive.
Speaker 1: right and First of all I think it's hard to argue after watching this video that cheese expert has a lot of bullshit in it.
Speaker 1: Like they were able to successfully and correctly identify like every single fucking cheese.
Speaker 0: So fun fact.
Speaker 1: I used to work with this awesome Greek dude at my old company and like they were able to tell you what kind of milk It was and like how long it was aged.
Speaker 1: And like welcome.
Speaker 1: and it was like.
Speaker 1: this is a first of all you it watching this really made me appreciate cheese more Care about cheese more.
Speaker 1: I learned a lot about cheese.
Speaker 1: I
Speaker 0: went out and got some feta cuz we were gonna have like just like tomato
Speaker 1: and it's clearly not an ad or anything because Like the person was able like I know exactly what cheese this is did not say any brands or anything Right,
Speaker 0: but I went out and got feta.
Speaker 0: cuz we're gonna make like a lunch in the office and I come back with it And it's just like in this nondescript bag like no label on or anything.
Speaker 0: I bring this feta out and we start to eat it and he's like, why'd you get some bullshit Bulgarian feta?
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm, and I'm like what?
Speaker 0: He's like, this is not Greek feta.
Speaker 0: This is Bulgarian.
Speaker 0: Maybe it's American but ain't real.
Speaker 0: and he was right.
Speaker 0: I bought like the cheap Bulgarian feta.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's yeah, if you want to you know, learn something about cheese.
Speaker 1: I'm sure everyone but a lot of people listening to this who aren't lactose intolerant Most people I know really fucking love cheese.
Speaker 0: Natalie's like me into this video.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, but it's like he's seen it.
Speaker 1: It's like I'm.
Speaker 1: you know, I think most people are like me at least most people I know where it's like.
Speaker 1: you're not a cheese.
Speaker 1: nerd cheese isn't your hobby.
Speaker 1: You just cheese.
Speaker 1: it really delicious.
Speaker 1: You always love to eat a cheese.
Speaker 1: You also would love to learn about a cheese.
Speaker 1: It's just not something that comes to mind except when cheese is available.
Speaker 0: That's why you need a friend like we go with Natalie will go out and come with like weird cheeses.
Speaker 1: So check out this cheese info here for a cheese layperson.
Speaker 1: good stuff.
Speaker 0: So speaking of Removing in for me deleting information why Scott can't delete these old videos of like packs 2008?
Speaker 0: so I found this Twitter thread and It's a real good Twitter thread about how someone wasted their day falling down this weird rabbit hole.
Speaker 0: So they found this picture of the Temple of Olympian Zeus in Athens from 1858.
Speaker 0: There's this thing on top of it.
Speaker 0: There's like this thing there in the phone in the picture.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so he's like What's that thing in this picture?
Speaker 0: and then he looks at a picture of the restoration.
Speaker 0: There's no thing like that in the restoration, but there's a thing like that in this picture.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: So then he goes maybe the restorations with the wrong angle.
Speaker 0: So there's not much to this ruin.
Speaker 0: Like it's just pretty tall.
Speaker 1: I mean, it's from Athenian times the shit old son way older than some piece of shit cloister.
Speaker 0: So then he finds in like a textbook or something.
Speaker 0: That's all Older than the Parthenon another picture that doesn't have the thing on it.
Speaker 0: So he's like, alright, maybe someone added this thing Like no, it fell off.
Speaker 0: No, it's so much crazier than that.
Speaker 0: so then he realized that the photo without the thing is the exact same photo as the photo with the thing and he Proved that the thing was clearly airbrushed out Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: So the plot thickened and then he found this painting that shows the thing.
Speaker 0: Someone painted it with the thing and then he found another painting.
Speaker 0: then he found this like essay Someone wrote from a lot like from the 1700s.
Speaker 0: That was like.
Speaker 0: there's this thing like.
Speaker 0: they mentioned the thing.
Speaker 1: Okay, and if you follow you sure this isn't a movie about a genie starring Sinbad the comedian.
Speaker 0: If you follow this thread all the way to the end What the thing is is funny Crazy and Ridiculous together.
Speaker 0: it did exist.
Speaker 0: It was a thing and now I know what that thing was.
Speaker 1: Why doesn't someone just go there now and look at it cuz it's gone.
Speaker 0: Oh, it was removed.
Speaker 1: I mean, I meant the whole temple is still there, right?
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, but the thing was removed.
Speaker 0: the thing was added after this was built in ancient at like old times.
Speaker 1: So it's not.
Speaker 0: the thing is not Athenian, but it was added to the Athenian thing Mm-hmm, and then someone else said what the fuck is this thing and removed it as it wasn't Athenian and There was very little documentation as to how or why.
Speaker 0: and this thread explains it all.
Speaker 1: and it was it perhaps Romans that added it.
Speaker 0: Oh, it ends with screaming hobos living on top of pillars demanding food from people who pass by.
Speaker 0: it goes crazy in a hurry.
Speaker 1: Okay, it's just some hostile architecture to keep hobos off the temple.
Speaker 0: It's so much better than that, but you end up with pictures like this of Saints sitting on top of pillars screaming at people, okay?
Speaker 0: This was a very fascinating thing that I read.
Speaker 0: all right, it's this guy this hobo guy.
Speaker 0: He's chained to the top of this pillar.
Speaker 1: Oh, is that what the thing is?
Speaker 1: Yeah People up there to punish.
Speaker 0: No, they've chained themselves up there to be closer to God.
Speaker 1: Good luck.
Speaker 0: It's good times.
Speaker 0: So some Christian nut jobs put it up there and then all then that our Turks removed them for it's complicated.
Speaker 1: You shoot arrows at him.
Speaker 1: I'll get him down.
Speaker 0: Yeah, or just don't bring them food.
Speaker 1: Oh rocks at him.
Speaker 0: So in the moment, we've been crazy busy.
Speaker 0: you notice we didn't do shows after back some plug.
Speaker 0: that's cuz.
Speaker 0: Scott apparently is dying of Tuberculosis.
Speaker 1: and then it was Thanksgiving.
Speaker 1: Yep, but now up until the end of the month.
Speaker 1: We are doing Jack and shit, which means you're getting geek nights episodes for four weeks.
Speaker 0: Yep, and other associated projects.
Speaker 0: that includes that includes this one.
Speaker 1: So this is the first of at least 18 nights episodes in a row and also much more important.
Speaker 0: in January There's gonna probably be like a couple weeks without a lot of geek nights cuz we're gonna be presenting a ton of things gonna be New Year's there's gonna be mad.
Speaker 0: We're gonna be a mag fast doing a bunch of panels.
Speaker 1: Can you hear it in the distance?
Speaker 0: I hear him.
Speaker 0: What's that?
Speaker 0: Do you hear it?
Speaker 0: I Got a terrifying shirt off like toga.
Speaker 0: We're gonna be a packs unplugged doing at least one panel.
Speaker 0: the panel You mean peck south peck south?
Speaker 1: Yes the packs unplugged already.
Speaker 0: You can see the number of packs is exceeded the ability of my brain to keep them all in order.
Speaker 0: I keep having these panic moments where I'll be like booking a hotel room for like pecks East and then be like, oh shit I didn't see my panels and they're like, oh wait.
Speaker 0: No, that's not even open yet.
Speaker 0: pecks East we I submit I got three packs is before pecks East.
Speaker 0: Yep So we will be at pecks out on Friday 4 p.m.
Speaker 0: In the Bobcat theater talking about balance in game design.
Speaker 0: This is a brand new geek nights lecture courtesy of Scott cuz.
Speaker 1: rim doesn't have anything new.
Speaker 0: Hey, do you know how much fucking work it took to make that carcass own panel?
Speaker 1: I made this panel already.
Speaker 1: It's like 30% done.
Speaker 1: It took me like a couple hours.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it only took me like one day to make that carcass own panel But it was like one full day of like get.
Speaker 0: mostly I had to take pictures of carcass own tiles a lot of them.
Speaker 0: That was a lot more word in front the old BGG.
Speaker 0: no, because Most people upload pictures of the BGG.
Speaker 0: upload them with the license of.
Speaker 0: you can't use this shit.
Speaker 1: Take a flatbed scanner.
Speaker 1: put all the carcass own tiles you can on it and the scan once now you get.
Speaker 0: That would be way more work than just setting up the cut it into a grid in Photoshop.
Speaker 0: That would be so much more work.
Speaker 0: I just took pictures of interesting carcass own situations.
Speaker 1: Anyway, uh, Use the app and take screenshots.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna pick the next book club book real soon.
Speaker 0: lean in toward the new translation of the Odyssey like real hard I don't.
Speaker 1: you're not choosing as your book club book is.
Speaker 1: if you were actually gonna you know Make the good on your threat you would have done it already, but I don't know if it's still the case.
Speaker 1: But it was recently the case that rims favorite count of Monte Cristo Kindle version was like 57 cents or something like that the penguin book.
Speaker 1: Oh, that's the good one, right?
Speaker 1: It was like 57 cents on Amazon.
Speaker 1: So I'm just like, oh 57 cent whatever.
Speaker 0: you should probably just read it anyway, even if I don't make it the book club Unlikely until I'm old man, but hey 57 cent.
Speaker 0: I was saying.
Speaker 1: I don't know if it's still true though Go take a look.
Speaker 0: All I'm saying is it's a lot of pages and something happens Every page.
Speaker 0: sure, there's no pages where nothing happens.
Speaker 1: So 10,000 things happen.
Speaker 1: It is.
Speaker 0: Yeah Yeah, it is not.
Speaker 0: it's like the Wheel of Time, right?
Speaker 0: It's not great expectations which to this day I never actually read.
Speaker 1: Ulysses the famous.
Speaker 0: I wrote multiple essays on great expectations.
Speaker 0: I know I can talk about miss Havisham forever and status house.
Speaker 0: I have no idea what actually happens in that stupid book pip and such.
Speaker 1: That's all I know is that it's the thing with the guy named Pip.
Speaker 1: You know less than me so, you know almost nothing it other than that it's a famous novel.
Speaker 0: All I know is that to write essays on it in high school and I wrote them without reading it.
Speaker 0: Anyway, I got A's.
Speaker 1: I guess You should go on the internet and find geek nights.
Speaker 1: in every place that geek nights exist Which is every place that is on the internet you probably before net neutrality is gone You can still find us on YouTube and every social network and then once net neutrality is here Who knows if you'll be able to find us at
Speaker 0: all?
Speaker 0: So main bit Talking about how to kiss because we've recently like I bought a new computer.
Speaker 1: today is Cyber Monday.
Speaker 1: Whoo.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and let me tell you where people spend money for the sake of spending money.
Speaker 0: in my opinion there is nothing on sale for either Black Friday or Cyber Monday in the nerdy PC.
Speaker 0: can pro-sumer electronics area That is worth it, nope, everything that's on sale is either old inventory that people trying to get rid of Crappy stuff like the bottom tier
Speaker 1: T only stuff that would be good and on sale is stuff that is Incredibly low availability and is not worth the fight.
Speaker 1: in order to save that amount of money You could like to spend five hours fighting to save like a hundred bucks on something.
Speaker 1: It's like dude in five hours.
Speaker 1: You could just work a job and make a hundred bucks even worse.
Speaker 0: So those NAS drives I want right like I was doing my research They're on crazy sale on Cyber Monday, and they're cheaper just normally on Amazon.
Speaker 1: So Yeah, oh you mean new egg Cyber Monday?
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but pretty much no.
Speaker 0: Cyber Monday tech sales seems to have anything worthwhile.
Speaker 0: No, it's always.
Speaker 0: it's literally like the laptop that is legit too slow for you to use.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like I have a new egg wish list and a steam wish list and all these wish lists.
Speaker 1: I get notifications like whoa shit on your wish list is cheaper now because it's a sale day.
Speaker 1: But it's like yeah, but after the sale the price always goes down.
Speaker 1: It just keeps going down and down and down forever until you get newer stuff.
Speaker 1: Yeah, new stuff is expensive.
Speaker 1: old stuff is cheap.
Speaker 0: Absolute RAM for your older computer is gonna be cheaper like a month from now than it is now.
Speaker 0: Yep, probably So, uh, we want to talk a little bit about how you how we at least like how you make the decision of what to Buy like how you actually do your research.
Speaker 0: You're trying to buy like a NAS or a computer like the specific ways we figure this out.
Speaker 1: Well, first of all, I got to say a lot of people out there Right, especially I see on the internet a frequent comment is like hey, you know, I just got a Nintendo switch What are essential things I should get for it?
Speaker 1: or hey, I just got an iPhone.
Speaker 1: What are what are apps that I must have right?
Speaker 1: It's like this kind of thinking not just in technology But in all consumerism is wrong.
Speaker 1: thinking you're basically saying I just want to spend money.
Speaker 1: What the fuck should I spend it on?
Speaker 1: where which toilet should I throw money into?
Speaker 0: there's no orthogonal direction to go.
Speaker 0: There's a third component.
Speaker 0: if someone said I am a gamer What are useful apps to have on my phone for tabletop gaming like scorekeepers and such?
Speaker 0: No, see that is different because that is still I have a task and I'm looking for tools.
Speaker 1: Okay, see, you know saying I'm a gamer what apps should I get is still.
Speaker 1: it's more specific but it's still not better enough.
Speaker 1: It should be.
Speaker 1: well you wait until the exact moment.
Speaker 1: You actually have a specific need.
Speaker 1: like holy crap I am here right now in my life and I'm trying to play a board game and I'm having trouble keeping score.
Speaker 1: Now I can ask what is the specific thing that will solve my problem?
Speaker 1: and then if it costs money then you buy it.
Speaker 1: Right, don't just go buying stuff right.
Speaker 1: you
Speaker 0: only
Speaker 1: buy things that solve a problem you have We just talked about NAS is if you have not run into the situation in your life where you are facing a hardship And then have discovered that the hardship related to storage will be solved by a NAS and that is the best solution to your problem.
Speaker 1: Don't just go in looking at NAS and pricing them out, right?
Speaker 1: You have to have the need for a thing comes first Then you do the research to find what is the best solution and then you go shopping.
Speaker 0: now We're gonna skip.
Speaker 0: there is a separate problem of how do you know what your needs are?
Speaker 1: Like what does you have a problem?
Speaker 1: There's something in your life that you are having trouble with people I'm playing.
Speaker 0: I'm playing a little devil advocate here.
Speaker 0: the people who clearly have a problem don't realize it's a problem.
Speaker 0: Well, they don't recognize.
Speaker 1: telling him how to shop isn't gonna help them, right?
Speaker 1: That's a different problem, which is you don't know you got a problem.
Speaker 0: But so think of it this way.
Speaker 0: There's a try fit.
Speaker 0: There's three elements.
Speaker 0: There's a triptych here you.
Speaker 0: there's the need Or the task.
Speaker 0: they're the same thing the task the thing you're trying to do That you either can't do now or want to be able to do better.
Speaker 0: There's the tool and Then there is the shopping.
Speaker 1: Yes, the actual purchasing of the thing Yes, so choosing the exact one and how much to pay get the best price for it, etc.
Speaker 0: So I will very rarely Occasionally, I'll poke around and be like are there hard drives that are cheap?
Speaker 0: because I want to.
Speaker 1: I want to be aware I'm just keeping I'm just collecting information.
Speaker 1: Yeah But I'm not buying unless I actually unless they have a bunch of full drives and go or buying a new computer and I'm going Oh shit, my drives are full.
Speaker 1: I need drives.
Speaker 1: I don't go randomly buying drives just because they're cheap.
Speaker 1: But if I'm in a situation where it's like, oh, I know I just but it I go to look at new I can see what drives cost just because I want to be informed of what the state of the world is.
Speaker 1: Yep So if you're the kind of person who buys computer, but even if I went to new egg and saw like 100 terabyte drive 10 bucks Unless I needed it.
Speaker 1: I wouldn't buy even the 10 bucks.
Speaker 1: Yep, cuz by they when I do need it They'll have thousand terabyte drive for five bucks.
Speaker 0: So I usually pretty much always first try to document for myself at least in my brain.
Speaker 0: But sometimes I'll write it down or usually I'll draw something like what do I?
Speaker 0: what do I need to do?
Speaker 0: Like in the NAS case, I want to back up all these PCs with tons of storage and your current NAS is full.
Speaker 1: Yep, and you got a problem.
Speaker 0: Yep to something and I want that thing to back up to some other thing like Amazon Glacier.
Speaker 0: So that already is a more complex task than you might think because I'm not just saying here's the workflow I want but I'm also thinking about What could be it?
Speaker 0: What could I do with this workflow that I couldn't have done before?
Speaker 0: Is there something I'm missing?
Speaker 0: Is there an alternative solution?
Speaker 0: is the thing I'm trying to accomplish even worth accomplishing Right.
Speaker 1: So for example, like I have a router my routers mad old and it's got some problems with it.
Speaker 1: It's not perfect.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right, but it works.
Speaker 1: everything connects to it.
Speaker 1: It you know, it does the DHCP just fine.
Speaker 1: It totally works, right?
Speaker 1: But I've thought you know my new iPads my new iPhones they use like newer faster Wi-Fi.
Speaker 1: this router I have only does a BGN this new stuff like AC and even other 802 11's that I don't even know what they are now.
Speaker 1: Right, but I could get faster Wi-Fi with a newer router and get better features and such, you know, whatever right?
Speaker 1: Should I buy a new router when I have a perfectly working one?
Speaker 1: and I said, you know what?
Speaker 1: You know while it's tempting to go around researching routers and you look at them and you want to buy stuff because you know Consumerism buying stuff is fun, right?
Speaker 1: You have to have the conscious brain that fights against that urge to buy stuff and spend money because it's like alright.
Speaker 1: I imagine that I bought a new fancy router and that Wi-Fi was somehow faster.
Speaker 1: How would my life be different?
Speaker 1: I would be poorer and Would I even notice?
Speaker 1: yep, like the speed of 802 11 and or whatever the hell I have now is already faster than the internet connection I get from the cable modem now, so An alternative discussion might be.
Speaker 1: so I never had a problem where my Wi-Fi wasn't fast enough for what I'm doing.
Speaker 0: say your router is marginal meaning it, you know, the speed isn't really a problem, but it occasionally needs to be rebooted because Overheating and you have a real problem.
Speaker 1: your shits broken.
Speaker 1: you gotta replace it.
Speaker 0: But then there's the question of do you replace it with the cheap thing that?
Speaker 0: Accomplishes the same thing before?
Speaker 0: or do your future proof by spending the money because you got to buy one Anyway to buy a better one?
Speaker 0: right and that comes down to the thing we say all the time on geek nights You got to identify.
Speaker 0: are you at a plateau of that technology?
Speaker 1: Yeah, so this happens.
Speaker 1: quite, you know When it actually comes to buying something there's usually three options, right?
Speaker 1: There's the bleeding edge latest and greatest expensive option.
Speaker 1: There is the very reasonable middle price option that it's pretty much like just great but not you know as amazing as the bleeding edge option.
Speaker 1: and there's the Really crazy value el cheapo option.
Speaker 1: that's not as good as the other two But damn you get a lot for your
Speaker 0: money like a one terabyte internal like cheapo West digital drive is 50 bucks
Speaker 1: right and it's like Shockingly cheap like
Speaker 0: any bucks for a terabyte
Speaker 1: like wow this hard drive might crash, but holy crap That's a lot for 50 bucks.
Speaker 0: Like that's such a value except yet 90 bucks for four terabytes.
Speaker 1: Like there's no read.
Speaker 1: like they're cheaper things than this, but why would you go cheaper?
Speaker 1: This is the cheapest thing you would possibly buy.
Speaker 0: tried to sort by cheapness and it's showing me cables because right sort.
Speaker 1: Well, so it's like how do you choose which?
Speaker 0: here you go Scott?
Speaker 0: You can buy right now today a refurbished Seagate Barracuda 160 gigabyte drive for 10 bucks, but I mean like damn.
Speaker 0: yeah That is a piece of garbage $10 for a literal piece of god.
Speaker 1: Well, you bought ten of them.
Speaker 1: Be 160 bucks.
Speaker 1: no 160 gigs for no.
Speaker 1: No 1600 $50 0.6 terabytes for $100.
Speaker 1: Is that a better deal than one terabyte for 50 bucks?
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: No, yeah anyway See like it's.
Speaker 1: oh it's always like a tough choice depending on what your situation is and it comes down to like How much you care right?
Speaker 1: So it's like for example, let's say you're buying.
Speaker 1: well You're buying a mouse.
Speaker 0: how much you care.
Speaker 0: but think how much you care now.
Speaker 0: how much do you care about the situation?
Speaker 0: Three to five years from now?
Speaker 0: and what's the opportunity cost for today?
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: It's like you're buying a mouse, right?
Speaker 1: Well, even if you're not if you're a pro gamer You should be buying the expensive mouse because that's a very important piece of equipment for your pro gaming needs.
Speaker 1: Right, if you're a gamer but not super pro You can definitely get away with the perfectly normal middle-of-the-road mouse.
Speaker 1: if you get the basic cheapo mouse You're gonna have problems even with your middle-of-the-road normal gamer ring, right?
Speaker 1: But if you're a normal person you get el cheapo mouse.
Speaker 1: But the thing with el cheapo mouse is even though it's an amazing mouse for five bucks is gonna break.
Speaker 1: It's like getting the $5 sunglasses or the $5 umbrella.
Speaker 1: You're gonna have to buy like ten of them, right?
Speaker 1: It's not gonna last that long.
Speaker 1: you're gonna be buying a mouse every year when like a Chip break, you know a piece of it breaks
Speaker 0: the old parable of it's it's it's more expensive to be poor because you have to buy stuff that costs too much for how durable it is and Then it wears out immediately because you can't afford to buy the one durable thing.
Speaker 1: Yep So, you know, that's you know It's like well if you need the mouse immediately and all you can afford is a cheap one get the cheap one Because it's still pretty great for that cheapo price.
Speaker 1: But if you can afford to go in middle-of-the-road then you should because then you're actually gonna be saving money possibly if Durability is your issue.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right But if the only if the durability of the cheaper one is fine And the only issue is like your DPI because it's a mouse and you're not gaming just get el cheapo mouse You'll never notice the difference in your whole life.
Speaker 1: Yep So buying a nice like I'll never notice the difference in that faster router in my whole life.
Speaker 0: But it is already a pretty specialized use case.
Speaker 0: So assuming I know like you'd like I said, I got to work for like there's a thing I want to do.
Speaker 0: Having a modern as will solve that problem.
Speaker 0: It additionally solves all these other like Problems that weren't pressing.
Speaker 0: like there are features that will be nice for me that I didn't need But if they come along with the solution to a problem I have then that's great.
Speaker 0: So I'll get the NAS but they're gonna figure out what drives to buy and that was how I'd you know I went to Newegg and I literally just showed to show me hard drives bigger than four terabytes Just to see like what are the options?
Speaker 0: What do things cost?
Speaker 0: so I can begin to figure out like, okay There's this green one in this red one.
Speaker 0: What the hell's the difference between those?
Speaker 0: does the NAS drive really matter all that nonsense?
Speaker 1: So the way to figure it.
Speaker 1: so that's like I get.
Speaker 1: I said basically choose between the cheap middle and fancy option.
Speaker 1: But when you go to Newegg or Amazon or wherever you're going to buy anything, there's not only three choices There's like a thousand choices.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: So how do you narrow it down?
Speaker 1: Here's how I narrow it down.
Speaker 0: All right, because I'll see how you if I do it different so they'll use your hard drives, right?
Speaker 1: So first of all, there's certain specs of the thing that you know are set in stone.
Speaker 0: It's got to be at least four terabytes.
Speaker 1: It has to be a SATA drive.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it can't be an old IDE drive Right.
Speaker 1: So you lock in.
Speaker 1: it must be SATA drives, right?
Speaker 1: You look at like SATA and like well all the new modern SATA is like six gigabits per second.
Speaker 1: So you filter out all the old versions of SATA only the new versions, right?
Speaker 1: Then you say okay And I need at least this much space per drive.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you filter on storage.
Speaker 1: That's set in stone.
Speaker 1: You can't change your mind about that.
Speaker 1: It needs to be at least.
Speaker 1: you said four terabytes.
Speaker 1: fine.
Speaker 1: All the ones smaller than four get out of my face.
Speaker 0: Yep, just broad brushes here All right, then you get your price in there.
Speaker 1: Well, obviously I don't even know point.
Speaker 0: Oh really because I want to know if there's an outlier either real high or real low.
Speaker 0: I want to know about it.
Speaker 1: at this initial stage I don't filter out low prices but I do filter out high prices because they like.
Speaker 1: if you're looking for video cards like Yeah, like there's always someone throwing in one.
Speaker 1: That's like the Intel i9 whatever it's like that.
Speaker 1: I don't need that It's never.
Speaker 0: I do like to know.
Speaker 1: so I pick a very red like there's a point at which the price is ridiculous.
Speaker 0: Hi, okay.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: So you're do the thing I do.
Speaker 0: I'll be like not more than two gray.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right It's like hard drives.
Speaker 1: It's like a four terabyte drive Not spending more than say $200 than one of those.
Speaker 1: filter out everything that cost more than 300.
Speaker 0: Oh Our drive filter I specifically looked for under 500 because I wanted to see I would never even spend 400 on a drive.
Speaker 0: But if you want to look sure, but you know Well, I wanted to see what the what the because here's the thing.
Speaker 0: get back to the plateau.
Speaker 0: I want to know where the plateau is on drives.
Speaker 0: in terms of like a six terabyte drive is Not that much cheaper than an eight terabyte so you should probably go for the eight terabyte.
Speaker 0: the ten terabyte is Significantly more expensive than the eight terabyte.
Speaker 1: to figure that out What I do is I sort by the low price and then I keep changing the storage requirement to look across right like that, but Like there's some like these are the specs that you care about?
Speaker 1: the price the story We're only.
Speaker 1: you know, this is only hard drives, but it applies to everything else.
Speaker 1: Let me talk about video cards, right?
Speaker 1: It's like, okay well
Speaker 0: I know
Speaker 1: that I'm either getting a 1070 or 1080 because 1060 and 1050 or two weeks for my awesome gaming PC and I know it's got to be PCI Express 16 and I know it's got to have two HDM eyes in the back and two display ports.
Speaker 1: Not one of those four display port ones because I'm plugging it into a TV you
Speaker 0: know, it's gotta be in video which actually we should talk about because we if you keep an eye on the trends of the thing you're researching you'll also be able to narrow it down by a Reasonable list of trusted brand.
Speaker 1: right you're buying a TV.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: Well, I know that you know, these brands are good.
Speaker 1: These brands are not good.
Speaker 1: I know that I need to have this many inputs on the bag like this the spec, you know I need this many inches for my room because my room is this big.
Speaker 0: Oh, these are.
Speaker 1: how do you?
Speaker 0: how do you figure out the brand like?
Speaker 0: do you even look at AMD or like?
Speaker 0: do you?
Speaker 0: Look at ATI video cards or just do you not know?
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: I know not anymore.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I might though I am slightly paying attention to all the rising.
Speaker 1: You know biz and radion biz but it I haven't heard enough biz from there to convince me to look at them yet.
Speaker 0: Well, like hard drives, I pretty much limited it to Western Digital and Seagate because all the other drives.
Speaker 1: Oh, you look to brands.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: Well, so I don't like in the brand what I do.
Speaker 1: I eliminate brand.
Speaker 0: I eliminate the Sorni's in the magnet box.
Speaker 1: the final thing I do and you know There's not a hundred percent validity to this but I sort by review rate user review, right?
Speaker 1: It's like an Amazon.
Speaker 1: I look at the stars and a new egg.
Speaker 1: I look at the eggs and I go bring the highest average reviews by users to the top.
Speaker 1: Sometimes this will send you on a false errand.
Speaker 1: For example, they're You know, this a system is as rock right as rock is like the cheapo aces boards that motherboards they kind of work But you know, they're good.
Speaker 1: They're not the worst but they're cheapo aces boards.
Speaker 1: They give rebates to people who write new egg reviews.
Speaker 1: So if you sort motherboards by reviews as rocks show up first like almost all the time because and you'll see in the reviews people are like I'm writing this because of You know the rebate review program, but they're still leaving a positive review.
Speaker 1: They're honest reviews.
Speaker 1: I've seen people doing for the rebate review program with one egg.
Speaker 0: So I used to I don't like.
Speaker 0: this option seems to have disappeared for me on Amazon because I tried to do it earlier today.
Speaker 0: But I used to sort things not by highest average review, but by number of reviews Because on Amazon that would tell me what's the thing most people after.
Speaker 1: well, I mean after sorting by best, you know highest rating Yeah, you can look and say oh well That first one has like only five ratings and it's like they'll be one with perfect five stars But only five like
Speaker 0: when you buy the CPU and
Speaker 1: another one has like 2,000 ratings and is like 4.3 stars.
Speaker 1: It's like if you got thousands of ratings and you're still at 4.3 stars.
Speaker 1: that is might as well be five stars.
Speaker 0: Yes, but if you're buying like a CPU and you're a gamer You just look for what CPU from the current generation has the most reviews.
Speaker 0: It's probably the one that every gamer is buying and that's probably the one you want.
Speaker 0: Yeah And it's in.
Speaker 0: previously was that Intel like 6700 K I7.
Speaker 1: the other thing is when you look at the reviews every site has a little graph showing you how many fives how many fours?
Speaker 1: How many threes?
Speaker 1: Sometimes you'll see two different things and both are rated like four and a half stars or four and a half eggs.
Speaker 1: When you actually look at the reviews, right?
Speaker 1: What you're gonna see is that one of them is gonna have a huge pile of fives and a little bit of ones.
Speaker 1: That's bringing it down.
Speaker 0: Oh Read I actually read the text.
Speaker 0: I read
Speaker 1: Yeah, and then so and then you look at another one and another one maybe has like sort of a little curve to it like some five fours threes twos ones and that's what's bringing the average down from fives and what you realize is that The one with the curve is sort of like, you know sort of mixed reviews, right?
Speaker 1: But the one with a big spike on five and a little bit of a little bump on the ones That's just like.
Speaker 1: well, it's a product in the real world.
Speaker 1: There's a small percent chance You're gonna get a broken one, you know, so I do the same thing with restaurants.
Speaker 0: if I look at like Yelp or Google Yeah if I see a restaurant that has a bunch of like low ratings and I Read them and if the complaints are all about the service and not the food I almost definitely go to that restaurant because the people who complain about the service usually are bad people.
Speaker 0: Yep, especially if you read the text and it's clear that they're just a bad person.
Speaker 0: Same thing with this.
Speaker 0: if I see a review of a hard drive and it's like one star head to RMA It's like okay, dude.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like one star head to RMA but it's like yeah any any product on Newegg or anywhere is gonna be.
Speaker 1: you know Probably, you know, no one's perfect right.
Speaker 1: even iPhones don't all show up 100% perfect.
Speaker 1: So people are buying, you know, the QA is not 100%.
Speaker 1: Someone's gonna buy an iPhone open it up.
Speaker 1: It's not gonna work.
Speaker 1: They're gonna have to return it and get everyone one star iPhone.
Speaker 1: That doesn't mean iPhones are bad, right?
Speaker 1: But some you know, so if that's the old of all the one-star reviews are RMA's then all the rest are five.
Speaker 1: That's a perfect product.
Speaker 1: say something with a curve though.
Speaker 1: Fours and threes and twos.
Speaker 1: that's people who have a working thing and found some other problem with it where they kept it.
Speaker 1: But they have a complaint about it and that to me is actually worse than a review that says had to return it.
Speaker 0: So the NAS is the non plus versions that are like 200 bucks cheaper.
Speaker 0: they were like that.
Speaker 0: They had a lot of middling reviews that were like, yeah, it works fine But like if I runs this kind of service on it, it's actually kind of slow turns out.
Speaker 0: It doesn't have as much RAM as the more expensive version like those kinds of things That led me toward getting the more expensive one because those are the kinds of things that I would complain about.
Speaker 1: And so this is how by using the reviews and the filters you can figure out what is the cheap option?
Speaker 1: That's like Wow inexpensive, but you get a lot for it Which one is the middling option where it's like that's the middle-of-the-road choice and which one is the bleeding edge.
Speaker 1: But it is the best.
Speaker 1: it just cost more money But I have money.
Speaker 0: and then the last thing I do is I try to narrow it down to like two case studies Like I could do it this way or this way.
Speaker 1: So like this NAS with this kind of drive this NAS with this kind of drive and imagine what your life is gonna be Like if you choose a or choose B and try to actually figure out like what's actually gonna be like when I use these.
Speaker 1: What's gonna be different for me in my life?
Speaker 1: What actual impact is it gonna have?
Speaker 1: Yeah is you know, okay Yeah, I'll buy the end.
Speaker 1: I think about are you gonna buy Nvidia 1080 or a 1070?
Speaker 1: It's like or a 1060?
Speaker 1: You think about it?
Speaker 1: All right, if I buy a 1060 what will my life be like?
Speaker 1: Well, you know what is gonna happen is I'm gonna buy some game on Steam like and it's it's gonna be a little slow Because you know the 1060 actually is quite significantly slower than the 1070 and a 1080 right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, that video I render is gonna take like quite a while longer to render like maybe even hours, right?
Speaker 1: I'm gonna lose time in my life for that 1060.
Speaker 1: Is it worth $100 to go to the 1070?
Speaker 1: It's like alright, I guess it is because that my life will be significantly better at 1070.
Speaker 1: There wasn't instant 1070 1080.
Speaker 0: It's like a lot more money.
Speaker 1: It is a lot more money and it is faster.
Speaker 1: But you know what that game that was slow in the 1060 is.
Speaker 1: it means like yeah the 1080 will get even more frames But the 1070 will still get enough frames, right?
Speaker 0: So they did like the 1080.
Speaker 1: I made this how much faster will my video render with a 1080 versus the 1070?
Speaker 1: faster?
Speaker 1: But how much faster?
Speaker 1: only 30 minutes faster not hours faster.
Speaker 1: All right, I can see where I should aim here.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and it comes down to once you narrow it down to like that level of granularity You're gonna make those tough calls like looking right here for hard drives for 90 bucks.
Speaker 0: I get four terabyte drives.
Speaker 0: Yeah, tough call.
Speaker 1: maybe even though I know the 1060 is gonna not be as good as the 70 to a significant degree It's just so much cheaper.
Speaker 1: That money is gonna make a difference in my life.
Speaker 1: What am I gonna spend that money on that?
Speaker 1: I'm saving.
Speaker 1: I'll have to pay that money that I'm saving.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna buy this other thing and that is I'm basically paying an hour of video and coding time to get something else.
Speaker 0: I'll do it.
Speaker 0: So with the NAS I Would have to pay more than double to double the space like to go from four terabyte drives to eight terabyte drives.
Speaker 0: It cost me more than double the money to do that.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: So what I imagined then was What is the pain?
Speaker 0: That I'm dealing with now?
Speaker 0: the pain of dealing with now is fucking NAS is full and I want to do complicated stuff.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm double the space Greatly reduces the chance.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna have to deal with the NAS is full in the next five years.
Speaker 0: Yep I mean I am willing to pay.
Speaker 1: how long have I had my NAS?
Speaker 1: It's never been.
Speaker 1: it was only it was only full when Windows backup rotation was failing.
Speaker 1: So I get a boat too many Windows backups Yeah, so I just deleted them all and now I haven't been out of space since.
Speaker 0: yeah But my NAS only has two terabytes of space in it.
Speaker 1: Oh my after redundant mine has I think four.
Speaker 1: is it four twos or four fours?
Speaker 0: That's two twos got about a long goddamn time ago.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so I looked at the space I'm using today and the panels and like I actually projected Storage requirements assuming that I do a full-on fucking backup pipeline.
Speaker 0: because my other biggest fear is I do not want to buy a NAS and still have Manual backups in different places.
Speaker 0: I want one ring to rule them all.
Speaker 0: So paying more than double to go from fair type of terabyte drives to a terabyte drives was worth it.
Speaker 0: I could not project a reasonable scenario where 10 or 12 terabyte drives would save me anything.
Speaker 0: They would just cost me a ton of money.
Speaker 0: Plus that NAS you can buy up to two Additional units that plug into it that can each hold five more drives.
Speaker 0: So I can upgrade it.
Speaker 0: So I could buy three years from now five twelve terabyte drives and shove them in there.
Speaker 1: Well, assuming they're still selling that attachment thing.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but QNAP seems okay about that.
Speaker 0: We'll see.
Speaker 0: I see a lot of reviews about people who've had these things longer not QNAP Synology.
Speaker 0: QNAP was the one that looked bad.
Speaker 1: So, yeah Synology does look better.
Speaker 1: you get the feeling from you know, that's one thing you had to do especially with Brands, it's sort of get a feel for like what you know, it's like brands don't mean nothing.
Speaker 1: It's like the brand itself is just a marketing logo symbol, whatever, right?
Speaker 1: But you get a feel for like.
Speaker 1: what is the company like?
Speaker 1: and I get a feel from Synology looking at their software.
Speaker 0: It's a bunch of open source Linux nerds working there Because basically their client base includes like offices and companies not just like me.
Speaker 0: Yeah in my house Yeah And.
Speaker 0: but then I went to like QNAP site and it didn't look as polished.
Speaker 0: So, of course that could be dangerous like don't go to aces website.
Speaker 0: You'll never fucking buy an aces thing again.
Speaker 1: That's right.
Speaker 0: So yeah, just know what know what you want to do first and everything else follows from there.
Speaker 0: And if you don't know what you want to do, don't do nothing.
Speaker 0: Don't buy anything.
Speaker 1: Don't buy stuff.
Speaker 1: just cuz you like buying stuff unless you mad rich.
Speaker 0: and if you're mad rich give me the money unless you want To buy episodes of geek nights.
Speaker 0: We are more than happy to make that happen.
Speaker 0: Yeah This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Speaker 1: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 0: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows Sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows It's actually recorded at night.
Speaker 0: and the patreon patreons for this episode of geek nights are Ellen Joyce, Heidi McNichol Amanda Duchette a shimmering ruby obelisk painting in the sky.
Speaker 0: mystati.com.
Speaker 0: Jeremy minor genuine bow to fight.
Speaker 0: Electrified six-car monorail.
Speaker 0: Shawn Yeager Matthew Smith Nicholas Brando captain Chinguakasi Rebecca Dunn for two one creations.
Speaker 0: No I never ever wonder why we're here.
Speaker 0: Semper Fi bitch Shervin von Horrell rare Lavell James David White Rochelle, Monta Nona Superboy rim says something funny here.
Speaker 0: Sailor Vista Don sh like chartovish and joshiro Joe stars Sam Cordray Clinton Walton Ren from New Zealand Ryan Perrin Drew open Lander Brian Cedroni Finn Chris midkiff Chris Knox Daniel Redmond Sean Klein Chris Reimer And Thomas Hahn.
Speaker 0: Scott definitely was sick and definitely got a bunch of our friends sick and is coughing constantly.
Speaker 0: But he insists that he is not sick.
Speaker 0: but anyway we're back and we'll be doing shows up until the holidays and all the nonsense that comes in January.
Speaker 0: and Now I leave you with.
Speaker 1: Well Seymour, I made it despite your directions.
Speaker 1: Ah superintendent Chalmers.
Speaker 1: Welcome.
Speaker 1: I hope you're prepared for an unforgettable luncheon.
Speaker 0: So he gods my roast is ruined.
Speaker 1: What if I were to purchase fast food and disguise it as my own cooking?
Speaker 1: Delightfully devilish Seymour Superintendent I was just Stretching my calves on the windows in isometric exercise.
Speaker 1: Can you join me?
Speaker 0: Why is there smoke coming out of your oven Seymour?
Speaker 1: No, it's steam steam from the steamed clams.
Speaker 1: we're having mmm.
Speaker 1: steamed clams Superintendent.
Speaker 1: I hope you're ready for mouth-watering hamburgers.
Speaker 0: I thought we were having steamed clams.
Speaker 1: No.
Speaker 1: No, I said steam.