Speaker 1: It's Tuesday August 1st 2017.
Speaker 1: I'm rim.
Speaker 1: I'm Scott, and this is geek nights tonight.
Speaker 1: We're reviewing Dream Daddy, oh baby.
Speaker 1: I dated some dads.
Speaker 0: I dated them days.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: What do you see?
Speaker 1: I see a book that I haven't finished yet.
Speaker 0: I I'm still got to read a couple of appendices But I've seen all there is to see.
Speaker 0: I'm at a point where I've seen holy consult.
Speaker 1: I've seen some go.
Speaker 0: I know all the secrets of the golden room and it's golden secret ways.
Speaker 0: There is nothing in the golden room that I don't know.
Speaker 0: There's still plenty of things that no one knows except the author, but that's how books do.
Speaker 1: I got some suspicions But I gotta wait and see In case no one knows how we're talking about.
Speaker 0: there's a series of fantasy novels called the prince of nothing.
Speaker 0: We've been reading these things for as long as geek nights has existed and the newest most epic revealing one came out an early July.
Speaker 0: I Finished it.
Speaker 0: Oh, no, it came out late July.
Speaker 0: I finished it in like a week.
Speaker 0: It came out.
Speaker 0: It was delayed from July 5th to like July 25th.
Speaker 0: So I read it.
Speaker 0: I got the Kindle edition.
Speaker 0: I finished it again Two days ago.
Speaker 1: the only reason I'm not done with it already.
Speaker 1: Is that my company?
Speaker 1: actually we moved offices to Midtown.
Speaker 1: I'm in the fashion district now like 38th Avenue or 38th Street and 7th Avenue.
Speaker 0: I'm kind of I am at 49th and 7th.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I don't want to go to the shnippers that is between both of us.
Speaker 1: I think we will at some point tomorrow not tomorrow.
Speaker 1: I got shit to do still next day.
Speaker 1: Well someday soon, but so my commute's real short.
Speaker 1: So I'm not reading as much and I was gonna just finish the book last night, but then I was playing dream daddy instead.
Speaker 1: Oh Someone brought the prince of nothing on the go thread into the new forum.
Speaker 0: good What what do you see?
Speaker 0: What do you see?
Speaker 1: I see MOG for our.
Speaker 0: I Definitely don't see God.
Speaker 0: I see no guy.
Speaker 0: a compass has brought a school About confess, he's not even and he's even mentioned in the newest book.
Speaker 1: I don't think he's mentioned once.
Speaker 0: that's wise.
Speaker 0: I mean, there's one thing I like about the series that this characters will be major characters in one book But they don't.
Speaker 0: they're not big enough to go to the next book.
Speaker 0: But at least my man's in him has got a mention.
Speaker 1: I was in him as he got the rusty treatment right there.
Speaker 0: So did his successor.
Speaker 0: the new marshal of a tramp has got a page or a couple paragraphs Yeah, like half a page who maybe also in route got mentions.
Speaker 0: in route got his name printed in the book more than once.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's more than not just and not counting the glossary where his Again, not idly to the leaves of DeLorean fall and such.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so, you know It's not like the greatest fantasy series ever written.
Speaker 0: It's not perfect.
Speaker 0: The author is known to be misogynist at times But we just love these books because they're so geek nights.
Speaker 0: Yeah, what they're?
Speaker 1: they're?
Speaker 1: they're all about what you see and What it is to be human and such.
Speaker 1: Yeah, what is the soul?
Speaker 1: It's the stuff.
Speaker 1: basically these books are everything We argued about.
Speaker 1: sitting around after D&D games late at night in college Coupled with the kind of crap we did in D&D games in college coupled with UM play God's sci-fi Coupled with oh my god magic was ours.
Speaker 0: Yeah goons and coupled with oh my god history nerd.
Speaker 0: It's actually the Crusades Yeah, but also coupled with horrific coupling.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's yeah, that's also in there.
Speaker 0: I guess this fits the North Star type action.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's that fits with fist of the normally not appropriate for eight-year-olds.
Speaker 0: No It might not even be appropriate for 80 year olds.
Speaker 1: These books are not appropriate for anyone.
Speaker 1: Well, yeah that that they've been.
Speaker 1: that's why the book club the new one is delayed NFL not safe for life.
Speaker 1: So it's Tuesday.
Speaker 1: So we have some gaming news before a lot of little gaming news.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so we'll start with this eSports.
Speaker 1: I know we've been talking about right stuff a lot because it's really happening big time now.
Speaker 0: It's like it's sort of like we're at the.
Speaker 0: we're at like the forefront here.
Speaker 0: So we're gonna just keep.
Speaker 0: you know Gonna keep our boat our surfboard on the crest of that wave as long as we can right cuz ever we don't even know.
Speaker 0: Say on the crest of waves there might be some other part of the wave that they stay on but the point is they like this is I'd like at the Part where the guy is hanging 10 right and is surfing super awesomely the perfect part.
Speaker 0: so I'm just so glad.
Speaker 1: for once we did our panel where we like said all these things that need to happen for eSports to get big and It's recorded and on YouTube with a date.
Speaker 0: We have a thousand thousand geek nights.
Speaker 0: episodes of the same thing happen.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, except what we don't have is we did that one panel.
Speaker 1: We only did it once.
Speaker 1: We didn't record it at like PAX Prime 2009 where we were like Nintendo should do this and Sega should do this and basically almost a look.
Speaker 1: We were like, why doesn't someone remake x-com?
Speaker 1: That would be good.
Speaker 1: And that it almost all of it happened anyway.
Speaker 0: So we talked a while ago about how the owner of the Mets piece of shit owner will upon bought some eSports team.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right But here we go The Madison Square Garden company owned by an even bigger piece of shit owner if that was possible.
Speaker 0: Dolan has bought some gaming team.
Speaker 0: I never heard of what the hell's their name computer counter logic gaming.
Speaker 0: I don't know who they are.
Speaker 1: It's more teams have the worst name.
Speaker 0: Yeah but it's.
Speaker 0: what's really awesome is like they put this video and it's like you got like the Knicks and the Rangers like Retweeting this video and it puts.
Speaker 0: it's like Madison Square Garden company Rangers Knicks Liberty, which is W NBA team.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and then counter logic gaming up for logos all equally sized horizontally arranged three of these team on the same level as New York Knicks of players who get paid millions of dollars every year.
Speaker 1: However, three of these logos look appropriate and One of them just does not look like it.
Speaker 0: I think they need some new branding because like I have a hard time caring about them with their branding I also think that they play MOBAs, which I don't care about But but they're not be under their logo.
Speaker 0: cuz even playing even playing MOBAs, right if they are playing those MOBAs in Madison Square Garden and They change their branding to make me care about them because they're more they would be more New York.
Speaker 1: It was something New York II like the New York subway.
Speaker 0: They were the least bit New York II even playing League of Legends, which I never played in my life.
Speaker 0: I played dota though.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if they played that in Madison Square Garden and the season tickets are cheap enough I would still go yeah and cheer for them if they just change everything in brand.
Speaker 0: cuz I don't care about Counter logic gaming.
Speaker 1: I mean I went and saw the Knicks a few times and I really don't like basketball.
Speaker 1: I really don't like basketball But I had a pretty good time Being at those Knicks games partly because I could sit like right on the court.
Speaker 1: cuz no one goes to Knicks games.
Speaker 0: going to sports Is really we.
Speaker 0: I mean we went to RIT hockey before we cared about them and then we cared about them.
Speaker 0: That's how that's how it works.
Speaker 0: you go and then you care more.
Speaker 0: It's a chicken and egg situation.
Speaker 0: You don't go.
Speaker 0: Oh when I care about that, I would go if I cared more.
Speaker 0: It's like you're never gonna care though But if you go to one then suddenly you're gonna start caring and that's how you get hooked.
Speaker 0: It's tricky though Like if I got a candy and you never ate candy in your life You're gonna be like I don't need to eat.
Speaker 0: that is bad for you and then you eat one candy.
Speaker 0: I guess the problem is I Like I can tell a candy when I seen it.
Speaker 0: I got experience of living a long time.
Speaker 1: I know I'm glad that we went to that game of footy But I don't think I'd go to more games of footy.
Speaker 0: would I go to more games of footy.
Speaker 0: That's a good I think.
Speaker 0: if I lived in Australia, I don't think I would go to season tickets of footy But I would go I would.
Speaker 0: it would be more like baseball where I go to like one footy a year
Speaker 1: like if we go to packs Australia this year and there's a footy game and I happen to be in Melbourne and
Speaker 0: And if I lived in Australia and like it was a thing I would probably be watching like, you know, the championship and the playoffs like on TV.
Speaker 1: I wouldn't.
Speaker 1: I've watched cricket.
Speaker 1: I would never watch cricket again.
Speaker 1: I can't could not care.
Speaker 0: cricket is weird because I love everything about it.
Speaker 0: The professional cricket right they do the the test matches that last for fucking ever.
Speaker 0: Yep, right But I actually would go.
Speaker 0: I can go to Queens.
Speaker 0: I can just bike out there to where like the amateur just people are playing for fun on the weekend and that's actually way fun.
Speaker 0: It's because they're so into it especially if you.
Speaker 0: just what you got to do is you can't just watch because the way cricket works is you send out two batters and The rest of the team is just like Except for the defense team is on is all over the place, right?
Speaker 0: You just hang out with the batting team Which is only only has two people out there and they're chillin and eatin and talking and they're so happy that you care about their game And are actually paying attention to them and they're ready to talk your ear off about how great cricket is and explain what's going on.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's a good time.
Speaker 1: Actually, I'm gonna watch cricket.
Speaker 0: I almost would rather watch the Trobriand Islanders playing great But the way they play cricket in out at the park is they don't play the infinite test match.
Speaker 0: They play a set number of you know runs or whatever or whatever it's called.
Speaker 0: So it's like there's a limited time to how long the thing is gonna get.
Speaker 1: and also like I know Emily be mad at me But I can't watch soccer and I just don't want to go to a soccer My hooligans and to.
Speaker 1: that is so boring.
Speaker 0: if soccer would a shrink the field and Be become more objective then I would I would like it.
Speaker 0: I would be like summer hockey, basically Only on grass, but those two things they did not fix.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so it is boring as hell, but I can't When there's an incredible soccer thing on you Internet.
Speaker 1: the gist of this news is that if you're not paying attention Esports all the real money people are coming into the eSports industry like right now.
Speaker 1: This is the like behind the scenes build-up because if public it's not even behind the scenes.
Speaker 0: This is in front of the scenes.
Speaker 0: Part already happened.
Speaker 1: So this is that there's some of this is appearing in front of the scenes.
Speaker 1: Usually when that happens, it's because there is a ton more going on behind the scenes.
Speaker 0: Oh, there's a huge avalanche.
Speaker 1: This is just what's bubbling out of the top.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah I mean Wall Street dudes.
Speaker 1: I've stood because they know that I do this stuff.
Speaker 1: because like LinkedIn profile and like something fine geek nights When I'm in like London or Singapore, whatever people ask me like so, how do I invest in eSports?
Speaker 0: They know you can't invent sports traditionally have been hard to invest in.
Speaker 1: you have to buy a team and eSports You have to buy a team in most cases, but you could like invest in blizzard Like I actually buy like NFL stock.
Speaker 0: Otherwise, I totally wouldn't something actually maybe not but technically have stock You can buy for like a fan.
Speaker 1: Like I own one share.
Speaker 0: That's the Green Bay Packers.
Speaker 0: That's the only one the only one but I bought only.
Speaker 0: that's the actually the team with the best ownership on earth.
Speaker 1: This is not investment advice.
Speaker 1: I'm not an investment advisor nor my lawyer But I bought a bunch of Blizzard stock a while ago and I can be an Activision stuff.
Speaker 1: Activision Blizzard ATVI I think is the ticker.
Speaker 0: Yes, because I But activisions non blizzard stuff is really falling though I know and their blizzard stuff is really taking up.
Speaker 1: exactly if they if they I'm hoping that someday They will cleave all that like all the cruft from that company.
Speaker 0: and just hey boss Why would they buy Blizzard that to then have?
Speaker 0: Their main part?
Speaker 0: I'll be like if we bought some other podcast and then that podcaster plays the ignites and geek nights went away.
Speaker 0: Yeah That happens more often than you'd think in corporate M&A Like that is you buy a thing and then that thing is better than the thing that bought it.
Speaker 0: It's you.
Speaker 1: it's like you try to eat this little guy and then he turns around.
Speaker 1: just eat you right back.
Speaker 1: And what do you do?
Speaker 1: Usually that'll happen if the other you still own it technically.
Speaker 0: see what do you care?
Speaker 0: But it's still weird.
Speaker 1: I feel like it usually happens when the buying party is a big old company with tons of money.
Speaker 1: That's shitty and not doing well and it buys a smaller better run company.
Speaker 1: and the smaller better run company It does better than it because it's actually a dying giant but it now has been money invested into it so we can do things Like it hasn't?
Speaker 1: it has old money and it buys a young money team and the young money team They're young money thing then turns into the real money and the old money thing just dies Like it's this cancerous corpse of a company.
Speaker 0: Activision is I mean blizzard is from the early 90s.
Speaker 0: Activision is from is only maybe 10 years older because Activision had Atari games.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like pitfall Activision was like blizzard.
Speaker 0: blizzard started blizzard started with PC games.
Speaker 1: I want to say like Activision is just this really long and they're both pretty.
Speaker 0: they're both downward spiral.
Speaker 0: They're both pretty old is the point.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but I got faith in them.
Speaker 1: So pay attention to this stuff.
Speaker 1: and There's.
Speaker 1: there are career opportunities in this space as well.
Speaker 0: That's what I'm looking for.
Speaker 0: Think about how many people work like a Rangers hockey game.
Speaker 1: How many people work for that team?
Speaker 0: Well aren't players?
Speaker 0: a lot a lot of those people work for the Mass Square Garden company, and they won't need new hires.
Speaker 0: They're not gonna need new ticket salespeople or new ushers.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right.
Speaker 1: They're not gonna tell me sports leagues and teams will need all that stuff, but they are gonna need I know other things equipment managers coaches Trainers like there's going to be an industry here.
Speaker 1: They're going to be people who go to school graduate with a degree in like sports medicine and are literally the trainer like Massaging the players hands and like keeping an eye on their tendonitis.
Speaker 0: It's not the job for me.
Speaker 0: but if you look at like the job postings of your local sport company like on their websites like in our case Madison Square Garden corporation or Sterling Mets whatever.
Speaker 0: Yeah, all right just look at the job postings on those company sites and look for ones that mention the eSport part and there might be a Future for you.
Speaker 0: It is not does not involve some boring ass corporate desk.
Speaker 1: Yeah Like think someone has to like.
Speaker 1: set up the PCs for the tournament.
Speaker 0: and even if you start with a low ass You know, that's a low paying part-time job like guy who sets up the PCs.
Speaker 0: But you know what?
Speaker 0: That's an entry position and you're getting in at the very beginning.
Speaker 0: Yeah, stick with it for a long as time.
Speaker 0: look at like really like 10 years from now You'll be running to shit.
Speaker 1: look at what?
Speaker 0: Manager like the general manager of a team which is like a job that pays millions of dollars a year.
Speaker 1: It's like in the military.
Speaker 1: It's the non-commissioned officer track like trades with this is you could be trading players.
Speaker 0: Let me talking about you on sports radio.
Speaker 1: But look what a team like that jet like the equipment manager retires and they'll always be like come on out on the eyes.
Speaker 1: You've been our equipment manager for 30 years.
Speaker 0: You're here.
Speaker 1: You could be that person.
Speaker 0: Yep So in some other news, let's do these news is quick.
Speaker 0: Yeah So that was the big news.
Speaker 1: there is a new hearthstone car.
Speaker 0: Well, the hearthstone expansions coming real soon and that what they do is they always give Individual cards to different like media outlets including streamers websites, etc.
Speaker 0: And they all reveal one card each.
Speaker 0: because there's plenty of cars to go around.
Speaker 0: There's like hundreds of them in different countries - they at least dole them out.
Speaker 0: So the one I forget who revealed this one, but it's a Kotaku revealed as far as I'm concerned Kotaku anyway, it's an insane card.
Speaker 0: you play it and it takes a copy of your opponent's deck and Shuffles it into your deck.
Speaker 0: They've had things like this before but this is they've like.
Speaker 1: this is a new frontier in the pre digital era like even if you came up with like cleverness in a collectible or Non-collectible card game was limited by the physical reality of the card.
Speaker 0: I can't just Oh take a copy of some dudes magic deck, you know Go into a box get a full set of cards exact and then see what's in his deck with my eye or even stuff like.
Speaker 0: Think about that.
Speaker 0: you get a copy of your opponent's deck you shuffle it into yours But you don't even know what's in there and you start drawing cards.
Speaker 0: and now when you draw a card You know that that was in his deck at the time that you copied it.
Speaker 0: Oh, it's just so much going on there.
Speaker 1: so the fat.
Speaker 0: when Blizzard went digital feeling at the information and the.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's okay.
Speaker 0: They basically.
Speaker 0: this is why I keep playing this game, even though it's a random bullshit money game.
Speaker 1: There's an ocean of amazing crazy things.
Speaker 1: they can do with the fact that it's digital while still maintaining the the simplicity of the card can see.
Speaker 1: But although up to this point, they've basically dipped their toes into that ocean They've been like poke and poke In the more and this in the in the expansion that just came out recently.
Speaker 0: They've done a few things like yeah cards that give plus ones and stuff to cards that are in your hand.
Speaker 0: That would be impossible with physical cards, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, and they've also done a lot of that's waiting.
Speaker 1: They still waited in a little bit.
Speaker 0: They've done a lot of stuff.
Speaker 0: Like oh if your deck contains no duplicates or Like all these things that you couldn't possibly or very very difficultly do with physical cards.
Speaker 0: But this is just.
Speaker 1: this is a guy in a catapult catapulted into the middle of the ocean.
Speaker 0: This is ridonkulous.
Speaker 0: I don't think it's like.
Speaker 0: can you really go further than this?
Speaker 0: How could you top this?
Speaker 1: I think this is just the beginning.
Speaker 1: I think there's gonna be a. I think there'll be an era of craziness at some point Mmm, so in some other news tiny tiny news, but GameStop is obviously a worthless company.
Speaker 1: It exists basically solely to Prey on kids too young to have credit cards.
Speaker 0: People who refuse to use Amazon.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like GameStop sir, even even buying video games Even Best Buy is better than games.
Speaker 1: Yeah Maybe Walmart's cheaper than GameStop and Walmart maybe sell you a pre-order and then not have.
Speaker 0: I mean There's the worst places in GameStop, but listen.
Speaker 1: Well, yeah, like by the worst place in GameStop is the guy in the alley behind game, right?
Speaker 0: But we are not paid by Amazon in any way.
Speaker 0: we honestly just use Amazon for everything because what Amazon does as a business is They screw over people who sell stuff in order to profit for themselves and to benefit customers.
Speaker 0: And since we are all customers, you know using Amazon is to our advantage.
Speaker 0: It's very important cheap.
Speaker 0: I don't.
Speaker 1: I would not care if things like Amazon were more expensive.
Speaker 1: I'd still use them because I just don't want to go shopping.
Speaker 0: The point is GameStop sucks.
Speaker 0: Don't go there.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so GameStop doubled down on being terrible and they announced I don't know if they've personally done this before but they announced this early.
Speaker 1: It's August and they already announced that for Thanksgiving.
Speaker 1: They're staying open.
Speaker 0: So all kinds of places are staying open in Thanksgiving.
Speaker 0: That's not new.
Speaker 0: I'm surprised they weren't open on Thanksgiving previously On Thanksgiving game because I feel like their customer base is almost exclusively 13-year-olds don't have credit cards, you know what the you know what the problem is.
Speaker 0: Here's why they got to be open on Thanksgiving because you know who's open on Thanksgiving.
Speaker 0: Walmart steam-powered.com is open Thanksgiving with a big ol fucking sale every goddamn year and GameStop is sitting there closed at that same exact moment.
Speaker 0: Yeah This is why GameStop.
Speaker 1: that is true because the other Demographic at GameStop other than 13 year olds.
Speaker 0: Are you gonna not buy games on Steam because they're open on Thanksgiving?
Speaker 1: are The PR grandma who wants to buy a video game present For Christmas and she buys it on the way to the Thanksgiving dinner at the Super Sale.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm, and she doesn't realize that Your grandma can buy you a steam gift card with her phone.
Speaker 0: you have the best grandma.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so I weirdly Deeply enjoy watching large conventions fail which puts extra pressure when we start our convention to not fuck it up.
Speaker 0: But gonna be so small we can't fuck it up if we mess it up like there.
Speaker 1: I have dug this grave for myself, but it happened yet again, and there's a moral here.
Speaker 1: Apparently there's a gamer cruise that was gonna be like like a PAX cruise or a joko cruise But it's gonna be like gaming.
Speaker 0: who ran it?
Speaker 1: the video gamer gauntlet.
Speaker 0: I never heard of them.
Speaker 0: So basically, where was the cruise going to and from who even cares?
Speaker 0: because the none of that's interesting could have been a cold cruise versus a Nice, you know Royal Caribbean.
Speaker 1: It was gonna be a big cruise ship.
Speaker 0: Well that they're only getting a part of it though Yeah, they're not the whole boat.
Speaker 1: But the story is they got a bunch of sponsors to make this happen.
Speaker 1: Some of the sponsors pulled out because they're not well organized I guess yeah, and because some of the sponsors pulled out.
Speaker 1: the cruise line was like yo, you don't have enough credit So you need more sponsors.
Speaker 1: I got a pony up money.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: Other sponsors were like, whoa, whoa.
Speaker 0: Why do those sponsors pull out?
Speaker 0: Why would I pull in?
Speaker 0: Yep So the moral here is this is a good deal.
Speaker 0: Why did those be?
Speaker 1: the reason I bring this news up is because there's a pattern here with all these Big nerd events that are starting to pop up and fail.
Speaker 1: The problem is a lot of companies or people who have some money or some investment ties go to a nerd convention like packs or S DCC or something and they see it and they go.
Speaker 0: some assholes go to a convention and they see it.
Speaker 0: They go.
Speaker 0: I could do this I could do this, but then I know like that.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, but here's the difference.
Speaker 1: Here's the difference.
Speaker 1: They try to start that big.
Speaker 0: They start cruises are not big.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but this Anyone can organize one of these crews already.
Speaker 0: So this one start crews events are actually some of the easiest to organize.
Speaker 1: It depends.
Speaker 1: so there's a lot of ways.
Speaker 1: there's like four or five different structures to those kinds of events But they started at the level of.
Speaker 1: you need multiple big-money sponsors for the event to even occur.
Speaker 1: That's already too big for a first convention.
Speaker 1: Yep You're we're starting on the level of.
Speaker 1: we're personally funding the entire first event.
Speaker 1: That is the level you start at.
Speaker 1: we're shooting for like a hundred people a one room.
Speaker 0: Yeah one room maybe Two rooms ready to room.
Speaker 0: daddy to room is.
Speaker 0: the second room.
Speaker 0: is the?
Speaker 0: is the storage room for our stuff?
Speaker 1: Yeah, and maybe the panel room for coat check is before.
Speaker 0: second room is the coat check?
Speaker 1: Yeah, if we have a panel track, there will be one track.
Speaker 1: Here are the panels.
Speaker 1: There's six of them Like that's.
Speaker 0: that's there in the same room as the other stuff.
Speaker 1: Yeah on a stage So there's a game called pub G. You might have seen player unknown battlegrounds.
Speaker 1: I really want to play it.
Speaker 0: I'm thinking about playing it, but it's too much money and it's whatever.
Speaker 0: but it's basically it's battle royale But the rules are slightly different.
Speaker 0: basically.
Speaker 1: instead in battle royale if you ever seen the movie, which you should Yeah, and do not read the comic it is vile Maybe and I say that having read a bunch of the last book of The Prince of Nothing Maybe you should be.
Speaker 0: I haven't read the book.
Speaker 0: the original Battle royale was actually a book the battle royale might I haven't read it might be good Battle royale manga is vile to the point that I stopped reading it after two volume.
Speaker 0: But anyway, the movie is good.
Speaker 0: So in the movie the way it works is you're there on the island and there's all these rules with the neck things and whatever It's like you have you can't be in certain zones at certain times.
Speaker 0: the way pub G What are games is there's a big circle.
Speaker 0: they get smaller and smaller and smaller aiming at a certain point.
Speaker 0: so basically even though the game is long you're forced to get closer and closer to everyone over time and Eventually, there's one person left at the end who wins right.
Speaker 1: so and now most people who I trust talk about this game.
Speaker 1: They always say oh, it's bad.
Speaker 1: Here's all the problems.
Speaker 0: But then they also I hear good things.
Speaker 1: But then they also say that they have a lot of fun playing it and they just keep playing it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I mean it's too much money right now for me to play.
Speaker 0: when I've got all these other games.
Speaker 1: I could buy it for you with the patreon money, but then we'd have to do shows.
Speaker 0: How much am I gonna play it though using waste that throw that money away?
Speaker 1: Well, what we'd have to do is like live stream it a bunch and then like do it.
Speaker 0: I'm not gonna play it enough to be worth paying.
Speaker 0: But anyway, there's a controversy now because the game is early access and they're starting to sell some loot crates with you know cosmetic loot in them for 250 right whatever I don't care about as long as they're only selling cosmetic stuff.
Speaker 0: that never bothers me because I just don't buy it Right.
Speaker 0: I only take free stuff or and but if it's paid away, it's not pay to win, right?
Speaker 0: Everyone's still on equal footing.
Speaker 0: So it's fine by me.
Speaker 0: I don't give a shit.
Speaker 0: if I played it I would just never buy a single loot crate ever.
Speaker 0: But people are real upset because they promised maybe that they wouldn't sell loot crates till they were officially released.
Speaker 0: But they're not yet.
Speaker 0: So there's something loot.
Speaker 0: and there was another game that did this.
Speaker 0: was that our survival evolved that was sold a whole DLC before it.
Speaker 0: Well, it's still early access.
Speaker 0: Yo, and here's the thing people and this.
Speaker 0: I've said this long line This this beta early access stuff is just like this completely arbitrary distinction.
Speaker 0: Right games don't get released and be done anymore If the game is either ready for the public to play it or not, right?
Speaker 0: It's like you might put some label on it to say oh it still has bugs.
Speaker 0: Oh, we're still working on it.
Speaker 0: But if people are playing it and having fun, it's fucking released.
Speaker 1: It's like dark.
Speaker 1: That's one of the problems with a video ball, which should have been great.
Speaker 1: Is that I think they spent they waited too long?
Speaker 0: Well, I think the thing is it's it's fine to wait too long.
Speaker 0: That's what half-life 1 did.
Speaker 0: right is like we're gonna just work on this forever until it's perfect.
Speaker 0: And then they released it all at once.
Speaker 0: right, you know, but you basically didn't see much of it until it was released.
Speaker 0: Right, but I mean I completely ignore whether a game pretty much like the only thing I look at when a game is early access Is.
Speaker 0: I'm nicely seeing how done the game is right because sometimes because it's okay to release a game That's not a hundred percent done as long as it's playable, but some people are putting games out that are like there's nothing there.
Speaker 0: It's literally like you can jump and it's a platform or you can jump and there's no bad guys or nothing.
Speaker 0: yet And they're like early access.
Speaker 0: It's like what?
Speaker 0: But I mean these games are at a point to where like the game is there.
Speaker 0: Tons and tons of people are playing this thing.
Speaker 0: It's a game.
Speaker 0: It's a real game.
Speaker 0: who cares if they call it early access because they're still doing stuff, right?
Speaker 0: They just put on an update that added like vehicle horns.
Speaker 0: It's like such a minor changes going on.
Speaker 0: Now you're telling me this game is not released.
Speaker 0: Seriously, it's like we got to start ignoring these labels.
Speaker 0: right at the same time.
Speaker 1: the players who are mad about this Just don't buy the cosmetic nonsense.
Speaker 0: Don't be a person who cares about cosmetic nonsense and never buy.
Speaker 0: if no one bought any cosmetic nonsense game Developers wouldn't be selling it because they would.
Speaker 0: no one would buy it because they'd go.
Speaker 0: Oh, why would I pay for that?
Speaker 0: That's literally nothing.
Speaker 0: Why am I giving you money for bits?
Speaker 1: That's stupid as people still whenever I play overwatch and I live stream it people increasingly get mad at me.
Speaker 1: I have a hundred and seven unopened loot crates.
Speaker 0: You should just go for a thousand And that you should never open those loot crates.
Speaker 1: I'm getting faster now because I'm actually playing the arcade mode So I get like a bunch of extra ones.
Speaker 1: Oh the arcade mode.
Speaker 1: They have a really good mode now like our like it's.
Speaker 1: it is so great.
Speaker 1: It's 6v6 and it's just deathmatch.
Speaker 1: You don't respawn and you play its best of like whoever wins.
Speaker 0: so counter-strike without bombs whoever wins three.
Speaker 1: But the rule is if you win around any characters that anyone on your team picked for that round You cannot use for the rest of the game.
Speaker 0: So if if we win round one and I chose That gamer girl with the robot.
Speaker 1: Yeah, then no one can be the gamer girl the robot for the rest of nobody No one on your team.
Speaker 0: No one on the whole team.
Speaker 0: Not just me.
Speaker 0: Yeah, what I'm a whole team.
Speaker 0: So there's only you run out of characters.
Speaker 1: yeah, so usually you'll see like one team wins two in a row and then they're kind of bad at the remaining characters and then They get steamrolled like stuff like that.
Speaker 1: Other team is gonna have to choose shitty characters in their round three or a team might mess up and pick two healers twice and I think I know healers for the last round.
Speaker 1: Like you can really mess yourself up.
Speaker 1: It's way fun like way fun.
Speaker 1: And the rose good mode, they're really short too good.
Speaker 1: So I can like play three rounds of it in like ten minutes and then just be done.
Speaker 0: I afraid I appreciate this mode.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's a good mode.
Speaker 1: and last and this could almost be a whole episode But we'll see where that.
Speaker 0: basically it's similar to the previous news, which is why I wanted to bring it up Bad.
Speaker 0: so you're bad in in the Zelda game for the switch, right?
Speaker 0: They had this thing where if you got amiibos You could hook them up and you would get like treasure chest falling out of the sky with stuff in them and some of the Stuff was exclusive stuff, but it was cosmetic stuff like Nintendo switch t-shirt.
Speaker 0: It's like who cares if you can wear a Nintendo switch t-shirt.
Speaker 0: I don't like.
Speaker 1: you can write a photo for a while like, okay You can get the actual Epona and not just some other horses, but it's like she's not as good as calamitous my giant Ganon steed.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you mean?
Speaker 0: The horse the demon horse.
Speaker 0: anyway the fist King rides.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but now there's some Metroid games coming for the old DS, right?
Speaker 0: There's that remake of Metroid to come for the DS.
Speaker 0: Yep, and you can hook some amiibos up to it.
Speaker 0: It's specifically and it's not just any amiibos and specifically these Metroid amiibos But that new me amiibo the one with the Metroid on the broken canister.
Speaker 0: if you get that amiibo It's specifically unlocks like hard mode and there's like actual game content is locked behind this amiibo.
Speaker 0: now It's like I could probably find someone who has the amiibo and like wave it near my DS and be good to go but or I would just do the pirate how much the fucking amiibos cost I. And also it's sort of like stealth deal like you're really charged like it's like it's like.
Speaker 0: on the one hand you can say All right, you sell a DLC and you get a free statue.
Speaker 0: Now you can think of it that way.
Speaker 0: it's like oh here's a deal.
Speaker 0: this game has a DLC.
Speaker 1: It feels dirty to sell a physical piece of plastic and then say oh you need this to play the full game.
Speaker 0: Well, it feels a little less dirty because you one person buys the piece of plastic and waves at night.
Speaker 0: Everyone's DS.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so you don't actually need to pay for it for everybody Right, but it's like this is still like.
Speaker 0: am I really gonna be able to find someone who has this fucking amiibo, right?
Speaker 0: I still have never waved even one amiibo near any of my Nintendo console.
Speaker 1: But also I've read if I.
Speaker 0: the thing is if I get that Metroid game, which I will I really want that mode.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I want that I pay I want that and I don't want to buy that amiibo.
Speaker 0: I think there's a useless piece of plastic.
Speaker 1: There's a wider problem that the amiibos Themselves sort of had a bubble and I feel like there's amiibo fatigue.
Speaker 1: is the problem.
Speaker 1: is people who collected them early really like them For their physical people who are nuts on collecting all the amiibos?
Speaker 0: Yeah, but now I think they're gonna run out of space.
Speaker 0: the Nintendo store had a big ol amiibo section.
Speaker 0: Everyone is into the amiibos.
Speaker 1: I'm just waiting for the amiibo bubble to crash.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'm not an amiibo fan But anyway things of the day.
Speaker 1: What do you got for me?
Speaker 0: Oh, so I you know We always talk about apparently we mispronounced his name wrong Neil Ciciriga the one of the creators of all great internet things.
Speaker 0: Right, you know, he's made some videos like that.
Speaker 0: You may have seen like what was that one in the arcade?
Speaker 0: They did the long one.
Speaker 1: Oh, well, there's friend or foe.
Speaker 0: friend or foe is the one of the shorter one But if you don't know he is done like pop puppet pop Potter puppet pals.
Speaker 1: That was him.
Speaker 1: Yeah So many internet things like it boggles the mind.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so he's got a new patreon with his friends here that he does videos with called guaranteed video and they have been guaranteeing videos and those videos have appeared.
Speaker 0: and the newest video is Everybody's pants now And I unironically fucking love that song and I had the original album on Came out and I love CNC music factory is my jam.
Speaker 0: I figure they're like one step under Captain Jack in the same musical category.
Speaker 1: Oh, it's Captain Jack.
Speaker 1: Oh my god I can't believe it.
Speaker 1: I love CNC music factory.
Speaker 0: They're great and They took that song and they changed the lyric to everybody's pants now and they made this great video And it is more than thing of the day worthy.
Speaker 0: you should patreon Guaranteed video so that you will be guaranteed video.
Speaker 1: I was guaranteed this video and I'm glad that I funded the creation of this video Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: So someone tweeted this and it's just four strips.
Speaker 1: It's from.
Speaker 1: you know, there's a lot of manga.
Speaker 0: obviously There is more manga than you can read in your life.
Speaker 0: accept it now.
Speaker 1: But this one in particular doesn't look like this has ever been translated except some fan translations And it looks like it's just this really funny for kill me about link being kind of excitable and dumb and it's Really really really cute and way funnier than I expected it to be.
Speaker 0: and I'm kind of really in AIDS.
Speaker 0: Wind Waker link, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, it looks like it cuz there's the bird girl.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, there's the boat.
Speaker 1: Yep Danger don't disturb the bomb plant, but he's already disturbed it.
Speaker 1: Yep This is just really cute and funny and I highly recommend you find this wherever.
Speaker 0: There are lots of four commas that are You know out there and they're rarely Translated in the meta moment.
Speaker 1: the book club book will very soon be the fifth season.
Speaker 0: Yep By NK jemisin.
Speaker 0: not spring not winter not summer not fall.
Speaker 0: It's March.
Speaker 0: It's a fifth season.
Speaker 0: Read this fantasy novel.
Speaker 0: It's like the hotness.
Speaker 0: I'm probably gonna start it once I'm in a reading mood again because I just finished reading some.
Speaker 0: so I'll take a break.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna play some games and then I'm gonna read again after seeing.
Speaker 1: what do you see?
Speaker 1: And now you've seen it.
Speaker 0: I seen.
Speaker 1: I want to see what I see in the fifth element now.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I need you to seize that we can talk.
Speaker 0: tell each other what we seen.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna burn I'm gonna.
Speaker 0: maybe maybe you've seen something.
Speaker 0: I haven't seen.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna see as soon as I can cuz I'm feeling it.
Speaker 1: I I particularly appreciated that the korai horde not only came back but was used to very Excellent effect.
Speaker 0: Uh, you're not done with that korai horde.
Speaker 1: Well, the korai horde was used and then recovered to be used again.
Speaker 1: You're not done with that and I'm sure there is yet a third usage of it.
Speaker 1: That korai horde is already doing some good biz.
Speaker 1: The fact that it the fact that's the car.
Speaker 0: Let's actually get home with the show.
Speaker 0: Okay, so much prison nothing action.
Speaker 1: So there's this game called dream daddy a dating simulator.
Speaker 0: And so this game was.
Speaker 0: I actually only saw the announcement for it like recently like weeks months
Speaker 1: Came out a couple weeks ago
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean anyway, then it was well There was a little drama because they're like, oh we had to delay the release and like a couple weeks later It was released and it was like people got mad upset.
Speaker 0: I don't I'm like people do not announce release dates for anything.
Speaker 0: Just let's say when it's done it's done and then put it out.
Speaker 1: and mostly I don't understand the people who get mad when a release Date changes.
Speaker 0: Yeah Just I would never put out a release date for anything that I do ever.
Speaker 0: I would just say I'm making this thing get hype.
Speaker 0: It's gonna come out when it's ready and then it'll be ready one day and I'll just release it surprise and people go Oh shit, and that's how I would do.
Speaker 0: And then you don't have to worry about delaying things cuz no one fucking knows.
Speaker 1: now This is on my radar for a while because obviously with pillified and like goes to Miami, you know I like.
Speaker 1: I have a I'm very invested in visual novel scene.
Speaker 0: This is a visual now.
Speaker 1: So I play a lot of visual novels for research.
Speaker 1: This one was all over my feed to the point that it felt like this omnipresent game Those are going to consume all right.
Speaker 0: So this is it.
Speaker 1: when I live-streamed it last night Almost everyone watching had never heard of it.
Speaker 1: What they were all like, what is this game?
Speaker 0: Do you read internet?
Speaker 1: Yeah, you're talk to an old person.
Speaker 0: read internet all day every day.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so this is a visual novel in which you date dads.
Speaker 1: like it.
Speaker 0: literally it does not have.
Speaker 0: you are a dad.
Speaker 0: It's the visual novel.
Speaker 0: choose on adventure style not the Tokimeki simulation style.
Speaker 1: that I think is more fun But anyway, it's closer to that though than a lot of other visual now.
Speaker 1: It has some it's It pretends to have some yeah But anyway, but it doesn't both the.
Speaker 1: the cleverness is.
Speaker 1: a lot of the greatest visual novels Appear to have a lot more going on in the back end than they actually do, correct?
Speaker 1: But it doesn't matter because if you feel like it's there it's there.
Speaker 0: as far as games are concerned The story is you're dead a single dead and you move into this town, right?
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah I think you already live in the town.
Speaker 0: you're moving across town.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you're moving.
Speaker 0: you're like you're moving.
Speaker 0: your point is you're moving to the cul-de-sac of dads.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like the dad Your daughter who is about to graduate high school It's her senior year of high school You move to a new house at a new cul-de-sac and every house in the cul-de-sac has a hot dad with or without children living in it.
Speaker 0: and You got a deal with your daughter and Because you know your your spouse is no more Maybe you'll hit on some of these dads.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: So I accidentally had sex with Robert like right away Like I wonder if there are any nice either town.
Speaker 0: There's there's these seven dads.
Speaker 0: They show you that are like the seven dads on down.
Speaker 1: You think there's like an eighth day.
Speaker 0: Is there a secret eighth dad?
Speaker 0: Because I didn't put a lot of effort in trying to unlock anything or do any good Play through once.
Speaker 1: just I wanted like.
Speaker 0: I just played through real fast straight through.
Speaker 1: I thought a lot of my design made my dad avatar and You may look like you.
Speaker 1: it looks exactly like me except I put the mustache back cuz it's dead.
Speaker 1: Mine looks a little like me cuz two people in the chat were like the default avatar looks exactly like Scott.
Speaker 0: Yeah The thing is you can really make the.
Speaker 0: the dad maker was like.
Speaker 0: it's almost like that in itself.
Speaker 0: Remember that MMO with the superheroes where you could really go nuts?
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, it's like the dad maker is pretty.
Speaker 1: it's not quite me level But it's pretty like I clicked around and like a few minutes later I had a perfect rim.
Speaker 0: you can make a lot of good dads with the dad.
Speaker 0: Did you see someone made dad maker alone is worth buying this game.
Speaker 1: right after the game came out This hit my Twitter feed like eight different ways.
Speaker 0: Someone made Roger Klotz and made I don't know who Roger Klotz from Doug.
Speaker 0: Oh with the orange the green face in the orange hair Klotz.
Speaker 1: That guy yeah made him perfect except he's not green cuz I can't make sure he's like perfect like almost too perfect.
Speaker 0: Yeah, why not?
Speaker 1: But the beauty of this game is just that.
Speaker 1: it's called dream daddy a dad dating simulator And you both are a dad and date dads because that that would be the question.
Speaker 1: So am I a dad trying to date or am I trying to date dads?
Speaker 1: It's both
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm,
Speaker 1: and I really liked it and it actually did a lot of clever things that I haven't seen in a lot of visual novels
Speaker 0: Yeah, so first of all, like the plot that involves the daughter is actually kind of like a decent plot Like, you know you learn, you know.
Speaker 0: And it's like even though I'm not a parent and have no plans to be.
Speaker 0: You can feel this frustration in these like just these multiple choice dialogue options right now of between being like the Overprotective parent or being the not enough parent right and it's like oh this is that and you can you know It's like whoever wrote this did a good job and there's like a little bit of voice acting that did a good job All you know, there's like oh, yeah It's like, you know It's like.
Speaker 0: it's really really well crafted using the thing that I care about the most always as a piece of software.
Speaker 0: Is it well craft it just works.
Speaker 0: It's like yeah, it works perfectly, you know, it works at all resolutions.
Speaker 0: It's smooth There's no weird lags or control problems.
Speaker 0: I get it's basically just perfect It saves.
Speaker 0: the one thing it does really nice as a piece of software is it saves the game basically constantly.
Speaker 0: Yep, so you it's basically like having a choose your own adventure.
Speaker 0: that automatically puts a million fingers in all the pages.
Speaker 1: That's a real important part of the UX of a good visual novel.
Speaker 0: You can always go back and load and redo anything you want But basically what it is?
Speaker 0: the game starts up with the intro day.
Speaker 1: That's all.
Speaker 1: it starts with that song and had they had like it's so well It has its own theme song about dads, right?
Speaker 0: So on the intro day you sort of go around.
Speaker 0: you move and you meet all the town and get set up with the basics.
Speaker 0: Then eventually on the next day or after that is a barbecue where like all the dads are there.
Speaker 0: After that barbecue the next day you wake up and you learn how to use dad book.
Speaker 0: So in dad book is basically Facebook just for dads plus dating And there's all the dads profiles there and you can mess it.
Speaker 0: you can choose which dad to message and the seven dads Yep, and whichever dad you message will say yes and go hang out with you that day And you can similar to Tokimeki like who you can hang out with this weekend, right?
Speaker 0: You choose one of the dads and then you get some dad plot and you get some daughter plot and you know You hang out with that dad and stuff happens and basically you can hang out with.
Speaker 0: as far as I can tell because I only did Basically, I you know one dad pretty much but basically I did one dad.
Speaker 0: then I did a different dad.
Speaker 0: Do the dad or just hang out with the dad?
Speaker 0: I chose one dad.
Speaker 0: Okay, because I chose vampire dad.
Speaker 0: then on the second the second day I chose banana bread dad and then I went back to vampire dad.
Speaker 0: and Then if you choose the vampire dad or any dad a third time, they're like, you know This is gonna basically end the game.
Speaker 0: once you choose a dad a third time You're committing to that dad and it's like alright I'll just commit to vampire dad and end the game.
Speaker 0: so I did and obviously I didn't get the best ending Right, but I got.
Speaker 0: I learned a lot about vampire dad, right?
Speaker 0: I chose him a third time
Speaker 1: because a big part of visual novels like this kind is you want like you expect people to play through it a bunch to sort of plumb the depths of all right,
Speaker 0: so I think the way
Speaker 1: the plot
Speaker 0: I think what you want to Do if you want to really completely do this game is do every dad twice Right.
Speaker 0: go to yeah, you can see on dad book Every dad is three hearts because every time you hang out with them you get one heart.
Speaker 0: So hang out with every dad two times to see a ton of plot Save the game and then do the third Episode of each dad one at a time
Speaker 1: and
Speaker 0: then that will be an efficient way to go through the game with all dads And try to get you know The best endings and see all of the things there are to see in the game.
Speaker 0: because like I did it I'm gonna have to load the game way back and go to different dad.
Speaker 1: So the thing is you're just gonna have to play it again, I think.
Speaker 1: because yeah based on what I played so far There's like a lot of the choices are arbitrary and just lead to like a slightly different funny joke.
Speaker 0: But sometimes you'll one choice will like make hearts come out of a dad and another choice will make like a black smoke come out.
Speaker 1: But also some choices will radically like will give you scenes You will not see otherwise just in the middle like in the first day You can have sex with Robert like right away even on the intro day.
Speaker 0: Yeah, not and you didn't even go to dad book.
Speaker 1: I didn't even know dad would existed.
Speaker 1: I already had sex with Robert while my daughter had a slumber party and then I woke up in his apartment Hung over and he's like, yeah, you should probably leave and I'm like, oh shit I hope my daughter's alive cuz I just left her home alone.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I saw Robert in the back of the coffee shop and didn't talk to him.
Speaker 1: coffee shop No Because I did not want to let anyone get in the way of me and Matt getting together.
Speaker 1: Cuz Matt is the best dad and there's no one fight me.
Speaker 0: Well, okay.
Speaker 0: So here's the thing with the dads at least what I gather.
Speaker 0: I don't want to like spoil any of these because the game is it's just a book right?
Speaker 0: It's a choose?
Speaker 0: Well, I don't.
Speaker 0: well, I don't believe the trademark term.
Speaker 1: So it's not a choose your own right.
Speaker 0: But while I don't believe in spoilers I still not gonna.
Speaker 0: you know, I'm not gonna tell you anything cuz I want you to buy this game.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I like.
Speaker 0: I think the way it works.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna play some more.
Speaker 0: each dad on the surface seems to have a stereotype, right?
Speaker 0: There's your old college roommate who seems a sporty dad.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there's a bunch of kids.
Speaker 0: There's the Christian ish yuppie.
Speaker 0: Where's a you know, looks like a guy from Scooby-doo who is clearly married to a demon from beyond?
Speaker 1: It's had demon children, right?
Speaker 0: It's like the stereotype surface level you see of all these guys, right?
Speaker 0: Is you know?
Speaker 0: cool coffee shop owning banana bread.
Speaker 0: dad who rim like thinks his best dad.
Speaker 0: He has the best voice.
Speaker 0: I thought he was best dad on day one.
Speaker 0: Also.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there's teacher dad sexy teacher dead.
Speaker 1: Yep, there's.
Speaker 1: I points to him for being an insufferable pedant.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah vampire dad Bad dad who's the one room had sex with so bad dads were in the the Vaughn from eska flown a shirt.
Speaker 1: So I'm assuming this is like washed up Vaughn when he finally made it, you know, it's sunglasses motorcycle alcohol.
Speaker 0: He's like hey dog with spike necklace dad, right?
Speaker 1: I just saw when I went to the bar.
Speaker 1: There's like this shitty dive bar in town and I went there to watch sports ball but with to avoid having to be around all my daughter at a slumber party and First the wife of the middle guy tried to sex me and I was like hell.
Speaker 1: no and then this guy was like Hey, and I was like, hey and then one thing led to another and I was in his apartment.
Speaker 1: Where's house?
Speaker 0: Hey, and then the final dad is the you know, the large, you know, oh, oh dad.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the you know the grilling and lawnmowing and sort of Viking ish kind of dad.
Speaker 1: It's complicated by the fact that they're all dads.
Speaker 1: They'll have kids, but they all have very different kids situations.
Speaker 1: Some of the kids are good.
Speaker 1: Some of them are bad Some of them are complicated, but anyway baby is not real because it never blinks.
Speaker 0: Yeah But anyway, the point is each of the dads.
Speaker 0: I think what happens is on the based on my judgment of vampire Dad is that on the third day of each of the dad you revealed his corn chip stash to you.
Speaker 0: They revealed that there's another side to them that you don't see.
Speaker 0: you only see the stereotyped Sort of character that they you know They appear to be.
Speaker 0: so you only see vampire stuff for day one and day two and on day three You see what is really like.
Speaker 0: it's really a Larpur.
Speaker 0: So I think that with all these other dads I Assume the same thing will happen that if I go out with them one two times I'll just see like if I hung out with college roommate dad I'd see him doing Sportsy stuff with his kids for day one and two and I think on day three like I'd learn his real Real deal that
Speaker 1: the kid he's carrying around everywhere is actually a robot.
Speaker 1: maybe Doesn't blink.
Speaker 1: every other character blinks, but not that baby, right?
Speaker 0: But I think that's generally the deal right.
Speaker 1: so so a really important aspect is that it has a lot of sort of Sort of minigames and some of them like are literally like a Pokemon battle.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and some of them you don't really.
Speaker 1: you don't quite realize it's a minigame until you lose it.
Speaker 1: like at one point we're cooking for cooking breakfast hungover with my daughter and That she says a weird word like Macadamia gazebo and my prompt is I can say a bunch of those words to check on the bacon and At first I'm trying to ignore her because I have a hangover and I don't want her prodding into the fact that I sex Robert.
Speaker 1: That'll have the previous night.
Speaker 1: So I just keep checking on the bacon and then she starts playing this word game with me and I as a player and this Is in the live stream legit get into it and start playing the word game with her in the voice dialogues.
Speaker 1: and because I didn't Check on the bacon it catches fire.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there's also actual like video game games like this one I go to.
Speaker 0: I went to a concert with the dad the rim likes.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, right and after going to the concert, it's like when I first saw him on the intro day I thought he was best dad, but after going to the concert I wasn't into him as much.
Speaker 0: But there was a mini just so hot that I'll overlook almost anything and he's still the hottest.
Speaker 0: Yeah but basically during the During that concert there was an actual game that was like get to the front of the crowd because I basically I went to the bathroom.
Speaker 0: Then the concert started.
Speaker 0: I had to basically find him in the crowd and like push my way up to the front and that game Was sort of not well programmed.
Speaker 0: It was sort of a pain in the ass and not the greatest and I lost it Because I couldn't figure out what the hell was going on.
Speaker 0: It was an actual video game and not a. it's like you had to maneuver in real time.
Speaker 0: It wasn't just multiple choice choices.
Speaker 0: It's like this other thing that affected the actual game and I
Speaker 1: for a second I thought I remember when you in order
Speaker 0: to play all of these little mini games I think you're gonna have to go out with each member
Speaker 1: in earth found you got to push through all the cultists to get to The big cultists.
Speaker 1: Yeah similar, but I feel like with all these little minigame things It's interesting because a lot of them sort of like that one in particular, right?
Speaker 1: The way the dialogue goes you're like you.
Speaker 1: the dad the dad Sona that you make Kinda like not super social and not really well versed
Speaker 0: you don't have any choice in your own personality is like your dad is sort of a not like a do-nothing doesn't have a lot of Interests and is socially awkward and not socially awkward like he behaves in a bad way like at that guy.
Speaker 0: But then he's just like shy.
Speaker 0: Yeah introverted Right, and it's really really cares about his daughter a lot But doesn't really like have anything interesting going on other than that, you know, yeah Warm caring kind of person, but he's not a complete self-insert because he has some right.
Speaker 0: if you're an extroverted like go-getter You can't be that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you can't you know, you can try to force yourself to do that.
Speaker 0: But even if you choose those options like I'm gonna you know, it basically it's.
Speaker 0: it comes It doesn't come off as a guy who actually is extroverted but as a dad who is you know?
Speaker 0: Do is still introverted but he's going out there because he knows he should and he's you know, succeeding and fighting himself Yeah as opposed to actually being the person you are.
Speaker 1: but to review it and again to not spoil anything because I think it's worth Playing it's if you're this game is really good.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah Yeah, I laughed out loud repeatedly.
Speaker 0: It's real funny.
Speaker 0: It's well written.
Speaker 1: It's well made It's well crafted and there's clever stuff in the UX like little things like most visual.
Speaker 0: when the dads kissed I was like, I was actually like, ooh, yeah It wasn't just like, you know, it's like, you know, what's gonna happen, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, you think it would just be like man.
Speaker 0: All right, we finally got to that part, but it's like.
Speaker 0: I was actually like.
Speaker 1: I don't think there are explicit sex.
Speaker 1: Like you can.
Speaker 1: you can straight-up have explicit sex, but it doesn't just show that.
Speaker 0: but nothing was.
Speaker 0: never is no visual.
Speaker 0: Even the kissing was not even visually displayed on the screen, but there were words.
Speaker 0: it definitely happened.
Speaker 1: It's like oh and we kissed when I when I when I sexed Robert on the first night.
Speaker 1: It was very well written.
Speaker 1: Yeah, put it that way.
Speaker 1: I could see why Robert is an attractive gentleman.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm But was it actually going into details about like your butt or whatever?
Speaker 1: It went into details about where he grabbed me and hips and things and it was pretty.
Speaker 1: it was pretty good Yeah, but there's the UX is pretty clever, too.
Speaker 1: So like it'll have a really good background like the fonts and everything are great.
Speaker 1: the things that like That'll that's the only thing that'll break me out of visual novel is there.
Speaker 1: the font kerning is bad.
Speaker 1: The font spacing is bad.
Speaker 1: There's.
Speaker 0: oh, yeah Not only did it not have those problems, but I was able to rapidly push the spacebar to get through text crazy fast But if you don't which is really good for my eyes.
Speaker 1: Timing and cadence is actually someone put way more effort into the text cadence than they probably even needed.
Speaker 0: I mean, it's correct, right?
Speaker 0: It's not usually.
Speaker 0: that's something that would bother me a lot But I was able to fly through at my reading speed and get through the game nicely.
Speaker 1: But if you let the game do the text reveal on its own it doesn't feel slow.
Speaker 0: It's just.
Speaker 0: you know, you still push the spacebar though.
Speaker 1: Mostly I was doing it slower because I was live streaming it.
Speaker 1: So I want to make sure everyone can follow along.
Speaker 0: Yeah,
Speaker 1: and partly I'd waited cuz I was laughing out loud a lot but also like so it shows dialogue boxes based on when people are talking and The characters react pretty well, but it also has a separate dialogue box for any inner monologue which is important because a lot of visual novels have trouble differentiating between characters saying something versus descriptive text and the descriptive text is framed as Your own inner monologue with a different box.
Speaker 1: and all these factors together the UX is nearly impeccable.
Speaker 1: There I can come up with very few criticisms of how the games actually put together.
Speaker 0: another thing that happens is After each date with a dad you this score screen comes up.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah and the score screen.
Speaker 0: I don't know how much of it is real and fake but you do get like an s-rank a-rank c-rank d-rank f-rank with that dad And I think that that does have some effect on where the game goes.
Speaker 0: You get all s-ranks of the dad, I'm pretty sure you you get better stuff with them.
Speaker 0: I think my ranks like a then C then s or was it s CS?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I got a big part of why I was into.
Speaker 1: Matt The the coffee shop guy.
Speaker 1: was that I?
Speaker 1: he really liked my name for the banana bread.
Speaker 1: like way liked it.
Speaker 0: Which one did you choose?
Speaker 1: I already don't remember what the options were.
Speaker 0: He really liked mine, which one was yours.
Speaker 0: I forget banana bread Dream Daddy.
Speaker 1: The problem is I'm reading Princeton nothing.
Speaker 1: So I got too many right.
Speaker 1: right said bread.
Speaker 0: That's what I chose.
Speaker 1: I chose right said banana bread also, but the fact that he has good taste means that he's like he's my main man My main dad.
Speaker 1: so far unless I learned like he's a serial killer or something.
Speaker 0: I mean, I think all the dads have a secret.
Speaker 0: after that after the third date the game ends.
Speaker 0: You know once you get a third date with a dad and then you learn their real deal.
Speaker 1: I worry what would have happened if I'd bought a drink for the bad lady Mmm, because she comes over and like aggressively flirts with you.
Speaker 0: I learned about her actually in Vampire Dead's third day.
Speaker 0: Oh Even though like I didn't think I would see her at all because I didn't go into Area of the game.
Speaker 0: I think I get her deal by dealing with him But I'll say that she was doing quite the opposite of evil in that area.
Speaker 0: So if you want to see some non-evil of that lady go to the vampire.
Speaker 1: I only assume she's evil because her kids are clearly demon.
Speaker 0: I think it's just the way they draw her face on purpose to make her know her kids are clearly inhuman.
Speaker 1: They're like Anna syramore kids.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: No, but I mean I got the at least from the barbecue.
Speaker 0: I actually did like hated her husband and I thought she was probably I don't like her husband either.
Speaker 1: He's bad news I don't like.
Speaker 1: I didn't like either one of them.
Speaker 0: Well, they're the Jesus II type people.
Speaker 1: If I had to rank them based on the surface only it's definitely but I seem like the Pleasantville.
Speaker 0: very it's like yeah No good banana bread guy.
Speaker 1: I feel like Roberts got some hidden depths.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: I feel like there's.
Speaker 1: there's something there.
Speaker 1: That's good.
Speaker 0: They all have hidden depths.
Speaker 1: Yeah, of course I mean, I guess his hidden death could be just worse than what he is on the surface Mmm, like oh, I'm a rebel.
Speaker 1: No, really.
Speaker 1: I killed a bunch of people.
Speaker 1: So yeah, this game is like super legit.
Speaker 1: good Even if you don't think you like visual novels, like I recommend it.
Speaker 1: It's not that.
Speaker 0: yeah I think this is actually a great like.
Speaker 0: if you are someone who hasn't played visual novels like.
Speaker 0: this is something that you could introduce to even people who aren't visual novel people or You know see if see if you're gonna like visual novel dude I think and this is so appropriate for anyone who's over like 18 or 16.
Speaker 1: My mom would legit like this game.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't know if my dad would but I mom my mom would definitely play this game.
Speaker 0: Yeah This game is so You know as such a broad appeal to anyone who has no problem with gayness.
Speaker 0: I'm uh, you can use it probably as a great way to detect if someone is a good person or a bad person.
Speaker 0: They don't like this game.
Speaker 0: They're probably a bad person.
Speaker 1: Uh, uh, I feel like I'm looking forward to cosplay.
Speaker 0: Oh What a cosplay some day.
Speaker 1: I could be the vampire dad.
Speaker 0: You maybe could be the vampire dad.
Speaker 1: That's the only one I could be.
Speaker 0: I can't be any of those dads.
Speaker 1: I'm not.
Speaker 1: I'm not hot enough to be most of them.
Speaker 1: Yeah, Pete could pull off Viking dad, I think if you grew a beard, yeah, it's a gross hair back.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you could do it.
Speaker 0: No, none of the none of the dads in the game are bald Except if you make your own dad bald.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and I don't know anyone in person hot as hot as Matt.
Speaker 0: So Who do I know?
Speaker 1: that's that I know anyone that hot?
Speaker 1: I Got no one.
Speaker 0: Nope.
Speaker 0: I mean the dads are unrealistically hot.
Speaker 1: Yeah I Okay, I think we're done but you should play this game.
Speaker 1: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at front row crew comm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 1: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 0: But unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 0: It's actually recorded at night And the patreon page runs.
Speaker 1: for this episode of geek nights are Alan Joyce, Heidi McNichol Amanda Duchette and Thomas.
Speaker 1: on my state I come William I suppose Jeremy minor.
Speaker 1: life and death and love and birth and peace and war on the planet earth a genuine.
Speaker 1: But if I'd like to buy six car monorail Nicholas Brando captain Chinguac see Rebecca done the terrible secret of space 421 creations That's because we're fighting each other.
Speaker 1: Sure about horrible rare Laval James David White Rochelle, Monta, Nona, who is an omega not superboy.
Speaker 1: I paid five bucks to make room say pickle sailor Vista Matthew Smith.
Speaker 1: Don't you like charge average and Joe Joe Joseph Sean?
Speaker 1: Yeah, you're Sam Cordery Clinton Walton Ren from New Zealand Ryan parent drew open letter branches for any fin.
Speaker 1: Chris mid give Chris Knox Daniel Redmond Sean Klein Chris Reimer and Thomas Hahn.
Speaker 1: I am working on the new tennis shows.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna chose to share some Pre-production notes on the patreon as soon as they get a chance.
Speaker 1: We're working on our convention We're getting ready for packs and our new panel and yeah stuff's coming geek.
Speaker 1: nice isn't full swing.
Speaker 1: You might have noticed I published a new rims rant on heuristics.
Speaker 1: I also published a roomly review of Fargo TV and a roomly review of Westworld will be up probably later this week.
Speaker 1: And now I leave you with.