Speaker 0: It's Tuesday January 17th 2017.
Speaker 0: I'm rim, I'm Scott and this is geek nights.
Speaker 0: We're back from mag fast talking about Poppin by Friedman freeze.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we're back from mag fest.
Speaker 0: as you know mag fest is a tiring convention.
Speaker 0: So, uh didn't do a show on Monday because we got back on Sunday And then I had to go to the dentist on Wednesday to get one cavity filled.
Speaker 1: You said it was a regular dentist, but no you had too much.
Speaker 0: So basically every dentist appointment for some time now like everyone for like a year and a half The dude's been like there's a spot on this one tooth and someday that's gonna be a cavity as well.
Speaker 0: It's keep an eye on it.
Speaker 1: and he was like, why don't you take care of it?
Speaker 1: So it doesn't become a cavity.
Speaker 0: He basically said there's nothing you can do like it's stop eating the sugar now.
Speaker 1: That's not to stop drinking the Red Bull.
Speaker 0: No, I drink so little Caffeinated beverage like that.
Speaker 1: You drink gallons.
Speaker 0: that is definitely not the problem.
Speaker 1: What if we took all the Red Bull you ever drank and put it in a bucket?
Speaker 1: That'd be some big-ass bucket.
Speaker 0: It would probably not.
Speaker 1: that would be a frighteningly large bucket.
Speaker 0: That would make you you forget the Red Bulls come in tiny cans.
Speaker 0: It's like a little tiny baby.
Speaker 0: can I drink?
Speaker 0: Maybe I don't know.
Speaker 0: to a week.
Speaker 1: I seem to remember there being various incidences where entire cases of Red Bull were purchased and then disappeared.
Speaker 0: Yeah, those were not just consumed by me though.
Speaker 0: Those are consumed by a certain Fat Fonson.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: So, uh, yeah We're back geek nights as normal and magfest was great as always and I already kind of regret the fact that I'm not currently there.
Speaker 1: Well magfest has many other events that you we go to none of.
Speaker 0: yeah, cuz they're always at bad times.
Speaker 1: There's like a magfest labs and there's a mag.
Speaker 1: The mag stock.
Speaker 0: every well mag stock I think in particular was during a convention We were at as a West Coast mag thing of some kind.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and West Coast is tough.
Speaker 0: I mean we go to West Coast for packs.
Speaker 0: The bar for me to go to the West Coast for another convention in the same year is pretty fucking high already.
Speaker 1: He went to the other side of the world Yeah, but that was different.
Speaker 0: It was a packs.
Speaker 0: Also, I don't go to pack sauce every year anymore.
Speaker 1: I want to.
Speaker 0: I'll probably go next year because I skipped the last two.
Speaker 1: Maybe you will.
Speaker 1: I'm thinking about if I do I'm going to the coral reefs.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't care.
Speaker 1: I don't care if they're closed or dead.
Speaker 1: I'm going there.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'll just go in the warm waters I don't care.
Speaker 0: Okay, just go up to Brisbane.
Speaker 0: Just go swimming.
Speaker 1: Is there a tropical fishies there?
Speaker 1: Maybe I don't know.
Speaker 1: Can I see through the water to the sand?
Speaker 0: Yeah, you can see through the water to the sand pretty much everywhere.
Speaker 0: and the tropical thingies like when we were Like a starfish in Sydney.
Speaker 0: We went swimming and it was cold like real cold because it was winter.
Speaker 1: There's no jellyfish.
Speaker 1: No jellies, right?
Speaker 1: I don't do jellies.
Speaker 0: The jellies there are way more dangerous than the jellies here and sometimes you don't worry about that.
Speaker 1: When I was in Israel, we went to the Red Sea and there's just jellies.
Speaker 0: Those are the chill jellies.
Speaker 1: No, they were not good.
Speaker 1: Someone got stung by them.
Speaker 1: They're bad.
Speaker 1: They're not like.
Speaker 1: you're dead jellies, but they're not good.
Speaker 1: And it's just like you look under the water and it looks like that fucking level in Mario 3 where it's just.
Speaker 1: You know I'm talking about right Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles 1 only horizontal.
Speaker 1: Yeah, exactly only only horizontal instead of vertical.
Speaker 1: Right because you're looking at it from the top.
Speaker 1: So it was just like polka dot or you know Zippa tone, but jellies instead.
Speaker 0: Oh my god I was watching some speedrun of Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles 1 and the that section is yeah You just take a lot of damage damage boost.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah damage boost through life rim.
Speaker 1: I Saw the damage boost down the schema.
Speaker 1: You know what happens.
Speaker 0: the real life done.
Speaker 0: quick parody account.
Speaker 0: the one that talks about real life like it's a speedrun Finally started updating again.
Speaker 0: They were like we've read.
Speaker 1: I gotta follow this.
Speaker 1: What is it?
Speaker 0: We've redone the any percent route.
Speaker 0: It's you can.
Speaker 0: you can clip in front of the shuttle from the hospital instead of waiting for traffic.
Speaker 0: They talk about like any percent runs and 100% runs.
Speaker 0: it's a real good Twitter account.
Speaker 0: They don't tweet that often, but when they do it's always gold.
Speaker 0: Hmm.
Speaker 0: So, uh, yeah, there's a lot of gaming news.
Speaker 0: So I feel like we should cover a bunch of it, but not all of it.
Speaker 0: Probably the biggest news is the Nintendo switch.
Speaker 0: We know about it now And I don't know I'm more excited about it than I was about the Wii U.
Speaker 1: I Pre-ordered it because I'll tell you the reasons right?
Speaker 1: So reason number one Bomberman.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that looks real good.
Speaker 1: He's number two Bomberman that bomber.
Speaker 0: Here's what sold me on it.
Speaker 0: I heard oh, there's gonna be another Bomberman on the switch and I thought that could be good.
Speaker 0: But then I clicked on it and I noticed something eight people Gaga.
Speaker 0: yeah, not just that but the avatars of the Bomberman's themselves Look kind of anime and like well-drawn, which I haven't seen recently.
Speaker 1: They're all you know, instead of just being the same Bomberman in eight different colors.
Speaker 1: They actually have eight different personalities, right?
Speaker 1: It's like it's you know, it's it's real Bomberman.
Speaker 1: And also I realized something it's like oh, you know When am I gonna get these eight people in my apartment to play a Bomberman right?
Speaker 1: Cuz like I have we you I got you know, I Was about to say when did you buy we?
Speaker 1: I didn't buy what you ever we right but it's like when you're in college.
Speaker 0: The GameCube party action happened so much like the GameCube was on like we played more games total on the GameCube When we were in beacon.
Speaker 1: the Wii party action happened so much.
Speaker 1: But as soon as I moved to New York We don't have parties at my apartment and my Wii party I have like Wii party games that have been Unplayed because we don't get people at my apartment in groups to play them counterpoint with the exception of Mario Kart.
Speaker 0: The Wii party games weren't that good.
Speaker 1: Not as good as the GameCube ones like I would put like to this.
Speaker 0: you cannot listen.
Speaker 1: go back to those early geek nights Right.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we bold we bold we bold and we did many a thing.
Speaker 1: on the Wii.
Speaker 0: We're gonna like the RIT like WarioWare like holy crap.
Speaker 1: Do we play that game a lot, but I realized something right this switch Unlike the Wii U right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's just 100.
Speaker 1: It's actually portable.
Speaker 1: It's like it might as well be a fucking DS.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm gonna.
Speaker 1: this thing comes out right before PAX East.
Speaker 1: We're bringing it to pack.
Speaker 1: I pre-ordered it on Amazon.
Speaker 1: I bought some controllers.
Speaker 1: I don't think I've eight controllers, but have four.
Speaker 1: It's like.
Speaker 1: I Pre-ordered the Zelda game just to be sure that I get it, but I'm not gonna probably not gonna buy any other physical games.
Speaker 1: I'm probably just gonna get them all in the e-shop so I won't have to buy a physical junk line around.
Speaker 1: yeah, and then It's like hey, I got eight player Bomberman.
Speaker 1: I could just take it with me anywhere.
Speaker 1: We don't even need to set up a fucking TV.
Speaker 1: We can sit down waiting in line and play Bomberman Right there.
Speaker 1: you cannot.
Speaker 1: with DS is it's like oh, we got to get this wireless shit to work.
Speaker 0: Actually work you try to play everyone.
Speaker 1: Everyone has to have a DS and people who don't have one.
Speaker 1: It's like no we put this thing on the ground.
Speaker 1: Everyone huddles around it and boom.
Speaker 1: We're good.
Speaker 1: You cannot do that really with the Wii U. you can't write.
Speaker 1: It's like.
Speaker 1: that is why I said all right No one else seems like they're super excited about it.
Speaker 1: if someone else is buying it Maybe I wouldn't buy it right you know But I have more monies than some of the other people so I will take the responsibility.
Speaker 0: So counterpoint also.
Speaker 1: it puts me in control of the bomber Privilege of the purchaser.
Speaker 0: on one hand you're gonna be the green Bomberman every time of course.
Speaker 0: on one hand There's a print like there's a new Zelda game.
Speaker 0: there hasn't been a new like full-on.
Speaker 1: That's the other reason that I'm buying it because even though you know There's probably not gonna be a large quantity of games like this I have except for Majora's Mask, which I don't like even though other people like it.
Speaker 1: Every single single player real mainline You know not side bullshit Zelda game that has ever existed.
Speaker 1: I have beaten to completion except Majora's Mask.
Speaker 1: fuck that game.
Speaker 1: So of course there's gonna be one and it's on Wii U also.
Speaker 1: But I ain't buying that.
Speaker 0: there is also a Splatoon 2 which if like Splatoon was a game where if I had the console I would've been all over it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean Splatoon is like it.
Speaker 1: I see it, and I say damn that is some legit game right there, right?
Speaker 1: But I'm not even playing competitive Counter-Strike.
Speaker 0: I'm not even playing Overwatch.
Speaker 1: I'm definitely not playing that right.
Speaker 1: so I don't got time for no FPS is or any multiplayer kind of action as it is.
Speaker 0: I still don't understand why you don't play over.
Speaker 0: What if I was released a game that was like hey Scott?
Speaker 0: Remember all those games you talk about being like the pinnacle of FPS thing?
Speaker 0: then we made a game That is just like those games anyway, and you're like.
Speaker 1: Yeah If I was not if I was a person who was not like a PC gaming like This would be like the glory of glory game.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, so you know what if overwatch had not come out I would have bought this just for Splatoon.
Speaker 1: Oh really you wouldn't see I would have you wouldn't have stayed with.
Speaker 1: like Rocket League or a counter-strike.
Speaker 0: I suck at Rocket League, and I'm too old for Rocket League like I watch Counter-Strike.
Speaker 0: Counter-Strike actually, actually NS2 I didn't.
Speaker 0: I've had weird like as much as I want to like NS2.
Speaker 1: It's partially revived.
Speaker 0: I hate to say it, but I didn't enjoy it that much.
Speaker 0: I couldn't stop playing it because it wasn't that fun.
Speaker 1: I like NS2.
Speaker 0: But actually I am playing Counter-Strike again, and I got to say I am bad at it But I am still way better than most people at it.
Speaker 0: It's I'm shocked at how good I actually am.
Speaker 1: That's how good I am at video games generally.
Speaker 1: I'm not it.
Speaker 1: I look at speedruns and I go man I'm bad at this.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like I see people playing Super Metroid on the speedrun It's like they beat the whole thing a hundred percent and like less than a couple like an hour and change right or like 40.
Speaker 1: Whatever it is 40 minutes something like that.
Speaker 0: I don't know but like still the other day our friend Judith, right?
Speaker 1: I play and it's like.
Speaker 1: I don't remember.
Speaker 1: I'm like I'm I'll get to the end and it'll be like 80% and I'm like.
Speaker 1: what the hell did I miss and that'll take me like all fucking day.
Speaker 0: Judith didn't really know like speedrunning was the big thing.
Speaker 0: it is like it's not super commonly known like it's only raised two million dollars.
Speaker 0: No, yeah, but it's not super kind.
Speaker 1: think about how much money how much money you raised.
Speaker 0: I'm saying it's not that it's not super well known Except for people who are kind of like in that subculture or people are like deep into gaming culture.
Speaker 0: So the other day she was like something something that Lion King game on the Genesis.
Speaker 0: I was real good at it and I was like Let's watch the AGD queue of it.
Speaker 0: and she was like I could beat the game in.
Speaker 0: I forget how many minutes.
Speaker 0: she's like n Minutes.
Speaker 0: and like I was like I played that game obsessively and then we've turned on the speedrun and her time Not that far away from the AGD queue like close to the world record time, right?
Speaker 1: I mean if you play a game quickly and some games have glitches you might not know about.
Speaker 0: Oh, she knew about.
Speaker 0: There's a section that came up and she's like, oh man You can actually one-shot those guys if you like.
Speaker 0: blah blah blah blah blah with the timing.
Speaker 1: I'm talking glitches.
Speaker 1: like you know I can super Metroid the big glitch like if you ever watch super Metroid speedrun no matter pretty much no matter what percentage it is There's no like you can like wall job.
Speaker 1: No, there's this part where they know, you know the green the first sort of boss.
Speaker 1: You fight the green plant thing.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, then no one ever fights that you never even see that section of the map.
Speaker 1: They never go there except for the 100% map category where you have to reveal the whole map.
Speaker 1: And the reason is because this is room where these, you know, little things come down from the ceiling.
Speaker 1: It's like tick tick tick tick.
Speaker 1: and then they're closed and you can only open them from the other side.
Speaker 1: But you can use a technique called the mock ball To like get through them and go through when you're not supposed to go through that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and that you skip that whole area.
Speaker 1: And it's like if you don't know that it's like you would only know that from like either a you're the person who discovered it.
Speaker 1: Or be you went and research speedrun shit.
Speaker 1: Like I've tried to get through those Like the way it's designed you sort of have this natural inclination because you enter the room and these things are closing like tick tick Tick tick and it's like you feel like you can get under there.
Speaker 1: It's just everyone who plays.
Speaker 1: it has this natural thing where they try to do it and then you can't because there's a second one You can't make it through that one.
Speaker 1: But the speedrunners know the trick to get through and if you practice you can do the trick, too.
Speaker 1: It's not impossibly hard.
Speaker 1: I've done it once.
Speaker 1: No, but they do it exactly right every single time.
Speaker 1: It's like holy shit.
Speaker 0: So in other news a GDQ, of course is happening or happened.
Speaker 0: by the time you listen to this It's done and it was the biggest one ever.
Speaker 0: Yep Uh, it made the news for a bunch of reasons but I kind of want to highlight the fact.
Speaker 0: a few things happened and this has happened more and more recently where AGDQ they will ban people from being on the streams.
Speaker 1: Yeah, AGDQ has really good policies.
Speaker 1: I'm like, you know, it's one of the good conventions like really good anti-harassment Whatever ex mag fest, you know all the good things that we support right?
Speaker 1: They have the good policies.
Speaker 1: they don't stand for your bullshit and Even more so than the other ones they can't afford to stand for your bullshit, right?
Speaker 1: Because whichever charity they're supporting whether it's prevent cancer foundation or doctors without borders who they support during the summer is Watching and they're seeing someone on the stream like swearing and giving a bad image.
Speaker 1: It's like we can't have that, you know charity is like nope.
Speaker 0: So the news specifically I mean penny arcade had that problem where the child's play charity Couldn't get a statue and public at a public place because someone who is approving that statue Looked up what penny arcade was and read a few strips, right?
Speaker 1: So the prevent cancer foundation would be very very unhappy if they saw some assholes on the stream.
Speaker 1: so they can't have you there You know and that's the end of it.
Speaker 1: So probably that's good because that's just like.
Speaker 1: that's a convenient excuse for enforcing policies that you should have.
Speaker 1: Anyway, which is up.
Speaker 1: This is for speedrunning.
Speaker 1: No assholes allowed.
Speaker 0: So they made the news.
Speaker 0: the biggest one during this AGDQ.
Speaker 0: was they banned a dude for busting out a make America great again Trump hat on the stream?
Speaker 1: Yeah, can't have that.
Speaker 0: and the guy like got mad.
Speaker 1: Of course.
Speaker 1: He's a mad guy.
Speaker 1: Well, so you wearing that hat if you're not mad Yep.
Speaker 0: so they basically he got banned dude went crazy and tried to get his legion of like shitlord trolls to go after AGDQ and Like boycott them and demand an apology.
Speaker 1: Yes, that will put you in the good graces of humanity.
Speaker 1: Supporting cancer.
Speaker 1: if you're against AGDQ, you're for cancer, which means you are cancer.
Speaker 0: So you can read the story of like this dude if you care about you're.
Speaker 0: either.
Speaker 1: you're either for.
Speaker 1: if you're against AGDQ That means you either a must want to play games slowly.
Speaker 1: Yeah Or games done badly or be you want people.
Speaker 0: So, you know shitty flute will start shitty games done badly and it's just cringy terrible streams of people playing games badly.
Speaker 1: That's my museum You know.
Speaker 0: Anyway, but the two points about this one if you run a convention and you have a good harassment policy Just stick by your guns.
Speaker 0: Like don't take right.
Speaker 0: like.
Speaker 1: if someone mouths off to the point of the harassment policy if you don't stick to it It might as well not exist.
Speaker 0: There's someone really Enforce it like a recording supposedly of like the dude getting banned and they're like look Here's your warning.
Speaker 0: you people are causing a problem and they start to mouth off at the staff and the guys like, you know What?
Speaker 0: nope, it's over.
Speaker 0: Give me all your badges.
Speaker 0: This is done
Speaker 1: You're done
Speaker 0: and that is the right way to do things at conventions because it's done
Speaker 1: son
Speaker 0: Staff a lot of conventions and all I want to say is that kind of crap happens all the time at every convention And if you mouth off to the staff, they'll just take your badge.
Speaker 0: In fact, if they don't just take your badge Usually that means that conventions not that well run and you basically have a license to raise.
Speaker 0: holy hell.
Speaker 0: So a GDQ props to you.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm The other news that came out there was actually pretty interesting.
Speaker 0: I saw boot disks all over my Twitter One day and I was like, why are people talking about boot disks?
Speaker 1: So people don't know this.
Speaker 1: right back in the day Let's say you're running a computer with Windows 2.1 and Windows 95 usually 3.1, right?
Speaker 1: And you want to play a game.
Speaker 1: say I did this for Mac or your - yep and here's for do my computer at that time I upgraded it later and I didn't need to do this anymore, but it only had eight megabytes Eight megabytes of RAM.
Speaker 1: Nowadays, I have 32 gigabytes, but then I had eight gigabytes.
Speaker 1: when I upgraded it It was 16 But I had eight megabytes of RAM and a 486 and I want to play Mac or your - and Mac or your - would work If you had eight megabytes of RAM, but you would use a lot of that RAM and it would in fact Often need to swap which means when it filled up the RAM it would say All right.
Speaker 1: Well the thing I need in RAM right now won't fit.
Speaker 1: I'll take some of the stuff in RAM right now I don't need.
Speaker 1: put it back in the hard drive.
Speaker 1: take the stuff I need from the hard drive put it back in the RAM.
Speaker 0: Oh, but back then hard drives were slow even slower than they are now.
Speaker 1: like you would be amazed at how hard drives That's what's known as swapping it still happens today on modern computers when they run out of RAM.
Speaker 0: and but when it happens Unless you turn that off and then your computer will just crash right?
Speaker 1: But when it happens like you'll notice why is my computer so slow?
Speaker 1: think about how slow it was when it happened back in the day with eight megabytes of RAM, so What you could do to avoid or alleviate this problem was saying, okay Look, here's what I'm gonna do.
Speaker 1: I turn the computer on.
Speaker 1: what's in the RAM?
Speaker 1: when I turn the computer on basically nothing like the iOS bootstrap, right?
Speaker 1: Well, the operating system is in the RAM right and then you know Windows started.
Speaker 1: So Windows 3.1 is in the RAM and then like my mouse drive thing is in the RAM.
Speaker 1: It's like there's a certain list of things that are in the RAM.
Speaker 1: when your computer just turns on right?
Speaker 1: You would make a boot disk that would say alright Look instead of booting from the hard drive boot from this disk and this disk Well has very specific boot instructions.
Speaker 0: So when the computer turns on It'll be like The sound card driver.
Speaker 1: all of only the things you need are in the RAM and no extra stuffs like Windows won't load and Extra drivers won't.
Speaker 1: anything you don't need To play the game will not be in the RAM and then you launch the game from the boot disk even though it's on the hard drive and then You have the maximum amount available RAM free for the game to use and nothing else taking up space there.
Speaker 1: That would be making your game run slower and a lot of times you could not get a game to run unless you used a boot Disk, so next time I computer I literally had this like library of boot disks tuned for each particular game that I owned.
Speaker 0: Yeah I would literally because computers didn't go to sleep.
Speaker 1: you put that you put the disk in for the game and you turn the computer Ah, this wasn't like Apple to where the game was literally on the disk.
Speaker 1: The game was on your hard drive or on a CD ROM or something or on both?
Speaker 1: but you put the floppy disk in and boot off of it and then it would launch the game from the CD ROM.
Speaker 1: slash hard.
Speaker 1: now
Speaker 0: if You were either way more hardcore or you didn't like you knew how to do this But you didn't understand how to make a boot disk You can hold that five when a computer booted and you get DOS with nothing
Speaker 1: and you could just type in the same command.
Speaker 0: I would type high mem and mem maker But that's the reasons for that or even more and if the game didn't have mouse support you wouldn't type mouse But if it did I type mouse dot exe yeah, which would load a basic mouse driver Like.
Speaker 0: so in the modern era like that does not really exist anymore.
Speaker 1: No Cuz your computer is so powerful and I have 32 gigabytes of RAM and even though that's a ridiculous Well, it's not a ridiculous amount 64 is ridiculous, but 32.
Speaker 1: I've never filled up 32.
Speaker 1: I can launch two virtual machines and a triple-a video game and Windows dude Adobe Premiere On this new computer.
Speaker 0: I was trained to be him.
Speaker 0: I was transcoding all of shoujo kakamei utenna from the blu-ray like ultra rip masters and a couple web browsers and Simultaneously, I was playing overwatch and my computer gave zero fucks except it made the room hotter.
Speaker 0: I was only using 12 gigs of that Ram.
Speaker 1: However, when you do this Ram is not the issue.
Speaker 1: Ram filling up is not the problem on a modern computer.
Speaker 1: the problem on the Computer especially if you don't have a super powerful one is Even if you've got multiple cores very often all these things running simultaneously are competing for CPU cycles.
Speaker 0: Right, you have a browser window.
Speaker 0: We got
Speaker 1: a browser open in the background and let's say it's got Google Hangouts in your email in it occasionally some of your CPU cycles are going to be it's gonna stop rendering your game for like a fraction of a second and Check your email and then start, you know working on your game again.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you'll get interrupts.
Speaker 0: stuff will happen.
Speaker 0: Now if you have a really fast computer, this probably doesn't matter.
Speaker 1: like you Like.
Speaker 0: I have four cores.
Speaker 0: You know what?
Speaker 0: Most people don't buy an i7 don't have four cores with hyper threading, right?
Speaker 1: but so maybe you're in a situation like eSports where it's like you really Cannot even even like the couple frames would be like a disaster.
Speaker 1: or you got a weak computer and you want to get every last Ounce of power out of it and dedicate it fully to the game that you're playing and nothing else.
Speaker 1: So Windows is 10 is adding game mode to which is basically boot disk.
Speaker 1: you boot into game mode and it's like, alright I'm Windows 10.
Speaker 1: I've booted with the bare minimum stuff needed to play your game.
Speaker 1: It's a little bit.
Speaker 1: I got your video driver.
Speaker 1: I got your sound driver.
Speaker 1: I got what.
Speaker 0: it's a little better than.
Speaker 0: it's not actually a boot It's a put the computer in game mode and it Suppresses all the things that could draw resources that are not needed to run the executable that you just ran, right?
Speaker 1: It's like alright, we're not gonna be checking for Windows updates We're not gonna be checking your email We're not gonna be doing nothing.
Speaker 1: you run your steam game and we are going to dedicate all the CPU cycles we can To doing that and nothing else.
Speaker 0: it appears that it On one hand it does all the stuff that an ultra nerd would do to do this on their own like I could Do stuff to a computer.
Speaker 1: I could just open up the task manager and end every single task Like oh, I'm gonna turn off my you know iTunes iPhone support service.
Speaker 0: We're not even just that.
Speaker 0: you can reprioritize threads Nice in them and all that start on nice thing the very nice, you know God does anyone who listens to the Tuesday geek nights know what re nice does me other than you don't listen to geek nights.
Speaker 0: But there's hints that this might also Be able like if you make a game the game might be able to tell.
Speaker 0: like use this as a function To tell it what it needs or doesn't need right?
Speaker 1: The thing is you don't.
Speaker 1: this is not something you want to do without telling the user that it's happening.
Speaker 1: because like you don't just want to say like Program your games to where.
Speaker 1: every time someone starts it your computer enters game mode.
Speaker 1: because then well, okay Someone did it.
Speaker 1: and now there's Spotify.
Speaker 1: music stops playing and they're like what the fuck It's.
Speaker 0: a look at Spotify music Xbox bars like one more thing here.
Speaker 0: Like you're in game mode and you're streaming and whatever Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: It's a lot like your phone like my phone will go into.
Speaker 0: yeah dog.
Speaker 0: Your battery's almost dead.
Speaker 0: So we're gonna turn off like everything we can just to save you.
Speaker 1: now You might think it's like well how much extra performance am I really gonna get out of this?
Speaker 1: Well?
Speaker 1: Consider like the power of like an Xbox one or a ps4 Compared to like a computer with the Nvidia 1080.
Speaker 1: It's not even close.
Speaker 1: The 1080 is like multiple times more powerful like than the console.
Speaker 1: consoles are weak as hell yet They get such great performance out of them.
Speaker 1: Why cuz they're not doing anything fucking else.
Speaker 0: Yep, right?
Speaker 1: Well, so they're only rendering 1080p I'm just saying but I mean even at 1080p right you're good.
Speaker 1: They're getting much more incredible performance than your PC games are per hardware.
Speaker 1: right in terms of efficiency right of You know resulting graphics and frames per amount of hardware, right?
Speaker 1: So you're gonna be able to get drastic support theoretically hypothetically drastic efficiency Performance improvements if you use this game mode, you know, yep I really want to see some benchmarks like how many frames you get in game mode versus not game mode.
Speaker 0: So last and probably least but this was making the rounds - there's this dude you can read about his story.
Speaker 1: You can just like tell him looking at him.
Speaker 1: This guy is a piece of shit.
Speaker 0: He's a professional baby.
Speaker 0: He's a bad person, but so This guy it appears to be the most toxic League of Legends player on earth.
Speaker 1: well, you know on the one hand he doesn't seem to be like actually a Racist or I mean he's about that line.
Speaker 1: He might be right but it's you know, that's not his problem, right?
Speaker 1: So he's not like.
Speaker 1: he's not like an actual KKK member as far as we know.
Speaker 0: He's basically a guy who wants to play this one character and he only plays one character.
Speaker 1: It's not.
Speaker 1: it's not a good character from either from what I hear and he's good at this character Like.
Speaker 0: he's really the only human on earth is good at this character.
Speaker 1: I'd be like if you're playing Street Fighter and you played Dan and you won.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like you only played Dan Yep, you didn't play guile.
Speaker 1: You didn't play ryu.
Speaker 0: You just bought bought bought and played Dan, but you were so good at it You kept winning with it, but imagine if in addition to that Let's say that you could ban characters like you can in MOBAs, right?
Speaker 1: It's a mobile.
Speaker 0: So yeah, you bet you've you draft and ban characters every time you play and let's say the other teams like oh, it's that guy Let's ban Dan.
Speaker 1: Yeah, of course.
Speaker 1: He's only knows how to play Dan and he's super dangerous with it.
Speaker 1: Well ban Dan because we see him on the other team.
Speaker 1: He'll have to use guile or something and then we'll win.
Speaker 0: if he can't play Dan he freaks out and basically flips the table and goes apeshit on everybody ruins the game and Is like does the ultra mega finger up rage?
Speaker 0: quit like he sounds horrible.
Speaker 1: So on the one hand, it's like wow such incredible skills.
Speaker 1: That is like amazing to behold.
Speaker 1: This guy is so good with this shitty character.
Speaker 1: if he just dedicated himself to like the good characters or like learn how to play Multiple characters.
Speaker 1: How good would he be?
Speaker 1: Like holy shit.
Speaker 1: He could be like the god of gods, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, like the Wayne Gretzky of law, but he's not but he is incapable of interacting with other human beings.
Speaker 1: Yeah, he's basically a three-year-old baby.
Speaker 1: Otherwise except for this one skill He is a savant in this one extremely narrow area and otherwise a baby.
Speaker 0: So his behavior was so egregious that riot banned him for life from competitive play, right?
Speaker 1: I mean you couldn't want him on your pro team anyway, even if he's so good at this character because you're never gonna he's never gonna need to play that character and To be a pro player at these games need to be able to fulfill multiple roles, right?
Speaker 1: And that's like having someone on your hockey team who all they can do is shoot.
Speaker 1: They can't play defense They can't do you know for check.
Speaker 1: they can't do anything.
Speaker 1: all they can do is shoot.
Speaker 1: So they just stand in one spot uselessly But if they get the puck they'll shoot and maybe in very likely it's like it's a useless person.
Speaker 1: you don't want them.
Speaker 0: so in response to this the dude keeps making new accounts and Rising through the ranks until they eventually figure out it's him and ban him again.
Speaker 0: And he made a YouTube persona around his toxic behavior.
Speaker 0: So now he's kind of more and he's popping.
Speaker 1: He's popular with the douchebags So hopefully the other people get banned right?
Speaker 1: He's popular with the other douchebags.
Speaker 1: He's like the king of the shitholes Yeah, and all the other shit lords like watching him and are like cheering for him and he gets monies from them.
Speaker 0: So this article on polygon and this is kind of why I bring it up The argument seems to be that because he's so popular and banning him didn't actually reduce the toxicity of the game They should unban him and like try to reform or whatever and I say no I say just keep banning him like whack-a-mole.
Speaker 0: his career will eventually fade.
Speaker 1: This is why I keep saying right and everyone keeps telling me this idea is no good But this idea is going to be tried at some point.
Speaker 0: Well, I see sports get professionalized.
Speaker 0: this will happen in the professional circuits.
Speaker 1: Sure, but once they draw salaries Oh, yeah, then you get suspensions and whatever like $10,000.
Speaker 0: fine Well,
Speaker 1: you know, but what is going to happen is someone needs to make a mode in the game That's serious mode and you join serious mode opt into it and you agree that this is serious mode And you put
Speaker 0: $100 in escrow
Speaker 1: and if you fuck around in serious mode You don't just get banned and then have to make a new account.
Speaker 1: There are real-world consequences for fucking around in serious mode, right?
Speaker 1: You know, you fucked around in serious mode.
Speaker 1: We're gonna take $1,000 from you.
Speaker 1: Oh, you fucked around in serious mode.
Speaker 1: I guess we're gonna you know, give you some other real-world penalty like oh, we're gonna put you in jail.
Speaker 0: Someone shows up your door just smashes your computer.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know, it could be all sorts of yo.
Speaker 1: you use cheat codes All right, I guess you know, we have your house now.
Speaker 1: Good job There will be.
Speaker 1: someone will set up a thing where there are real-world consequences for fucking around and being a shithole and then people like this can actually be punished.
Speaker 0: my buried lead here is that MOBAs just engender the most talks like as much as I run into the occasional toxic person in overwatch or even by God counter-strike.
Speaker 0: MOBAs are unique.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean, well look it's a game where you got all these character.
Speaker 1: The fact that they can ban his character from being played right that that's even a thing creates this situation in the first place.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right You know the fact that there's all these characters to choose from and you can specialize in just one of them.
Speaker 0: streaming community the ladders.
Speaker 0: It's like.
Speaker 0: this article encapsulates a perfect storm of all these factors around MOBAs that lead to the fact that
Speaker 1: Player the fact that he can play solo queuing right which is basically saying I'm all by myself put me on a team Right versus having to have a team at that high level of competition We're like at the highest end of the ladder Like I would make it where it's like.
Speaker 1: oh you're at that top of the ladder.
Speaker 1: You have to be on a team.
Speaker 1: You can't just solo queue up there.
Speaker 1: All right, that wouldn't happen.
Speaker 0: So you can enjoy this fascinating story of this baby guy and Decide what you will.
Speaker 0: but anyway things of the day Lemma smash.
Speaker 0: so Emily and I we were in Australia.
Speaker 0: One of the funny things we encountered was we were hiking and off in this like little side area We see what looks like like.
Speaker 0: it looks like a net like a plastic net some garbage.
Speaker 0: It's like this checkerboard of blue plastic.
Speaker 0: but then as we walk over like ah someone left some garbage.
Speaker 0: here we see this little guy a little bird a bower bird and He starts dancing for us and we realize the bower birds.
Speaker 0: they're a kind of bird where the males will make little houses and Decorate them with colored bits to try to attract mates and the mates Basically evaluate them based on how good their bower bird art is.
Speaker 1: man.
Speaker 1: I'll be so good at being that burden Like.
Speaker 1: I want to be that kind of bird to be like you want blue.
Speaker 1: I'd have all the ladies in my house Hey girl, blue and yellow.
Speaker 1: So apparently they blue is now see this is my trick is I would be all green.
Speaker 1: I'd have like all this green arts everywhere one blue.
Speaker 1: Well blue and yellow is okay because that combines to make green, right?
Speaker 1: I'd have green and blue yellow which is green and if the if the lady bird doesn't want my green arts I'd be like, I don't want you.
Speaker 1: Anyway, you don't like green.
Speaker 1: So I'll wait for the one who likes green to come along.
Speaker 1: So apparently the green is the best.
Speaker 1: there would be plenty.
Speaker 0: the females tend to prefer Blue like a certain shade of blue like if that's arranged symmetrically they like it the most.
Speaker 0: But young male bower birds can't see blue until they get older So they won't know if it's blue or not.
Speaker 0: then they get older and they're like, oh I get it blue.
Speaker 0: We got this and the shade of blue they like happens to be that blue of like water bottle bottle caps.
Speaker 0: So they go like stealing bottle caps to arrange.
Speaker 1: We should take like a whole sack of them and just make a barber like yo dog Got you and go out where the birds are and just like dump them out.
Speaker 0: Well, you're like the wingman.
Speaker 0: Well wingman, you're their wingman.
Speaker 1: I mean people really like, you know human beings.
Speaker 1: They tend to really like that, you know, the gold color, right?
Speaker 1: They're like old.
Speaker 1: it'd be like you're going up to a homeless prison and dump it out a bunch of gold.
Speaker 0: Here's a better skit.
Speaker 0: Here's your comedy skit.
Speaker 0: you go you go out to like the middle of a bar like this would be it like something that like I don't know Upright citizens brigade would do and you go to a bar like you're gonna pick up some ladies and you start dumping blue garbage all Over the ground and spreading it around.
Speaker 0: then you stand there like check it out blue.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but people would have to know about bower birds for that to be funny.
Speaker 0: Well, then you video it and it's funny when it doesn't work and then it does work.
Speaker 1: suddenly Oh, this is bower bird girl comes in.
Speaker 1: Yeah, she's like, hey, she's like forgot an Audubon Society members.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you got any yellow to go with that blue.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah So you got a thing of the day?
Speaker 1: Yeah, so Chad these dudes I assume they're somewhere in the UK because they talk like it and They bikin.
Speaker 1: cuz they're like us they bikin and they're biking somewhere with his farms.
Speaker 1: All right, and farms tend to be surrounded by electric fences to keep the cows in.
Speaker 0: Yep, I as a kid I was I knew what electric fences looked up like and after I encountered if you're not the high-quality Jail kind of electric.
Speaker 0: Yeah, not the Jurassic Park the kind where it's like three shitty wires that are electrified somehow The ones that like ground to the earth, right?
Speaker 1: So they didn't realize it.
Speaker 1: but you know, they.
Speaker 1: they stopped for a bit to have a little rest and One of the guys accidentally unknowingly leaned his bike up against the electric fence Like it is stuck on that fence.
Speaker 1: It's not just leaned on it where he could like kick it and it would fall over and no longer be touching the fence.
Speaker 1: It's got like one wheel on one side of the fence and one wheel on the other side of the fence And the fence is touching the frame and I guess it's conducting.
Speaker 1: They have a jolly old time getting that bike off that fence.
Speaker 0: in this funny I like how they keep thinking like if I just grab it quickly, I'll be fine and then they're not fine.
Speaker 1: I want to know why they didn't just find the owner of the electric fence and tell them to turn it off temporarily or Find the wire power.
Speaker 1: It's not like.
Speaker 1: it's not an electric fence that can keep people out, right?
Speaker 0: It's probably like the humans away.
Speaker 0: It's probably like around the property.
Speaker 1: I'm just saying This is a fence that is easy for humans to get over.
Speaker 1: they get over it.
Speaker 1: No problem whatsoever, right?
Speaker 1: It's not a human proof fence They can find like, you know, they can cut the power to it somehow With what do you carry like wire cutters with you insulated wire cutters.
Speaker 1: I'm just saying there's another bright better solution than what owners Are we like a mile away or not?
Speaker 0: Even home like.
Speaker 1: but the solution they came up with is way more entertaining for us Yep, so especially because short stick still conducts electricity.
Speaker 1: Okay, I Think the power on this fence was turned way up because the electric fences I've encountered using the same design Doesn't the voltage have not been that powerful in my experience.
Speaker 0: Also, I thought when I watched the video I was like yo dog Why you not carbon fiber?
Speaker 0: and then I learned carbon fiber fucking conducts electricity.
Speaker 1: I did not know that carbon fiber is awesome.
Speaker 0: Do not know?
Speaker 0: carbon fiber conducts electricity well enough to where you will get shocked.
Speaker 0: Watch out I even found a YouTube video where someone's like so in case you thought also it's a fat bike.
Speaker 1: fat bikes Usually aren't carbon fiber.
Speaker 1: Yeah I guess they could be.
Speaker 0: there's no reason a lot of mountain bikes because you don't carry about the weight as much as the durability.
Speaker 0: Like.
Speaker 0: I'll use mountain bikes with steel, too.
Speaker 1: Well, if it's it depends if it's uphill or downhill.
Speaker 1: if you're going uphill the weight is the price.
Speaker 0: So I gotta say the last time I went mountain biking.
Speaker 0: I rode this like $15,000 all carbon like crazy-ass mountain bike.
Speaker 0: The more expensive mountain bike is clearly superior.
Speaker 1: Everything is a barrier.
Speaker 1: Holy have you ever seen a more expensive something?
Speaker 0: It's got that mountain bike Wade Similarly to your fancy speed bike.
Speaker 1: My bike isn't that fancy?
Speaker 0: Yeah, but holy shit that mountain bike.
Speaker 0: Anyway in the meta moment we were at magfest We did six panels and I think they're all already on loot at YouTube because magfest just records the panels.
Speaker 0: So I'm gonna find out about that.
Speaker 1: I haven't seen magfest ever upload anything.
Speaker 0: They're all up there.
Speaker 0: Actually, I'm gonna go and find all the video of panels that we didn't video ourselves and just start like linking to them.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we'll see if it's there.
Speaker 0: but we are doing one panel at Pac South which is in like a couple weeks.
Speaker 0: Grind mechanics in games an updated version of our grinding panel on Friday.
Speaker 1: Why do keep doing the same pan?
Speaker 0: I Submitted this panel, but I told them yo if you want a second or third panel from us We will happily do this updated version.
Speaker 1: I thought Pac South was desperate for panels But why will we know one?
Speaker 0: I also submitted what I think is our best new panel the quitting panel Like.
Speaker 0: I really like our quitting panel a lot.
Speaker 0: quitting panels good and we already practiced it at magfest.
Speaker 0: now We got like the hyped up version and I was like, but really this is the one we want to do.
Speaker 0: And they were like, yeah, that's well and good, but we actually want you to do the grind one specifically.
Speaker 0: So we're doing the grind one 4 p.m Friday in the cactus theater.
Speaker 1: wonder if we just only submitted the quitting one where they reject us entirely.
Speaker 0: I only submitted that at first but then I added more and said yo if you need more panels because I know they extended the Panel deadline.
Speaker 0: Yeah, then they're like, oh actually we want that grinding one.
Speaker 0: So and at PAX East we are also doing a panel.
Speaker 0: So I submitted the quitting one to PAX East But I also submitted play dirty to win because we used to have this panel a long time ago called how to win at games And it was good.
Speaker 0: And actually like.
Speaker 1: we just want to do it again, but you can't you do it again.
Speaker 1: So you just made a new name same thing.
Speaker 0: Actually, I'm making all new slides.
Speaker 0: just because modern era like there's more better techniques to win Like it's we can update that panel a lot.
Speaker 0: We did that pen a long time ago.
Speaker 0: Talk about football Yeah talking about basketball in the granny shot.
Speaker 0: So it's an all-new version of that panel and of course they picked that one instead of quitting.
Speaker 0: So that's the one we're doing a paxies.
Speaker 0: Maybe we don't like.
Speaker 1: they don't like quitting I guess.
Speaker 0: Oh, well, at least we did it at magfest.
Speaker 0: So I'll be uploading that as soon as I get a chance to edit it, but and the geek nights book club book is still Rebecca.
Speaker 1: I finished reading it.
Speaker 0: We are doing the show on it this week on Thursday.
Speaker 0: So finish Rebecca so you can listen to the spoiler full Episode about Rebecca that we were doing on Thursday or read it sometime in your life and then come back.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you should read this book.
Speaker 0: It's pretty good.
Speaker 0: And actually it'll probably really color your perception of the movie Rebecca.
Speaker 0: Yep, and if you haven't seen the movie Rebecca At least watch that movie even if you don't read the book I mean, it's one of those cases where it's like, you know, the movie definitely doesn't replace the book.
Speaker 1: It never does but it's one of those ones where it's like.
Speaker 1: Oh, that's actually a good movie and not just some like movie based on the book.
Speaker 1: That's not good Yep, but I have a very just don't try to write your book report from the movie cuz it'll be wrong.
Speaker 0: your opinion of The titular character may be different if you read the book, maybe So Friedman Fries is one of our favorite Ford game designers The guy he made power grid Swoggle thinking something.
Speaker 1: he makes games.
Speaker 1: His name is freedom freeze.
Speaker 1: He's got crazy.
Speaker 1: His hair looks like Jared Sorenson's hair right and his games come in a green box and the names of the games always begin with F and They're usually really good like fresh fish.
Speaker 1: So we played a couple tiny games made by him at magfest Both small card games.
Speaker 1: One of them was Fuji flush and the other one was foppin.
Speaker 0: I didn't play foppin, but I've had it explained to me a bunch of times, but I did play Fuji flush Mmm and both these games don't warrant a super deep review, but there are interesting things to say about them Like, I don't know.
Speaker 0: I've been enjoying these trick-taking ask light Relatively quick games that actually have pretty serious strategy, right?
Speaker 1: It's like, you know in terms it's like these games aren't like so great and so amazing that like in the Puerto Rico T any level but It's like in terms of efficiency like the most strategy and good brain thinking and in the least amount of game Right.
Speaker 1: It's like oh, it's just so like, you know elegant and efficient and it's like you can get a whole ton of good You know satisfying worthwhile Strategic gaming in like 10-15 minutes.
Speaker 0: Yep, but more importantly they're quick to teach.
Speaker 1: They take like a minute I think especially if they already know what trick-taking games.
Speaker 1: All right It's like, you know trick-taking games in general I think because it's like it's all the strategy of like, all right Cards and how do I take or not take tricks?
Speaker 1: Hmm, even hearts is like, oh there's a lot of thinking going on here.
Speaker 1: It's not just some random bullshit Even though there is some very randomness, you know And then you get a real game and then it's over.
Speaker 0: now what I've also found this kind of a side note.
Speaker 0: But this applies to all these games Independent like it's.
Speaker 0: only someone knows the basics of what trick-taking is and we skip that problem.
Speaker 0: It is readily apparent immediately when you teach this game to new people.
Speaker 0: some people just have a knack For understanding the core of what the game is once you explain the rules and some people just don't.
Speaker 0: Yes, and when we taught when we played Fuji flush About two-thirds of our table.
Speaker 0: No one had played the game before except the person who taught us Got it right away and started playing like this really a game like real quick.
Speaker 0: and the other people?
Speaker 0: I don't think they I don't think even by the end of the game.
Speaker 0: They really understood what was happening to them.
Speaker 1: It's not the games fault.
Speaker 1: No, here's the deal with Fuji flush, right?
Speaker 1: You got this hand of cards Right and you are trying.
Speaker 0: they're numbered like what one through twenty four or something, right?
Speaker 1: You're trying to get rid of all your cards.
Speaker 1: You don't want any cards in your hand and then you are the winner, right?
Speaker 1: So what happens is you put a card down on the table and the cards with really high values.
Speaker 1: There's not a lot of them in the deck Like.
Speaker 0: I think there's one of each of the really high value and then there's like two of the middling ones and three Like if you've got like a sixteen, there's probably not another sixteen out there.
Speaker 1: There might be one.
Speaker 1: maybe I don't think there is.
Speaker 1: There's a million - but it's like twos and fours like galore, right?
Speaker 1: So I put down a four.
Speaker 1: I'm starting the game.
Speaker 0: I'm winning two through twenty.
Speaker 0: All right, I'm winning.
Speaker 1: four is the highest number out there.
Speaker 1: right rim plays an eight.
Speaker 1: Oh, I've been beat right?
Speaker 1: We're going around clockwise.
Speaker 0: Yep, all the people who were beat their card goes away.
Speaker 0: That's a draw.
Speaker 1: My four is beat my four goes away and I draw a new card into my hand.
Speaker 1: My hand is not decreased in size Therefore I am NOT any closer to winning.
Speaker 1: I'm trying to get rid of all the cards in my hand So that sucks.
Speaker 0: So then Joey Jojo plays a two.
Speaker 0: that doesn't beat the card I play.
Speaker 1: it doesn't beat rims eight, but it hasn't been beat by someone after him.
Speaker 1: So that two stays.
Speaker 1: now the next person plays another eight.
Speaker 1: So we got rims eight a two which survives and then another eight Would get rid of the time.
Speaker 1: obviously the two is defeated and you know Joey Jojo's two goes to the middle and I draw a new card.
Speaker 1: that eight ain't an eight.
Speaker 1: Oh rims eight wasn't defeated because it's an eight right and he got tied.
Speaker 1: but because now there are two eights on the table.
Speaker 0: They are now both Sixteens and say Scott plays an eight now.
Speaker 1: I got gets back to me.
Speaker 1: It's a four player game and I play an eight 24 that's 24.
Speaker 1: So all the eights are now worth 24, right?
Speaker 1: Someone would need to make us throw those eights away.
Speaker 1: Someone couldn't just play a nine.
Speaker 1: They'd have to play a 25 Right, or they'd have to like have two people play like you.
Speaker 1: have a bunch of people in a row I'll play like nines to get a. you know A bunch of other people have to combine their numbers together somehow to beat our combined force.
Speaker 1: So everyone like eight eight nine Nine Nine.
Speaker 1: Oh the eights got beat, right?
Speaker 1: But if it gets back to your turn and your card in front of you has not been defeated You put your card in the middle and you do not draw a new card and your hand is now smaller.
Speaker 0: if you shared that Card with other people.
Speaker 1: They also put their card in the middle.
Speaker 0: So you basically can form Coalitions with other players to like.
Speaker 0: you'll all rise together.
Speaker 1: but it's not just a vote who wins game because You've got a very limited hand at any given point in time.
Speaker 1: You don't want a big hand you want a small hand.
Speaker 0: You're trying to get your options Keep decreasing as time goes on.
Speaker 1: You can't just say man.
Speaker 1: I can see that rim only has one card left.
Speaker 1: I really need to team up with Chris against him.
Speaker 1: Let's not form any coalitions with rim.
Speaker 1: right now You can do that all really rim places for and what I've got in my hand to four is great.
Speaker 0: Now it is elegant though in that the the bigger your hand still is the easier It is to form coalitions with other people whose hands are bigger.
Speaker 0: So as you are closer to winning the game your options for coalitions decrease.
Speaker 1: I think this is the one flaw in the game.
Speaker 1: Is that at the very end you got one card and on your turn?
Speaker 1: You play it and that's all you can do.
Speaker 1: then when if you get beat you draw a new card and then when it's your Turn you play it and it's pretty much at the end of the game.
Speaker 1: You're not making decisions anymore.
Speaker 1: You're just playing the card that you draw and hoping that it wins out at some point before someone else empties.
Speaker 0: Reducing that ability.
Speaker 0: that coalition ability of the leading players is a very good mechanic.
Speaker 0: It actually it balances the game out like very well.
Speaker 0: Yeah If someone gets a little head with luck They got to be real skilled or real lucky to keep getting ahead.
Speaker 0: Everyone else can catch up by going like five five five five and just blow past.
Speaker 1: I think the way to make this game absolutely perfect and it may require adding some more cards to the game.
Speaker 1: yeah, but basically make everyone's starting hand three cards bigger and Have someone win if they get down to three.
Speaker 1: if they get to three or maybe below three Yeah, as soon as they get to two cards left they win immediately, right?
Speaker 1: That way that way and at the end of the game You're still making decisions.
Speaker 1: Right, and it's not just down to a hundred percent luck at the end where you only have like one or two cards But you still have to win the same number the game would still be just as long.
Speaker 1: You start to win the same number of times get rid of the same number of cards But you never reach a part of the game where it's just draw play drop.
Speaker 0: That that small rule change.
Speaker 0: We've not play tested this, but I think that small rule change.
Speaker 1: You'd have to rebuild the deck is you need more cards?
Speaker 0: Yeah, maybe we have to test.
Speaker 0: maybe you might just have to reduce the max.
Speaker 0: It takes up to eight players, which is also actually like right.
Speaker 1: Oh, you could just.
Speaker 1: yeah, if you reduce the players count to five then you can give everyone three more cards without any problem.
Speaker 0: right, yep, but I'm confident that a small rule change like that takes this game from good to great and It'd be really interesting to try it and see if our hypothesis is correct.
Speaker 0: Cuz I really the why play this game once I really enjoyed that one play it become high level.
Speaker 0: You can see there is a lot of high level interaction.
Speaker 0: for how short this game, right?
Speaker 1: You're like how many?
Speaker 1: like.
Speaker 1: rim plays an eight and I say I got eight in my hand and it's like well Do I want to help?
Speaker 1: but you might can also just play a nine and shut you down.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right.
Speaker 1: then you decide like say you say oh no rim has a ton of cards in his hand.
Speaker 1: I'm beating him.
Speaker 0: Let's go in on the eights.
Speaker 0: and then I think oh shit I don't want to go out with Scott because that doesn't get me closer to winning.
Speaker 1: There's nothing you can do about it.
Speaker 1: You already played.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Oh, by the way, it's not just eights that form coalitions, right?
Speaker 1: It could be.
Speaker 1: we kept using that as the example.
Speaker 1: But it could be like there are times where someone played like 11 and someone else is like, oh, yeah 11 and there's 22 and then another person.
Speaker 1: It's like that.
Speaker 0: shit happens and you'll see sometimes like someone plays like a four or a five and then someone's like two And then two and then two and then two and then the four gets knocked out and shit happens.
Speaker 0: It's awesome.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the low numbers can beat the high numbers.
Speaker 1: it happens.
Speaker 0: apparently this game re implements another older game called drop pelt wound drifak Great name designer Friedman fries.
Speaker 0: All right, so I guess he remade the game.
Speaker 0: Okay, this original game had cards number two through 15 But was otherwise mostly.
Speaker 1: how old is this guy now?
Speaker 1: Cuz I remember him looking pretty young in the 10-15 years.
Speaker 0: I think he's been making games forever.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean he made power grid.
Speaker 1: He doesn't have to do anything else.
Speaker 0: how much money made from drop felt and drifak was anonymously sent to various people in March of 2016?
Speaker 0: the rules or the box gave no hint to the identity of the designer in July of the 2016 Friedman freeze was revealed to be the designer.
Speaker 0: So he anonymously sent this game out to get it play tested I assume and then reimplemented it based on that feedback as Fuji flush.
Speaker 0: Wow, he released it as a D&D game as opposed to an F&F game.
Speaker 1: Well, he had to hide.
Speaker 0: I wonder if there's other D&D games released anonymously.
Speaker 0: They're actually him.
Speaker 1: go for it.
Speaker 0: So this games if you like if you want a game like six nymphs or Yet or even wizard like this is just one of those games.
Speaker 1: The thing with I was gonna say like wizard is like the best still but wizard takes a while.
Speaker 1: You got a lot of hands.
Speaker 1: You got to play through all these other games that you know.
Speaker 1: The six are these smaller card games?
Speaker 1: Get you almost all the fun of the wizard and a lot less time and a lot less space.
Speaker 0: even six nymphs Like requires many plays sure to finish.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: This is just like BAM and it's done.
Speaker 0: Yep So the other game which I did not play but I need to know the rules Play to know it is foppin so foppin.
Speaker 1: I guess our friends couldn't get a real copy But their friend was a graphic designer and made a Steven Universe themed copy.
Speaker 1: that looked like a professional game.
Speaker 0: Oh, what Claude?
Speaker 1: Oh that yeah, it was Claude.
Speaker 1: That's what it was called.
Speaker 1: So and that game it was basically the same exact game only it looked like Steven Universe and it looked like someone Professionally made this.
Speaker 1: that was unreal cards.
Speaker 1: It was you know, but it was the same game as foppin.
Speaker 0: Oh, the original art is real good though, too.
Speaker 1: Sure.
Speaker 1: Why wouldn't it be?
Speaker 1: So here's the deal with foppin.
Speaker 1: you got four different suits of cards but one of the suits as like a ton of cards in it and the Second one is less cards.
Speaker 1: The third one is even less cards and the fourth one is like a really weak suit.
Speaker 1: it doesn't have a lot of cards at all and it's trick-taking.
Speaker 1: so you play a card and everyone has to follow suit and Someone wins the trick by having the highest card and then you know, they take the lead and so on and so forth.
Speaker 1: It's a trick-taking game.
Speaker 1: however The goal of this trick-taking game is not to win all the tricks.
Speaker 1: right.
Speaker 1: that is something you can do.
Speaker 1: That would be beneficial for you, but it is not necessary.
Speaker 1: It is the game about not being in last Right.
Speaker 1: So what happens is you play the trick and if you have the weakest card in the trick You are now the Claude and on the next hand you don't play.
Speaker 1: you just sit there and watch everyone else play that trick.
Speaker 1: So on the first trick of the game everyone plays but from then on Someone's always sitting out and it's never the same person twice in a row because they were the Claude last hand.
Speaker 1: So then I can't be the Claude this hand, right?
Speaker 1: And when you're the Claude you don't play a card because you're sitting out.
Speaker 1: But that sucks because you win the game when you get rid of your last card which means you play your last card in a trick and you don't come in last place.
Speaker 1: and That's how that goes.
Speaker 0: It's a clever mechanic because think it think about it.
Speaker 0: Usually it's like in hearts.
Speaker 0: It's Somebody wins the trick and may get fucked because there might be a bunch of hearts in the trick.
Speaker 0: This game is somebody loses the trick badly.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: so That's pretty much all it comes down to this.
Speaker 1: is the extra rules right?
Speaker 1: if let's say someone can't follow suit?
Speaker 1: Obviously, you know matter how high the number on their card is they're losing.
Speaker 1: But if two people or more can't follow suit whoever's got the lower number and the weaker suit is the person who is the Claude.
Speaker 1: Right, so it's like, you know playing a higher number when you can't follow suit is still better cuz at least.
Speaker 1: hey I'm not gonna you know, hopefully I'll beat someone else who can't follow suit also at the end of the hand, right?
Speaker 1: Usually people don't have positive scores in this game.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if you and and You have gotten rid of all your cards you get ten points.
Speaker 1: If you have any cards in your hand those cards become negative points.
Speaker 1: So the bigger the numbers are on the cards that are still in your hand the more points you lose.
Speaker 1: you want to get rid Of your big numbered cards.
Speaker 1: if you got like a 15 in your hand and the hand is over.
Speaker 1: That's negative 15.
Speaker 1: That sucks ass.
Speaker 1: you want to end the hand with like a negative 2 in your hand.
Speaker 1: That'd be way better.
Speaker 1: Also in the deck are four ones.
Speaker 1: The ones are weak.
Speaker 1: Obviously, it's hard to win a trick with them, right?
Speaker 1: It's hard to avoid if you play them.
Speaker 1: It's hard to not be Claude because they're number one the weakest number, but they follow suit no matter what?
Speaker 1: So if everyone can follow suit and you can except for one other person and they play some other suit.
Speaker 1: That's off suit and you play your one you beat them and you can.
Speaker 1: yeah I couldn't follow suit but I had my one and I got.
Speaker 1: I avoided being Claude one extra time.
Speaker 1: Yeah There's one other thing in this game.
Speaker 1: when the hand starts Everyone looking at their starting hand right has to bet.
Speaker 1: you either say I'm going to get rid of all my cards or I'm Not going to get rid of all my car.
Speaker 1: If you say you're not going to you play just you just play.
Speaker 1: but if you say I can do it, I'm going to get rid of all my cards with this hand and You succeed.
Speaker 1: instead of getting 10 points you get 20 points.
Speaker 1: That's big.
Speaker 1: That's real big.
Speaker 0: That's a lot like Euchre like go it alone.
Speaker 0: I'm going alone double my score right?
Speaker 1: But if you say you can do it and you can't your negative is doubled.
Speaker 1: So if you got like a 15 in your hand, it's like negative 30.
Speaker 1: Ah Oh, you went alone.
Speaker 0: You got youked, right?
Speaker 1: So when I played this it was funny Like there was a hand where I bet and I came close, but I didn't make it so like negative five or something.
Speaker 1: It was.
Speaker 1: it was you know, it was negative six something like that, right?
Speaker 1: Cuz I had like.
Speaker 1: I'd like a three left.
Speaker 1: It was grid the next time like I'm not betting and then I got rid of all.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and then I like.
Speaker 1: it was the first three hands of the stupid game and Every single hand I bet the opposite of what I should have bet and I'm just like ah if I just bet differently I'd be at like plus 30 right now, but instead of a negative 10
Speaker 0: Yeah,
Speaker 1: I played it.
Speaker 1: I played it great, but I bet wrong.
Speaker 1: So the betting is huge and That's this game.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's not as short as Fuji flush because you got to play the multiple hands.
Speaker 0: There's more tricky.
Speaker 1: You're dealing out the whole deck to everyone or you didn't got a lot of cards to everyone right and you're playing all of them Right, you know so it but it's not like wizard.
Speaker 1: we have to do that multiple times.
Speaker 1: So it's sort of this in-between length game.
Speaker 1: But it's also really interesting like trying to just not be last.
Speaker 1: if you just come in second on every trick It's like it's super great.
Speaker 1: Another thing that can happen a lot is because there's different numbers of the different suits.
Speaker 1: It's like this we were playing in a Steven Universe version, right?
Speaker 1: So Stevens were the weakest suit.
Speaker 1: Yeah, of course, there were not a lot of Steven cards in the deck period And there was one hand where I had a ton of Stevens, which is really bad because no one else is gonna lead Stevens.
Speaker 1: So if I try to I'm eventually gonna be forced to play them and they're gonna lose every time and I'll keep being the Claude.
Speaker 0: And that's like when you're stuck leading the hearts at the end of a game of hearts and nobody else is gonna top you.
Speaker 1: However What happens if say I play I didn't I wasn't a hundred percent Stevens in my hand, right?
Speaker 1: I win.
Speaker 1: just one trick.
Speaker 1: gotta come in first.
Speaker 1: So now I'm leading.
Speaker 1: I Play a Steven and no one can follow Stevens.
Speaker 1: I just play another Steven and another Steven and another Steve.
Speaker 1: I just I'm keep winning the tricks first place.
Speaker 1: I'm Setting the suit at Steven every single trick Constantly.
Speaker 1: no one can follow suit.
Speaker 1: the Claude keeps moving around between the other players as they dump their other Cards and suddenly they see me keep doing this and they don't have Stevens.
Speaker 1: They had to keep playing like they want to play their high point cards from the other suits.
Speaker 1: Right because then if they lose this trick, but that just feeds you but that if they dump those cards That means when I get to when I'm out of Stevens and I have to play something else my something else's Mar probably the strongest cards left.
Speaker 1: because they wanted to avoid having low scores.
Speaker 1: they use those strong cards and lost them.
Speaker 1: Right, but maybe they save them and then if they end the gate the hand with those still in hand.
Speaker 1: That's big negative, right?
Speaker 1: And so is this really great balancing act that goes on where you got to really count cards?
Speaker 1: Think about what's in other people's hands, you know And adding a theme to it because you can't get the original version.
Speaker 1: I guess you know, it would be probably a little bit more fun If I watched more episodes of Steven Universe than like three you should it's.
Speaker 0: uh, it's escalated quite a bit since you stopped watching.
Speaker 1: Why I got me, you know My plan right now is wait for adventure time to end Like in a year or six months or whenever.
Speaker 1: watch all that now and then I'll move on.
Speaker 0: Well, dr.
Speaker 0: Me ninja just ended like for real so you can catch up on that, too.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna.
Speaker 1: I'm working on my.
Speaker 1: basically I've been because of technological issues.
Speaker 1: I failed to read webcomics for like a year and I'm gonna rectify that real soon.
Speaker 0: Yeah Luckily you're at a point where multiple webcomics that are long-running are getting their ends or big stopping points So you can just catch up to those points.
Speaker 1: Yeah in like binges It's more about figuring out where I left off and getting everything sorted out.
Speaker 0: Yep, and actually dr Me ninja is kind of complex in terms of like.
Speaker 0: even saying who was he fighting does not necessarily tell us where you were.
Speaker 1: You know King radical.
Speaker 0: Yeah, King radical pretty much all the way to the end.
Speaker 0: King radical hundred years.
Speaker 0: King radical calm, yeah.
Speaker 0: Was he up to something?
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: It was yes.
Speaker 0: He was up to something.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 1: That's what dr.
Speaker 1: Me ninja is about.
Speaker 1: It's about King radical being up to something.
Speaker 0: He was up to something, you know This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Speaker 1: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 0: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 1: But unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night.
Speaker 0: And your picture on.
Speaker 0: patrons for this.
Speaker 0: observe geek nights in order of the amount of money we give us on a continuing basis.
Speaker 0: are Alan Joyce Rebecca done the case?
Speaker 0: Brando Heidi McNichol Amanda Duchette?
Speaker 0: construction noises.
Speaker 0: I can say my state II calm William Isenbroughs Jeremy minor Chris Reimer and Thomas on Christian coons.
Speaker 0: word order doesn't matter.
Speaker 0: It's only important that the first and last sure in but horrible rare Laval James David White Rochelle, Monta known as Superboy nah, nah, doo doo dee doo doo Aaron series Brian Fisher sailor Vista forgot to lower my pledge.
Speaker 0: So another month to the rim remote registered trademark exclamation point.
Speaker 0: Matthew Smith Don Schleich Sure, Thomas and Jojo Joestar Tyler Ella Shawn Yeager Sam quarter Clinton Walton run from New Zealand.
Speaker 0: Brian parent drew open letter.
Speaker 0: Brian, Sir Andy Sidroni cure and if redacted Chris midkiff Chris Knox Daniel Redmond Shawn Klein Chris Reimer and Thomas on.
Speaker 0: We're back at least for a while For anyone who listen to the end.
Speaker 0: We actually recorded like the next four episodes including this one all on one Monday afternoon.
Speaker 0: and now I leave you with something odd.