Speaker 0: So it's been a little while since we've done a roomly reviews, huh?
Speaker 1: And also Scott doesn't watch shows as far as I can tell.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Oh, well, he watches anime.
Speaker 0: Apparently though do anime stuff.
Speaker 0: and also you don't read as many comics cuz there's been comics.
Speaker 0: I've been like room.
Speaker 1: You gotta read this Watching anime reading books playing overwatch.
Speaker 0: Yeah Overwatch Like overwatch, I think overwatch.
Speaker 0: It was funny.
Speaker 0: I was I went and saw the Guardians of the Galaxy or not?
Speaker 0: Guardians of the Galaxy Thor Ragnarok Very similar vibe.
Speaker 0: It was one of the crazy space nonsense ones and They played like as a trailer before the movie a commercial for overwatch And I don't know all the cinematics and everything.
Speaker 0: I just like the feel of it.
Speaker 0: I mean blizzard doesn't half-ass things I always really get like hype even though I don't really play the game and like the times I played it I'm really really bad at it, but it's like Play.
Speaker 0: I mean like I own it.
Speaker 0: so it's like why not?
Speaker 0: but even if I just do like the AI mode I could always just like go and zip around his tracer fun against bots.
Speaker 1: But anyway, but in particular Scott won't watch anything that has live-action Actors.
Speaker 1: he'd a TV for.
Speaker 0: no, that's a lie because he will watch Korean shows You he doesn't so much even like the dramas.
Speaker 0: he likes the variety stuff, but he will watch Asian television.
Speaker 0: But he won't watch domestic television, but he won't watch television.
Speaker 1: That is like serial plots anymore.
Speaker 0: So much.
Speaker 0: I mean he was never super big on that as far as I can tell.
Speaker 0: he never really like.
Speaker 0: he always hated Star Trek Yeah, and he wasn't a fan of Firefly.
Speaker 0: He was like cuz.
Speaker 0: we were all like yeah Firefly like ten years ago, and he was like boo.
Speaker 0: He also only ever saw like one episode Yeah but he never has struck me as somebody who would get really into a TV show which is kind of weird.
Speaker 0: because I think with the way the markets moving like movies and television are really converging like the budgets are getting higher on TV and Because most people consume them in a binge watching format because of Netflix and Hulu and all the streaming services Their plots are getting more contiguous.
Speaker 0: They're not as episodic anymore And even though they'll often have plot arcs per episode.
Speaker 0: They have like a general season-wide Narrative.
Speaker 0: so I think I think it's kind of like you're you're missing out a bit if you don't watch any television.
Speaker 0: and What are the things.
Speaker 0: you want to hear something weird that I noticed.
Speaker 0: so I was walking down.
Speaker 0: I mean you will say I don't see.
Speaker 0: In the subway at Grand Central and one thing I noticed almost every ad was for a TV show.
Speaker 0: Almost none of them were on a network.
Speaker 0: They were all Hulu Amazon Prime Netflix.
Speaker 1: It also makes sense because the main things that get advertised Well the main thing that gets advertised in America is cars, and you can't really sell cars to people who are in Manhattan in the city.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so like you know those those things.
Speaker 0: They'll have Broadway shows.
Speaker 0: They'll have Generally their entertainment billboards like in that corridor going from the seven train to the Metro North and stuff like that.
Speaker 0: You you have this blank look on your face like I don't see it.
Speaker 0: No.
Speaker 1: I just don't notice.
Speaker 1: I'm like I just ignore them and avoid them.
Speaker 1: I just don't care.
Speaker 1: like I'll see I'll see a poster and say oh That's there's some TV show, but I literally don't even look at the name of it.
Speaker 0: anyway now.
Speaker 1: You can really tell the streaming Revolution has has changed the landscape of television well to the point that I think as people like Netflix start making these shows They're gonna push movies off of these streaming platform Which kind of sucks.
Speaker 1: cuz I think it's pretty much.
Speaker 1: no I'd say 90% of the time if I type the name of a movie into Netflix.
Speaker 1: It's not there.
Speaker 0: well That's that's the way their business model is moving.
Speaker 0: They they actually said they're gonna dump a ton of money into original content Which for me with Netflix is kind of hit or miss.
Speaker 0: some of the things are amazing and some of the things seem like really dumb.
Speaker 0: But yeah like hardly any of the like more obscure foreign films or the big blockbuster films Don't end up on Netflix anymore.
Speaker 0: They're definitely moving more toward.
Speaker 0: we'll have to pay like three bucks to rent a movie on Amazon except They're not.
Speaker 1: they're moving even further into like.
Speaker 1: everyone seems to want to have their own service of check out our movies Like the Disney one, which I'm probably gonna pay for.
Speaker 1: I feel like we should just pirate them.
Speaker 0: It just well, I mean, that's what the core mean spikes a good reason to do a lot of things.
Speaker 0: The cord cutters were just like.
Speaker 0: well, you know all this if you pay for all the streaming services It's more expensive and I feel like it's starting to move that way.
Speaker 0: Like everybody has original content and like Oh, well, if you want Game of Thrones, you got to do HBO.
Speaker 1: Luckily I really fell off the boat on Game of Thrones and I don't feel like I'll ever watch any more of it.
Speaker 0: Anyway, that's providing a little bit of context for Stranger Things, which is a Netflix original and I thought it was a really really good Netflix.
Speaker 1: Yeah, no spoilers till those will spoil a little bit at the end.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if you grew up in the 80s in America, the show is already like a hundred percent up your alley problem.
Speaker 0: so I was really late to the boat on this one.
Speaker 0: like a lot of my friends were like watching this and drawn fanart and Twitter was all like nuts about this show last year and I remember my co-workers I think most of them had seen it and they were having like lunch conversations about it.
Speaker 1: I think pretty much everyone I know except my mom who really should see it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I had already seen it.
Speaker 0: Yeah like a lot of our buddies had seen it and so I waited a really long time to see it partly because I Was like they were like, yeah, it's disturbing or it's scary and I you know, I'm an anxious person.
Speaker 0: I tend not to gravitate towards Stressful like I've got to be in the right mood to watch stressful television.
Speaker 0: But like especially horror like horror is incredibly hit or miss for me and you love horror movies But with me it's like some horror movies I love like.
Speaker 0: I really like to get out and I really like.
Speaker 0: sometimes I like comedy horror.
Speaker 0: I really like Japanese Like the ones that have like a ghost and it's all eerie, you know, it's like supernatural stuff.
Speaker 0: But like I was kind of like and not super into horror.
Speaker 1: But I was just more simply as much as the show looked like it was Literally everything that I would reference know about care about.
Speaker 1: remember from my childhood The people who were telling me to watch this have also told me to watch a ton of other Similar shows or shows on like Netflix or whatever That were not good or that I didn't care about and I questioned a lot of their tastes.
Speaker 1: I wasn't.
Speaker 1: it's very.
Speaker 1: it takes a lot to get me to actually watch a show when it comes out.
Speaker 0: Yeah, even if people are raving about it I mean like Jessica Jones was one that our friends were like.
Speaker 0: Oh, you should watch this and we ended up seeing it and it was pretty good.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but um this one the.
Speaker 0: the thing that made me actually decide to watch it was one.
Speaker 0: It was October You know, it was like the season for spooky things and I was like I'm in the mood for spooky you know doesn't come around a lot, but I was in the mood for spooky and Everybody was saying it's got like an early 80s Stephen King vibe and it's very like very nostalgic.
Speaker 0: and I was like, well, maybe it's not Exactly to my taste But I think rim will love the heck out of it.
Speaker 0: like all the adjectives people were using to describe the show I was like, this is a show for rim.
Speaker 0: And so that's why I was like, oh, let's let's watch it.
Speaker 0: And so and then like the first scene it's a bunch of like twelve-year-old kids in a basement playing D&D.
Speaker 1: Is that the kids and it's so rare to see this actually sound and act The way?
Speaker 1: I remember sounding and acting when I was a teenager like a young teenager a tween.
Speaker 1: it's like they're
Speaker 0: kind of goofy and they cuss but they don't cuss like fluidly all the time or like the cusses they have are like Not super Severe, like they'll be like son of a bitch Something and that's like, you know, very emphatic,
Speaker 1: but it's got the right level of like the bigger dependence that kids.
Speaker 1: yeah, the error they're setting is like a Little bit before the error when I had sort of full independence of a tween.
Speaker 1: Yeah But most of the aesthetic and most of kind of what we were up to was pretty much the same like tooling around on Bikes and coming home late and like parents actually kind of just letting you go do your thing.
Speaker 1: and we didn't really have like.
Speaker 1: we had video games, but we didn't have like Internet.
Speaker 1: yet the kids having the CV radios.
Speaker 1: Yeah was like a hundred percent.
Speaker 1: I literally that was me as a kid.
Speaker 1: We had the CV radios.
Speaker 0: Didn't you go?
Speaker 0: wasn't there a thing where you'd go on the roof of your house?
Speaker 0: So was that a cordless phone?
Speaker 1: Oh, that was just a cordless.
Speaker 0: Yeah But I remember with with me it was a little different because I don't remember the 80s as well.
Speaker 0: I was not like the show is set Pretty much around when I was born but like a lot of things ring very true like the group of kids who are like we're gonna go on our bikes and we're gonna like investigate this thing and like the When I was like 13 goofing around with my friends and like the graveyard and stuff like that that it was across the street from my house was like a thing and I don't know it felt There's a certain Element to fiction where may not be true but aspects of it make you feel like it's true even even if like Crazy stuff is happening.
Speaker 0: You're like, yeah kids are kind of like that and they bicker like that.
Speaker 0: They're also really loyal like that.
Speaker 1: But they also like if the show were set where they think these things are going on.
Speaker 1: But there isn't actually a supernatural mystery.
Speaker 1: They act the way.
Speaker 1: kids that age tend to act like they want to solve mysteries and have the kinds of adventures They remember from like their stories and things they saw on TV or whatever.
Speaker 1: and kids do that Like oh, we'll investigate the thing.
Speaker 1: like our friend disappeared and all the adults know that he ran away or drowned or something.
Speaker 1: But the kids like they believe something different happened and they try to figure it out except there actually is a monster.
Speaker 0: Yeah, this yeah.
Speaker 0: Oh and I gotta say one of the things I really liked about this show is that one People people are both skeptical, but they'll also be pragmatic about believing and sharing information.
Speaker 0: Yeah, most you know Talk to each other and you know, you'd think it would be very easy to make this the kind of show where the kids Know there's something creepy going on But no one believes them and they become kind of like this Cassandra like saying doom and all the adults are like, don't worry It's just a bad dream kind of thing this one the adults that are affected by it.
Speaker 0: They're like, no, there's something weird going on and we're gonna get to the bottom of this, too.
Speaker 1: But they they tackle it in an adult way as opposed to a kid way But to in an adult way with the adults and kids and everyone and this is something at any time Immediately like a show or a movie.
Speaker 1: does this?
Speaker 1: it just?
Speaker 1: it reeks of crappy writing from the 70s and earlier When the whole plot is just oh, there's a misunderstanding or oh no one listen to each other.
Speaker 1: Pretty much everyone based on the every character based on the information They have does an appropriate thing at basically all moments.
Speaker 1: so like Anytime a new piece like the cop or a mom figures something out or learn something or witnesses something They act in an intelligent way.
Speaker 0: So much an intelligent way cuz.
Speaker 0: like with with Will's mom she's like freaking out and she seems really emotionally unstable, but like she's reacting in an Expected way like an understandable way, like, you know why she's acting like that.
Speaker 1: But it's also intelligent because part of the way she's reacting that way is as she expresses herself that no one would believe her Like she's the thing she's seeing and experiencing.
Speaker 1: literally no one would believe her even if she told them Yeah, and she would just sound crazy.
Speaker 0: So she's sort of in this alone Whereas like her son right her older her older son.
Speaker 0: He sees her acting crazy and he acts.
Speaker 0: he's like trying to calm her down trying to Like inject some reality into her world, even though he's wrong, you know, it is actually this nonsense that's going on.
Speaker 0: he is like the smart rational thing to do if my mom is having a nervous breakdown is Be real with her.
Speaker 0: try to calm her down try to get her to stop putting nonsense around the House.
Speaker 0: That was really good.
Speaker 0: that was one of those things where I'm like.
Speaker 0: Oh, that's such a great.
Speaker 1: the show first came out.
Speaker 1: a bunch of people posted this picture and they were like This is why this show is good and it was just a bunch of Christmas lights with like letters painted next to them on the wall.
Speaker 0: No, that was brilliant.
Speaker 0: It was like seeing something and coming up with like a clever Solution was is always one of the things that I love in fiction Like when somebody has a problem and they solve it in a really ingenious way.
Speaker 0: I was like, that's so smart, you know, and it's just like most I hope I do.
Speaker 1: there's so many moments where you could project based on what just happened in a typical sort of Pre-modern era show where from that point the characters would do something stupid or like not tell anyone.
Speaker 1: but in this information gets shared rapidly among characters and They react appropriately and it sounds simple, but that makes this show Like when some characters go and buy a bunch of bear trap.
Speaker 1: That was great And the gun and everything and every point where the plot could veer back into that misunderstanding trope.
Speaker 1: It basically takes a hard 180 away from that back to based on information characters act in a reasonable manner.
Speaker 0: Well, actually that's the thing that I think Sets it apart from something that I dislike about a lot of horror movies.
Speaker 0: in it in many horror movies.
Speaker 0: I've seen the characters React like they freak out and like they'll run away into the woods screaming Oh, no, there's a monster and that you're like don't go in there.
Speaker 0: Don't get the.
Speaker 0: that's a really bad idea.
Speaker 0: but like it's like a horror movie where everyone reacts in a fairly Understandable and also usually pretty intelligent manner.
Speaker 1: but then you get this interesting situation where you see characters Acting or doing something and you know, like why they're acting that way But the other characters around them don't know and bit by bit everyone who starts to figure out what's going on Seems pretty objectively crazy.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if you were a bystander like watching Will's mom you'd be like, yep She's losing it.
Speaker 0: She's having a nervous breakdown.
Speaker 0: poor poor lady lost her son.
Speaker 0: That's so sad, you know, and So I I think that's what really kind of set it apart.
Speaker 0: for me is that I like the characters.
Speaker 0: I think in general the characters are pretty appealing.
Speaker 0: not necessarily cuz they're Perfect all the time like.
Speaker 0: sometimes they can be very frustrating but like because they're twins.
Speaker 1: That's the by definition.
Speaker 0: how many times to the adults and the teenagers and stuff too.
Speaker 0: like all of them I think they make bad decisions and don't always Aren't always like The the nicest or the best.
Speaker 0: but they're like, they're good.
Speaker 1: They're good characters Yeah, but also the show moves pretty quickly Like.
Speaker 1: it's the kind of show that could meander forever around this vague mystery.
Speaker 1: and I think at least something Material is revealed in every single episode and I like that too that it doesn't have a single antagonist.
Speaker 0: there's like there's The monster stuff that's happening like the horror movie stuff that's happening.
Speaker 1: There's the lab stuff.
Speaker 0: There's like government conspiracy stuff, so it's.
Speaker 0: it's like the characters aren't just getting it from one angle.
Speaker 0: It's not just like there's a monster on the loose.
Speaker 0: There's like weird supernatural stuff, but there's also conspiracy government stuff and those two things combined lead to double danger in a lot of cases.
Speaker 0: and So so who is your favorite character?
Speaker 1: It's hard to say they're pretty great.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean the kids are good.
Speaker 1: Yeah both in terms of acting and as characters I just really like them.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean like I I think that Who's the who's the main kid with the shaggy hair?
Speaker 0: Finn Wolfhard is the guy who plays it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I already forget after names He's the freaking main character Mike Mike.
Speaker 0: Mike, I really do like Mike.
Speaker 0: I thought he was he was good.
Speaker 0: Um, I know that's like kind of boring to just pick who's What amounts to the central character, but and I like to love it a lot.
Speaker 0: I like that.
Speaker 0: she was kind of petulant a lot of times like she was.
Speaker 0: She was not just like shell-shocked because she was an experimental subject.
Speaker 0: She was also kind of.
Speaker 0: Sometimes if she didn't want to do something she'd just be like no and just be like kind of.
Speaker 1: Well, kind of like how the kids look at mad and punch each other except she'll do a crazy dangerous psychic.
Speaker 0: She'll like, you know slam the door with her mind and you know, she she doesn't really have any social skills.
Speaker 0: But she'll.
Speaker 0: she'll be scared.
Speaker 0: and because she'll she's scared She'll do things that aren't necessarily helpful, but she'll also be like no.
Speaker 0: I want my way kind of almost like she acts younger.
Speaker 0: She has both younger and older than she actually is because of her isolation.
Speaker 0: So I I liked her.
Speaker 0: I felt really bad for like the scenes where you see her past stuff.
Speaker 1: Yeah So but also the the very specific environmental storytelling of her name is 11.
Speaker 1: Yeah, very clearly Probably at least 10 more.
Speaker 1: I would assume that there's also a 12 and that'll be a big part of the end.
Speaker 0: But yeah, basically we've.
Speaker 0: we've only just started the second season.
Speaker 1: So this is a review of the first season and Absolutely going for a while because the one thing much like Cowboy bebop and other great shows that I've liked over the years.
Speaker 1: It has this sort of Overarching meta plot but season one pretty much focuses on just the disappearance of Will Byers.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like how where?
Speaker 1: what happened to him?
Speaker 1: What's what's the deal with him?
Speaker 1: Yeah, and it resolves Pretty interestingly well in a way that makes sense in the broader picture of the story because the story has to continue in this town with These people and it does a pretty clever job of making sure that could continue.
Speaker 0: I feel like it's one of those things where it it opens a bunch of questions and it doesn't necessarily answer all the questions.
Speaker 0: But it like it definitely leaves a lot of fodder for coming seasons.
Speaker 0: But in terms of the main mystery like it solves the plot, you know, you're like, okay How are they gonna get this kid back?
Speaker 0: And that's basically what the entire thing is about.
Speaker 0: so So do you want to do spoiler line and like talk about specific scenes?
Speaker 1: Yeah, I guess we'll just assume that you guys saw it.
Speaker 1: So spoilers past this point.
Speaker 1: if you haven't seen it because it's a horror mystery Probably want to see it rather than getting stuff spoiled.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it does use a good mix of horror and mystery tropes Both from modern shows and from media of that era like Stephen King.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so whether or not certain characters survive Certain jump scares and things are actually it's pretty good to go in unknowing like you would when you were a kid.
Speaker 0: People do get killed too.
Speaker 0: Like some people.
Speaker 1: actually there's a really high body count.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like a lot of people get and like some of them some of them are just like side characters but a lot of times it's very like it sucks because they're just Random bystanders or nice people like like the the guy who helps 11.
Speaker 0: You're just like.
Speaker 1: no.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think 11 kills more people than anything else though.
Speaker 0: No, she's like she is the most dangerous.
Speaker 0: She's like a weapon.
Speaker 1: So yeah spoilers ahead.
Speaker 1: Yes It was interesting that the way Ellis gave to she just fucking well first Murdered those other guys instead of murdering the cat and then when she escaped and then all the scenes again.
Speaker 1: She is perfectly willing to just kill people directly with her mind and doesn't even appear to feel bad about it.
Speaker 0: But that's what I was saying where you know, I said she laughs.
Speaker 1: he murders all those FBI agents or whatever Like like.
Speaker 0: they just fall over convulsing with blood coming out of their eyes and stuff like that and like she snapped people's necks And like she causes a heck ton of car accidents and stuff.
Speaker 0: She but that's what I'm saying where it's like she seems both younger and older than she is but I think part of the thing that makes her seem like a little kid is because like her moral Compass isn't necessarily the most developed.
Speaker 0: like she she's very.
Speaker 0: her focus is very narrow.
Speaker 0: She will Really?
Speaker 0: Try hard to protect the people who are friends like she has a very narrow Group of people who she trusts and then everybody else she doesn't care.
Speaker 0: She's just like, yep, if you blow up whatever.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and So she can be a little selfish or like lacking empathy.
Speaker 0: but like do you blame her given the fact that she like grew up as a lab subject and was Like exposed to all these horrible experiments.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and they would like trying to make her blow up cats and stuff like that.
Speaker 1: I mean like serious But I like the sort of subtle story that she didn't blow up the cat and then she lashed out when he had when her fake father had her thrown into solitary confinement and then she murdered two of her Guards instead.
Speaker 1: and then the dad guy is just like oh cool.
Speaker 1: My experiment was a success.
Speaker 1: She can murder people with her mind, but like he's clearly happy that he got the answer to the question.
Speaker 1: He didn't care if a cat died or a person died.
Speaker 1: He just wanted to know the answer to that quest.
Speaker 0: I don't even I kind of wonder if he's gonna come back because it was implied that he got eaten by the monster.
Speaker 0: But they didn't show it.
Speaker 1: and the trope of me from that era if you don't see someone you don't see them die.
Speaker 0: They might come back.
Speaker 1: They're almost definitely not dead.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so the the monster is actually really scary.
Speaker 0: It's like those uh, those wolves from that anime we watched a long time.
Speaker 0: the brave story.
Speaker 0: Oh remember he's like nice doggy and then it's its face opens like a flower Like that's.
Speaker 0: that's the monster it like has a mouth but it's like its head just opens up as like this huge carnivorous flower and it will just be like.
Speaker 1: and but I love that bit where the teenagers the legit teenagers get together and Just they go and buy like all the bear traps and they make the fire bomb and they literally are ready to just murder the thing.
Speaker 0: You know Their booby trap was really their booby trap was another thing where I was like.
Speaker 0: that is a good plan.
Speaker 0: That's a smart plan except that the bear trap it was like.
Speaker 0: I was like, oh no, they have to jump over it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I was like, oh no, but then when boyfriend Oh shows up Oh my favorite sad bad boyfriend Steve Steve shows up and you're kind of like.
Speaker 0: He's not the worst but he's kind of a douchebag like he's like douchebag.
Speaker 1: Yep, you're supposed to come around like especially as he sort of ditches his other loser.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like his friends are the worst right, but he also goes along with him and he's kind of like her.
Speaker 0: her her.
Speaker 1: He comes in and they're gonna fight the monster.
Speaker 1: He's like what.
Speaker 0: he's like what what?
Speaker 1: and they pull the gun and he's like Ah, what.
Speaker 0: and so he comes in and he sees this house.
Speaker 1: That's like rigged up with bear traps and like the one He's got spiked bat and like the guy he thinks is probably a serial killer His girlfriend has a gun and they're telling him to get the fuck out.
Speaker 0: He's like something real bad is going on and then the monster comes out of the wall and he just flips out.
Speaker 0: I I love Times like that where a character who hasn't thus far been introduced to any of the like terrible secret That's happening in like a fantasy Sci-fi thing gets it all at once like Surprise, and that was that was really excellent because he was being a pain in the neck And then he was freaking
Speaker 1: out.
Speaker 1: great also because he he stepped up.
Speaker 0: Yeah, he actually was helpful and when Jonathan was in danger He was like he saved Jonathan's life.
Speaker 0: So I was like good on you Steve.
Speaker 0: You're not so so jerky after all.
Speaker 1: I really like the bit by bit as hopper.
Speaker 1: The cop starts to figure things out and follow the thread I like when he was checking his apartment for bugs or he does it in such it once again.
Speaker 1: Like even when he's alone, it's the kind of thing that crazy people do.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and then he finds it.
Speaker 0: He's he's like trash in his apartment and you're like or his his house and you're like Oh, like is he gonna find it?
Speaker 0: and then he finds like an actual microphone on the lamp.
Speaker 1: But then he's already go straight to the what's-her-name's house, mrs.
Speaker 1: Byers.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and then he comes in the door and like and then they work together.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well that that was the very satisfying thing.
Speaker 0: once the two groups start consolidating like once Oh really three groups.
Speaker 1: It was it was Those two would be figured out.
Speaker 1: then there was the teenagers.
Speaker 1: They'd figured a bunch out and then there was the kids and all three groups came together.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and then they immediately are like, well let's minority report.
Speaker 0: and yeah, well they had the the sensory deprivation tank thing.
Speaker 0: that was another like kind of jerry-rigged smart solution to a problem.
Speaker 0: and Yeah, I also.
Speaker 1: one of the things I like about the show is just the production design is really really good The framings good the scene transitions are not only great, but they're very reminiscent of horror like movies from the 80s.
Speaker 0: Well, you said like the soundtrack not just the the music they lay crappy synthesizers are educating.
Speaker 1: Yeah I was on that panel at magfest with the dude who wrote like and and performed like half the horror Soundtracks from the 80s.
Speaker 1: and this dude he was talking about how they the studios he worked with often couldn't afford modern synthesizers.
Speaker 1: So what he do is he would manually use the synthesizer and like play the arpeggios and he manually do it to record the Soundtrack like doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo.
Speaker 1: The whole soundtrack is that 80s horror synth arpeggiating in the background.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and but not just that like the lighting.
Speaker 0: I just like a lot of the props and set designs as well much like Fargo.
Speaker 1: It's a period piece
Speaker 0: Yeah
Speaker 1: but and that and you don't need to know the period like you don't need to get there's a million references to like Stephen King and Steven Spielberg like they're everywhere, but you don't need to pick out specific ones because together they just set this very Like early 80s vibe, but the
Speaker 0: thing is like Fargo.
Speaker 0: that was something I really appreciated about Fargo.
Speaker 0: Yeah, too, but this one is much closer to home.
Speaker 0: This one is one I identify with a lot more.
Speaker 1: I grew up in the tail end of that era.
Speaker 0: Well something you also noticed too is like talking about environmental.
Speaker 0: storytelling is like how the different characters Socio-economic.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, look at like everywhere told to their houses.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the houses in the suburbs Tell you everything about these families.
Speaker 0: like like Steve's the boyfriend.
Speaker 0: he's definitely like his family's rich and they have like this rich kind of yuppie house.
Speaker 0: and With Like my normal house Mike Mike has the like suburban split-level, right?
Speaker 1: It's like totally that 70s And the buyers have the like rundown house in the pre-subdivision and yeah It's like the.
Speaker 1: those specific like straight Asians of society were around me as a kid in the suburbs in the Midwest.
Speaker 1: Yeah, totally and they really stood out like it because I knew kids from like from every one of those kinds of houses.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I think all all told the the CG stuff was really good.
Speaker 0: I liked when they'd go into the alternate dimension and it had the really spooky lighting and Actually, that was.
Speaker 0: I don't know how They did it, but I I want to say that it was actually probably not super Crazy, like they probably put a lot of filters over like the forest and everything There was.
Speaker 0: there was a ton of CG animation, but it's not like they created that from scratch.
Speaker 0: I Assume, you know, I don't actually know I haven't seen like a enough Compositing breakdown or anything, but it's like a lot of it is just like weird lighting like weird overlays and it just like takes the forest or takes the arcade or takes like some place and makes it just really creepy and dusty and It's pretty neat.
Speaker 1: It's also just the the normal like non upside down places.
Speaker 1: They said when they weren't doing something creepy.
Speaker 1: They evoked that nostalgia in a powerful way kind of like that San Junipero episode of Black Mirror.
Speaker 0: I haven't seen black.
Speaker 0: you should see it.
Speaker 0: I will.
Speaker 1: it very similarly even if you don't know anything about the 80s say like just like this like specific References.
Speaker 1: just you see the way things are lit and the way people are dressed and it just it puts together this setting very well.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so yeah, I'm.
Speaker 1: uh season two seems to just be continuing Exactly in the vein of season one and I have no complaints about one year later kind of thing.
Speaker 0: It's it's the yeah, I was born.
Speaker 0: so So yeah, it's good show.
Speaker 0: Definitely.
Speaker 0: Glad we watched it and Definitely.
Speaker 0: It's the kind of horror that I really enjoy.
Speaker 1: it legs up to the height.
Speaker 0: So pretty cool.
Speaker 1: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at front row crew comm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 1: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 1: But unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night.