Speaker 0: It's Thursday July 20th 2017.
Speaker 0: I'm rim.
Speaker 0: I'm scared and tonight on the geek nights book club We're talking about dune by Frank Herbert.
Speaker 0: just the first book.
Speaker 0: none of that.
Speaker 0: other nonsense.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: Last night.
Speaker 0: I actually went to a concert like down at the Highline Ballroom.
Speaker 0: It was pretty good.
Speaker 0: Okay I went to see the Aquabats, but isn't that a band for children?
Speaker 0: Ostensibly yes.
Speaker 1: I mean my sister liked them when she was still pre-college age.
Speaker 0: well, they had like a kids show, but they're basically like a neo ska Band and they play real music.
Speaker 0: Yeah and it was a good show.
Speaker 0: like I was that I went and it was interesting because a lot of the audience was like a Third parents with like young kids a third people our age and a third people older than us who were just like Really into the Aquabats.
Speaker 1: That's weird.
Speaker 0: I didn't know about the older crew though You know what the opening acts were?
Speaker 0: Reggie and the full effect which was.
Speaker 1: I've heard of it.
Speaker 0: There was an interesting set.
Speaker 0: They did and they actually dune came up which is why I mentioned this.
Speaker 1: What the hell?
Speaker 0: So he does like.
Speaker 0: he plays these songs that are kind of weird.
Speaker 0: it's almost like a joke band and they like.
Speaker 0: they come out and these they're all dressed like the Cobra Kai.
Speaker 0: and Then the main guy comes out and he's dressed up like Daniel-san from karate kid And he does like a song and stand up and kind of back and forth.
Speaker 0: And he tells this anecdote where he was like I guess drunk or something.
Speaker 0: and he went to see showgirls in the theater Which I've never actually seen.
Speaker 1: I haven't seen that either.
Speaker 0: apparently the dude who played Paul Atreides in one of the dune adaptations is a character.
Speaker 0: He plays a character in that movie.
Speaker 1: The only thing I know about showgirls is that the girl from Saved by the Bell gets naked.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, that's that.
Speaker 0: That is the other thing that I knew.
Speaker 1: That's the only thing I. that's the only thing I know about that movie.
Speaker 1: It was like a big deal because it was when it came out.
Speaker 1: It was NC 17 and not yokes.
Speaker 1: So it was actually in movie theater and his anecdote was around that.
Speaker 0: how like.
Speaker 0: it's kind of shameful that he went to see that Movie because that movie's not good.
Speaker 1: No, but
Speaker 0: Apparently because the person who played Paul Atreides is in this movie playing some other character He tells his long anecdote where he's there seeing the movie on like opening night and the theaters packed and that dude comes on screen And he just sort of blurts out like Maa Dib Maa Dib and one other person in the audience laughed.
Speaker 0: I don't even know If someone just has never seen any of the adaptations.
Speaker 1: if someone just goes Maa Dib Maa Dib I don't know what the fuck that means.
Speaker 0: Yeah Laughed at it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I can see there's an apostrophe pronounced Kwisatz Haderach Kwisatz Haderach.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: Well, apparently that's it's like real close to this Kabbalah word for someone who can teleport.
Speaker 0: I was I read a little bit up on dune.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: Oh, you know Kabbalah Can you cast Kabbalah spells?
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: So anyway, yeah, the concert was great.
Speaker 0: But you know the other opening act was CJ Ramone as in the old lead singer of the Ramones and they just did like classic punk and it was awesome.
Speaker 0: Okay, so it's a pretty good show and dune came up which was weird.
Speaker 0: and then like There was this long segment where he keeps telling all these dune jokes and half the audience gets it and half the audience has no Idea what's going on?
Speaker 0: And then that was just interesting.
Speaker 0: and that's all I had there.
Speaker 0: and I'm just killing time before Things of the day.
Speaker 0: So what do you got?
Speaker 0: actually?
Speaker 0: I can see it here but tell the crowd what you got.
Speaker 1: So this is someone runs this website called what email put games by email calm.
Speaker 0: It's a.
Speaker 1: it's a website where you can play games by email and a lot of those games involve dice and randomness, right?
Speaker 1: So people who are dedicated enough to play a game by email are the kind of person who's really gonna care about the randomness of those dice and they don't probably know enough about Dev random to realize that that's actually pretty legit.
Speaker 1: random I'm just saying so.
Speaker 1: Basically, he was the website was originally coded just to use the random number generators that are in computers Which are fine for games like this.
Speaker 1: yep And but people complained about the randomness like they complained like they were winning or losing because the randomness was no good Because people can't tell what's random.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: So people were like according to this article by the creator of this website We're like putting more effort and writing like dissertations on the right the bad randomness of games by email calm.
Speaker 1: so The creator of games by email calm made a machine that physically rolls actual goddamn dice 200,000 rolls
Speaker 0: a day 200,000
Speaker 1: dice rolls a day and uses computer vision to look at the dice To capture the numbers that they have rolled and then it uses those numbers to you know for all of the games by email.
Speaker 1: So you cannot possibly complain about the randomness and evil.
Speaker 1: still complain people still complain because people don't know what the fuck they're talking about.
Speaker 1: But you know, if you're really upset, he'll send you some dice from the thing.
Speaker 0: Well, he'll crush them and send them to you as an example to the other dice.
Speaker 0: Sure the the funniest thing about this is that he points out that one side effect of the way you built it is that it Destroys the dice and there's a high rate of die attrition.
Speaker 1: dice can only roll so many times before they disintegrate.
Speaker 0: Casino dice like they wear out real fast actually change the dice in the casino like constantly.
Speaker 1: now Imagine actually this gives me a cool idea at a con like packs or especially packs unplugged Like if you think about how much how much the dice in a casino roll in a day even unfelt.
Speaker 1: Like if you didn't change them, you'd have like balls in like, you know some weeks.
Speaker 1: Well, like it'd be really smooth like a burning wheel.
Speaker 0: I roll my dice like six times tops in a given night.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if you just played burning wheel all day.
Speaker 1: every day though Your dice would turn into balls because due to erosion.
Speaker 0: really I've seen some ball looking Warhammer dice before.
Speaker 1: I know right?
Speaker 0: So but imagine so, you know like in a fancy wedding of like the champagne fountain or some nonsense at the chocolate fountain.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we want to have a dice bow.
Speaker 0: Imagine at the middle of packs packs unplugged there's a dice fountain and in the packs app You could just ask it for die rolls from that thing during packs.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: That would be like the cool weird thing to do.
Speaker 1: I'm just saying check out this cool dice rolling.
Speaker 0: It's pretty cool.
Speaker 0: Like it's it's legit I would.
Speaker 1: you know, I don't really even it only rolls d6.
Speaker 1: I wish he would start a service where like I don't want to play any games by email I just want to app on my phone.
Speaker 1: right if I need a real dice roll I can get one from there.
Speaker 0: Yeah, especially if it showed me a picture of the dice I feel like that would like seal the deal with people who don't understand RNG Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: So all I got is, you know way back in her undertale was a fantastic game.
Speaker 0: I love the hell out of it but the Phantom around it kind of got like pony level of creation of stuff and People made all these like animatics and cool things.
Speaker 0: and I just noticed recently that one of those animatics They actually went and finished the entire animation like they made the thing and it's done and it's out there.
Speaker 0: Okay, and it's actually like really super well done.
Speaker 0: and it's the the fight you see between a Character and another character.
Speaker 0: that is spoiler that you'll only see if you do a genocide route and murder people.
Speaker 0: and it's just super Well done.
Speaker 0: and I'm really impressed with it.
Speaker 0: and I'm extra impressed that some fan animatic stuff turned into a finished thing because oftentimes you see a YouTube thing that's like work in progress and that is literally the last thing ever uploaded on that account.
Speaker 0: Okay, so I'm impressed by the fact that this finished and it's legit good.
Speaker 0: And also if you don't want to do the genocide run, which I didn't because I'm not a bad person You can see some of the stuff that you wouldn't see otherwise in the game.
Speaker 0: And that's that other than in the meta moment.
Speaker 0: The book club book.
Speaker 0: is Dune talking about it.
Speaker 1: in like two minutes I'd selected a new book club book.
Speaker 0: Oh, so what is the new book club book?
Speaker 1: I'm gonna find it.
Speaker 1: Hold on Oh, yeah, so cuz I'm like Ram.
Speaker 1: It doesn't take me long to select a new book club.
Speaker 0: All I'm gonna warn you about is that if you did not read Dune, you're going to spoil Dune Dunes pretty straightforward.
Speaker 1: I mean, I feel like like do it like so dude was already spoiled like Old that the statute of limitations is out.
Speaker 1: Like I knew a lot of shit about doing before I read it.
Speaker 0: I don't think anything.
Speaker 0: any event that happened in this book surprised me No But anyway other than that the Baron was way worse than I thought.
Speaker 1: the next book club book is.
Speaker 1: So there's this lady in Brooklyn.
Speaker 1: I think she still lives in Brooklyn.
Speaker 1: I saw her at gamer X last year, but I mean I knew about her before then.
Speaker 0: Oh right that book.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so well, she's got a lot of books.
Speaker 1: So her name is.
Speaker 0: you talked about this book.
Speaker 0: You wanted to do it.
Speaker 1: Her name is NK Jemisin, right and she apparently writes these fantasy novels that are like the hotness right now Or they've been the hotness for like a year or two, but you know fantasy novels.
Speaker 1: you got time.
Speaker 1: You don't got to stay on top of those and read them as soon as they come out unless it's a prince of nothing I'm just saying.
Speaker 1: but I mean we even read the first prince of nothing how long after it came out, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, like three cycles of our friends had already read that book before we read it, right?
Speaker 1: It's like, you know, so it's still the new hotness because books are slow compared to say YouTube.
Speaker 1: Yeah So I think this is like she's got a lot of books in there if you go to Amazon.
Speaker 1: But apparently the hottest book is this series which is about the broken earth.
Speaker 1: So the broken earth book number one is called the fifth season and the cover is green, which is good Because some of the other covers are like red or blue Careful.
Speaker 0: the cover of I think the third of that horrible trilogy dragons gold serpent silver Cameras copper was green.
Speaker 1: I'm just saying just say I've read.
Speaker 1: I actually started reading like a chapter of this book.
Speaker 0: It's three dollars on Kindle.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I started reading one chapter of this book before I switched to do not because this was no good But because I had to read the book.
Speaker 0: I just bought it.
Speaker 1: So so yeah, this is like praised by Everybody like that you ever knew this is mad.
Speaker 1: got like so much praise.
Speaker 0: this won the Hugo Award for best novel.
Speaker 1: This book is a huge huge hotness in the world of fantasy.
Speaker 1: It's like people who know like whose main nerdery is fantasy type sci-fi type novels, you know, those kind of nerds They're like all over this already like this, you know, but if you're just a regular old nerd, you know And that's sort of off to the side.
Speaker 1: Well, this is what you're missing apparently.
Speaker 1: So let's find out what the deal is.
Speaker 0: All right, I'm into it But be warned the last of the Prince of Nothing books is coming out imminently five days Supposedly, I think we're gonna read that first and then we're gonna jump on this book.
Speaker 1: But it doesn't count as book club though.
Speaker 0: No, that's just the ongoing.
Speaker 0: That's like our favorite fantasy book series.
Speaker 0: for some reason, right?
Speaker 1: Something about it.
Speaker 0: Yeah We'll see how it ends.
Speaker 1: I'm mostly the horses and men getting broken.
Speaker 0: I just the literal Broken horse.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: I guess I should have seen that coming Mm-hmm, but like should have seen us betrayal coming because the book literally says from like page three I did see it coming.
Speaker 1: I was just waiting to see.
Speaker 0: I think everyone sees what's coming.
Speaker 0: So yeah, we're talking about Dune.
Speaker 0: So last warning if you somehow don't gonna do any meta moments.
Speaker 0: Uh, the next book club was that.
Speaker 0: oh, yeah, we're going to be at PAX West doing at least one panel.
Speaker 0: We're doing a much updated and rewritten panel on quitting Focusing more on specifically people who quit because they're butter.
Speaker 1: translation.
Speaker 1: barely changed because we had new ideas.
Speaker 1: We had no new ideas.
Speaker 0: I think it is gonna be significantly changed barely change.
Speaker 0: We ran that old quitting panel again at kinetic on and I actually have a much more Specific and nuanced point.
Speaker 0: I want to make about quitting Insignificantly changed.
Speaker 0: I think it'll be significantly changed.
Speaker 1: doesn't have any new ideas for panels Actually, it's trying to get a free ticket again.
Speaker 0: I did submit like three other panels, but this is one they wanted so Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: So yeah, otherwise, I think the next con after that is gonna be pecs unplugged Which will be at doing a bunch of panels and then pecs Australia Which I'm very likely to be at and I am now.
Speaker 0: I'm 100% confident that our friend row is also going to be there.
Speaker 0: Because well, we'll talk about that in the next Tuesday show, but for the first time ever Geek nights has an official champion in the omegathon finale Finale.
Speaker 1: you got to make it to the finale.
Speaker 0: I'm pretty much Babe Ruth and I'm pre Babe Ruth in her.
Speaker 1: That's a bad idea.
Speaker 0: row is pro Rose like the most pro we know.
Speaker 1: Yeah But the omega-thon might have a random round two or some shit and then what it will and then what.
Speaker 0: but usually the random isn't Like in or out it's the bottom of a pile is gonna be knocked.
Speaker 1: out is saying I mean I don't like it happen.
Speaker 0: well either we're gonna be going crazy at the omega-thon finale because row is pro or We're going to be heckling mercilessly whoever it is that knocked row out.
Speaker 1: I think we're just gonna be heckling mercilessly either way.
Speaker 0: Yeah we're.
Speaker 0: uh We've never been this invested in an omega-thon before.
Speaker 1: why would we be?
Speaker 0: Yeah It's an extra fitting because the first packs we ever went to Row who is just like a listener like a fan of geek nights offered to pick us up at the airport and we just trusted the stranger to like show up at the airport and like literally pick us up and drive us to a hotel.
Speaker 0: and It totally happened and it was cool.
Speaker 0: So that otherwise our YouTube channels to go in.
Speaker 0: we're live streaming this podcast so you could actually watch like my sweaty butt.
Speaker 0: I don't know about.
Speaker 1: you don't need to do that.
Speaker 0: There are.
Speaker 1: I don't even need to be listening to this like you should.
Speaker 1: if you're listening to geek Surely there must be some better way you could be spending this hour of your life.
Speaker 0: There are nine people watching us live right now nine saddest people and there are way more than nine messages in this chat.
Speaker 1: Nine sad messages.
Speaker 0: there are in fact, one, two, three, four five.
Speaker 1: There's only one night.
Speaker 0: Oh, oh, no, there there's actually exactly nine messages in the chat and there is one message that is not sad.
Speaker 1: So it's actually only eight sad mess.
Speaker 0: No, these guys they seem pretty chill.
Speaker 0: They're happy.
Speaker 1: No, there's one message is not sad.
Speaker 0: I think though your message is the only sad one.
Speaker 0: That's the not sad one, even though I have the same policy.
Speaker 0: But anyway, I digress dude.
Speaker 0: We're talking about Frank Herbert's 1965 epic science fiction novel called dune, right?
Speaker 1: So this is like one of the legendary nerd books of all time and we never read it into completion before.
Speaker 1: Yep in middle school.
Speaker 1: I've said this before but you know We got to say everything about the book in the actual episode about the book, right?
Speaker 1: I think in middle school or something.
Speaker 1: I don't remember.
Speaker 1: ish I tried to read it and because it was such a famous nerd book and I did not get very far and was Unpleased with it.
Speaker 1: and then for a long period of my life, you know Especially at RIT nerds would talk about doing on occasion because that's gonna happen and I'd be like, yeah, I'm not into dune I don't know what the deal is.
Speaker 0: I don't know why Star Trek either I just sorta like.
Speaker 0: I always heard that people talked about doing a lot and I read a little bit of it.
Speaker 0: I didn't care that much and I was into really dumb fantasy novels back then.
Speaker 0: Yeah,
Speaker 1: as time went on Eve just by being a nerd and living in the internet and knowing nerds I learned things about dune because that's how happens and we played the dune game, which is quite a good game
Speaker 0: And actually I have a lot more to say about that game now that I read this book.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah But anyway save that talk for the end though, right?
Speaker 1: So I said, you know, we know we got this book club going on.
Speaker 1: even you know We did that wheel of time on basically the same premise, right?
Speaker 1: Which was like hey because you're a nerd what good or bad you sort of have to read this cuz and
Speaker 0: a side effect of that Was I actually just read all of the wheel of time
Speaker 1: Anyway, but which you see wouldn't have even read one of those if not for me selecting it.
Speaker 0: I ain't gonna do that with dune.
Speaker 1: So I said well, you ain't a nerd if you haven't read the dune good or bad.
Speaker 1: So let's read the dune.
Speaker 0: So the most important thing I want to get out there is that one despite having not read it until now It is exactly what I thought it was.
Speaker 0: Nothing was surprising at all And I already knew almost the entire plot just from casual pop culture interaction in the first.
Speaker 1: like.
Speaker 1: there are all these proper Nouns about dune that I vaguely knew what they had.
Speaker 0: them all straight in like a few pages, right?
Speaker 1: But in like the first chapter every single one of those proper nouns is introduced But then every single one of them like right away.
Speaker 0: They're all explained Explicitly.
Speaker 1: a lot of them get explained explicitly pretty much right away.
Speaker 1: But the one thing I think that they're lacking is that in I'm gonna compare it to Prince of Nothing Because that's how we do.
Speaker 0: This is like 90%.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna be comparing this to Prince of Nothing.
Speaker 1: But anyway in Prince of Nothing, it's proper.
Speaker 1: It's even more proper noun hell.
Speaker 1: However, the Prince of Nothing Uses, you know Latin roots and you know roots itself But it's proper nouns in real-world languages Which this does too in a way that you can infer the meaning of the word Just from how it feels.
Speaker 1: to read and say whereas dune does not do that because that's how to act doesn't mean shit.
Speaker 0: You get that explanation Apparently, you know Kabbalah.
Speaker 0: it's like a spell I guess.
Speaker 1: in the Kabbalah maybe but in Prince of Nothing.
Speaker 1: if someone says I own the Ione or Ionia Ionia sounds like the name of a country.
Speaker 1: it and it is and it kind of feels like the name of a country like Ionia wouldn't be a name of a Beverage or a person right it cuz it ends in yeah, right?
Speaker 0: It's like oh, that's Or just II I don't remember.
Speaker 1: well Ionia is you know, well I'm saying with the AI the Ione people right So that Ionia is a great anyway, right, but I'm saying to say like Ione It's like oh that feels like.
Speaker 1: it just feels like, you know, your name wouldn't be Ione.
Speaker 1: So I'd say that a lot of the name of our people like when you read it in context It's like the Ione.
Speaker 0: but a lot of a lot of the words in dune are like based in languages and have some reasonable Context but a lot of them aren't.
Speaker 0: but more importantly rather than just being used by Characters and then you infer meaning the same way you infer meaning in real the real world.
Speaker 0: when you talk to people Dune introduces terms and then sort of just explicitly explains what they are.
Speaker 0: It never just casually uses a word it waits you to figure it out.
Speaker 0: It explains what it all is at some point.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm and also some of like the.
Speaker 0: the provenance of these words like the etymology like what they seem to be based on.
Speaker 0: It's just like a vague smattering of like Arabic and Persian and Hebrew and stuff.
Speaker 0: Just sort of all mixed up.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm and some of them like chamurky.
Speaker 0: That was not that important and I was shocked at how specifically they focused on the different kinds of poisons.
Speaker 1: Yeah, which is kind of poison.
Speaker 0: The other thing is that the book is really straightforward and the characters are really simple and The world that is constructed is actually also pretty simple.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like there's nothing fancy about it.
Speaker 1: Right?
Speaker 1: You know, it's like there's no mysteries.
Speaker 1: There's literally even wheel of time is fancier.
Speaker 1: It's like ooh, like what's the deal?
Speaker 1: What's the deal in doing?
Speaker 1: you're never asking?
Speaker 1: What's the deal?
Speaker 1: Even the stuff they try to keep in mystery.
Speaker 1: like the guild it's like oh and the cages blows his load.
Speaker 1: It's like you can.
Speaker 0: just a spaceman loses his contact in the end and you see his eyes are blue and you're like Oh, I see what's going on, but I knew that they were fucked.
Speaker 1: I knew they were fucked up in spice a long time ago.
Speaker 1: That before you read the book cuz it always talks about how Even in the book it like it right away.
Speaker 1: It talks about like yeah, the guild loves this.
Speaker 1: They keep buying all the spice.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they're selling all the spice to the guild and then it's like oh It's.
Speaker 1: it's supposed to be a big reveal that despite that the guild guy has blue eyes, too.
Speaker 0: That might have been a bigger reveal if not for the fact that we knew a lot about - no They tell you earlier in the book that like the guild people are buying all the spice.
Speaker 0: Make a big point about how the Emperor and the guild and the Harkonnen are all Hoarding spice because it's literally the most valuable thing in the world and because there's that big plot They're obviously hoarding it to corner the market when the plot happens like.
Speaker 0: the book does set up all these rational explanations and it is easy to feel like we Figured stuff out earlier.
Speaker 1: partly because it does it.
Speaker 1: there's no figuring stuff out earlier like at one point.
Speaker 1: What's this?
Speaker 1: Paul has like a you know, one of his visions and it's like yeah he had a vision.
Speaker 1: It's like literally like, you know He had a vision of the future where he's a pilot of a guild spaceship all fucked up on spice.
Speaker 1: and it's like oh Well, they just that's already halfway through the book, right?
Speaker 1: But it's like they just tell it to you and that's way before the end of the book where they wrote It's the good.
Speaker 1: this guild guy loses contact lens.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right.
Speaker 0: at the same time It causes sort of interesting thing that I haven't seen in a lot of books.
Speaker 0: Where to compare to the prince of nothing or wheel of time?
Speaker 0: When you're in a cow perspective of a character you tend to be there for a while like you're in some random characters head like you're in the I don't know a Cameon's head because each chapter will be coming like from a specific character in dune.
Speaker 1: There's just sort of this narrator, right?
Speaker 0: Well, you jump between the characters heads a lot Yeah And you get their exact thoughts like in the say like it's best.
Speaker 0: There's one scene in the book that dinner party Which is probably my favorite scene in the entire book.
Speaker 0: Mmm, and it's literally like all the big important characters.
Speaker 0: Well, most of them are at this dinner party and it's one of those like high Political tension like everyone like what's going?
Speaker 0: all these people have different motivations.
Speaker 0: What do they want?
Speaker 0: what's that guy gonna do?
Speaker 0: like everyone's posturing?
Speaker 0: and there's intrigue and drama but Every character's motivation is explicitly explained to you the reader.
Speaker 0: You literally know everyone's secret everyone's motivation everyone's everything throughout that entire scene, right?
Speaker 1: This is I told you this is omniscient narrator just sort of telling you the story.
Speaker 0: Well kind of like how Paul Atreides becomes omniscient, right?
Speaker 1: But it's not.
Speaker 1: You know a lot of books will use sort of like narrative devices like, you know First-person storytelling or like saga.
Speaker 1: you have like the daughter is telling the story from when she's older about her baby years Like oh my parents such-and-such.
Speaker 1: right.
Speaker 1: Dune is literally using no fancy writing techniques whatsoever.
Speaker 1: It's just a narrator and dialogue between characters Characters perspective and like.
Speaker 0: what are those better Jesser and up to and it cuts to Jessica and Jessica's like I am up to XY and Z. That is what I want.
Speaker 1: It reads the way that like a D&D book could read like oh the you know.
Speaker 1: Or like it's written the same way that you know much better.
Speaker 0: obviously Like that those D&D books hide everything from you.
Speaker 1: no, no not in terms of the hiding in the information But in terms of just the the fact that it's a narrator, you know, just telling you what's happening, right?
Speaker 1: It's not written in a fancy, you know, there's no sort of device right?
Speaker 0: Yeah in the way that it's told Well, the pros is pretty simple too, but that's not what I want to focus on yet.
Speaker 0: But I feel like the story is actually kind of the same story that Hyperion is trying to tell and that parts of The Princess of Nothing are trying to tell a lot of things.
Speaker 1: Obviously you mean you mean things that came after this?
Speaker 0: Yeah crib from Dune, but the story is just I mean it is.
Speaker 1: It is one of those situations where something is such a big deal in the nerd world and so famous But you didn't read it and when you go back to it you realize Oh all the things were borrowing or referencing or homaging this and I missed it.
Speaker 0: So then I read a spoiler.
Speaker 0: so in one of the later Dune books There's a group of people called the face dancers.
Speaker 0: They could do the thing with their faces to look like anyone just like the the what sits in The Prince of Nothing Like that exact same thing.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but the story is just.
Speaker 0: humanity has this like transhumanist crisis because they invent AI and they have nuclear weapons.
Speaker 0: and It's almost like you.
Speaker 0: look at the culture books.
Speaker 0: The culture books are the.
Speaker 0: what if humans just embrace transhumanism and become crazy different?
Speaker 0: Awesome and Dune is what if humans freak out and try to remain human forever?
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm, and the only story here is that you have this existence of humanity that Had this like transhumanist crisis and it's discreet.
Speaker 0: Oh, they've mentioned it as the butlerian jihad where they basically said, you know Thou shalt not to figure this figure this way before the beginning of the book.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but it's explained pretty explicitly like nothing.
Speaker 1: They just tell it to you.
Speaker 1: Yeah Especially in that appendix the history of the human race is not like a mystery to humans.
Speaker 0: humans decide you can't make Humans have to be human as they are now Literally forever and they issue all technology that could make humans different, right?
Speaker 1: It's weird though, but they keep some technology that they still had there like it's weird.
Speaker 1: They'll be fighting with swords and knives and poisons and things and though but they'll also be using like ridiculous fancy poison detecting machines Yeah, the stupors.
Speaker 0: and they'll also be using like lays guns and shields, but they don't use other wet like they use swords Dark guns.
Speaker 1: they have ridiculous Ridiculous spaceships some sort of ornithopter flying device like.
Speaker 1: there's some level of fancy technology.
Speaker 1: That is Simon Simultaneously high but also low and it really feels a lot like the kind of technology that you see in Star Wars, right?
Speaker 1: it's Simultaneously fancy.
Speaker 1: this x-wing could enter hyperspace but go somewhere else but look at it.
Speaker 1: It's a piece of shit, right?
Speaker 1: So it's an ornithopter.
Speaker 1: Look at this.
Speaker 1: It can fly around and it can survive in this crazy storm kind of but it's obviously not really a great flying device.
Speaker 1: It's kind of a piece of shit, right?
Speaker 1: But
Speaker 0: the storytelling there is kind of an interesting subtle thing and it's pretty consistent Because remember I mentioned like there's so much focus on those proper nouns of different kinds of poison and all that the society that humans have built is this like static thing where the rules of conflict like if humans have a Conflict.
Speaker 0: the rules are very specific and designed to ensure that Individual humans matter a lot and the technology just not.
Speaker 0: if you want to assassinate someone There are specific rules of the kinds of poison to use and rules of the ways you can try to detect and stop that poison Like if you want to fight someone in.
Speaker 1: obviously all these rules only matter for like these ultra elite people who run the galaxy.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, no one else matters.
Speaker 0: normal humans don't matter.
Speaker 1: It's really only a story of you know courts and emperors and kings and dukes and not really a story of normal people.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know they don't matter too much.
Speaker 0: Well, yeah, we can talk a little about normal people other than other than as followers or supporters Of.
Speaker 1: you know, it's very futile system.
Speaker 1: They built it.
Speaker 0: Well, it's literally 10,000 years.
Speaker 0: there is no democracy involved But every rule like the rules of atomics and like the rule of have the fight with someone with knives.
Speaker 1: I didn't use atomics on people.
Speaker 1: I'd atomic that terrain and I just happened to let this horrible storm through that ruined you.
Speaker 0: but the rules are so specific to ensure that among the people who run society an Individual human will be making decisions and matter a lot and nothing else will matter.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm and that definitely fits into this rule of Humans must remain human and it's this arbitrary definition of humanity at this certain point in time probably right about like the year after the Butlerian Jihad ended.
Speaker 0: and the whole story of Dune seems to be that the Bene Gesserit and like making of the Mentats and all these things like the breeding programs are everybody trying to skirt the rules To make non-humans yet.
Speaker 0: They refuse to actually let them be fully non-human.
Speaker 0: So they still constrain them and as a result they fail.
Speaker 0: and the story at the end of this book I feel like is Paul Atreides who is the best Mentat and he's there.
Speaker 0: He's basically the Dunyane like the end of all that line of genetics and nonsense.
Speaker 0: The the moral of the story is what you made is not human.
Speaker 0: You cannot remain static and the entire book is just telling that story.
Speaker 0: Yeah, pretty much humans are static.
Speaker 0: They're uniform.
Speaker 0: They're boring and they suck and transhumanism is the right way to go.
Speaker 0: The culture is the right way.
Speaker 1: But I think what's also interesting is that you know In putting they were able to put down technology to some extent only because there's also magic, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, there's a lot even though it's a sci-fi Arguably, they.
Speaker 1: it's a sci-fi with the space and the lasers, but it's also the fantasy.
Speaker 1: well so it's like Star Wars again.
Speaker 0: prescience is coached in terms of Higher order.
Speaker 0: beings like the AI's and things that they jahad it against Could access other dimensions.
Speaker 0: the Bene Gesserit stuff in the appendix kind of says this Explicitly that their goal in making the quiz ops heterok was to make a multi-dimensional human.
Speaker 0: But the problem is the multi-dimensional human is not humans the multi-dimensional being.
Speaker 0: but the prescience could be Like.
Speaker 0: it can be explained by that stuff.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and also the way Paul Sees the future is definitely cuz you know how there's like the blind spots.
Speaker 0: He can't see.
Speaker 0: it's definitely coached in terms of.
Speaker 0: It's actually just a supercomputer in his mentat brain Calculating based on all the information he has what would have occurred kind of like it I think.
Speaker 1: I think it's also sort of bowing to the sort of possibly true Scientific idea that this basically existing dimensions for all possible futures and they collapse into right.
Speaker 1: So there are certain Nexus points in which you don't you can't really tell which one you're gonna collapse into Because you know, right and then and then as you move.
Speaker 1: as you're slowly going through dimension after dimension It becomes more obvious which ones are more probable than others.
Speaker 1: quantum mechanics.
Speaker 1: Yeah ish kind of thing, right?
Speaker 1: It's like you never say any of that explicitly But it sort of leans to similar conceptual ideas to that sort of real-world science in some ways.
Speaker 0: Yep But there's a few points when Paul's having his awakening where he definitely Like it's sort of implied that the parts he can't see here because he doesn't have enough input into his mentat brain and actually He's just a magic computer now.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like he's just a fancy computer.
Speaker 0: I like.
Speaker 0: there's one little scene I like where I think his father is like Blah blah blah son.
Speaker 0: You might like you could be a mentat if you want to be and he's like, but that's stupid.
Speaker 0: Uh, I'm like obviously you weren't training me I mean.
Speaker 0: and then he realizes that mentats can't be told that they're being trained.
Speaker 0: and then he's like, oh shit You didn't tell me because I am a mentat.
Speaker 1: So his dad is the best guy in the whole book, yeah, he's got flaws.
Speaker 0: he's not like the best person.
Speaker 0: No, he's a pretty good person by the standards of this fucked up society, right?
Speaker 1: It's like whenever I read some fantasy story.
Speaker 1: I always want to read the story about like the great.
Speaker 1: It's always like there's always used to be a kingdom that was great and it it's ass got crumbled.
Speaker 1: and now you're reading the story.
Speaker 0: Nothing you want to read about says watha idea stuck with the came in and in.
Speaker 1: here at least we get a chapter of the Duke in his home place.
Speaker 1: That's awesome.
Speaker 1: What's the name of that?
Speaker 1: Awesome planet?
Speaker 0: They're from Caledon.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like.
Speaker 1: I just want to read like.
Speaker 1: give me the.
Speaker 1: is there a prequel book about just like awesome parties on Caledon?
Speaker 0: I think there is a prequel but I've I've.
Speaker 0: I have it on good authority that I should not read any more Dune books.
Speaker 1: I also have that good authority and I don't find I'm wasting my time with it.
Speaker 0: It's just like best as every further work is a diminishing returns situation.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but it's like, you know, this Duke is awesome Duke and he just got moved to this other planet by the Emperor for political reasons.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right.
Speaker 1: and it's like even though he's now.
Speaker 0: no, he's only awesome in the context of that feudal nightmare society.
Speaker 1: Sure, right, but he's like as far as Kings go.
Speaker 1: He's legit good.
Speaker 1: You could call this guy a good King.
Speaker 1: well like.
Speaker 0: there's that scene where he goes out to see the spice harvest and he risks his life and his son's life to save those people.
Speaker 0: and He's very clear like fuck the machines Fuck the spice save those individual like six humans down there and everyone's so like everyone's freaking out about it in any other novel.
Speaker 0: You would wonder if he did that because he actually cared about those people or if it was a clever ploy To like get the Fremen on his side, but because you it doesn't matter but because you know the characters motivations It's obvious that he does actually care about the people.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: No, he's legit like awesome Duke guy.
Speaker 1: It's like damn.
Speaker 1: It's like I like that guy.
Speaker 1: it's like I always want to see like the badass heroic actually good King like.
Speaker 0: actually if the story if Hue had not you a had not betrayed and the entire book was just Them trying to avoid the cat the trap that the Harkonnen have set that would have been awesome.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if the whole book was just like that dinner party and just kept going until they won I would have enjoyed it just as much.
Speaker 1: Yeah, actually and you could have just ended it.
Speaker 1: Yeah I do like even though that there are more dunes and clearly they play.
Speaker 1: Frank Herbert intended there to be more dunes.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right from the get-go You know because he didn't say everything you had to say in the one book It still stands alone as itself as a complete book.
Speaker 1: that doesn't feel like you need like.
Speaker 1: if there had never been another dune at All yeah, you wouldn't feel like you were missing anything.
Speaker 0: That is a big difference from like other fantasy series like Locke Lamora the Wheel of Time.
Speaker 0: every book ends and you're like.
Speaker 0: I really got to know what happens now.
Speaker 1: Yeah It's like.
Speaker 1: it really feels like there's supposed to be a volume.
Speaker 1: to a lot of times when there's a volume one even if they Didn't get a guaranteed contract to write a volume to it feels like the day intended for one from the get-go.
Speaker 1: But here no, this is a standalone book.
Speaker 1: You can pretend the other ones don't even exist.
Speaker 0: No problem And the end is actually solid ending pretty satisfying.
Speaker 0: like it's one of those situations of let's get all the characters who are important who are still alive in one room and kill some of them and then let's get them all in one room again whoever's left and resolve Every plot thread and they.
Speaker 1: it's surprisingly that ending part The only thing negative about the ending part is it feels kind of rushed.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like it's like they get them all in one room and then everything happens real fast.
Speaker 0: Yep, like how odd pops out and he was the only one where I wasn't a hundred percent sure what he was gonna do.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'd seen at the end.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm, but I realized I look back and flip through.
Speaker 0: he was set up.
Speaker 0: You know, all the other characters are like what's dangerous?
Speaker 0: What's what up to?
Speaker 0: is he really on their her cone inside?
Speaker 0: But if you read what he actually does he's just fucking with the Baron Harkonnen the entire time Waiting for his moment to betray that dude.
Speaker 0: Yeah Actually, I think my favorite character.
Speaker 0: I keep saying it's Keens or Kynes.
Speaker 1: likely it kinda think it's Kynes cuz it's a wife.
Speaker 1: It was Keens.
Speaker 0: It would be ke a actually Really like and I remembered this guy just a second ago the Count Fenring.
Speaker 1: Oh, that's definitely a rim character.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that guy's totally like.
Speaker 1: oh, but he's also ridiculously badass.
Speaker 0: said there was a really good scene.
Speaker 0: What am I?
Speaker 0: this is also one of my favorite?
Speaker 1: You know who Count Fenring reminds me of?
Speaker 1: Uh-huh.
Speaker 1: Kefka like he's that he's that kind of guy.
Speaker 1: Yeah, only less ridiculously evil, but there's that.
Speaker 1: but he's also Aesthetically, he seems the same.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but unlike Kefka.
Speaker 0: He's actually honored.
Speaker 1: like if you had to draw a picture of him I draw Kefka like they could share wardrobes.
Speaker 0: I imagine even though there's not not exactly the same There's that moment where I think he's talking to the Baron and he talks like so Baron Like he's humming and hmm and all the time and you're like god, what the fuck dude.
Speaker 0: and then the next scene is Someone like he basically like it says yes him and his wife Were talking in their private humming language and you're like, oh They were just talking to each other right in front of this stupid Baron's face and plotting against him And he didn't even realize it.
Speaker 0: The Baron is not the smartest He's.
Speaker 0: he's not as capable as I expected him to be from playing the game.
Speaker 1: Well, yeah.
Speaker 1: Well, the thing is with the Baron right.
Speaker 0: everybody was playing him literally everyone.
Speaker 1: It's it's weird and that he is.
Speaker 1: He's not like completely incompetent, right?
Speaker 1: He's not like one of those like really stupid bumbling know-nothing.
Speaker 0: bad plan was pretty good, right?
Speaker 1: It's like you see a lot of like I guess in a lot of kids stuff, especially where the bad guy is like bad.
Speaker 1: Yeah, Skeletor is a great example.
Speaker 1: He's bad and he's bad at being bad right or like, you know, Megatron like messes up every time.
Speaker 1: Cobra Commander messes up every time.
Speaker 1: a bad guy who's actually skilled and really dangerous doesn't really do too much right, you know, but Here it's like yeah, he is a bad guy who is not nearly as good at anything as anyone else around him.
Speaker 1: Well, even the person that he wants to be his successor is better than he is Yeah at everything in life.
Speaker 1: But he's actually I mean his plan to get Reno kill the Duke of what.
Speaker 1: I get worried, right?
Speaker 1: It's like God, you know, he's.
Speaker 1: he's not completely.
Speaker 1: He's like actually has skills which actually is good because it just shows you how really awesome everyone else is.
Speaker 1: It's like this really dangerous.
Speaker 1: this pretty dangerous dude is Actually chump change compared to all these actually really amazing Jessica or still gar or any of those people right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, so it's like oh and that makes everyone in the book, even though there's not really any superheroes besides computer man Paul Arguably still got like some of the Fremen.
Speaker 1: so guys not I mean They're just super at fighting because they lived in the harsh desert.
Speaker 0: true Well, I saw the car but it's right.
Speaker 1: that's a another example of the same technique.
Speaker 1: right the sourdough car Are presented as like these ultimate fighting Navy SEALs space dudes of super dangerous and they were and they are.
Speaker 1: But Fremen kick their asses in like a fight like one.
Speaker 1: Fremen is like five is worth like five sourdough cars.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so I'm just.
Speaker 1: I'm pronouncing it that way on purpose Although seems to her on the prison by using this relative technique where you show you present one thing is being really strong and then you present something else is kicking that thing's ass.
Speaker 1: it The thing that kicked ass seems so awesome.
Speaker 1: And so it you know nerds love all these powerful epic dudes.
Speaker 1: It's like D&D with everyone's level 20.
Speaker 1: Oh shit, son.
Speaker 1: Get your nerd jerk off on.
Speaker 0: meanwhile based on popular media I kind of expected Duncan, Idaho to have a lot more screen time.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and he was.
Speaker 0: he was Indiana Jones and then he just died like right away.
Speaker 1: I think it's true for like.
Speaker 1: there's a lot of characters in here like Peter DeVry.
Speaker 0: He's just dead like right away.
Speaker 1: There are a lot of characters that have a name and it's a name that I knew even before reading the book.
Speaker 1: For example Beast Rabanne is the one that comes to mind first, right?
Speaker 1: It's like dude, the dude's name is beast Come and he's like Beast Rabanne.
Speaker 1: that first of all.
Speaker 1: That's as really nice to say.
Speaker 1: Like that you imagine just before knowing nothing about do and you imagine a character and a fantasy novel named Beast Rabanne And it's like.
Speaker 1: that's got to be awesome, dude.
Speaker 1: That sounds like someone the Kenshiro punches in the head a few times and takes like an extra punch to explore.
Speaker 0: Is he ever in more than like?
Speaker 0: like you never actually see right any of him administering Arrakis?
Speaker 1: they talk about Beast Rabanne Like 10 or 20 times in the book.
Speaker 1: You only actually see Beast Rabanne like once and maybe twice.
Speaker 1: all he does is like talk to the Baron for a second and that's it.
Speaker 1: and you like.
Speaker 1: then he's dead.
Speaker 1: and it's like There's such a big character, but you know, nothing about them.
Speaker 0: Actually like Peter DeVry gets a bunch of screen time You're like, wow, this guy is gonna be a big part.
Speaker 0: Oh, whoa.
Speaker 0: He's dead.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 1: Yeah, Duncan I know this name keeps coming up.
Speaker 0: people keep talking In the later books, they keep resurrecting his like they use his DNA and they keep bringing like clones of him back.
Speaker 1: Yeah, Scott Johnson's told us that.
Speaker 1: yeah, so that's why everyone talks about Duncan, Idaho, but no but not sound nothing about in real life.
Speaker 1: I'm saying just in this book Oh, he's Duncan.
Speaker 1: Idaho's name comes up as characters talk about him or think about him But his actual presence on the pages where he's in the scene Right where you see him doing something or he's actually doing something of note in the time frame of this story From the time they land on dune to the end.
Speaker 0: Not much Duncan, Idaho action really.
Speaker 1: I just imagined him as Indiana Jones.
Speaker 1: Of course, Indiana Jones didn't exist when this book was written.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so I wonder how much Indiana Jones Meanwhile gurney Halleck who no one had talked about ever I didn't really know who that character was actually a major character and it's like one of the top characters Yeah, and he's also great.
Speaker 0: Like I really like him.
Speaker 1: Yeah Well, I mean if you take gurney Halleck and you know, he has sex with fenring rim comes out.
Speaker 0: Yep Well, cuz gurney came from one of those prison type planets.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so he's like that powerful.
Speaker 1: Yeah, he's a powerful dude and a bard.
Speaker 1: He's spooning and strong.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: We should let's go You know what?
Speaker 0: He reminds me of to the bard guy in the wheel of time.
Speaker 1: He just reminds me of bard guide the beginning.
Speaker 1: I can find a fantasy 6.
Speaker 0: Yep bard guy I could.
Speaker 1: that's how generic this does.
Speaker 1: I could pick eggs.
Speaker 1: Are you thinking of for know what the guy that always named Scott?
Speaker 1: What's his actual name?
Speaker 0: That doesn't help because you name like every first guy you meet.
Speaker 1: that's not the magical girl.
Speaker 0: He's not a bard.
Speaker 1: It still feels like that guy.
Speaker 0: the only bard is in Final Fantasy 4.
Speaker 1: well that guy's too spoon.
Speaker 1: He's more like fenring.
Speaker 0: Yeah He's not that dangerous though either.
Speaker 1: No, he's not.
Speaker 0: let's just go through all the characters because there's there's.
Speaker 0: they're so simple That you can say we can say like a few words about every character.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm Paul Atreides It's just like this.
Speaker 0: it's interesting because he we get this sort of coming-of-age story.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there's a little bit of a coming-of-age story.
Speaker 1: is the main character?
Speaker 0: He's the only character in the entire novel who at any point evolves, I think yeah.
Speaker 1: But it's still like, you know fantasy about being a super powerful guy.
Speaker 0: Whoo.
Speaker 1: It's a super powerful.
Speaker 0: Perfect guy.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we already talked about he has some internal struggles, but it's mostly the struggle of oh my god I have too much power.
Speaker 1: What the fuck?
Speaker 0: I'll be just like ah I want to fuck over the Harkonnens and the Emperor get my revenge and I want to save the people of this planet But I don't want them to jihad the universe.
Speaker 1: Yes, and that's the one thing that keeps you I guess not just sort of.
Speaker 1: That's the one thing that keeps him tied to humanity and not just be like at first like you can really get you know Identify with him because he's yeah, he's like this, you know, right because he's basically superhero generic, you know what's it called the What.
Speaker 1: the thing where you put yourself in is the character the self insertion.
Speaker 1: yeah, right It's not Mary Sue, but you know the the you know, the dude one anyway, but it's like, you know He's the guy that you want to be right.
Speaker 1: and then as it goes on and has he becomes just sort of not a person anymore you sort of like You know and he's in less scenes Actually, like you see less of him as like he goes into the desert
Speaker 0: and when he acts is much more like you being happened.
Speaker 1: Right, you become detached from him right?
Speaker 1: Like what happened to this guy?
Speaker 1: He's not I don't know him anymore.
Speaker 0: But then you get those little glimmers where he's like, oh no, it's yet another my friends become a creature.
Speaker 1: Yeah, he's like.
Speaker 1: he's like I can't let this horrible jihad Happen.
Speaker 1: it's like oh, alright, he's still like, oh, you know good person wants to.
Speaker 1: you know Even when he's like he's like my mom wants me to leave this jihad.
Speaker 1: I can't let it happen.
Speaker 1: It's like oh look at that.
Speaker 1: It's like that's pretty that's awesome.
Speaker 0: Well, though you get the impression that still being herself Didn't really have the full knowledge of what the Bene Gesserit were trying to do and that was a Bene Gesserit plan.
Speaker 0: Her plan was somewhat different.
Speaker 1: She just wanted the best for her son, really You know, she wanted him to be awesome Duke and be awesome and strong and she did cake Harkonnen ass And she did actually legit love Duke Leto and Duke Leto legit loved her and didn't marry her cuz political reasons.
Speaker 0: Yep I'm glad that the plot of Every like dark the Harkonnen plant of the sea and everyone thought Jessica was a traitor.
Speaker 1: I like how every character who was actually a terrific scene where he Gurney comes he's like you traitor and he's like wait actually We'll tell you how it went down.
Speaker 1: it's right away and he's like, oh my bad my bad.
Speaker 1: It's like how many fucking anime?
Speaker 1: Other shit.
Speaker 0: that's ten episodes.
Speaker 1: people don't open their fucking mouth and just tell someone what the deal is.
Speaker 1: Drama.
Speaker 1: and look we finally, you know, I'll give doing so much credit for that, right?
Speaker 1: Finally someone comes in and drama is avoided in one scene because someone just tells someone everything right away.
Speaker 1: Good job, dude.
Speaker 1: Also all you people do in your stories borrowing from dune.
Speaker 1: How come you don't borrow that?
Speaker 1: Yeah bother every other fucking thing in dune you steal from the one thing you should be stealing.
Speaker 1: you don't steal.
Speaker 0: Yep, you know you got the good guy You got the early bad guys who are gonna turn good and you got the bad guy.
Speaker 0: have those early bad guys Just turn good life three pages in right?
Speaker 0: Oh, oh, okay.
Speaker 0: We're on the same side.
Speaker 1: Whenever this good guys fighting give them a minute to talk and see.
Speaker 1: if they just resolve their differences when they air the truths and Then if they still can't resolve then they can fight.
Speaker 1: right but don't have these good guy fights for no reason.
Speaker 0: Later to when Hawat because someone refuses to tell someone something remember her what out of nowhere is like.
Speaker 0: by the way, Jessica I thought you were the traitor and I was wrong and I'm sorry.
Speaker 0: then he died.
Speaker 0: Yep Oh, by the way, I have this poison.
Speaker 0: they were gonna betray you.
Speaker 0: I killed myself.
Speaker 0: instead you to dick everybody.
Speaker 0: I'm out.
Speaker 0: He drops the mic and falls dead.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I like that.
Speaker 0: I like how out a lot because he just played the Baron the entire time.
Speaker 1: But yet again Hawat is a character who's there a lot in the like first few chapters.
Speaker 0: Yep goes away.
Speaker 1: You don't really see him.
Speaker 1: you hear about him a few times.
Speaker 1: Maybe there's a scene where he talks to the Baron and then there he is at the end.
Speaker 1: Yep It's like where were you?
Speaker 1: people talked about you more than I saw you.
Speaker 0: I liked you a - because again because they didn't have the mystery, you know is the reader right away.
Speaker 0: He's like, you know, he is the betrayer.
Speaker 1: I think it's like maybe even page one.
Speaker 0: They're like, oh by the way you a is the betrayer, but then the whole you keep reading and you're just waiting Like when's he gonna betray?
Speaker 1: How's he gonna betray?
Speaker 0: and you see everyone else and they add an additional mystery.
Speaker 1: It's like oh you a has this special training.
Speaker 1: How could he possibly?
Speaker 1: but this special betray training prevents him from betraying?
Speaker 1: How could he still betray?
Speaker 1: The special training?
Speaker 1: and then they reveal the reason that it he was able to betray despite the training.
Speaker 0: the power of his love was Greater than his conditioning.
Speaker 0: Yep, but none of the characters know that.
Speaker 0: it's all the characters like.
Speaker 0: there's all these infuriating scenes But in the good way.
Speaker 0: where people sit around they're like, who's the betrayer?
Speaker 0: Well, it can't be you and everyone's like duh can't be you a special training Who else is it?
Speaker 0: and you're just like god?
Speaker 1: I just want to tell you people well because that's you have this narrator who just tells you everything.
Speaker 0: But I also like how his betrayal is so just direct and simple.
Speaker 0: It's like oh, I turned off the shield and killed some people.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's it.
Speaker 1: She'll stand on the shield at the right time.
Speaker 0: It's just literally the shield comes down.
Speaker 1: and that because the thing is they're so good.
Speaker 1: And there's a little bit especially in that beginning part that nerds also love that procedural security part.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like, you know You get a little bat from the ghost in the shell and such and such or it's like, alright We're gonna tell you every detail of how we're protecting ourselves and how we can't be betrayed.
Speaker 1: You know what?
Speaker 1: You know and it's like and that makes it more interesting of like.
Speaker 1: oh How are they gonna get through this like and sort of like?
Speaker 1: oh, here's a dungeon.
Speaker 1: Look at all the traps in the dungeon how dangerous it is.
Speaker 1: How are they gonna get through there?
Speaker 1: Yeah, then learn it, you know get the details of how to get through.
Speaker 1: is a shit that nerds love?
Speaker 1: nerds eat that shit up.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so there it is.
Speaker 1: They give it to you.
Speaker 0: So I like the Lady Jessica because she was actually probably the most complex character Because she had a lot of very different conflicting motivations, right?
Speaker 1: And then it's like then she has the baby and then she has the mistake with the baby But she's also has all these different phases, right?
Speaker 0: I like how instrumental she is like Paul would have just died without her.
Speaker 0: and anytime Paul a few times Paul's like I don't need you mom and she's like son.
Speaker 0: You don't even know the half of it.
Speaker 0: You think you know the voice?
Speaker 0: Let me show you the fucking voice.
Speaker 0: But the only thing that bothers me about her and it's kind of a Because I read the Wheel of Time not that long ago and I read this what is with old sci-fi?
Speaker 0: and like male and female are these intrinsic traits of being that are like a big part of the fundamental reality of the universe.
Speaker 1: It's because dudes who wrote old sci-fi books didn't get a lot of sex action.
Speaker 1: Yeah nerds had a lot of sex fantasies Every.
Speaker 1: Haven't you seen the photos?
Speaker 1: and like the 70s sci-fi conventions?
Speaker 1: Yeah, right Those are really like half orgy half sci-fi convention.
Speaker 0: But at the same time I do appreciate that Jessica was a complex very powerful car Really one of the most powerful characters in the book.
Speaker 1: I would actually say for a sci-fi book written at this time It was restrained compared to say a Robert Heinlein, which is what you get when you just let it go.
Speaker 0: Just let it go.
Speaker 0: Herbert was probably holding back all the things you expect.
Speaker 0: like Jessica surprised me a lot too because she was the one character with the most complex motivations.
Speaker 0: So she would do things.
Speaker 0: that surprised me and I don't think any other character surprised me at any point Except when Fen ring at the end was like no, we're cool I'm not I'm not gonna I'm not gonna fight you.
Speaker 0: We're good.
Speaker 0: I The footnotes we find out that he is like one gene short of being Paul Atreides.
Speaker 1: He's super badass, but he I like how he retired to like the Grey Gardens with the Emperor.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the prison planet.
Speaker 0: They were best bros Aaliyah the little sister.
Speaker 0: Mmm.
Speaker 0: I didn't know anything about her.
Speaker 1: I never heard of her before actually one of the few characters.
Speaker 1: I'd never heard the name.
Speaker 1: I knew reading but was a little girl Basically gonna be.
Speaker 1: she's basically the magical girl.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like they like putting her in this book.
Speaker 1: It's like she did some stuff But really it's just creating her in this book so that she she clearly plays you know a large role in the future.
Speaker 0: her great scenes are just when the other Ben and Jess are at like the Reverend.
Speaker 0: mother is like she's an abomination and Jessica's like dick.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and When she's kidnapped and she's sitting with the Emperor and the Baron and she's just sort of fucking with both of them It's it's like she's like a child don't like in the Prince of Nothing book There's the one young Dunyane during that one part.
Speaker 1: It definitely reminds me There are a lot of anime characters again that remind me of that.
Speaker 1: Yeah The girl the psychic girl in one punch man, or you know, there's a lot of those You know person who looks like a little girl or is a little girl But like you you imagine them like sitting on a fence like Humpty Dumpty kicking their legs and like sass and everybody.
Speaker 1: That kind of scene.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: You know that kind of.
Speaker 0: I like how the Emperor thinks he's got her as this powerful Leverage and tool against Paul and he's using her to mess with the Baron because the Baron's done at that point.
Speaker 0: but then she Starts scaring the Emperor and the Emperor's like, you know what I could do to you.
Speaker 0: and she's like no you won't you're gonna die You're all gonna die.
Speaker 0: You're all fucked.
Speaker 0: Oh Wow, we talked about how like.
Speaker 0: we talked about that Emperor, right?
Speaker 1: The Emperor is actually like.
Speaker 1: he's not like, you know, he's not super good.
Speaker 1: He's not super evil Like he's just he's an emperor.
Speaker 1: He's obviously like he's not a chump.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know you think like, you know a lot of times you get an emperor who's a chump or something like that.
Speaker 0: There's a reason why his family's been in power for 10,000 years and it's not just that the Bene Gesserit made that happen, right?
Speaker 1: It's like he's actually pretty good at being an emperor.
Speaker 1: He's like really confident and you know, he's doing what he can do and the really only reason he goes down is because Paul too strong, yep, but I also like how He definitely has some honor and he actually likes the Duke a lot.
Speaker 0: Yeah, he would.
Speaker 1: he hates the Baron Yeah, he's forced into helping the Baron Yeah, but it's like, you know Fenring and you know Lido or like it would be his best buds.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know, it's just he's the Emperor so he can't be best buds too much.
Speaker 0: He's not really human anymore in the sense that he's almost just like this archetype all of that static society.
Speaker 0: So there's almost a side argument to be made that people like him like all the leaders of these houses They also lost their humanity because they're just instruments of this static system.
Speaker 0: Yep, like no one's human anymore in trying to remain human No one is human.
Speaker 1: Also, you know, it's pretty much like the guild really runs the show.
Speaker 0: Yeah Where's the guild?
Speaker 0: also as we learn socks and what they do, yeah, they messed up real bad.
Speaker 0: They could have had everything and they're they're actually the biggest jumps.
Speaker 0: I think in the entire book.
Speaker 1: It's weird, right?
Speaker 1: It's like everyone's bound down to the chumps But really they're just.
Speaker 0: ooh when Paul goes them in the end He's like I'll destroy it all they're like and you think like they're gonna be like.
Speaker 0: no you won't.
Speaker 0: But they can see the future and they look at each other and they're like, ah shit.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you got us But that's the thing is big, you know that.
Speaker 1: That's another thing.
Speaker 1: this book does that nerds love right?
Speaker 1: Is it?
Speaker 1: it has this sort of this fake science magic system, right?
Speaker 1: You know talk about this in Prince of Nothing also with the the gnosis, right?
Speaker 1: so instead of the gnosis is this sort of biological thing going on with how do the worms work and the spice and what a little makers that has all these hits that Water and that is it.
Speaker 1: How could we have not have even mentioned water until now?
Speaker 0: So cuz we're not from it We don't understand the importance of water, right?
Speaker 0: But the.
Speaker 1: so there's like.
Speaker 1: they created this whole fake biological system Which is basically the magic system of the universe.
Speaker 1: Yep that for nerds to eat up on right and at the same time It's a really sort of like Like.
Speaker 0: there's the story's kind of like a spice and wolf is about like debasing silver and currency.
Speaker 0: Yeah, this spice spice and wolf.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: This book is about Like just basic environmentalism and like cycles and planets and things.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: But so, you know, they tie that in there, right and by bringing that in.
Speaker 1: they created this sort of like dependent Cycle so that like yeah, they need the spice But it's like the guild is in charge of everything because they control the space travel Even though technically the chome company is right.
Speaker 1: Well, that's another we were talking about.
Speaker 1: the chome thing is the coolest scariest thing that we don't actually know a lot about Right, so that it's like but the spice comes from this planet with the Fremen on it.
Speaker 1: It's like.
Speaker 1: but so everyone's sort of interdependent in this circle.
Speaker 1: So no one can really just be on top of everything and just run the show.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and that's what allows For that fundamental structure that involves like this ecological thing Right is what allows for this political intrigue and wheelings and dealings of people trying to basically get ahead You know and get leverage against the other people in the same system, right?
Speaker 1: So you had a chome thing.
Speaker 1: That's the one weird thing.
Speaker 1: You have an emperor who rules.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you've got the land Noble you have been addressed or it's a sort of like Infused the entire galaxy with like their religion.
Speaker 1: ish in there.
Speaker 1: What's out?
Speaker 1: What do they call it?
Speaker 0: Oh, whatever that they like precede the religion.
Speaker 0: What do they call that?
Speaker 0: I already forget.
Speaker 1: I forget what it's called.
Speaker 1: But basically they went.
Speaker 1: they went around everywhere preceding like these knowledge in knowledge and superstitions into everyone.
Speaker 0: So some random been adjusted like when Jessica is just like, oh, okay I see how they treated the myth.
Speaker 0: if I say these words, they'll think I'm a goddess or whatever.
Speaker 1: Let's rock Yeah, and then you have the guild who controls all space travels.
Speaker 1: Yep, right So I get the.
Speaker 1: and then you have all these dukes and barons who are like under you know Like different Kings basically underneath the Emperor cuz they ever can't just run everything right.
Speaker 1: and then you have this lands dread And that's the noble houses.
Speaker 0: That's like the counterbalance.
Speaker 0: That's like old magnet pre-magnet Carta style nonsense.
Speaker 0: That's like the nobles who are ostensibly together equal in power to the Emperor and the Emperor nominally rules at their consent.
Speaker 1: Yep, that kind of like the Commission of the NFL rules the consent of the owners of all the team.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's how they have the convention.
Speaker 0: Like if you use an atomic will destroy your entire planet.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: And then you had this chome company that everyone has shares in.
Speaker 1: everyone has shares in the chome company.
Speaker 1: If you have enough shares you get like a. you get a directorship or something in the company missionary or protective?
Speaker 0: Uh, yeah, thank you Lord truck, right?
Speaker 1: That's what it's called.
Speaker 1: Right?
Speaker 1: So you have.
Speaker 1: it's like.
Speaker 1: so you're a duke and you have represented in the lands dread.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you also have a seat at the chome company.
Speaker 1: Not all dukes do not all dukes do but like a seat of the chome company is the most valuable thing.
Speaker 1: But it's like and the chome company own the guild.
Speaker 1: not really There's a bunch of.
Speaker 0: even at the end when Is ready to be the God Emperor of all?
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: He still is like I can get guy can get gurney like a directorship in the chome company.
Speaker 0: Yep, like that's you can't just give him an entire paradise planet.
Speaker 0: You're the God Emperor.
Speaker 0: How dangerous is this company and what exactly does it actually do?
Speaker 1: and when I like there was one really important.
Speaker 1: See the biggest thing revealed I think about the chome company, which I'm sure it gets revealed much more in other books.
Speaker 1: Yeah, is that there's a scene very close to the end when the Emperor's already landed on the planet.
Speaker 1: He set up his little temporary castle.
Speaker 1: Yep, and they're looking to see like what flag he puts up And he oh, yeah Cuz he doesn't put up if he puts up like the Duke's Lido's flag is basically acknowledging that Paul runs the shit.
Speaker 0: And if he puts up the hard code, it was an hour Conan flag.
Speaker 1: It's like art.
Speaker 1: Let's fight Yo, but he could have put up his own flag, I guess.
Speaker 1: but he puts up the chome flag, which is like All right.
Speaker 1: Okay So it's like who runs the who's like.
Speaker 1: is it just?
Speaker 1: who are the other directors of chome like?
Speaker 1: what the deal?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: It's not super well explained Sinister and terrifying whatever it is and they even tell you what the letters stand for.
Speaker 0: I forget But it's just like a normal corporate sounding.
Speaker 0: You know what it is.
Speaker 0: It's one of those mega corpse in like a net run, but there's only one of them Yeah, and it runs everything like what.
Speaker 1: like what's the deal?
Speaker 1: Yeah Yeah, I don't know.
Speaker 0: so the Baron Harkonnen like.
Speaker 0: there are heel characters and stories That Frank Herbert went out of his way to make the Baron the most vile Possible being to make you hate him over Literally anyone else in these books.
Speaker 1: Is it fat shaming to the vet?
Speaker 1: It's like like they make him fat to a degree that requires science fiction Yep to hold up his fat off the grass because otherwise he can't want pedophile.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they make him a murderous pedophile And he doesn't seem to have any motivation other than selfishness and greed.
Speaker 1: yeah, he just wants fade to take over when he dies because he likes fad and Doesn't like anyone is why he just wants what he likes because that's what he wants cuz he's a bad guy.
Speaker 1: He doesn't have like a reason or any nobility or anything.
Speaker 1: He just wants power and money.
Speaker 1: and What do you want?
Speaker 0: He kind of reminds me of in Prince of Nothing.
Speaker 1: There's the president of our country.
Speaker 0: Well, yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah I was gonna make only way more confident.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I would actually rather have the Baron Harkonnen than Trump because the Baron wouldn't fuck up on purpose.
Speaker 0: Sure, like the Baron might fuck up.
Speaker 0: But look who the Baron would have succeeded if it weren't that he was the least dangerous person.
Speaker 0: It also the danger room.
Speaker 1: It also doesn't seem like the people who living in Harkonnen had any bad were like living a bad time Until the Baron spends all the money he spent.
Speaker 1: remember he spell.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah Just It seemed like his kingdom or whatever you call it that a Baron has was actually not really the worst place But he spent all his money in his treasury to fuck up the Duke Leto the good Duke and then that ruined his own country.
Speaker 0: Ostensibly was because he wanted fade to become the Emperor and he had this whole plan.
Speaker 1: You know, there aren't any stuff like.
Speaker 1: I'm sure there might have been but you don't read a lot in this book.
Speaker 0: Hanet Ober advancing mercantiles.
Speaker 1: Sure.
Speaker 1: It doesn't talk a lot about for example, like the Baron You know genociding his people or anything like that.
Speaker 1: Like.
Speaker 1: yeah, it doesn't seem like it was bad.
Speaker 0: You do see the slave pits and the fights.
Speaker 1: those weren't Harkonnen people.
Speaker 0: Yeah Well kind of like how in the Sardaric or Sardaric or Sardaric are occur.
Speaker 0: They the ones who survived the prison planet live like God Kings except that they are expected to die if there's a fight.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean that's you know, it's like alright look you're basically a God King when you're not working but your job is awful.
Speaker 1: It's like being underwater welder you get paid a fortune
Speaker 0: you might die and you
Speaker 1: might die in your job because it's super fucking dangerous Yeah, or like being a professional athlete Yeah during your when it's your job You have to train and do all this ridiculous intense labor for a very short, you know, 10 20 Maybe 15 years of your life, you know, it's horrible suffering.
Speaker 1: But when you're not working and when you retire you're gonna be the multi-millionaire.
Speaker 0: So I kind of liked Peter to ride like as a weird sort of like like.
Speaker 0: he seemed like I thought he was gonna be The square boss like the real villain.
Speaker 0: Oh, really?
Speaker 0: Okay, then they just went down like a chump like right away.
Speaker 0: Yep, and that was just.
Speaker 0: he was interesting.
Speaker 0: He reminded me of the assassin guy in the prince of nothing and he reminded me This is the original the Baron's original mentat.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right the one wasn't.
Speaker 1: He wasn't as good as who wants a whole lot replaced him.
Speaker 1: He was also addicted to spice and like super nihilist and I thought he was addicted to something else.
Speaker 1: That wasn't spice.
Speaker 0: No, you're thinking of I think oh, he's the other guy.
Speaker 0: you're thinking of Harford Nefad.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the guards addicted to that music dress the captain of the guard just like dies randomly.
Speaker 1: So the Baron just picks a new captain of the guard in a very Darth Vader and I was about to say Admiral neats Admiral.
Speaker 0: Yeah can Nefad.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but the admiral neat basically is addicted to some kind of drug.
Speaker 0: That's the Emperor something like that.
Speaker 1: It seems like it was basically like some sort of cyber drug where it's like involved movies in VR.
Speaker 0: He'd like take a drug and then listen to weird music at the same time.
Speaker 1: Yeah, something like that.
Speaker 1: That guy I'd be addicted to that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that guy was not the worst like.
Speaker 0: he was surprisingly competent Yeah, and the things the Baron was mad at him for were not like the most important things.
Speaker 0: No Fade was actually the most dangerous to the Baron.
Speaker 0: The Baron's only goal is to make Fade the Emperor and the Fade just keeps trying to kill the Baron.
Speaker 1: Yeah like It's not fat and disgusting.
Speaker 1: Oh my god, my disgusting uncle.
Speaker 1: Well, he's in charge.
Speaker 1: I hate.
Speaker 0: it's just like ultra ambitious and that seems to be his soul like Fade didn't actually seem to be.
Speaker 1: Usually when you cease like, you know that story of someone trying to put their evil nephew or son into power It's usually the nephew or son is also evil.
Speaker 1: Yeah in this case It's like actually if he succeeded in getting Fade route that it might be better than the Baron.
Speaker 1: It's like Fade route.
Speaker 1: that didn't seem like he was bad.
Speaker 1: No, he's mad combat.
Speaker 1: He would use dirty tricks sometimes Well, but they weren't really dirty.
Speaker 1: They were just like yeah, I poisoned my other knife.
Speaker 1: cuz you know, that's how one I like out.
Speaker 0: there's that moment where he's like Pull poison me he's poison.
Speaker 0: Paul's like yeah, you also use poison you piece of shit.
Speaker 0: We're both cheating.
Speaker 1: Don't pretend Yeah, but it's just like.
Speaker 0: he doesn't really seem like a bad person by a generally objective moral sensibility But in the context of this fucked up society, he was by far the one of the least worst people there.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if he would he's killed and replaced his uncle.
Speaker 1: it probably he might even just like stop, you know being even.
Speaker 0: but it almost makes you fantasize like if the Emperor and the fen rings and Fade and Paul and Lito were all just friends and Jessica like they could have run the world a lot better.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm Uh, let's see.
Speaker 0: Who else did we talk about?
Speaker 0: princess Arulan?
Speaker 0: You basically never I got it.
Speaker 0: I got to talk about princess Arulan, but you like how you get all her right?
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah at the beginning of every chapter There's a little you know a quote from something right and a lot of books do this.
Speaker 0: Nothing does that
Speaker 1: sure but the quote the vast majority of the quotes not a hundred percent of them but like 90 plus percent are from some fictional book that's never been actually written and the author of that fictional book is Princess Arulan and you learn as you read these a few some number of chapters in.
Speaker 1: Oh Princess Arulan is the Emperor's daughter.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and she wrote a lot of books and apparently she's writing a lot about Paul Right.
Speaker 1: He knows Paul intimate and the whole book.
Speaker 0: All I'm thinking is when she gonna show up, right?
Speaker 1: It's like so, you know, there's a some princess named Arulan.
Speaker 1: She's gonna survive Lives long enough to write all this shit about Paul and she's super close to Paul and knows everything there is to know about him.
Speaker 1: So as Paul's going along and this he's not even in the picture whatsoever except for these pre chapter Paragraph quote things.
Speaker 1: It's like when are they gonna meet?
Speaker 1: How did they get close?
Speaker 1: What's Paul doing with this other person?
Speaker 1: Does this person become princess Arulan like?
Speaker 1: because what's what's her name?
Speaker 1: The the girl that Paul actually Johnny Johnny right is like.
Speaker 1: is Johnny gonna become princess Arulan like?
Speaker 1: what's?
Speaker 1: what's the deal with that?
Speaker 0: I had no idea.
Speaker 1: and then at the very end of the book, it's like here's princess Arulan Here's her deal and it's like Oh Paul marries her for just to become Emperor in name and whatever.
Speaker 1: It doesn't give a shit about her But she's just gonna be there all the time because she's out the Empress or so Whatever it is.
Speaker 0: She seems pretty dangerous to like.
Speaker 1: Way awesome and way good like they're even like.
Speaker 1: oh, yeah, you don't have to worry about her.
Speaker 1: She's just quiet and cares about writing.
Speaker 1: just ignore her.
Speaker 1: just technically married because that way you're marrying the Emperor's daughter Technically speaking.
Speaker 0: So let's talk about the Fremen a little down fret.
Speaker 0: So spice is just oil, right?
Speaker 0: this is all like a really big metaphor for oil in the Middle East powering the international machinery of Capitalism, but what about them worms?
Speaker 0: The worms are part of that cycle.
Speaker 1: I wonder if the worms like it's even though they Even though they explain the cycle to you, right?
Speaker 1: They don't actually fully explain Everything like.
Speaker 1: is the spice a worm shit.
Speaker 1: Yeah worm vomit Disintegrated worm, you know skins like like what like what, you know, and then it's like oh Well, if you mix the spice with water you get this other magical poison shit, and it's like how does that fucking work?
Speaker 0: I think it's a much more important point.
Speaker 1: There is this, you know, the spice smells like cinnamon So you just put it in all your fucking food.
Speaker 0: It's like oh my god one like leotkien's and the ecologists and the scientists and the Fremen all understand how this works.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and if anyone else had spent any time studying it they could have also figured out how them to study it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and they because they're providing the guild with spice.
Speaker 1: they you know, they created this.
Speaker 1: they create this.
Speaker 1: the you know Frank Herbert created this structure where oh the guild desperately needs the spice.
Speaker 1: the Fremen give the spice to the guild.
Speaker 1: Therefore the guild protect the secret of the spice right and so forth.
Speaker 1: Yeah And the guild knows the Fremen can destroy all the spice but because water is toxic It's really good, you know.
Speaker 0: or to the make yet.
Speaker 0: This is like the makers or whatever.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: I Suspect that if you make the planet habitable and livable the spice disappears.
Speaker 1: That's why you have to make only part of the planet because there's already that other plot about hell.
Speaker 0: planets make the most dangerous people.
Speaker 0: Yeah, help.
Speaker 0: you need hell planets to fuel the hell machinery of the society.
Speaker 1: or you just don't make any dangerous people.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but then you also.
Speaker 1: but there are dangerous people already existing So they're just gonna run everything unless you make other dangerous people to fight them.
Speaker 1: Yeah and it just so happens that we're.
Speaker 1: the story was in such a situation where the sour dark hours are the most dangerous.
Speaker 1: people actually use their dangerous abilities.
Speaker 1: and Then they encountered the Fremen who are actually the most dangerous.
Speaker 1: people just weren't revealing or using their dangerousness.
Speaker 1: And then this is the story of you know, the beast is unleashed Here they go.
Speaker 0: but there's also that very simple obvious metaphor of Spices oil.
Speaker 0: people exploit the oil because it runs Lawrence of Arabia.
Speaker 1: Yeah, he goes into the desert He comes back, you know and fight grabs the desert people in fights against the man.
Speaker 0: But I like how leotkine seems to be Pretty like.
Speaker 0: he seems like actually the most baddest ass of all the characters because in that dinner party scene He's like the one who's in the most control.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm You don't see them too much.
Speaker 1: Yeah They don't do a lot.
Speaker 0: you feel like they're cool and you're like gurney and the one guy one of the two like they hang Out and there's all these scenes with them.
Speaker 1: But the one thing I do is like I want to say is that before reading the book, right?
Speaker 1: Like I knew the word Fremen.
Speaker 1: I knew the Fremen were the mysterious desert people.
Speaker 1: but I got the idea before reading this that the Fremen were like literally Mysterious desert people like like you really don't see them, you know They're sort of like, you know cloaked figures in the dark and you don't like
Speaker 0: the ale were for like the first half of the wheel Of time.
Speaker 1: right exactly, right?
Speaker 1: It's like oh, what's their deal?
Speaker 1: But no, it's like this walk up like yo, I'm Fremen.
Speaker 1: How's it going?
Speaker 0: Oh Lord Crunk is giving me like the details of this life cycle of the sandworm in here.
Speaker 1: But anyway, it's just like, you know, it's like yeah, I'm a Fremen person.
Speaker 1: How you doing?
Speaker 1: Like right away.
Speaker 0: Oh, you wanna know still see works.
Speaker 1: Let's go as soon as they land on the planet.
Speaker 1: It's like this that basically housekeeping Fremen lady and she just like mopey.
Speaker 0: Yeah, baby.
Speaker 1: Yeah, maybe she's like, hey, how you doing?
Speaker 0: And it's like, oh, I guess Fremen's are just out and about and then you get the backstory of the Fremen were a chaste Genocided people from somewhere else and were forced onto this plan, right?
Speaker 1: Right, but it's super long ago.
Speaker 1: But I'm saying like I had the wrong impression.
Speaker 1: Like I had the right impression about Baron Harkonnen.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know I the only.
Speaker 0: I thought the ramen would be inscrutable and they were just literally like well We're in the Fremen now.
Speaker 0: Yep, Fremen from the Fremen.
Speaker 0: Yep, the worms.
Speaker 0: What's the worm riding?
Speaker 0: No, they literally just put hooks on there at worms and ride them.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like really straightforward.
Speaker 0: It's not even magic.
Speaker 0: Oh, if you hook it open it tries to keep it out of the sand.
Speaker 0: So it rolls over on his back and then you're good to go like it's.
Speaker 1: yeah It doesn't want to rub its hooked area on the sand.
Speaker 1: That would hurt.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if I got hooked I don't want to rub my wound in sand Even though I'm a sandworm.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I mean I'm a. I don't want my hooked wound to be like in out in the air.
Speaker 0: Even I want a band-aid on it or something.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: I can like rub it against my bike seat.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and it's like the worm doesn't really notice that there's like a tiny person on it.
Speaker 1: It doesn't give a shit.
Speaker 0: So I guess because we've talked a lot.
Speaker 0: so the only other thing I really want to point out is that what I thought was really interesting is that So little is described in detail that it is very hard to visualize literally anything except for like a few people's faces and A handful of the devices that they use.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like they don't really.
Speaker 1: What's gurney's guitar thing called a balisette.
Speaker 1: yeah, it's a real instrument about it Yeah, but they describe that balance describe him the ornithopter even like they describe it.
Speaker 0: But I've seen so many different renditions how people drew.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, they talk about like oh the the spice collecting thing.
Speaker 1: I imagine it looking basically like the thing that the Star Wars again Jawas.
Speaker 1: oh, yeah, I imagined it being like a big Jawa tank thing.
Speaker 0: I imagine more like this giant scarab beetle just like scuttering over the land.
Speaker 1: Maybe you know But it was big and they had it had treads and it was hard to get it out of there.
Speaker 0: Landscapes and planetary stuff and like were described in detail and so are specific things like.
Speaker 0: some still suit stuff But most things were described based on like How they matter to the people but not in any actual.
Speaker 1: they would describe what a thing did what it was named how it moved But not what things look like.
Speaker 1: what.
Speaker 1: this is Lou are not a lot of adjectives and those sorts of words used to describe What things looked like what shape they were.
Speaker 1: well color they were.
Speaker 0: that explains why all the art I've ever seen related to doing is super abstract and weird.
Speaker 1: I kind of like that our style though.
Speaker 0: I do like the art style in the board game.
Speaker 0: They have a lot of Hill board game.
Speaker 1: No, that's all right.
Speaker 0: That's good stuff.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm Like you serve for Dune art on Google Imager.
Speaker 1: It's like you see a lot of good stuff.
Speaker 1: Yeah So there's a movie about this.
Speaker 1: I haven't seen.
Speaker 1: people say like a lot of crazy shit about it and David Lynch did it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so positive or negative.
Speaker 1: I feel like I have to see it for the same reason.
Speaker 1: I had to read the book easy Thursday show, right?
Speaker 0: Sure.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but people say it's bad.
Speaker 0: But I still do this.
Speaker 0: they don't know if they say it's bad because they love the book and it's not perfect or what?
Speaker 0: I mean, I like a lot of movies that I also want to see that Joe Durovsky's Dune Documentary because I feel like that could have been the good Dune.
Speaker 1: Oh, there's a documentary about the Dune that they didn't make.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I heard about that too.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I feel like we should watch that too and do a show on it.
Speaker 1: I think you know.
Speaker 1: But in a way does making a movie about it ruin the.
Speaker 1: the fact that you used to use your imagination For all of these things that aren't described and how they look I feel like giving them an actual concrete, you know picture Right sort of.
Speaker 1: take that away a bit.
Speaker 0: I feel like if you animated it instead of doing live-action and made it kind of Really abstract.
Speaker 1: the problem is you can't who you gonna get to do the art.
Speaker 1: Mobius died.
Speaker 1: Yeah Who's gonna draw it?
Speaker 0: We've got to do a selective breeding program for 10,000 years to have the Mobius reborn Mobius quitter act.
Speaker 1: I feel like Mobius is really the only art style that goes to Dune in my mind.
Speaker 0: But I don't like.
Speaker 0: I enjoyed reading this book like I don't have any regrets I don't you know.
Speaker 1: I mean when I was young, I guess I couldn't even get through the first chapter and I said I didn't like it.
Speaker 0: now I'm not like.
Speaker 1: I don't think I'm not gonna say this is like it's not great.
Speaker 1: It's not like my favorite.
Speaker 1: I'm not a Dune nerd now or anything.
Speaker 1: I'm not gonna read well any more.
Speaker 0: Would have tried the next book had so many of you not warned me away from them.
Speaker 1: Maybe maybe If I you know, but it's like It was worth reading.
Speaker 1: I think if you're a nerd that you should read it, uh, you know for many reasons It's got a lot of great moments Like.
Speaker 0: I have a 10 to 10 or 15 more of those like little moments that I really enjoyed.
Speaker 1: but right I mean we've what we haven't even begin to cover like the amount of things that you can.
Speaker 1: the book is large Yeah, but you can still read it quickly.
Speaker 1: And because it's so large is just there's so many things to talk about if you have a nerdy kind of mind.
Speaker 1: So it's fun, it's enjoyable It's worth like the almost no money it cost to buy and not a lot of time it cost to read.
Speaker 1: Yep, but I can't say that this is like, you know, it gets credit for being like, you know, so legendary.
Speaker 1: Well, I don't know
Speaker 0: that may have not really been seen together
Speaker 1: and I don't know if the actual I don't I don't think it's actual quality is Worthy of its, you know legendary Hall of Fame status, but I think that it's Unprecedented nous right, you know and it's Its influence is what gets it into the Hall of Fame status, right?
Speaker 0: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at front row crew comm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 0: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 0: But unlike those other late shows It's actually recorded at night and the patreon patrons for this observe geek nights are Ellen Joyce, Heidi McNichol a manager shut and Thomas on my steady calm.
Speaker 0: William Isen rose Jeremy.
Speaker 0: minor.
Speaker 0: life and death and love and birth and peace and war on the planet earth.
Speaker 0: a genuine bonafide.
Speaker 0: electrified six car monorail Nicholas Brando Captain Chinguac see Rebecca Dunn the terrible secret of space for to one creations.
Speaker 0: That's because they're fighting each other.
Speaker 0: Shervin von Horrell rarely vile James David White Rochelle, Monta Nona Superboy I paid five bucks to make room say pickle sailor Vista Matthew Smith Don Schleicher Jartavish and Joshua Joe star.
Speaker 0: Sean Yeager Sam Cordery Clinton Walton Ren from New Zealand Ryan Perrin drew open Lander Brian's the droney Finn Chris midkiff Chris Knox Daniel Redmond Sean Klein Chris Reimer and Thomas on.
Speaker 0: don't think we'll be reading the rest of the dune books But like we said, I'm glad we read that one and now I'm gonna leave you with something that is both smooth and deadly.
Speaker 1: Oh.