Speaker 0: It's Wednesday June 14th 2017.
Speaker 0: I'm rim I'm scared, and this is geek nights tonight.
Speaker 0: It's an anime news random.
Speaker 0: Let's do this The longest time.
Speaker 0: whenever we like don't have a Monday episode We always think why don't we do a tech news roundup?
Speaker 1: we do it once a year and for some reason It's once a year around the same time every year like right around that time.
Speaker 0: We run out of tech news.
Speaker 0: We're like well.
Speaker 0: We can't do one again.
Speaker 0: We just did one.
Speaker 0: then we look and it's almost exactly a year previous Mm-hmm, but we never really do that with all the other days, and I feel like that could save us.
Speaker 1: well cuz there aren't Enough news is in any of the other categories true to make a roundup, right?
Speaker 1: And also we weren't.
Speaker 1: we were gonna do just a regular old episode reviewing something.
Speaker 1: you just didn't watch it.
Speaker 1: I've been busy.
Speaker 0: I'll watch it for the next Wednesday show and I'll read that manga that you saw me by Literally before he started streaming, and I'll be going to London, so there's no excuse to not read it.
Speaker 0: In fact there's no excuse not to watch the thing either because I have the Now that you can offline watch a lot of the anime on Netflix is in the offline things like gonna watch it like on my Flight mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: so I can watch the thing and read the manga which I've seen everywhere And I just never read for some reason.
Speaker 0: cuz actually when I looked at that cover again It actually looked like the kind of thing I would like.
Speaker 0: so uh Yeah, guess we'll just get right into our anime manga comic and related media news, but first Things of the day, so what do you got?
Speaker 1: so this Austria?
Speaker 1: I think it's an Australian guy.
Speaker 0: this guy sounds so Australian 90% sure it's Australian guy.
Speaker 1: He goes to the beach and one of the things you do at the beach besides swimming is Digging a hole in the sand.
Speaker 1: because what else you got to do with Sam?
Speaker 1: besides dig a hole I'll build a castle out of fun fact.
Speaker 0: when I was a kid like young kid we'd go to the beach up in Northern Michigan every year and One day us and all the other like kids like relative kids and neighbor kids We just started digging a hole and we dug a real deep hole.
Speaker 0: And then we got the idea to cover it in sticks.
Speaker 0: cover those sticks and leaves cover that those leaves and sand Mm-hmm, and then we left it there and we're giggling about it all day.
Speaker 0: and finally our parents like what are you guys all giggling about?
Speaker 0: And we're like we left a man-trap on the beach.
Speaker 0: We explained what we're doing and I remember so clearly.
Speaker 0: all the parents kind of look at each other.
Speaker 0: And then one of the dads was like oh shit And they like run to the beach to find this thing and dismantle it before someone died.
Speaker 1: I once made a tiny hole.
Speaker 1: It was only like maybe a foot deep and I was putting sticks in it upright.
Speaker 0: Oh, that's even worse.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, at least he didn't poop on the sticks, right?
Speaker 1: And then I went no and then I went to test it and I cut my foot a little bit Like you got a sword.
Speaker 0: you're like gonna test the sword.
Speaker 1: He's like I didn't want to matter want to make you want to make sure someone would actually fall through the top and I just walk across safely.
Speaker 1: I cut my foot a little bit and I was like, oh, this is actually I actually made a real trap.
Speaker 0: Awesome There's definitely a young age were like swords and traps seem like the coolest thing in the world because you don't quite the world needs A lot more traps.
Speaker 1: I say yeah, not enough traps.
Speaker 1: I come alone style coolest part not even when you play D&D the place you're supposed to encounter traps.
Speaker 1: There aren't enough of them.
Speaker 1: people don't use traps enough instead.
Speaker 0: All we get is occasional electrified manhole Which is not cool, even when I made like burning wheel micro dungeons like for old burning cons and things I only had like two or three traps.
Speaker 1: Everyone's always like.
Speaker 1: I check the door for traps to check the chest for traps.
Speaker 1: Yes, and there's never any fucking traps anywhere.
Speaker 1: It's like dude just trap it up.
Speaker 1: Come on people love traps.
Speaker 0: I remember long ago playing a D&D game.
Speaker 1: what you got to do is put a trap on the door where they know it's gonna be.
Speaker 1: But also they check they check for trap.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and they they find the trap and they pick the lock and dismantle the trap and they feel all great and they're like All right, we met our trap quota and then you get him with a good old Stone rolling down the hallway trap or no, you're a step on the plate on the floor trap.
Speaker 0: You got a stone rolling trap that goes toward the door and it's triggered by successfully picking the lock on the door.
Speaker 0: I'm just saying so has a trap.
Speaker 1: I'm just saying you got to get him with the traps.
Speaker 1: They're not thinking about traps.
Speaker 0: We should do a gig not one.
Speaker 0: to an episode on traps Thursday show.
Speaker 1: I got nothing else to say about traps except we need more.
Speaker 0: come up with traps.
Speaker 1: Let's trap people.
Speaker 0: Yeah Next episode of gig nights why rim and scott are in jail.
Speaker 1: podcast from jail.
Speaker 0: So anyway, I super interrupted you on your thing of the day.
Speaker 1: Oh, this guy's in Australia and he's digging a hole in the sand, but not to put a trap in it.
Speaker 1: Well, although digging a hole in the sand is this deep may be dangerous to yourself.
Speaker 1: Don't yeah?
Speaker 0: Oh, seriously, a lot of kids die every year by digging holes in the piece.
Speaker 1: Danger imagine if you're at six feet tall and you did like I'm 511 right and I dig a hole in the sand.
Speaker 1: It's like eight feet and I go in and then the sand caves in on me if it's covering my head and I People can't pull me out of there.
Speaker 0: They're done.
Speaker 1: I die the end.
Speaker 1: So anyway, this guy digs a hole in the sand.
Speaker 1: it's deep enough to stand in for sure and His goal is to make sort of like an underground Living shed tent area a to you people make something you'll see like depending on certain beaches people like bring tents or bring portable huts or Like.
Speaker 0: they'll make a semi-permanent structure for like their month-long beach vacation Like that's where they go hang out every day and they leave their beach stuff in the shade.
Speaker 0: This is that plus a basement.
Speaker 1: Yeah, he made a two stories of basement Followed by a hut on the surface area the surface level.
Speaker 0: I want to.
Speaker 0: I just want to go to a beach where I'm living.
Speaker 0: I'm hanging out at the beach long enough to where this is a feasible idea.
Speaker 1: I want to lock the door and then fill it with water because traps.
Speaker 0: I Did not expect you to bring it back so soon.
Speaker 0: So my thing today is definitely not a trap.
Speaker 0: so, you know, there's a genre of YouTube video that is someone plays a song Accompanied by a thing that is not a musical instrument like a washing machine that makes a weird noise.
Speaker 0: or there's a famous one of this like country band playing a song where there's this tractor idling and the tractor idling is the drums for The song.
Speaker 0: that kind of thing.
Speaker 0: This video is one of those and you'll see those videos are all linked here.
Speaker 0: Like there'll be the recommended videos for you probably But this escalates so far beyond what you expect.
Speaker 0: So there's a thing that'll happen if you have shitty pipes in certain kinds of like old pipe fixtures Where if you turn the faucet on to certain points the pipes will drone like they'll make a droning sound
Speaker 1: Because the speed of the water going through resonates with the pipe and makes it shake and vibrate.
Speaker 0: Yeah Coupled with the mechanism of the faucet kind of like how you can get water hammers and all those other things that'll happen.
Speaker 0: Oh water hammers water hammers are bad fucking news, but they're fun.
Speaker 0: They are fun until like the pipe in the basement at the apartment You're renting literally explodes because you water hammered too much.
Speaker 1: I don't live in the basement.
Speaker 1: So that's fine.
Speaker 0: But there's another thing they'll do where they'll do that in a rhythm and all sorts of nonsense can happen with pipes.
Speaker 0: So my video is simply and you just have to watch it triple concerto for faucet water pipes and fiddle.
Speaker 0: And when you start watching this you'll think all right, that's pretty cool.
Speaker 0: And then he escalates it a little bit.
Speaker 0: he incorporates the water pipes and the faucet to a degree that is Really legit.
Speaker 0: like this is good stuff here.
Speaker 0: This is one of my favorite things that I have ever found.
Speaker 0: We watched it over the weekend and it's pretty good.
Speaker 0: Maybe I'll put it as the stinger instead of weird internet shit this time.
Speaker 0: Hmm So I in the meta moment the booklet book is Frank Herbert's Dune.
Speaker 1: I started reading.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna read start reading it like this weekend.
Speaker 0: Uh We'll see how Doonie we get maybe a live tweet.
Speaker 1: I just want to say like, you know I'm a nerd who knows about Dune even though I never finished reading it before and haven't read it at all since middle school and In just chapter one.
Speaker 1: They've already introduced every single proper noun.
Speaker 1: I've ever heard anyone used to talk about Dune.
Speaker 0: So on a scale of Cat in the Hat as a zero and prince and nothing is cat in the Hat zero I don't know.
Speaker 0: It's cat hat.
Speaker 1: You don't like cat in the Hat.
Speaker 0: I'm not saying I don't like it.
Speaker 0: I'm saying the number of proper nouns introduced in that book approaches zero.
Speaker 0: Oh, it's true come for Anna tan is the prince of nothing.
Speaker 0: Where does Dune sit for you so far?
Speaker 1: Well, it's not the number of proper nouns.
Speaker 1: It's that a Unlike Prince of Nothing which uses the price say this when we do the book of episode again.
Speaker 1: Anyway, but Prince of Nothing uses proper nouns that have been invented based on languages of the world.
Speaker 1: So you can sort of get a feel of like a Latin root or something on a lot of words to sort of guess at Their meanings like I'll sort of tell.
Speaker 1: that feels like the name of a place that feels like the name of a person.
Speaker 1: that Feels sort of like, you know Middle Eastern kind of word, right?
Speaker 0: That kind of thing where and that's all consistent like the aesthetic is Consistent so you can make inferences inferences that make sense.
Speaker 1: the words in the proper nouns in Dune had Their their structure gives you no sense to their meaning.
Speaker 1: the best Sam a flange right and then it's.
Speaker 1: sometimes some of them get explained And some of them are just like all right.
Speaker 1: There's a proper now and I have to wait till I see it again And then once they explain it come back and read this again To see what the hell they were saying.
Speaker 0: Otherwise you should go to Scott's YouTube channel and my youtube channel because we're both uploaded a lot of stuff.
Speaker 0: Yeah Utena show is coming back.
Speaker 0: I think I talked about this last time but This Wednesday, so I really want to bring it up again.
Speaker 0: as you know We haven't done a geek nice presents Utena analysis episode in a while And part of that is because half the fucking videos were taken down by copyright.
Speaker 0: I have done the work.
Speaker 0: I filed like 50 notifications and counter notifications.
Speaker 0: all of the series We've done to date is back on YouTube free and clear.
Speaker 0: you can watch them.
Speaker 0: So finally we can start the production pipeline up again pretty much right after Kinetic on.
Speaker 0: so like middle of July We're gonna start making the Utena videos again, like everything the stars are aligned and When he gets the news, we'll talk about it.
Speaker 0: It's a good time to start doing the Utena stuff again.
Speaker 0: I'm feeling Utena a lot lately.
Speaker 1: You should also follow us and all the places on the internet that you can follow people Twitter Right.
Speaker 1: We even have a Facebook that There are some people that go there.
Speaker 1: it's really just messages that are automatic like hey new episode Like g-plus like there's comments in there and stuff.
Speaker 0: I guess We get a lot of fans.
Speaker 1: We also I have a geek nice Instagram account that I haven't used but I think like for now like when we do stuff like Go to a convention or there's a geek night's activity.
Speaker 1: I'll post some photos there.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'll find me Where I post like okay like old episodes and like things there and that has like its own feeds.
Speaker 0: The moral is we have fans.
Speaker 1: I mean you're already listening to the stupid podcast.
Speaker 1: It's kind of the wrong place to spread this message.
Speaker 1: Yeah But then again I think like there's a lot of people to all those places and tell you and in each of the places talk about all the Other places we have like a forum community.
Speaker 0: That's kind of separate from our YouTube community Which is separate from like the people in iTunes.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you can go to the forum also at front.
Speaker 0: recruit calm our forums pretty baller Like it's.
Speaker 0: I hang out there because it's actually like a pretty great.
Speaker 1: make sure that when you register for it There's a little box that says why are you joining?
Speaker 1: a lot of people write things in there?
Speaker 1: For discussion, oh you're about to meet right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, I might have rejected people who might have been real people.
Speaker 1: You have to write something in there that like lets us know that.
Speaker 1: yes You are really someone who you know knows what gig night says or something.
Speaker 1: Yep You know some examples of things people have written there, you know have been like.
Speaker 1: I want to listen.
Speaker 1: You know, I have something to say to these two morons Something along those.
Speaker 1: what a sock on your head to prove you're done Right, you know something like that, you know people will write in the in that box and that will get your you know Registration approved.
Speaker 1: if you write something else you won't get approved.
Speaker 0: and also if you go to my youtube channel We started doing this.
Speaker 0: This is originally a patreon goal, but I just I made a pipeline to this.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so like fucking I'll just do it.
Speaker 0: We live stream like most of the geek nights episodes like as we record them.
Speaker 0: I'm also live streaming them.
Speaker 0: It's on YouTube right now.
Speaker 0: There are nine people watching and they're talking about Plumbing the nine saddest people.
Speaker 0: they know stuff about plumbing and pipes.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there's a bunch of.
Speaker 0: there's a lot of stuff going in here because because someone here big fan first time catching you two live Talking about pipes talking about traps talking about mouse trap pipe trap.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Anyway sad people.
Speaker 0: but uh As you might know many of you might not realize but geek nice.
Speaker 0: We've been doing this for like 12 years.
Speaker 0: We record straight to tape like geek nights is not edited the lie.
Speaker 0: The only difference between the live stream and the podcast is that one the live stream.
Speaker 0: you see our faces.
Speaker 0: You see that we don't look at each other and the Scott has his eyes closed for most of the show.
Speaker 1: What's there?
Speaker 0: look at rims head now the back of my head because we don't even look at each other.
Speaker 0: my like thinning hairline right there, but You also see when we pause in the middle of the episode and transfer from like news bit to main bit And occasionally you'll see us trying to figure out what the hell to do the show on.
Speaker 0: so there's biz in there.
Speaker 0: Oh, the chat just keeps going.
Speaker 0: I can't keep up with that.
Speaker 1: So otherwise ten people such it's such a chat You couldn't possibly keep up with.
Speaker 0: well cuz I gotta look here to do that.
Speaker 0: But I gotta look here to get ready for the next bit of the show.
Speaker 0: Uh-huh.
Speaker 0: Woo.
Speaker 0: He read my comment.
Speaker 0: They're excited.
Speaker 0: We're averaging one message a minute.
Speaker 0: The most people we've ever had watched the show live at one time was like 30 and I was during the barbecue episode.
Speaker 0: cuz I guess food Somebody.
Speaker 0: if we just did geek night's food.
Speaker 0: I think we'd actually have more fans.
Speaker 1: Probably said the cameras in the kitchen, you know, we don't know anything about food.
Speaker 1: I know how to cook some things.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I know how to cook some things.
Speaker 0: I don't know how to do like a food show though, cuz I don't know it's like the barbecue show.
Speaker 0: We don't shit about barbecue.
Speaker 0: No, so I guess let's get right into it with our anime news roundup.
Speaker 0: So first things first.
Speaker 0: Uh Utena was a manga by Chiyo Saito and an anime by B Pappas which is sort of like a collaboration of Chiyo Saito and Ikuhara and all these other like important people and It's kind of like a unique and magic show.
Speaker 0: There's a reason we did.
Speaker 0: we're doing like an entire YouTube chat like show around trying to analyze this.
Speaker 0: It's like the Hawthorne Anime, like there's nothing else like it.
Speaker 0: but if you got really into Utena, you might have read the manga like Ostensibly, it is a big part of the source material of Utena and you might have wondered why.
Speaker 0: it's completely different.
Speaker 0: and like Utena's Dating Toga and like no one appears to be or Toga was dating Juri like no one's homosexual.
Speaker 1: It's no one's incestual.
Speaker 0: It's real simple and not at all like the show and It is definitely important and there's a lot of reasons to talk about Chiyo Saito and like all these things But most fans of Utena don't really talk much about the manga.
Speaker 0: the manga is real old and It's coming back.
Speaker 0: There's gonna be a new Original Utena manga.
Speaker 1: So wait Chiyo Saito is writing and drawing this.
Speaker 1: Someone else.
Speaker 0: so B Pappas blah blah blah develop the manga and anime at the same time.
Speaker 0: I didn't actually read this article yet.
Speaker 1: Who's making this manga?
Speaker 1: What's it about?
Speaker 1: is it brand?
Speaker 1: is it starting from scratch?
Speaker 1: We're picking up at the as just the next volume of the manga like Utena volume Whatever.
Speaker 0: this year's July issue of Shogakukan's flowers magazine announced on Saturday that a new Utena manga will run In the September issue on July 28th.
Speaker 0: Chiyo Saito is drawing the new manga.
Speaker 0: Writing it does not say she's writing it just drawing.
Speaker 1: It's the same thing.
Speaker 1: I'm pretty sure it means she's doing it.
Speaker 0: Uh, and no one knows like more details than that as far as I can tell.
Speaker 1: well I'm sure it'll be scans laid in like two seconds.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: So, uh, I don't know.
Speaker 0: Maybe I'll give Scott the Utena manga so we can read it.
Speaker 0: Maybe we'll review it cuz I read it a long time ago Back when I was ultra obsessed with trying to like analyze Utena the first time I watched it.
Speaker 0: But uh, it's just really interesting that this is having more like old properties are coming back and oftentimes Original talent are involved again, and I feel like there's a new wave of nostalgia.
Speaker 1: That's the opposite of in America.
Speaker 1: Everything's coming back and has been coming back for many years now, but the original talent is not the ones doing it.
Speaker 1: It's like, you know, what spider-man movie has been written by Stan Lee.
Speaker 1: none.
Speaker 0: Yeah, none.
Speaker 0: Not a wonder.
Speaker 0: part of this is that the anime industry is starting to pick up again in a big way in Japan.
Speaker 0: It has its problems obviously with monetization and like the there's the industry might not be healthy But it's growing again, which wasn't the trend like ten years ago.
Speaker 0: So I wonder if that might be driving a Re-plumbing.
Speaker 1: I think it's only.
Speaker 1: it's only able to grow because of the abuse of the employees.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah working at slave wages They actually had to pay animators and and artists their amount of money that they deserve.
Speaker 1: There would be much less but much higher quality anime and manga.
Speaker 0: of course you know once we've reviewed the new Little Witch Academia TV show because there might be a model where American companies like Netflix finance the creation of anime and go big-budget and pay people that might actually soup like Little Wish Academia.
Speaker 1: Or the executives take all the money.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, and the in-betweeners are still outsourced to some rando country.
Speaker 0: I feel like Companies like Netflix investing in anime style or animation or things like this might really disrupt the Japanese Industry.
Speaker 1: We'll see.
Speaker 0: Yeah But yeah, it's just it's kind of I would have.
Speaker 0: until I read this news which is recent I would never have thought that there would ever be another Utena ever.
Speaker 1: Yeah Imagine like, you know That's like hearing like oh Yeah That thing that ended and was done for like your band that favorite band that broke up or you know What's another thing that ended?
Speaker 1: Oh, there's gonna be.
Speaker 0: there's gonna be cowboy bebop - fuck it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you're just gonna pick up off where episode.
Speaker 1: it's episode 27.
Speaker 0: There's a spin-off IO AV edit cowboy cowgirl ed and I'm gav.
Speaker 0: magical adventures Like that, that's kind of what this is like.
Speaker 1: I guess this happened already is called Star War.
Speaker 1: Yeah By the way, it's been like it's many years but Star War It's like when I was a kid.
Speaker 0: until episode one was announced I just assumed the Star Wars was a complete thing that was done forever.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm When Star Wars one was announced that was possibly the most excited I had ever been about anything ever.
Speaker 1: That episode one trailer is still like, you know, the movie was garbage.
Speaker 1: But that trailer for episode one was like the most might be the most watched trailer there ever was Yeah
Speaker 0: like someone
Speaker 1: we were downloading real media files and carrying them around so you can watch it like
Speaker 0: a BBS posted like there's gonna be a new Star Wars movie and I didn't fucking believe the guy until I saw the trailer myself
Speaker 1: Watching that I had a 486. we were watching that little video file.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we were.
Speaker 0: we used to wait like when we watch try gun at what 40p It's 40 I 20 pixels interlaced is bad.
Speaker 0: So in some other news, this is sort of related to Japan.
Speaker 0: But there was apparently you know, the answer man is a column on anime news network And I thought that column ended but I guess not.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't remember cuz I don't follow it that often Much attention, I usually only since anime news Nina ended I stopped paying attention to yeah, but I answer man is always pretty good.
Speaker 0: But they did a thing recently on like what do Taku or otaku or like in Japan?
Speaker 1: discussion is so old and I've read like so many things about where the word came from and what it means and what it Means what it meant before and all etymology.
Speaker 1: I've read everything there is to read about that and my memory doesn't serve me that well.
Speaker 0: But you know, I read all the things you would probably say if you were off-the-cuff told to explain that.
Speaker 0: yeah And the internet reacted and to have sort of a retraction slash follow-up.
Speaker 0: basically, none of the very few people in America have been paying a lot of attention to the fact that Anime fandom in Japan has actually changed a lot in the last decade.
Speaker 0: Okay and there appears to be a lot of evidence that it is actually turning a lot more into like what American anime fandom was like in the 90s.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm in that it's a lot more social.
Speaker 0: There's a lot more girls and women who are in the fandom.
Speaker 0: Oh people are more.
Speaker 1: I knew that.
Speaker 1: just look at the yellow petals in the high cues.
Speaker 1: Yeah freeze in the area and ices.
Speaker 0: but it talks about like the growth of otome road and ike bukuro and like for Joshi content being Produced more and more and more.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and how?
Speaker 0: like we know about that We're like movies like your name actually like kind of showed that anime is like getting legit mainstream But the biggest change seems to be that the stereotype of like super ultra shut-in hikikomori like those people exist.
Speaker 0: but anime like fan conventions in Japan and fan gatherings are becoming more and more social like they are in the US Mmm, and that is all fascinating.
Speaker 0: You can read this article.
Speaker 0: I'm not gonna read the article to you, but it is fascinating to see this column sort of retract the 90s 2000s view of what Japanese anime and manga fandom was like.
Speaker 0: and Actually, look at what it really is like today in 2017 because you know the world changes and stuffs different today.
Speaker 1: I think there's enough people that speak Japanese and English and are in both places that they could like he was more up-to-date on these sorts of things.
Speaker 0: But again, remember that art that book I read on the Battle of Midway.
Speaker 1: Like if I spoke a different language and went to another country, like I don't know what if I spoke Lebanese and hang out in Lebanon I would be keeping everyone in the English-speaking world up-to-date on what the fuck it's like in Lebanon now.
Speaker 0: and shit people Translating primaries.
Speaker 0: or remember the thing with the pirates in Japan like some they've translated some French document.
Speaker 0: They were like, oh shit There's history in here that we just never looked at because none of us bothered reading a translation of this thing that happens all the time.
Speaker 0: Language barriers actually really prevent like information exchange to this day and it's not because we can't translate there's no one bothers.
Speaker 1: Scott is now king of world.
Speaker 1: Everyone must learn Esperanto and Lojban.
Speaker 1: Only two only two approved languages.
Speaker 1: no more speaking any old stupid human languages.
Speaker 0: So this is probably the most important link I got here because this is a there's two big deal items.
Speaker 1: I don't know how confirmed this is.
Speaker 1: It's a picture of a poster on a wall somewhere.
Speaker 0: No, no get Genco booth at the film.
Speaker 0: some film festival revealed that like this is announced.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: So the two big things are Pluto which might be one of the best comics ever written.
Speaker 1: No, it's up Sure top hundred top 50 maybe.
Speaker 0: yeah, maybe Pluto's real fucking good.
Speaker 0: Yeah, especially because of the context of what it is.
Speaker 1: I think that's part of its.
Speaker 1: that's part of the weakness of Pluto is.
Speaker 1: maybe one of its a few weaknesses is that you have To understand the context.
Speaker 1: Otherwise a lot of it is lost on you, but I'll give you context.
Speaker 1: right after him stops talking.
Speaker 0: I'll stop.
Speaker 0: I was waiting for you.
Speaker 0: keep talking.
Speaker 0: go for it.
Speaker 1: Oh you wanted the context of Pluto.
Speaker 1: All right, so Astroboy effectively like the first anime the first real manga.
Speaker 1: maybe right anyway In Astro boy, right there is a story a sub story right that takes place.
Speaker 1: and in this story There is a robot named Pluto and he's bad guy.
Speaker 1: He's.
Speaker 1: he wants to be the strongest robot there is on the whole earth, right?
Speaker 1: So he goes around.
Speaker 1: So he goes around to all the other awesome robots on the earth who are the awesomest by the way And who are supposedly the strongest robots like Mont Blanc the mountaineer?
Speaker 1: And my favorite guy Botar who's the robot who takes care of the children And many other really badass robots.
Speaker 1: and he he says come out here you awesome robot I had to fight you and beat you to prove that I'm the strongest robot there is because that's what I want to be.
Speaker 1: the strongest robot there is.
Speaker 1: and Astro boy, of course is on the hit list, right?
Speaker 1: And in this story what takes place is basically Something that is now the tropest of tropes.
Speaker 1: the good guy gets defeated Powers up and comes back stronger than before.
Speaker 1: Astro boy gets beat up spoilers He goes back and he gets upgraded from like however many horsepower.
Speaker 1: He was before up to a million.
Speaker 1: I forget what the exact number is But it just pretend that he used to be a thousand horsepower and is now a million horsepower and he comes back Right.
Speaker 1: and you see that happen in every anime ever.
Speaker 1: Oh, no Goku got defeated.
Speaker 1: He'll come back.
Speaker 1: He's super saiyan.
Speaker 1: now Right, you can see that in real.
Speaker 1: it's like this is the North star or like every single shonen story and a lot of other stories right Your superhero?
Speaker 1: or even even in non super stories Somebody is the main character on their journey.
Speaker 1: his face is a setback.
Speaker 1: They go and train and level up somehow and they come back right and Pluto is as far as I can tell like the first main Exact.
Speaker 1: I can't find an older Example of that trope that is so clear and distinct that every later thing, you know borrows from right?
Speaker 0: So but it's just one like story.
Speaker 0: It's like an arc in Astro boy, right?
Speaker 1: So it's just a story arc in Astro boy that this happens in but it establishes this trope for all time, right?
Speaker 1: So if you look at all the other iterations of Astro boy, right the different anime series all three of them
Speaker 0: I think the 80s one might be the most like the
Speaker 1: 80s the 80s rendition of that story I think is the best one I've seen compared to the black and white 60s one in the 2000s.
Speaker 1: One in the 2000s was Pluto's like completely different.
Speaker 1: but What happened was is this story was retold yet again, right?
Speaker 1: Urasawa the manga artist who made 20 century boys Monster Billy Bat, which I'm still waiting for in English.
Speaker 0: I haven't read it.
Speaker 1: right?
Speaker 1: all these all these terrific amazing master Keaton, right all these amazing mangas, right?
Speaker 1: He made Pluto which was how many volumes is it?
Speaker 0: I have I don't even remember have all the volumes.
Speaker 1: It's published in English.
Speaker 0: You can read it again.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I forget if it's eight or ten volumes or whatever, but it basically retells that story of Pluto.
Speaker 1: But eight book volume in eight volumes and obviously it's in the art style of Right cuz.
Speaker 1: he's drawing and writing it.
Speaker 1: but instead of telling the story from the perspective of Astro boy, it tells the story from the perspective of guess act.
Speaker 1: I think that's how you say it.
Speaker 1: G E S I C H T the German detective robot who is in the original story Just one of the super badass robots that is on the hit list of Pluto.
Speaker 0: and it is just such a beautifully told nuanced story.
Speaker 1: Yep, so he's easy retelling that exact same story again right?
Speaker 1: yet, you know dread, you know by expanding it so much and now able to go into the details and Characterize, you know really get into all the characters and explore You know, the sick character a whole lot more than you know The what few pages he had in the very original, right?
Speaker 1: So there you go.
Speaker 1: Also Astro boy itself.
Speaker 1: The manga has been almost or has been entirely reprinted now Recently by dark horse.
Speaker 1: It used to be you could get it in these tiny little volumes and needed a whole bunch of them.
Speaker 1: They printed Astro boy omnibus.
Speaker 1: you buy these books.
Speaker 1: I think maybe like eight or nine.
Speaker 1: I forget how many they made.
Speaker 1: I have a whole bunch of them And it's all of the Astro boy manga in English and it's like these fat books I still got.
Speaker 0: I have all of dr.
Speaker 0: Slump, but I only made it like three volumes into that.
Speaker 0: Good luck I gotta start bringing that on flights.
Speaker 0: You start paging through it slumping it.
Speaker 0: I didn't even finish crew Marty I got a ton of that too.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: I love from party.
Speaker 1: You want to see my unread mangas?
Speaker 1: No, you're like rims got like rims.
Speaker 1: Like I got two unread mangas.
Speaker 1: I'm like, uh-huh.
Speaker 0: All right Let me show you my unread mangas, but yeah, so This anime is gonna be real interesting and we're gonna we're gonna keep an eye on thing.
Speaker 1: Is is like.
Speaker 0: on the one hand it's exciting to popularize Pluto again but on the other hand I hated the monster anime only because The manga was so good and the anime was just the exact same thing plus music, right?
Speaker 1: So is Pluto gonna be the exact same thing as the manga in which case which urasawa is directly involved?
Speaker 0: So the answer is probably we need it.
Speaker 1: Is it necessary?
Speaker 1: I just want to see.
Speaker 1: you know, this is good stuff.
Speaker 0: controversial opinion I think.
Speaker 0: on one hand monster popularized urasawa's work and probably got more people to go read his manga, but the counterpoint is that it is Literally redundant.
Speaker 0: if you've read the comic like if you like because I had read monster the anime had nothing for me.
Speaker 1: Of course nothing, you know urasawa's other work.
Speaker 1: I didn't mention that I want the most.
Speaker 1: that is the hardest to get in English.
Speaker 1: is Yaura fashionable, you know?
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, I was forget about that one and it's not easy to get in English.
Speaker 1: So manga or anime.
Speaker 0: so the other thing that's coming back is there's gonna be a new Patlabor.
Speaker 1: Oh shit There's always new Patlabor's reason they don't let it.
Speaker 0: she is involved.
Speaker 1: He was only involved with a few Patlabor's the first two movies and the OAV.
Speaker 1: He wasn't involved with the TV series or the third movie or the mini Pato or any of that other stuff that came after.
Speaker 1: There was you know, there's some other things.
Speaker 1: there's a lot of action.
Speaker 0: I always thought he was.
Speaker 1: I don't think he had anything to do with live-action.
Speaker 1: one.
Speaker 0: I always thought he was involved in the TV show, but that wasn't based on knowledge.
Speaker 0: That was just me assuming which often happens.
Speaker 1: No but some of the.
Speaker 1: there are a few TV episodes that are oshi s that clearly he took inspiration from the Oshi days or maybe he was secretly involved with just a handful of them or you know.
Speaker 1: Some of his materials leaked into there, but mostly now he wasn't and I think he's on the credits list for the TV series.
Speaker 1: Yep, but yeah, Patlabor is the shit.
Speaker 0: Patlabor easy easy.
Speaker 0: Why?
Speaker 1: Alright, is it?
Speaker 1: and the thing is is the original Patlabor characters or is it like all new, you know?
Speaker 0: Just well, I have to so all we know.
Speaker 1: as far as I can tell One of those things we're like they'll just take the same concept of yo It's a world where labors are and just make all new characters.
Speaker 1: But the thing that makes Patlabor great is the original character else.
Speaker 1: That's what people care about.
Speaker 1: I don't care about the student.
Speaker 0: robots got that same kind of dynamic that like I care about the chief.
Speaker 0: These are way different shows but there's a certain kind of dynamic that you see in things like here is Greenwood or Tank Police of like.
Speaker 0: this comes a certain kind of like camaraderie Among people who are ostensibly all on the same team doing.
Speaker 1: they're like workaday job But it brings in the humor but also the seriousness and also the greater They're in the world at large, but also, you know the small All right The micro interactions like even like the original Ghost in the Shell.
Speaker 0: manga had a lot of that.
Speaker 1: Some of it some of it but did that?
Speaker 0: because that does not exist in most of the rest of Ghost in the Shell.
Speaker 0: It's only like the first manga.
Speaker 1: I think standalone complex has it more even than the first month Yeah, but central complex is a little more serious.
Speaker 0: It has less of like the major literally puts a car bomb in Aramaki's car because fuck you.
Speaker 0: You didn't give me a raise.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's true.
Speaker 0: But we all we know is and I'm quoting this is the English text that was on the poster at their booth.
Speaker 0: With the rapidly accelerating development of hyper technology a humanoid type robot called labor is being used in every field of industry.
Speaker 1: That's the story of Patlabor.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: Okay special vehicle section number two, uh-huh That's it like that.
Speaker 0: That's all we know.
Speaker 1: Well, that's the story of Patla the original Patlabor.
Speaker 0: So we have no idea.
Speaker 0: It's just gonna be more Patlabor, but there's big big real names behind it.
Speaker 0: Like it's a fully funded project.
Speaker 0: It looks like.
Speaker 1: so They just keep.
Speaker 1: my can't let go of that Patlabor.
Speaker 1: They keep bringing it back only like the tiny bit at a time.
Speaker 1: They just can't let go.
Speaker 0: there was even that live-action that no one I know watched Mmm, in fact, I didn't know it existed until I knew it existed.
Speaker 1: But how was I gonna watch it if I knew I forgot?
Speaker 1: so here it is Watch the Patlabor that exists, but you might not want to bother with the second TV series.
Speaker 1: It's not as good.
Speaker 0: Yeah, first TV series two movies.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: Was there any more?
Speaker 1: you watch the OAV?
Speaker 1: Then you watch the first movie then you watch the TV and then you watch the second movie And then you don't really need to watch anything else.
Speaker 0: The second movie is real good But it also it's way better if you've seen a lot of the other.
Speaker 1: in case I was slightly wrong about that check the internet.
Speaker 1: But yeah, just just watch the OAV first.
Speaker 0: the last time I watched any Patlabor.
Speaker 0: We still lived in Beacon.
Speaker 0: So so What about?
Speaker 0: one of my favorite anime ever was Gog manga biore?
Speaker 1: Thank you, man.
Speaker 0: We talked about it before.
Speaker 0: I should whenever I do a clip show at cons if pretty much always show.
Speaker 0: There's two episodes the Harris one and the one with the sticker.
Speaker 0: But I'm not saying this is gonna be anything like it, but I'm reminded of it.
Speaker 0: based on surface details alone There is going to be a short improv style anime and The main character is going to be Pico Taro who you know from pen pineapple apple pen.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so this guy is basically, you know, he's a comedian or whatever and he has one tiny hit thing.
Speaker 0: He had a pan AP and he had Right.
Speaker 1: his one thing became a catchy hit and now he's busy milking it for all he can which can't blame him.
Speaker 1: And he's not doesn't seem to be a bad guy he's funny guy.
Speaker 1: I want to see how long he can hold on before he fades and do obscurity again.
Speaker 0: Pico Taro Will improvise the story of each three-minute episode using an illustration by the anime's director.
Speaker 0: He's going to tell a fairy's tale and voice every character including himself.
Speaker 1: This is he's working hard right?
Speaker 1: It's not.
Speaker 1: he's not faking it.
Speaker 1: He's putting in the efforts.
Speaker 0: This is like got talents.
Speaker 0: This is the level of like weird Improvisational comedy concept that it's not gonna be real bad or it's gonna be bad, but I'm gonna really like it.
Speaker 0: I feel like that's the way it's gonna go.
Speaker 0: It's not gonna be bad or bad, but I like it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know Oh, yeah here at the end Pico Taro is best known for his bizarre viral music video PPAP.
Speaker 0: and then in case you didn't know what that was pen pineapple apple pen and So we don't need to talk about this.
Speaker 0: it's the same store detail that a lot.
Speaker 0: This is the same story that happens everywhere.
Speaker 0: I don't have a news link for it.
Speaker 0: Anime Expo is looking for volunteers to be like walk-around translators for their guests Which is fucked up because that's a professional difficult expensive job.
Speaker 1: Shouldn't they hire people with money?
Speaker 0: that's the fucked up part.
Speaker 0: apparently they have both paid and Unpaid positions.
Speaker 0: so they're paying some people and they're asking other people to volunteer To do our crazy ton of expensive work for free.
Speaker 1: so don't do that job if you're not getting paid.
Speaker 0: Yeah also most people who are professional translators There's knowing a language.
Speaker 0: even being semi fluent or fluent in a language is not the same skill as being a translator That's true.
Speaker 1: And a lot of people can translate like written stuff when they have time to sit there with the dictionary and think about it.
Speaker 1: You know because they know the language enough But they do not have the skills like sit at the UN and translate as someone is talking in real time.
Speaker 1: Yep, that is entirely different skill.
Speaker 1: that is much more difficult.
Speaker 0: and translating talking real time is also very different from Translating walking around in like just general day-to-day interactions with someone.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: So the moral is F these cons that try to have very specialized work be just unpaid free labor.
Speaker 1: Listen There's nothing wrong.
Speaker 1: see, you know, there's nothing wrong with someone who asks around and says hey who wants to work for free?
Speaker 1: Yeah, just stop working for fucking free.
Speaker 1: Stop it.
Speaker 1: Don't do it.
Speaker 1: Yep And if someone doesn't pay you right you said they said they were gonna pay you and they don't stop working.
Speaker 0: I mean, maybe it's your passion.
Speaker 0: I mean I volunteer like I do free work for things occasionally, but I know I'm doing It's also.
Speaker 0: I do it super on purpose and I don't have unreasonable expectations about that becoming something like real later.
Speaker 0: Do it and volunteering for this if you're not already a professional will probably not give you the experience to be in New York.
Speaker 1: We actually recently there was a new law recently that to make it easier when freelance If you someone hires freelancers and doesn't pay them, it's easier not to go after them to get your fucking money Yep, and it's harder for them to not pay.
Speaker 0: So also, uh, we've never been to anime Expo and partly because never based on all accounts It is the worst anime con to go to in the u.s.
Speaker 1: As far as I can tell it's a really crowded mostly professional not fan Yeah, black and then like if you like anime go to anime Boston.
Speaker 0: It's probably the best anime con in the u.s.
Speaker 1: Even Oda.
Speaker 1: Yeah Yeah, which is at least fan run even though industry presence is large.
Speaker 0: Yep I think I anime Boston is smaller than Otakon, but I also think it's a lot better run based on Previous experience coupled with current anecdotal evidence.
Speaker 0: Hmm.
Speaker 0: Frankly.
Speaker 0: We didn't go to either this year.
Speaker 0: Just cuz too busy like we got like going on.
Speaker 0: but Yeah In terms of other things coming back Many of you have probably seen project echo like the original project echo.
Speaker 1: Some people might not have heard of it But project echo is a big deal because it was one of the animes on the sci-fi channel.
Speaker 1: So all the oldest all the nerds who found anime in those days know about it.
Speaker 0: people our age.
Speaker 0: This is like the third anime they ever saw right but anyone newer anime fans might not know what the hell it is at all Just like if you've listened to geek nights like project echo We've talked about a lot at least in older episodes.
Speaker 0: and here's the thing most people who even know what project echo is Don't know.
Speaker 0: there was actually based on what was supposed to be porn, but it's not porn.
Speaker 0: It's actually just a comedy.
Speaker 0: it's actually a really funny comedy and It's also a very like like I didn't realize it was making fun of like fist of the North Star and all this other anime Cuz.
Speaker 0: I'd never seen another anime before when I first saw it But it's legit funny.
Speaker 0: Like it's a funny show, but most people know it as this one movie Which is actually no AV.
Speaker 0: It's like one story about these weird characters in this high school and superpowers and stuff.
Speaker 0: If you're a little more inside baseball or a little more pro You might know that there was a like double feature movie project gray and project blue.
Speaker 0: I think that is the same characters but like alternate universe.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm What most of you probably don't know is there.
Speaker 0: there is a whole ton of other Project echo avs.
Speaker 0: there's episode two three and four.
Speaker 0: I've seen all of them.
Speaker 0: I don't think they've been Legally able to be seen in the US since the 80s.
Speaker 1: Are they any good?
Speaker 0: Yeah, they're just as funny as part one.
Speaker 0: Like I've rented them all from block.
Speaker 0: Well, I rented two of them from blockbuster.
Speaker 0: I got a bootleg like fan sub of the third one.
Speaker 0: I actually don't know if I ever saw the fourth one now that I think about it, but I've definitely seen the plot of the Taitoku G financial group in Cinderella Rhapsody, uh Disco check picked them all up and they're all just gonna be.
Speaker 0: you're gonna be able to watch him Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: So if you have if you have not listened to geek nights for 12 years and don't know what the hell we're talking about.
Speaker 0: Go find project echo the first like OAV and just watch it.
Speaker 0: It is like a big part of American anime fandom history, and it's pretty funny.
Speaker 0: So this is crazy, uh There's gonna be a new Irresponsible captain Tyler anime short series.
Speaker 1: This is crazy.
Speaker 1: This is like we just talked about there being a new antenna manga.
Speaker 1: I think that was dead and someone's gonna make a new thing Captain Tyler.
Speaker 1: was it the one?
Speaker 1: it was just a 26 episode anime series, right?
Speaker 0: Then it was.
Speaker 0: there was a. no That was it.
Speaker 0: Nope.
Speaker 0: There was no.
Speaker 0: AV came out later.
Speaker 0: All right, there was a movie, too Yeah, but the movie is sort of like the capstone to the OAV.
Speaker 1: But anyway, but it's still.
Speaker 1: it's like this thing is bigger than I thought it was.
Speaker 0: So here's the thing.
Speaker 1: but it hasn't been around in years.
Speaker 1: hasn't been a single thing related to this property made in forever?
Speaker 0: Yeah Like no one.
Speaker 0: like most people in America have never even heard of this.
Speaker 0: but to this day like irresponsible captain Tyler is One of my favorite anime ever.
Speaker 0: like it is in my personal top 10 list and I feel like it is an a anime.
Speaker 0: It is legit.
Speaker 0: It is good.
Speaker 0: It is funny.
Speaker 0: It is serious.
Speaker 0: I've never seen anything else quite like it.
Speaker 0: And if you've seen even one episode of legend of the Galactic Heroes, it's even better but You should watch it.
Speaker 0: But much like cowboy bebop much like utenna It is a thing that what came out originally was perfect and ended like it finished itself.
Speaker 0: It was done.
Speaker 0: It told its story.
Speaker 0: So it is shocking to me that Oh, yeah The series is the first television anime adaptation of the 24 year in the 24 years since the 1993 Irresponsible captain.
Speaker 1: that's how old it is 93 24 years.
Speaker 1: I thought it was later than I thought it was like 97 98 or something.
Speaker 0: I in 1993 like well, I think probably in 94 or 95 is when I actually got it.
Speaker 1: That's what I was in like middle school.
Speaker 0: Yeah I watched a fan sub of some irresponsible captain Tyler Cuz.
Speaker 0: then I got through.
Speaker 1: I didn't know I never heard of it until college and we saw it at the anime club.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like a second meeting maybe or something like that.
Speaker 0: I was like advocating constantly.
Speaker 0: I was like guys you got a show captain Tyler captain Tyler captain Tyler cuz.
Speaker 0: I was obsessed with it and I could never get until RIT anime.
Speaker 0: I never saw more than like the first five or six episodes and then like one or two random episodes near the end.
Speaker 0: I literally like had no idea like how it ended.
Speaker 1: I don't think I saw the whole thing I saw.
Speaker 1: I watched a whole bunch of episodes and then stopped before the end and then I don't know how far before the end And then didn't ever watch it again.
Speaker 0: Oh shit The end is so.
Speaker 0: I'm not saying that the like what it does in the end is as good as cowboy bebop But it is real fucking close It's real.
Speaker 0: There is this moment where a character salutes a character and you'll just like the tears just gonna stream down from the one eye.
Speaker 1: But anyway, there is no more star lock.
Speaker 1: show up.
Speaker 0: Ah It's I can't I'm just not even you gotta see it.
Speaker 0: This is set I guess in the far future after the world of the original captain Tyler and the main character is Banjo wacky Tyler who probably is a great descendant of Justy Ricky Tyler the original captain Tyler.
Speaker 0: I guess he carries a banjo around.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm and I Don't know if this looks like it's gonna be good Makes it look scary.
Speaker 0: It draws heavily from the original source material, which I actually didn't know shit about.
Speaker 1: I know what's the original source material?
Speaker 1: the anime bad?
Speaker 1: What it wait what came before the anime?
Speaker 0: apparently it was a series of light novels, of course I'm gonna quote this con that.
Speaker 0: so basically because it's being re-released and a Twitter was in the boat with me They were like wow That is some in like who is bringing this back?
Speaker 0: and they all learned about captain Tyler all at once.
Speaker 0: Quote all this Tyler talk led me to look up the original novels and wow, there were some cream lemon shit.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm apparently, uh captain Tyler in the manga or in the original novels is way older than the one in the anime and the girl oselin is Way younger than the girl in the anime alien girl.
Speaker 1: Yeah bad news Like the alien Queen princess, whatever she is, she's the princess.
Speaker 0: there's the all like Queen.
Speaker 0: I could use the Queen that it's complicated.
Speaker 1: her dad is the bad guy.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and I read it.
Speaker 0: So, uh Yeah, this is all bikini armor Heba file nonsense probably and the fact that this draws from the source material really worries me.
Speaker 0: So until I say otherwise because I think I am like the biggest fan of captain Tyler Do not watch the new show Go watch the original TV show and nothing else and I will find out if the new show is creepy porn or bad or maybe good, but I'm
Speaker 1: in the movie also, uh
Speaker 0: So the OAV is like a bunch of short stories that don't really add much to the universe.
Speaker 0: The the the original TV show is literally all you need to see everything else.
Speaker 0: It'd be like remember the cowboy bebop movie.
Speaker 0: It's like that like here's some more stories, but we don't actually bring anything new into the world Which I guess is good because if the cowboy bebop movie added more to the world it kind of would have ruined what the show did
Speaker 1: whatever, uh
Speaker 0: So kimono friends, which we already talked about why
Speaker 1: is this even coming up again?
Speaker 1: Holy shit It's a big deal right now, but who cares?
Speaker 0: it is like it's getting so big in Japan that apparently the character song alga album Which I love the Japan even today the IST.
Speaker 1: This is one of the things that fascinated me about Japan and I guess also has to do with the business model for anime.
Speaker 1: They're right here.
Speaker 1: The anime itself is the product whereas in Japan anime is just an advertisement for stuff.
Speaker 1: Yeah But the sheer amount and wide variation of stuff that they make for every single property is like mind-boggling.
Speaker 1: I did not learn back in the day.
Speaker 1: They would make so many crazy things And like these things take a lot of effort to make.
Speaker 1: but like you can go back and it's like Oh Sailor Moon like character album and it's like oh, please save my earth.
Speaker 0: the Second is T. That is all original music that was not in the anime coupled with an audio drama with the original voice.
Speaker 1: There's like Trigon audio drama album and it's like who put that much work into making this.
Speaker 1: Yeah obscure Minuscule audience thing.
Speaker 0: I got a fan sub of the fucking please save my earth.
Speaker 0: audio drama and like read through it while I listen to it.
Speaker 1: Right, so it's like for some small intellectual property.
Speaker 1: mikamoto friends is bigger than those but it's like they'll makes this thing.
Speaker 1: that's like how many is this gonna sell?
Speaker 1: like No, there's a handful of people on earth who want this and a lot of people worked hard to make it.
Speaker 0: I learned about that aspect of the industry in high school because I was really into Sailor Moon Like.
Speaker 0: I got all the fan subs like watched it all and I found the figurines of extremely obscure Side character who appears in one scene.
Speaker 0: I found the soundtrack like and it was like this Well, I want to say it was like a 12 CD box.
Speaker 0: So I pirated that shit and it took me a while to pirate it.
Speaker 0: cuz that back then like 12 CDs.
Speaker 0: yeah, that was a big deal.
Speaker 0: and most of those songs were never in the show and Some of them were OSTs and which I figured out was like, you know original soundtrack and some of them were ISTs.
Speaker 0: and I started learning about all this music that gets made that is never featured in shows.
Speaker 0: and then Eska flown ahead.
Speaker 0: the same thing.
Speaker 0: and there's this whole weird world the kimono friends, I guess IST Was apparently ranked number one and Its OST was ranked number two on the weekly album chart this month.
Speaker 0: so Holy shit is kimono friends like the exploding nonsense in Japan?
Speaker 1: It means more people bought this than bought any other music.
Speaker 1: They bought an album of kimono friends music that was not in kimono friends ever and an album of music that was in it.
Speaker 0: Cuz they're two different albums.
Speaker 0: See this this is this is the difference between someone who watches anime versus someone who watches anime and then like looks at the Internet You see this nonsense going on and someone an anime fan in Japan who buys character albums Fan in the u.s.
Speaker 1: Who watches on crunchyroll and that's it.
Speaker 0: I want to know like are there people who buy these albums that don't watch the anime like How deep does the rabbit hole go?
Speaker 0: and I just don't know I know.
Speaker 0: So last and least, uh, oh, yeah the watermelon thing.
Speaker 0: I'm not gonna talk about I think we're out of time.
Speaker 0: Actually, we've done like a full show and the last thing I got here is the Japanese video game rankings.
Speaker 0: Cuz that was my backup in case we went too quick.
Speaker 0: Whatever Mario Kart 8 is number one Tekken 7 Breath of the Wild Monster Hunter xx.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 1: There's a lot of games still making ease.
Speaker 1: They're never gonna stop making ease.
Speaker 1: The only East game I ever played was I want like wanders from yeast on the SNES Which there's a lot of games that they make in Japan and only released in Japan pretty much that a lot of people play.
Speaker 1: And people in other.
Speaker 0: fire emblem used to be like that.
Speaker 0: fire emblem used to be the game that only like Crazy nut jobs in America would play like Japanese releases of right.
Speaker 0: but no one ever thought fire emblem would exist in the u.s.
Speaker 1: But dragon quest they keep trying to put popularized in the u.s.
Speaker 1: And no one gives a fuck.
Speaker 0: Yeah East I feel like it's the thing that will never break.
Speaker 1: I was saying no one are some people but it's like a Fraction.
Speaker 1: where's?
Speaker 1: and you believe the new dragon quest is Japan and like the whole country comes to a halt Saikan Densetsu collection.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, that's so that's Yeah, so the secret of mana.
Speaker 1: people don't know that.
Speaker 1: the Saikan Densetsu - which is secret of mana - which is one of the Best games there is but never been in English ever.
Speaker 1: and but on the switch e-shop You can buy second assessor collection, which includes all the second and set suits in America with an American.
Speaker 1: No It's in Japanese, that's why I don't look I because the region free but you better be able to read Japanese.
Speaker 0: That's why I don't ever look at the Japanese side because I just get really sad.
Speaker 1: But yeah also Final Fantasy adventure for the Gameboy in America, that's also second.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they only called it Final Fantasy because the Final Fantasy brand was real valuable in the u.s I mean remember Final Fantasy mystic quest Right.
Speaker 1: I really want to play secret of mana - yeah, but it's not in English.
Speaker 1: I'm sure there's some fan translation thing.
Speaker 0: I remember it wasn't like you Alex and Katsu were like going through like me and Kazuo.
Speaker 1: see we played site.
Speaker 1: We played secret of mana one.
Speaker 1: Yeah a whole bunch.
Speaker 1: you didn't beat it.
Speaker 1: I don't think cuz that game is hard as fuck.
Speaker 1: It's pretty hard.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's not the hardest though.
Speaker 1: No, it's not.
Speaker 0: Of course.
Speaker 0: You just take harnesses Tumbleseed.
Speaker 1: it just takes time.
Speaker 0: Double sees the hardest game I've ever played on.
Speaker 1: Mostly we play a secret of mana.
Speaker 1: You just got to be careful and go slow.
Speaker 1: and yeah Think of think things through don't just rush in and start attacking everything.
Speaker 1: cuz it's not like Zelda.
Speaker 1: We can just go stab stab stab.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you stab it's like.
Speaker 1: are you committed to stabbing?
Speaker 0: Yeah, you better have wanted to stab.
Speaker 0: love you better better You better hit that rabbi.
Speaker 0: that level to stab was the one you wanted not three and not one.
Speaker 0: you want a level two specifically.
Speaker 0: Yeah All right.
Speaker 0: I think we're out of here and We'll do shows next week.
Speaker 0: And then I think the week after that I gotta go to London.
Speaker 0: So I'm at skip a week and then Connecticut.
Speaker 0: my tire is out But then we're gonna come back with gusto and with you.
Speaker 0: tennis show.
Speaker 0: Stay tuned.
Speaker 0: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Speaker 1: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 0: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 0: But unlike those other late shows It's actually recorded at night and the patreon patrons for this episode of geek guides are Nicholas Brando Alan Joyce Heidi McNichol Amanda Duchette and Thomas Hahn.
Speaker 0: mystati.com.
Speaker 0: William Eisneros Life and death and love and birth and peace and war on the planet Earth.
Speaker 0: genuine bonafide like to ride six car monorail captain Chinguacu see Rebecca done the terrible secret of space.
Speaker 0: 421 creations.
Speaker 0: as far as I can tell it's just a box canyon in the middle of nowhere.
Speaker 0: Shervin von Horrell rarely.
Speaker 0: Val James David White Rochelle, Montana Superboy.
Speaker 0: I paid five bucks to make rim say pickle Say Larvista Matthew Smith a Don Schleich Kajar tovish and Joshiro.
Speaker 0: Joe starts Sean Yeager Sam Cordery Clinton Walton Ren from New Zealand Ryan Perrin.
Speaker 0: Mr Black Brian Cedroni Finn Chris mint give Chris Knox Daniel Redmond Sean Clyde Chris Reimer Who still is at war with me in the sieve game and Thomas Hahn and now I leave you with Triple concerto for faucet water pipes and fiddle Concerts nakran.