Speaker 0: It's Wednesday October 31st 2018.
Speaker 0: I'm rim I'm pushing the cat and this is geek nights.
Speaker 0: It's an anniversary of us starting geek nights.
Speaker 1: I guess 13 18 minus 5.
Speaker 0: it's been a long time We've been doing.
Speaker 1: get the unlucky 13th year of geek and tonight.
Speaker 0: We're talking about the dragon prince.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: Good God, we've been doing it not a long time.
Speaker 1: All right, that's it.
Speaker 1: we're done.
Speaker 0: just stop just drop the mic walk away Good and go home.
Speaker 0: And if I go into the archive and go all the way back October 31st 2005 we did our first episode called arguing science and then the next day we did an episode called Video game argument.
Speaker 0: Okay, so you can see where how we've evolved over time.
Speaker 1: Not at all.
Speaker 0: We don't argue that much on the show anymore.
Speaker 0: We argue before the show because you never want to do any of the topics.
Speaker 1: That's right, cuz your topics are bad.
Speaker 0: My topics are real bad.
Speaker 0: I got great topics.
Speaker 0: All right, you got any news?
Speaker 1: son Do you have a news?
Speaker 1: so, you know, there's a lot of Great animated series that have been made by Channel Frederator or whatever.
Speaker 1: They call themselves Like all these different names.
Speaker 1: I don't know the red robot head.
Speaker 1: Anyway, yep shows like bravest warriors and being puppy cat.
Speaker 1: Those are the main two.
Speaker 1: all the other ones are lesser.
Speaker 1: We everyone except for the one with the dolphin that goes.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I forget what that one's called but anyway For a while.
Speaker 1: They just posted episodes on YouTube and it was great.
Speaker 1: And then they like moved all their stuff to like some other weird services and I couldn't like verve.
Speaker 1: I don't fucking know how to how to watch their content.
Speaker 1: So I stopped watching the content.
Speaker 0: I mean the point.
Speaker 0: we're already like most content.
Speaker 0: I watch not this stuff just other things like cartoon.
Speaker 1: Hey, is it cartoon hangover or is it Frederator?
Speaker 1: It's like it's only different names.
Speaker 1: Anyway, I Point is they now have a come back to YouTube so you can get full episodes of being puppy cat on YouTube Which is good because I fucking kick-started them.
Speaker 1: I paid.
Speaker 1: I should be able to see them.
Speaker 1: I paid the money but also new episodes.
Speaker 1: Finally.
Speaker 1: finally, it's not like oh we're working on them.
Speaker 1: It's like no we waited long enough.
Speaker 1: How long?
Speaker 1: we've been waiting a long-ass time.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we waited long enough.
Speaker 1: Now.
Speaker 1: They're here.
Speaker 1: We were our patients paid off.
Speaker 1: There's more being puppy cat.
Speaker 0: Imminently I was wearing my be pin today coincidentally, uh-huh.
Speaker 0: So they don't have a puppy cat van only have a beep.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if you have not seen any be puppy cat brave warriors or other cartoon hangover slash Frederator slash whatever other names their studios have.
Speaker 1: I don't.
Speaker 1: they're all mixed up.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they make good stuff and you don't need a television with cable to see it.
Speaker 1: You can see it on YouTube cartoon hangover cartoon hangover.
Speaker 0: select on verve.
Speaker 0: watch now on verve.
Speaker 1: Yeah, those are probably older videos.
Speaker 1: that when they were still I don't know.
Speaker 1: But yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I pretty much do this.
Speaker 0: I feel like I'm not going on verb.
Speaker 0: I'll go to Netflix I go to crunchyroll go to Amazon video and if it's not in any of those places Usually I end up on the Pirate Bay next.
Speaker 1: Oh that reminds me of another news that I Just now that I didn't include in our news list because it was from like a week ago.
Speaker 0: All right, I'll type it in.
Speaker 1: There was a. there was an alliance between I don't know people know this crunchyroll and funimation had an alliance.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, that's actually kind of bad news and this alliance allowed some significant amount of funimation.
Speaker 1: shows Shows the funimation of the rights to in America to be on crunchyroll and I think possibly vice versa So that you didn't really need to pay for funimation.
Speaker 1: Everyone just paid for crunchyroll.
Speaker 0: And yeah I paid for funimation of like once and then I stopped because it wasn't worth it and I just went crunchyroll right.
Speaker 1: the point Is this alliance is officially over.
Speaker 1: there is I guess some date in the future where some on?
Speaker 1: Some list of shows that I didn't wasn't able to find yet Will no longer be on crunchyroll because those are funimation shows which means that's bad news because most anime fans are not paying for two separate anime Right.
Speaker 0: So also Netflix which also has anime.
Speaker 1: It's also there's a. there's a website filmstruck which I was paying for but no one else was which had all old movies.
Speaker 0: and now we What happens when no one else pays for it?
Speaker 1: and it's basically there was this idea.
Speaker 1: that and drama fever also shutting down the Korean Drama, right?
Speaker 1: Basically, there are all these streaming services that we're trying to serve content niches Like hey, you only care about watching old movies.
Speaker 1: Don't pay for Netflix.
Speaker 1: that has everything a little bit everything.
Speaker 1: pay for this.
Speaker 1: that has tons of the one thing that you want.
Speaker 1: And but the problem with this is much like cable a la carte cable TV.
Speaker 1: Is it's like how many fucking channels.
Speaker 1: am I gonna pay for every one thing?
Speaker 1: if they were like a dollar each I could pay for like 10 of these freaking services.
Speaker 0: Well, I guess it's.
Speaker 1: it's a little worse than that in that I know each one of these services wants to charge you an arm and a leg.
Speaker 0: So I have a limited amount of time irrespective of money.
Speaker 0: So even if even if money was not a factor and all these services were free I'm just like most fans of things including me don't have time to watch everything anyway, so whichever you
Speaker 1: pay for crunchyroll I only watch maybe like less than 10 shows on total series on crunchyroll per year.
Speaker 0: So whatever that's a good value whatever services I go to I'm pretty much just gonna watch something on those services and it is shockingly rare that I will ever Start with a show.
Speaker 0: I want to watch and then go figure out what service it's on.
Speaker 1: Well, even when I do start with a show I want to watch I'm not gonna subscribe to like another service Just because I'm like.
Speaker 1: I'm already on Netflix.
Speaker 1: Right, what I used to do is I used to be like, all right I'm on Hulu watching the Hulu shoes.
Speaker 1: Cancel Netflix.
Speaker 1: watching the Netflix shows cancel.
Speaker 1: now crunchyroll.
Speaker 1: watching crunchyroll shows cancel and always be one at a time.
Speaker 1: No, but that was a pain in the ass.
Speaker 0: So I just keep Netflix and crunchyroll and nothing else exists, right?
Speaker 1: It's like I'll pay for so much.
Speaker 0: I'll buy stuff.
Speaker 0: I won't straw just buy like videos on Amazon.
Speaker 1: That's not bad, but it's way too expensive.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but you know what?
Speaker 0: It's not that expensive.
Speaker 1: So very expensive.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know what I bought there.
Speaker 0: Like I bought a lot of the later seasons of Adventure Time there.
Speaker 1: How much were they each?
Speaker 0: I don't even remember.
Speaker 1: Yeah, okay, uncle money bags over here.
Speaker 1: It ends up.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'm willing to pay a couple bucks an episode.
Speaker 1: That's a lot for a 15-minute.
Speaker 0: There's no other way to make money making content.
Speaker 1: That's not my problem.
Speaker 1: Anyway, the point is I'm only gonna pay for so many services.
Speaker 1: So if you start putting less and less content per service And if the services that I pay for have don't have enough content on them I'll cancel those and just go back to the high seas.
Speaker 1: So like if there's a show I want to watch now and it's not on crunchyroll because it's a funimation show.
Speaker 1: Yeah Well, there was and if it turns out there's not enough shows on crunchyroll and I'm hardly using it.
Speaker 0: cancel and yeah There were multiple articles recently.
Speaker 0: But there's a lot of evidence that because of the increasing fracturing of the streaming like landscape Piracy which was actually like really bottoming out to like near nothing has surged again.
Speaker 0: Yeah, of course I mean not gonna lie.
Speaker 0: I went and just downloaded a bunch of the good place from the Pirate Bay a little while ago So you figure out how to watch it.
Speaker 1: Oh, that's just pirates for Halloween.
Speaker 0: So the saddest thing with the fun with the funimation thing in particular, you know, why this is happening Specifically yeah, cuz they're jerks.
Speaker 0: no because of Sony's acquisition It's always Sony.
Speaker 0: Sony is the one that like always if there's a bad decision to be made it's always Sony.
Speaker 0: So quote according to a memo sent to staff from funimation president Fukin aga the decision was made as a direct result of the company being acquired by Sony Pictures television.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: Sony really wants to directly monetize and is going to do a bad job.
Speaker 1: Instead of splitting up and like we're basically spoiling the water and ruining Lean on the central service like crunchyroll.
Speaker 1: instead of ruining your service and and the other person service Why don't you just fucking buy crunchyroll and merge?
Speaker 1: Yeah crunchyroll and funimation into one Anime owning an America company that takes care of everything and then you'll get all the money.
Speaker 0: The.
Speaker 0: so the funniest thing, you know who else has heard by this?
Speaker 0: because a lot of those funimation shows are also on Verve.
Speaker 0: Verve is just gonna die.
Speaker 0: I think is nothing's gonna be on Verve anymore.
Speaker 1: Who's paying for a verb?
Speaker 1: Oh, there's another one like high dive.
Speaker 0: I've never even been on verbs website.
Speaker 1: What the hell.
Speaker 1: what's high dive then?
Speaker 1: I've heard of that.
Speaker 1: I don't know what it is.
Speaker 1: It's just another streaming service.
Speaker 1: right?
Speaker 0: verve is a digital.
Speaker 0: Oh it launched in 2016.
Speaker 0: So it's like brand new.
Speaker 1: It's not that?
Speaker 0: yeah, it's not old and it bundles together several geek related channels into See.
Speaker 0: I feel like the business people making all these decisions just have no idea what consumers of media are like.
Speaker 1: Netflix does.
Speaker 0: Netflix is the only one Crunchyroll - crunchyroll knows what's up crunchyroll is like.
Speaker 1: why doesn't Netflix buy funimation?
Speaker 1: Well, I guess Sony already bought us a too late.
Speaker 1: Yeah, Netflix.
Speaker 1: You just like buy crunchyroll.
Speaker 0: So this is kind of all bad news.
Speaker 0: But I think the result is just I'm not gonna watch any funimation anime and Amazon really fucked up with that.
Speaker 1: Remember they had that the prime anime special thing.
Speaker 0: No, that was a bad Bad bad situation of the same enemy strike.
Speaker 1: They fuck that was a fuck-up.
Speaker 0: - yep.
Speaker 0: So in some other news that we came out of nowhere if you follow Toby Fox on Twitter Who's that?
Speaker 1: I've heard that name undertale guy.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: He started tweeting a bunch of weird stuff Yeah, and then he put out a games that no one knew was coming.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's basically just undertale - and it's just free.
Speaker 0: Just like download it and run it.
Speaker 0: Okay, so I don't know anything about it.
Speaker 0: Like I've avoided reading about it.
Speaker 1: I'm just gonna download this exe and I play it without finishing undertale.
Speaker 0: one Probably not.
Speaker 0: I don't.
Speaker 0: I feel like it might not resonate.
Speaker 0: I mean you didn't even get past but one didn't resonate when I was playing it.
Speaker 0: I don't understand how I think undertale is one of the better games ever made.
Speaker 1: think it was.
Speaker 1: it's a crappy game maker RPG.
Speaker 0: I don't know how you had such trouble getting by papyrus.
Speaker 1: I tried like because I have no patience and I didn't.
Speaker 0: but it's just like a base like it's a shmup.
Speaker 0: It's not hard.
Speaker 0: Just move the heart around.
Speaker 1: I had no patience.
Speaker 0: I didn't give a shit, but I'd be I'd be papyrus.
Speaker 0: I like my second try.
Speaker 1: I think I didn't care enough to try.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: Anyway undertale is a triumph And if you need more undertale, it appears that there is in fact more undertale and it's just here for you and it's probably spooky.
Speaker 0: probably have some creepypasta based on the media that I saw around it and all these cryptic cryptic tweets from Someone at undertale that Toby Fox was retweeting.
Speaker 1: I definitely got to give credit though to doing one thing right which is just don't.
Speaker 1: there's two ways that I think are the correct way to market media a Keep your fucking mouth shut until it's a hundred percent done and then boom here it is done right.
Speaker 1: and way number two be a hundred percent open with everything and say I'm doing this to give daily fucking reports and 100% engage in their community and keep no secrets.
Speaker 1: the standard operating procedure for just about everyone in all media is to Hold your cards close to the chest slowly reveal tiny bits of info and tease people and then there's leaks Which could be fake or real and then put release dates and then miss them.
Speaker 1: and it's like fuck it.
Speaker 1: either be a hundred percent Open and tell your your your audience everything or tell them fucking nothing and then surprise them.
Speaker 1: Those are your two choices that are good.
Speaker 1: if you do the in-between thing that most people do you're doing it wrong in the opinion of sky.
Speaker 0: so in a brief aside because it's not really like animation or anime related other than very tangentially because a big part of anime fan culture is conventions and twitchcon happened and twitchcon is is it's weird?
Speaker 1: right cuz?
Speaker 1: twitch is Almost entirely a gaming thing, but it's pushing into like all these other avenues.
Speaker 1: And they have like this, you know Digimon Pokemon they got all these anime Marathons on there.
Speaker 1: They're like crunchy little partnerships on there and there's tons of weebs and all the Chad.
Speaker 0: So I always ignore twitchcon cuz I don't care and like that.
Speaker 0: but I so it made the news and I actually paid attention to it.
Speaker 1: I watch twitch.
Speaker 0: twitchcon is bad as much as we Like we make fun of how a lot of anime comes are really really badly run.
Speaker 0: Anime con people have a great amount of convention privilege compared to almost every other kind of convention like.
Speaker 1: well because Gaming cons right developed to a certain point and then didn't progress except packs packs and magfests.
Speaker 0: They're like the only gaming cons that are progressed Right.
Speaker 1: the almost gaming cons just stayed and kept doing their tiny thing and didn't try to become didn't try to grow.
Speaker 1: They just stayed where they were at.
Speaker 0: but packs and magfest are sets of conventions.
Speaker 0: where?
Speaker 0: as they grew they Did the things necessary to allow that growth to happen.
Speaker 1: anyway anime cons have been around a long time You know perhaps longer as long as they grew, but did not change.
Speaker 0: and then a few of them change, right?
Speaker 1: Well, they tried to grow many of them right and they learned and developed to some extent.
Speaker 1: Did is some didn't?
Speaker 0: that's by kicking us off the staff or telling them to mail the badges.
Speaker 0: They eventually started mailing the badges because this is objectively the right thing to do.
Speaker 1: The point is they developed over time.
Speaker 1: they tried to grow they learned lessons.
Speaker 1: They've had many years to get shit right, but you know conventions like twitchcon.
Speaker 0: So twitchcon the reason it was in the news is that no one could get in because of quote unquote unprecedented crowds which again How are conventions messing this up?
Speaker 0: packs has a number of people who can attend and it's sold out and that's it.
Speaker 0: No one's gonna show up and think they can get in.
Speaker 1: yet twitchcon seems Like online registration with mailed badges.
Speaker 0: no, so a million people showed up and couldn't get in.
Speaker 0: Like basically there because of a combination of Security theater and poor planning so many people couldn't get in that it was one of those convention disaster stories.
Speaker 0: They ended up like extending the hours of the con to like let people who couldn't get in or what would happen during those Extra hours.
Speaker 1: Did you add did you invent more content?
Speaker 0: No, which I don't understand because there's not a lot of content at twitchcon.
Speaker 1: No, that's the thing is like.
Speaker 1: no matter how much I like twitch and I actually watch twitch more and more there's Like.
Speaker 1: I can't imagine what I would do at twitchcon.
Speaker 1: go to my someone that I watch on twitch that go see them sit on a panel and Just answer question.
Speaker 0: So I'm one.
Speaker 0: and it's funny because they actually have more than I expected in some avenues.
Speaker 0: like they have this little artist alley and they Have like.
Speaker 1: I guess there is an art.
Speaker 0: There are a lot of art streams Yeah, and there's like a little tabletop area and there's a little cosplay contest.
Speaker 1: There is tabletop.
Speaker 0: you is like an area set up.
Speaker 1: They could do some RPG acquisitions ink stuff.
Speaker 1: That's that's too extreme.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but they have like gaming and arcades and stuff, but they're all kind of small.
Speaker 0: but the problem is There's not a lot of like actual other content like their panels.
Speaker 0: There aren't that many and almost all of them are like meet and greet like just a meet and greet.
Speaker 1: the one thing that was Happening sort of at with adjacent to twitchcon was the mini GDQ.
Speaker 1: Yeah, actually quite excellent to express and that's most.
Speaker 1: I was surprised how small the donation count went You know, even though people were watching it, but it was excellent.
Speaker 1: But apparently the problem wasn't just like a distilled like it was like all the best parts of a full GDQ Without the slow part.
Speaker 1: So it's like it was like you wanted to watch the whole thing because every single event on the tiny GDQ is great.
Speaker 0: So there were huge lines to get in and people couldn't get in and there were huge lines to do Anything at the cons.
Speaker 0: even if you got in you couldn't do anything.
Speaker 0: yeah, and there's all sorts of drama.
Speaker 0: and what's amazing is this isn't like like anime cons even when they're big often don't have a Lot of money or expertise, but twitch is a real company.
Speaker 1: You mean Amazon?
Speaker 1: Yeah Amazon is a real company.
Speaker 1: Amazon is a real company headed by the wealthiest person to ever live.
Speaker 0: There are people who know Professionally how to run events.
Speaker 0: They're perhaps called event managers.
Speaker 1: They have.
Speaker 1: Amazon runs many events.
Speaker 1: There are like all kinds of professional conferences.
Speaker 0: How is twitchcon such this like goddamn amateur hour like the problem of too many people show up and you can't let them in Coupled with As no one who works for twitch ever been to any other conference or convention ever.
Speaker 0: Yep, and what's worse is all the press about it like Attendees of these comms you don't go to like PAX's or magfest or the few good anime cons Like they expect and accept this bullshit Which is amazing to me.
Speaker 0: like all the people used to go to Otacon and wait four hours on Thursday to get their badges And couldn't even dream that there was a better way to do it.
Speaker 0: like most people do not have imagination So the craziest things are.
Speaker 0: a lot of the press say things like I'm gonna quote this article.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna link to Every convention.
Speaker 0: tickly typically features long lines as fans are supposed to wait in security cues before entering.
Speaker 1: that is no no That's not true at all.
Speaker 0: One packs has that problem and they've actually really fought the city of Boston to not make it a problem.
Speaker 1: and also There's only lines if you want to do stupid shit.
Speaker 1: If you don't do stupid or you
Speaker 0: want to do like them like the biggest things that usually isn't that much of a line because They're in giant theaters and the things that tend to fill up where you would have to wait in a long line Tend to be things that are in pretty small rooms.
Speaker 0: But there's room for people to do things and there's enough content to try to spread that.
Speaker 0: load out It just.
Speaker 0: it bothers me How baby's first mistake happens at a con like twitch con and San Diego comic-con only has mega lines for like there.
Speaker 1: They're infamous.
Speaker 1: what Hall D or whatever?
Speaker 1: whatever college?
Speaker 1: they don't clear the room Which is that's people just constantly waiting to get in the room and that would they let one person comes out.
Speaker 1: That's what I've heard in years past.
Speaker 1: I don't know if they've never been to San Diego comic-con.
Speaker 1: I never will go so I don't know what it is like now.
Speaker 1: Someone can correct me if they've know better, but that's the story I heard a few years ago, and I have not heard that it is Jane.
Speaker 0: Yep, but anyway things Of the day.
Speaker 0: so because it is the anniversary of gig nights since we started on October 31st One of the things today, I'm gonna link to is the first episode of geek nights.
Speaker 0: That is public.
Speaker 0: great I'm not linking to the beta episodes.
Speaker 0: those are buried behind the patreon wall.
Speaker 0: But I'm gonna link to the first episode of geek nights And you will be shocked and disappointed if you click on that link.
Speaker 1: do not listen to that.
Speaker 1: I mean you already shouldn't be listening or watching this right now.
Speaker 1: Yes, you should, but if you are you really shouldn't be listening to that.
Speaker 1: What is this do I invite as an experience?
Speaker 1: like Scott 13 years ago is not the same person You know what's funny is a bad person.
Speaker 0: Scott 13 years ago Talks a lot about politics.
Speaker 0: It's a bad person 13 year olds I guess you like you were convinced that Rumsfeld was gonna get a war crimes trial.
Speaker 0: Should President he will?
Speaker 1: yeah, so will a lot of other people.
Speaker 0: But anyway my real thing today, I think are good.
Speaker 0: my real thing of the day to segue from politics is a 538 article.
Speaker 0: That's very important, so it is the ultimate Halloween candy power ranking.
Speaker 1: How do I judge the power based on sugar?
Speaker 0: No, so what they did?
Speaker 1: all our per ounce.
Speaker 0: They basically did an experiment where they pitted different candies against other candies in a. here are to Pick the superior one type contest.
Speaker 1: and they did this to a whole bunch of people to figure out which guns were the most.
Speaker 0: 5,371 unique IP addresses.
Speaker 1: and so neko wafer has low power.
Speaker 0: so the whole rating is here and We have the full order.
Speaker 0: so number one is the Reese's peanut butter cup.
Speaker 1: I was gonna that was one of my guesses for a very valuable one 84 percent of all its mashups.
Speaker 1: Oh, cuz I mean it's so good.
Speaker 0: I mean oh look candy is garbage.
Speaker 0: I'm an adult.
Speaker 1: I really a Reese's peanut butter cup is a good candy.
Speaker 0: number two is Reese's minis.
Speaker 1: Oh Just the small peanut.
Speaker 1: yeah, they really broke it down right.
Speaker 1: 81 percent 81.9.
Speaker 0: Reese's miniatures, okay?
Speaker 1: There's basically the same fucking.
Speaker 0: so number three is Twix Which is disgusting disgusting garbage trash.
Speaker 0: when I was at home caveat when I was in middle school I did like four Twix bars a day sir poison.
Speaker 1: I could never eat one even no matter even no matter how young I was and addicted to sugar I was.
Speaker 1: Twix never tasted good.
Speaker 0: So then Kit Kat Snickers Reese's Milky Way.
Speaker 1: Reese's stuff with pieces peanut butter seems like so Basically any of the full-on chocolate candies are powerful.
Speaker 0: No, it's specifically chocolatey candies mostly adjacent to peanut butter Really good Reese's is one two three four five Dents right it's.
Speaker 1: yeah, you know you get a Snickers right?
Speaker 1: It's like.
Speaker 1: I got some fucking caramel some peanut in there It's but but but Milky Way is number seven the least dense candy bar, Milky Way is very dense.
Speaker 0: Musketeers musketeer is the non-dense three musketeers is number 12 there.
Speaker 1: I mean it's still really fucking good.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I used to buy used to buy three musketeer on purpose.
Speaker 1: so grocery checkout I'll.
Speaker 0: I like to.
Speaker 0: I do like like.
Speaker 0: Twix is okay, but butterfinger.
Speaker 0: you Reminds in Twix that biting into a butterfinger Reminds me of the fucking my imagine.
Speaker 1: I never understood my Bart Simpson like this because they're so nasty.
Speaker 0: They taste like bile.
Speaker 0: that is what I would describe.
Speaker 1: I think it's.
Speaker 1: I think what it is is that there's real this.
Speaker 1: there's levels of peanut butter right.
Speaker 1: the top level is obviously Oh Natural peanut butter.
Speaker 0: just eat it out of the bowl.
Speaker 0: They make it that.
Speaker 1: they make it the deli counter bike with some fucking peanuts and a roaster right behind in the grocery.
Speaker 1: That's the best you can get it.
Speaker 1: like Publix in Florida one of the only good things in Florida.
Speaker 1: That's like the top quality.
Speaker 1: like farmers market peanut butter is the top level right where the oil Separates.
Speaker 1: the second level is like grocery store real peanut butter like Skippy or whatever peanut fitter panner You know like it's real peanut butter, but it's you know it's factory peanut butter Not real peanut butter.
Speaker 1: and then the next level is the Reese's peanut butter Which you can tell obviously tastes like fake peanut butter, but is still palatable and good, and it's sugary.
Speaker 1: So your body likes to eat it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, any peanut butter below that such as whatever the fuck is in Twix and butterfinger and other garbage I wouldn't doesn't taste like peanut butter and is inedible, so here's here's something.
Speaker 0: What do you think is at the bottom here?
Speaker 1: Oh?
Speaker 1: Neko wafer no the bottom See is those weird those hard old lady thing good and plenty.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's bad.
Speaker 0: Those are disgusting.
Speaker 0: yeah, Boston baked beans.
Speaker 1: I don't know what the fuck that is.
Speaker 0: chiclets.
Speaker 1: Oh you mean?
Speaker 1: do they mean actual baked beans?
Speaker 0: I imagine there's some candy.
Speaker 1: chiclets are okay, but they're just like they're just gum that runs out in two seconds.
Speaker 1: They're not bad, but it's like they're not.
Speaker 0: Boston baked beans is a candy.
Speaker 1: never heard of it.
Speaker 0: It looks like rabbit poop.
Speaker 0: Okay, okay, I guess that's so.
Speaker 0: that's the thing Super bubble jaw buster show your daddy or like ginger sugar babies Etc.
Speaker 1: all these hard things that old ladies the dots.
Speaker 0: so anyway this article in proper 538 style goes through like a pretty detailed analysis of the results with data, and it's fascinating.
Speaker 0: That is my Halloween thing of the day.
Speaker 1: I have a non Halloween thing of the day.
Speaker 1: so in the year 1987 or 88 When I was in kindergarten for the first time in my life I had access to a Personal computer the Apple - that was in the classroom and on it was shit like well flop.
Speaker 1: Well, there was nothing on it except for the OS Floppy disk next to it five and a quarter inch ones and some of them had Some member munchers or word munchers.
Speaker 1: But some of them had turtle graphics slash logo, and that is where I programmed a computer for the first time.
Speaker 1: someone who is a perhaps genius has created this web app.
Speaker 1: you can just go to this turtle that audio in your browser and There it is.
Speaker 1: it's turtle graphic slash logo.
Speaker 1: it operates.
Speaker 1: If you know how to operate turtle graphics or logo you know how to operate this Except if you just look at it.
Speaker 0: You can operate this you do not.
Speaker 1: well You also.
Speaker 1: you can do vice versa also, but it is not used to make graphics.
Speaker 1: It is used to make audio much like a Mario Paint.
Speaker 1: the line you draw controls the the frequency of the notes you are making and they sequence and then there is well, and then there's the.
Speaker 1: you know you paint different colors onto your sequence to play different notes and There you go you have a music sequencer that you control via turtle graphics.
Speaker 1: It's really slick for being something in a web browser.
Speaker 1: It's way good, and I think in the past We've I've had other things of the day that were basically musical tools in the browser like yeah We have a forum thread where people were making music.
Speaker 1: There was one that was like a drum machine and one that was like a synthesizer.
Speaker 1: So I think like I don't have the skills to do this, but I I'm sure someone else has done it already.
Speaker 1: But it would be really cool if somebody went and like collected all these different web-based Synthesizing drum machine sequencing music making tools and Use them all together to make.
Speaker 1: there's a Google doodle that was a music tool.
Speaker 1: once I do right combine them together Into a music rig to create an EDM song.
Speaker 0: I guess the only trouble I have is that not to be EDM.
Speaker 0: I could just be em having a an actual legit background in for real music and composition.
Speaker 0: It is I find it like Especially hard and strange to use any of these things Because it is so much faster to just write out sheet music for me than to do any of this nonsense.
Speaker 1: Yeah, no almost no musical tool.
Speaker 0: That's or use like a real synthesizer like.
Speaker 0: I can do that almost nothing.
Speaker 0: that is well with a keyboard on it Or even without a keyboard like if it's just like a drum machine style like synthesizer or a ranger sequencer and synthesizer.
Speaker 1: I have several iOS apps that are like, you know full-on.
Speaker 1: You could make like crazy music with them and people do and I just can't even figure out what the fuck to do with them.
Speaker 1: I have that had more success with Korg on the DS than with any of these iOS things I'm gonna.
Speaker 0: yes at least acts like real stuff like.
Speaker 1: I know how to use but the user interface of it You can figure it out.
Speaker 1: Even if you are clueless if you're just competent to a degree.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but like what is what is this app?
Speaker 1: I have my iPad here.
Speaker 1: What is this thing?
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know what app I would use that Maker 3.
Speaker 1: so I beat maker 3 on my iPad.
Speaker 1: I think it was like free or like on super sale for like 50 cents or something at one point.
Speaker 1: So I just got it and I don't think it's free all the time.
Speaker 1: But it's like you open this up and it's like you can tell.
Speaker 1: this is a serious app.
Speaker 1: It's not like.
Speaker 1: it's not like reason but it's like a level below that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's still.
Speaker 1: you could make real music with this.
Speaker 0: So will you listen to it?
Speaker 1: I can't even figure out how to make it be like, you know?
Speaker 1: Okay The UI is just such a mess of craziness.
Speaker 0: granted the last time I was actually composing music I need a tutorial or something.
Speaker 0: I was I was using a for a long time like up until when I just kind of stopped doing that stuff.
Speaker 0: I had a pirated copy of cakewalk studio and I had a pirated copy of Cool edit 2000.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and though that was like my final rim is actually making real music pipeline before that Ship kind of sailed.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the one thing I always look at whenever like I think yeah, I should become a become a DJ.
Speaker 1: It's like get though.
Speaker 1: What's it called?
Speaker 1: The starts of the a. what the hell's that thing?
Speaker 1: Well the thing with the two the thing without the digital records You get to know you get the lot you get the pad with all this the touchy the square.
Speaker 0: I don't like that thing at all.
Speaker 1: you get that and you connect it to what the hell's the set?
Speaker 0: That thing feels like it's purely Performative and isn't that useful.
Speaker 0: and it seems like the people who use it either use it to make a spectacle around it or our DJs or our people who don't have a classical education in music and are sort of naively deriving and making music using Simpler tools that don't come from the tradition of
Speaker 1: sure, but those people live the life of a world hopping DJ.
Speaker 0: Some of them do.
Speaker 0: some of them are just like Jason in the good place.
Speaker 0: What you haven't watched anyway them at a moment.
Speaker 0: We've reviewed all the anime that came out and is coming out in the fall a while ago and it's on YouTube.
Speaker 0: And the point is if you're new to geek nights, we reviewed it all before we watched any of it.
Speaker 0: So go watch some of this anime and tell us if we're right.
Speaker 1: Oh Ableton.
Speaker 0: That's that In some other stuff coming up sooner than you think we are going to be at Pax unplugged doing not one but two events on Saturday.
Speaker 0: learn and win Puerto Rico.
Speaker 0: We're gonna teach everyone how to play this classic board game.
Speaker 0: They're going to teach everyone how to be good at it.
Speaker 1: That was the number one game on board game geek for years before it was unseated.
Speaker 0: It is still highly ranked, but you know, yeah But it is arguably one of the most elegantly designed euro like style board games ever.
Speaker 0: yep, and there's a reason why it gets talked about to this day.
Speaker 0: and we're also gonna be doing a Slightly more advanced version of the 40 tabletop games you must play because it's a tabletop con.
Speaker 0: We can assume the audience knows some stuff about tabletop and if they don't that sucks for them.
Speaker 1: Why are they there?
Speaker 0: Why at Pax unplugged?
Speaker 0: Did you not realize it was the unplugged packs?
Speaker 0: That panel will also be streaming from Pax unplugged.
Speaker 0: So yeah, if you're not a fax unplugged you can watch us do a panel live.
Speaker 0: So maybe like one of us will fall off the stage or something like stage on purpose push rim off the stage.
Speaker 1: The book club book is a Space Odyssey 2001 a Space Odyssey by Arthur C. Clarke.
Speaker 1: We just did the the real Odyssey now.
Speaker 1: We're doing the Space Odyssey.
Speaker 1: I'm still reading fantasy novels because I'm a nerd but as soon as I finish them I'll read.
Speaker 1: I'll probably be able to read 2001 a Space Odyssey very quickly.
Speaker 0: Yep, so weirdly enough somehow Scott and I both watched our cartoon all the way to the end, right?
Speaker 1: So I was on a tropical island and I don't know if you know this but on tiny tropical islands that don't have like major cities and commerce There are.
Speaker 1: I don't know how many nerds are there but not a lot especially not in a district full of hotels and beaches.
Speaker 1: and also There's not really anything to do at night unless you want to drink dance or go to a casino.
Speaker 1: So at night I saw lots of people not just me.
Speaker 1: we were like we were walking back to the hotel after you know, lazing by the pool after dinner and We looked into people's rooms because their windows are open and they were all sitting around watching TV at like eight o'clock On a tropical island in a hotel where they were on vacation because what the fuck else are they gonna do?
Speaker 1: so we went back to our room and Watch TV.
Speaker 1: wife put out the iPad and the Wi-Fi totally worked.
Speaker 1: So we watch we open up the Netflix and we're like, all right, watch the dragon thing.
Speaker 1: It's all like nine episodes upstairs the deal.
Speaker 0: The Dragon Prince is a cartoon on Netflix.
Speaker 1: It has a Netflix original.
Speaker 1: You can only see it legally on Netflix.
Speaker 0: It has a lot of people involved in it who were involved in Avatar the Last Airbender, which is an a-plus show and It's pretty good and there's only nine episodes in the first season.
Speaker 1: So I wonder if it'll how many seasons it will go.
Speaker 1: unlike other some Netflix shows they just go.
Speaker 0: Well, I feel like it'll be a lot like they're obviously gonna have a second one Definitely like it's.
Speaker 0: following the same pattern as Avatar the Last Airbender and the plot at the like there is going to be probably a plot that concludes and Resolves everything that needs to be resolved over the course of five or so seasons.
Speaker 1: that show is a. it is a computer animated show, but the computer animation is like most of the time I was watching on a High-resolution iPad.
Speaker 1: Yeah a small screen and because of that I think I didn't notice a lot of rough edges.
Speaker 0: So the ad is interesting.
Speaker 0: I noticed them occasionally but rarely it has a watching on a bigger TV.
Speaker 0: it's interesting because a lot of people are complaining about the animation and what I can basically say is that The animation is a little off-putting in the sense that the characters tend to strike pretty static poses.
Speaker 0: I think Emily pointed out like once they strike a pose Like it's a thing so they're all kind of like And then they just stay in that pose.
Speaker 1: There were some weird poses, but there are also some amazing facial expressions.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, so the character the girl wizard.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah She oh god already forgot her name.
Speaker 0: it is his name.
Speaker 0: I pulled up the I know no character's name Claudia Claudia.
Speaker 0: Okay, she makes good faces.
Speaker 0: the elf girl make Rayla makes good faces.
Speaker 0: But the character designs are a plus.
Speaker 0: like the art is great the animations The animation is it.
Speaker 0: I'd say that at worst it's about as off-putting as the animation at a walk through But for different it's better.
Speaker 1: It's way better than what?
Speaker 1: Thing is like.
Speaker 1: it's because it's CG, right?
Speaker 1: It's like you don't really.
Speaker 1: it's like you're always gonna pick on it for its imperfections.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right when it's like a 3d CG I stop noticing and just really like the show.
Speaker 1: and yeah, it's like I didn't you know, I didn't stand out it didn't Interfere with the show in any way and it's like yeah, okay you want to complain about this But it's like no one complain about Toy Story.
Speaker 1: put this next to Toy Story.
Speaker 1: Toy Story looked like garbage.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right, even though you know cuz Toy Story's from the 90s.
Speaker 0: Well, so what helps is like the characters are good.
Speaker 0: The plots actually pretty good and more complex than I expected, right?
Speaker 0: So the plot the characters motivations are all Not just one-dimensional which is interesting, right?
Speaker 1: I think the thing is it's like There are a lot of shows that complain about because they have no characters I care about at all in this show.
Speaker 1: Some characters that are way awesome that sort of hold the show and the some characters that are me.
Speaker 0: I think I like almost all the characters who have speaking lines.
Speaker 0: I think that you like.
Speaker 1: so I don't know spoilers, but so the main dude don't like him.
Speaker 1: He's just a boring annoying dude.
Speaker 0: his voice acting is really good and he's clearly Is like it's.
Speaker 1: it doesn't sound like Shaggy from Scooby Doo, but he's sort of like that same sort of like.
Speaker 0: No, that's the same voice actor who played Sokka who's one of the main characters in Avatar The Last Airbender Whatever is.
Speaker 1: he's annoying dude.
Speaker 1: I want to smack Best character in.
Speaker 1: the whole show does not talk because they're deaf.
Speaker 0: Oh my god the commander.
Speaker 0: What's-her-name?
Speaker 1: General Amaya.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the aunt.
Speaker 1: The aunt of the princess.
Speaker 1: It's like the kings like the Kings.
Speaker 1: No, it's the.
Speaker 1: it's the Queen's sister.
Speaker 1: It's the Kings sister-in-law.
Speaker 0: It's worth noting that this show has a very good and broad set of representation.
Speaker 1: I feel like what they must have done is just been like, okay, we gotta we want to.
Speaker 1: we want to be cool and modern.
Speaker 1: Let's make sure everyone's represented.
Speaker 1: So it's like who can we represent?
Speaker 1: Blind people deaf people disabled people diseased people black people white people Color of people every gender of people.
Speaker 1: Let's get them all in there.
Speaker 0: I like they like they're consistent and stuff like the fact that the moon elves all just have like vaguely Scottish accents Like.
Speaker 0: I like that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that was strange Was like wait, why are the elves got it, but that's just how they are Like.
Speaker 0: I like how they just did.
Speaker 1: that is I bet you know, we haven't seen a map of this land.
Speaker 1: Are they gonna?
Speaker 1: is it gonna be Great Britain and the elves live in the north?
Speaker 0: We've seen a really high-level map.
Speaker 0: on the right side of the island there's elves and magic.
Speaker 0: Is it?
Speaker 1: the UK turned right to the right and supposedly everything's great.
Speaker 1: is the East actually the norm?
Speaker 0: but I wonder if it's great in the same sense that the White Tower in Wheel of Time is great.
Speaker 1: and then when you get there Oh, I see is the basic plot is a generic fantasy plot where there's elves in a magical land in the East And there's a human land in the outside because in the ancient times there was a war and they divided Human.
Speaker 0: and then there's there's normal magic.
Speaker 0: humans find shitty evil magic that they shouldn't be touching.
Speaker 1: So there's all these good kinds of magic, you know that are all elemental magics.
Speaker 1: But there's also evil magic that some humans did.
Speaker 0: elves won't do it very like Wheel of Time Like that's the magic you weren't supposed to touch.
Speaker 1: you get the idea for this intro that they give you in like the first minute.
Speaker 1: Humans are bad elves are good But then the show entirely focuses on humans and most of the humans they show you were totally good Except for the evil one.
Speaker 0: So I suspect not to give you spoilers But a lot of the humans who were introduced as good are going to become and be legit evil And I don't even know if they'll all get redemption arcs.
Speaker 1: I think the only one who's evil is the number one evil guy and even his I think even his evil kids are not evil.
Speaker 0: I mean, I'm not gonna lie.
Speaker 0: I think Claudia in particular The wizard girl who's the I think she is going to choose the evil magic.
Speaker 0: That's a big part of her life.
Speaker 1: I think she's going to choose the evil magic, but I don't think she's going to do evil things.
Speaker 0: I think she is I think she person.
Speaker 0: I think she's gonna end up doing evil things.
Speaker 1: because above all the thing with this show Is that despite being like an excellent show for children because like it goes it is a kid show It's aimed at kids.
Speaker 1: It is a kid show.
Speaker 1: and because it is a kid show Even though it's like ah This is great for children because it is deeper than other garbage kids shows and still entertaining for an adult It is still 100% predictable.
Speaker 1: I was basically as you're watching I said This is this and as soon as I said anything it immediately happened and I had never seen it before.
Speaker 0: Yeah of course Avatar was a little bit like that too in its first season and then every season it got more complex and more nuanced and started.
Speaker 1: Take like for example, this is not a spoiler because it is at no point Confirmed to be the truth in the first season at any point.
Speaker 1: So it can't be a spoiler if it's just a prediction by me.
Speaker 0: But your prediction might be based on things you saw later in the season.
Speaker 1: I predicted this within like the as soon as the snake appeared in the first episode Right, which was like 10 minutes into the show that the king would be swapped into the birds body.
Speaker 0: I was yeah 100% and I will bet my entire fortune lingers on this shot of the bird.
Speaker 1: I will bet my entire fortune that the king has been swapped into the body of the bird.
Speaker 1: Figured that out as soon as they said we they basically like we have a snake.
Speaker 1: It has two heads.
Speaker 1: if the two heads bite two things the souls of the two things will be swapped and there's a king standing There who's awesome, by the way.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 0: The king is both awesome and the hottest character in the show Yes, and he reminds me of the pirate from You because I felt similarly and the king has a pet definitely some sexual tension between him and the wizard guy.
Speaker 1: Yes, the king has a pet bird who is also awesome.
Speaker 1: Yeah And as soon as I saw the king of the pet bird and a two-headed snake that swapped souls between two beings I said the king will be soft with the bird.
Speaker 1: and While it was never confirmed at any point in the first season I will bet every dollar that I in my possession that that is the case yep, and the show does not explicitly say it.
Speaker 1: but oh and this does like.
Speaker 1: the money cannot be awarded to Anyone who writes for the show?
Speaker 1: Yeah Could then in the second season find a way to write their way out of that money.
Speaker 0: So the basic story is pretty good like it's a typical fantasy story.
Speaker 0: but basically the humans got the evil magic and Then they decided to go invade the other side of the planet and be jerks.
Speaker 0: and the dragons were like nope fucking stop it.
Speaker 0: I'm not letting this happen.
Speaker 0: and they use the evil magic to kill the king of the dragons Yep, and his son.
Speaker 1: Well, his son who's still in an egg.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they broke into dragon.
Speaker 0: It's not the ass right king of the dragons.
Speaker 0: His prince son is dead.
Speaker 1: So now that all those human princes now the elves want to get revenge So there's the badass king really like honestly the elven.
Speaker 0: justification for this assassination Pretty fucking justified right?
Speaker 1: So the elves are coming.
Speaker 1: They're like, hey you killed the king of mood.
Speaker 0: Oh, right.
Speaker 1: You killed the king of the dragons and the egg his son.
Speaker 1: So we're gonna come and kill the king.
Speaker 1: We're gonna kill your king and kill the human king and his son and base symmetry Right.
Speaker 1: So the show starts where there's the assassin.
Speaker 1: moon elves are coming.
Speaker 1: the humans find out that they're coming and they're like Well, I guess you're dead because we can't stop moon elves.
Speaker 1: They're too strong.
Speaker 1: Yep, and then the show goes from there.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and not really.
Speaker 0: It's the first episode like right away, but spoilers the egg wasn't actually smashed.
Speaker 0: There's a dragon prince and that's good.
Speaker 0: The whole show is gonna be about that.
Speaker 0: They're trying to get the dragon prince's egg home to the dragon queen who is still alive, right?
Speaker 1: Obviously the human kings vizier is the bad guy like Jafar.
Speaker 1: Yeah The only thing about him that I can say is because I mean really he thinks the vizier is the bad guy.
Speaker 1: again The only thing about him that I can say one him and the king were definitely fucking.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah But the only thing I can say about him is that I like how he actually can put on an act of being a good guy.
Speaker 1: sometimes Jafar who was always like Occasionally, he's like I am pretending to be good and I'm doing a good job of pretending to be good.
Speaker 0: I'm always impressed when there's an evil character who lies convincingly in a show.
Speaker 1: Yes And that led to the best moment in the entire first season when the best character the general who cannot hear.
Speaker 0: Oh my god She is so awesome.
Speaker 1: She says The she needs the evil guy is lying convincingly and she says bring me a stable boy I found a pile of bullshit.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well, she signs it.
Speaker 1: Yeah But I love that line was the funniest line.
Speaker 0: That's the other thing I like about this show.
Speaker 0: It is that there are funny times that in general like there are some stupid characters.
Speaker 0: But characters who aren't written to be stupid are Smart and figure stuff out that you as the viewer have also figured out and it skips a lot of those tropes That a show like this could follow of like everyone being fooled by the wizard like no every
Speaker 1: almost
Speaker 0: everyone is not fooled by the Wizard.
Speaker 1: Yep But yeah, the show is Humorous.
Speaker 1: it is good at the humors.
Speaker 0: There's a lot of really funny bits.
Speaker 0: There's some there's good like the drama is pretty good.
Speaker 0: The characters make plans and follow them for good reasons.
Speaker 0: Yeah like I like this.
Speaker 1: don't just don't.
Speaker 1: it's.
Speaker 1: the only thing you can't get from the show is unpredictability because if you are an Intelligent person who can see foreshadowing you will know everything that is going to happen.
Speaker 1: Well before it happens and then you will watch it happen.
Speaker 1: Yep But you will still be entertained because the characters that are good will be entertaining and fun to watch.
Speaker 1: you Care about them to some extent.
Speaker 1: there'll be funny times.
Speaker 1: There will be some action scenes that are Right.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they they're.
Speaker 0: they come and go they're like, they're mostly pretty good.
Speaker 0: None of them are really bad.
Speaker 0: There's not a lot of monster of the week nonsense either.
Speaker 0: like it moves along for it's definitely not monster of the week.
Speaker 1: It's definitely a quest kind of structure.
Speaker 0: yep, right and it does.
Speaker 1: every conflict that occurs has stakes that matter to the story which is a lot more like You know Galaxy Express kind of situation.
Speaker 1: We got to get from here to there.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so not not.
Speaker 1: we got a.
Speaker 0: you know We stay in one place and bad guys come also frankly hot elves How do humans dragon like the shows up my alley and I'm gonna watch the rest of it Definitely watch the second season.
Speaker 1: I mean, I'll probably end up watching it, but it's not like I'm gonna run to watch.
Speaker 0: I mean avatar is a like a a show like.
Speaker 0: it's a great show But it's done and we've seen it all and it also.
Speaker 0: not only was it good, but it got better with every season.
Speaker 0: So the real test of the dragon France is if season 2 improves upon this base.
Speaker 0: Because if it improves at the rate that avatar did the final seasons of the show are gonna be a plus.
Speaker 0: Because avatar season 1 so it has a lot of the similar issues to what this show season 1 has.
Speaker 1: I think it comes down to.
Speaker 0: you should watch avatar Scott.
Speaker 0: It is really really good Yeah.
Speaker 1: So I think what this show its goodness level in the future is gonna come down to like how many seasons it has.
Speaker 0: Right if I had to guess because that will deter because right now the six how many times how many kinds of magic are there?
Speaker 0: There will be a number of seasons equal to the number of kinds of magic with a plus or minus one.
Speaker 0: Cuz they final season might be the evil shitty human magic.
Speaker 1: cuz the pacing of season one.
Speaker 1: It was really good in terms of how things moved along.
Speaker 0: avatars like that to avatar.
Speaker 0: just like stuff happens It's like moving.
Speaker 1: you can only keep that pace up so long without reaching the elven land.
Speaker 1: And once you've reached the elven land I assume they're gonna bring the dragon egg all the less like in the wheel of time and like an escaflown a. it's a children's show.
Speaker 1: They're going to succeed in their quest.
Speaker 1: Yeah, bring it all the way there.
Speaker 1: But I'm saying you can't have too much more content after that point.
Speaker 0: cuz.
Speaker 0: yes, you can cuz.
Speaker 0: I am confident that there will be Drama in the elven lands that we have not seen yet.
Speaker 1: That would make that.
Speaker 0: thinking about that makes me like there's probably like some elves that want to invade the human.
Speaker 1: I want them to reach the elven land and then tada we have reached the climax Climax.
Speaker 0: Now the dragon princess.
Speaker 0: here the humans still have their shitty magic Some sort of resolution.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the end I mean the show will definitely resolve itself drags on then I will stop caring.
Speaker 0: so I'll bet there be a number of seasons equal to the West your way to the elven land for a season or three more plus.
Speaker 0: There's two ways to go if you got to keep a show moving.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they're just end it good or like right away or You ask a flown a.
Speaker 1: the other problem.
Speaker 0: Just keep escalating and escalating and eventually Isaac Newton shows up.
Speaker 1: The other problem could be if they do to Netflix it ends too soon and they either a Russian ending which won't be good or Be cut it short and you don't get resolved and get to the elven land, which that would be some bullshit.
Speaker 0: I think it's doing well enough to where it's gonna just continue.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: We'll see.
Speaker 0: Let's see.
Speaker 0: release.
Speaker 0: Season two is definitely confirmed.
Speaker 1: The season two is a hundred percent confirmed.
Speaker 1: They can't.
Speaker 1: Maybe the look just if you watch season one, you know, they already made season two, but season three I think may be in question.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I suspect it'll make it all the way to its end though Based on the popularity I've seen so far and the fact that the season is relatively short like nine episodes if you do six or so Seasons of about nine episodes each that's actually a pretty good number
Speaker 1: of episodes.
Speaker 1: This much in nine episodes.
Speaker 1: we watched it in one sitting and it wasn't even.
Speaker 1: you know Late is that in three seasons you've got nine 1827.
Speaker 1: That's one season of anime, right?
Speaker 1: So that's why I think like wrapping it up in three seasons would be like way good.
Speaker 1: if they wrapped it up even in less Than five that would be like super good.
Speaker 0: cuz I'm pretty sure there's gonna be new like stakes.
Speaker 0: We don't know about yet.
Speaker 1: It'll be close to like the 48 episode area.
Speaker 0: Yeah 52 episodes seems like it's still like.
Speaker 0: that's my magic number of.
Speaker 1: It's getting a little long in a tooth at the 52.
Speaker 0: anything that goes beyond 52.
Speaker 0: I'd better be really goddamn good.
Speaker 0: reason for going longer than 52 like it better be fist in the North Star.
Speaker 0: Yeah Moon if you're gonna go that way, but yeah, this is death or Galaxy Express.
Speaker 0: This is definitely worth watching a few episodes of to see if you like it.
Speaker 1: I feel like if you got Netflix and you're saying I want to watch a thing that I haven't watched before.
Speaker 1: This is nine episodes.
Speaker 1: You should choose this.
Speaker 1: if you're me for anime nerd or someone who watches animation You should not buy Netflix to watch this.
Speaker 1: You should not watch this if you don't like fantasy or animation.
Speaker 0: Also, I get the only the only thing I'm disappointed in is that if we are right and the king is in the bird Then we lost the awesome hot king body and now he's just in the hot bird body instead.
Speaker 0: Well, they're like the king body is hotter.
Speaker 1: There could be some sort of saving for that king body.
Speaker 1: that was not revealed But there was no foreshadowing of any way to save the king.
Speaker 0: I worry we're never gonna get him back in his proper hot king body.
Speaker 1: I think you could just be saved by Fiat dragon magic by the end in the.
Speaker 0: yeah Yeah, I just I wonder what the drug I think like up.
Speaker 0: the big turning point in the show is gonna be either Some at like some elves that don't want the parents to be found because they want to start the war themselves with the humans.
Speaker 1: or Well, it's like at the beginning of the show They're like, oh humans are using the bad magic they bad.
Speaker 1: but then at the end once they get to the elven land It's gonna be like, oh look there's some bad elves, even though they're not using evil magic.
Speaker 0: so far We've only met like one kind of elf the moon elf.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: No, we met two kinds of elves.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah Yeah, that's magical.
Speaker 0: I also did enjoy that like there's that side bit where the elf There's mustache guy and she like totally punks him.
Speaker 0: I thought mustache I thought you would be cool and he's just a shithead.
Speaker 1: Well, that's actually one thing I can say.
Speaker 1: the only prediction I made that was wrong.
Speaker 1: Yeah was when Mustache guy appeared I said he's gonna join the party and then he didn't join the yep.
Speaker 0: Not only did not join the party.
Speaker 0: I do think though.
Speaker 1: He will reappear much like say Those guys in Star Wars who don't like you.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I like how she didn't even steal his stupid sword.
Speaker 1: She didn't want this.
Speaker 0: She was just like.
Speaker 0: I don't watch your sword.
Speaker 0: What's wrong with you?
Speaker 0: Never mind.
Speaker 0: Jeez.
Speaker 0: So, uh, yeah, this is worth watching and is really good and at some point Maybe we'll do a spoiler episode, but we'll probably wait for another season to come out.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we'll wait for at least after season two We'll probably do an episode where we'll talk about his guts cuz like it's not like there's.
Speaker 1: no it's never a lot of metaphor going on in this guy, but I think the other The other big turning point I predict it's just an adventure.
Speaker 0: I foresee the dragon Queen Not doing what we expect Not having the same motivations is what we might expect and being a big monkey wrench in the overall plot.
Speaker 0: I think that I think The meeting of the dragon Queen is gonna be like a big moment.
Speaker 0: where the show swerves is my guess.
Speaker 0: Hmm that's just like that's.
Speaker 0: that's pure speculation.
Speaker 0: I can't say that I have any specific thing that I'm pointing at for that.
Speaker 0: I just think that's gonna be a big turning point.
Speaker 1: She's not gonna be like, oh, thank you for bringing my egg I don't know.
Speaker 0: Maybe she wants revenge.
Speaker 0: Anyway, maybe she's mad me.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I don't know what her deals gonna be.
Speaker 0: Hmm.
Speaker 0: I feel like she's gonna have a deal.
Speaker 0: That's not just I am now the dragon Queen.
Speaker 0: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Speaker 1: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 0: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows Sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: geek nights is distributed under a creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows It's actually recorded at night.
Speaker 0: and the patreon patrons for this episode of you guys and it's the actual current list because patreon isn't down like it was when We did the show on Monday.
Speaker 0: Craig Oliver Alan Joyce heading McNicholas shimming Ruby obelisk hanging in the sky kashar tovish in my state e.com Linky GJ band scooter lonely Roberto Kingsley Sean Yeager Matthew Smith Nicholas Brando, mr Strong stretch and 4 to 1 creations Chris Reimer and Thomas Hahn.
Speaker 0: sure fun horror.
Speaker 0: Aurora Michelle, Monta Nona Superboy trip wire sailor Vista Don Schleig Joe Shiro Joe star Clinton Walton read from New Zealand Ryan Perrin drew open lander Finn Chris midkiff Daniel Redman Sean Klein Chris Reimer and Thomas Hahn.
Speaker 0: Thank you for 2018 minus 2005 years of geek nights.
Speaker 0: I can't believe we've done this much.
Speaker 0: if any of you have listened to every one of these episodes I don't actually want to know because that's terrifying but just note the fact that you've done that because that seems remarkable.
Speaker 0: and anyway now I leave you with Such a screeching.
Speaker 0: you'll shake and share in surprise when you hear these zombies.
Speaker 1: We're so sorry skeletons.
Speaker 1: You're so misunderstood.
Speaker 1: You only want to socialize The.