Speaker 1: It's Thursday, March 29th, 2018.
Speaker 1: I'm rim Scott and tonight on geek nights We are talking about socks for your feet Not socks proxies Let's do.
Speaker 1: this is a joke about a socks proxy actually An obvious joke.
Speaker 1: I was I was also thinking it but I feel like the average listener Is too young to have ever encountered that.
Speaker 0: I was also thinking it like war.
Speaker 1: yeah, but we're the same age and we come from the same.
Speaker 1: like generation of computer.
Speaker 1: like Sox isn't really used anymore except in like archaic enterprise nonsense.
Speaker 0: Just saying that.
Speaker 0: I was also thinking this.
Speaker 1: Yep In fact, one of my first jobs was maintaining a socks proxy that ran on os2 warp To connect this SNA network with the internal Ethernet network in a print in an IBM Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: That was a Shall we say ancient times?
Speaker 1: So, uh, yeah, it's a Thursday geek nights.
Speaker 1: It's the lounge.
Speaker 1: we can talk about anything.
Speaker 1: It's not the lounge.
Speaker 1: You can't talk about anything.
Speaker 0: No, that's it going home.
Speaker 1: Yeah But uh, yeah packs is coming up real soon.
Speaker 0: we're doing kind of a weird skip into the minute moment right now.
Speaker 0: I'm saying we're.
Speaker 1: it means we're doing sort of like a weird abbreviated schedule and I'm sort of Preoccupied with the fact that packs has come in.
Speaker 1: I'm pretty hyped for it like more.
Speaker 0: so I knew furniture.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, you just then.
Speaker 1: It's interesting to be in the position.
Speaker 0: We're having rid of a bunch of crap.
Speaker 0: My apartment is taking up too much room that would need.
Speaker 0: the furniture needs to go.
Speaker 1: We're old enough to where you Telling us.
Speaker 1: Oh, I'm buying furniture and like the details are like who are you getting a chase?
Speaker 1: Like what are you gonna put what kind of furniture you get?
Speaker 1: And that was a real exciting conversation for us when I moved into the apartment.
Speaker 0: I just got IKEA furniture as fast as possible And that was the cheapest and the most convenient without planning or designing or anything.
Speaker 0: and now it's like, okay The couch is broken.
Speaker 0: I need new furniture.
Speaker 0: Now I can actually think about this and get the best furniture.
Speaker 1: furniture ain't cheap?
Speaker 0: No, not good furniture unless you want the worst furniture or you know.
Speaker 0: I mean IKEA is slightly less cheap, you know, it's still way cheap compared to real furniture.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but it doesn't last that long.
Speaker 1: And the problem is it's very easy to find furniture that I like.
Speaker 1: That looks good.
Speaker 1: That would be 100% perfect.
Speaker 1: Usually the things that are perfect are it's not even like oh, it's a few thousand dollars.
Speaker 1: It's like yeah, that's eight thousand dollars fucker Yep.
Speaker 0: Well also, you know the other problem is like if I had a big old empty house It'd be really easy to get furniture.
Speaker 0: But when you have a tiny ass apartment suddenly, everything is difficult.
Speaker 1: Yep, like giant like when I was a kid, we had a giant living room and a giant family room.
Speaker 0: So they go to the furniture store and you see this big layout.
Speaker 0: You're like, oh, this is perfect And it's like take that whole place to be late.
Speaker 0: This would be terrific if I had an enormous room that was bigger than my apartment.
Speaker 0: five times five.
Speaker 1: Yeah the Midwestern like Large house you have the giant lazy boys somewhere and then he got like the big sectional couch That takes up like it would fill this entire room.
Speaker 0: I don't think you could fit it in this room.
Speaker 1: You could probably cut it up and fit all the pieces in this room.
Speaker 0: sure It would be just a big.
Speaker 0: the room would just be one big cushion.
Speaker 1: So maybe that's my strategy just cushion the floors.
Speaker 1: Okay, so you got any news?
Speaker 0: I do have a news.
Speaker 0: So, I don't know if this is really news.
Speaker 0: It was almost thing of the day, but whatever.
Speaker 0: So they someone wrote and investigated and got this article about the history of nesticle.
Speaker 0: And if you don't know back in the day like late 90s, right?
Speaker 0: I'll never get over that icon.
Speaker 0: when I first discovered what an emulator was and realized I could play Console games on my computer and download them for free and not have to pay money and get cartridges And just use my gravis gamepad and not you know, the real controllers Which you can now use the real controllers things to USB which didn't really exist too much then eggs only uses it then a little bit.
Speaker 0: but yeah Someone went and researched the history of nesticle.
Speaker 0: who made it where it came from when they made it how they made it all the Drama that happened in the scene around it.
Speaker 0: You know where the why there was a pair of testicles as the icon.
Speaker 0: All this grand nesticle was.
Speaker 1: it's interesting because not only was it like the first Widespread use emulator that like nerds would find and use who weren't like deep into the scene It was really like fully featured.
Speaker 0: No, it was in this emulator basically invented all those features They talk about like what happened is nesticle what you know, what happened to the guy I ended up using SNES 9x for SNES?
Speaker 0: You read this article you'll know I just saw.
Speaker 0: You'll find out why you ended up using SNES 9x.
Speaker 0: Oh, yes, and yes and ZSNES that came later.
Speaker 0: And yeah, I didn't realize that Genesis was made by the same guy who made nesticle Stuff like that.
Speaker 0: So this is like it's like weird to read an article about history that I lived.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right like it'd be like if there was an article that described the inner workings of the magic the gathering scene during the revised era.
Speaker 0: It's yeah, it's like what this is.
Speaker 0: So yeah If you know if you're just somebody takes emulators for granted or someone who also lived through this And doesn't you know?
Speaker 0: because I lived through this but I didn't know all these details about what was going on Wasn't in the scene.
Speaker 0: I was just some kid who was downloading rums.
Speaker 1: Yeah, a friend of mine on a BBS was like yo You can play any yes games on a computer and I was like you're lying Mm-hmm, and then they were like no no no check this out.
Speaker 1: And then I installed nesticle and it was it.
Speaker 1: it was like that moment when I first heard an mp3 And I realized what that meant for the future the first time I started Mario 1 in an emulator.
Speaker 1: I just paused it and sat there thinking wow, this changes everything.
Speaker 1: and Most of the NES games I played on the emulator were games I already owned cartridges for.
Speaker 1: it was just way more convenient to play on the computer Also saves eights men.
Speaker 1: I beat a lot of games that I never bet beat on a real console Like Wizards and Warriors games Wizards warriors fucking three.
Speaker 0: There was no way I was gonna beat that game I like with no warriors to all the elemental bosses.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah - it's pretty good I like -.
Speaker 0: I had a strategy guide for that.
Speaker 0: I was one of those times where you're a kid you buy a strategy guide and all the strategies for games You don't have yep, which just made me want to buy those games.
Speaker 0: It was in there.
Speaker 1: but actually I was thinking I was watching the world records for Wizards warriors 1 and I remember I played that again recently on an emulator and Hard as balls.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but it's also pretty fun.
Speaker 1: Like I feel like I could beat Wizards and Warriors 1.
Speaker 0: I like the aesthetic of it Wizards and Warriors.
Speaker 0: Well the spiders and the treasure chests and the candidates and the wizards.
Speaker 1: Yeah I'd like I'd like to see a remake of that kind of game Sure, like Shovel Knight style like take it and make it a little bit more accessible and less bullshit.
Speaker 1: But no I mean I have not read this article and I'm going to read it because I'm really curious about all these details that were Completely opaque to me as a child.
Speaker 0: I mean, I think the main takeaway from this right is like, you know There's all this scene drama.
Speaker 0: and we you know, even today this every scene has drama.
Speaker 1: right now, you know any fandom whatever Going crazy right now about some like YouTube shouty man that I'd no idea right kind of in that scene.
Speaker 0: But in the long run, it's the all that scene drama doesn't matter and goes away.
Speaker 0: No one cares everyone just laughs about it if they even remember it.
Speaker 1: Well, I guess it turns into like.
Speaker 0: and this is you know, you can see the things that last you know That really matter is goddamn.
Speaker 1: we can all play any of this game yep, and but I guess like which emulator became the one of choice is probably driven by drama that No longer is remembered only the result remains.
Speaker 1: So in some other news, this is actually Really relevant to the fact that we're going to PAX.
Speaker 1: So, you know, you can crack your knuckles make some noise.
Speaker 1: Some people can some people can yep Some people can some people can.
Speaker 1: did you know that to this day?
Speaker 1: No one Actually knows what makes that sounds.
Speaker 0: what do you mean?
Speaker 0: It's like your knuckles, right?
Speaker 1: Okay, explain it to me what when I crack my knuckle what causes that sound specific?
Speaker 0: Well, I've seen this article so I know the real answer.
Speaker 0: But this is the answer that a common person would say.
Speaker 0: so I'm gonna pretend to be naive, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, so you got bones.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you got muscles holding the bones together.
Speaker 1: Well, you got tendons holding the bones.
Speaker 0: It's all the same shit.
Speaker 1: No, it's not.
Speaker 0: you got flesh holding bones together, yeah, there's human.
Speaker 1: Otherwise the bones would just sort of fall apart like like the other half of stone to flesh the spell Which is really gross.
Speaker 0: if you cast Kellan's that you see in the classroom are held together with screws because without the flesh the bones don't stay together.
Speaker 0: Yep, and then the flesh moves and the bones are in there, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, and when you don't move them for a while, you know the muscles sorta, you know Or whatever and the bones get close they're moving around.
Speaker 0: so sometimes, you know You'll loosen them up and when you move the muscle the fleshy bits.
Speaker 0: Sometimes the bones scrape against each other and go click click.
Speaker 0: No, no the reality is That is incorrect, but isn't that a common sense?
Speaker 1: It is a common sentiment and the thing I can say is that it's a common sense answer.
Speaker 1: you would but the other common sense Answer is you would fucking know if your bone was scraping against your bone.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't know really.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's a lot of the problems that runners and people get.
Speaker 0: isn't that every joint bones are touching bones?
Speaker 1: No, actually the like.
Speaker 0: your shoulder is in a socket and it moves.
Speaker 1: Yeah There's a total in all the.
Speaker 1: there's a joint and tendons and pads and buffers in there.
Speaker 1: We have actual bone is scraping against actual bone.
Speaker 0: You're in for you're in you're in trouble so that you're telling me that not no zero bones in my body makes No contact whatsoever with any other bone.
Speaker 0: There's always just something in between every bone.
Speaker 1: There are definitely exceptions to that.
Speaker 1: Okay, but generally like the bones you're thinking about there's tendons.
Speaker 0: There's cartilage I mean like my my in my shoulder socket moving around.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there's like cartilage around it.
Speaker 1: Okay stuff there.
Speaker 1: The next most common theory is you get bubbles in your joint and if yep, that's partially true.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well you a lot of you some people get always there's fluids and shit.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there's fluids and there's bubbles But the bubbles popping is not what causes the sound and apparently this article is fascinating.
Speaker 1: the reason why it's so hard to answer this question is The same reason why it's actually hard to answer a lot of questions about the human body.
Speaker 1: There's no way to just video it happening.
Speaker 1: Like you can't just make a video x-ray and high enough speed.
Speaker 0: You'll see bones That's it.
Speaker 1: You'll see bones and a lot like you and you might say oh, but I can see like the inside of a cell.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I like dead died Stabilized cell that was held under a special microscope for a long time.
Speaker 1: Yeah live video, especially high-speed live video of fast events inside of things that you did not kill are Almost impossible to get.
Speaker 1: and is it even gonna work if you're alive or like, you know, yep So I mean there's a reason if you get an MRI, you're basically strapped in and can't move at all.
Speaker 1: So this article talks about how the way they figured this out recently like really recently was by making mathematical models of what those bubbles would look like and then simulating them and then comparing the sound that the simulated bubbles would make when they're interacting with the rest of these joints and bones to Actual recordings of knuckles cracking and looking for matches and all this fancy stuff.
Speaker 1: the article goes into detail.
Speaker 0: It sounds like bones hitting against each other, right?
Speaker 1: Yep, so it ain't even bubbles popping Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: It seems like at least from this data, which is these data, which is pretty new which are pretty new is That it is the cavitation of those bubbles.
Speaker 1: So the bubbles compress and they expand again and that makes the sound they don't pop.
Speaker 0: Oh am I less cracky because I have less gas?
Speaker 1: So they don't know any of those other answers.
Speaker 1: Okay, they don't.
Speaker 0: they still don't know Why some people can crack like crazy and other people can't.
Speaker 1: seems like they don't know that either.
Speaker 0: wouldn't it just be because I'm less Gassy, ah, it's hard to say.
Speaker 1: It's also not clear if those gas bubbles have like if they're important or not.
Speaker 0: Are they have any connection to arthritis or other joint?
Speaker 1: that seems to still be.
Speaker 1: no There's see there doesn't seem to be.
Speaker 1: now again This is just based on my like not scientists and I try problems that people have.
Speaker 1: It seems like there is no real correlation between knuckle cracking and any negative outcomes.
Speaker 1: Okay, so I'm gonna keep cracking my knuckles cuz it feels great and I like the sound.
Speaker 0: yeah They can't do it, you know based on the feeling we can't figure anything out.
Speaker 1: No, I don't think so.
Speaker 0: No, does it feel like gas bubbles are popping when you feel the crack?
Speaker 1: I don't know what it feels like if a gas bubble pops inside of me.
Speaker 0: Maybe you do.
Speaker 1: I know what it feels like when I'm full of gas in certain specific areas But it doesn't make it sound like that.
Speaker 0: no Doesn't.
Speaker 1: if they if that area of gas made a sound like that I would be waiting for the ambulance If I wasn't already dead.
Speaker 1: But this is just sort of a fascinating greed.
Speaker 1: things that appear to have simple answers or common-sense answers Very often have a complex and ambiguous answer.
Speaker 1: That is way Different from what you think.
Speaker 0: Oh, but my Occam's razor.
Speaker 0: Why?
Speaker 1: Yeah Occam's razor doesn't always work.
Speaker 1: son I cut you with the reason this is relevant and I'll say it because a lot of you might not go to Pax's and you Might not have listened to old episodes of geek knives.
Speaker 1: There's a tradition.
Speaker 1: It doesn't happen at every packs anymore not safe.
Speaker 1: The envelope was invented every now and then someone puts it in the envelope.
Speaker 1: I feel like I should ask the question in the envelope for a future packs.
Speaker 1: But occasionally at Pax's in the main theater at the opening ceremonies the
Speaker 0: Q&A
Speaker 1: will do a thing where Everyone in the audience so like thousands of people Crack their knuckles at the same time and you might think that it couldn't possibly be that loud you crack your own knuckles.
Speaker 0: It's not that everyone's quiet and trying to listen.
Speaker 1: Yeah but like even if you're and it's indoors if you're in a giant quiet room and like you crack a knuckle like in a football stadium Like how loud could it be?
Speaker 1: But when a thousand people all crack their knuckles at the same time It is one of the worst sounds Imaginable.
Speaker 1: Mmm.
Speaker 0: It's not that bad.
Speaker 0: It sounds like Someone being destroyed by horrible magic like what it sounds like a whole bunch of people clapping once.
Speaker 1: Nah, it sounds more like squeaky than that I imagine.
Speaker 1: it said.
Speaker 1: it sounds like what I imagined the sound was when a certain character in the fifth season was killed by.
Speaker 0: Sounds like a whole bunch of people holding little twigs and then sort of everyone breaks their twig.
Speaker 1: No, but it only if the twigs were like Meaty and wet like it has this wet character to it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it recordings of it.
Speaker 1: Don't really do it justice You just have to be in the room physically to see what I mean.
Speaker 1: It's a good time It.
Speaker 1: it always goes the same way.
Speaker 1: they count down Everyone cracks their knuckles and then most of the crowd goes.
Speaker 1: Ah Then we all shiver and then we move on.
Speaker 0: I don't I just are like, alright, I don't know.
Speaker 1: good Do you like that sound?
Speaker 0: it doesn't bother me.
Speaker 1: We should make an album about that sound.
Speaker 1: Okay, so one last little bit of news before we get into the very important main bit.
Speaker 1: Scott found this article like 14 minutes ago and I didn't read it.
Speaker 0: I didn't read it either.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 1: Well, there you go but the article is essentially about The idea of active travel and how pretty much Americans in particular But just people in general who live in modern industrialized societies tend not to travel via their own Capable, like they don't bike or walk anywhere.
Speaker 1: They drive everywhere Mm-hmm, and the article talks basically from what I skimmed about how the average person Vastly overestimates the time and effort actually required to travel in that manner.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know, I mean if you don't use if you'd never use a car, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, then you're gonna be pretty bad at estimating how long it takes to get somewhere with a car.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if you never use a plane You're not gonna be good as so people who don't walk and don't bike Don't know how long it takes to get places with cars and bikes.
Speaker 1: So they literally don't realize with feet and by things like it only takes 15 minutes to walk to that like bodega That's down the street from your neighborhood.
Speaker 1: And it's just sort of interesting because we live in New York Which is almost the opposite problem because you're pretty much everyone walks because there's no other way to get to places.
Speaker 0: So people who can't walk
Speaker 1: yeah Well, yeah, but obviously but I feel like among all the people we know here The real problem is that most people vastly Underestimate how long it takes to walk or take a subway to get somewhere like oh I'll be there in a half hour when it'll guaranteedly take them at least 45 minutes to walk there.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: So, I don't know people need to walk and bike more and we really need to ban cars is the only thing I got to Say about this.
Speaker 0: That was good.
Speaker 1: But anyway things of the day.
Speaker 1: So, uh, I found this YouTube video that was fascinating and it was just this long video showing a machine that Semi automatically knits socks from the main bit.
Speaker 1: So I decided to make this my thing of the day before we decided to do the show on socks.
Speaker 1: The fact that this is about socks is literally 100% a coincidence.
Speaker 1: There is a connection.
Speaker 0: It is only in rims brain.
Speaker 0: this connection.
Speaker 0: He's denying it exists.
Speaker 1: You know how we decide how to do a Thursday show.
Speaker 1: the uh, so Scott and I will be on G chat.
Speaker 1: We're at work on Thursday Usually like Thursday afternoon and one of us will measure the other one show tonight on question mark And then we won't say anything for a while.
Speaker 1: What I tend to do is literally look around wherever I happen to be and If anything I can see gives me an idea for a show.
Speaker 1: Those are the things I suggest Like.
Speaker 0: I'll look around and I'll be like see you looked around at this YouTube video.
Speaker 1: No I looked around and I happen to be wearing green smartwool socks despite the fact that I was wearing black dress shoes because I was out of my Shitty black socks and I actually I wanted to wear my comfortable socks.
Speaker 1: So I wore socks I wouldn't normally wear so I was thinking about my socks all day.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: And then we're like, oh, let's do a show on socks and it totally worked.
Speaker 1: Never talked about socks before somehow.
Speaker 1: But anyway, that video is fascinating But it doesn't explain anything.
Speaker 1: So I have this other video that's my thing of the day and it is someone Explaining how these machines work.
Speaker 1: These machines are things that were used like a hundred years ago as an early form of mass production.
Speaker 1: they were there way way faster than hand knitting and way way slower than the modern machines that make these things.
Speaker 1: but it is really fascinating to see in detail how this kind of Purely mechanical machine run driven and run by humans manipulating physical bits Like.
Speaker 1: the complexity of what it's accomplishing is pretty pretty amazing Mm-hmm, and this video is like seven minutes long and you'll know everything about how this machine works by the end of it.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: So what do you got?
Speaker 0: Oh, what do you have?
Speaker 1: anything sock related, you know?
Speaker 0: So there was a news today that they're gonna sell a Kirby Automaton which is something just makes sense if you don't know what automaton is.
Speaker 0: It's a cheapo musical instrument of the digital variety and at the bottom is a ball with a slit in it.
Speaker 0: The only reason the slit is there is because when you squeeze the ball at the bottom you don't you know It's it's cute that it has the mouth open up and also as the sound comes out of and you can sort of you know More sound will come out of this.
Speaker 0: like it's like you cut a tennis ball and you can make a little face and make it Talk, it's like that right except and then coming out The back is a stick and it looks like a musical note.
Speaker 0: Right because you got a stick with a ball and a little flag at the top and then you can move your finger up and down The stick, you know, there's a little touch sensitive strip to make the.
Speaker 0: you know, the sound go.
Speaker 0: We sort of like a slide whistle, but you know, whatever And there's no like.
Speaker 0: as far as I know there's no frets on it.
Speaker 0: So it's.
Speaker 1: no it's a hundred percent portamento.
Speaker 0: So it's like a violin where you got it.
Speaker 0: You gotta know.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you got to feel it out.
Speaker 1: Well, it's it's portamento in the sense that if you if you naively play it Notes will just slide into each other.
Speaker 1: you could you might say they drift into each other as opposed to.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so they're coming up with a kirby themed on which is obvious.
Speaker 0: It'll be pink and have Kirby's face at the bottom and someone's gonna play.
Speaker 0: As soon as they get one, they're gonna play that song, right drop it like it's hot, but no one has that.
Speaker 0: yet It's I don't think anyone.
Speaker 0: I think you just announced Uh, but because of this, everyone posted all sorts of automatoned videos today.
Speaker 1: Now this ain't new.
Speaker 1: I feel like seven months ago there was like a big automatoned like wave.
Speaker 0: Probably, but the point is that wave has made a second wave.
Speaker 0: Look, you know, the roller coaster, the big hill, and then the second second hill that's still big.
Speaker 0: That's the second big hill.
Speaker 0: So, uh, here is a video of the best automatoned video that I could find.
Speaker 1: This is better than what was hitherto my favorite automatoned video, which was Ave Maria.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 1: This is pretty good.
Speaker 1: I debate, I'm still debating whether or not I should get one because in terms of musical complexity- On the one hand, it is a annoying noise-making device, which is a thing that RIM wants.
Speaker 1: Yo, say, say hello to my harmonicas.
Speaker 0: On the other hand, we must not allow for the sake of all of our sanity and preventing the end of the world and making, you know, God's too angry.
Speaker 0: We must prevent RIM from having any more-.
Speaker 1: Just warning you, what I think is going to happen is I might bring one of these to say MagFest, and I feel like- That's an appropriate place to have one.
Speaker 1: I feel like a lot of other nerds are going to bring the Kirby one specifically to the next MagFest.
Speaker 1: Are you going to go to a jam space with your automaton and- I feel like there's going to be an automaton specific jam space event at the next MagFest.
Speaker 1: This is a prediction.
Speaker 1: I feel like this is going to happen.
Speaker 0: I should make a double automaton.
Speaker 0: Ooh.
Speaker 0: There's still one face at the bottom, but there's daddy two sticks.
Speaker 0: The barrier to entry.
Speaker 1: on playing an automaton, it's like a theremin, but way easier coupled with a kazoo.
Speaker 0: Also way cheaper.
Speaker 0: You can just get one of these.
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 1: Like it costs less to buy one of these than to buy an okay harmonica.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: And you know, musical instruments that are real are actually kind of expensive.
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 1: Now I feel like maybe I'll just start playing my harmonic again because that is sufficiently annoying and I already- It's sufficiently annoying.
Speaker 0: He admits his goal is to produce annoying sounds.
Speaker 1: Well, because playing my trumpet is too much investment like physically, but playing like harmonicas or this kind of thing doesn't really require me to stay in a good physical shape vis-a-vis my lungs and lips and tongue.
Speaker 1: I can kind of just play them whenever I want.
Speaker 1: Like I'll be just as good at them if I don't play them for a month as if I play them every day.
Speaker 1: My skill level won't change.
Speaker 1: In the meantime, the Book Club book remains Emily Wilson's modern translation of Homer's Odyssey.
Speaker 0: The- I'm still reading it on the pooper in the train and you know what?
Speaker 0: The Odyssey, you know, it's an epic.
Speaker 0: It's the Odyssey.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: The word Odyssey.
Speaker 1: Odysseus.
Speaker 0: It makes it seem real big, but you know what?
Speaker 0: It's not so big.
Speaker 0: This book is going by fast.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I told you.
Speaker 1: I mean, it starts with Telemachus being like, oh shit.
Speaker 0: I'm already like book four or five or something.
Speaker 1: Oh shit.
Speaker 1: Where's my dad?
Speaker 1: And Athena being like, yo, I'm going to make you a man and you're going to have a crush on me, but that's not going to matter.
Speaker 1: And then I'm going to help your dad.
Speaker 1: And then we're going to kill a whole bunch of people at the end.
Speaker 0: I'm hanging with King Nestor.
Speaker 1: Oh, the Nestor.
Speaker 1: I didn't remember all the details of King Nestor.
Speaker 1: I love how he never fucking shuts up.
Speaker 1: Like Nestor is, it's not my favorite character, but if there was a, if there was a good movie version of the Odyssey, I feel like he would be the funniest character.
Speaker 0: I think we're next.
Speaker 0: We're going to go check out Menelaus.
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 1: You're going to go to Menelaus and then you're going to cut back to what Odysseus is up to with Calypso.
Speaker 0: And being sad, even though he's banging the god lady.
Speaker 1: I still like the idea that the implication is eventually he's too sad and wants to go home, but he does just go and have sex with her literally every night.
Speaker 0: Why wouldn't you?
Speaker 1: The opening scene is like, he's like, oh, I want to go home.
Speaker 1: And she's like, well, you can't anyway.
Speaker 0: It's about 5 p.m So, uh, I'm like, I'm also like the hottest guy.
Speaker 1: I mean, it's telling when, uh, uh, Mercury comes or Hermes.
Speaker 0: Mercury is his Roman.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: When Hermes comes to tell Calypso, yo, you've got to let Odysseus go.
Speaker 1: Even he is like, wow, she is beautiful.
Speaker 1: Wow.
Speaker 1: This island is a paradise.
Speaker 1: Holy shit.
Speaker 1: I'm impressed.
Speaker 1: And I literally just came here from Olympus.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Why doesn't, uh, Hermes get it on with Calypso?
Speaker 0: I feel like.
Speaker 0: Why does it, why does Calypso want Odysseus?
Speaker 1: I feel like Calypso doesn't particularly like Hermes or Zeus or really any of them.
Speaker 0: Why did you like Odysseus?
Speaker 1: Uh, they get into that the same reason.
Speaker 1: Athena and Zeus like Odysseus, because of all the humans, he's kind of the smartest one, but in quotes, because he's smart, the way they like people to be meaning lying all the time to everyone about everything.
Speaker 0: God's just decided he shall be the protagonist.
Speaker 0: Therefore he is.
Speaker 1: I mean, the book opens with literally Athena's like, yo, you can help Odysseus out.
Speaker 1: And Zeus is like, oh, right.
Speaker 1: Odysseus.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: He's pretty cool.
Speaker 1: I like him.
Speaker 1: But he pissed off Poseidon.
Speaker 1: What do you want me to do?
Speaker 0: Oh, my boy, Poseidon.
Speaker 0: What's up?
Speaker 0: I like how, uh, King Nestor, he'd be sacrificing to Poseidon because he knows.
Speaker 1: Because nobody likes Poseidon.
Speaker 0: I do.
Speaker 1: No, no one does.
Speaker 0: Scott does.
Speaker 1: You, you avoid pissing Poseidon off.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 0: Because he's awesome.
Speaker 0: You should avoid pissing Scott off the same way.
Speaker 1: Poseidon is awesome.
Speaker 0: So don't make annoying noises.
Speaker 1: And everyone will say that he is awesome because you don't want to piss him off.
Speaker 0: Anyway.
Speaker 1: But yes, we will be very soon at the Penny Arcade Expo East in Boston.
Speaker 1: It is four days long.
Speaker 1: We're going to be there on Wednesday and there is official gaming on Wednesday.
Speaker 1: It's five days long.
Speaker 1: So we will be there and it's going to be awesome.
Speaker 1: If you want to find us and play games, we're pretty much going to be in tabletop morning and afternoon every day.
Speaker 1: Except on Sunday morning, we're going to be doing, uh, the final full version of our 40 tabletop games.
Speaker 1: You must play panel at 10 30 AM in the arachnid theater.
Speaker 0: Also, if you're listening to this right now, it's probably too late, but anime Boston that we used to go to, but no longer go to is like tomorrow.
Speaker 1: And I do want to say, or today for most of you, us not going to anime Boston for a few years should not convince you not to go because you're near it and you like anime.
Speaker 0: Go to it is the best anime con on the Eastern Seaboard.
Speaker 1: Like there is these days.
Speaker 1: I haven't been, I mean, I hear things.
Speaker 1: It's hard to say.
Speaker 1: Like it's hard to tell what these definitely past its peak is the thing.
Speaker 0: So it's like, I don't know.
Speaker 1: But having been to much more recent anime Bostons, it's got everything you want out of an anime.
Speaker 0: You want to go to anime con is worth going to.
Speaker 1: the panels are.
Speaker 0: NYC is too new for me to judge.
Speaker 1: But you heard me saying the panels and anime Boston.
Speaker 1: There are good panels there.
Speaker 1: I barely even say that about packs is also a real good.
Speaker 0: Japanese guests there.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Like if you want to see legit guests, good artists alley there.
Speaker 1: And there's great food like right there.
Speaker 1: Like anime Boston has got a lot going on.
Speaker 1: The only reason we are not there is that we go to four between four and six packs as a year and magfest.
Speaker 1: And it's hard to go to more than 10 conventions a year.
Speaker 0: Also, we gotta be doing some, uh, anime judging for the, uh, spring, whatever season is next real soon.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: So what would be on the lookout for?
Speaker 1: our geek nights presents utenna show, which is continuing, uh, the geek nights judges anime by its cover, which is continuing.
Speaker 1: All that stuff is coming.
Speaker 0: There's a new season.
Speaker 0: We got judge.
Speaker 1: And if you want to actually find us and see us at packs east, it's actually really hard to find us in tabletop because east is an enormous convention.
Speaker 1: It's the biggest packs.
Speaker 0: And it's at least it's all one building at west.
Speaker 0: It's like you could be in any building.
Speaker 0: You don't know where someone is.
Speaker 1: Well, you know where we are.
Speaker 1: There's only two buildings with tabletop in them.
Speaker 0: I'm just saying at east, you know, it's, it's one building.
Speaker 1: East we say, Oh, I'm in tabletop.
Speaker 1: That literally doesn't help.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you can find them.
Speaker 1: You can't find us, but coming to our panel is the only guaranteed way to find us.
Speaker 1: Just saying so socks.
Speaker 1: Let's talk about socks.
Speaker 0: You put them on your feet because it's cold.
Speaker 1: So there are two kinds of socks.
Speaker 1: Well, there's three kinds.
Speaker 0: There's four more than three guys for a, then there's five.
Speaker 0: There's many kinds.
Speaker 1: So five socks.
Speaker 1: Five is from RFC 1928, which extends the socks.
Speaker 0: So the first thing I got to say, holy shit socks.
Speaker 1: Five supports IPV six.
Speaker 0: The first thing I got to say, okay, I'm not going to is that if it's warm out and you got sneakers, no socks is maximum comfiness, but the problem your S your feet and your shoes will smell like death forever permanently.
Speaker 0: Yes, that is the old.
Speaker 0: So that is like the worst.
Speaker 1: So there's a second worst there that I have found that if you go barefoot and you do sports, you will get blisters even if you have really comfortable shoes.
Speaker 0: Also, you'll probably get foot fungus.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you're, you're gonna have a lot of trouble.
Speaker 1: Same reason why if you never wear underwear, uh, you're gonna have trouble with the jeans, son.
Speaker 1: Just saying, just saying.
Speaker 0: So, uh, therefore I found that in the summer when it's warm and when I'm wearing sneakers, I have discovered that I prefer the most minimal sock possible.
Speaker 1: I was at work.
Speaker 0: that only covers the bottom of the foot and the back as a little rubbery bit.
Speaker 0: So it stays on at the heel, the no-shows.
Speaker 0: And then when you put your sneaker on, you can't even know that I'm wearing a sock.
Speaker 0: And then it's basically almost as comfy as not wearing any socks.
Speaker 1: So my UX team at work, actually, they were going out to like to have drinks and hang out and celebrate something today.
Speaker 1: And they were like, oh, you should come.
Speaker 1: And I only didn't come because I was coming here to do this.
Speaker 1: I was like, oh no, I get to do the show.
Speaker 1: And they were like, oh, what are you doing the show on?
Speaker 1: And I was like socks.
Speaker 1: The immediate reaction was the conversation we're having immediately.
Speaker 1: They were like, oh yeah, I'm all about the smart wool.
Speaker 1: And someone else is like, no, no, you got to get the no-shows.
Speaker 1: And everyone like took their shoes off and socks happened.
Speaker 1: The no-shows are really popular lately.
Speaker 0: So the ones I found, so I've researched them.
Speaker 1: Why do you care if they show or not?
Speaker 0: It's not about the showing.
Speaker 0: It's about the fact, like I just said, having no sock is maximum comfort.
Speaker 0: So you're getting as close to no sock as possible.
Speaker 1: Ah, the minimal sock.
Speaker 0: That's the same reason I wear toe shoes.
Speaker 0: While also still gaining all the benefits of sock of avoiding the fungus, avoiding the smell, avoiding the, you're basically getting all the benefits of sock with the least amount of socks when it's warm and you don't need the sock to warm your foot and you're wearing a comfy shoe and such and
Speaker 1: such.
Speaker 1: I do point out that there is a very specific use case between like maximum comfort, barefoot, and you're trying to be as close to that as possible is one thing.
Speaker 1: But one thing you don't do is endurance sports, like running.
Speaker 1: When you're running, you actually need the sock for a specific thing where barefoot would be objectively worse, even if you, even if you ignored the fungus in the smell.
Speaker 1: And the problem is it'll get wet and sweaty and lead to blisters.
Speaker 1: And like the wetness will be a problem.
Speaker 1: Good quality socks, even the no-shows provide the wicking effect to keep your foot nice and dry when you're running like 10 miles.
Speaker 1: It also provides a tiny bit of padding to prevent like chafing.
Speaker 1: Like you don't want your toes to chafe because when you're just walking somewhere, you're not like rubbing your toe against the front of your shoe.
Speaker 1: But when you're running, you're rubbing your toe against the shoe because you're hitting the ground hard with every step.
Speaker 1: And your foot has a lot more movement.
Speaker 1: Even if you've tied your shoes, you should be the wrong size.
Speaker 1: If your toe is hitting the, uh, no, even, even if there's buffer in the front, like your foot's going to move a little bit, you might hit the ground hard.
Speaker 1: There's no shoe.
Speaker 0: Anyway, it's perfect.
Speaker 0: So as for the showing part, right?
Speaker 0: It's, you know, depending on the pants you're wearing and the shoe you're wearing, right?
Speaker 0: The amount of showing and the style of showing could be cool and or dorky.
Speaker 1: Well, case in point, I see a lot of people, like a lot of people and it kind of, it kind of bothers me when people have pants that are a little too short and they're wearing socks that show like a crew sock size, but the pain when they sit down, you see bare leg above a tall sock.
Speaker 0: That's me right now.
Speaker 0: That is bad news because I'm sitting down.
Speaker 1: But if you show bare leg because you're wearing no shows, that's, that feels more like that seems more socially acceptable and more like this hipster style.
Speaker 0: That real, I don't like.
Speaker 0: where you're wearing like, you know, like the dress sock with the designs on the side or whatever, like the diamonds and shit.
Speaker 1: With that, the argyle sock, it's all cover.
Speaker 0: It's all colored and shit.
Speaker 0: But when that, when someone's wearing that, I like that, but the, it doesn't go and the length is wrong and it's sort of like, well, that's it.
Speaker 0: Sort of like this awkward hipster, you know, situation.
Speaker 1: If you're wearing the sock that has stuff on it, but the, there's a gap between the top of the sock and the bottom of your pants.
Speaker 1: You fucked up, son.
Speaker 1: But yeah, as long as they're properly sizing most people, their pants are the wrong size and I don't know why this is such a common problem to be honest.
Speaker 1: But in terms, I guess, so I have, I'll go straight in.
Speaker 1: I used to, when I was in like RIT, I would buy big old bags of just Hanes cotton socks, like as many as possible.
Speaker 0: I would buy bags, bags of white socks and then.
Speaker 1: And bags of black socks.
Speaker 0: And when they got, oh, I didn't do that.
Speaker 1: And then when they went bad, I had to dress up a lot for my work.
Speaker 0: When they went bad, I would get rid of them and replace them again.
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 0: And that was all I did.
Speaker 1: But the problem, and the only, the main reason I bought them in bulk was one, I was poor.
Speaker 1: Like that, that's a valid reason.
Speaker 0: Cause I didn't care.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Two, I didn't care.
Speaker 1: And three, I didn't know better.
Speaker 1: Like I didn't know.
Speaker 0: Also even like El cheapo, you know, generic white socks are way comfy when they're new.
Speaker 0: It's like, wow, these are great.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: But as they get old, they get like, they become negative comfort.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 0: They're a little scratchy and stiff.
Speaker 1: But I also didn't really, I didn't know like in high school and even like in the early years of RIT, that there were kinds of socks that were objectively better in structural ways or materials that like, I didn't know.
Speaker 0: I went to the store, there was a bag of white socks and I was like, hell yeah.
Speaker 1: And then next to them, I'd see one pair of socks that cost the same as the whole bag.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: And more importantly, same, I did the same thing with underwear and t-shirts in college.
Speaker 1: My main, one of my main goals in life was to do laundry as few times as possible.
Speaker 1: So buying more socks, man, I could go longer before I had to do a unit of laundry.
Speaker 1: And then I do a little, I'd literally take all my socks and wash them all at once and put them right in the dryer.
Speaker 1: But yeah, those socks suck.
Speaker 1: And now I know better.
Speaker 1: So nowadays I probably, I actually have a bunch of different kinds of socks for different contexts.
Speaker 1: So on one hand I threw away on my old shitty side.
Speaker 0: I just change them with the weather.
Speaker 1: So I do buy black cotton crew socks in bulk still.
Speaker 1: I have a big old bag of like Hanes equivalent, just black socks.
Speaker 1: And the reason for that is black and nondescript socks are what I generally like.
Speaker 1: They're the safest thing to wear at work.
Speaker 1: Just the way I dress at work.
Speaker 1: They don't in any way interfere with anything I would wear at work in any context.
Speaker 1: And I can throw them away as soon as they start to wear out and replace them and never worry about it without wearing out my actually really expensive socks by wearing them every single day.
Speaker 1: So I have these like shitty socks that I wear when it doesn't matter and I buy them in bulk.
Speaker 1: I throw them away when there's even a hint of trouble and just buy them in bulk again.
Speaker 1: But then I have my running socks.
Speaker 1: They're not no shows because actually I have a problem when I run.
Speaker 1: If I wear the completely minimalist socks that you don't even see the top of my foot, like my ankle area, like the bottom of the ankle will interact with the top of my shoe and cause chafing.
Speaker 1: If I run long distances, I need a sock that at least gets above the ankle.
Speaker 1: So I have ankle socks.
Speaker 1: They're all smart wool.
Speaker 1: I buy this one particular smart will sock.
Speaker 1: That is like the perfect long distance running smartwool.
Speaker 0: Smartwool is a brand like TM Smartwool.
Speaker 0: You can get anything.
Speaker 1: You can get any smartwool equivalent, right?
Speaker 0: It's like, but the actual smartwool brand costs a fucking fortune.
Speaker 0: You can buy it.
Speaker 0: Like for example, when it gets cold, I wear like big fancy wool socks, right?
Speaker 0: And I bought them in bulk on Amazon, but they're high quality.
Speaker 0: But the brand is like people socks, but they're the exact same thing as smartwool socks.
Speaker 1: It is the way it makes really good ones too.
Speaker 0: There's tons of them you can get.
Speaker 0: They're all pretty great.
Speaker 0: They're real.
Speaker 0: You know, they're really meant for like wearing big boots and hiking in the woods, but they keep your feet so warm and toasty and they're so nice and comfy.
Speaker 0: If it's cold out, why not wear them?
Speaker 1: So I have smartwool socks that are like crew length that I'll wear.
Speaker 1: Like if I'm not at work, like if I'm hanging out on the weekend, I'll wear those kinds of socks with my comfortable shoes.
Speaker 1: But, or like at a packs, like those are the best things to wear at a pack.
Speaker 0: So you can, you can also just wear them without any shoes if you're in the house or whatever.
Speaker 0: Cause it's almost a slipper.
Speaker 0: Almost.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: It does wear them out faster though.
Speaker 1: You're going to wear out the bottoms.
Speaker 0: You mean you put your slippers on if you got them, but you know, you, you know, they're still comfy.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: You can wear them while you're sleeping to keep your feet warm.
Speaker 1: Then when I'm doing shorter runs or like high speed runs, like I'm running a 5k instead of the smart wool ankle socks, I wear the like super middle.
Speaker 1: They're basically like spandex no-shows.
Speaker 1: They're kind of, they're made out of various materials.
Speaker 1: They're like super sporty.
Speaker 1: Their sole goal is to protect my foot, wick sweat away.
Speaker 1: And I wear those for like short runs.
Speaker 1: And then I have a whole bunch of winter socks that might be smartwool or other brands, but those are like the ones that go all the way up my leg.
Speaker 1: They're like super warm.
Speaker 1: They're super expensive relative to socks.
Speaker 1: I only wear them when I have a good reason to like, I'm going skiing or I'm going to be walking outside in New York a lot on this day.
Speaker 1: That's really cold.
Speaker 1: Or I'm at PAX East because fuck the weather in Boston during PAX East.
Speaker 0: My sock drawer actually right now is full of the previous generation of socks I have to get rid of, which I don't wear.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: It's full of the no-showing socks, right?
Speaker 0: It's full of the wool, the big wintery warm socks.
Speaker 0: I have two pairs of socks that are just for bicycling because they're warm, but they are also thinner.
Speaker 0: I couldn't wear the big thick wool socks in a bicycle shoe.
Speaker 1: If it's summer, I wear those no-show minimalist ones on my bike shoes.
Speaker 1: And if it's cold out, I just wear my smartwools.
Speaker 0: And then I have one dress sock of each color in case there is a dress occasion, which there hardly ever is.
Speaker 1: So because of the nature of the dress, when I wear dress clothes, like formal attire, I tend to do traditional black suits.
Speaker 1: And I tend to have a slightly longer leg cut on my dress pants on purpose.
Speaker 1: So I tend to actually use my shitty black socks because no one can tell.
Speaker 1: Like I don't have, I do not have proper dress socks currently.
Speaker 0: I just have one pair of every, you know, one black, one brown, one blue, one, you know.
Speaker 0: I do not have an occasion.
Speaker 1: I have no formal outfit that would require a non-black dress sock.
Speaker 0: I think my suit is blue and my shoe is brown.
Speaker 0: So they usually use the blue sock, but I can switch it up.
Speaker 1: Well, usually I'm wearing like a jacket.
Speaker 1: Like I'm wearing like more business casual or like pre-formal wear.
Speaker 0: The point is it never hurts to have, right?
Speaker 0: Just one of each just covers any possible scenario.
Speaker 0: You don't, cause you know, what ends up happening is if you don't have that, you know, there's that like, Oh no, I got to go to a thing.
Speaker 0: And you go to the store and I had to buy a sock.
Speaker 0: I never had to do that because I have one of everything.
Speaker 1: It also, I do need a new like set of dress socks because the deal with the dress sock is that unlike say the cheapo black socks I have, the dress sock will still look black.
Speaker 1: Like the color will be good.
Speaker 1: So no one will notice it.
Speaker 1: Someone who pays attention to the fashion will notice if they see your shitty sock, but normal people don't.
Speaker 1: But two, if your dress pants are not perfectly fitted, you need to make sure the dress sock is tall enough to make sure you never show any skin.
Speaker 1: You cannot show skin with formal dress pants.
Speaker 0: The other important thing is that like, you know, you get a tall sock, you got to make sure it's nice and tight against your leg.
Speaker 0: Oh, it can't roll down.
Speaker 0: If it sags or rolls down, you're going to be pulling it up all the time.
Speaker 1: Or you're going to give up and then you're going to maintain that elasticity.
Speaker 0: A sock that gets pushed down a whole bunch or falls down is no good.
Speaker 1: So I have one more kind of sock actually.
Speaker 1: And I did recently, I actually bought a bunch of metal bins and I filled my sock drawer with them to separate all my kinds of socks.
Speaker 1: So I never have to fumble because I got a bunch of different kinds of socks.
Speaker 1: But, uh, so I have toe socks.
Speaker 1: They're all minimalist.
Speaker 0: They're all like, oh, for your toe shoes.
Speaker 1: I got the toe shoe, but actually toe sock real comfortable inside of regular shoe.
Speaker 0: Well, because I mean, yeah, you got something in between your toes, right?
Speaker 0: You know, scratching that bit in between there where the web is.
Speaker 1: Which feels good, which is interesting because full disclosure, when I was a kid, like elementary school, I had two weird hangups.
Speaker 1: If I, if my sock got wet at any point, it has to go.
Speaker 0: Well, okay.
Speaker 0: So I think everyone has this hang up.
Speaker 0: I got, I can't deny if I'm wearing a wet sock.
Speaker 0: That is awful.
Speaker 1: When I was a kid, like if I was getting dressed for school and I stepped in some water in the bathroom in my sock, I took the sock off new sock.
Speaker 0: But some people, you know, obviously I think, I don't know anyone who likes a wet sock.
Speaker 0: I'm sure there's someone, right?
Speaker 0: But most people, I think when their sock is wet or like, oh, this is really uncomfortable and awful.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: But, uh, there are some people like you and other people I've known where if the sock gets wet, it's beyond awful.
Speaker 0: Like they're like, oh my God is the worst thing.
Speaker 1: I was only like that.
Speaker 1: However, in elementary school and nowadays it's more like, uh, my sock is wet.
Speaker 0: For me, I just go and I get rid of it as quickly as possible, but I don't like freaking freak out.
Speaker 1: But I, well, but it's more like if I, like, even if I'm rushing out the door and I step into some water, I don't replace the sock.
Speaker 1: I just, this too shall pass.
Speaker 1: And then I go about my day cause it'll dry soon enough.
Speaker 1: That's the advantage though.
Speaker 0: You can get some, you know, then you get stinkies and funguses if you do that.
Speaker 1: Well, if it gets that wet, then yeah, if I like step in the toilet, of course I'm replacing the sock.
Speaker 1: I like spill an entire glass of water on my foot.
Speaker 1: But if you wear the fancy socks, like the sports socks, it doesn't matter if they get wet, they like dry immediately.
Speaker 0: No, some of them.
Speaker 1: The good ones.
Speaker 1: Like, so one time we went to anime Boston, right?
Speaker 1: And I was wearing my toe shoes and I was wearing some, uh, fancy sport, like wicking socks, like toe socks.
Speaker 1: I forgot to actually pack socks for the trip.
Speaker 1: So for three days in Boston, I only had one pair of socks.
Speaker 1: So every night when we got from, when he came in from the con, I took the socks, I just washed them in the sink.
Speaker 1: Like it went with my hands and a tiny bit of soap.
Speaker 1: And then I just left them out and they were always dry by morning because they were fancy modern wicking socks.
Speaker 1: If those had been cotton socks, I would have been fucked.
Speaker 1: I would have had to go buy socks.
Speaker 1: Cotton socks have a lot of problems.
Speaker 1: Like you were better off having synthetic, uh, Merino wool or a combination of synthetic and Merino wool.
Speaker 0: Here's the thing about cotton, right?
Speaker 0: And it counts not just for socks, but for all clothes.
Speaker 1: There's an entire Seinfeld episode about this.
Speaker 0: Is that cotton clothing is way comfortable and way inexpensive and it can be way nice, right?
Speaker 0: But it's only good for sedentary, dry activities.
Speaker 0: Also good if you're going to get set on fire somehow.
Speaker 1: Real good for like firemen, not pajamas you're going to wear to bed necessarily, but pajamas you walk around the house with.
Speaker 0: But any other activity, right?
Speaker 0: Cotton is not so good.
Speaker 0: If you're doing anything athletic, right?
Speaker 1: If it gets wet, it's not going to dry.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: You'll melt inside of it and it doesn't block the wind.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: It doesn't wick sweat away so much as concentrated in your armpits.
Speaker 0: It's not proof.
Speaker 0: It doesn't protect you from the rain.
Speaker 0: It's like it turns into sandpaper.
Speaker 0: It's basically the worst possible fabric material for actually doing stuff and the best for laying, lazing about.
Speaker 0: Most people laze about all the time and the cotton can work for all their clothes.
Speaker 0: But if you do any activity whatsoever involving the environment or athleticism, then you want zero percent cotton.
Speaker 0: Cotton is the worst.
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 0: And that's pretty much it.
Speaker 1: But yeah, I watched those toe socks.
Speaker 1: They just dried immediately.
Speaker 1: But I have a whole bunch of toe socks.
Speaker 1: There's one real annoying thing about toe socks.
Speaker 1: Left and right matter because they're different.
Speaker 1: So you can't just have a bin of 30 identical socks and just pull two out of it.
Speaker 1: You got to get a left one and a right one.
Speaker 1: And for a while, I tried to separate left and right and two separate bins.
Speaker 0: What if one person has long toes and one person has short toes?
Speaker 1: That usually doesn't matter because actually I have a freakishly long middle toe and it just doesn't matter because they stretch a little bit.
Speaker 1: No one makes shady toe socks really for sports.
Speaker 1: They're all fancy.
Speaker 1: And EG makes them and Smartwool, that kind of stuff.
Speaker 1: So they just work.
Speaker 1: They fit.
Speaker 1: But I tried separating left and right and that was not tenable.
Speaker 1: So what I did instead is every single toe sock I buy is a different color.
Speaker 1: So every pair is absolutely unique.
Speaker 1: So I just have to find the pair as opposed to finding the one with the L on it and then finding the one with the R on it.
Speaker 1: Or even worse, the shitty brands that don't label them.
Speaker 1: So you got to dig through and be like, is this a left?
Speaker 1: Is this a right?
Speaker 1: Whoa betide, you bring four left socks on your trip.
Speaker 1: Granted, actually my fancy ski socks also have a left and right despite the no toes because they're sort of like they're set to fit your foot very particularly.
Speaker 1: But that's sort of a weird edge case.
Speaker 1: That's like specialty sports equipment more so than sock.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I guess I didn't think a lot about socks in high school.
Speaker 1: And I think a lot more about socks now that I'm older.
Speaker 1: And apparently on this Wikipedia page, there are special specific socks just for flip flops.
Speaker 0: No.
Speaker 0: Yeah, no.
Speaker 0: Flip flops if you should never wear them, but if you do, no socks.
Speaker 1: The whole point of a flip flop is that they are the minimum barrier to entry between barefoot and something on your foot.
Speaker 1: If you do anything to increase the complexity of that arrangement, you have already ruined the sole reason to wear flip flops in the first place.
Speaker 1: The whole point of a flip flop is you literally want there to be less than a second between not wearing shoes and technically wearing the barest minimum legal definition of shoes.
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: I think we killed enough time with this.
Speaker 1: Share your sock comments in the forum.
Speaker 1: Like and subscribe.
Speaker 0: No, don't.
Speaker 1: This has been Geek Nights with Rim and Scott.
Speaker 1: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design, and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at frontrowcrew.com for show notes, discussion news, and more.
Speaker 1: Remember, Geek Nights is not one, but four different shows.
Speaker 1: Sci-Tech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays, and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 0: Geek Nights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 0: Geek Nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 0: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.
Speaker 1: And the Patreon patrons for this episode of Geek Nights are Craig Oliver, Alan Joyce, Rebecca Dunn, Heidi McNicholas, Shimmer and Ruby Obelisk hanging in the sky, mystady.com, Jeremy Miner, Link Iggi, Cold Guy, Amanda Duchette, Sean Yeager, Matthew Smith, Nicholas Brando, Mr.
Speaker 1: Strong Strachan, 421 Creations, no, I never ever wondered why we're here, Semper Fi, bitch, Shervin Von Horrell, Rare Laval, James, David White, Rochelle Montanona, Superboy, Rim Says Something Funny Hair, Sailor Vista, Don Schleit, Kajar Dovish, and Joe Shirojo Star, Sam Cordery, Clinton Walton, Wren from New Zealand, Ryan Perrin, Drew Openlander, Finn, Chris Midgiff, Chris Knox, Daniel Redman, Sean Klein, Chris Reimer, and Thomas Hahn.
Speaker 1: See you guys at PAX!
Speaker 1: Bye!