Speaker 0: It's Wednesday August 8th 2018.
Speaker 0: I'm rim.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott and this is geek nights tonight.
Speaker 0: city the manga by Kei Chiarari the nichijou guy.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: So, you know you go to buy some breakfast right like you do.
Speaker 1: sometimes you can get a whole but you know And to save money I want to get breakfast that I can have at home.
Speaker 1: I just wake up and eat not have to stop and get an expensive bacon egg and cheese every day.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so as much as I would think that as much as I like things like yogurt and stuff for breakfast I pretty much want a hot breakfast.
Speaker 0: I'm not gonna make a hot breakfast at home.
Speaker 1: No, so, you know, I got.
Speaker 1: I got some pancake mix.
Speaker 1: I got some.
Speaker 1: sometimes I buy some English muffin.
Speaker 0: Yeah pancake mix that's a weekend breakfast.
Speaker 1: Just make a few pancakes.
Speaker 0: You're not gonna do that before you go to work unless you work from home.
Speaker 1: I do it anyway.
Speaker 1: But you know sometimes even though you know people our age don't do cereal Sometimes I'll go for some cereal.
Speaker 0: So where I work we have like the cafeteria with snacks and stuff But in the morning, there's a gigantic cereal bar With like ten different cereals and a lot of people eat cereal for breakfast with their milk.
Speaker 1: But anyway, so the cereal that I like is Shredded wheat because it's nothing but wheat.
Speaker 0: What are you 90 years old?
Speaker 0: shredded wheat is awful.
Speaker 1: It's great.
Speaker 1: And then there's no bullshit.
Speaker 0: Is it at least the frosted shredded wheat?
Speaker 0: No.
Speaker 0: Why would you eat shredded wheat?
Speaker 1: It's delicious.
Speaker 1: It tastes like nothing.
Speaker 1: Tastes like wheat.
Speaker 0: Tastes like, yeah, nothing.
Speaker 1: You don't like cream of wheat either.
Speaker 0: I think you just don't like wheat.
Speaker 1: Cream of wheat is Disgusting.
Speaker 1: I think rim just doesn't like wheat.
Speaker 0: Wheat is excellent if converted into something like bread.
Speaker 1: It can burn it into a hard biscuit or into a watery mush.
Speaker 0: Yeah, hard biscuit is fine.
Speaker 0: hard shredded wheat not fine.
Speaker 1: that's a biscuit.
Speaker 0: anyway that is not.
Speaker 0: There is a world where someone would call that a biscuit.
Speaker 0: That is not a biscuit to me.
Speaker 1: a biscuit is It says first of all, it says biscuit on the box right because the there's two versions.
Speaker 0: There's the one I could take a poop in a box and write the word biscuit.
Speaker 1: It's the one with the big one and the one with a lot of little ones Right the big one.
Speaker 1: that it says right on the box big biscuit.
Speaker 1: I don't like that one.
Speaker 0: I was about to say if you like that one.
Speaker 0: that's even worse.
Speaker 1: You got to get the ones a lot of small ones and it's the grocery store next to me doesn't have it.
Speaker 1: I got to go far away to get it and I don't want to.
Speaker 1: so I look at all the Cereals in the grocery store next to me to see which one doesn't have any fucking sugar in it.
Speaker 0: right and Granted like for comparison.
Speaker 0: as a kid the cereals I ate were the Nintendo officially branded cereal.
Speaker 1: So just sugar in a bag.
Speaker 0: I didn't like the charms, but I really only ate the marshmallow sugar in a box.
Speaker 0: Okay and frosted flakes.
Speaker 1: so actually I found that the cereal with the most sugar per gram is Honey nut Cheerios, which is one of the series that I would eat.
Speaker 0: Yeah But actually I used to really like sugar crisp.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I like which was renamed what golden crisp?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I like corn pop was a sugar cereal a Most sugar cereals.
Speaker 1: I would not eat.
Speaker 0: I usually eat cinnamon toast crunch was my jam.
Speaker 1: That's what I would eat.
Speaker 1: If those were like.
Speaker 1: it was like the only sugar Cereal maybe but whatever the point is.
Speaker 1: So the sticker.
Speaker 1: I went and I looked at all these healthy looking cereals that looked healthy on the box.
Speaker 0: That's our next Thursday show.
Speaker 1: We've never done a show on some all these healthy looking brands like Kashi and Whatever the fuck right and all these series.
Speaker 1: you look at the box.
Speaker 1: They look super healthy like hey We are you know tons of greens.
Speaker 1: and then you look at the fucking ingredients on the side And it's like sugar a bajillion grams.
Speaker 1: You know that's like.
Speaker 1: it's like this.
Speaker 1: shit's no better than the lucky charms.
Speaker 0: That is like when you try to get like a fruit juice and you look at it And it's actually just concentrated apple juice and flavor right.
Speaker 1: so it's like all these healthy looking cereals are just sugar.
Speaker 1: So I'm like alright fine.
Speaker 1: I'll just get a rice krispie.
Speaker 1: It's rice plus fire, but no even rice krispie has some sugar in it.
Speaker 0: I so there was a time when I would eat rice krispies every morning rice krispie.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like some banana in there.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but but that's the thing I'd only eat.
Speaker 0: rice krispies adorned never unadorned.
Speaker 0: You eat a frosted or a non frosted flake unadorned.
Speaker 0: would you eat a no shredded weed unadorned?
Speaker 1: No, I put a raisin in the shredding.
Speaker 0: just one raisin.
Speaker 1: No just one raisins.
Speaker 1: You don't eat it.
Speaker 1: You don't eat those either.
Speaker 1: I like raisins.
Speaker 1: You don't eat raisins I don't.
Speaker 0: so I take issue with the fact that 99% of the time when I see a cookie that from a distance is chocolate chip, and I find out that it's oatmeal raisin.
Speaker 1: I'm disappointed.
Speaker 0: oatmeal raisin is delicious And I actually like oatmeal cookies without raisins in them more than I like oatmeal raisin cookies.
Speaker 1: anyway I do like raisins.
Speaker 1: I go to buy the rice krispies.
Speaker 1: It's a little box of rice krispies.
Speaker 1: They didn't have a big one, and it was mad expensive, so I'm like what the fuck is this?
Speaker 1: Why is it like $5 this tiny box of rice krispies?
Speaker 1: inflation, so I go over and as I'm walking I realize hey There's those like off-brand cereal in a bag.
Speaker 1: Well you really are like 70 years old, and I'm like hey There's that off-brand cereal in a bag that I would never in my whole life think of possibly buying when I was a kid.
Speaker 0: But actually I bought my term for those because as a young child I noticed them in the grocery store.
Speaker 0: there were two levels of the low-rent cereal.
Speaker 0: there was bottom shelf cereal That usually was in boxes or big bags and had names that evoked the names of real cereal.
Speaker 0: But then there's one step lower.
Speaker 0: there was the giant troughs where you could just scoop it into your own bag.
Speaker 1: Oh, I didn't see that anyway, so yeah I see the off-brand rice krispies in a bag and it's way cheap compared to the real rice krispies.
Speaker 0: All right was it worth it?
Speaker 1: cuz I'm assuming you bought it And you tried it and had less sugar than the real rice krispies.
Speaker 0: It was probably worse.
Speaker 1: It was pretty much just right just and it didn't even have high fructose corn chip.
Speaker 1: The ingredients were literally just like rice You know and crispy increase.
Speaker 1: right?
Speaker 1: I had some sugar, but not near not as much as the actual name-brand rice krispies.
Speaker 1: So I'm like.
Speaker 1: you know what fuck it.
Speaker 1: It's so cheap.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna buy the off-brand rice krispies in a bag And you know what you could not tell it apart from real rice krispies with a blind taste test.
Speaker 1: It is the same fucking thing right?
Speaker 1: why I'm the same factory I have no idea, but well it's different though the ingredients wise, but it tastes a hundred percent identical.
Speaker 1: You could not fucking tell.
Speaker 1: even I was unblind and I couldn't tell.
Speaker 1: there's no way you could tell if you were blind.
Speaker 1: Why did I not buy the off-brand cereal in a bag before?
Speaker 1: Right why did.
Speaker 1: I fall for the marketing of the snap crackle and pop dudes youth naivety and classism right?
Speaker 1: So give up your your whatever pride or whatever you can trust.
Speaker 0: the cereal in a bag however I would argue that far superior to any form of cereal would be the shredded wheat or the cream of wheat would be just like The bagel with a couple of eggs and some bacon.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, that'd be great But that cost four dollars a day whereas a bet the cereal in a bag is like two dollars.
Speaker 1: And as I said last you a whole week what?
Speaker 1: Regardless of how much a week or four dollars a day.
Speaker 0: back when I was pretty poor I was willing to sacrifice most things in my life to have a good hot breakfast or not.
Speaker 1: poor I'll get a four dollars.
Speaker 1: Maybe once or twice a week.
Speaker 1: Maybe once every other week.
Speaker 1: You know I still would rather pay two dollars a week total.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I will say though that lately I pretty much my breakfast is like two bananas.
Speaker 1: well No, you get a banana a crispy and some or sometimes.
Speaker 0: I'll been in one banana one plum.
Speaker 0: like that's good breakfast mmm.
Speaker 0: So yeah in some news since Wednesday anime manga comics.
Speaker 0: What do you got?
Speaker 1: So I don't know.
Speaker 1: if people realize this if you don't read underwear.
Speaker 1: perfect comics right but Fantastic Four has.
Speaker 1: which was Marvel's like.
Speaker 1: the first Marvel Universe comic was Fantastic Four.
Speaker 1: people Don't?
Speaker 1: I don't have many people don't know that or do whatever right like.
Speaker 1: the Marvel Universe didn't even exist until The Human Torch met Namor right at some point.
Speaker 1: that was like when it became a universe.
Speaker 1: before that it was just separate heroes.
Speaker 1: But yet the Fantastic Four it was like the first Marvel comic and it ran super long.
Speaker 1: And then some time ago it disappeared.
Speaker 1: and not only did the comic disappear but all the characters disappeared from pretty much every Marvel thing.
Speaker 1: and the story goes that basically the Crazy, you know nut job owner of Marvel studio video, whatever right you guys got bought by Disney.
Speaker 1: But he's still.
Speaker 1: he's still the owner chief of Marvel who basically doesn't seem to do much.
Speaker 1: He just sort of an owner like the editor-in-chief of Marvel's who really makes the comic book decisions handed down some decree like no more Fantastic Four because They didn't have you know, even they didn't have the movie rights.
Speaker 1: So he felt like they were.
Speaker 1: this is just a story, right?
Speaker 0: He felt like Marvel Comics were giving free advertising to someone else's movies someone else's stuff Which honestly makes sense because the market the core market for actual floppy comic books pretty tiny.
Speaker 0: You're gonna only gonna make real money by selling the movies.
Speaker 1: So they so they did stuff in the story to basically make the Fantastic Four go away So you wouldn't see those characters anymore and such.
Speaker 1: But now they're back because why?
Speaker 1: well Disney which bought owns Marvel as that 21st century deal.
Speaker 1: But that's gonna finish probably next year and then they will own the Fantastic Four again.
Speaker 1: So they got to get the hype up because they're gonna you know, bring it in.
Speaker 1: probably one or two years from now You're gonna see some Fantastic Four Marvel Universe stuff happening.
Speaker 0: Anyway, I don't know it's hard to say if I care or not.
Speaker 1: So the thing with Fantastic Four right is like.
Speaker 1: they're not like my favorite heroes, right?
Speaker 1: You know, it's like but not like the biggest Fantastic Four fan in the universe.
Speaker 0: They are very simple one could say elemental.
Speaker 1: well But the thing is if you read the old comics, they're hella corny.
Speaker 1: Right as underwear.
Speaker 0: perfect comics of all old underwear.
Speaker 0: perfect comics are corny.
Speaker 1: the special thing about Fantastic Four Right with Stan Lee and Jack Kirby is That it is not quite.
Speaker 1: Dr Strange level of psychedelic but still sort of old crazy sci-fi Twilight Zone.
Speaker 1: ish in a way Right.
Speaker 1: It has those vibes going on.
Speaker 1: the other comics don't really have that sort of you know Sci-fi stuff going on.
Speaker 0: Well, like venture brothers has like their superhero stuff in that universe and it's basically the Fantastic Four and it's like that fits with The like super science genre, right?
Speaker 1: So if you read say, you know a Fantastic Four story You're basically like you can as a with a human.
Speaker 1: as a human with a good brain You can sort of extract and separate like this corny presentation.
Speaker 1: I'll hit you you little guy
Speaker 0: From
Speaker 1: this sci-fi story that also comes sort of intertwined and like your brain as you read them sort of splits them apart like a DNA coming apart in two strands Right, so it's very easy and many people have in more recent times You know made Fantastic Four stories that don't have the corny part
Speaker 0: But at the same time like to be fair if I really want like a trippy far-out sci-fi story I'm gonna read like a culture book or something.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you can do you know, whatever It's not that it's not exactly that kind of sci-fi.
Speaker 1: But anyway So Fantastic Four number one, I think comes out today cuz it's Wednesday right available on August 8th for purchase.
Speaker 1: Yeah, okay I was right Wednesday is Comics Day came out today.
Speaker 1: It's written by Dan slott.
Speaker 1: I've seen some rumblings online that like maybe Dan slott is a bad guy But I don't know why because I've only ever seen him being a good guy.
Speaker 1: He I think I mentioned this before that I found out that he wrote the red and stinky comic.
Speaker 1: That was awesome when I was a kid and he also is like any.
Speaker 1: any Dan slott comic I've read has been Sort of that really light-hearted and fun but still really good like the kind of thing that a kid could read and connect with but also an adult can read.
Speaker 1: and You know, it's sort of you know.
Speaker 1: lifts makes the kid feel like he's smart, you know, and it's still.
Speaker 1: you know.
Speaker 1: The kind of that's the kind of feel like you're right.
Speaker 0: matrix made a lot of people feel very smart about baby's first philosophy Right, but you know, he writes, you know, the more like.
Speaker 1: it's fun, but it's not stupid fun It's it's somewhat intelligent, but still like.
Speaker 1: there's something there like like a Saturday morning cartoon that you can appreciate You know like a Dexter's lab kind of level maybe even a little more than that, right?
Speaker 1: That's the kind of stuff he writes.
Speaker 1: and Yeah, so he's writing this new fantastic four.
Speaker 1: So maybe is gonna be good.
Speaker 0: I feel like we're gonna have to review it.
Speaker 0: We can't avoid it, maybe I'm not gonna buy the issue By comic issues, it's 2018.
Speaker 0: Say you don't buy comic issues.
Speaker 1: It's 1998 But yeah, but apparently from what I've heard is that you know since the fantastic were like been missing that in the first issue It doesn't get him back together yet.
Speaker 1: So it's sort of like it's almost a zero issue and not a number one issue.
Speaker 0: I did.
Speaker 0: I Really have a hard time with.
Speaker 0: well, let's start over again like that.
Speaker 1: I think it more explains what happened to them since you haven't seen them in so long.
Speaker 0: Oh, but I don't care about that either.
Speaker 0: I Almost would want a new Fantastic Four to just start in media res with.
Speaker 0: yeah, here's the Fantastic Four and let's just go They're doing something.
Speaker 1: Well, the problem is is like, you know that I think they were like all in different places.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know, yeah do something like more reason spider-man stuff.
Speaker 0: We're just like, you know, who spider-man is.
Speaker 1: We're just gonna have a spider-man story, you know spider-man like, you know Peter Parker's company is like in the Fantastic Four is building or something.
Speaker 1: Yeah Cuz they're not there anymore.
Speaker 0: So in some other news if you didn't know Otacon which is no longer in Baltimore and we no longer perform at is Actually this coming weekend.
Speaker 1: There's supposed to be a Nazi rally down the street.
Speaker 0: Yeah So the news here is one if the Nazi rally is happening and you're going to Otacon You should go counter-protest the Nazi rally and go to Otacon.
Speaker 0: Don't just do one bring.
Speaker 1: make sure your cosplay includes, you know rocks or something to throw at them.
Speaker 0: Yeah, yeah do not cosplay as a Nazi.
Speaker 0: No But that's generally good advice anywhere.
Speaker 0: Not just if there happens to be a Nazi rally nearby.
Speaker 0: It's still weird though like to this like we don't go to at this point in geek nights.
Speaker 1: I've been to Otacon in nine years.
Speaker 1: We don't perform went to two three We went to eight Otacon's.
Speaker 0: until a few years ago We had done more panels at Otacon than at pecs.
Speaker 1: I went to eight Otacon's and there's been a lot since we stopped going.
Speaker 0: there have been nine that we haven't gone to but more importantly we used to Attend and perform at a lot of anime cons and we're actually at a point where we neither attend nor perform At any anime cons.
Speaker 1: not your anime cons.
Speaker 0: Yeah, at least currently there are no anime centric conventions that we attend or perform at in any capacity.
Speaker 0: Anime, Boston is still fantastic.
Speaker 0: Like it's a great convention.
Speaker 0: It's the best anime con I can think of but One it's in a cold part of the year.
Speaker 0: and to the security in Boston means that I basically don't want to ever go to Any convention in Boston?
Speaker 0: I'm even annoyed at going to PAX East because of that security.
Speaker 0: but Even though we haven't been to Otacon in a long goddamn time.
Speaker 0: I don't want to go to Otacon.
Speaker 0: I definitely don't want to perform at Otacon.
Speaker 0: I Still get weirdly nostalgic when I think about Otacon because we went to a lot of Otacon's and spent a lot of time there.
Speaker 0: So yeah, it's this weekend And I guess if you're going I'm curious how it goes Because since they moved it seems like a lot of the but like almost no one I know goes anymore Either to perform or just to attend.
Speaker 0: so I like don't know what the state of Otacon is.
Speaker 0: mmm If you want to go to an anime con that we might go to though Anime NYC is coming up in November.
Speaker 0: It does not overlap with PAX meaning we can actually go to it.
Speaker 0: There's a good chance.
Speaker 0: We're gonna actually perform at it and do some panels.
Speaker 0: We're still working that out.
Speaker 1: Just take the subway over.
Speaker 1: Yeah walk around look around do a panel go home.
Speaker 0: Yep, the subway that goes to anime NYC also goes directly to my apartment.
Speaker 0: Yep, like it's real hard to not go to this.
Speaker 0: I'm not gonna go to that anime Expo sponsored other anime event.
Speaker 0: No, that's gonna be in New York.
Speaker 0: Yeah, because one I can't take the subway to it and two I don't think it's gonna be good.
Speaker 0: But if you want to do a panel at this anime convention anime NYC You should submit them because the panel deadline is like next week.
Speaker 0: It's coming up real quick.
Speaker 0: They're actually doing it way in advance because it's all smart people around on the con.
Speaker 0: But anyway things of the day what do you got?
Speaker 1: So, you know, I'm sure rim is familiar I don't know how many listeners are familiar with the Yoshida brothers who are a a group of people who play The.
Speaker 1: I believe they're brothers.
Speaker 1: They play traditional Japanese instruments.
Speaker 0: I'm a big fan of the Yoshida brothers.
Speaker 1: Typically shamisen I think right and they play, you know, they don't play typical japanese music on those shamisen.
Speaker 1: They play fucking awesome music.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so if you just go on youtube type yoshida brothers, you'll find good stuff.
Speaker 1: here is something I came across.
Speaker 1: It is a group of people with traditional japanese instruments Uh, and they are playing the theme song to sailor moon.
Speaker 0: This is real good, which is pretty good.
Speaker 1: So, uh, I think this channel I think has other stuff too.
Speaker 0: Well, both the stagecraft is good and the music is good.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like it's like a filming of a live performance.
Speaker 1: So This is worth a listen.
Speaker 0: So I had a different thing in the day, but since scott had traditional japanese instruments I have one I found a long time ago.
Speaker 0: I think I used it as a stinger at some point.
Speaker 0: But this is a traditional japanese band using mostly traditional japanese instruments covering a song you all know and love Africa by toto Which has been continuously stuck in my head for almost eight months now.
Speaker 1: It hasn't been eight months since we talked about this.
Speaker 0: oh we got stuck into my head well before we started talking about it.
Speaker 1: so at least Nobody once told you So he's gone.
Speaker 0: he blessed the rains down in africa.
Speaker 1: It has ousted a different song.
Speaker 0: So i'm gonna warn you guys though like fair warning.
Speaker 0: because remember a while ago.
Speaker 0: I was like I should make an anime music video and then like I just did and I made it.
Speaker 0: So I have that same feeling in my brain and I took that same first step.
Speaker 0: I took all-star And I took africa.
Speaker 1: I don't know if those mixed well together.
Speaker 0: They so you wouldn't think they would.
Speaker 1: You tried.
Speaker 1: you're trying to do a neil scissor ego job.
Speaker 0: So I pull I I threw together like I hacked it together just to see like is there a way to make it work?
Speaker 0: and it worked About as well as when I was like I should just take this pony song and take Takes utenna and just like mash them together.
Speaker 0: and I just like threw the timeline together and just listened to it.
Speaker 0: It kind of worked.
Speaker 0: I might try to make the cesarengian style Africa all-star.
Speaker 1: How do they give the skills to do that?
Speaker 0: Uh, it'll be quite low bar here.
Speaker 0: Quite low bar.
Speaker 0: You don't have a lot of experience making mashups, but I do have a lot of experience arranging.
Speaker 1: I think if you made a hundred of them, then you would certainly make good ones.
Speaker 0: Yeah But you know I'd never made an amv before and I had none of those skills and I met a pretty fucking good amv.
Speaker 1: in my opinion It's a little more, uh obvious to you know, I don't think it takes a hundred.
Speaker 1: I think it only takes like 10 to make a good amv, but I only made one.
Speaker 0: Well, I just made one.
Speaker 0: it only took like two days.
Speaker 0: But uh, we'll see i'm working on this a little bit But it's past.
Speaker 0: the point of this won't work and it's at the point of it's stuck kind of like a rabbit.
Speaker 0: So if you the thing about pet rabbits is that sometimes they'll get an idea in their head Like how do you know?
Speaker 1: So how do you know what the rabbit's thinking?
Speaker 0: So here's here's an example.
Speaker 0: So say there's an area the rabbits can't get to and should not get to.
Speaker 0: usually it's not a problem.
Speaker 0: They can't get there.
Speaker 0: They don't express any interest in getting there.
Speaker 0: It's not a problem.
Speaker 0: But occasionally the rabbit will appear to be like investigating the area that they're not supposed to get into Or actively attempting to get into the area.
Speaker 0: So of course you fortify the area from that point forward.
Speaker 0: For the rest of time the rabbit will always be trying to get into that area and you see them attempting it Once they decide they want to do something the more you try to stop them the more they will try to do it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's what children do.
Speaker 0: That's what I do when it comes to Mashing up.
Speaker 1: What is this?
Speaker 1: No trespassing sign.
Speaker 1: I want to go in there.
Speaker 0: real bad No swimming.
Speaker 0: fuck you you can't.
Speaker 0: you're not my boss.
Speaker 0: Fuck you dad.
Speaker 1: I do what I want.
Speaker 1: Maybe they maybe you only see this in rabbits because they're learning from you.
Speaker 1: They got your your dna's.
Speaker 1: Other rabbits don't do this.
Speaker 1: Well, the only rabbit says they learn.
Speaker 0: they learn from a professional.
Speaker 0: In the meta moment the book club book is no longer the odyssey.
Speaker 1: No, it is now the odyssey Regular odyssey space odyssey.
Speaker 1: you got to find a third odyssey.
Speaker 0: Yep, uh, actually If I use that uh planescape book What I keep talking about it is odyssey adjacent the pages of pain pages of pain.
Speaker 1: it is pages of pleasure instead.
Speaker 0: Uh pages of pleasure is basically all the culture books.
Speaker 0: The party and player of games.
Speaker 0: in the beginning before he goes off the guy gets so drunk He falls off the cliff and it's totally fine.
Speaker 1: Let's watch the mel triple.
Speaker 0: Everyone's walking around with their narcotics bowls Full of web.
Speaker 1: I see.
Speaker 0: I had to explain.
Speaker 0: I said full web to someone at work yesterday.
Speaker 0: Oh, they didn't know what it was.
Speaker 0: Of course not Of course not.
Speaker 0: I had to explain it, but you know what?
Speaker 0: Full web as a concept.
Speaker 0: that is the most succinct way to express that con like that Moderately complex concept in a succinct form, right?
Speaker 1: Well, well, I think there's two.
Speaker 1: those are two terms from uh, science fiction novels, right?
Speaker 1: There's grok.
Speaker 1: Yeah, which is sort of like you have a full web of Understanding is what.
Speaker 1: so grok means you a full web of understanding.
Speaker 1: Yeah and full web means you have accomplished a complete, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, sort of they're related in that way and they both sort of uh Communicate fullness.
Speaker 1: Yep, right of of you know I don't know.
Speaker 1: That's why that's why we need words like grok and full web because there's no other word.
Speaker 0: Yep Well, it works.
Speaker 0: i'm taking over like i'm taking over an area for someone else.
Speaker 0: So I have to like do this knowledge transfer and like learn all their biz so I can deal with their biz.
Speaker 0: And one of the engineers was like so does this all make sense?
Speaker 0: And I said I understand it, but I do not yet grok.
Speaker 0: and he said all right like he He fully grokked what I said to him grok the grok.
Speaker 1: Yeah, perfectly chromulant word But anyway 2001 a space odyssey.
Speaker 1: I went to see the movie in 70 millimeter.
Speaker 1: It was still great.
Speaker 1: I hadn't seen it in a long time.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna read the book like imminently.
Speaker 1: I started Like two chapters of the book.
Speaker 1: it doesn't seem that long.
Speaker 1: actually.
Speaker 0: I was planning to read it Uh, possibly to fullness at the beach, but I feel like we're not going to the beach.
Speaker 1: this looks like it's gonna rain now.
Speaker 1: Maybe the weather will change and we will go to the beach.
Speaker 0: We'll see.
Speaker 1: The point is uh, I didn't realize this but the I thought it was a book was written and then a movie was made.
Speaker 1: But actually the book and screenplay were written simultaneously by simultaneously Right, uh, what's author's name again?
Speaker 1: Arthur Arthur C. Clark and Stanley Kubrick worked on this at the same time.
Speaker 1: That was news to me and that's kind of really interesting But that's still different from the movie and still worth reading.
Speaker 1: Uh separate even if you see.
Speaker 0: the important point is we have a book club and you should read these books.
Speaker 0: I think every book we've read and done a show on is worth reading.
Speaker 1: actually at least one person Who had already read the book said they were going to read it again.
Speaker 1: Wow Uh, okay, but yeah That's a person who already reads books.
Speaker 1: we need people who don't read books.
Speaker 1: This is a all-time classic book.
Speaker 1: I feel like you should read it if you're a nerd of any kind.
Speaker 0: I was just scrolling through.
Speaker 0: I think there's.
Speaker 1: I haven't read it and i'm fixing that you should fix it, too.
Speaker 0: I am confident there is in fact only one book we have ever done on the geek nights book club that you should not bother reading world war z. That book's real fucking dumb.
Speaker 1: I'm pretty sure we did name of the wind also.
Speaker 0: Uh I don't.
Speaker 0: I think that's almost worth reading.
Speaker 0: It's worth reading name of the wind's.
Speaker 0: Okay Remember most of our complaints about name of the wind were based on knowledge from the second book Not based on that book.
Speaker 0: that book in and of itself.
Speaker 0: wasn't that bad?
Speaker 0: It wasn't.
Speaker 0: it was worth reading.
Speaker 0: I think world war z is literally the worst book we've ever talked about.
Speaker 0: It's not good like by a mile not good.
Speaker 1: Anyway, uh, yeah and pax west is uh labor day weekend.
Speaker 1: We're gonna be there.
Speaker 1: Our panel is monday at the crack of dawn.
Speaker 1: It's gonna actually be streamed even though it's in such a shitty time.
Speaker 1: That's a trade-off.
Speaker 1: Whatever i'm going to pax.
Speaker 1: I don't care.
Speaker 0: Yep, otherwise, we'll just be at pax doing paxing.
Speaker 1: Duh.
Speaker 0: Uh Yeah, if you see us around we're gonna try to do our expo hall thing Like the video thing that we used to do and then we stopped.
Speaker 0: I think we'll have time to do it at this pax west.
Speaker 1: I got I got some ideas.
Speaker 0: I got some ideas too.
Speaker 0: We should plan this.
Speaker 0: i'll have the new camera by then too.
Speaker 1: Are you you definitely here?
Speaker 1: Yeah, so it's about how to bring any.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna bring a real camcorder to get this.
Speaker 1: I don't have to bring any video cameras.
Speaker 1: I can bring way less stuff.
Speaker 0: Uh, we'll see.
Speaker 0: So what's your debate?
Speaker 0: because if you bring your camera the only value of that other than you taking photos But you could bring a smaller camera for that.
Speaker 0: indeed Is that we would have two 4k high quality actually color correct camera angles for our panel.
Speaker 0: We've never had that.
Speaker 0: we always have your good camera and my like 15 year old camcorder.
Speaker 1: Uh, we'll see We'll see.
Speaker 0: we'll play it by ear but for at least for the purposes of doing Non-panel content.
Speaker 0: I will have a real camcorder Which will just make that way easier to pull off So city.
Speaker 0: so, uh keiichi arawi Is the person who wrote the manga nichijou that you probably know from the anime nichijou.
Speaker 1: I've never read that manga nichijou, but i've watched like a handful of episodes of the anime.
Speaker 0: I've watched a lot of the anime.
Speaker 1: It is one of my favorite Non like non-narrative anime and it was all right, but it was sort of it was a little bit more disjointed and wacky Uh than say as among a dial which is similar in feel and genre.
Speaker 0: It's one step more zany than as a manga dial
Speaker 1: But it also has didn't feel compelled to keep watching it even though watching it wasn't so bad
Speaker 0: I did but not in the sense of like watch every episode in order but more in the sense of I want to see something funny.
Speaker 0: I'd pick literally a random episode and just watch it.
Speaker 1: but anyway Uh, so I saw in the comic order form city volume one and it's like from the creator of nichijou a new manga volume one.
Speaker 1: Buy it now and i'm like, all right.
Speaker 1: I'll try that out.
Speaker 1: See what the deal.
Speaker 1: right, you know, not an anime manga, right?
Speaker 1: We'll see what the deal is.
Speaker 1: So I got city volume one and I also got city volume two, but rim only read volume one.
Speaker 1: I read both but I remember two way better than one because I read one a long time ago.
Speaker 0: Yep, so the short the tldr version is.
Speaker 0: I really like it.
Speaker 0: i'm gonna read all of it, right.
Speaker 1: so it's weird.
Speaker 1: So the best way I can describe it is it's like a it's like a super cliche like you've seen all this before But it's crooked slightly.
Speaker 1: So and it's also current right?
Speaker 1: It's like even though I feel like i've read These exact stories before.
Speaker 1: i've seen all this these characters before and everything.
Speaker 1: I haven't exact not exactly anyway.
Speaker 1: Oh other characters slightly different.
Speaker 1: But what other manga anime coming out now?
Speaker 1: Is this kind of thing?
Speaker 1: It's like in the past.
Speaker 1: there were I feel like i've.
Speaker 1: I feel like even though I had a hard time naming them right these kinds of stories.
Speaker 1: But what were they?
Speaker 0: I think it's this.
Speaker 1: and what coming out now?
Speaker 1: is that kind of story?
Speaker 0: I guess like the genre it's It's slice of life Crossed with like a little more zaniness than the real world, but not much more.
Speaker 0: Yeah, because honestly like the level of things that happen in this comic Are about on par with the level of like things that I encounter living in new york city on a like weekly basis.
Speaker 1: Yeah, all right.
Speaker 1: So the deal is right.
Speaker 1: and his israel see the cliches, right?
Speaker 1: There is a very poor.
Speaker 0: She's my favorite character.
Speaker 0: What nagamo?
Speaker 1: Yeah, I guess.
Speaker 1: so it's hard to say there's a main character.
Speaker 1: It's called nagamo.
Speaker 1: It's called city because it's really about all these characters.
Speaker 0: I think the main character is the creepy guy spying on everyone.
Speaker 1: Anyway, it's it's about all these different characters living in a city.
Speaker 1: So it's sort of simpsons-esque or they'll be like chapters that are about a character who's not the main one.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but you start off focusing on this one character and that sort of is really the.
Speaker 1: she's the driver for that first volume And it seems to get more focused than the others Uh, thus making her the main one, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, even though it's not she's not.
Speaker 1: as it goes on she doesn't really get that much more focused, you know percentage wise anyway, um But yeah, so she is poor she can't afford to pay the rent and she's kind of like neutral evil.
Speaker 1: Yeah, she's got to do some shenanigans to get rent money.
Speaker 1: Uh, you know escapes her apartment and stuff when you know landlords all upset.
Speaker 1: Right, you know, it's like you feel like you've seen that before right somewhere, right?
Speaker 1: Uh, and then there's all these other wacky characters around.
Speaker 1: there's the girl who keeps taking photos of stuff.
Speaker 1: There's there's the cop the cop who always stands at the booth.
Speaker 0: There's the old lady who apparently knows hokuto shinken, right?
Speaker 1: There's a restaurant where somehow she ends up with a job at the restaurant has like the dad who's the cook and the son I like how she didn't want to work there.
Speaker 0: They didn't want to hire her and yet she ended up working there.
Speaker 1: Yep Yep, you know, it's like oh, you know stuff like that, right?
Speaker 1: uh, and then it's like on the one hand is like this thin line of like things developing like it actually Even though like nijijou there is a narrative emerging slowly through this slice of life, right?
Speaker 1: Even though each chapter is like completely episodic comedy situations that come Like there's a chapter in volume two.
Speaker 1: That's about uh, the the kid who works at the restaurant getting trapped in the mascot costume.
Speaker 1: Yeah, yeah, that's like a whole chapter right even though this every chapter is like that.
Speaker 1: there is sort of this thread of very slow progression where like The character the connections between the characters are increasing and they know each other more because at the beginning They like don't know any even though they live in the same city.
Speaker 0: They have no Visible connection to yeah, the one guy's like wait, isn't that the restaurant that girl works at right?
Speaker 1: It's like they start discovering each other and learning about past connections to each other and developing current connections to each other and learning Each other's names.
Speaker 1: and you know creating a group And coming closer to each other sort of like that scene in snatch where all the cars crash into each other, right?
Speaker 1: Uh, it's through.
Speaker 1: you can see that slowly happening and you can also see people like getting their shit together slowly, right?
Speaker 1: She's slowly Getting money and getting her shit together and they sort of hint at like, ah This is her.
Speaker 1: she actually has a talent and when you know the photo girl, you know gains a fan.
Speaker 0: The see The one nagamo like busts into her apartment and she's just like taking pictures of broccoli that she's arranged on the floor.
Speaker 0: Yeah Pretty much if I I mean if I had to describe like the important point about this market because it's great I like.
Speaker 0: I think it's really funny and I like it.
Speaker 0: it has impeccable comedic timing The way like even in terms of like what will be on the next page?
Speaker 0: Like.
Speaker 0: it's so well crafted.
Speaker 0: I laughed out loud Easily a dozen times reading volume one and I think the part like the best.
Speaker 0: the most illustrative story in volume one about this is When the dude at the restaurant the chef Spills the dish he was going to serve to this client.
Speaker 1: That's a very seinfeld-esque chap.
Speaker 0: It is he spills this new these noodles, right?
Speaker 1: He's going to.
Speaker 1: he's going to I think what.
Speaker 1: he's going to give someone noodles to serve them and the guy's like drinking some wine.
Speaker 0: So he doesn't like.
Speaker 0: he's not noted.
Speaker 0: He doesn't notice.
Speaker 0: He spills the noodles into the guy's open bag on the ground and the guy doesn't notice.
Speaker 0: yeah, and the whole question is What does he do in this situation?
Speaker 0: And it is so utterly funny Like I can't even spoil it.
Speaker 0: the last page of that arc Is a comedic triumph.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's a good one But I don't know.
Speaker 0: This is for everyone.
Speaker 0: Like I think I can't think of the person who wouldn't enjoy this comment Person.
Speaker 0: Even then it's just looking at the pictures.
Speaker 1: It's funny be cold-hearted evil person.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, I guess if someone's evil They would not enjoy this.
Speaker 0: Yeah, even then they might still think it's funny.
Speaker 0: Sometimes I mean some evil people also read books and enjoy them.
Speaker 0: So it's possible.
Speaker 0: I guess so But like I really I literally recommend this manga to anyone who's a fan of nijijo to anyone who's a fan of autism as a manga Daio To anyone who listens to geek nights Like I. I I think this is great and I think you should check it out.
Speaker 1: So the the thing is the art is very Simple, right?
Speaker 1: It's like it's sort of like folk up for come for panel.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the characters are all Instantly recognizable.
Speaker 0: I'm never confused as to who someone is.
Speaker 1: Yeah I mean, it's sort of like the art is like is if you ever read the asa manga dial manga Which was a four panel a four coma they call it, right?
Speaker 1: Uh, it's better than that, but it's like you look at say yotsuba yotsuba is like elaborate compared to City, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, so if you're looking for like fancy artworks, this is not it.
Speaker 1: I think the important part is also if you're looking for length This is not it either.
Speaker 1: like this reads in like two seconds.
Speaker 1: Like yeah, you buy this thing for what does it cost?
Speaker 0: I have no idea what things cost.
Speaker 1: Uh, it was.
Speaker 1: it's not expensive but it's like, you know.
Speaker 1: Uh see what it is to get it from the south american.
Speaker 0: Yep, but it's low investment Like it's easy to pick up and put down.
Speaker 0: it's episodic enough to where it doesn't really matter like how quickly you read it.
Speaker 0: You're not gonna get sucked into some long crazy narrative.
Speaker 1: All right, so it's like it's like 12 13 dollars a volume, right?
Speaker 1: Uh, you're gonna blow through that in like 15 minutes.
Speaker 1: But also it's like a dollar a minute.
Speaker 1: entertainment.
Speaker 0: the dialogue like the way the car like especially nagamo and the girl she's kind of mooching off of Their dialogue is actually pretty like realistic to how friends would interact.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's not you know, it's it.
Speaker 1: they don't talk in any kind of weird way.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but it's it's all.
Speaker 0: everything's very natural.
Speaker 1: you're reading a translation also But I guess you know the translation totally.
Speaker 1: I you forget that it's japanese except you're reading right to left.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they're in a very japanese city.
Speaker 0: So i'm gonna read the rest of this.
Speaker 0: if scott keeps buying it I'll just keep borrowing it from him.
Speaker 0: And if he stops buying it, I might just buy the rest of it.
Speaker 1: No, you're gonna spend your 13 dollars.
Speaker 0: I'll just buy it on kindle.
Speaker 0: Oh Is it on kindle, uh, let's see i'm on the amazon page.
Speaker 0: it is kindle and comixology eight bucks.
Speaker 0: Paperback 11 30.
Speaker 1: Oh, it's actually much cheaper to not buy the paper version.
Speaker 1: Maybe i'll buy the not paper version from now on.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it seems like it's eight bucks a volume.
Speaker 0: That's not bad.
Speaker 0: comixology and kindle.
Speaker 0: That's fine.
Speaker 0: the art This is.
Speaker 0: you don't need this to be like full color retina display to appreciate the art.
Speaker 1: Yeah, no, it's not good, but it's I don't need.
Speaker 1: there were no color pages, right?
Speaker 1: I think none.
Speaker 0: Uh, there's a handful.
Speaker 1: the cover the cover wasn't.
Speaker 0: there's the insert and there's a couple of little colors.
Speaker 1: I mean if I read on my ipad, i'll see color anyway.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so what do I care?
Speaker 0: There's the bit in the beginning about the bird the irrelevant bird.
Speaker 0: Yep, and even though the bird is irrelevant I keep seeing the bird on things.
Speaker 0: Also, the one unexplained mystery i'm kind of invested in is in the police station.
Speaker 0: You keep seeing in the background There's a picture of this like cobra looking snake and it's just like have you seen me?
Speaker 0: I expect at some point that is chekhov's cobra and we're gonna see that you're really noticing all the details.
Speaker 0: Yep But the bird appeared a couple of times in the background too.
Speaker 1: Well, I think that's what it is is like, you know, like I said before there's these connections building, right?
Speaker 1: So and it's you have all these individual episodes.
Speaker 1: yet during those individual episodes.
Speaker 1: There's small things Happening being said characters seeing each other, you know I think there are some chapters where like you see even though it's this you read one chapter And then you read.
Speaker 1: the next chapter has nothing to do with the one previous But you can see that aha these character was there right near the character.
Speaker 1: the other character Yeah was doing something at the same time.
Speaker 1: It's like aha.
Speaker 1: they were in the same place in this small little city Right, and even though they didn't see each other or talk to each other But they show you that they were near each other at that exact moment in time these two events took place You know on the same exact street, right and that somehow, you know Maybe they bumped into each other if it didn't say anything or one person caused a thing that You know.
Speaker 1: was it, you know, you see if like someone trips and falls But then in the second in the next chapter they show you ah that actually happened because of this Yep, and you didn't know it uses the fact that you see everything like.
Speaker 0: there's all this stuff around These statues and like one girl steals one to try to sell it.
Speaker 0: But then it's like when she tries to sell it it's worth way too much money.
Speaker 0: So she feels bad about stealing it.
Speaker 0: She puts it back, but then she breaks it.
Speaker 0: someone else talks later about her like, oh, yeah I've just been throwing those things away because like our friend my mom keeps sending them to us and I don't really care like There's a lot of jokes that are based on the fact that you know the true story of the thing that all these other people are interacting with.
Speaker 0: So yeah, you should pick this up and read it.
Speaker 0: and if someone in the stream asked this is not at all similar to dr Slump, no, dr.
Speaker 0: Slump is much more simplistic.
Speaker 0: humor Does not rely very much on timing and frankly i've read a lot of dr.
Speaker 0: Slump because I own it all.
Speaker 0: Not actually that good.
Speaker 1: Well, dr.
Speaker 1: Slump is made by the dragon ball guy.
Speaker 0: Yeah, toriyama it it's enjoyable, but it's not like.
Speaker 0: I like gin tama too.
Speaker 0: I think in tom is really funny.
Speaker 0: This is Both very different from gin tama and objectively superior to gin tama in terms of its comedy.
Speaker 0: I'd say the same thing.
Speaker 0: This is objectively comedically superior to dr Slump.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think the thing I like about city the most is that it's sort of less Uh zany and ridiculous, right?
Speaker 1: Even even if you look, you know, it's not completely unzany But like, you know nichijou is famous for like the goat wrestling.
Speaker 1: Yep gift or whatever.
Speaker 1: Even I was among a guy.
Speaker 1: I was like chio chan's dad where it's like what the fuck?
Speaker 0: Well, that's just asaka dreaming right?
Speaker 1: But I mean the point is is that there's none of that in the city.
Speaker 1: It's much more down to earth.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know, it's not a hundred percent realistic, but there's no.
Speaker 1: like Super things like.
Speaker 0: the zaniness is literally like I said.
Speaker 0: It is the level of zaniness that I actually for real encounter on a regular basis living in new york city.
Speaker 0: So check this out.
Speaker 0: It's totally worth reading.
Speaker 0: This has been geek nights with rim and scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to dj pretzel for the opening music cat lee for web design and brand ok for the logos.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at front row crew.com for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 0: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech mondays gaming tuesdays anime comic wednesdays and indiscriminate thursdays.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a creative commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 1: But unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 0: It's actually recorded at night And the patreon patreons for this episode of geek nights are in an order that I don't know if it changed again.
Speaker 0: Craig oliver ellen joyce rebecca dunn hiding mingle shimmering rubi obelisk hanging in the sky jar tavish in my city.com jeremy miner linky g j band scooter lonely roberto kingsley kelly snyder Amanda douchette sean yager matthew smith nicholas brando.
Speaker 0: Mr.
Speaker 0: Strong distraction for doing creations.
Speaker 0: chris rimer and thomas han sherman von horrell rory james david white rachel montanona superboy tripwire sailor vista don schlage Joe show joe star clinton walton redford new zealand ryan paren drew openlander finn chris midkiff daniel redman sean klein chris rimer and thomas han.