Speaker 0: It's Thursday, June 7th 2018.
Speaker 0: I'm rim.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott and this is geek nights tonight.
Speaker 0: Indian food cuz.
Speaker 0: we really are out of Thursday.
Speaker 0: show ideas.
Speaker 1: This is my microphone working complaining.
Speaker 0: Your microphone is working.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: So at work, I got this new job in a new neighborhood.
Speaker 1: It's actually old neighborhood is the same neighborhood.
Speaker 1: my previous job, you know, it's crazy ten years ago was in.
Speaker 0: I'm in the exact same boat.
Speaker 0: I recently got a new job and I'm in the neighborhood where my job from ten years ago was anyway, so The problem is is food situation down there.
Speaker 1: There's plenty of places to get food But a lot of them are very expensive.
Speaker 1: There are some cheap ones.
Speaker 0: Oh cry me a river.
Speaker 0: I'm in Midtown next to Grand Central All right, but it's either pret or a twelve dollar sand.
Speaker 1: But the thing is even at least in Midtown I could go to the everything deli and there were some everything delis there that were good.
Speaker 1: down in Soho There's like one everything deli and it's gross.
Speaker 1: Yeah And basically all the good food is fancy.
Speaker 1: There's a. there's some food that is cheap and not fancy.
Speaker 1: go to Chinatown or I can go to like the bond me place.
Speaker 1: That's about it though.
Speaker 1: So it's like if you eat the cheap food, you're gonna be eating the same food every day Which is no good.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so I try to find a different solution.
Speaker 1: My previous solution used to be to bring bread peanut butter and jelly to work and make sandwiches and you know Keep it cheap, but I really don't want to eat peanut butter and jelly every day Anymore like I used to.
Speaker 0: well, I made it.
Speaker 0: I made a conscious decision In fact, we thought about doing this show on lunch.
Speaker 0: We looked up and sure enough we did a show on lunch and I said something in that show and I'll say it again now Is this relevant?
Speaker 0: I made the decision a long time ago even when I didn't have a lot of money that I was willing to pay What it cost to have a good hot lunch every goddamn day that I do not have to make myself And I consider that a cost of.
Speaker 1: it's weird how near Times Square there were.
Speaker 1: I could save like it was multiple dollars per day Cheaper than where I am now.
Speaker 1: But anyway.
Speaker 1: So for once, you know, I made a some dinner I cook some dinner and I actually brought the leftovers to work.
Speaker 1: and I was like I finally brought the leftovers to work.
Speaker 1: Go me I did it and I'm gonna pay zero dollars effectively for lunch today.
Speaker 0: My co-workers are all on a kick with that lately.
Speaker 0: Everyone's like who did you bring today?
Speaker 0: or did you bail?
Speaker 1: That's what everyone and my you know, a lot of people in my work They bring.
Speaker 1: the fridge is like totally full But it's like I have to actually cook and remember to do it that one person brings.
Speaker 0: everyone else gets impressed Like whoa, you actually did it.
Speaker 0: No, I should do it too.
Speaker 1: Almost everyone does it.
Speaker 1: But the thing is I go out and like sit down at a restaurant the day that I brought in my leftovers to eat.
Speaker 1: The microwave at work is broken and it won't be fixed till like tomorrow.
Speaker 1: Ah, so I brought sucks.
Speaker 1: So I brought the leftovers home During your fridge.
Speaker 1: now, I'll either microwave them and leave or go home then microwave.
Speaker 0: See when I would bring lunches Like the few times I would do that I would never rely on a microwave at the remote destination partly because I don't like reheating things with microwaves.
Speaker 0: They tend not to.
Speaker 1: how can you?
Speaker 1: but there are certain things that I mean, it's like yes, it's true.
Speaker 1: If I'm gonna reheat say, I don't know Like a Sandwich.
Speaker 0: I worked in a place once that had a fucking stove.
Speaker 1: I mean we have a toaster oven.
Speaker 1: I can reheat things in but it's like I'm gonna reheat a sandwich.
Speaker 1: I'll do that in a toaster oven.
Speaker 1: so it's nice and crispy Right, but if I'm gonna reheat a bowl of pastas, I'm not gonna do that in a toaster oven.
Speaker 1: that doesn't work.
Speaker 1: It dries out.
Speaker 1: You got to do it in the microwave.
Speaker 1: That's a microwave.
Speaker 1: Anything mushy is a microwave reheating.
Speaker 0: see I would only ever bring lunches that were things that didn't require reheating.
Speaker 1: I cooked a pasta for dinner and now it's still.
Speaker 1: it's not gonna magically change into a sandwich.
Speaker 1: It needs to be reheated in the microwave.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't know I just I. it was partly when I was working at a hospital.
Speaker 0: I was in Yonkers.
Speaker 0: there were.
Speaker 0: Well when I say were there was one place you could get lunch without driving somewhere.
Speaker 0: Oh boy, so I would walk 20 minutes to that one place and you know what it was.
Speaker 0: It was a sit-down Italian restaurant nice, but because it was in Yonkers, it was actually really cheap.
Speaker 0: so every day for lunch I'd have like spaghetti or like a lasagna like real Italian food for like six bucks.
Speaker 1: I'm used to when in Midtown the lunches were usually like $8.
Speaker 1: He'd end up spending $10 maybe for lunch down in Soho It's like $15 and $3 a day adds up real fast.
Speaker 0: If I just go to the Pret in Midtown It's like nine bucks for a mediocre sandwich.
Speaker 1: That's not enough food.
Speaker 1: The other thing is like a lot of times It's not enough foods.
Speaker 1: No, and I'm still hungry and it's just like that's not good.
Speaker 0: The only thing that saves me is that there's an unlimited Pantry in my job so I can basically get free breakfast and constant snacks like bananas and stuff.
Speaker 1: It's like I've been.
Speaker 1: you know where I was in Midtown.
Speaker 1: I can go to the food emporium, which is an overpriced supermarket.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but you think oh, that's an overpriced supermarket.
Speaker 1: Guess what?
Speaker 1: down in Soho It's a Dean and DeLuca, which is a one-percenter Supermarket.
Speaker 0: where I do an apple is $10 a little bit even though the commute was longer.
Speaker 0: I miss working downtown because I could get it like go-go curry.
Speaker 0: That is plenty of food for like $6.
Speaker 0: that's what.
Speaker 1: that's the kind of places I'm need for my lunch if I had enough of those places that I didn't have to eat.
Speaker 0: I mean, I know the problem was I went to go-go curry like twice a week.
Speaker 0: That's bad news.
Speaker 0: That's bad news for a lot of reasons.
Speaker 1: That sounds like good news to me.
Speaker 1: It's good.
Speaker 0: Well, you know what it is like all things.
Speaker 0: It's good news until it's bad news.
Speaker 1: It sounds like it's just good news.
Speaker 0: in the immortal words of Dave Riley The best thing in life is pooping and the worst thing in life is too much pooping.
Speaker 1: I think to go curries a week will not be too much.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the problem is I wanted to go that third time.
Speaker 1: No I'd be holding back at the second time.
Speaker 0: So there's a bunch of news going on.
Speaker 0: But I do have an opening bit too because you might have noticed We didn't live stream some of our shows recently and then we started up again and the one Live stream we did earlier in this week Scott was really quiet.
Speaker 0: so the deal is we've had a lot of Hardware issues in the geek nights pipeline lately because the mixer we use is Hella decommissioned like it is to even down mission.
Speaker 1: Do you know what decommission means?
Speaker 1: So do you mean deprecated or discontinued?
Speaker 0: So it's not just so.
Speaker 0: it's not just discontinued.
Speaker 0: It is discontinued to the point that I can't even get support.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: It's actually hard to download the drivers.
Speaker 0: There's like.
Speaker 1: I even try to download them and back them up on your neck.
Speaker 0: I did download.
Speaker 0: I have them backed up on the NAS.
Speaker 0: It is to the point where hardware failures like I even contacted third-party people like yo, well, that might be a problem.
Speaker 1: if you know Windows 11 comes out and the drivers don't work.
Speaker 0: Yeah I'm already at the point where I have an extra firewire card that I know works with this thing.
Speaker 0: in case the card I use doesn't work anymore.
Speaker 1: So you might need to keep like a computer around but the old software on it.
Speaker 1: in case you know I'm.
Speaker 0: uh, well the software is audition.
Speaker 1: luckily I'm saying like, you know, if you say one day Windows 11 now You might want to like grab a laptop that has a fire, you know, an old laptop with a firewire.
Speaker 1: My hope runs Windows 10.
Speaker 0: My only hope is that the audio hardware industry Joins the modern world before this mixer dies because I do not want to buy another mixer because I love the hell out of this thing and It's shocking how shitty most of the even professional Audio equipment out there is.
Speaker 0: if you want a digital mixer and you're not willing to spend like eight to ten thousand dollars.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I looked and I saw tons of new mixers that lots of fancy features that could be good For example, then you die integrate with apps.
Speaker 1: They have touch screens.
Speaker 1: They don't have too many software instead of having hardware control.
Speaker 0: They say things like yeah 24 channels but no, it's 24x2 channels or sometimes it's 24 analog channels 2x2 digital right and it'll be like when you plug in the USB 3 cable There's only two channels.
Speaker 1: Ah, it's just a stereo sound card Whereas this a real digital mixer.
Speaker 1: in audition will actually every single channel on the mixer will be a different line in audition.
Speaker 1: That's the.
Speaker 1: that's literally the only feature we need.
Speaker 1: We don't need all these other features.
Speaker 1: They've crammed in there like effects and shit because our podcasting Want is that there should be at least like four to eight channels in audition All separately up.
Speaker 1: That's it.
Speaker 1: That's all we need.
Speaker 0: I use more than that.
Speaker 0: so the other things we use cuz in the geek nice pipeline is The thing is we don't do it cuz we haven't interviewed anyone and for fuck There are other ways we can interview people though without doing that.
Speaker 0: Yeah but there are a pain in the ass.
Speaker 0: and Also, I have this integrated into the room like I can throw a channel into the mod like the speakers in the room or the Headphones.
Speaker 0: I use this mixer as my sound card and it's it's kind of great actually to have those capabilities.
Speaker 0: Like I can record audio from the computer.
Speaker 0: I could actually pipe our voices into audition and have a real-time pipeline to have the effects come back into the mixer for the live stream.
Speaker 0: But I'm actually using the old compressor for that because that's just easier.
Speaker 0: But again, like this mixer has inserts and all that stuff so the a big part of why These mixers all suck.
Speaker 0: Is that all the companies that make USB mixers?
Speaker 0: Still just use USB to Mmm, like webcams to like.
Speaker 0: there really aren't USB 3 webcams or USB 3 mixers.
Speaker 1: Why don't we just make one?
Speaker 0: cuz I Don't know what the market is for these.
Speaker 0: Mmm.
Speaker 1: I actually asked her you'll find out.
Speaker 0: so I actually asked her out.
Speaker 0: I dug around and make a Kickstarter.
Speaker 1: if there's a market it'll you'll get kick-started.
Speaker 1: if Think oh, we'll make a Kickstarter, but then we'll be one of those people who don't deliver.
Speaker 1: cuz what do we know?
Speaker 1: We'll just set the goal so ridiculously high that if we get that amount of money We're guaranteed to succeed exactly if we get like five million dollars.
Speaker 1: It's like.
Speaker 1: I think we can do it.
Speaker 1: we get you know We can deliver to the people and if we don't then we don't do it.
Speaker 0: But let's get my friends who work in like professional podcasts.
Speaker 0: I ask people who are like in studios I even ask people at my job because where I work we have professional recording studios.
Speaker 0: I went to the recording studio and fucking looked at what they got.
Speaker 0: It's the same shit.
Speaker 0: I got.
Speaker 0: everyone's just running the legacy hardware because it's still the best hardware But it's no.
Speaker 1: all these companies that produce this equipment have to be.
Speaker 1: are they like?
Speaker 1: is People buying the new equipment because otherwise they'd be out of business?
Speaker 1: It seems like are they not selling?
Speaker 1: or maybe they are selling?
Speaker 1: and if those people who are buying what are they doing?
Speaker 0: Yeah, and it seems like are they all musicians?
Speaker 1: is they doing musicians only and they don't?
Speaker 1: And talk people?
Speaker 0: a lot of the people who are at the level of sophistication that geek night says for audio They primarily do live Mixing.
Speaker 0: where you need analog you need all that crazy analog shit.
Speaker 0: So the room like the house has good audio like that, but they're not really trying to record The level of quality that we're recording.
Speaker 0: They're recording the final mix.
Speaker 0: They're recording like some track inserts.
Speaker 0: It's a very different production pipeline from talk radio.
Speaker 0: Talk radio is still using this shit.
Speaker 0: Talk radio is still literally using morances.
Speaker 0: I went to a professional recording studio Yesterday and what did I see?
Speaker 0: sitting on the desk through the window?
Speaker 0: a fucking Marantz PMD 660?
Speaker 0: The same thing.
Speaker 0: I got sitting right here that hasn't been manufactured since like 2003.
Speaker 0: So yeah I Just want this mixer to last and I'm gonna see if I can physically fix some of the ports that have died.
Speaker 1: You're gonna break it will try and fix it and that's gonna be the end.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'll cry.
Speaker 0: I did open it up though to take a look and I actually looked as you saw fire in there The magic smoke came out.
Speaker 0: I could solder in there that complicated.
Speaker 0: Uh-huh.
Speaker 0: It's a pretty well documented actually all this stuff.
Speaker 0: So in other news you might have noticed I think I mentioned this on gig nights a while ago But there is a weird story that kept popping up in the real news Like I saw this on FARC and then like months later it started appearing in crackpot news but eventually it started appearing on like CNN and like Washington Post and like real news.
Speaker 0: and it was this story about like Sonic attacks.
Speaker 1: didn't we talk about this?
Speaker 1: In Cuba we did so.
Speaker 1: I think the final thing I saw about that was that it wasn't actually intentional.
Speaker 1: It was some sort of accident where they just had a bunch of different equipment all set up near each other.
Speaker 1: that happened to combine in a bad way Unluckily and it's due to incompetence and not due to some genius, you know intentional thing.
Speaker 0: So I read that same story and that was a narrative.
Speaker 1: I mean the thing is I don't have none of know.
Speaker 1: all this was just articles.
Speaker 1: There's.
Speaker 1: no I haven't seen any actual evidence for any of this.
Speaker 1: I haven't even seen somebody like set up like in a test lab like proof that this happen Right.
Speaker 0: So basically that was a plausible explanation.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: It's happening in other US embassies.
Speaker 0: now Mm-hmm It's happening in China and they did.
Speaker 0: we just have the US just evacuated a bunch of diplomats For basically the exact same symptoms the exact same problem.
Speaker 1: My guess, you know something more realistic?
Speaker 0: It appears that mass hysteria is ruled out.
Speaker 0: the doctors have found actual specific brain damage.
Speaker 1: No, no.
Speaker 1: No, I'm saying is that I don't think it's caused by a You know say audio.
Speaker 1: I don't think just because audio is just vibrating air.
Speaker 1: I don't think vibrating air can cause brain damage.
Speaker 1: Yes, it can.
Speaker 0: Uh-huh.
Speaker 0: Yes, it can.
Speaker 1: I think that it is more likely caused by maybe a virus or a parasite or something like that.
Speaker 1: That virus or parasite fucks with your ear so you think you're hearing sounds you ain't hearing or so It's not just that people are hearing sounds There's a you'd like.
Speaker 0: this article actually goes into a little more explanation and a little more detail about it but the ultrasonic attack thing is still not actually ruled out and still seems to be feasible because the deal is Sound waves.
Speaker 1: I think it's something else that causes an audio hallucination.
Speaker 0: It's not just audio hallucination.
Speaker 0: It's physical damage to the brain.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the parasite or virus causes damage to your brain and gives you an auditory hallucination.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but this is my reasonable guess.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so the crazy thing is that this is now happening in multiple places.
Speaker 1: Yeah You know what?
Speaker 1: This tells me let's not travel to any countries that really hate the u.s So much in case we have to end up going to the end.
Speaker 0: I saw a great tweet.
Speaker 0: That was like 99% of everyone outside of North America who has a Canadian flag displayed is an American And I can feel that I mean we Emily and I were in Australia right before the election and It was rough even then and now it's getting rougher.
Speaker 0: Let's try.
Speaker 1: they got their own problems.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Oh, there's a crazy story.
Speaker 0: I didn't make my news because I don't fucking understand it or believe it about this town that has 12 people in it in Like the like the fucking nowhere in Australia.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: Was it just the word?
Speaker 1: Oh, I written 12 times.
Speaker 0: So somebody disappeared from the town.
Speaker 0: The government's pretty sure the town fucking murdered this dude and all agreed to keep it quiet and they can't prove it.
Speaker 1: I mean, that's the only reasonable explanation.
Speaker 1: So therefore there's no reasonable day.
Speaker 1: There's no other reason.
Speaker 0: there's also a hint.
Speaker 1: if there is no other reasonable explanation then it's beyond reasonable doubt.
Speaker 1: There's all the evidence you need and there's no other reasonable explanation.
Speaker 0: That is not the standard of American jurisprudence or law at least.
Speaker 1: Oh It's Australia.
Speaker 1: The law is just like.
Speaker 0: ah, but this story was so crazy I didn't have time to read it enough to even talk about it.
Speaker 0: But I think the real thing we need to do is avoid US consulates and embassies in countries that hate us.
Speaker 1: It sounds good.
Speaker 1: I'll just go to some other countries ever see instead.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but this story just it's You know, okay, you'll see like a crazy story.
Speaker 0: And if you're a reasonable person you think that is probably not true and I will ignore it unless I keep seeing it.
Speaker 0: This one keeps happening and I'm getting increasingly fascinated by it.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: so maybe they're hoping that some of that maybe it is like a virus or parasite and they're hoping that the Diplomat or someone will eventually meet the president and pass it on.
Speaker 0: I mean like.
Speaker 0: this is in the realm of something like something like that about the Ukrainian guy who faked his own death to catch The Russian assassin.
Speaker 1: that guy's badass.
Speaker 1: They're gonna make a movie about that.
Speaker 1: Probably at least it'll be at least made for TV movie If not Hollywood movie and it will definitely be out within like a year because that story already is Literally twice as crazy as you realize.
Speaker 0: like the story escalated.
Speaker 1: It is 100% true.
Speaker 0: It escalated way beyond what we already know Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: But again, I didn't read it deep in depth enough to talk about it.
Speaker 0: I read enough in some other news.
Speaker 0: if you ever been in New York There's a. we have this huge bridge between New York and the rest of the country.
Speaker 0: It's called, New Jersey.
Speaker 0: I don't know if anyone's ever been to it But to get to that land bridge you have to go over another bridge called the Verrazano narrows bridge.
Speaker 1: You can use the George Washington bridge you can but and also technically the Verrazano bridge connects you to Staten Island and not to New Jersey.
Speaker 1: but Staten Island is New Jersey.
Speaker 0: well, so The Verrazano narrow bridge and Staten Island combined is a bridge to New Jersey, which itself is a land.
Speaker 1: After you go over the Verrazano and then over this elevated highway that allows you to not touch Staten Island like it's hot lava you go over either the The what's it called?
Speaker 1: There's the gothals bridge.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and then there's the what the cross something.
Speaker 1: I don't cross island.
Speaker 1: I forget what it's called.
Speaker 0: I usually use the gothals.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's the other one.
Speaker 1: anyway I forget what it's called.
Speaker 0: the Verrazano narrows bridge is real fucking long.
Speaker 1: I biked over it because if you do normally you cannot bike over it.
Speaker 1: You can only car over.
Speaker 1: it has two levels.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but if you do the five borough bike tour It's like.
Speaker 1: the only part of it worth doing is that you can bike on roads that are otherwise Unbikable like the FDR and the BQE.
Speaker 1: and it's when?
Speaker 1: then the Verrazano.
Speaker 1: So I did it once and that's enough.
Speaker 1: But you go over there Verrazano and let me tell you I bike over like the Queensborough bridge every day.
Speaker 1: It's like not even I don't even notice that it's a hill.
Speaker 1: It's not that it's like you look at the grade and it doesn't seem like it's so bad.
Speaker 1: It's like fuck that bridge.
Speaker 0: Yep, two miles later.
Speaker 1: It is long and it's a big hump.
Speaker 1: They keep.
Speaker 1: people keep like campaigning like we want to put a bike path on it.
Speaker 1: I'm like, you're never gonna use that.
Speaker 1: go up and you're just gonna turn right back around Especially when you realize Staten Island's.
Speaker 1: on the other side There's a kind of person who will use that and you're not gonna be able to bike if you're trying.
Speaker 1: You know you once you get to the other side on.
Speaker 1: if there was a bike path now You can't go on the highway.
Speaker 1: instead you're gonna go down and actually touch that lava.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you do not want to touch Staten Island You're gonna.
Speaker 1: you're gonna bike as fast as you can back to the ferry cuz you can go back over the bridge Rise back to civilization.
Speaker 0: the Verrazano narrows bridge is named after Giovanni de Verrazano some Italian guy.
Speaker 0: So there's a bunch of crazy shit going on with this bridge and Giovanni de Verrazano.
Speaker 0: so in the 50s the Italian American community was really I guess concerned about Its image in America and it made a Concerted funded effort to get things named after Italians all around the country funded with the money from the family.
Speaker 0: And one of those things was they wanted this bridge which was just going to be called the narrows bridge to be named after Giovanni de Verrazano, why is it called the narrows?
Speaker 1: It crosses the least narrow part.
Speaker 0: That's actually them.
Speaker 0: It's the narrowest part.
Speaker 0: If you wanted to put a bridge down there.
Speaker 0: anywhere else is way less narrow.
Speaker 0: I guess so and they needed a bridge there.
Speaker 1: So who do need a bridge?
Speaker 0: New York and Robert Moses is like.
Speaker 0: the response to this was who the fuck is Giovanni de Verrazano?
Speaker 0: because apparently Giovanni de Verrazano is Less objectionable than a lot of the explorers like.
Speaker 0: it doesn't seem like there's a lot of genocide in his history like certain other people But he was really unlucky and that he discovered for white people a bunch of important things.
Speaker 0: He's one of the more important explorers.
Speaker 1: I never heard about him in school.
Speaker 1: Yeah, no one heard about him I heard about like fucking Pons de Leon and shit instead.
Speaker 1: We all learned about Spanish explorers.
Speaker 0: He happened to discover all these things in the 1500s while Magellan and the Conquistadors were happening.
Speaker 0: So everyone paid attention to all that nonsense and ignored the fact that he basically Discovered like New York Harbor for white people.
Speaker 1: didn't Henry Hudson discover.
Speaker 0: No, that was way later and you're one of those people.
Speaker 0: Hey Verrazano's reputation quote I'm recording Wikipedia was particularly obscure in New York City where the 1609 voyage of Henley Henry Hudson was regarded as the de facto start of European exploration of New York, even though Giovanni de Verrazano mapped all that shit in like 1519.
Speaker 1: fuck you school.
Speaker 1: Yeah, tell me wrong.
Speaker 0: So nobody remembered this dude at all.
Speaker 0: and New York City was like why the fuck would we name it after him?
Speaker 0: and the Italian Community was like because here's a pile of money.
Speaker 0: Shut up We spelled it wrong.
Speaker 0: They fucked up and spelled it with one Z and when they realized it it was too late to change it.
Speaker 1: So that's why it has two and it's supposed to have three supposed to have two Z's it only has one.
Speaker 1: I Thought I had two Z's.
Speaker 0: Yeah, apparently a lot of people think it only has it.
Speaker 1: apparently this is why this is the pretty sure It has two Z's.
Speaker 1: This is why I've never seen a sign with only one Z on it.
Speaker 0: So this is the news June 7th 2018.
Speaker 0: There is a bill in the New York State Senate Assembly that just passed unanimously.
Speaker 0: Wait, the Senate Assembly the New York State Senate passed the bill.
Speaker 0: Okay Unanimously.
Speaker 0: that would correct the spelling of the name and even Simba Felder voted.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 0: Yeah unanimous.
Speaker 0: To add a Z to the name of the Paris.
Speaker 1: I thought it had two Z's already.
Speaker 0: Yeah, not only did it not but it's been spelled wrong forever and For almost a hundred years.
Speaker 0: the statue at the base of the fucking bridge has its that was made at the same time as the Bridge was spelled correctly.
Speaker 0: Two Z's it's spelled correctly.
Speaker 1: I feel like all the green highway signs have two Z's on them.
Speaker 1: Am I remembering wrong?
Speaker 1: because I know how to spell.
Speaker 1: I think my brain if I brain just Transforms a misspelled word into a correctly spelled world.
Speaker 1: when I look at it, I think Now the Mandela I can't even go over and look cuz I have a car.
Speaker 0: Yeah So the bill was now sent to the assembly where it must pass and then Cuomo will have to sign it.
Speaker 1: Apparently the assembly will vote.
Speaker 0: Apparently they tried to do this earlier this year and the assembly didn't fucking vote.
Speaker 1: Yes, the assembly is usually like the one who votes yes all the time and everything it's held up in the Senate.
Speaker 1: I cannot for the life assembly actually has voted for things like universal health care for all New Yorkers and the Senate won't vote on so I Cannot.
Speaker 1: why is this the opposite situation?
Speaker 0: I do not know and no one will tell me and my research came up with.
Speaker 1: this makes no sense.
Speaker 0: Yeah This is the first time in New York State history where the New York State Senate did something right and the assembly is doing something.
Speaker 1: Why do we need a law to fix spelling?
Speaker 1: Like the DOT or the Port Authority?
Speaker 1: just fix it.
Speaker 1: They don't need it.
Speaker 1: Why do they need a law for that?
Speaker 0: This is my more meta argument.
Speaker 0: Why the fuck does New York State have any fucking say in anything we do down here?
Speaker 0: That is not I'm actually mad about.
Speaker 1: I mean Why is you even need a law to make the name of a bridge?
Speaker 1: can't just like, you know The Port Authority or MTA whoever runs the British.
Speaker 1: It's a Port Authority bridge the outer bridge crossing.
Speaker 0: That's the other one.
Speaker 1: That's the other one.
Speaker 0: Thanks to Amanda But anyway things of the day.
Speaker 0: so I found this video.
Speaker 0: it's like 10 minutes long where this dude is like I'm a make a bike where the entire frame is made out of spring.
Speaker 1: that will not work.
Speaker 1: The bike will just go blorp and fall over and this video is an exploration.
Speaker 1: You will have it.
Speaker 1: you will have a sculpture made that looks like a bike that is made of spring.
Speaker 1: That will be impossible to ride and it will not stand up.
Speaker 0: this video basically tracks a long journey of this person Trying to make a bike where the frame consists entirely of Springs and Failing in most of the endeavor.
Speaker 0: Yes, and it's pretty funny and pretty interesting.
Speaker 0: there's points where he's took like talking to people who manufacture Springs and like that Simpsons episode where Moleman is like I need the biggest seed bell you've got.
Speaker 0: no, that's too big.
Speaker 0: He's not talking to people who make industrial Springs where he's like I need the stiffest spring you got and they're like Yeah, so we have a forty thousand dollar spring.
Speaker 0: That's a foot wide and he's like, okay, let's back it off And eventually he is able to replace the entire core of the frame of the bicycle with Springs.
Speaker 0: Yeah, not the whole frame just part that basically like the the top bar and the three bars Made one where the struts for the front tire were made of Springs and it did not.
Speaker 0: it was unbikable.
Speaker 1: Yes, I think what someone should do though.
Speaker 1: This is a stupid idea.
Speaker 1: I think right it's all it's cute But I think would be not.
Speaker 1: that would be much cooler would be to make a bike entirely of shocks because then the springs Would do what they supposed to do and only spring in the one, you know axis and not wobble a bike sideways Right, I'll ride this thing when he finishes it.
Speaker 0: It's just like.
Speaker 1: so you would have a. you right, you know You have a bike that is flexible forward and back and up and down in certain dimensions But you wouldn't have like the front part of the bike on warp to the left or the right making it unrideable And I think that that would actually be.
Speaker 1: it probably still wouldn't work too Well, but it could actually be way comfortable like the bike would get longer or shorter as necessary, right?
Speaker 1: You could depending on how the stiffness of the springs.
Speaker 1: I would you probably just use yeah I'll use adjustable like pneumatic shocks that way you could like, you know ease up certain ones Stiffen other ones so that you can get the bike like just right.
Speaker 1: it would probably the smoothest fucking ride.
Speaker 1: You probably wouldn't even feel the ground at that point.
Speaker 0: I want a computer-controlled active ground cancellation bike.
Speaker 1: The only reason I think that won't work is because you won't have enough fuel to carry a battery big enough to power the computer And such.
Speaker 1: yeah, because you all the sensors you would need and plus, you know Plug it in really long extension cord.
Speaker 1: It would be a tank like bike.
Speaker 0: But this video is pretty funny because in the end He does make a functioning bike that has three spring leaves fun for some definitions of funk.
Speaker 0: He's able to ride it like look it's going sure.
Speaker 0: He's pedaling It's going barely and he explores fully what this bike is capable of and it's not much.
Speaker 1: Nope I Think that just making a gif of that one, but up but up but up part I think illustrates the whole thing.
Speaker 1: That's all you need to see.
Speaker 1: So you got a thing of the day.
Speaker 1: I got two things of the day.
Speaker 1: Why not?
Speaker 1: one of them is just a gif I saw on Twitter of this dog.
Speaker 1: He float.
Speaker 1: Oh, he float and I want to.
Speaker 1: when I saw this gif it had such a profound impact on me I wanted to immediately leave work and float and I'm still considering just leaving here and floating.
Speaker 1: I can just go.
Speaker 1: they won't stop me.
Speaker 1: if I just go to the airport and give them my credit card They will take me to a place where the water is warm.
Speaker 1: They will not object no one will stop me and then when I get there I can give my credit card to someone else and they will give me a place to sleep and float.
Speaker 0: Yep I think that will happen.
Speaker 0: You can keep floating till one day that person comes back and says sir Your credit card was declined and then I will go back to the airport.
Speaker 1: It could happen.
Speaker 1: I could do it.
Speaker 1: I'm thinking about it.
Speaker 0: any water at Sandy Hook is 68 degrees too cold.
Speaker 0: We are five degrees away from the bare minimum.
Speaker 0: I'm willing to put my body in that water.
Speaker 0: We are ten degrees away from.
Speaker 0: I will swim.
Speaker 1: So I went to.
Speaker 1: here's my real thing of the day.
Speaker 1: It's not just a gif.
Speaker 1: so, you know, I pretty much have you know, you know Sometimes you get you know in a consumer materialist mood you start buying stuff, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah It's always that thing when I go to Amazon to buy like a serious thing.
Speaker 0: I started looking at other serious purchases I've been holding a while ago.
Speaker 1: like a year or two ago I bought basically every kind of camera that I'd ever need in my life and I actually use them all.
Speaker 1: none of them became bowling Balls, I did a good job of buying exact amount of camera stuff that I use it all to the correct degree.
Speaker 1: I don't feel regret buying any of it and I didn't buy too much.
Speaker 1: and as soon as I bought like enough I like lost all desire to buy more camera stuff.
Speaker 1: Like I have no desire to buy another lens or camera because I already have every single situation.
Speaker 1: I've got covered except for taking photos of space which I can't do like ignites once and if I had to I would just I would keep reading about microphone once we bought the countrymen and these beta mics.
Speaker 0: I've got every microphone I'll need forever.
Speaker 0: Maybe I'll get one shotgun mic.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm good for life anyway, but I then discovered the other day someone posted one of those gifts where it's like You know animates a little bit like to the left and right.
Speaker 1: it wiggles and it looks 3d, right?
Speaker 1: It's one of those wiggling gifts that looks 3d, but it's not.
Speaker 1: I like those Yeah, and usually there's different.
Speaker 0: one can just make them.
Speaker 1: I know a lot of people make them using different techniques.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well, I mean there's a lot of different techniques for making them.
Speaker 1: but apparently this person, you know Did it with a thing called a Nim's low and I was like what the fuck is a Nim's low?
Speaker 1: Nim's low is apparently this old camera.
Speaker 1: There's another cheaper version That's like a conica something or whatever, but the Nim's low is the good one.
Speaker 1: where it's a 35 millimeter film camera It just has four fucking lenses on it with four shutters.
Speaker 1: Oh and it makes lenticular pen and you take a picture and when you take a picture It uses the amount of space on the film that would normally be used for two normal 35 millimeter shots And it basically cuts each frame in half and uses two frames.
Speaker 1: So if you have a roll of film that has 36 shots you would get 18 shots Right with this and each shot gives you four slightly different angles on the same thing.
Speaker 1: It's a completely automatic camera.
Speaker 1: It requires basically no focus autofocus.
Speaker 1: No, you don't got to do anything.
Speaker 1: I just push the button and if it's too dark you put a flash on it.
Speaker 1: You don't got to adjust the f-stop.
Speaker 1: You don't go to just the shutter speed.
Speaker 1: You're gonna nothing.
Speaker 1: You just aim it and shoot.
Speaker 1: it takes four shots slightly different angles of the same thing Simultaneously.
Speaker 0: just lens lens lens lens.
Speaker 1: when you get home you scan your four shots in Photoshop You drag you put them on four layers.
Speaker 1: You put them on top of each other and you tell Photoshop Hey make an animated gif go frame one, two, three, four, three two and then you're back to one again and then loop it.
Speaker 1: and then you've got one of those things and I kind of wanted this.
Speaker 1: and it's only like, you know for like a new one in box from the olden days that was never open is like 250 on eBay, you know.
Speaker 0: So it looks like before.
Speaker 1: He's probably too much.
Speaker 0: before the era of gifting.
Speaker 0: people would use this camera to make physical versions of that with the lenticular print.
Speaker 1: Well people would use this in the olden days.
Speaker 1: I think there was actually a way to make an actual 3d image somehow develop.
Speaker 1: You would look at it with you know, the the piece of plastic on it with the ridges.
Speaker 0: that's called lenticular printing.
Speaker 0: Oh, okay.
Speaker 0: I kept I didn't.
Speaker 0: I look here see that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so I don't know how to print one of those things with the ridges.
Speaker 1: But yeah, I kind of want this.
Speaker 0: I haven't bought it yet But I kind of thing got pretty cheap toward the end of the 90s Like I recall there was a.
Speaker 1: yeah now I haven't seen it hardly at all recently It's coming back feel like cuz.
Speaker 1: everyone looks at things on a screen.
Speaker 1: There's no interest in having a still image on a piece of.
Speaker 0: so from what I gather Relatively recently like in the last few years there was a further advance where it's way fucking cheap to print this.
Speaker 0: so people are starting to make like Small low-key cheapo merch like keychains and things that has lenticular printing again.
Speaker 0: Cuz now it's in the realm of like geek nights could make a thing pretty cheaply and just do it All right.
Speaker 1: Well go buy me a nims little so I can.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'll buy you a nims low after I buy a new camera for geek nights.
Speaker 0: Now I'm gonna camcorder.
Speaker 0: Okay I don't want.
Speaker 0: I want an actual camcorder.
Speaker 0: the features of a camcorder Compared to the features of a micro four-thirds just like real camera I can do video.
Speaker 1: the only real feature that the camcorder offers is the larger shape of it.
Speaker 0: the physical Object is the integrated XLR and all that's just built in.
Speaker 1: I mean, yeah, you can get one of those Thingy attached on top.
Speaker 0: Yeah, this is just built into the camera body Like a built-in ND filter.
Speaker 1: Otherwise, they're really.
Speaker 1: it's like built-in video lens.
Speaker 0: I don't need to get like a expensive lens to go with.
Speaker 1: most of the good camcorders have lens mounts on the front these days Not built-in lenses.
Speaker 0: Mmm depends depends on which one I'm looking at.
Speaker 0: these Sony usually Panasonic usually their worst.
Speaker 0: They're larger.
Speaker 0: there's a new Panasonic one that just came out with a one-inch sensor.
Speaker 0: that's pretty good.
Speaker 0: one inch is way small Yeah, but for what I need it's fine.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: I don't need a full-frame camera.
Speaker 0: We're not we're not.
Speaker 1: no I don't have a full-frame camera.
Speaker 0: In the better moment the geek notes book club book is Emily Wilson's translation of the Odyssey by Homer.
Speaker 1: I read all the you know, the famous parts with the sirens and oh, yeah I gotta catch up.
Speaker 0: then we got to finish it.
Speaker 0: if you're reading at that rate I'll finish the book also.
Speaker 1: that part is for being the most famous part.
Speaker 1: That is the most adapted.
Speaker 1: it's like one is like less than a page long.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like all that stuff happens in this one chapter and it's like people think that that's the whole Odyssey.
Speaker 1: That's like a few pages.
Speaker 0: I think it's just American kids in high school.
Speaker 0: They only read like three sections of the Odyssey.
Speaker 1: No, I think it's that you know.
Speaker 1: popular culture adapted this one part of the Odyssey so heavily Yeah, and ignored all the other parts.
Speaker 0: But most of the people we talked to like you guys fans who were talking or like reading the book with us None of them remembered any of this.
Speaker 0: telemic is stuff like.
Speaker 0: I don't remembered the.
Speaker 0: everyone thinks the book starts Odyssey.
Speaker 1: or if you read the pop-up book You should read this real new adaptation of the book so you can actually understand what the whole deal is.
Speaker 0: cuz I bet you don't Yep, and we're gonna do a whole show on it and we're gonna assume you also.
Speaker 1: I hope she finishes that Iliad because all the others does is make me like want to read the Iliad.
Speaker 1: That's where all the Agamemnon Anything she translates Achilles is.
Speaker 1: I'm going to listen my boys this doesn't have my boys in it.
Speaker 0: So I'm gonna read every if she go if she does more Greek stuff.
Speaker 0: I'll read it all.
Speaker 0: and what is she?
Speaker 1: what if she translates Antigone?
Speaker 1: know the the story of rim Mel Pupo.
Speaker 0: If there's a story about me written in ancient Greek, I feel like I need to read it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it talks about awful.
Speaker 1: You are you're the worst If you read.
Speaker 1: there was a rim.
Speaker 1: he was the worst the end.
Speaker 0: Do you have you read like Antigone or like any of that stuff?
Speaker 1: I think the one I actually want to read is this What was it?
Speaker 1: I forget what.
Speaker 1: it is some guy with an X in his name and it's a story about like Xenophon.
Speaker 1: It's one of those Xenophon stuff.
Speaker 1: This is why I forget what it was.
Speaker 0: I think you're thinking of Xenophon.
Speaker 1: There's something like that.
Speaker 1: It was a story about like a Traveling through Turkey or something on some sort of adventure.
Speaker 1: Apparently a lot of stuff is based on this store.
Speaker 1: Oh the one that the Warriors is based on.
Speaker 0: Okay, I just I went to Xenophon.
Speaker 1: No go to the Wikipedia page for the Warriors.
Speaker 1: the movie And there's the Warriors is based on a book and the book is based on an ancient story.
Speaker 0: Oh, right.
Speaker 1: You sent me a link to that, but That warriors right because it's about traveling through on it to go about going on this difficult journey, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah to escape which is what about the Warriors is about and you know, so Well, let's hope Emily Wilson translates ever all this stuff Otherwise, hey, you should follow both me and Scott on YouTube because we both are uploading and also Twitter and Facebook.
Speaker 0: But YouTube in particular because we made a new gig nights presents Utena.
Speaker 0: We uploaded our last talk from PAX.
Speaker 0: We're uploading a lot of our panels.
Speaker 0: We're doing judge anime by its cover.
Speaker 0: We're doing geek nice presents board games.
Speaker 0: There's a lot of geek nights content on YouTube.
Speaker 0: We'll never abandon the podcast.
Speaker 1: but kids today tomorrow podcast the Ignites over.
Speaker 1: this is the last episode.
Speaker 0: Yes, the kids are on YouTube.
Speaker 0: So that's where a lot of our stuff is.
Speaker 0: So full disclosure, we do a lot of shows on food.
Speaker 0: Like that's.
Speaker 1: that's the thing we do on that side.
Speaker 1: That's you know on Thursday.
Speaker 1: We run out of ideas.
Speaker 1: That's what happens to send us your Thursday ideas.
Speaker 1: Any show idea that requires no research And is not technology gaming or anime or comics or manga related?
Speaker 0: You know what I could do again?
Speaker 0: I could let the patreon just vote on it.
Speaker 0: But if they vote on something bad, it's their fault.
Speaker 0: if we do a bad show I don't want to make a bad show though, but then we'll blame it on them.
Speaker 0: They paid for that.
Speaker 1: I'm actually not too worried about making a bad show.
Speaker 1: I'm worried about sitting here and saying nothing.
Speaker 1: Yeah, because then there's no show.
Speaker 0: but I feel like our thing is that it doesn't matter what the topic is We can somehow end up talking forever.
Speaker 1: I mean we can hopefully.
Speaker 0: I mean we could find a tangent and talk about The first four years of geek nights was just well, we're gonna talk about tangent 40 minutes of tangent.
Speaker 1: but then I feel like I didn't do the show on the thing I was said I was gonna do.
Speaker 1: the show doesn't matter.
Speaker 0: We just got to make a show.
Speaker 1: We just change the show title later on.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we record the intro.
Speaker 0: It's just geek nights Thursday.
Speaker 0: They're all just called geek nights Thursday The lounge sure.
Speaker 0: so full disclosure though, we are not Indian.
Speaker 0: No, you're not Authority as an Indian food.
Speaker 0: No, I don't actually know that much about Indian food.
Speaker 0: No, I'm not even going to pretend that I know the regional differences of Indian food.
Speaker 0: No with the caveat that I do know a little bit about a hydra bad food.
Speaker 0: Because guys you went there because I spent a lot.
Speaker 0: I have probably spent a total of like five or six months in Hyderabad over the years.
Speaker 0: Like I've spent a lot of time in Hyderabad I love Hyderabad food and the way I will describe food from Hyderabad is that you know when you get Indian food is really spicy Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: So if you go to Hyderabad and you get the non spicy food, it's that spicy.
Speaker 0: If you get the spicy Hyderabad food, you're dead.
Speaker 0: You're done.
Speaker 0: That's it.
Speaker 0: It's game over.
Speaker 1: But are there people in Hyderabad eating that spicy food?
Speaker 0: Oh, they're eating that food and they're complaining about how it's not that spicy.
Speaker 0: They as the first time I was in Hyderabad.
Speaker 0: I was warned.
Speaker 1: Why don't we send Judith there?
Speaker 0: I was worried the food was spicy.
Speaker 0: cuz I was warned from my friends in Mumbai.
Speaker 0: They're like, yeah, just be warned Hyderabad food is spicy.
Speaker 1: I'm sure there are people that who live.
Speaker 1: if people Tend to think that when someone comes from a country that has is known for its spicy food They think like Thai people.
Speaker 1: they can all eat spicy food.
Speaker 1: There's plenty of Thai people who can't eat spicy food and there's plenty of Thai food That's not spicy and they don't.
Speaker 1: they just eat that It's not like it's like even though a country has spicy food and is known for it.
Speaker 1: Don't mistakenly think that all the people there love the spicy food.
Speaker 1: I'm sure there's people in Hyderabad who don't eat the spicy food and ask for mild food, right?
Speaker 1: There's nothing wrong with that.
Speaker 0: There's a Thai place near us called tuk-tuk and one cool thing about it plays.
Speaker 0: It is a real good place.
Speaker 0: They have a special menu like on the back page.
Speaker 0: They have a menu that is five or six Thai dishes that are not in any way Americanized.
Speaker 0: There's no substitutions.
Speaker 0: they explain what they are.
Speaker 0: they explain the history.
Speaker 0: you can order them But they make it very clear if you are unable to eat it.
Speaker 0: It's your fucking fault.
Speaker 0: No refunds.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: And I mean, isn't that the true with all restaurant food?
Speaker 1: If I go to a place unless the food is like poison or has you know metal shards or glass?
Speaker 1: I don't expect the reef.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I find that most people are uncooked or something.
Speaker 1: I think the reason is it's got to be really messed up for me to ask for my money back.
Speaker 0: I think in this case, the reason is white folk will order this food and it is too spicy for them And then they can't eat it.
Speaker 1: Well, that's your home.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: So the menu is like listen kid This is actual Thai food.
Speaker 1: That's right.
Speaker 0: But uh, so yeah, I got.
Speaker 0: I got some like lamb beer out biryani cuz I was like I have some of that in my fridge.
Speaker 0: Yeah, very on e tomorrow.
Speaker 0: Maybe yeah, Hyderabad is known Specifically which I did not know then for its fucking spicy biryani And I was defeated by this dish in the hotel.
Speaker 1: I ever see when if I'm gonna travel to a country that doesn't speak it English, right?
Speaker 1: Even if you know, even if the people there do speak English, even though it's that's not their primary language Yeah, I'm always gonna make sure that the phrase I gotta learn is always please serve me your local specialty in whatever language And I'll just go there.
Speaker 1: and as long as it's not a thing that I don't eat which is a very short list like octopus and dolphin and whale and you anything to Monkey brain we got away.
Speaker 1: as long as it's not one of those things.
Speaker 1: It's just like bring it on.
Speaker 1: I want to eat whatever your best thing is and however you eat it and if it kills me because it's too spicy alright, if Went out good if turkey calms down and is safe to travel to again And maybe the u.s.
Speaker 1: Is hardly come down and safe to travel to.
Speaker 0: yeah But turkey if it for that if that is what you want Istanbul is the place to go.
Speaker 0: You want though you want like that any restaurant you go to as an American?
Speaker 0: They're gonna be like do you want to tribe the like our delicacy?
Speaker 0: Do you want like they're really into the specific river fish that they get right there in Istanbul sounds good.
Speaker 0: It's so good.
Speaker 0: I think I think.
Speaker 0: of all the places I've traveled in my life Istanbul had the best food anyway India.
Speaker 1: so back in the day.
Speaker 1: I was not big fan Indian food.
Speaker 1: I've always been a person Ellie not always but at least in my adult life I've always been a person who was willing to try any food.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, right It's like it was just very rare because I grew up in the Midwest.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's over.
Speaker 1: It was right, you know my you know, my family was.
Speaker 1: it's weird because when I was a kid I was you know, my brother was you know, super picky like french fries and you know, I remember that We'd all eat steak and he'd have his chicken.
Speaker 1: I have like a piece of chicken nuggets and french fries kind of you know It seems to be a thing a lot of picky eaters do right?
Speaker 1: Yeah But anyway, I was less picky, but I was more picky than like my parents.
Speaker 1: But as when I became an adult and moved out and was able to eat a different food and not the food that was you Know given to me or available in a suburb.
Speaker 1: I was like, oh other food is good.
Speaker 1: And now my parents and my family are way pickier than I am.
Speaker 1: But you know, even though I was willing to try any food once right at least, you know When I tried Indian food, I wasn't really that into it.
Speaker 1: You know, it's like I remember I was like.
Speaker 1: You know, I think we were living in Beacon and there was that Indian place next to the to the dragon's den.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah And I went there, you know like a few times with those because you know That's where people were eating after playing games at the dragon's den, right?
Speaker 1: So I would go there but you know the food there wasn't really that.
Speaker 1: you know, it wasn't doing it for me so much Right, so I wasn't that into Indian food, but you know what?
Speaker 1: You know a lot of people out there when they don't like a food, right?
Speaker 1: They just refuse to eat it, but it's like I'm like, all right, listen, I don't like this, but you know It's not gonna poison me.
Speaker 1: All right, and you know, the group would be, you know The whole crew to get together like Indian food and I'd be like, man, I don't want to go Right, but then I would go because I wasn't gonna be a baby right like some people are whoever if you're, you know I'm not gonna say any names, but you know who you are, you know who you are.
Speaker 1: people who say no I'm not eating that.
Speaker 1: I mean obviously allergies, you know vegetarians vegans.
Speaker 1: That's all valid excuses Things like that, right?
Speaker 1: I'm talking about.
Speaker 0: I don't like like.
Speaker 0: I don't like natto.
Speaker 1: I'm just yeah I don't like not to either.
Speaker 1: but you know what if everyone's like, hey, let's go to the natto place.
Speaker 1: I'm not gonna be that, you know socially ruining person.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'll go.
Speaker 1: maybe I'll go Order a natto and begrudgingly eat it slowly like an adult.
Speaker 0: That's one difference between us.
Speaker 0: You'll begrudgingly eat.
Speaker 0: I'm half perfectly willing to go hungry.
Speaker 1: Oh, you'll go hungry and not even eat the natto.
Speaker 0: I will happily go hungry rather than eat food I don't like.
Speaker 0: the other thing I'll do is I'll find something on the menu to eat if there is right like especially like You know a lot of times I don't understand the kind of person who can go to a restaurant And there's not one goddamn thing on that menu.
Speaker 0: They'll eat.
Speaker 1: even if I go to like a super seafood restaurant There's always like one steak on there.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right cuz there's always the baby meal.
Speaker 1: There's always a hamburger and I wouldn't do that.
Speaker 1: But Anyway It's the thing.
Speaker 1: the point is that I'm trying to make is that you know I was not a big fan of Indian food, even though he had tried quite a few different dishes There were some things I like.
Speaker 1: like who doesn't like a naan?
Speaker 1: right as a brand?
Speaker 1: Yeah, but you know, I wasn't into it, but we can't tolerant people.
Speaker 0: people kept.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm sure they like it.
Speaker 1: They just came in We kept going to eat it over and over again and I kept trying different things there and discovering new things.
Speaker 1: You know new things on the Indian, you know restaurant menus And trying different styles of Indian food and now I order any food on my own for delivery.
Speaker 1: yeah, right and I think the thing is is a lot of people who don't like a thing and They don't even want to try it and it's like just keep begrudgingly eating it and develop a taste for it.
Speaker 0: now Well, I've noticed I've known a lot of people There's a thing where people will try food that is from a particular Region or ethnicity or nation and if they don't like it They assume that that region's food is all one.
Speaker 0: that exact thing They just tried to eat and to bet.
Speaker 1: imagine if someone tried a hamburger like.
Speaker 1: I don't like American food.
Speaker 1: So now they won't try fried chicken.
Speaker 1: Yep, which is American food.
Speaker 1: Awesome.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right.
Speaker 1: It's like that's not right.
Speaker 1: Another thing I think that happens is the people get a bad first impression and pass a judgment.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and unlike anime where you can totally do that just fine.
Speaker 1: They'll try say a bat.
Speaker 1: They'll try a fruit and that fruit that they try for the first time this new fruit.
Speaker 1: Maybe it's like Not a durian.
Speaker 1: They'll try like a mango for the first time and they'll try a mango.
Speaker 1: That's not ripe and delicious.
Speaker 1: And then they'll judge all mangoes and now they won't drink a mango lassi.
Speaker 0: So it's got.
Speaker 1: I know you don't watch.
Speaker 0: It's always sunny in Philadelphia.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm, but there's a scene that is relevant to your interests Where basically there's one guy who's like never been outside of Philly in his entire life.
Speaker 0: Okay, that's his deal like.
Speaker 1: he's a character like When I was in Florida in the 90s like late 90s, or maybe he was even too early 2000s.
Speaker 1: I needed a haircut because it was too hot and I still had hair And I just went to a rando haircut place and the lady who cut my hair who was in her 40s or something at the time I just went wherever she told me she had never.
Speaker 1: she was like, oh, where are you from?
Speaker 1: Like oh, I'm from you know, I guess I was in.
Speaker 1: I don't know if I was in New York or Connecticut, but whatever She's like I never left Florida Emma her whole life and she was like 40 or 50.
Speaker 0: something I mean, I read saw a statistic a while ago that a good 20% of Americans have never lived outside of the county They were born it but I mean she'd never left period traveled.
Speaker 1: No, not even in a car not even to, Georgia.
Speaker 0: Well, at least New York City.
Speaker 0: I'm more willing to accept why someone might live that way cuz I've been outside of New York.
Speaker 0: So I'm just saying But so this scene so this dude who's never enough out of Philly.
Speaker 0: They're having some like normal Steinfeld style conversation and it turns out he's never had a pair Doesn't even know what a pair is.
Speaker 0: He's never.
Speaker 0: So they're like you gotta get a pair and they like stop at a market and they're like buy a pair from like a dude And they hand it to him fights into it and he's like, ah, no, I don't like this I don't like this at all.
Speaker 0: They're like what what he can it's a pair.
Speaker 0: What do you not like about?
Speaker 0: he's like it's Sandy and bland and then they look it like oh, it's not a right pair.
Speaker 0: and there's this whole thing about the.
Speaker 0: it's true.
Speaker 1: It's true.
Speaker 1: See pairs are one of those things where they're only good if you get the right variety of pair and it's perfectly Ripened the right amount.
Speaker 1: Otherwise, it just tastes like a nothing fruit.
Speaker 1: if it's ripe, then it's a sweet and sugary.
Speaker 1: But the thing about pear is unlike other fruits.
Speaker 1: It doesn't sort of have a flavor to go along with its sweetness.
Speaker 1: It's literally like just sweet and that's it.
Speaker 1: It tastes like pear Yeah, but pear doesn't have a strong flavor the way.
Speaker 1: see certain apples.
Speaker 1: Yeah, have a strong there's then there's.
Speaker 0: you want to really taste certain other apples that just taste like sweet.
Speaker 0: Yes It's true, but all pairs look at you read delicious You're the worst Apple exactly.
Speaker 1: But the point is if you want to taste a really good pair the best way to taste really the best pair.
Speaker 1: Just get canned pear.
Speaker 1: Yeah, get canned pear bits in pear juice at the store and just eat it with a spoon.
Speaker 0: That is probably the best pair that I was a kid I would just open up a can of canned pears and just eat it, right They're actually at the grocery store.
Speaker 1: when I was a kid There was actually it would.
Speaker 1: they sold canned pear as like yours as snack as like you a pack.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, I had those two.
Speaker 1: I hate those.
Speaker 1: like every day I'd eat I'd always been up a can of pear and eat it.
Speaker 0: So in high school, and then I drink the juice instead of bringing the small can pair with a little like Big like I brought a big one and a can opener I do that with pineapple.
Speaker 1: these days I don't buy a whole pineapple.
Speaker 1: I'll buy a can of pineapple.
Speaker 1: It comes in rings.
Speaker 1: Anyway, Indian food.
Speaker 1: So in food I the point I was trying to make earlier about developing a taste for something right is.
Speaker 1: a lot of people make the argument Oh, you could develop a taste for alcohol And or develop a taste for smoking and all these harmful activities.
Speaker 1: and it's like no because harmful activities don't develop a taste for them.
Speaker 1: But something like Indian food is not harmful.
Speaker 1: It's good for you and delicious.
Speaker 1: So even if you don't like it at first You should try to develop a taste for it because it will benefit you in life and also bring you joy without harming you.
Speaker 1: so You know if there are things in life that are good and would be good if you like them Even if you don't like them originally, you should try to develop a taste for them.
Speaker 1: Maybe you don't like sci-fi novels.
Speaker 1: Well, try to read it's.
Speaker 1: they're good.
Speaker 1: So try to read a few.
Speaker 1: maybe you'll develop a taste for them.
Speaker 1: You should at least try a little bit, you know Indian food.
Speaker 1: You should try drugs.
Speaker 1: No, don't Develop a taste for the meter if you could Depending on the drug.
Speaker 0: I mean my dad is really excited about his medical marijuana card.
Speaker 1: I'm talking like, you know, don't develop a taste for heroin guys.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's that's even though you could get used to shooting yourself up.
Speaker 1: do not But do get used to curry cuz it's delicious.
Speaker 1: Even if you don't like it at first maybe try again.
Speaker 0: We've already been going for like an hour halfway.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we didn't have any Indian foods though.
Speaker 0: Let's go.
Speaker 0: Let's go through.
Speaker 0: Let's just do a best of an Indian food.
Speaker 0: All right, so we're only talking about our personal.
Speaker 0: we gotta start.
Speaker 1: We got to start with rim.
Speaker 1: Mr.
Speaker 1: Samosa Samosa.
Speaker 0: I fucking love Samosa.
Speaker 1: They are delicious.
Speaker 0: Oh my god.
Speaker 1: First of all, it's fried.
Speaker 1: It's got this fried shell which is delicious and Inside the fried shell is chickpeas.
Speaker 1: Yeah inside the fried shell is potato, you know Like mashed potato potato and chickpeas are two of my favorite things on earth.
Speaker 1: and in that potato.
Speaker 1: It's not just potato It's potato that's been flavored up with all kinds of spices and shit.
Speaker 1: So it looks all yellow or green or yellow and green.
Speaker 1: and then the potato is filled with like peas and chickpeas and other Delicious naughty bits that are in that potato.
Speaker 1: and then it's all been fried and it's nice and warm and toasty.
Speaker 1: And then you dip it in either the red stuff, which is sweet and fruity kind of The green stuff.
Speaker 1: and you know what when I get Samosa they when you get ordered delivery They give you two samosas dip in both Alternating and they give you a red and they give you a green.
Speaker 1: and you know what?
Speaker 1: I randomly pick one or based on my mood and I eat the first samosa in that and then the next day I heat up The other one and eat it in the other cup.
Speaker 1: So I think the last one I got I got red So I got a green one.
Speaker 0: that's the difference Emily and I reorder.
Speaker 0: when we order Indian food We get a samosa.
Speaker 0: it comes with two.
Speaker 0: we each eat one.
Speaker 0: There's never one left over.
Speaker 1: I got it left over.
Speaker 1: I'm only one person.
Speaker 0: So in terms of naan garlic naan is one of my favorite foods on earth.
Speaker 1: I mean, I like all naans and I sort of just keep picking different flavors of naan.
Speaker 1: I'll even eat the plain naan.
Speaker 1: you get more naan flavor because a lot of times the you know Onion naan or a garlic naan will cover up.
Speaker 0: but you need the naan to scoop the food together to finish it.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm I do like the rosemary naan quite a bit.
Speaker 1: That's what my least favorite naan.
Speaker 1: maybe cheese naan is the naan that I think I like a lot But I don't go for it too often because it's too powerful.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: It's a. it's too filling and strong same with Oh Is one of my favorite things.
Speaker 1: the poor II feels.
Speaker 1: when you order a poor you feel like you're wasting your money because you're paying Basically a lot of money for a lot of nothing.
Speaker 0: It's basically a bread balloon.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like so thin You're but it's it feels like eating like just the crust of a bread like you're peeling the crust off of a bread.
Speaker 1: It's so good.
Speaker 1: We're only eating the crust.
Speaker 1: But yeah, it's basically just a balloon of bread and you pop it and then you eat it and it's delicious.
Speaker 0: I'm a real in terms of like core Indian food like main dishes.
Speaker 0: I think the sogs are my favorite types.
Speaker 0: Green spinach II maybe with the cheese like that.
Speaker 0: That's my go-to.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: Not the chicken tikka masala That's like the American defaulting.
Speaker 1: Well, I actually like a chicken tikka masala but some places don't spice it up enough and it's just bland as hell.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you gotta have a place where it's.
Speaker 1: you know, it doesn't need to be hot spicy But it needs to have lots of you know aroma going on and some places do it in some places make it Land.
Speaker 1: super bland is not good.
Speaker 0: I like the Rogan Josh too, but sometimes it's just like a Rogan Josh.
Speaker 0: Sometimes it gets a little too spicy for me.
Speaker 1: No, that's not too spicy.
Speaker 1: The thing that gets too spicy for me is What's it called chicken?
Speaker 1: The chicken why we know where it's all covered in the hot red stuff where it's like just super on fire.
Speaker 0: Not that not the tandoori chicken.
Speaker 1: No, the tandoori chicken is the one where it's not in a curry, right?
Speaker 1: It's just on its own.
Speaker 1: Yep, and it's you put that in a nice yogurt sauce.
Speaker 0: I love that Favorite actually my favorite thing to eat, but I can't anymore cuz I'm old on that.
Speaker 0: heartburn is like tandoori chicken and biryani together Mmm, but as an adult that is too powerful.
Speaker 0: That is too much.
Speaker 1: Just bringing up the menu here.
Speaker 0: Yeah I'm just looking through the Wikipedia.
Speaker 0: I'm just getting real hungry.
Speaker 0: Look at all this.
Speaker 0: The meta point is that I actually don't know enough about Indian food.
Speaker 1: Vindaloo that's the one that's too.
Speaker 1: Vindaloo is delicious.
Speaker 1: I love vindaloo.
Speaker 1: I'll order it sometimes but that actually usually it doesn't go into so hot that I'm like needing to eat snow and ice or something.
Speaker 1: but it's usually like crosses the border of my heat tolerance like by like one step and then my head ends up breaking out into sweat and My mouth hurts a little bit,
Speaker 0: but I guess When I'm at a good Indian restaurant, I'm ordering from a place in New York.
Speaker 0: There was a lot of options And I don't know that much about Indian food in that depending on what I order I might not actually be a hundred percent sure Exactly what I'm gonna get.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: And I've never been super wrong.
Speaker 0: I I'm always.
Speaker 1: I know that I'm gonna get some kind of meat Probably in some kind of sauce or curry or something and I'm gonna put it on rice and based on some of the words I might have a vague idea like something something sog.
Speaker 0: It's gonna be the green stuff.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: But I'm always weirded out when we go to Indian place.
Speaker 1: Korma.
Speaker 1: It's gonna be like the yellow white stuff, right?
Speaker 0: I really love doll.
Speaker 0: Oh my god I was like my go-to really.
Speaker 0: but a lot of people we know a lot of people I've encountered over the years.
Speaker 0: they Won't order anything from any restaurant let alone any place unless they know every detail of exactly What is it now if you like?
Speaker 1: I said if you're allergic or have some sort of dietary Right, but if you don't have that kind of restriction Not just Indian food.
Speaker 1: you just order whatever.
Speaker 1: don't ask them to change it.
Speaker 1: Everything on the menu is delicious delicious.
Speaker 1: If no one liked it.
Speaker 1: They won't put it on there.
Speaker 1: Just keep ordering stuff and keep trying.
Speaker 0: This has been a problem though.
Speaker 0: Sometimes we've gone out with a lot of people to get some Indian food and I don't remember what I ordered And I don't care what I get.
Speaker 0: nope, so whatever plate ends up in front of me I just eat.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: And sometimes I've eaten someone else's dish and then they come out with the thing I ordered and I'm in trouble.
Speaker 1: Oh, well.
Speaker 1: Oh the last thing we can't neglect to mention which I already mentioned a little bit Is the mango lassi the the king of?
Speaker 0: Promode is the rose loss.
Speaker 1: No, that's your promo.
Speaker 1: I don't like the rose loss.
Speaker 0: You're really only supposed to get that for like weddings, but there's a few places I know in New York that'll serve that and I always get it if it's on the menu.
Speaker 1: Do not I get the regular mango lassi.
Speaker 1: I don't eat no roses.
Speaker 0: I do like the gallop jump.
Speaker 0: the the Fried dough soaked in sweet water with cardamom I mean roti is also good to go a nice roti shop.
Speaker 1: But the thing is a roti.
Speaker 1: usually the other Indian foods that we've talked about.
Speaker 1: that's like you're getting dinner Right.
Speaker 1: roti is something I'll get for lunch or like, you know, I'm just going in real quick.
Speaker 1: I need some snack.
Speaker 1: I'm biking.
Speaker 1: I'll stop at the road.
Speaker 1: I see a roti shop and I'm like, whoa, give me that roti and then I'm on my way All right.
Speaker 0: Now I'm too hungry.
Speaker 0: I think we're ending the show.
Speaker 0: Okay good This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Speaker 1: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 0: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 1: But unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night.
Speaker 0: Andy patreon patrons for this episode of geek nights.
Speaker 0: Ah Craig Oliver, I'll enjoy some I could done.
Speaker 0: How do you mean?
Speaker 0: Nicholas shimmering groovy obelisk hanging in the sky my stadium calm Jeremy minor link eg Roberto Kingsley Kelly Snyder cold guy Amanda Sean Yeager Matthew Smith Nicholas Brando, mr.
Speaker 0: Strong stretch in 4 to 1 creations.
Speaker 0: No, I never ever wonder why we're here separate.
Speaker 0: five bitch Sir Shervin not Horrell Rory, James David Wright white Rochelle, Monta, Nona a superboy a couple our pickle come quiet.
Speaker 0: Sailor Vista Don July kajar tovish and Joe Joe Joe star Clinton Walton Ren from New Zealand.
Speaker 0: Ryan Perrin drew open letter Finn Chris midkiff Dangle Redmond Sean Klein Chris Reimer Thomas, hon.
Speaker 0: I'm losing my voice inexplicably.
Speaker 0: So now I leave you with.