Speaker 1: It's Thursday August 2nd 2018.
Speaker 1: I'm rim.
Speaker 1: I'm Scott, and this is geek nights.
Speaker 1: tonight We're bringing back a long-running geek night series how to not suck at things with how to not suck at the beach.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: Yesterday I come home, and I do some stuff that plays them overwatch.
Speaker 1: I'm doing a bunch of chores like I'm doing my things and I smell a smell that I haven't smelled in a long time poison just a little bit poop.
Speaker 1: the best way I'll describe It's a smell that in the modern era all for you never smell anymore.
Speaker 1: It's the smell of you know when you have an incandescent bulb that's covered in dust how it'll have this sort of like Slightly burning dust smell if it's on a long time or like you turn it on and it hasn't been turned on in a long Time like like.
Speaker 1: that's the smell from my childhood that I don't encounter anymore cuz literally every light bulb.
Speaker 1: well with the exception of two Xenon but nobody cares every other light bulb in my apartment, so I thought was either a CFL or mostly LEDs.
Speaker 1: so uh I Think like I'm thinking like I'm gonna find that smell later And then eventually I get some groceries and I opened the fridge and I found the smell.
Speaker 1: So the fridge door had closed and in fact the seal around the edge was like touching.
Speaker 1: But the door was held a tiny bit open And I cannot identify what.
Speaker 1: held the door open and held it open just enough to leave the lights on in the fridge.
Speaker 1: Those two light bulbs.
Speaker 1: There's two not one are both 40 watt incandescent fucking bulbs And they basically cooked everything in the top half of the fridge.
Speaker 1: I had to throw away almost everything in the fridge.
Speaker 1: Yeah Luckily a lot of the stuff was kind of old so I didn't feel too bad about it.
Speaker 1: and the bottom of the fridge cuz The fridge was just cooling the whole time was cool enough to wear like all the veggies and all that stuff was fine.
Speaker 1: So I lost some meat.
Speaker 1: I lost some old sauces, and I lost all the like dairy Related product.
Speaker 0: like all the dairy adjacent will throw food away like the drop of a hat when it's perfectly fine.
Speaker 1: So would you if your fridge for an entire day was well above the FTA approved temperature keep some?
Speaker 1: Like nearing room temperature ground beef.
Speaker 0: I check it.
Speaker 1: What do you?
Speaker 1: how would you check it?
Speaker 0: check it?
Speaker 1: Yeah?
Speaker 1: What would you do?
Speaker 1: What is your?
Speaker 1: what would you do to determine whether or not this?
Speaker 1: Nearing brown room temperature ground beef that has been at this temperature for an unknown amount of time is safe.
Speaker 1: What?
Speaker 1: what is the thing you will do?
Speaker 0: well first of all right the longest it could have been at that temperature would be?
Speaker 0: Like since you left in the morning.
Speaker 1: so like eight hours.
Speaker 1: That's way above what was okay when I worked at that restaurant.
Speaker 0: I mean if I take some you know I might have.
Speaker 0: you've got some food And it's currently cold and from the fridge or freezer I take it out leave it on the counter for eight hours And then cook it.
Speaker 0: I would not leave ground beef on the counter for eight hours To that you know to get it to room temperature for cooking cuz you don't want to cook it when it's cold.
Speaker 0: right that's perfectly Okay, so maybe I cook it right away.
Speaker 1: I take issue with saying that leaving ground beef on the counter for eight hours before you cook it is okay.
Speaker 1: I don't see a problem all right.
Speaker 1: I uh we should do the ground beef challenge Mmm.
Speaker 1: I'll get some ground beef, and we'll leave it out for eight hours at room temperature.
Speaker 1: Then you can eat it, and we'll see what happens.
Speaker 0: Anyway, I ordered that we're not leaving it out for like 24.
Speaker 1: I I. so I could not be sure that the problem didn't happen the night before either.
Speaker 1: Hmm could not be sure it was.
Speaker 1: the top half of the fridge was warm like all.
Speaker 0: the butter was completely liquid And I'm still cooking it to the appropriate safe temperature to kill.
Speaker 1: fucking everything right yeah But that does not necessarily matter.
Speaker 1: a lot of the pathogens and food create poison so even if you kill the bacteria It's too late.
Speaker 1: the food is already unsafe even if you kill all the bacteria in it, but I've set the poison on fire.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it doesn't work for many things.
Speaker 1: Anyway, it's Thursday.
Speaker 1: It's the lounge.
Speaker 1: We can talk about anything.
Speaker 1: He's got any news.
Speaker 0: I do have a news.
Speaker 0: this news like.
Speaker 1: he didn't fight me on how it's called the lounge.
Speaker 0: You gotta give up on that.
Speaker 1: That is one of the hills I will die on oh Die.
Speaker 1: and our website even calls it the lounge.
Speaker 0: die soon then.
Speaker 1: So what do you got?
Speaker 0: so?
Speaker 0: The you know people.
Speaker 0: I know most people know about the Nobel Prize, but only nerds know about the Fields Medal.
Speaker 0: The Fields Medal is basically what you is like sort of like the Nobel Prize for math only sign.
Speaker 1: I know about the Fields Medal only because of YouTube channels.
Speaker 1: I follow that talked about it.
Speaker 0: Okay, I knew about it before then, but basically if you win the Fields Medal You're like one of the best maths people ever right.
Speaker 0: There's not a lot of people who want it.
Speaker 0: It's only given to like math geniuses.
Speaker 0: So it's a big deal if you get the Fields Medal.
Speaker 0: and so just recently what a few days ago Just super recently yeah August 1st.
Speaker 0: so yesterday yesterday.
Speaker 0: They awarded the Fields Medal to someone.
Speaker 0: What's his name?
Speaker 1: Feels metal The most prestigious award in mathematics.
Speaker 1: I reckon it didn't say it is winner of god.
Speaker 1: damn it article Kocher.
Speaker 1: Burkar receives the medal okay?
Speaker 0: Yes, so the person won the medal and after Burkar that name sounds really familiar.
Speaker 0: Anyway, famous math genius person yeah, so I don't know what math they want it for cuz probably where over my head.
Speaker 0: So you won the medal.
Speaker 0: you know nice ceremony and everything put it in his his briefcase right?
Speaker 0: And I guess it was.
Speaker 0: you know it was a party some sort of reception or something you know.
Speaker 0: yeah, right a Few minutes later that briefcase is gone.
Speaker 1: Pro that is Pro.
Speaker 1: I mean I Think the only place that's a public place where I trust anything out of my own sight is actually enforcer land.
Speaker 1: That is literally the only place that is acceptable.
Speaker 0: the point is is that that briefcase is gone So everyone starts looking for it now.
Speaker 0: This is like a serious.
Speaker 0: Hi someone Yeah Got into this an invite only of well clearly an inside job.
Speaker 1: someone who's jealous someone who knows what the fields fucking metal is Right and wants it right.
Speaker 1: I mean unless it's made out of gold or something.
Speaker 1: I've never seen it.
Speaker 0: pretty sure.
Speaker 0: It's a solid gold disc anyway.
Speaker 0: It's value.
Speaker 1: Oh, okay.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's worth $4,000.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's not.
Speaker 1: It's pretty good Because the thing the reason you steal gold is that unlike other things that are melted the fuck down then no one knows it.
Speaker 1: There's no way to determine what it was.
Speaker 0: they can just make a new Fields Medal But they should also catch whoever stole the $4,000 lump of gold.
Speaker 0: yeah, anyway they found the briefcase tossed away and open and Not only was the Fields Medal gone as well.
Speaker 0: It was gone I don't know.
Speaker 0: puts their wallet in a briefcase and not in their pocket, but whatever.
Speaker 0: And yeah, there's this.
Speaker 1: there's a situation.
Speaker 0: I have done that for this is like a loupon situation.
Speaker 1: No, but the situation where I have basically put my wallet in like a bag or something and not had it on me at An event like this is in my job.
Speaker 1: I would often like be on a stage giving basically like a TED talk so and I wouldn't carry anything on me.
Speaker 1: So I can put it all somewhere now swimming.
Speaker 1: It's not in a briefcase somewhere It's like in my hotel room probably in that safe.
Speaker 0: Yeah, anyway This is awesome loupon thief story, but they're totally gonna get caught.
Speaker 1: I think they got seen on camera Yeah, but okay, so someone wearing a hat and dark clothes Yeah, I feel like it's easy to get away with the crowd.
Speaker 0: It's such a. it's such a small You know event with not too many people at it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like it's gonna be really hard for these people.
Speaker 1: I feel like there's two main possibilities.
Speaker 1: possibility number one that I think is the second most likely is Inside job of someone related to the event.
Speaker 1: this number two thing that I think is the most likely is someone who works at the hotel.
Speaker 0: Well, I think what it could be is actually someone who's real smart and was perhaps got You know in by working for the caterer or working for the hotel or dressing like that, you know or some such.
Speaker 0: So there probably wasn't mega security there.
Speaker 1: I imagine you trust the people at an event like this.
Speaker 0: It's the kind of thing where you could probably just walk in right?
Speaker 1: Yeah I mean, I didn't read the details of like when and how like I didn't see the breakdown of the timeline.
Speaker 0: Like when did they last see the pretty think about like a wedding?
Speaker 0: It's like you can just walk in until someone says who the hell are you?
Speaker 1: Okay, so he what he what he got the award for or for?
Speaker 1: let's see if we understand this for his work on Categorizing different kinds of polynomial equations.
Speaker 0: I know what polynomial equations are.
Speaker 0: I know what categorizing is.
Speaker 1: So we're halfway there.
Speaker 1: He proved that the infinite variety of such equations can be split into a finite number of classifications.
Speaker 0: Actually make sense.
Speaker 0: Okay, so every kind of polynomial equation fits into one of some number of categories.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and that number of categories is finite as opposed to infinite.
Speaker 0: Well, what's what are the number of categories?
Speaker 1: It doesn't say He might not have identified all the categories.
Speaker 1: He just proved That's a finite number of categories a major breakthrough in the field of bi-rational geometry.
Speaker 1: I have no idea what that is.
Speaker 1: That's the kind of thing that that like three blue one brown channel We'll talk about.
Speaker 0: I can understand why that's a big deal.
Speaker 1: This sounds like the kind of thing where I will find a YouTube video that will explain this and I'll feel like I Understand it after I watch the YouTube video.
Speaker 0: But you know and you won't be able to use it whatever.
Speaker 1: in the same way that I feel like I understand how 18th century ships work after I read a Horatio book.
Speaker 1: So in turn in another high story something was stolen that cannot just be melted down and cannot easily be fenced.
Speaker 1: Someone stole the Swedish crown jewels work work work like.
Speaker 1: I'm just gonna read the first part.
Speaker 1: Thieves stole priceless royal artifacts in a daring raid on a Swedish Cathedral.
Speaker 0: Before escaping by speedboat all the Swedish sports teams are gonna have to change the Jersey to have one crown instead of three.
Speaker 1: Or they should just put that little logo on milk back on milk cartons.
Speaker 0: But this story is crazy and I guess it's a lot harder to heist than yeah.
Speaker 1: And even if you succeed like maybe no one thought anyone would try to steal them and like maybe it was easier than you expected What are you gonna do with them?
Speaker 1: If you sell it to a supervillain?
Speaker 1: He's just going to have you killed.
Speaker 1: If you keep them you gain nothing.
Speaker 0: great, I mean I can wear the.
Speaker 1: Yeah, to be fair if I stole the crown jewels It's me.
Speaker 0: people always think when you steal something you want to fence it to get money because money is what you actually want.
Speaker 0: What if what they wanted was the crown jewels a fucking sweet?
Speaker 1: Yeah I mean, I feel like if I got my hands on these getting crowns even only plays you could buy a crown.
Speaker 0: I have a tiara still yeah going to go on Amazon you search for crown.
Speaker 0: You can find a real one.
Speaker 1: No Well, what do you mean?
Speaker 1: right real like actually made out of gold or real like?
Speaker 0: yeah an actual jewel a real jewelry crown.
Speaker 0: I bet even if you go over to Fifth Avenue, you couldn't find a crown.
Speaker 0: I'll bet a real crown.
Speaker 0: I could get a crown jewel quality crown.
Speaker 1: Maybe that's what I'll spend my square money on.
Speaker 1: But you can read the story about this thing.
Speaker 1: But yeah, if I stolen if I had these ground jewels I would tell no one But I would wear them around the house and I would ensure that I was buried in them and that would be the extent.
Speaker 0: I would just go someplace where no one to recognize what they were and Just be the the crazy dude who wears a crown all the time like the dude who would wander around.
Speaker 1: Magpies are not.
Speaker 1: make that the dude the banana maracas guy.
Speaker 1: and in a maraca my hero You could be the banana maraca equivalent except the thing you're doing is walking around the convention.
Speaker 0: I walked around a convention with the crown.
Speaker 0: nice cosplay bro, right?
Speaker 0: Nobody who would know at PAX East unless they was like even if there was a Swedish person there would they fucking recognize it?
Speaker 0: Would they believe that it was the real one right?
Speaker 0: It's like it would just look like an awesome crown.
Speaker 0: No one would even say anything.
Speaker 1: Yep, right, but then again you might find that one nerd who's like.
Speaker 1: That's the.
Speaker 1: that's a really good Swedish King cosplay.
Speaker 1: Wait a minute.
Speaker 0: No, it would be a banana maraca crown.
Speaker 1: That's what I would do.
Speaker 1: I would give them to and also I would give the crown to the banana maraca guy.
Speaker 0: You could also just do.
Speaker 0: I know I can just dress up as Burger King.
Speaker 1: you could probably really On your deathbed you reveal it.
Speaker 0: The one problem with this plan is that One of many problems.
Speaker 0: There's really only one problem with the plan Is that actual crowns are heavy as fuck and your neck is gonna hurt like a motherfucker.
Speaker 1: Uh They're actually lighter than you think because that while they are heavy because it's gold they are.
Speaker 0: Go wear that crown for all of packs and tell me how your neck doing I don't know.
Speaker 0: I have none didn't wear crowns for eight hours.
Speaker 1: Yeah, no, they only wore them for specific ceremonies.
Speaker 0: They wore them for the ceremony.
Speaker 0: then they went in the back room.
Speaker 0: They took that shit off.
Speaker 1: I didn't look at what they actually stole.
Speaker 1: if they're I hope they got one of those like.
Speaker 0: They stole actual crowns.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they stole other thing because I really like those holy hand grenades.
Speaker 1: Yeah, look there's a picture of the two of them right here.
Speaker 1: hide your bunnies the holy hand grenades.
Speaker 0: hide your bunnies.
Speaker 1: They got these two maces and the crowns.
Speaker 1: mace Septers.
Speaker 1: don't mess with the scepter in Shadowgate.
Speaker 1: It's bad news.
Speaker 1: So in some weird side news This just like this weird story about cuz but it illustrates a broader point Kroger which is like this Midwestern grocery store chain.
Speaker 0: It's like only rim cares.
Speaker 0: It's a really big chain.
Speaker 1: But but the news is not about.
Speaker 1: I don't care about Kroger like.
Speaker 1: that's not the crux.
Speaker 1: They are a bunch of their stores have banned Visa credit cards.
Speaker 0: I'm surprised they're banning Visa and not Amex.
Speaker 0: is Amex.
Speaker 0: I'm pretty sure has the biggest fees?
Speaker 1: Yep, but visa is used the smallest fees visas used the most by people.
Speaker 1: That's correct and visa has very high fees.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and from what I gather visas I mean they all have high fees.
Speaker 0: just Amex is even higher.
Speaker 1: Yeah So the dispute is over the high annual swipe fees.
Speaker 1: So visa charges these like annual fees.
Speaker 1: right and the grocery store is basically trying to ban visa.
Speaker 1: Well, they're they can like.
Speaker 1: there's no law that says they have to accept one kind of credit card.
Speaker 1: No, what sucks is that my entire life?
Speaker 1: I always had this policy to have at least two different types of credit cards just in case this kind of bullshit happen.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I have an Amex and a visa.
Speaker 1: So I had um And I had that for my like a long time.
Speaker 0: I had a MasterCard.
Speaker 0: originally it changed a visa without my input.
Speaker 1: Yeah my MasterCard fucking changed a visa and all my credit cards are visa.
Speaker 0: then I got a American Express and then I got another visa and I don't use the old two old ones.
Speaker 0: So I still have them.
Speaker 1: there's a restaurant in Long Island City called turn us all and I forget this every goddamn time I eat there.
Speaker 1: they accept two forms of payments cash or Amex.
Speaker 1: hmm, they don't accept visa or MasterCard.
Speaker 1: Hmm.
Speaker 1: I forget this every goddamn time we go there.
Speaker 0: Yeah Cuz Amex me.
Speaker 0: one of Amex's things they did and I guess still do is make like exclusive deals Especially with restaurants, which is horrible.
Speaker 1: Like I Almost want to boycott places that do stuff like that.
Speaker 1: Hmm on principle.
Speaker 0: See here's the thing right.
Speaker 0: on the one hand It's like man cards are super convenient.
Speaker 0: I just want to use my card or Apple pay everywhere so I don't have to carry any cash.
Speaker 0: Think about it and life is super easy.
Speaker 0: and I get points and bonuses, right?
Speaker 0: and of course the reason I get bonuses?
Speaker 0: because as we've said many times credit cards are Benefit the user of them because you know us yep And as long as you always pay off your your balance Which you should yeah, and they benefit the credit card company and the bank that use the credit card But they hurt the merchant.
Speaker 0: the credit cards suck for merchants a cost of money.
Speaker 1: But here's my.
Speaker 1: I have an actual solution.
Speaker 0: so I was but I would love to use credit cards everywhere.
Speaker 0: But something that's actually been happening lately is you know, obviously it's because I like this convenience.
Speaker 0: cash only is annoying, right?
Speaker 1: Oh, I won't go to places.
Speaker 0: Here's the thing.
Speaker 0: What's even worse than cash only won't accept cash is I've run into.
Speaker 0: that is especially where I work now in Soho, there are several places that are card only.
Speaker 0: and Now you might say well, why would you be upset about card only if you love to use?
Speaker 1: Poor people marginalize people poor people kids.
Speaker 0: Not everyone in the world can even have a credit card Even if they're smart and listen to our advice and try and get a credit card.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like we say they should like I got a credit card at 16.
Speaker 1: It's a big part of why my credit so good.
Speaker 1: that is actually not easy to do.
Speaker 0: I think it should be illegal to not accept cash at all because you're basically saying yeah You can't shop here unless you are, you know, it's like even if you're.
Speaker 0: You're a smart person who wants a credit card and would use it everywhere and would always pay off the balance.
Speaker 0: Sometimes you just can't fucking get one.
Speaker 1: So here's to count.
Speaker 1: I'm not arguing these but these are Valid counterexamples.
Speaker 1: What if there is a place that only sells very expensive things.
Speaker 1: It is dangerous to accept cash in a place like that.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm Like say you sell like ten thousand dollar suits and twenty thousand dollar ostrich things Like.
Speaker 1: is it okay to not accept cash?
Speaker 0: It's okay, I guess if you also accepted things like say a money order from the post office Okay, or maybe a cashier?
Speaker 1: Cashier's checks are pretty much not.
Speaker 1: they're always a scam.
Speaker 1: They're they're less secure than a regular goddamn check really.
Speaker 0: They're not a certified check It's a check the bank prints out.
Speaker 1: Yeah So that you know It's more easy to counterfeit because they're weird and people don't know how to like.
Speaker 1: people don't know about them.
Speaker 0: I thought they were harder to counter.
Speaker 0: no than uh, so why doesn't the bank fix that then?
Speaker 1: because they don't give a shit.
Speaker 1: Cuz cashier's checks are basically only used by people trying to scam them.
Speaker 1: Why don't we here's it?
Speaker 0: Why don't we scam and commit counterfeit cashier's check?
Speaker 1: the the real fancy check is the certified check.
Speaker 1: All right, a certified check means the the issuing bank Guarantees the money.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: Well, that's the point is that you just accept something that anyone could have access to.
Speaker 0: Regardless Person suddenly gets mega-rich and finds a suitcase full of money that's not stolen and they hand it into the police.
Speaker 0: the police give it Back and it's all legal and they want to buy a crown And they go into the crown store and they're like cat the no cash accepted at the crown store.
Speaker 0: They should.
Speaker 0: they should have some other option because no one's gonna give that person a credit card yet Right they?
Speaker 0: because they haven't established any credit rating.
Speaker 0: There's still a homeless person with a pile of dollar bills, right?
Speaker 0: They should be able to go to the post office get a money order and buy the crown.
Speaker 1: So To at least we'd have to change a lot of laws because cash is only required to be accepted to pay debts.
Speaker 1: Technically, I'm not a lawyer but that is what lawyers have said Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: It's so I'm saying the law should be so.
Speaker 1: say you eat at a restaurant that didn't say they won't take cash.
Speaker 1: They usually have to take cash because now you owe them a debt.
Speaker 1: You can pay that debt with cash.
Speaker 1: But if you didn't get food yet, they could say we won't serve you if you're gonna pay cash.
Speaker 1: That would be okay, but they couldn't say we won't take cash after they served you the food anyway.
Speaker 1: So all that aside, I think the real answer is Credit card should be nationalized.
Speaker 1: They shouldn't be private.
Speaker 1: There shouldn't be private companies running them.
Speaker 1: They should be regulated and nationalized.
Speaker 1: Well, I think that the private company should be able to offer their own credit cards But there should be government-issued credit cards that anyone can get that Are regulated heavily and compete with the private with the party all private.
Speaker 0: So the problem is is two different things going on here, right?
Speaker 0: The first thing what's really?
Speaker 0: it's like a credit card is technically like a loan, right?
Speaker 0: That's the thing.
Speaker 0: It's like you're getting a loan to buy things and then paying it back.
Speaker 1: Well, yeah, but they function the same way as a debit card.
Speaker 0: Well, right is they?
Speaker 0: what they should do is they should make just a nationalized free to anyone who wants one anonymous Cash cards so you can have the who.
Speaker 1: those are dangerous, too.
Speaker 1: those do not solve a lot of the problems of why we want to eliminate cash because Bearer instruments are valuable to steal.
Speaker 0: No, no, the cash isn't on the card.
Speaker 0: It's still attached to your account.
Speaker 0: It's just a. it's just a mechanism for buying things.
Speaker 1: There should be national nationalized credit and debit cards that are available to anyone.
Speaker 0: No, it's that the loan part shouldn't be nationalized.
Speaker 0: right if you want to get loans and have a line I think the loan part should also be also be nationalized.
Speaker 1: They might not have to issue a high limit to everyone.
Speaker 1: No, you might only get a limit of $10.
Speaker 0: No You should just.
Speaker 0: just.
Speaker 0: the ability to buy things online In stores that only take cards to just the ability to conveniently buy things without carrying pieces of paper should be free to everyone.
Speaker 0: With loans and interest that doesn't need to be free to everyone.
Speaker 0: It's better off if it's not free to everyone.
Speaker 1: I would argue that that should be.
Speaker 0: but a three-year-old who wants to buy something from the ice-cream man Should be able to have a card not have to carry pictures of George And the ice-cream man should be able to accept should be forced to accept that card, right?
Speaker 1: But what about Bitcoin?
Speaker 1: that'll solve all these problems?
Speaker 1: Fuck your coin.
Speaker 1: but anyway things of the day.
Speaker 1: so as much as I Think a lot about UX and like UX is literally like one of my core Areas of expertise professionally like I've done it professionally for a long goddamn time and I think I'm good at it.
Speaker 1: But nowadays I rely mostly on teams of UX people and I'm kind of not allowed to do my own UX because I'm supposed to be doing this higher-order stuff, but this article that I found is Fantastic and all of you should read it.
Speaker 1: It is a very detailed explanation of the principles of using animation as part of UX in a way that adds value to the UX as opposed to just looks nice and this is Really really well put together and really really accurate.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm, and it has animated examples Like remember a while ago someone did that thing that all these animated gifs showing all the ways to handle scrolling in platformers.
Speaker 1: It's like that but for basically UX animations like real-time versus not real-time and the way is to separate elements and it's really really intuitive and really well put together.
Speaker 1: This should be your Bible if you design user experiences that involve motion.
Speaker 0: So we're doing our episode today about the beach.
Speaker 0: Yeah, my thing of the day is someone very excited to go in the water.
Speaker 0: Oh, it's very appropriate.
Speaker 1: This individual is exactly excited sadly.
Speaker 0: There's a link.
Speaker 0: is a link to Facebook.
Speaker 0: I couldn't find the link anywhere else, but I also didn't put that much effort into it.
Speaker 0: So if you send us a non Facebook link to the same clip in the next hour, so we can we can replace the Facebook link.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: This is real good.
Speaker 0: It should be publicly visible.
Speaker 0: Even if you don't have a Facebook account I think is it has that like?
Speaker 0: I think people don't realize that is like.
Speaker 0: they say oh never get a Facebook account.
Speaker 0: Well, it's like.
Speaker 0: actually even if you don't make a Facebook account There's a like.
Speaker 0: most stuff on Facebook is just publicly visible If you link to it like even like where they have live streams and stuff Like they were streaming like some sports on there.
Speaker 0: You just could go visit it without an account and watch so whatever.
Speaker 1: But this person is very excited in the meta moment.
Speaker 1: the new geek nights book club book that has not been updated on the website is 2001 is a space odyssey.
Speaker 0: is it written by?
Speaker 0: was Arthur C. Clarke?
Speaker 0: Yeah Yeah, is that right?
Speaker 0: So we don't know anything about Arthur C. Clarke except he was the author of that book and I assume an old white guy.
Speaker 1: so we did an odyssey.
Speaker 1: now We're doing a space odyssey.
Speaker 1: Oh It gives me an idea actually for the third book pages of pain by Troy Denning that that that's that Forgotten realms adjacent planescape book.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna go see the movie in 70 millimeter on Sunday.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna go read about Arthur C.
Speaker 0: Clarke on Wikipedia.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't know that much about him.
Speaker 0: I just know all I know.
Speaker 0: he's is an old white Side-by-side dude, it's an author.
Speaker 0: I literally know nothing else.
Speaker 1: the next invention We're going to perform at will be the penny arcade expo even alive or not West the real one.
Speaker 1: We're gonna be there doing the 40 tabletop games.
Speaker 1: You must play on Monday, September 3rd 10 a.m.
Speaker 0: Seattle time.
Speaker 1: Yeah 10 a.m.
Speaker 1: Ps PDT PST.
Speaker 0: I think it'll be an old time.
Speaker 0: Yeah, whatever time it is specific time, but in New York It'll be 1 o'clock p.m.
Speaker 0: On Monday.
Speaker 1: But the thing we're doing that we've never done before is Pax is going to live stream this panel on one of their three twitch Channels.
Speaker 0: well assuming it works.
Speaker 0: It'll either be working by Monday It'll have like three days to figure it out.
Speaker 0: There was a time but also it's the first panel in the morning.
Speaker 0: So will they have it set up yet in time?
Speaker 1: I mean all I can say is there was a time when I was the deputy manager of the enforcer team that did the live Streaming and the and it was a game.
Speaker 1: They never messed it up.
Speaker 1: I'm assuming they will continue that tradition of quality and You will be able to watch us live on either Pax 2 or Pax 3 and I imagine what will happen is a large number Of people will have no idea who the fuck we are and we'll be commenting who the fuck are they?
Speaker 1: But to give you some perspective When I was moderating the Pax chat in the back in the day when I did this for Pax That was the those.
Speaker 1: that was literally what everyone said about literally everyone on every panel.
Speaker 0: so So I already learned one interesting thing about Arthur C. Clarke.
Speaker 0: All right, so he's born in England.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: He lived there until 1956 and then he moved to Sri Lanka because he was big into scuba diving.
Speaker 0: I did not know that he discovered the ruins and assuming Wikipedia is not lying He discovered the underwater ruins of the ancient Konaswaram temple in Shrinkhoma.
Speaker 1: Tracy's already posting Arthur C. Clarke facts in the chat here.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and then he died 10 years ago Well in March of 2008 and he was 90.
Speaker 0: So if he was alive today, he'd be a hundred.
Speaker 0: All right Pretty good run.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so This how to not suck if that seems like a weird title.
Speaker 1: we this was a series We started in geek nights many many years ago like 2006 was when we were doing this.
Speaker 1: 2007 2005 maybe even yeah.
Speaker 1: But we did up like 2006 was like the peak of doing these.
Speaker 1: so the idea was We wanted to have geek guys have a little mini-series like how to not suck at things was one of the series.
Speaker 1: So I'm gonna bring it back because that's an easy way to make Thursday episodes And the idea is to give our own direct advice on how to not suck it.
Speaker 1: not necessarily how to be good at something Not necessarily useful skills, but if you're going to interact with the thing we talk about We've done such episodes as how to not suck at life how to not suck at driving how to not suck at taking your turn.
Speaker 1: I don't suck at settlers of Catan.
Speaker 1: So we're going to talk about how to not suck at the beach as in that place with water and sand.
Speaker 0: It's definitely beach season right now not this weekend, but next weekend I'll probably going to a beach assuming the weather cooperates.
Speaker 1: yep And as you might know if you listen to geek nights We are big fans of beaches.
Speaker 0: if I had so much money didn't have to work I'd probably live on a beach.
Speaker 1: yeah But out of scope for this episode is advice on how to not suck at going to the beach When that is used in the context of quitting your job because you're rich Because the.
Speaker 1: that advice is if you have enough money to go to the beach you should go to the beach.
Speaker 0: Yes That's it.
Speaker 1: That's the full advice right?
Speaker 0: so no you're a normal person.
Speaker 0: It's summer You don't have to go to work today.
Speaker 0: The weather's good right.
Speaker 0: you're going to go to the beach.
Speaker 0: first thing you got to do How to choose the right fucking beach.
Speaker 1: there's different kinds of beaches.
Speaker 1: so if you live in part We're going to mostly talk about America because that's where the most big beach experience.
Speaker 1: But we will talk about some other beaches in America.
Speaker 1: They're basically three kinds of beaches.
Speaker 1: There's well four there.
Speaker 1: the three main ones are beach that has normal sand and is only slightly polluted beach that has Abnormal sand and or rocks and sucks and they very small number of Very nice beaches yeah that have sent normal sand right.
Speaker 0: so you got to make sure that a you're allowed to access the beach.
Speaker 0: There are beaches that are public, but there are also beaches that are public But like technically only open to townies for example in Fairfield, Connecticut, right?
Speaker 0: There's a beach on Long Island Sound and it's open to the public.
Speaker 0: you can just go there But you can't park.
Speaker 0: the only way to get there is with a car unless you live super close right because it's a suburb.
Speaker 0: The only way to get there with a car.
Speaker 0: you got to park somewhere And you can't park there unless you got a sticker from the town or some shit like that.
Speaker 0: right because they want to keep out People from other towns and people who can't afford to live in Fairfield.
Speaker 1: There's a lot of classism Around America, and there's weird weird old laws about beaches, too.
Speaker 0: So whenever beach you want to go to the first thing you got to do is make sure it's a beach that you have some Way to get to without.
Speaker 0: and you know sometimes they might try to charge you money Or some other bullshit.
Speaker 1: figure out if you have to pay or not.
Speaker 1: like there are beaches that are Excess, but those signs are illegal.
Speaker 0: right.
Speaker 0: there's beaches where there's like in California.
Speaker 0: I know that there's public beaches But you to physically get to the public beach you would have to go through the private property of a rich person.
Speaker 0: But according to the law you there is.
Speaker 0: there must be a path for people to do so.
Speaker 0: But the rich people block off those paths so you could get there with a boat.
Speaker 0: The rich people might try to harass you.
Speaker 0: you got to fight with them.
Speaker 1: my favorite thing is Activist hanging out on a beach that they got to buy a boat and pissing off some rich person who probably shouldn't be allowed.
Speaker 0: Or like busting open a path where they're legally supposed to be one in hopes that You know because they're willing to go and fight the rich person.
Speaker 1: well like even even places like Wildwood like actually I would.
Speaker 1: In my experience North Wildwood, New Jersey for all of the problems of that area has one of the best Actually public no problems getting to it.
Speaker 1: beaches in the East Coast.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if you got a car It's a fantastic markings a little tough But you can just park and you can park in the town doesn't matter where you from.
Speaker 0: you could drive there from California and park there.
Speaker 1: you can park for free legally on the street close enough to walk to that Beach if the spot open.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but the laws they've passed.
Speaker 1: There's still classes laws there.
Speaker 1: the law is there's like a $500 fine.
Speaker 1: You don't see a lot of not white people there If you change your clothes in any public bathroom.
Speaker 1: They want you to have to live there or pay for a hotel to have a place to change into your swimsuit.
Speaker 1: Yep, like literally the only reason that law exists is to harass poor people who want to enjoy the beach But don't want to spend the night in an expensive hotel.
Speaker 0: I mean the rule.
Speaker 0: the law is that you can't change into your bathing suit in the bathroom change in your car Yeah, or wear a bathing suit in the car when you go home.
Speaker 0: You know get in your car wrap a towel around you.
Speaker 1: I saw I've seen people do this.
Speaker 1: The pro move is the family brings.
Speaker 1: you have four family members stand in a square holding up a big beach towel and you take Turns everyone else changing in that temporary area.
Speaker 1: Because another things a lot of beaches do is they ban tents because people might use tents to change their clothes?
Speaker 1: Yep, that's the primary reason they ban tents.
Speaker 0: so you got to find a beach that you can go to.
Speaker 0: now now that you've Figured out the beaches that are in range that you can go to go online and you will find there's actually a surprising amount of real somewhat real-time information about the beach such as Water temperature how much bacteria is in the water how what the waves and the tides are gonna be Where the beach is open.
Speaker 0: are the lifeguards gonna be there?
Speaker 0: all this info is available online For just about any beach that has enough people visiting it.
Speaker 0: Right and you got to check it out because you want to go get some warm water.
Speaker 0: You wanna go into frigid cold ass polar bear water, right?
Speaker 0: And if you don't know anything about the beach water clothes because of some bacterial growth or some shit You don't want to go there.
Speaker 1: Like if you don't know say if like it's summer, it's summer and you might just assume Oh, it's summer so I can go to the beach but water temperature changes on a different schedule from the regular seasons.
Speaker 1: So if you try to swim in June, the water is gonna be freezing.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if you try to swim in August, it's gonna be warm.
Speaker 1: if you try to swim in like October It'll actually still be kind of warm September.
Speaker 0: it's still kind of warm in the water a little bit but get because the specific heat of water is real high Obviously slow and cools down.
Speaker 1: obviously shift those months if you live like in Australia.
Speaker 0: Yeah, flip to the six months plus, you know, yeah on the bottom of the earth.
Speaker 1: So the fourth kind of Beach Lake.
Speaker 1: beaches are garbage unless they're on the Great Lakes.
Speaker 1: That's really all there is to say.
Speaker 0: Well, I mean so the thing with a lake right?
Speaker 1: Beaches they have they have an area of scum and then it really depends.
Speaker 1: There's land there's scum There's the shitty little lake.
Speaker 0: it varies a lot.
Speaker 0: Actually when I was growing up the town lake was it's like it sort of just got worse over time.
Speaker 0: It started out kind of great cuz like.
Speaker 0: actually fresh water does not moving a whole lot, you know But it's also not.
Speaker 0: a pool has a lot of advantages over ocean depending on what you want to do there.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it'll smell weird.
Speaker 1: It'll be slimy.
Speaker 0: That's the thing is that when I was very young like elementary school Right the lake beach in the town had a very large area you could swim in.
Speaker 0: it had a lifeguard there.
Speaker 0: We would.
Speaker 0: there would be tons of people there.
Speaker 0: We'd be doing awesome shit in the sand.
Speaker 0: Someone made like a huge sand sculpture.
Speaker 0: I remember one time was a big alligator.
Speaker 0: Yeah Right and everyone had a super blast there.
Speaker 0: and then like five six years went by by the time I was in middle school like late Middle school the the area you were allowed to swim had gotten much smaller.
Speaker 0: No one was going there.
Speaker 0: the lake was like covered in like a sheet of green algaes.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right It's like though if they had you know Whatever caused that probably some pollution in some other environmental not goodness.
Speaker 0: Right that lake beach could have maintained its awesomeness and it didn't you know?
Speaker 0: fresh water needs to be you know Well taken care of to be good.
Speaker 0: You can also do things in the fresh water like take a little rowboat out and do some fishing.
Speaker 0: You can't do it a you know, you you go to ocean.
Speaker 0: You gotta do different kind of fishing, right?
Speaker 0: You're not gonna get away with a little rowboat.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: So, you know, you got it, you know Yeah, but I have their merits the ocean and also the the lake Yeah, but ocean beaches can also be mad gross doing all that.
Speaker 1: that is true.
Speaker 1: But I guess ocean beaches and Great Lakes beaches have a primary advantage that no lake no normal baby-ass lake could ever have Waves.
Speaker 0: well, you some people don't want to wave.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I want to wave.
Speaker 0: I know you want to wave, you know, but the thing is if you want surfing you gotta have gotta have way Body surfing.
Speaker 0: If you're surfing there's like tons of apps and websites that give you super surfing information.
Speaker 1: There's also way more surfing beaches than you might think.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah There's people who are like actually down in Rockaway like that area.
Speaker 0: There's like super crazy surf people.
Speaker 0: They'll surf any time of year if the app says it's a good surf day, even if it's super cold.
Speaker 1: Yep, but if you don't know the body temperature stuff like look it up.
Speaker 1: I'm not gonna try to explain all the temperatures here, but as a general rule of thumb 65 degrees Fahrenheit water temperature is The minimum that most people would stay in the water for more than like a minute.
Speaker 1: Yeah 70 is where people tend to be comfortable.
Speaker 1: I I'm okay I'll take 60 though Like I'll swim in 60 But it hurts after a while because I'm skinny.
Speaker 1: my ankles hurt a lot if I swim in water like that.
Speaker 0: You see if I feel myself shivering I get out.
Speaker 1: Yeah any body of water Some of our friends who have a little more padding were are Shockingly capable of staying in water.
Speaker 1: that would kill me for a long period of time.
Speaker 0: Yeah, as I have seen them do out of pure spite I mean that just happens and even if you go in a pool, that's the heated pool or tub.
Speaker 0: It's like even if the waters, you know, if the water is less than 98.6 degrees, you're cooling off your body You're gonna.
Speaker 0: if you stay in there too long, you'll get hypothermia.
Speaker 1: All right, so we'll get back to the water.
Speaker 1: But let's talk about what you got to bring.
Speaker 1: if you're going to a beach I gotta bring a towel of some kind to lay on.
Speaker 1: Yep, because laying on a beach is one of the primary pleasures of a beach.
Speaker 0: I've actually got a. now what I've got is I've sort of upgraded.
Speaker 0: this is not a necessary upgrade.
Speaker 0: It's basically this giant mat.
Speaker 0: It's it's basically like a bunch of plastic straws.
Speaker 1: The only flaw is I think I'm gonna get one made out of bamboo instead of plastic.
Speaker 0: No, I mean, I just bought the highest rated cheapest one and it you know It totally rolls up super small it unfolds super big, but you don't lay directly on those things.
Speaker 0: No, it's not put a towel on top of that thing.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's not that comfortable if you lay directly on it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but yeah You want to you don't want to lay directly on the sand because then you get scratched up and it's not so comfy and also Sand gets crazy hot in the Sun even though it's brightly color.
Speaker 1: rule number two bring Sandals.
Speaker 1: do not assume you can just walk barefoot on the beach.
Speaker 0: a lot of times Legit hurt yourself.
Speaker 1: it can get hotter than you think something that can happen to you.
Speaker 0: A lot is like you'll get to the beach early in the morning and the sand isn't hot yet Yeah, and you walk on the sand like a nice cool sand Ah, and then you lay out you lay down you go in the water you do some stuff and then you start to walk back And now the sand is hot and you burnt.
Speaker 0: you literally could burn your feet and get blisters on your feet from the hotness Of the sand like burn yourself in a legit way, right?
Speaker 0: Like oh my god, I might.
Speaker 0: you could even burn yourself so bad.
Speaker 0: You have to go to the hospital Yep, so make sure you protect your feet somehow from burning sand.
Speaker 1: if you ever think Maybe you can get away with just wearing your shoes and you'll be careful and you won't get sand in them.
Speaker 1: You know get sand in them.
Speaker 0: Even if you just go near the beach you're gonna get sand.
Speaker 0: You're gonna get sand.
Speaker 0: you want a sand everywhere something like that where the sand can just be knocked off or some.
Speaker 0: You know something you can wash off.
Speaker 1: I don't think you're gonna wash off your Jordans Yeah, so in terms of the beach towel do not buy a traditional like cotton beach towel.
Speaker 1: The pro move is to buy a Turkish towel and regular beach towels.
Speaker 0: good now.
Speaker 1: They're too bulky.
Speaker 0: Yeah big.
Speaker 0: the bulkiness makes it easier to dry yourself off because they can hold more water you don't and they're more comfortable to lay on.
Speaker 1: My other rule is towels at the beach are never for drying yourself off.
Speaker 0: They're only for laying on They're also for drying off.
Speaker 1: Why would you ever dry yourself off?
Speaker 1: Just stand there.
Speaker 0: Sometimes it doesn't work.
Speaker 1: Well, yeah, if it's really if it's too cold to be at the beach also, it's not necessarily drying yourself off from the ocean.
Speaker 0: It's after you get out of the ocean You could take a little shower to wash off all the sand and then you want to dry.
Speaker 1: see, you know Yeah, I mean then you can use the thing you laid on the beach with because you can shake all the sand out then dry Yourself off with.
Speaker 1: I'm just saying it's useful to have a towel for dry If you're gonna be there a long time.
Speaker 1: the beach umbrella is actually pretty key.
Speaker 1: Do not buy a cheap one.
Speaker 0: Well, I bought a cheap one and the cheap one has a hard time staying in the ground, you know But it still works.
Speaker 0: The thing is because I had a hard stain staying in the ground.
Speaker 0: I went and I bought an anchor which is actually super fan anchors.
Speaker 0: It's a big plastic screw and then you can basically shove any umbrella in the top of it And that will keep the umbrella from flying away.
Speaker 0: So but if you buy a fancy umbrella, it will have a built-in super anchor like that.
Speaker 0: So, you know You just need some kind of umbrella that's actually strong enough that it won't fly away and is actually large enough and will block the sun.
Speaker 0: You got to position it just right.
Speaker 0: you might have to some of the umbrellas Actually can move and change the position throughout the day which is good because you're gonna stay at the beach all day.
Speaker 0: Why are you going if you're only going for five minutes?
Speaker 0: you go to the beach early the morning and you stay there as long As you possibly can.
Speaker 1: that's really those important advice.
Speaker 1: if you're gonna go to the beach make it a whole day thing.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you go as early as you can you stay as long as you can.
Speaker 0: the sun's gonna move.
Speaker 0: You got to move the umbrella to stay in the shades.
Speaker 0: You don't burn.
Speaker 1: It always weirded me out like especially in Wildwood.
Speaker 1: We would be leaving the beach as a lot of people were arriving at the beach.
Speaker 1: Yep, like they wasted their whole day.
Speaker 1: They're gonna spend the worst part of the day on the beach and they're missing like the good parts.
Speaker 0: Yeah, also, you got to look at the hours for the lifeguards too because you know, you don't want to drown.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so let's talk about.
Speaker 0: even if you know how to swim and you're good at swimming It's not the greatest idea to go at least in an ocean With no lifeguard.
Speaker 1: So one thing that annoys me is that American beaches have gotten increasingly paranoid about safety And they don't let you swim out far enough anymore.
Speaker 0: Like anywhere The lifeguards these days are jerky and will will definitely err on the side of caution.
Speaker 1: Like the same beach ten years ago I would swim way out and like it was awesome and nowadays I get even ten feet out and they're like tweet tweet Yep, bring it in Yep.
Speaker 1: So the pro move there is to go with a bunch of people and swim before the lifeguards come because you have enough people To be able to deal with a situation that might occur.
Speaker 0: Plenty of people drowned when they were with a bunch of friends.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but it's usually because.
Speaker 1: usually that happens because some beaches are more prone to that or not.
Speaker 0: And this is again A good idea is make friends with someone who is a real lifeguard and then you won't be afraid to just go in an unlived.
Speaker 1: But two things one if you don't know how to swim do not go into the water unless there's a lifeguard.
Speaker 1: No kidding.
Speaker 1: Two Read about the beach.
Speaker 1: Some beaches are very prone to riptides.
Speaker 1: Some beaches are not prone to riptides.
Speaker 1: Some beaches have dangers you might not know about like on like Submerged rocks or sandbars like you got to know this stuff or a lifeguard will just yell at you and make sure you don't engage With those situations.
Speaker 0: even if you're dainty you're willing to swim with no lifeguard.
Speaker 0: I am and I have much of my life and if there are signs that say like this is a no swimming area There's a reason.
Speaker 0: don't swim in that area.
Speaker 0: swim in the place that usually would have a lifeguard.
Speaker 0: That's a swimming area.
Speaker 1: Yep, so when Scott was dumber like not that long ago.
Speaker 1: He didn't believe in riptides.
Speaker 0: I didn't believe that a riptide was me.
Speaker 0: drag me someone who knows how to swim like me out into the ocean.
Speaker 0: you just swim Sideways and you escape.
Speaker 1: so riptides are dangerous.
Speaker 0: I didn't say they didn't exist.
Speaker 0: I said they weren't gonna say they didn't exist To see.
Speaker 1: you would argue at length that there's no way a riptide on any beach could pull you out to see.
Speaker 0: that's what I Said.
Speaker 0: it's not gonna pull me out to see.
Speaker 0: I know how to say good not that doesn't matter.
Speaker 0: I could swim sideways that doesn't matter.
Speaker 0: in some places if I can't if I'm trying to go towards the beat the sand and I Feel that the water is not letting me do so I'll just swim sideways until I could get to this.
Speaker 1: there are Depending on the conditions of certain beaches there are riptides.
Speaker 1: They'll be so wide that they will carry you out to seed to see no matter how fast you swim sideways.
Speaker 0: Oh, then I will go to a boat.
Speaker 1: There will not be a boat.
Speaker 1: You'll just die.
Speaker 0: Someone will see that I'm doing.
Speaker 1: that means but it shocks me How many people swim at beaches and don't know how to deal with riptides because generally unless you're at a beach that has specific Specific problems like some beaches will have legit crazy dangerous riptides.
Speaker 0: This is also info you can check online in advance.
Speaker 1: - yeah But if you're caught in a riptide Meaning the water is like pulling you out to sea and you can't.
Speaker 0: you're trying to go back to land.
Speaker 0: But no you're going out to sea even though you're swimming towards the land.
Speaker 1: It's real simple Do not try to swim back to the beach.
Speaker 1: You will literally die if you do that, right?
Speaker 0: You basically just exhaust yourself and then you won't even be able to stay afloat and you'll drown swim Perpendicular to the beach in any direction until you feel the riptide in parallel to the beach.
Speaker 1: Yes parallel to the beach Sideways until the the current pulling you away from the beach.
Speaker 1: lessons then turn toward the beach.
Speaker 1: Yes And if you can signal for help the other thing that people because if
Speaker 0: you can just signal for help someone can like throw you The ring and you can grab and let us pull you or
Speaker 1: they'll at least keep track of where you're being pulled out to see So they can send someone to go rescue you.
Speaker 0: Coolest thing about swimming in beaches in Australia They'll give like a lifeguard of like a lifeguard with a floaty and a rope will go swim out to get you and then the life Guard on the land will hold on to the other end of the rope.
Speaker 0: The lifeguard will grab you and then the lifeguard on the land will pull the rope to pull you both back to the sea.
Speaker 1: I've spent a lot of time swimming at Manly and Bondi beaches in Australia and the coolest thing about Australian beaches other than the fact That they're literally perfect in every possible way Good God, is that the lifeguards will let you do whatever the fuck you want.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you could swim all the way out of the ocean and they'll just know like oh, yeah He's out there and they kind of keep an eye on you and then some you know fish creature comes and kills you.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but they'll deal with it.
Speaker 1: Like they'll save you.
Speaker 1: They'll try.
Speaker 1: Well nowadays they do these cool things.
Speaker 1: Well, they'll send a drone out to like drop a life preserver.
Speaker 1: Ooh Yeah, or they'll like they'll do like they will yell at you if you're doing something.
Speaker 1: that's really really dumb But they give you way more rope than American lifeguards.
Speaker 1: well, and I really appreciate that the other thing I appreciated was that I really like waves and Like at Manly Beach that like six-foot waves were just coming in constantly.
Speaker 0: Yeah the kind you see like it's.
Speaker 0: it's weird because my whole life you would watch like TV or you know watch cartoons and people Surfing in cartoons.
Speaker 0: you see these waves that looked like cartoon waves like, you know Never experienced that in my life in America Except like once a big wave can go into a lot of beaches my whole life and I never saw a wave like that.
Speaker 0: I thought that they were made up cartoon waves.
Speaker 0: It's like no those cartoon names exist.
Speaker 0: Just not in Anywhere in Northeast United States.
Speaker 1: So if you don't like waves, that's fine.
Speaker 1: But if you do, I'd highly recommend even if the waves seem small to learn how to like the techniques to deal with waves because if you're swimming like you didn't like a Wave hits you and you don't ride it the right way.
Speaker 1: It doesn't matter.
Speaker 1: It's just like, okay Whatever if a big wave comes you could have a mouthful of disgusting salt.
Speaker 1: Yeah You could be slammed into the sand under the water.
Speaker 1: The wave could like knock you over and hurt you and the rules are pretty simple when the wave is coming You have to decide are you going to go under it or are you going to ride it?
Speaker 1: Any other thing you could do carries significant risk.
Speaker 0: if the wave is big and you don't know what you're doing You could jump you can go under you can let it push you.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know you can just go with it.
Speaker 0: There's a lot of things you can do, but if you are standing firm and it smacks you that's the bad news.
Speaker 1: But also if the wave is big like for example thing I like to do when a wave comes in is to jump into it and ride it like on my chest up through the crest Pop out the top and then land on the other side of it in the water.
Speaker 1: If you do that to a large wave and you do not have excellent form It's just gonna fucking throw you down and it'll hurt like hell Depends how deep you are out there.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there's a sandbar maybe or it'll it'll like throw you into the top of the water.
Speaker 1: But the guaranteed way to get through any big wave no matter how big it is is as it's coming you dive You like push yourself forward Dive into it as it's cresting over you go down and ride under the bottom and come out the top behind it.
Speaker 0: So you learn about tides but being on the beach You don't have to learn nearly as much about tides you do.
Speaker 1: All you got to know is how.
Speaker 1: where is the high tide line?
Speaker 0: and put your towels and all your stuff Beyond that line right because if it's low tide when you get to the beach That means there's a lot more sand and a lot less water And so it's gonna be a lot less sand later in the day, right?
Speaker 0: This the water is gonna come up and they'll be.
Speaker 0: the beach size will decrease and if you put your stuff too close to the Water that will come up and make all your stuff wet.
Speaker 0: So and it will come faster than you realize like it might surprise you and tides do not line up two days.
Speaker 1: No, it's not like at four change.
Speaker 0: It doesn't change just like once a day changes a few times a day Yep, so make sure you when you get to the beach just put it doesn't matter.
Speaker 0: You know people are like so interesting like picking a good spot at the beach.
Speaker 0: It's like no just put your shit pretty much anywhere as long as it's far enough away from the water that it won't get wet But close enough to the water that you don't have to walk super far to get to the freaking water.
Speaker 1: So put on sunscreen.
Speaker 1: I do not care if you think you put on sunscreen.
Speaker 0: I don't care if you believe sunscreen will give you cancer.
Speaker 0: guess what the Sun will also give.
Speaker 1: you can't put on more sunscreen than you think you need and put it on more more times Than you think you need.
Speaker 0: I guess the recommendation they say is like if you get in the water and get out put it back On every few hours put it back.
Speaker 0: That's like the official recommendation I actually personally have had.
Speaker 0: as long as I cover every part of my body that's exposed to the Sun With one really good fit, you know heavy application.
Speaker 0: I've never been burned.
Speaker 0: I only get burned when I forget a spot or miss a spot.
Speaker 0: But if I go to a beach if I go in the water, I'll put it on again.
Speaker 0: Also, what I'll do is to avoid having to save up money on sunscreen.
Speaker 0: When I get out of the water, I put on a shirt and get into the umbrella.
Speaker 1: Yep, so bring with you a shirt that blocks UV.
Speaker 1: cuz not all shirts do yep.
Speaker 1: And also bring an umbrella like we said because actually one of my favorite things to do on the beach I only do this if I got there via car or I'm staying in a place that's near the beach like overnight is the beach chair.
Speaker 1: So I'll lay in the Sun for a while But most of my day will be me sitting in the chair under the umbrella reading a book and just enjoying the ambiance of the beach.
Speaker 1: God, that's the one thing I can't really do it Sandy Hook that I would do in Wildwood.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know food on the beach is always a thing.
Speaker 0: So a lot of beaches will have a place where you can buy food and that is the best option Even though it costs money because now you don't have to carry shit Yep.
Speaker 0: But if you have a car or the beach is super close to your house or super convenient or whatever and the beach allows it You can get some grilling going on there.
Speaker 1: bring that cooler.
Speaker 0: bring a cooler full of good stuff, you know.
Speaker 0: It's usually easier to do when you got more people, you know, you know, just think about it.
Speaker 0: And yeah, you know don't do anything to dirty up the beach.
Speaker 0: If you leave any litter on the beach, you must die.
Speaker 1: Yep, if you smoke on the beach, I hate you as a person.
Speaker 0: you must die.
Speaker 1: Uh, don't play music.
Speaker 1: That's annoying.
Speaker 1: Usually some beaches that's okay, but most beaches that's not okay.
Speaker 0: A lot of minor stuff.
Speaker 0: if your towel gets all sandy you want to shake it out.
Speaker 0: Okay, good You're gonna want a sandy towel.
Speaker 0: watch the wind.
Speaker 0: don't blow that sand on someone else.
Speaker 0: Yeah jerk face What else you know, you play some music at the beach with your Bluetooth speaker, that's cool.
Speaker 0: playing it too loud and not just me not cool.
Speaker 1: So the main things I like to do at the beach the things that the highest quality activities in order are throwing a frisbee Cool throwing a frisbee being having it, you know bumping to other people not cool.
Speaker 1: Yep In order of my enjoyment.
Speaker 1: So therefore this is the order of things you do.
Speaker 1: swimming is the best thing to do at the beach because it's the most exclusive to the beach.
Speaker 1: laying in the sand Laying on a towel enjoying the Sun Sitting and reading and making fucking sand castles if you have the skills to make a sand castle If you don't just make bad sand castles, I've made a lot of bad sand castles.
Speaker 0: I've only made bad sand castles.
Speaker 1: But I feel like sand castles are the thing that are most likely to cause me to get a sunburn.
Speaker 0: I've come to the conclusion like I see, you know sand castles are one of those things.
Speaker 0: when I see people make them It's like it looks like the sand when I see like the really fancy professional ones.
Speaker 0: Right the sand that they're using looks nothing like the sand I see on a New York That one year we made a shit ton of sand castles in a while.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they're shitty.
Speaker 0: I'm pretty sure that the people who make the best sand castles are doing it at these beaches Where the sand is different and thus easier to make a sand castle.
Speaker 0: and the ones like we get this.
Speaker 0: you get the sand Wet up in New Jersey or whatever and it's like it's all wet and super dark and you sculpt it or whatever But then it gets all dry and crumbles apart, right?
Speaker 0: I see people making a fancy sand castle.
Speaker 0: They're saying looks dry like it's brightly colored.
Speaker 0: It's not dark yet It's staying together in like a really awesome shape and that's a different.
Speaker 0: it must be a different sand At least I'm.
Speaker 0: I believe it's different sand they've got And there must be certain beaches that are really good for sand castle.
Speaker 0: that I haven't been to.
Speaker 1: so someone asked What about kite flying?
Speaker 1: so kite flying is banned in a lot of beaches because it is dangerous to the other people on the Beach, right?
Speaker 0: I mean if you're really good at kite flying it won't be dangerous.
Speaker 0: There's a lot of incidents or people are really shitty at kite flying and the kite comes and swoops down.
Speaker 0: if I can like stab Someone.
Speaker 1: well, you saw that happens.
Speaker 1: We just got impaled by a umbrella that got away, right?
Speaker 0: You can get impaled by a kite too.
Speaker 0: If you do want to fly a kite at the beach Usually that's the thing that's off season, right?
Speaker 0: Well, it's a thing you can do offseason and it's a thing you can do super early or super late when people are not.
Speaker 0: You know, the lifeguards aren't there but the beach you're allowed to go on to the sand.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's the time for kite flying.
Speaker 0: as soon as people are beaching and the lifeguards show up You got to reel that kite in.
Speaker 1: so I am also a fan of the beach sports.
Speaker 1: Like I like to play beach volleyball.
Speaker 1: Unfortunately, most of our friends we would go to beaches with are not into.
Speaker 1: we're not into that when we would go.
Speaker 0: So I'll say you don't need to go to a beach to play beach volleyball.
Speaker 1: There's beach volleyball courts Yeah, but I'm not into it enough to seek it out on its own.
Speaker 1: It's the kind of thing I like to.
Speaker 1: it's like an Activity I like to add to the beach because there's a big difference because it's hard to find a beach It's got that shit pre-installed.
Speaker 1: Well more importantly nowadays when we go to the beach because we're busy we tend to go for like a day trip and that's it.
Speaker 1: The day trip to the beach is a very different experience from the.
Speaker 1: you are at a beach for a week.
Speaker 1: the longer you're going to be at the beach the more Adjacent activities you bring to the beach.
Speaker 1: Like I'll read a whole book as opposed to reading my phone and then just laying there.
Speaker 0: I've seen a lot of new and interesting takes on like beach sports.
Speaker 0: Like there's that one where there's like a. there's like basically a mini trampoline, but you don't jump on it You like trampoline you throw a thing at it.
Speaker 0: I think we must have might have even done this as a thing of the day once like, you know these weird.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah You're talking about.
Speaker 0: isn't there one where like you've got bowlers where it's like it's like two wooden balls on a rope and then There's like these sticks and you try to throw it to get it to wrap around the sticks.
Speaker 0: Yeah It's like there's all these.
Speaker 1: really horseshoes is a good beach thing.
Speaker 0: I like playing horseshoes at the beach Yeah, but there's lots of new and interesting different ones.
Speaker 0: Oh, what's the one where it's like all kinds like Viking bowling or something?
Speaker 0: What's that one?
Speaker 1: Oh, I saw someone talking about.
Speaker 1: that seems really hipstery, right?
Speaker 0: There's basically all these like outdoor sports and some of them you can't do like.
Speaker 0: you can't really pray croquet on the beach But some of them are beachable right, you know You can.
Speaker 0: if you smooth out an area you can do bocce on the beach sort of yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah, Frisbee I am a big fan of the boogie board, but I actually can't surf at all.
Speaker 1: So I don't really can't surf.
Speaker 0: I want to seem safer than skiing.
Speaker 1: if I ever leave America like if I'd flee Politics and go to Australia or something I feel like I'd take up surfing.
Speaker 1: but I'm not gonna take up surfing here because I wouldn't be able to do it often enough to get good.
Speaker 0: You could do it often enough people.
Speaker 0: I know that.
Speaker 1: I know that I wouldn't because I'd have to like go to the beach every day Like I have to skate like they're beaching and going in the freezing cold and they they want to serve so bad.
Speaker 0: That's what I do.
Speaker 1: but like Sky already have enough sports where I have to like make it a central part of the season like skiing and biking like they're a Central part of my season.
Speaker 1: I'm not gonna add another sport that requires that level of effort.
Speaker 1: But boogie boards is a low barrier to entry.
Speaker 1: like it does not take long to learn how to use a boogie board or body Surf, so that's the thing I do in the water and that's the main reason why I want waves.
Speaker 1: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Speaker 0: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 1: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays and make comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 0: geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows It's actually recorded at night and the patreon that runs for this particular episode of geek nights, which is August 2nd 2018.
Speaker 1: it gives you a word that I was reusing these recordings or anything we have Craig Oliver, Ellen Joyce, Rebecca Dunne, Heidi McNicholas, Sherwin Ruby, obelisk hanging in the sky J. Bantz, Scootal Only, Roberto Kingsley, Kelly Snyder, Amanda Duchette, Sean Yeager, Matthew Smith, Nicholas Brandau, Mr.
Speaker 1: Strong Stretching, 421 Creations, Chris Reimer, and Thomas Hahn, Sherwin Van Horro, Rory, James David White, Rochelle Montanona, Superboy, Tripwire, Sailor, Vista Donch, like Jojo Joestar, Clinton Walton, Wren from New Zealand, Ryan Perrin, Dropen Lander, Finn, Chris Midgiff, Daniel Redman, Sean Klein, Chris Reimer, and Thomas Hahn.
Speaker 1: He turned to me as if to say, "Hurry boy, he's waiting there for
Speaker 1: you!".
Speaker 1: It's gonna take a lot to drag me away from you.
Speaker 1: There's nothing that a hundred men or more can ever get to blame.
Speaker 1: It's only that it's gonna take some time to do the things we never had.
Speaker 1: To one dog's crowd in the night, I say you're restless, longing for some solitary company.