Speaker 0: It's Wednesday, May 2nd 2018.
Speaker 0: I'm rim.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott again, and this is geek nights.
Speaker 0: tonight We are reviewing Ed Piscor's x-men grand design.
Speaker 1: Let's do this woman It's not woman.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we'd.
Speaker 0: you realize you realize it's warm today.
Speaker 1: Warm today warm yesterday even warmer today.
Speaker 1: Well, I say is the warmest Tied for the warmest May 2nd, dude, it's 89 degrees.
Speaker 0: Of course.
Speaker 1: It is in New York City history.
Speaker 1: It says 85 degrees, but that's fine.
Speaker 0: My watch says 89 or 87 87.
Speaker 0: Yeah, anyway, it is 87 right now.
Speaker 0: The high was 89. according.
Speaker 1: point is I Neglectfully forgot the yesterday.
Speaker 1: I was the first of me.
Speaker 1: Oh outdoor fucking Mm-hmm Weather's just in time.
Speaker 0: it's.
Speaker 0: uh, it was a good day because you know, I started a new job and Yeah, you wonder why we've been busy.
Speaker 0: there's been a lot of life changes in the rim and Scott households, but As you know in my last job, I'd biked to work every day and it was like a seven ish mile ride So like 25 to 28 minutes,
Speaker 1: let me check on the Strava how long the ride was to work today.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so but I'd bike hard and get sweaty and wear shorts and everything and I had it like it.
Speaker 0: in New York There's always this minefield of will your building let you bike even though the law says they have to?
Speaker 0: there's a lot of loopholes in.
Speaker 1: Well, oh, it's not about the it's not always about the building.
Speaker 0: But anyway, yeah, maybe your employer might just suck.
Speaker 1: And anyway, so this morning to the new work, which is seven point two miles It took me 39 minutes from my home on the slow heavy bike.
Speaker 1: No and to get to rims house Okay to get to rims house which is much closer than my house from work took 30 minutes in his 5.3 mile.
Speaker 0: it took me to get home 12 minutes to bike the 3.2 miles to get home.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: That's a real nice bike.
Speaker 0: What's interesting is it takes me years?
Speaker 1: Oh my god That's not as unfairly close.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'm telling you you're cheating.
Speaker 0: Oh even better if we move offices, I'll be here.
Speaker 1: What?
Speaker 1: Oh at 59, yeah Building with the weird.
Speaker 0: Yep, that would mean I think I would literally just bike over the bridge.
Speaker 0: I'm at work if I go to the version of home.
Speaker 0: It'll be like seven minutes tops.
Speaker 1: The difference is when you bike you try to go fast only on the way home.
Speaker 0: I don't want to show up to work all huffing and puffing and sweaty.
Speaker 1: I basically even when I'm biking like on the weekend with the biking group.
Speaker 1: I never huff or puff But not even as if I feel any.
Speaker 0: but like dynamite I'm huffing and puffing in the community if I feel any like difficulty or strain.
Speaker 1: or you know exercise Happening gear down to slow down.
Speaker 0: This is why I took you like two more hours to do the Hudson Valley Well ride.
Speaker 1: they take me more hours.
Speaker 0: It was a long time before you rolled in.
Speaker 0: No, it was.
Speaker 0: I'd already eaten like a full dinner and had a couple beers Mm-hmm But I got huff and puff.
Speaker 0: I bike hard and fast wherever I am unless I have a reason not to you like I'm with other People.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: I like it.
Speaker 0: I still do that thing where I run everywhere if I have a good excuse.
Speaker 0: And I'm doing a thing at work now.
Speaker 0: So I try to not ever use the elevator in the high-rise.
Speaker 1: How what floor is your office?
Speaker 0: So previously?
Speaker 0: I'm previously at rooms job.
Speaker 0: I was on the tenth floor.
Speaker 1: That's a little too high.
Speaker 0: That's fine.
Speaker 0: That's like a five minute walk up.
Speaker 0: Like it wasn't a big deal I used to be a little like out of breath by the time I got to the eighth or ninth floor But now up ten like no big deal.
Speaker 0: I'm just skipping steps is fine We moved up to the 18th floor.
Speaker 0: Let me tell you 18 8 10 18 8 10.
Speaker 1: You know what?
Speaker 0: But it's even worse because the 13th floor is where there's like the unlimited food and coffee and stuff.
Speaker 0: So now I'm going up and I hit 13.
Speaker 0: It's like a fuck it.
Speaker 0: and I go and get like some breakfast that I take the elevator.
Speaker 1: the rest of my previous work was On the seventh floor, right?
Speaker 1: But guess what are the eighth floor?
Speaker 1: I think.
Speaker 1: but anyway, yep My apartment is on the third floor.
Speaker 1: Your apartment is on the third floor right my new work.
Speaker 1: Guess what third floor?
Speaker 1: That's right.
Speaker 1: And whenever I get so weird whenever I get an elevator, I only got to push three.
Speaker 1: I don't got to push no other buttons only threes and ones.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we got to push nothing else.
Speaker 1: no matter where I go I can't forget dude.
Speaker 1: It's either three or one.
Speaker 0: to this fucking day Two jobs ago.
Speaker 0: My company was on a certain floor.
Speaker 0: I will if I'm really tired and not paying attention when I'm going to work anywhere.
Speaker 0: I'll hit that floor number.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I haven't worked at that place in like a decade.
Speaker 1: This is why it's real good to have one of those fancy buildings like the building Microsoft is in where when you go to the Front desk.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah You just tell me what floor you're going.
Speaker 0: or if you're
Speaker 1: an employee you waive your card at this Turnstyle and then an elevator comes with no buttons on it And knows that a person going to floor 12 or whatever has gone through the turnstile and an elevator comes Programmed to go to that floor and no other.
Speaker 0: Oh, it's even better.
Speaker 1: or it's not only secure It is also convenient which is great because usually security, you know Usually means a decrease in convenience.
Speaker 1: that technology of the elevator with no buttons is a dramatic security increase along with a Dramatic convenience increase like any hotel that has that will literally never have the checkout problem at a con again.
Speaker 1: The only problem is People who don't know know if you if you go through the turnstile, right and the elevator comes and you don't get on Are you just trapped.
Speaker 1: you have to go back out and then go back into the turnstile again?
Speaker 1: Yeah, there isn't like a place to waive your bar.
Speaker 0: So a cool thing about the building I'm in now and actually a lot of the buildings here They're double-decker elevators so the elevator stops at two floors at any given time and Algorithms just manage that as the elevator is two cars one on top of each.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, so we can open on floor one and two at the same.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: And then it goes up and it just cleverly tries to multiplex the ride.
Speaker 1: So you might but you might be say in a car stopped while the people above it's rare though It avoids that when it can.
Speaker 1: it might as well open the doors.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so the other thing is and just because the kind of company I work for now They really want people to walk because it's good for you.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: So elevators by default unless you have a special access card that says you have made it like Privately if it basically flags you as some sort of disability or reason why you should be able to pick your floor Elevators only go to odd or even floors.
Speaker 0: So you got to use the stairs Unless you're real lucky and you're on an odd-numbered floor because then you can get to the food floor and your office and theoretically never Have to use the stairs.
Speaker 1: One final thing there's some health insurance companies in the US now giving discounts to people who do enough exercise.
Speaker 1: You know like there's things that you can put in your car that will monitor your car and see that you drive safely Yeah, and give you a discount on your car insurance.
Speaker 1: Yeah They're doing the same thing where it's like where a Fitbit equivalent device and we'll check the data on it as if you're healthy enough.
Speaker 1: We'll give you just kind of hell dude.
Speaker 0: I get a credit because I bike to work sometimes but most of them are Really just like pedometers.
Speaker 1: Yeah people on Amazon are selling devices that will shake your pedometer to give you the health insurance discount without exercising.
Speaker 0: that is Amazing and very American.
Speaker 0: Yes both sides of that conversation.
Speaker 0: But uh, where's that going with that?
Speaker 0: I don't know all we got.
Speaker 1: go to the go to the news All right.
Speaker 0: So in the news, there's actually some pretty interesting news about Hasbro and the Power Rangers.
Speaker 1: right, so right it seems like in the world of the US at least all of the popular culture nerd properties right are being gobbled up by Disney and or Hasbro, which is extra complicated because Did Hasbro already has the rights to.
Speaker 0: I most like Disney princesses like Disney stuff.
Speaker 0: So if Disney gets something has basically has a real has a lacy difference over that.
Speaker 1: well license to like toys Right this version doing license licensing and owning.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like Disney owns fucking Star Wars Right, but they don't make the Star Wars toys.
Speaker 1: Someone else makes.
Speaker 0: well Hasbro makes them.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah Disclosure I own a lot of Hasbro stock.
Speaker 0: I've been buying Hasbro stock for like a decade and I'm continuing to buy it for reasons like this rims.
Speaker 1: Eventually, it's gonna own Hasbro.
Speaker 0: Well, holy but surely, uh, and my current rate of buying when I'm a hundred and thirty years old give or take you'll own like a fraction of a percent.
Speaker 0: I'll own enough to where I could actually Vote in a proxy election and if it was real close You One day so that the Hasbro executives are gonna call ribbon be like, huh?
Speaker 1: Who you thinking of voting for for the board rims?
Speaker 1: a 90 year old man?
Speaker 1: They're all like these 40 year old executive.
Speaker 1: He's like son my save games older than your grandpa.
Speaker 1: Don't try to tell me who to vote for.
Speaker 0: My goal in life is to walk into Hasbro's office vote in one shareholder election and then immediately collapse into a skeleton.
Speaker 1: And they'll make a toy skeleton.
Speaker 0: That's my one vote.
Speaker 0: You got to make it skeleton rim.
Speaker 1: All toys then will just be cyber it constructions.
Speaker 0: anyway Your hands.
Speaker 0: What is this?
Speaker 0: a baby game?
Speaker 1: You'll be going to their virtual executive.
Speaker 1: You have to hack your way in.
Speaker 0: But yeah this there's a lot of things going on here.
Speaker 1: But yeah Hasbro bought the Power Rangers from Saban Saban, however, you pronounce it, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, they didn't license it or any like.
Speaker 1: they now own it the same way they own Watsy and Transformers and My Little Pony.
Speaker 0: they fucking own it Meaning they can make the shows they can.
Speaker 1: so if you want to make a Power Rangers movie You have to buy a license from Hasbro.
Speaker 1: if they want to make Power Rangers and My Little Pony Transformers crossovers guess what they can just fucking do it if they want.
Speaker 1: you can't stop them because they own it all.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they probably will and it's real interesting.
Speaker 0: This is all happening.
Speaker 1: people that they currently licensed to like IDW who makes all the pony Transformers GI Joe comics, I think they also make.
Speaker 1: they might even already make Power Rangers comics.
Speaker 1: I bet who makes the Power Rangers comics, but guess what if the IDW doesn't already?
Speaker 1: they're going too soon.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you can expect any place that you currently see.
Speaker 1: Hasbro stuff the Power Rangers you get in that mix.
Speaker 1: You'll probably go home and you're probably watch My Little Pony on the hub.
Speaker 1: Is that still a network?
Speaker 0: I don't even know.
Speaker 1: I don't even know anymore.
Speaker 0: but Power Rangers Hasbro is down right now because of an unrelated thing because as you all recall Toys R Us is gone bye-bye and It's while it's not gone for any good reason.
Speaker 0: like the reasons why Toys R Us actually went bankrupt are just really fucked up.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but Because the last national toy chain is gone.
Speaker 0: That's really hurting Hasbro's sort of short-term value.
Speaker 1: and the guys market cares about short-term.
Speaker 1: But rim who's gonna be 90 to get his one vote?
Speaker 0: Yeah Short I am not giving investment advice.
Speaker 0: do not construe anything that I'm saying as investment advice.
Speaker 0: I swear to fucking God.
Speaker 0: do not do not talk to me about this, but don't do it done in brim Don't does.
Speaker 0: but I am continuing to buy a lot of Hasbro stock now that it's down.
Speaker 0: just cuz someone does something does not mean They're suggesting that you do that thing cuz I also drink a lot of poison and huff and puff on a bike Sometimes not wearing a helmet.
Speaker 1: So yes, I Don't wear a helmet if I ride a city bike, but on a city bike There's even.
Speaker 0: I already don't feel like the city bike.
Speaker 0: I should be wearing a helmet.
Speaker 1: I or I already don't huff and puff on a road bike on a city bike.
Speaker 1: I even know how do I somehow negative huff city bike.
Speaker 0: I fought and fuck city bike.
Speaker 0: I'm rarely even in that top gear.
Speaker 0: I'm just like putter.
Speaker 0: putter.
Speaker 1: putter Like the city bike is just so heavy and slow.
Speaker 0: That's not a thing.
Speaker 1: I'm not gonna carry a helmet with me.
Speaker 0: not a single drop of sweat is gonna come from my brow on a city bike.
Speaker 0: I'll tell you why I used one the other day.
Speaker 0: cuz yesterday I didn't bring my bike to work and it was so nice I was like fuck it and I took a city bike home.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well, you're close enough.
Speaker 1: Yeah for me it'd be cutting it.
Speaker 1: I could I could do it I could make it all the way to work in one ride without docking but it would be close.
Speaker 1: Cuz I mean I'd lose time because it's a big heavy but even better because I bought the day pass.
Speaker 0: it was 24 hours.
Speaker 0: So later that night.
Speaker 1: Oh, you don't have a permanent thing.
Speaker 0: I used to and I cancel it.
Speaker 0: cuz they doubled the price.
Speaker 0: I might get it back.
Speaker 1: So I paid for it.
Speaker 0: right but I paid for it back.
Speaker 0: It was like a hundred bucks But you know what my new job.
Speaker 1: they pay for it.
Speaker 1: So as soon as it expires, I just renew it for free.
Speaker 0: I'm not gonna get it again cuz They're screening Porco Rosso at Kips Bay.
Speaker 1: Just watched it.
Speaker 0: I haven't watched it in a while.
Speaker 0: Okay so I might go see the fact.
Speaker 1: I gave a computer to George and I left my Porco Rosso DVD in the DVD player and then he's like, oh we watching this and I'm like, oh good Good thing I left it in there.
Speaker 0: He was just asking me.
Speaker 0: He wants all my old computers too.
Speaker 1: Good take them.
Speaker 0: Yeah Start mining those bitcoins or whatever you're gonna do.
Speaker 1: I don't know what you can do with them But please take all of my unused technology.
Speaker 0: So in some other news more of a geek bite Scott I want to review this on geek nights But I gotta get Scott to watch it first.
Speaker 0: Emily I have been watching on Judas recommendation and also the Internet's recommendation because this is one of those things we talked about with judge Anime by its cover.
Speaker 0: I ignore a lot of anime even if I'm positively inclined toward it unless people keep talking about it and People keep talking about made in abyss.
Speaker 0: So I felt like I had to watch it.
Speaker 0: So I watched one episode and it was intriguing enough to watch the rest and I'm almost done with it.
Speaker 0: It's not long.
Speaker 0: It's like 10 or 11 at 13 episodes the season supposedly.
Speaker 0: I haven't seen the end yet, but supposedly it ends in a reasonable place unlike say attack on Titan.
Speaker 0: And what I have to say about it is that if you're an anime fan, it is definitely worth watching.
Speaker 0: I'm really enjoying it.
Speaker 0: I think Scott will really like it.
Speaker 0: It reminds me of the good parts of Jew.
Speaker 1: Oh say if you remember that show I remember there was a show called you.
Speaker 0: Oh, so that was owners like the brothers on the planet with the plants It'll eat you.
Speaker 1: Oh, I thought that was number nine.
Speaker 1: I don't know anymore.
Speaker 0: number six Yeah, I can play.
Speaker 0: I can play it.
Speaker 0: all these shows together because I can't.
Speaker 0: anyway the show is plants to eat people but coupled with Secret of Mana Like a secret of mana's got cute slimies.
Speaker 0: Yeah so imagine a show that is the terrible secret of space which is there's this pit and It no one knows how deep it goes and it's called the abyss.
Speaker 0: And like Dragon Quest everything is like cute Dragon Quest looking characters.
Speaker 0: Everything's set up like an RPG with people like upgrading their equipment and like levels.
Speaker 1: You know what delicious and dungeon is a lot like that.
Speaker 1: only it's about eating the monsters But it's still about going deeper in the dungeon into different.
Speaker 0: but the deal with this show?
Speaker 0: I'm not gonna spoil anything, but here's the real deal.
Speaker 0: This pit is Golgotharoth.
Speaker 0: This might as well just be the prequel to the prince of nothing But it's framed in that there's these kids who live in this town.
Speaker 0: That's on the edge.
Speaker 1: Is it Golgotharoth or is it?
Speaker 1: You know Lord of the Rings.
Speaker 0: It's Golgotharoth.
Speaker 0: Okay, like specifically it's a pit.
Speaker 0: There's like a probably an alien ship buried down there and the story is there's this orphanage and kids in the orphanage Are forced to go down into this pit and bring back artifacts and if they grow up and survive They eventually level up.
Speaker 0: and now they're employees of this thing that goes down deeper into the pit to bring up artifacts and they don't really understand how the artifacts work, but they use them and If you go the further down you go the harder it is to come back up because it starts fucking with you.
Speaker 1: I mean, that's how all holes are now.
Speaker 1: Like can you tell me a hole that is it buddy where that rule is?
Speaker 0: No, we're talking like go down a hundred feet trying to walk back up ten feet.
Speaker 0: You start getting sick.
Speaker 0: walk back up twenty feet.
Speaker 0: You start vomiting.
Speaker 0: walk out fifty feet.
Speaker 0: blood starts coming out of your eyes.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean that might be harder than a normal hole.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the same is true in a normal hole the farther you go down the harder it is to get back up.
Speaker 0: But it's framed in this like very cute JRPG like Secret of Mana looking way.
Speaker 0: It's a Japanese fantasy show Yeah, but unlike a lot of these shows that have nothing going on Really feeling it.
Speaker 0: Okay, really good.
Speaker 0: I've thoroughly enjoyed it.
Speaker 1: It's I just want to watch a Gretzky co.
Speaker 0: but did.
Speaker 0: oh, we're gonna wash the shit out of a Gretzky co.
Speaker 0: It is a plus as well.
Speaker 1: But yeah, you watched any of it.
Speaker 0: I watched one episode.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna watch again with Emily.
Speaker 0: It is a Gretzky co.
Speaker 0: if I had to give the shortest geek fight possible There is a lot more to it than you would have guessed.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: It is a. it's a legit show.
Speaker 0: It isn't just DMC which as much as I loved it DMC is basically just the same joke over and over again.
Speaker 1: The DMC manga is a complete.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but aggressive co Feels like it'll be very simple jokes and it's not.
Speaker 0: it's actually a pretty good character drama.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm But made in abyss is good And way dark.
Speaker 0: like one of the things is these kids?
Speaker 0: Like the environmental storytelling like they find one of the things that they find and no one knows what they are is skeletons.
Speaker 1: Oh, this is why you like this show all around this pit like everywhere people who tried to walk up from 200 feet.
Speaker 1: What if you're just down there like let's say you're a thousand you just stay sure.
Speaker 1: no No, I'm saying you're a thousand feet deep right?
Speaker 1: Oh and just like you jump You just jump in place.
Speaker 1: Do you like?
Speaker 1: Disintegrate from going up a little bit.
Speaker 0: So I don't know because the characters I am following are only in the fourth level.
Speaker 0: now There are four levels down Which is way beyond what normal people do.
Speaker 0: and the people who are allowed to go down there like the black whistles or the white Whistles, they're all fucked up non men.
Speaker 0: now, like they've been fucked up by this stuff Yeah But they'll keep.
Speaker 0: they keep finding just thousands and thousands and thousands of skeletons.
Speaker 0: nice and they're all Buried in the same way.
Speaker 0: They look like they're praying and they're all facing toward the center of the abyss and they're so old.
Speaker 0: No one knows what the deal is.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm It's fun stuck.
Speaker 0: It's this is a good show and there's a reason why everyone's talking about it.
Speaker 0: But anyway things of the day we got a double thing of the day feature.
Speaker 1: well, one of them is a thing of Remix thing of the day and one of them is a just the unoriginal a thing from the olden days that's not remixed at all,
Speaker 0: so I found this because the the the sort of the buried lead here is that all those Psychedelic Awesome shorts from Sesame Street in the back back in the day they're all just on YouTube like all of them and they're amazing.
Speaker 0: and I've been watching them when I'm bored and It's shocking to me how little I remember some of them until I hear that first note and suddenly my brain remembers every single Possible detail of this animation.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: But this one is one that has been stuck in my head for the last 36 years.
Speaker 0: It is the Sesame Street pinball song.
Speaker 0: This is a remix of the Sesame Street pinball song with the animation also remixed and it's pretty great.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean the original song is already great.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so while talking about things that are great This video reminded me of another Sesame Street video.
Speaker 1: So we searched for it and there it was the king of eight.
Speaker 1: He's really great too, but he's not remixed.
Speaker 1: It's just the king of eight official Sesame Street YouTube channel.
Speaker 1: And the king of eight has the same exact vault voice as the Muppet Rolf the piano playing dog, which is Obvious.
Speaker 1: Whoo.
Speaker 1: Take out those hot princesses.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I feel like these Sesame Street shorts were a big foundational part of my life and I'm starting to notice as I'm older that Between like these and things like Donald Duck in math magic land and the anime I watched when I was a little little kid.
Speaker 1: I Like it's.
Speaker 1: you know It's hard not to draw a connection between the aesthetic of these and the aesthetic that I like in artworks today.
Speaker 0: Yep, I do really like late 60s early 70s semi psychedelic stuff.
Speaker 0: Then the minute moment the geek nights book club book remains Homer's the Odyssey.
Speaker 0: Mmm.
Speaker 0: I got a bunch of travel coming up So I'm gonna finish it in the next month or so if not sooner.
Speaker 1: I thought you had finished it and we're waiting for me.
Speaker 0: No, I slide.
Speaker 0: I stopped reading to wait for you to start reading again, but I'm all well on my way.
Speaker 1: I'm probably gonna read, you know, but I'm chillin in the park laying down in the Sun with the grass and such.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna read on trips cuz uh, although the part of the meta moment is that I'm going to be Scottless in Lancaster, Pennsylvania this weekend for Zenkai counter.
Speaker 0: I'm doing three panels Anime openers from around the world which important point.
Speaker 0: This is the last time I'm running this fucking panel.
Speaker 0: Thank God, I've run this so many versions of it so many years and it is not feasible for me to make new versions of it.
Speaker 0: and Because I can't put it on YouTube.
Speaker 0: I'm increasingly unwilling to make content that I can't put on the internet.
Speaker 0: So I'm letting that ship sail.
Speaker 0: This is the final performance of anime openers from around the world.
Speaker 0: I got a couple of little gems.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna share but that's it.
Speaker 0: I'm done Underrated anime.
Speaker 0: you should see the first brand new geek nights anime panel in a long goddamn time.
Speaker 1: It's anime.
Speaker 1: You should see only ones that he just cut the list apart to be different.
Speaker 0: I'm really because I looked.
Speaker 0: every anime panel we've got has bullshit old slide.
Speaker 0: So I'm making this like we make modern panels.
Speaker 0: So I'm making it from scratch and Apocalypse zero is in there.
Speaker 1: No, it's not.
Speaker 1: Nor is it underrated?
Speaker 0: I feel like everyone needs to see it exactly once.
Speaker 0: no when they're an adult No, they know.
Speaker 0: no that is that type of anime is an important Area of anime.
Speaker 0: no and knowing what the fuck it's deal is if you're gonna watch one of those fucked up violent weird ass old Anime, I feel like that's the one.
Speaker 0: no, I mean name in that genre.
Speaker 1: name a better show to watch The educational channel, which is turning TV off and go outside.
Speaker 0: I mean we said people should play pandemic legacy in our 40 tabletop games.
Speaker 0: I don't like that shit.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: pandemic legacy is different than pandemic, which is garbage.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, you don't need to play regular pandemic.
Speaker 1: I haven't played pandemic legacy.
Speaker 0: So, you know, I've heard some people say that it might have some redeeming qualities over regular pandemic That I want to point out that that is the most positive you have ever sounded about pandemic.
Speaker 1: I cannot confirm or deny.
Speaker 0: No, do not watch mad bull 34.
Speaker 0: I think you're better off watching a popular apocalypse zero.
Speaker 0: No Anyway when I'm not doing those three panels I'm either gonna be playing board games in my hotel room or playing board games in the tabletop area.
Speaker 0: And also I'm not gonna be there on Friday because I'm just go to work.
Speaker 1: I Will not be wasting my time going to Lancaster friends.
Speaker 0: I don't know why you're so down on zinc icon.
Speaker 0: It's a great.
Speaker 0: It's basically review con.
Speaker 0: Plus I I do some panels and otherwise it's just review con.
Speaker 1: I mean Lancaster Pennsylvania.
Speaker 0: Yeah with amazing food.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: It's a short train ride on Sunday.
Speaker 1: No, they fix that and at night.
Speaker 0: No, there's food now.
Speaker 1: Uh-huh.
Speaker 0: I talked about this when I reviewed the con last year.
Speaker 0: There's plenty of food now.
Speaker 0: all these non-religious restaurants opened up.
Speaker 0: Apparently the locals are mad about it and apparently only non locals eat at these places Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: There's all these like.
Speaker 0: there are literally restaurants there that basically people who take the Amtrak from New York.
Speaker 0: No one else does okay Which is sad because when I was on the ski trip this year, we ran into the same thing.
Speaker 0: There's this place we eat at which ironically is called the common man And it's got.
Speaker 0: its motif is like I don't know farmer Peasants and it's got like.
Speaker 0: this logo is literally like a peasant pushing some peasant ass thing But the proprietor of this establishment I was talking to him because we were there alone because we were there like in a time when most tourists don't come in to Ski and he was like, yeah, literally no one who lives within a hundred miles of this place will ever eat here.
Speaker 0: Okay, no one can afford to.
Speaker 0: this place exists solely for New Yorkers and mostly New Yorkers who come out here to ski And that's it.
Speaker 0: And that's sustainable business model, apparently.
Speaker 0: So Ed Piscor, right?
Speaker 1: So we talked about him on the show before.
Speaker 0: I think there's awesome posters, right?
Speaker 1: No ed Piscor is the creator of a comic known as hip-hop family tree.
Speaker 1: Family tree is a comic which is in.
Speaker 1: ed Piscor is unique.
Speaker 1: It's he has a unique style yet.
Speaker 1: It is familiar to you feel like you've seen this style before Yet you can't name where you've seen it before.
Speaker 1: But he made a comic called hip-hop family tree, which is the history of the creation of the hip Genre of music in somewhat documentary but also Somewhat definitely document her somewhat not documentary for that is a photograph.
Speaker 0: I'm assuming
Speaker 1: So It was such a mega amazing awesome comic that you should read if you can get your hands on it, which you can just buy it That Marvel the you know, well Disney hired him to make a comic called x-men grand design Which he made joyfully as he is a big-ass x-men nerd a little younger than me, but still a big x-men nerd.
Speaker 1: Yeah, he grew up drawing some x-men as a kid.
Speaker 1: you know, that's how he ended up doing comics.
Speaker 1: and this x-men grand design is Thankfully an x-men comic a normal person can read or at least a normal nerd can read Because it is not involved with any current x-men stuff.
Speaker 1: It is basically Same thing as hip-hop family tree.
Speaker 1: almost you could almost call it x-men family tree.
Speaker 1: It is a retelling, you know of the original x-men story in a new Digestible form yet also an old form right.
Speaker 1: and then at the very end of this first volume There's also a bonus which is basically a redrawing of the first issue of x-men just redrawn But otherwise exactly identical to the first issue of x-men just in his style instead of in the original style.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna say that I really enjoyed it first off.
Speaker 0: What uh, it's definitely.
Speaker 0: It captures a lot of what x-men is really like in condensed form Meaning that the statement I just said is either a strong positive or a strong negative depending on who you are.
Speaker 1: That's all yeah, it's still x-men, right?
Speaker 1: It's not, you know sort of taking the x-men out of x-men.
Speaker 0: It's not read writing anything It's not really changing like plots or back story But what it does do is sort of tie things together.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: because if you actually read the original real x-men comics, right?
Speaker 1: Let's say you get your hands on every fucking x-men comic ever and you freeze time except for everyone but you so you can read them all.
Speaker 1: You know, there are things that happen and some of those things, you know Sort of come out of nowhere.
Speaker 1: They don't have.
Speaker 1: you know it, you know, it's like you get time travel You get characters coming in.
Speaker 1: Yeah And it's like things happened and changed over time because writers would change new series would come up Crossover events would happen with the rest of the Marvel Universe.
Speaker 0: I would read for a while and then I go to a comic shop and literally just buy like Whatever uncanny x-men was there and it would just be like I wouldn't know what was happening.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that'd be retcons and this and that and all you know things would happen.
Speaker 1: But like if you were to say see something happen in x-men issue 200 It's like the things that foreshadow that may have been a non-existent or be only go back a few issues Here, for example, you've got like, you know the sentinel thing which came, you know quite a bit later.
Speaker 1: Yeah, no tied in from the beginning, right?
Speaker 0: They're showing you back to like Xavier finding storm right Farouk and all that like really old ass nonsense, right?
Speaker 1: You've got you know, the Phoenix Force, you know being foreshadowed heavily like oh the feet They're like, hey the Phoenix Force is coming Even though if you actually read the comics is sort of like Phoenix for it's like.
Speaker 0: what's that?
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: Here it is.
Speaker 0: I Remember as a kid when the from the dart in the Phoenix shit happened.
Speaker 0: I remember feeling dumb and thinking wait, I should know if shouldn't I know what this is.
Speaker 0: Did I just like not read this?
Speaker 0: and I didn't like I didn't understand what the deal was.
Speaker 1: Yeah I mean actually bought um, I didn't read the actual Phoenix, you know The famous comic where Sokolov is holding the dead dream girl in the cover.
Speaker 1: Yeah That comic and the couple issues before after it until I was living in Beacon and I bought basically like Marvel Essentials essential x-men volume something that contained all those issues in black and white and it's really only like a few issues.
Speaker 1: It's not like this big mega thing that leads into it.
Speaker 1: Right and it's you know, it's like uncanny x-men from like the 80s Like, you know, it's like it comes way deep in.
Speaker 1: Yeah story Whereas here you've got you know in this retelling that's sort of trying to take all the major Plot points of x-men the you know, the big things that happen right get rid of all those meaningless details and you know Month-to-month garbage that doesn't matter, you know the in between the real issues.
Speaker 1: Just take the big major plot points.
Speaker 0: right x-men are created because X their magneto is here and Xavier Yeah, there's magnetos deal if you want to know like Other than oh he was in the Holocaust and then he has reasons, right?
Speaker 1: It's like basically he you know, well, how did why did professor X already know storm?
Speaker 0: Like what's Jean Grey's deal?
Speaker 0: Where did you really come from?
Speaker 1: Yeah, all this stuff is You know Told without any cruft and it sort of feels a bit hurried because you're only going over these major details
Speaker 0: and it feels somewhat disjointed because literally read a page and it's like Professor X deals with Farouk over the span of like six panels like that entire story.
Speaker 0: the next page is like what was magneto doing?
Speaker 1: Yep, it's like you might not even realize you're like, oh, it's magneto.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I actually took me a couple panels.
Speaker 1: I'm like, all right, that's what's going on And that only it helped that I had all this x-men knowledge.
Speaker 1: if you don't have x-men knowledge at all I can't.
Speaker 1: I don't know if this will be I can't tell.
Speaker 1: this will either be great for you because it'll allow you to get the big picture of What the egg all the major things that happen to the x-men the important parts of the story without the garbage.
Speaker 1: that's hard to understand.
Speaker 1: Honestly, I didn't know or you might not know what the hell is going on because you've never read any x-men before.
Speaker 1: Like who the hell are these people?
Speaker 1: there's no character development No character advanced for the x-men that I had read.
Speaker 0: I never knew who the fuck Namor was.
Speaker 1: Oh, you know Namor I never read those parts.
Speaker 0: I had no idea.
Speaker 1: that's that.
Speaker 1: well see the thing is that's actually a very interesting part of this x-men grand design because Namor the Submariner was.
Speaker 1: you know, he is a mutant.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but that part of you know Establishing why humanity hates mutants it being Namor's fault of sort of making the wrong first impression Was not really in x-men comics.
Speaker 1: That was a Motherfucking comic.
Speaker 1: Namor is way.
Speaker 1: Namor is like one of the original Marvel things from like decades before the x-men.
Speaker 1: He predates the x-men by like a zillion years.
Speaker 1: the fact that he's a mutant.
Speaker 1: I'm pretty sure Came way later.
Speaker 1: This is originally just like the prince or king of Atlantis who is evil.
Speaker 1: This is actually the thing that caused more not really evil but sort of you know Seen as evil by humans, right?
Speaker 0: So when I was younger like middle school elementary school every time I started reading x-men the other kids who read more comics than me would always Like like.
Speaker 0: I wouldn't know about shit like Namor and they all knew.
Speaker 0: and I and it wasn't until much later in my life That I realized there were all like you had to read non x-men comics to understand.
Speaker 1: see I going on.
Speaker 0: I just assumed that they knew and I didn't understand.
Speaker 1: why see I cheat?
Speaker 1: when I was a kid There were only three kinds of comics that I read.
Speaker 1: I read Spider-man, but I read spider-man 2099 because it started at issue one and in 1990 Whatever two three and it was cyberpunk.
Speaker 1: So it was the best I read like still the best.
Speaker 1: if you want to read I highly recommend spider-man 2099.
Speaker 0: I also I read x-force and like later uncanny x-men.
Speaker 1: I also read all that infinity stuff, which is becoming very relevant.
Speaker 1: It's good to have that knowledge today.
Speaker 1: Yeah, even though I'm not watching that movie And three.
Speaker 0: so the best part about that movie is of course like a ton of characters die.
Speaker 0: from what I gather.
Speaker 1: Well in the comic half the superheroes died, but then they undyed.
Speaker 0: so from what?
Speaker 0: Yeah, this is something like I was curious about this.
Speaker 0: it appears that the majority of the people who went to see this movie have mostly just been watching MCU and I Realized if you've never actually read comics and just watch the movies the idea that superheroes die all the time And like that's just a thing is unknown
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 0: So teenagers who have watched every Marvel Cinematic Universe thing and read zero comics are Freaking the fuck out because all their favorite characters are dead.
Speaker 1: They'll be back in the next movie.
Speaker 1: They'll have different actors coming back.
Speaker 1: Those are mostly just to kill off the contracts.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but they literally don't know that like Superman died a hundred times He died the first time he died.
Speaker 1: It was a big deal.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah the first time a super big superhero died It was a big deal and then we learned and knew better.
Speaker 1: But yeah, well anyway Was I saying?
Speaker 1: Right, and I read the Infinity comics and I read x-men comics right now and the way I knew about other things in Marvel anyway.
Speaker 1: Well, I was like collected superhero cards.
Speaker 1: I cards to but Characters were without having to.
Speaker 1: I didn't read any Namor moon Knight or fantastic or con.
Speaker 1: I mean I've read them later.
Speaker 1: But as a kid, I didn't read any of those other comics never read an Avengers comic I never read any of that garbage, but I knew who Iron Man was a new Captain America was.
Speaker 1: I knew what their origins were what their deals were and all this stuff.
Speaker 1: because I read those superhero cards that I collected I collect.
Speaker 1: there was then when they were Like single panel references to these other characters and things.
Speaker 1: and also there was for example one time There was a series right after there was fatal attractions Which is the the crossover between all the different X series which let me learn all the X for.
Speaker 0: yeah I read fatal attractions.
Speaker 1: There was that's the one where Wolverine got all the metal ripped out of him.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right after that cuz then he had the bone right right after that the next there was immediately a second crossover Which is the x-men Avengers like blood ties cross.
Speaker 0: Oh, that is when I stopped reading.
Speaker 1: but I read that and that's how I knew who some Avengers were at that point.
Speaker 1: Right and things like that.
Speaker 0: I never read any Avengers.
Speaker 1: I mean I that's the only Avengers I read was yeah Not even that I just didn't care.
Speaker 1: later on I guess I read Kree's girl war which is include some event.
Speaker 0: part of what messed it up.
Speaker 0: Is that because I got into anime so young?
Speaker 0: I was like trying to read x-men after I'd already discovered anime.
Speaker 0: So as soon as I found as soon as manga was purchasable by me I basically stopped reading American comics for like a decade.
Speaker 1: I Stopped reading the comics when they comic book store went away, and then it got anime.
Speaker 0: Yep, but like I read one manga, and I was like whoa.
Speaker 1: This is a comic Mm-hmm anyway, but yeah if you.
Speaker 1: So this x-men grand design by the way is like a large.
Speaker 1: It's not a. you're gonna get the trade paperback.
Speaker 0: Don't get the trade.
Speaker 0: get this giant ass book.
Speaker 1: That's it well.
Speaker 1: No then this is the trade paperback.
Speaker 1: There's a hardcover is the other one?
Speaker 0: don't get the hardcover.
Speaker 1: So this is a. this is like it's like a Marvel Treasury Edition.
Speaker 1: It's not a normal size trade paperback.
Speaker 1: It's like this big fucking thing and the pages are like not quite newspaper size But they but they feel very newsprint.
Speaker 1: It's bigger than an old-life magazine.
Speaker 0: I'd say oh easily bigger than life magazine.
Speaker 0: It's.
Speaker 1: the point is is big.
Speaker 1: It's not a normal size book.
Speaker 0: I can't actually like get it all in frame here.
Speaker 1: Yeah It's at least it's probably like it's like a legal pad, but whiter almost.
Speaker 0: I had trouble.
Speaker 0: I was reading it in bed, and I wanted to set it down, and it wouldn't fit on the tiny table.
Speaker 1: It's not thick or heavy.
Speaker 1: It's just big.
Speaker 1: it's gonna take up like it's like laptop size Maybe even like 15.
Speaker 0: this is way bigger than my laptop.
Speaker 1: It's bigger than my laptop, too.
Speaker 1: It's bigger than my big iPad.
Speaker 1: so it needs to be that big because the art blows up to that big.
Speaker 1: really well I'm gonna say even though like it includes a lot of the corniness If they come out with a smaller edition you don't want the smaller edition.
Speaker 1: But just got to know it's a big book if you buy it on Amazon, but
Speaker 0: most of the joy I got from reading it is just that it was a condensed Feeling of what it was like when I was reading comics as a kid, but condensed to my adult.
Speaker 0: Let's move it along sensibilities, and I really enjoyed just Looking at all this art.
Speaker 0: I really like like this style of comic art.
Speaker 0: You know One of these pages would be a great poster.
Speaker 1: There's another so you get Charles Xavier with dot eyes and dot eyes is one of my favorite things googly eyes, but There is another x-men series from that was not super recent, but somewhat recent.
Speaker 1: I think it's.
Speaker 1: I don't know if it's x-men forever it might be called and what that is is it's basically.
Speaker 1: you know There's the wheat this uncanny accent, but then this adjective list x-men We read where the first issue with Jim yeah, yeah with the full all the multiple fold-out covers Yeah So that adjective was x-men sort of got away from where it started at a certain point.
Speaker 1: And is that more recent series is basically ignoring all other x-men continuity.
Speaker 1: it basically just picks a spot in that series where it's veers off and cancels everything that veers off and just starts at that veering off point and Keeps going as if it had been had the same writer the whole time now.
Speaker 1: This is one thing I like about the MCU and it has only these 90s character designs with it.
Speaker 0: I'm hoping the MCU will keep its continuity and never Split off again like they're releasing the movies and slow enough right?
Speaker 1: or the people who are the realities of actors and money-making.
Speaker 0: That will never happen yeah, but we'll see how it goes cuz.
Speaker 0: right now It's coming at a sustainable rate because instead of read this whole series then this whole series.
Speaker 0: It's literally There's 19 movies.
Speaker 0: Just watch a movie and then watch a movie.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's 19 movies.
Speaker 1: wait until there's 190 movies.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I mean I've watched.
Speaker 0: I've watched all of Sailor Moon in a weekend.
Speaker 0: That's 200 episodes.
Speaker 1: you're gonna watch all the superhero movies in a weekend.
Speaker 1: Their movies.
Speaker 1: it must be 90 minutes right these things.
Speaker 0: I mean I've seen a few of them.
Speaker 1: there are at least 90 minutes each right?
Speaker 0: yeah the trouble is the ones I enjoyed the most were Guardians of the Galaxy one and I Haven't seen Thor Ragnarok yet, so I don't have any opinions on it.
Speaker 0: Yeah Guardians of the Galaxy Doctor Strange was okay, but I don't need to watch it again.
Speaker 1: the main problem.
Speaker 1: Is that they don't have the Aesthetic enough.
Speaker 1: the comics you know Marvel Comics that I like have that.
Speaker 0: Well even in this one in Grand Design in the very beginning you get the watcher and his recorder.
Speaker 1: yeah Yeah, that's actually really.
Speaker 1: you know cuz that the watcher doesn't show up in x-men comics very Right.
Speaker 0: so the fact that they bring him in there Really sort of sets the tone of like what this just I love the fact that he's standing there with his hand on his chin Just like I have watch now.
Speaker 0: I'm going to record on a tape.
Speaker 1: well the reason He's watching right is not just to sort of you know provide a non corny intro at the start Which is often the watchers use in Marvel Comics is to provide this sort of narration.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but you see what's going on here.
Speaker 1: well But it is here it actually serves a second purpose and that it shows it says is the story of the x-men Which is usually a very local story a very American story an earth story, right?
Speaker 1: It only goes into space when you're dealing with Cyclops is dead Which actually they totally bring into the fold here properly right and you know instead of having it come out of nowhere the starjammers.
Speaker 1: But he you know combined with the Phoenix force it shows how the x-men it sort of takes the x-men story and shows How it is a grand you know design a universal design of some sort and not just this local story, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, if it does this does do a very good job.
Speaker 0: It is comic of fitting the x-men shit into this like giant Apocalyptic future space world right.
Speaker 1: it's sort of you know whereas before again It was just sort of like you know a Marvel comic.
Speaker 1: if you read it over time It's just sort of bouncing around.
Speaker 1: It's like well.
Speaker 1: What do we do the x-men now into space with you, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, where you know here?
Speaker 1: It's like you know by having that watcher there all this stuff for the Shi'ar come.
Speaker 1: I guess professor X didn't date the Shi'ar Queen yet, but yeah that comes later.
Speaker 1: spoilers And the Phoenix.
Speaker 1: Find out what Magneto's up to right, but you know they sort of you know it helps tie.
Speaker 1: He's tying all those random x-men bits together into a grand design.
Speaker 1: Right which is what makes it?
Speaker 1: Great and more comprehensible.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: I think this is definitely worth your while.
Speaker 0: I really enjoyed it.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm I think Emily's gonna read it before we give it back to you because I think she'll like it too good.
Speaker 1: I don't need to carry giant as book.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna give it back to you though, but not today.
Speaker 0: Yeah This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and brand.
Speaker 1: ok for the logos be sure to visit our website at front row.
Speaker 1: crew comm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 0: Remember geek nights is not one But four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows It's actually recorded at night.
Speaker 0: and the patreon patreon for this episode of geek nights are Craig Oliver Ellen Joyce Rebecca Dunn Heidi McNichol a shimmering groovy obelisk hanging in the sky.
Speaker 0: and why?
Speaker 0: Stady.com.
Speaker 0: Jeremy minor Ligeti Kelly Snyder cold guy Amanda to shed Shawn Yeager Matthew Smith Nicholas Brandau, mr.
Speaker 0: Strong distraction for two one creations.
Speaker 0: No, I never ever wonder why we're here.
Speaker 0: Semper Fi bitch Shervin, but horrible.
Speaker 0: Rory James David White Rochelle, Monta, Nona Superboy with points copy bar a pickle come quat sailor Vista Don Schleich Kajar tovish and Jojo Joestar.
Speaker 0: Clinton Walton run from New Zealand Ryan parent drew open lander Finn Chris mid give Chris Knox Daniel Redmond Shawn Klein Chris Reimer and Thomas Hahn.
Speaker 0: hopefully, I'll see a bunch of you in Lancaster this weekend and now I leave you with.