Speaker 1: It's March 7th 2018.
Speaker 0: I'm rim didn't see what the date was Wednesday Wednesday.
Speaker 0: It's like.
Speaker 0: it's March something I'm like.
Speaker 1: It's Wednesday, March 7th 2018.
Speaker 1: I'm rim humska and this is the second take on the opening in the pop team epic style And we bring you a show about pop team epic which I don't know.
Speaker 0: guys it's an anime it's.
Speaker 1: it's a thing.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: So, uh last night the news was is gonna be some sort of ridiculous snowstorm in New York And I woke up in the morning assuming there was nothing.
Speaker 0: there was a tiny drizzling rain when I woke up But I went to work.
Speaker 0: It wasn't even raining.
Speaker 1: There was nothing.
Speaker 0: No when I got to work it was wet, but like there was no flakes or anything There's.
Speaker 0: no it was not a storm as far as I could tell.
Speaker 0: usually Storms seemed like happen at night.
Speaker 0: like you wake up in the snow is there but in this case Got to work and while I was at work it started snowing, but even while I'm at work and the snow's coming down I look out the window.
Speaker 0: I don't see any flakes sticking anywhere.
Speaker 1: It's just wet everywhere Yep, but then just as I'm leaving I'm looking out the window and bit by bit I see it starting to stick and The few people who came into the office all sort of were like well and bad.
Speaker 0: I didn't see any sticking in Manhattan.
Speaker 0: But when I but I did see lots of wind and flakes blowing, but just not on the ground.
Speaker 0: But then when I got to LIC and I came out of the ground there's actually snow and mush here everywhere.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I guess it's way Colder than Manhattan even though it's just on the other side.
Speaker 1: Oh, it was started to stick in Manhattan while I was waiting.
Speaker 0: it was not a very large river either.
Speaker 1: I think it's just it.
Speaker 0: we crossed that threshold I don't know, but there was a lot of mush here.
Speaker 0: There was not even one flake on the ground in my work.
Speaker 0: Yep, there's a lot of annoying wind and flakes blowing in my face.
Speaker 1: Some lightning struck in the middle of all this.
Speaker 0: I kept hearing stories about you know thunder snow, but I did not see or hear any thunder snow.
Speaker 1: Yeah, thunder snow was so prominent where I was that it startled the shit out of everyone in the at least on the floor I was on Like people ran to the windows like what just happened out there.
Speaker 0: I didn't see or hear any thunder snow only rumors of its existence.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: I encountered a full-on.
Speaker 1: It was pretty cool.
Speaker 1: So, uh, yeah despite the weather we're here doing geek night, so it's Wednesday.
Speaker 1: you got any news.
Speaker 0: What was my news?
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah so one of like the best comics there ever was that everyone knows about if they care anything about comics is the Sandman by Neil Gaiman and It's mega popular.
Speaker 0: It keeps selling even though it's been you know, sort of done for years and years and years and years.
Speaker 0: I read the whole thing long ago.
Speaker 0: Forget probably how.
Speaker 1: it's the kind of thing that's always on the end cap at a bookstore if bookstores still exist near you.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like you go to any bookstore or comic store.
Speaker 0: It's like they got it Yeah And someone's always some new kid teenager is discovering it for the first time.
Speaker 1: some it's always right next to like a copy of the Watchmen.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's got.
Speaker 0: you know, it's got.
Speaker 1: a house is always on that same end cap.
Speaker 0: It's got some spin-off series out there and stuff like that.
Speaker 0: But vertigo that published it way back when vertigo wasn't dead Has been sort of off for a while now.
Speaker 0: and we talked about previously like way long ago about the the burger books cuz Karen burger burger.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I'm sorry She was the editor of vertigo for all those glory times and then she left and then vertigo dead basically effectively dead Not completely though.
Speaker 0: And now she's a dark horse doing those comics we talked about but I guess those haven't really come out.
Speaker 0: I think they're only like issued One of some of them and like three or four of others like I've been waiting for like a trade for any of those books And they have not come yet.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so they're going pretty slow over there, but There's a big news here that basically they're gonna.
Speaker 0: I think it's like a new imprint like it's not vertigo Even though it was announced at a vertigo thing at Emerald City comic-con, which was like a week ago.
Speaker 0: That I think it's a new imprint called Sandman Universe comics And they've already got at least one issue with Neil Gaiman's involvement.
Speaker 1: a one-shot comic plotted by Neil Gaiman co-written by Nella happens in right Hopkinson.
Speaker 1: So basically they're gonna Howard etc, right?
Speaker 0: They're gonna try to re milk that Sandman Universe a gain As if the original wasn't enough.
Speaker 1: I'm not okay with this.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so I mean if you really wanted more Sandman's you didn't have enough Then it's your lucky day and Otherwise, I think it's interesting that like Are they gonna if this works?
Speaker 0: So they're gonna go back to the other successful vertigo things and like be like, all right We're now starting.
Speaker 0: why?
Speaker 1: the last man universe and preacher universe and you know It's interesting because that's sort of the kind of thing that Underwear hero pervert comics try to do with their console to Sandman boots and reimagine.
Speaker 0: It's interesting because it sort of has this little bridge right between the set Sandman and the DC Universe.
Speaker 0: There's like this weird tiny space in between involving like you got like the house of mystery is sort of in the space in between there and you got like What else he got, you know little swamp thing mixes in there a little bit, right?
Speaker 0: And it's sort of like this this like some sort of multiverse barrier between the two.
Speaker 0: But they this leakage right and I think that's why you know, perhaps they're going for this Vertigo series don't have that leakage.
Speaker 1: We'll see though if this is done Well, it might set a precedent or if it's done Well, it might just do well and it doesn't necessarily mean it'll be the the path for every other property They can get their hands on.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and it's it's you know, it's weird cuz like usually Companies that try to revive series like reviving things that finished and it's like why you're reviving a thing That is done and done.
Speaker 0: Stop doing that.
Speaker 0: Leave it alone.
Speaker 1: I mean I never even bothered watching the like Madoka movie because the show was good and enough and I didn't want to even bother with any further story in that world.
Speaker 0: Well, actually all the Monica I looked it up.
Speaker 0: Most of the Monica movies are just Compression.
Speaker 0: Oh, no, but there is.
Speaker 0: but there is one that happens after.
Speaker 0: yep, that is not I didn't watch it But it's actually on Netflix.
Speaker 0: I put it I marked it.
Speaker 1: I don't want to see the continuing adventures of Shinji after the offensive Evangelion, right?
Speaker 0: But this is you know, it's sort of like people usually have a leave well enough alone kind of attitude.
Speaker 0: But Sandman was such a thing that like actually, you know, it doesn't have that feel of leave well enough alone.
Speaker 0: It has that feel of being large right and it was always, you know Moving about and in growing in it.
Speaker 0: even we're just reading the main series You can feel it growing and filling in more spaces.
Speaker 0: So it's like well if we're gonna continue something that you know Which you know is interesting because if you think about it.
Speaker 1: another recent property that has a very similar thing going on is actually Adventure time.
Speaker 1: Mmm adventure time has continued to just expand and fill spaces and go in different interesting directions.
Speaker 1: And even there they've said enough is enough.
Speaker 1: We're going to end it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I have like all these adventure time comics and I have not read enough of them.
Speaker 1: I haven't even read all the pony comics and they don't have all.
Speaker 0: I have every pony.
Speaker 1: Every time I pick the pony comics up again and read like another trade.
Speaker 1: They're so good.
Speaker 0: Literally every issue of a complete run of pony comics Yeah, and I have not read even half of them.
Speaker 1: So I got.
Speaker 1: it's not so much news, but this is something that's been in the anime discourse recently in a bunch of places and the answer man even jumped in on it, but basically in pop culture a number of sort of legit celebrities or Sort of more mainstream appeal people have been casually admitting that they watch anime And more importantly they've been casually admitting that they watch anime that so-called anime Nerds would consider inside baseball.
Speaker 0: I mean nerd gatekeeping is not new.
Speaker 0: Yeah,
Speaker 1: but what's interesting is That for the longest time like when I was now having an anime fan since I was in the fourth grade Which is before most of you listeners were born and all I ever wanted Was for anime to just be mainstream like everything else that I like like.
Speaker 1: I wanted to be out there in the mainstream.
Speaker 1: I didn't.
Speaker 1: I didn't want to have to go to like weird conventions to get my anime stuff or this like special section of blockbuster video or like weird fan sub crap like all the Ephemera of anime fandom was really just annoying to me because all I actually wanted was just for anime to just be normal Mm-hmm, and it basically is and has been for some time Mm-hmm, and I feel like just recently a whole bunch of anime voices Who are invested in that ephemera Looked up and realized that anime got way more mainstream than they'd expected.
Speaker 0: Well is the thing that applies to all geekeries or and is a common phenomenon for example?
Speaker 0: Did you know there was a recent soccer game right?
Speaker 0: they got better ratings in the United States than an NBA game, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, and it's like.
Speaker 0: but do you see soccer represented on like any sports channel except the soccer specific channel?
Speaker 1: Not about any time eSports comes up in a mainstream conversation in the media Most of the commentary and response is why is this being talked about even though more people are watching that than watching?
Speaker 0: You know your world series.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right.
Speaker 0: It's like the nerd.
Speaker 0: things are big, but they're not in the mainstream You know, they're not being talked about on ABC NBC CBS Fox.
Speaker 0: your main stream stuff, you know is not Recognizing the size of these things.
Speaker 0: So it's like there's all these giant monsters of culture that everyone is watching but nobody knows because the you know There's like this, you know The media is not talking about these things and the people who are in the media don't know about these things Before.
Speaker 1: but look at like top-selling comics in America pretty with almost without exception.
Speaker 1: Every conversation about that at almost every level of media in the industry Pretends that manga doesn't exist and counts everything after that and there's a reason they do that actually.
Speaker 0: That's a good.
Speaker 0: a related thing.
Speaker 0: the New York Times for example got used to have this in the top-selling book list used to have this sort of like Graphic novel and manga sections and they got rid of all those.
Speaker 0: there was actually when they first added those those Controversy that they had to keep them separate because they lumped them together.
Speaker 0: It would just be all manga.
Speaker 0: It wouldn't be representing any of the non-mang, right?
Speaker 0: It's like this stuff is a way big and they just I don't know There's.
Speaker 0: no I don't think it's a conspiracy like Hebrew for knowing it's big but it's just because of the way You know media works.
Speaker 0: Right, the actual sizes of things have no relation to the amount of attention they get.
Speaker 0: Yep and I think the only thing that's more people more people go to an Otakon and say a Baseball game do yet and the baseball game can be on the big giant.
Speaker 0: You know news and the Otakon will be in like a tiny tiny article.
Speaker 1: I mean Otakon has its problems.
Speaker 1: I'm not necessary zone.
Speaker 0: You should do anything.
Speaker 0: as an example.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like when we were going to Otakon Otakon was bigger than Pax by a ridiculous margin.
Speaker 0: Yep, Otakon was bigger than those and even within the nerd media, right?
Speaker 0: The Pax would get bigger play than Otakon.
Speaker 0: Yep, right You know, but yeah so but the other thing besides just gatekeeping and people not realizing how big things are.
Speaker 0: the main attitude that I have a problem with is I remember one of my sister's friends had this attitude when she was like in high school and I was home from RIT for some reason and You know, they were talking about animes and the friend was like, oh, yeah cowboy bebop Was that's a cool show until everyone else started liking it.
Speaker 0: That is not cool anymore And that's someone who's like.
Speaker 0: you're not judging the thing based on the quality of itself But based on you know, how many people like the thing?
Speaker 0: It's like it's only cool of a few people like it that hipster attitude.
Speaker 0: My band is only cool if it's not big enough.
Speaker 1: I just remembered the last time we videoed one of our panels of an anime Boston Remember.
Speaker 1: I captured that nerd Talking about that exact bullshit with his friend because he happened to be sitting near the microphone.
Speaker 0: Right that attitude is a bad attitude that you know.
Speaker 0: It's somehow the number of people that like a thing.
Speaker 0: when a thing becomes well known it is somehow Changed in its inherent qualities.
Speaker 0: It's like.
Speaker 0: no the quality of a thing is nothing to do with how many people like or dislike it the same way that a Fact does not become more or less true based on how many or few people believe it.
Speaker 1: There is one cut sort of nuance to that.
Speaker 1: in terms of a media you can consume.
Speaker 1: That is absolutely true.
Speaker 1: But in terms of a finite thing like say a magfest or a pax?
Speaker 1: Yes, the number of people consuming it can affect the thing But in the terms of the more people like it the harder it is for anyone to consume it.
Speaker 1: Yes, there's a very limited amount of Pax West.
Speaker 0: That's how many people like your favorite kind of Apple.
Speaker 0: the price can go up and the the farms get right But in terms of something that is infinite, you know music doesn't degrade in quality if more people listen to it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the sound waves of the concert hit everyone's ears.
Speaker 0: So I think that it might be annoying the concert ticket prices go up Or that you can only see this person at a large venue and not a small venue.
Speaker 0: Yeah But the music is the same music either way you like it or don't like it regardless of how many other people feel the same Way or differently, but I think the only reason this conversation sort of suddenly really like reemerge.
Speaker 1: We've definitely been on this track for a long time and this has been a constant evolution.
Speaker 1: A lot of people just watch anime and don't even think of it as anime.
Speaker 1: It's just something they watch on Netflix or whatever.
Speaker 0: Yeah, anyone who has that attitude though?
Speaker 0: Or is trying to gatekeep and keep people from liking the same thing that they like you can all go to hell.
Speaker 1: but I think what specifically happened is Main and I. recently there have been a spate of a smell of a number of mainstream celebrities Mentioning casually some anime they watch in the course of some unrelated conversation and a bunch of nerds picked up on that as being newsworthy Simply because they mentioned anime.
Speaker 1: and that seems to be worried.
Speaker 1: Like I'm seeing this conversation like circling to a degree that I haven't seen in like five plus years and it's sort of interesting but anyway things of the day, so I got a thing that is Weird, but it is the most interesting thing.
Speaker 1: I've seen you know, that's the whole idea of thing of the day.
Speaker 1: Like what's the most interesting thing you've seen?
Speaker 1: Since the last time you had your thing of the day like back when we started geek nights What I saw is this picture of a car and The car has a bunch of words all over the back of it the words of a crazy person.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm, but the words Seem to imply that dogs cause cancer.
Speaker 0: That is not true because I know many people had cancer who did not have any like cancer dog for it's basically that is a child Get cancer.
Speaker 0: They don't have a dog yet.
Speaker 1: It is the time cube babies born with cancer.
Speaker 0: They were never near a dog.
Speaker 1: It is the time cube of cancer dog, and I really am Surprisingly invested in finding out what the hell the deal is with this.
Speaker 0: They're just a nutty delusional person.
Speaker 0: It's like I read a story last was a week or two ago about this.
Speaker 0: Someone grew up and there they kept moving homes and it was really weird.
Speaker 0: They didn't understand like like one day their mom threw out all the food in the fridge or something.
Speaker 0: It's like they had a weird childhood and they didn't know why until later in life.
Speaker 0: Their mom told them like oh, yeah, we've been on the run from the mob this whole time Oh, he doing witness protection stuff, right?
Speaker 0: But then years later she found out Oh, no My mom actually just got involved with this other dude who wasn't my dad and that dude was totally delusional.
Speaker 0: I got my mom to believe this nut job story.
Speaker 0: That wasn't true at all.
Speaker 0: And then she looked it up and it's like yeah It's an actual like disorder that you can have where you're otherwise like a normal kind of.
Speaker 0: you know, you'd like person.
Speaker 0: you just have this crazy thing that you believe as if it's true and It's like this particular flag that gets to this person.
Speaker 0: It might not even be a nut job, but they might send on this one issue.
Speaker 0: They could be having that same thing where they're completely normal person who just believes in all their heart.
Speaker 0: for some delusional reason The dogs cause cancer.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but it's always this like or they could be or they could be a nut job.
Speaker 1: It's always this like very specific type of Activision of activism.
Speaker 1: So because that's just weird.
Speaker 1: I have a better thing of the day More consumable by all of you.
Speaker 1: It's a record that has a gimmick a vinyl record a lot of vinyl records of gimmicks.
Speaker 0: That's old hat.
Speaker 1: actually I'd say a very small percentage of vinyl records have gimmicks other than the fact that in the modern era all vinyl records are gimmicks.
Speaker 0: No, but even in the vinyl record days like we had so so many of the records we had were gimmicks.
Speaker 0: There's one that came in the newspaper.
Speaker 0: There was an ad for something or there was the McDonald's one.
Speaker 1: I think that was me.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think that was one of them where if it played the song a certain way you want a bunch of money.
Speaker 0: Yes, I'm like that There's the Monty Python one where there's a track in between the tracks a three track record three track.
Speaker 1: We got a copy of that later on somewhere, you know.
Speaker 0: There's the Beatles one where once it gets to the middle it does stuff.
Speaker 0: This is the one where you play it back you spin your turntable backwards and it does something different.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so any trick that could be pulled with a vinyl record was it has been pulled.
Speaker 1: So this is probably the only instance of the so-called gimmick actually having a very valid Specific use that is intrinsic to the purpose of a record which is for you to hear music.
Speaker 1: All right, so the record is called Orelob Okay, which is Bolero backwards as in Bolero Ravel's Bolero Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: If you don't know the deal with Bolero is that it starts out real quiet and it gets louder and louder And louder at this constant pace throughout the entire song.
Speaker 0: So the outside of the record that spins faster can be better at being louder.
Speaker 1: So yes This record is a gimmick in that you put the needle in the beginning.
Speaker 1: actually I realize most people listening to geek nights are probably too young to actually have ever used a vinyl record.
Speaker 0: Maybe I don't know normal on the records.
Speaker 1: You put a needle a Physical needle like a pointy needle out out out my finger on the outside of the record the large edge and the record Spins.
Speaker 0: and because you know about circles You know that when a disc is spinning the edge of the disc is going faster than the middle of the disc Even though the whole disc is spinning it whatever pi radians per second.
Speaker 1: now a record is recorded.
Speaker 1: taking that into account The rotation rate of the record is what's counted like 33 rpm.
Speaker 0: For example Yeah, the music that's on the edge of the record is further apart and the music that's in the middle of the record is closer Together.
Speaker 0: so the speed of the music is always the same.
Speaker 1: But anyway, most records you put the needle on the outside of the record and it slowly moves down the spiral toward the inside of the Record.
Speaker 1: till it's done this record you put the needle on the inside and it slowly moves to the outside.
Speaker 1: Now a lot of fancy record players couldn't play this record because fancy record players Assume that records are normal.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like I want to resist this right?
Speaker 0: So like records some record players I had early in life You just you just the needle moved all about.
Speaker 0: you could pick it up and move it wherever the hell you wanted and you It would just be controlled by the groove.
Speaker 1: Yeah our turntable in the hi-fi system actually had a little like Mechanized thing that would steady the rate like it would try to move the thing inward.
Speaker 0: but there is a yeah fancy record.
Speaker 0: players had all these features like Automatically picking up and resetting the needle with little motors being able to choose a track if I record like ridiculous shit, right?
Speaker 0: It's like pushing a button and having the needle would go to the start of the record on its own.
Speaker 1: Scott and I are compared to a lot of you - we.
Speaker 0: If your turntable was attempting to move the needle on of its own volition that would counteract the you know This record.
Speaker 0: you'd be to have a difficult time playing it.
Speaker 1: But anyway this video Explains in very good detail why this was actually not really a gimmick.
Speaker 1: But legit was useful for this specific song and possibly no other song on earth that would ever be on a record.
Speaker 0: But of course you could make the song better just by putting it on.
Speaker 0: I don't know a wav file MP3 or a CD.
Speaker 1: the only value The sole value of this trick is this assuming vinyl records are all you got makes it better and it would be possibly better than a cassette depending but actually probably not because the height of cassette technology was actually Really freaking good.
Speaker 0: all the all the masters of all the music that went on a lot of these vinyl records were on debt tapes actually.
Speaker 1: So eight tracks have a reputation for being pretty shitty.
Speaker 1: They are.
Speaker 1: I had an eight-track player I actually we had a car with an eight-track player in it and we had an eight-track deck in the stereo rack.
Speaker 1: But eight tracks not that bad a quality.
Speaker 1: Usually it's just that the eight-track players were shitty.
Speaker 1: Yeah But anyway, that's my thing of the day.
Speaker 1: So what do you got?
Speaker 0: So this video was going around but I don't know how many people saw it.
Speaker 0: it's a pretty long video and the title of the video is a gay man's opinion about yaoi slash BL.
Speaker 1: now with English subs a 40 minutes lie saw this floating around.
Speaker 1: I actually queued it to watch.
Speaker 0: So literally it is exactly what it says.
Speaker 0: It's some gay dude from Japan is Japanese, dude And he knows a lot about yaoi and BL.
Speaker 0: like whatever you thought you knew about yaoi and bl.
Speaker 0: This guy knows more right and it's just his opinion.
Speaker 0: You might disagree.
Speaker 0: I'm not saying that I agree with everything in this video.
Speaker 0: I watched almost all of it, but it's way long so I couldn't finish.
Speaker 0: I had to leave.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I watched like maybe 20 out of the 30 minutes or whatever, but it was very fascinating and enlightening.
Speaker 0: So if you are in the anime community, right and like you have, you know preconceived notions about yaoi and bl or even if you're a fan of yaoi and bl you think you know a lot or You know, you know a little bit like I do right but I've never you know gone into the hole.
Speaker 0: You just like know that that's a thing like oh really gone into the hole.
Speaker 1: That's where you're gonna use for this.
Speaker 0: Yes Okay, it's like I'm like for me before watching this video like I knew like.
Speaker 0: oh, I know what yaoi bl is.
Speaker 0: I know, you know, I know it's general deal.
Speaker 0: I never researched it, but I know it's like nope now I know way more.
Speaker 0: so this is Recommended viewing for all anime peoples to be you know enlightened and such All right.
Speaker 1: so in the meta moment the book club book is Emily Wilson's new translation of the Odyssey by Homa.
Speaker 1: Oh, it's pretty good.
Speaker 1: I'm actually About halfway through at this point.
Speaker 0: Mmm.
Speaker 1: You're halfway through further than me because this translation Reads in a very natural way and I am able to very directly and naturally enjoy the story at face value Without being required to interpret what's happening to gain enjoyment from the actions in the story.
Speaker 1: So it's just a really fun story.
Speaker 1: reading it from this perspective And even though I know the broad strokes and I've read the Odyssey before in high school Reading it closely with a modern translation it's it's Until we do the book club show about it, but if you're gonna follow us on the book club Hopefully Scott will read it soon and we can do a show on it.
Speaker 0: other meta news very soon is PAX East 2018 a four-day packs five.
Speaker 1: if you show up early and go to the prepacks gaming on Wednesday Yeah, I'll be there Wednesday night.
Speaker 1: I'll be there Wednesday Afternoon night.
Speaker 0: Anyway, you gotta play quartermaster general as this tradition It's gonna be a PAX East is gonna be four days.
Speaker 0: for the first time.
Speaker 0: We got a panel on Sunday at the worst possible time.
Speaker 1: It's not the worst possible time.
Speaker 1: It is a bad time is a bad time, but it's not opposite the Omega thongs.
Speaker 0: I'm very happy You can still go to this panel though.
Speaker 0: We'll be there.
Speaker 0: Yeah If you really want to you can go to it.
Speaker 1: Yep Otherwise, so we'll see.
Speaker 0: you recommend though going to if you don't have don't have tickets for this packs You can go to it on Thursday.
Speaker 0: It's not sold out.
Speaker 0: Just buy a Thursday only ticket.
Speaker 0: You'll get a full day of packs plus a keynote plus a Q&A.
Speaker 0: It'll be less crowded than the Friday and Saturday which are sold out.
Speaker 0: Totally worth it.
Speaker 0: Even if you're any distance of Boston is totally worth it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if you can get there for a day trip like Thursday at PAX East you could do a lot.
Speaker 0: Let's stick to work.
Speaker 0: do what you got to do.
Speaker 0: All you people who are like can never go to a PAX in my whole life.
Speaker 0: Well, here you go.
Speaker 0: It's the set.
Speaker 0: It's maybe the biggest or second biggest bags And you can go to it real easy.
Speaker 0: is the biggest packs in terms of people maybe but it's the second biggest in terms of.
Speaker 0: They do not publish Official stats now, it may be the biggest in terms of people but it's definitely the second biggest in terms of industry presence.
Speaker 0: Yes, South and OS have a small industry presence.
Speaker 1: West and East have a large And unplugged has a vendor presence, but not so much of the real like wider industry presence Which is still pretty good.
Speaker 0: industry presents, but it's you know tabletop doesn't have video game money.
Speaker 1: There's definitely more focus on vending by the industry as opposed to expo in.
Speaker 0: Anyway, there's a packs coming.
Speaker 0: also the anime seasons about like gonna be over in like three weeks.
Speaker 0: So we're gonna judge anime by its cover for the spring season.
Speaker 0: Maybe after packs right before packs Yep.
Speaker 1: And if you're waiting for us to resume our antenna show on the day that we record the video for the next judge anime by Its cover we're also going to record the video for the episode 16. geek nice presents utenna Which is the episode where spoilers nanami?
Speaker 1: Literally turns into a cow like moo moo cow moo moo cow making milk move which then Inexplicably happens in the movie with zero context.
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 1: My mom walked.
Speaker 1: I literally was watching the utenna movie and my mom like came into the room just as that scene started and She watched it like just while she was doing her thing.
Speaker 0: She's like what the fuck.
Speaker 1: and then later that day She was like what the hell was that movie about.
Speaker 1: I?
Speaker 0: Watched the whole thing and I couldn't tell you.
Speaker 0: Yeah naked cars.
Speaker 0: That's all It's all I know is naked cat.
Speaker 1: There's that interview with Ika Hara where they're like.
Speaker 1: So what's different about utenna in the movie as opposed to the show?
Speaker 1: and he literally says well for one thing in the movie Utenna turns into a car and then he just stops talking.
Speaker 1: Anyway If yeah, if you've you've if you're an anime fan at all?
Speaker 1: You've seen the ephemera of pop team epic in your social media.
Speaker 0: It's the day you use social media.
Speaker 1: There's a tall anime moe blob with blue hair and a short anime moe blob with yellow hair and I Usually flipping you off.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so I saw them very very often around the internet.
Speaker 0: in many places I kept seeing these same two characters the tall one in the short.
Speaker 1: like my Anna Twitter was filled with this shit.
Speaker 0: I've seen them for a long time many many months.
Speaker 0: Perhaps even I don't know how long it's been around But I've been seen a lot.
Speaker 0: I've been seeing those call the anime not along but I think it's based on a four coma which is a four panel comic Like as among Adia was a four panel comic right basically like, you know a penny arcade of Japan Only penny arcade of three panels usually anyway.
Speaker 0: So yeah, I mean I've been seeing this everywhere and this season during judge anime by its cover we saw Oh, this is now an anime for season one.
Speaker 0: I guess we'll have to check that out.
Speaker 0: And so I checked it out.
Speaker 0: What did we say when we judged it?
Speaker 1: So what I there was a chat.
Speaker 1: I'm not ready to get out now where Scott a while ago just a couple times asked me Did you watch any of it yet?
Speaker 1: Cuz I had.
Speaker 1: I kept saying I'll watch it.
Speaker 1: I'll watch it.
Speaker 1: So Scott having watched an episode one episode kept asking me.
Speaker 1: Have you seen it?
Speaker 1: And then I saw it now.
Speaker 1: I know why he asked me that I I Really like it.
Speaker 1: Okay, but the caveat is It took me a while to understand The hell I was watching.
Speaker 1: this is there's a time where we would say like Oh, there's anime that someone who hasn't seen anime before could watch like cowboy bebop Mm-hmm, and then there's anime that really only makes sense.
Speaker 1: If you are deep in the anime bullshit like Excel saga Elf Princess rain Bobo Bobo Bobo Bobo.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there are you know, this.
Speaker 0: this is a long and treasured Anime genre the completely insane wacky off-the-wall Parody crazy anime that is nonsensical and you know whatnot.
Speaker 0: and there are many of those that I enjoy.
Speaker 0: It is not a genre that I'm opposed to in fact, I find it quite humorous, but this instance of the genre left me Dumbfounded like I didn't like.
Speaker 1: I was dumbfounded.
Speaker 0: I felt like it's like usually.
Speaker 0: I'm a person who knows anime things so I should be able to understand this.
Speaker 0: I enjoy things that are quite hellish.
Speaker 0: Right anime hellish and yet watching this.
Speaker 0: I didn't understand a fuck thing that was going on Other than like, okay.
Speaker 0: I see what you did there and then and then it was over and it's like what the.
Speaker 0: so People love this and I don't know if I can watch anymore because my life is short.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna watch it all.
Speaker 1: Okay, so I watched a second episode and I watch half of a third episode.
Speaker 0: I'd only watched the first episode.
Speaker 1: So I figured out the D. I figured out what I liked about it because I spent when I was watching this The first 15 minutes or 12 minutes of the episodes the first half of episode one.
Speaker 0: but first it shows like this other anime right and I'm pretty.
Speaker 0: I could sort of guess like did I did crunchyroll mess up or are they starting with a joke by showing this?
Speaker 1: Other anime and being like ha ha ha that kind of thing has itself been a trope in anime.
Speaker 1: There's an episode of gassaraki where the opener is different and you're like, wait what?
Speaker 1: Did I watch the wrong show?
Speaker 1: Is this the wrong VHS tape?
Speaker 1: There's an episode of try gun.
Speaker 1: That's like wait Why are they all on a space station?
Speaker 1: What the fuck is this?
Speaker 1: is this?
Speaker 1: try again, right?
Speaker 0: So it's like at first you don't even know if you're watching pop teen epic And then of course you are right and I sort of like.
Speaker 0: I guessed it and then it was confirmed.
Speaker 0: But the thing is that weird parody anime that they showed at the start.
Speaker 0: the reason that it was so confusing was because it Wasn't even like a parody of a more generic anime.
Speaker 0: it literally was.
Speaker 0: they just made a generic anime But they literally made like a minute of generic anime not doing any weird jokes or anything crazy.
Speaker 1: Like.
Speaker 1: if you showed someone this they were.
Speaker 1: just assume They're those b-minus anime that everyone ignores like one of a dozen from every season, right?
Speaker 0: It's like you could have just found an anime that like failed to get finished Taken the first minute of it and slapped it in the first minute of this show without any changes whatsoever.
Speaker 0: And it's like I see what you did there, but it's not funny It just leaves me confused.
Speaker 1: so watching this through the first half I laughed out loud a couple times, but then I'll mostly.
Speaker 1: I was just trying to figure out the fuck this what was going on.
Speaker 1: But then in the second half, I thought crunchyroll messed up and it was looping.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they do because they do it that they repeat the thing again.
Speaker 1: format is WarioWare style.
Speaker 1: there will be like six to seven second shorts Just one after another like it is so rapid-fire that if you're not paying attention You will miss it all and then they'll be closing credits halfway through the episode.
Speaker 1: then there will be the exact same set of stuff.
Speaker 1: skits again Mostly the same But something will be cooked slightly differently the second time through the second episode.
Speaker 0: do the same thing.
Speaker 1: Yes, really and as soon as I got that.
Speaker 1: so I literally was watching this and then I was like wait What the fuck.
Speaker 1: I started going back and forth between the first half and the second half to see if they were actually the same.
Speaker 1: I ended up having two C rolls open like watching the same bit side by side and then I got it.
Speaker 1: and When I when I watched the second half all the way through I Saw I remembered like oh that this is the joke that was happening and then it would be different in a way.
Speaker 1: That was really funny okay, and when I watched the second episode kind of having this gnosis of what the deal was I Laughed out loud several times.
Speaker 1: I find the show legitimately funny and more importantly I Can't necessarily place every reference to a specific show But I started picking out a lot more of what the parodies were.
Speaker 1: Like.
Speaker 1: one of them was straight-up like hey remember chrono trigger the end and then they did the same chrono trigger again.
Speaker 1: But then it was a different particularly like.
Speaker 1: here's an example of the kind of parody in this show There'll be a moment where the girls bump into each other and fall over because one's running with toasters some shit.
Speaker 1: Yep In one of the instances the one girl drops a pendant that the that is on that it landed on the other girl And that's sort of like a trope.
Speaker 1: that's happened with like some magical girl type fantasy shows when the same scene happens again There's no pendant and instead like the girls bump into each other and then you get this very particular scene That has occurred in a ton of anime over the years where someone is knocked down and you get and they look up and then You get this flash you get a close-up of their face looking up and then you get a close-up of the other character Looking down at them and smiling reaching out their hand.
Speaker 1: then it cuts to the wide shot of the two of them looking at each other and then that shot pans up and Accelerates into the sky and then you get the opening credits.
Speaker 1: That is the extent of the parody.
Speaker 1: that entire scene is itself the parody and then it moves on to a completely Different set of parody, right?
Speaker 0: So I already brought up Azumanga die, which is also based on for coma, right?
Speaker 0: And I was a manga that expands right?
Speaker 0: It's it's it's it's you know, it stretches the four coma out.
Speaker 0: What was originally just four panels and a gag will now be like a 30 second to one minute like, you know gag.
Speaker 0: we're like you actually animate the cat biting someone right whereas this is Compression.
Speaker 0: they take the the each comic and it's like boom It's on the screen for a few seconds and there's just tons of them.
Speaker 1: Everything is distilled to its like minimum viable parody compressed not you know Whereas the Azumanga die was decompressed so much like how Wario were?
Speaker 1: Was like six second games like these micro games that were themselves these like simulacra echoes of real games Like you appear as Zelda and our link in a Zelda game and literally it's walk up into the cave.
Speaker 1: You're done you win That's it.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: This is the anime equivalent of that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so I still like say I just couldn't I just couldn't follow what the hell is going on.
Speaker 1: I gave up like as soon as it clicked I was laughing out loud and I find this show Utterly delightful.
Speaker 0: so something that really surprised me.
Speaker 0: It's like the most obvious thing can't be ignored about the show.
Speaker 0: is that the voices of the two characters changing?
Speaker 0: Well, not only they keep changing but it's like they're not girl.
Speaker 0: They look like girls.
Speaker 0: They're not girl voices.
Speaker 0: They're like, oh dude voices.
Speaker 0: I think the I think the voice actor for one of them is the same.
Speaker 0: voice actor is like the Japanese wash the stampede.
Speaker 1: it's way better than that.
Speaker 1: Okay, go to just go to anime news network and look at the voice cast.
Speaker 1: okay, so Different people voice either of those characters in every episode.
Speaker 1: forever Like this is literally so and so is PP me so and so is PP me PP PP PP PP PP PP PP PP ... there's one two three four, five.
Speaker 1: There's like 30 different voice actors so far.
Speaker 1: like this person was Popoco in episode 5b Mm-hmm, but then an episode 5a a different voice actor played that character.
Speaker 0: Yeah And it's that's definitely unique.
Speaker 0: I haven't seen that the animation style is different.
Speaker 1: Everything is different.
Speaker 0: It goes live action pattern does change like constantly.
Speaker 1: Oh in episode 2 It's almost like this scrap princess level of like anime like that kind of fantasy anime.
Speaker 1: But it's like the storyboards except these two characters are animated and the conceit Is that those are the main characters and everyone else is like the barely drawn background character from an unfinished slayers episode.
Speaker 1: Like that kind of nonsense.
Speaker 0: So I'm glad that like this kind of anime is still getting made like the genre of in completely insane comedy Highly evolved and Niche form of that kind of.
Speaker 0: yeah, I'm glad it's still being made.
Speaker 0: It still exists right because it feels like it's been gone for a long time.
Speaker 0: But this particular one.
Speaker 0: I just don't know if I have the effort or the patience to like bother understanding it.
Speaker 0: I bet you know rim also likes crazy YouTube crap like I do like potato conditions or whatever.
Speaker 0: I don't understand that either.
Speaker 1: But one thing I got to say about this.
Speaker 1: it is very easy to dismiss it as cheap and weird.
Speaker 1: It is actually.
Speaker 0: it's not.
Speaker 0: it's not cheap and weird.
Speaker 1: It's for what it is.
Speaker 0: It is definitely not cheap.
Speaker 1: It is Extremely high production values.
Speaker 1: a lot of care is going into this.
Speaker 1: the people writing this show are Doing a lot of very difficult work to make the comedic beats and parodies.
Speaker 1: They're trying to convey.
Speaker 1: It's almost like worry aware loss edit the anime parody.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: I can completely recognize all that going on.
Speaker 0: I just can't with my brain just doesn't Like.
Speaker 0: it tries to go in my brain.
Speaker 1: That's clearly a parody of like the sele style enemies from like Evangelion.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like when you're trying to type stuff into a mud and it's like I don't understand that command.
Speaker 0: That's my brain.
Speaker 1: Yep, it took me a while Like.
Speaker 1: it literally took me until halfway through the second episode and then suddenly it clicked and this shit was hilarious.
Speaker 0: I only watched one episode and then I was like, well, I'm not watching another one even though I still think my favorite Joke is the.
Speaker 1: are you okay joke?
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm where she's just punching the other girl.
Speaker 1: She's like punches.
Speaker 1: It's like are you okay?
Speaker 1: He punches her harder Are you okay, and then something happens after that?
Speaker 0: Yeah, that seems to be like that.
Speaker 1: the most running joke that there was like he just kept repeating Yeah, I guess I'm I'm look at steamed hams like that kind of shit.
Speaker 1: That's the kind of stuff that really steams my hams.
Speaker 1: when there's a when there's a joke that is Distilled to its most minimal form kind of like how I really enjoy loss at it like.
Speaker 1: I understand steamed hams Yeah, but take that and distill it further and further like the last.
Speaker 0: you're not supposed to drink ever clear.
Speaker 1: No, this is this is ever clear.
Speaker 1: You take the ever clear.
Speaker 1: get it.
Speaker 1: get the like the syringe of ever clear.
Speaker 1: kill yourself But then turn that into a 12 episode 23 minute long episode anime series.
Speaker 0: I was very surprised I thought it was gonna be one of the short ones like the animate with the opener and closer or longer than the actual show The fact that the episode was actually 20-something minutes long.
Speaker 0: I was amazed at that.
Speaker 1: but the craft of taking the most minimum viable components of parody and then using those and from there making a Full show is just amazing to me.
Speaker 0: Yeah I'm a sort of afraid for the future like the people who are making Masterpieces of steamed hams now are gonna be like the animators and TV show creators of the future.
Speaker 0: I is all the shows gonna be like this.
Speaker 1: Will there be a future version of a show like gig nights where some people are like?
Speaker 0: Yeah There's those like there used to be those animators like or show and then it goes to cuts again and then halfway through the show They're like one day again Only slightly different.
Speaker 1: I'm thinking people like us or maybe us 20 years from now will be like, yeah Remember those accessible parody shows like pop team epic.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't understand the shit.
Speaker 1: They're making.
Speaker 1: now Watch one episode of this.
Speaker 0: Yes, you're not a no if you're an anime person.
Speaker 0: This is like essential watching because it's such a big deal.
Speaker 0: Apparently at least one episode got to see what the deal is.
Speaker 0: and then if you understand it because you have a young Brain or rim brain then keep watching it.
Speaker 0: And if you're an old man brain like Scott and you don't understand what the fuck you just saw Well, at least you saw.
Speaker 0: that was important and you don't need to keep watching.
Speaker 1: I don't think the thing I actually would need to know the most is Like.
Speaker 1: the thing that would solidify every thought I have about the show would be finding out.
Speaker 1: Suppose Neil Cisarega watched a few episodes of this.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: Would he get it and like it or would he be confused and annoyed by it?
Speaker 0: I don't know because I annoyed by it I'm just confused.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I I Like the show a lot.
Speaker 1: you like a lot yeah, but I like the show a Lot.
Speaker 1: All right, and I don't know what to do about that.
Speaker 0: It might be related also to like you like all that like Adult Swim stuff that understand either.
Speaker 0: true It could be say if it's not anyway, it's not like from a surface level It's not at all similar to that.
Speaker 0: and humor style, right?
Speaker 0: But it you know, it feels the same way where it's like.
Speaker 0: I can see that there is a joke here.
Speaker 1: There are things that I like that you don't like.
Speaker 1: that are just like.
Speaker 1: I like a different style of humor but this is a much more specific type of hyper distilled and then Every possible variation using the most minimum possible components.
Speaker 1: That is a particular genre of media.
Speaker 0: I don't think there's.
Speaker 0: what else is in that genre anything.
Speaker 1: Steamed hams is almost too long form for that.
Speaker 0: That's what I'm saying.
Speaker 0: This is really like a unique thing that the Which is.
Speaker 1: why would argue that Wario aware micro games themselves are that?
Speaker 0: yeah, probably.
Speaker 1: But the thing there's no other Wario.
Speaker 0: where anime that I'm aware loss edits are that?
Speaker 0: yes sort of.
Speaker 0: but I understand a loss at it Yeah but most of the time and the thing about a loss at it is when you see one and you don't realize it is one and Then you do realize it is one.
Speaker 0: and then because it took you time to realize That's where its power lies if there's one you recognize immediately.
Speaker 0: It has no power.
Speaker 1: It's a full.
Speaker 1: you know what that is.
Speaker 1: That is the fully evolved form of the Rick roll.
Speaker 1: You don't trick someone in looking at some with something.
Speaker 1: you get someone to look at something and wait for their moment of parapeteia.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like you.
Speaker 0: it's like it's a Rick roll.
Speaker 0: It's just Rick Astley's face right there But you don't see it cuz like a magic eye.
Speaker 0: and yeah once you do the magic eye and there's the face and you know You've been looking at it all along.
Speaker 0: You just didn't realize it immediately.
Speaker 0: It was you that was slow.
Speaker 0: Nobody popped out at you and surprised you or tricked you right?
Speaker 0: It was just your mind that was slow because it was hidden in plain sight and that hidden in plain sight is where the art lies.
Speaker 1: So love it hate it.
Speaker 1: Whatever watch one episode.
Speaker 0: I don't hate it or love it.
Speaker 0: I just don't.
Speaker 0: I just don't get it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I just doesn't.
Speaker 0: it's like I see that this wizard is casting a spell yet for some reason It has no effect on me, even though I am submitting myself to it.
Speaker 1: Yep I rolled a one on that saving throw or 20 depending on what edition of D&D.
Speaker 0: Why did I accidentally pass this saving throw that I was attempting to fail?
Speaker 1: You know, it's.
Speaker 1: you know, it's like some monsters are just immune to certain kinds of magic.
Speaker 0: It's like.
Speaker 0: it's like oh heal me cleric.
Speaker 0: So bleeding cleric wise is not working.
Speaker 0: I see you're doing a cleric man.
Speaker 0: Then he goes over to rim and rims like he'll be cleric Right and rims like scars all disappear and even his butthole seal shut because his wounds have healed so much.
Speaker 0: and it's like what the hell Are you holding out on me?
Speaker 1: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott.
Speaker 1: special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brand.
Speaker 1: ok for the logos.
Speaker 0: be sure to visit our website at front row.
Speaker 0: crew Com for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 1: remember geek nights is not one But four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 1: But unlike those other late shows It's actually recorded at night and the patreon patrons for this episode of the ignites are Alan Joyce Craig Oliver Rebecca Dunn Heidi McNichol a shimmering rubiobolus Hanging in the sky.
Speaker 1: my state calm Jeremy minor link eg cold guy Amanda duchette Sean Yeager Matthew Smith Nicholas Brandau captain Chinguakasi Four to one creations.
Speaker 1: No, I never ever wonder why we're here.
Speaker 1: Semper Fi bitch Shervin van Horl rare Laval James David White Rochelle, Monta, Nona Superboy rim says something funny here.
Speaker 1: sailor Vista Don Schleich chartavision joshiro Joe star Sam Cordery Clinton Walton Ren from New Zealand Ryan Perrin drew open lander Finn Chris midkiff Chris Knox Daniel Redman Sean Klein Chris Reimer and Thomas Hahn.
Speaker 1: I Thought I'd put a pop team epic thing here at the end, but that's too weird even for the end of geek night.
Speaker 1: so instead I leave you with A duck walked up to a lemonade stand and he said to the man running the stand.
Speaker 1: Hey Got any grapes?
Speaker 1: The Men said no, we just sell lemonade, but it's cold and it's fresh and it's all homemade.
Speaker 1: Can I get you a glass?
Speaker 1: The duck said I'll pass.
Speaker 1: Then he waddled away waddle waddle till the very next day.
Speaker 1: bump bump bump bump bump.
Speaker 1: But um when the duck walked up to the lemonade stand and he said to the man running the stand Hey bump bump bump got any grapes The Man said no, like I said yesterday We just sell lemonade.
Speaker 1: Okay, why not give it a try?
Speaker 1: The duck said goodbye.
Speaker 1: Then he waddled away waddle waddle.
Speaker 1: then he waddled away waddle waddle.
Speaker 1: then he waddled away waddle.