Speaker 1: It's Monday March 5th 2018.
Speaker 1: I'm rim.
Speaker 1: I'm Scott and this is a geek night's tech news roundup.
Speaker 0: Let's do this Every year around this time.
Speaker 1: I run out of Monday show ideas.
Speaker 0: No you run out of Monday show.
Speaker 0: I'd like up two months before now about the in late March and then You always want to do tech news roundup on every Monday because you don't have any ideas.
Speaker 0: I would just make tech news roundup the show yeah, but We either managed to either come up with a bad idea or bail on every other Monday show Yeah, and then eventually when it becomes March again rim is like so excited.
Speaker 0: He can now have it's a tech news round Free permission to do the tech news roundup once a year.
Speaker 0: So I don't want to say hit points mana because that clock does ring yeah rings once a year.
Speaker 0: In fact the last tech news roundup was a year and a day ago.
Speaker 0: There was no another episode last year.
Speaker 0: that was not tech news roundup.
Speaker 0: it was all Listeners submitted tech news roundup so that one does not count.
Speaker 1: That's true.
Speaker 1: That's true, but I still think about talking about a moment.
Speaker 0: I'm still thinking about changing the format of Monday, but cuz you have no ideas for Monday shows though if you like Monday show You should help out Monday show by sending in some ideas.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so uh before we get into the baby Okay, there's no I will probably shoot it down.
Speaker 1: There is no news other than the tech news for obvious reasons.
Speaker 1: so uh I Went skiing this weekend, and you know I you might if you heard me.
Speaker 1: I think I've occasionally said this on geek nice But I tend to go to hunter mountain because it's the best skiing within like a day trip of New York City.
Speaker 0: So it's not great.
Speaker 0: It's not that great.
Speaker 0: But if you want to go there you always go there to the same mountain and whenever other people talk about that mountain They're like man.
Speaker 0: that is crappy skiing actually.
Speaker 1: no.
Speaker 1: so when I talk to other people about that mountain They always say the same thing that I say which is that's the best mountain Within a day trip of New York City.
Speaker 1: there are better places.
Speaker 0: the thing is you can't reach some Pocono Mountain within a day.
Speaker 1: Oh, those mountains are bullshit.
Speaker 1: Uh-huh.
Speaker 1: I've skied down there.
Speaker 1: That's a bullshit.
Speaker 1: mountains that place that everything in the Poconos is garbage as far as I'm concerned Uh-huh, but so there's hunter mountain, and there's Wyndham Mountain Which is actually the same distance is owned by a hotel.
Speaker 1: No, I think it's spelled differently.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 1: It's just Wyndham Mountain.
Speaker 1: It's this other mountain, so I go to hunter.
Speaker 1: I've never been to Wyndham But I talk shit about Wyndham a lot and I have for a decade you talk shit about a place you never been Judging it without trying it.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 1: So now now I've been to Wyndham and now I know the fullness.
Speaker 1: now if I want to go a little further like if I Went real skiing.
Speaker 1: There's not a day trip.
Speaker 1: I could go to Killington, but even then Killington's like a five-hour drive.
Speaker 0: Vermont Yeah, yeah, that's real.
Speaker 1: it's like a five-hour drive But Killington's kind of shit because if you drive just a couple more hours you get to Bretton Woods and Loon and the good shit.
Speaker 1: Anyway, that's all orthogonal to this discussion.
Speaker 1: So
Speaker 0: I got a hunter and
Speaker 1: The reason I never went to Wyndham wasn't just that I went to hunter first But it was that when I read reviews or talk to people about stupid hunter versus Wyndham Mountain They'd always say that Hunter has better expert terrain and the old-timers ski there and Wyndham is all just snowboarders smoking pot.
Speaker 1: That idea was reinforced.
Speaker 1: when I take this bus out of Manhattan That's how I get up there to ski usually and what I always noticed over all these years the last decade of going up there on this bus is that There'd be a ton of people standing by the new victory theater in Manhattan and Times Square and a bunch of buses would come up and one by one the buses are like hunter or Wyndham without fail.
Speaker 1: the people who got on the hunter bus Were old-timers or people like me who had their own skis and were just standing there quietly and they're gonna go up there and ski and without fail.
Speaker 1: almost everyone who got on the Wyndham bus were first-time snowboarders going on some sort of package trip most of whom did not even have their own snowboards.
Speaker 1: and Then I'd read that the lift capacity was low and the mountains not that high and all the so I finally had the displeasure of going to Wyndham Mountain and all I learned why would you go to it?
Speaker 1: because Hunter Mountain and Bel Air and basically the entire region upstate had no power this weekend because of that giant blizzard.
Speaker 0: So Wyndham Mountain was the only one with power?
Speaker 0: Wyndham Mountain was the only one with power.
Speaker 0: So the ski mountain was closed after a blizzard.
Speaker 0: Shouldn't that be when the ski mountains opened?
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, do you know how much money hunter mountain lost out on because of that that?
Speaker 0: can they get the money back from insurance?
Speaker 1: I have no idea.
Speaker 1: It was basically a disaster for them to not be open on Saturday.
Speaker 1: Okay, like ridiculous disaster.
Speaker 1: So, uh, I ended up my bus just went to Wyndham instead.
Speaker 0: Maybe it wasn't a disaster because then no one died this way.
Speaker 1: Um, yeah So only four people have died at hunter in like the last five years.
Speaker 1: That was gonna be the day they got saved by the power and as far as I can tell one of them was that lady Who fell off the ski lift.
Speaker 1: the other three were people who were doing something they shouldn't have.
Speaker 1: but uh Wyndham Mountain lived up to every negative expectation I have ever encountered.
Speaker 1: it was like it was.
Speaker 1: it was literally a Simpsons.
Speaker 1: Lisa opened the envelope.
Speaker 1: I gave you moments.
Speaker 1: So now not only can I continue to talk shit about Wyndham But I've been there and I have first-hand evidence that I was in fact 100% of crack correct from the beginning.
Speaker 1: you can always judge a book by its cover and a rough spotty reading of its reviews.
Speaker 1: So you got any non tech news roundup before we get into the tech news roundup, not really not really it's cold That's it's nice out.
Speaker 1: It's cold.
Speaker 1: It's pretty warm out.
Speaker 0: Oh, it's gonna snow on Wednesday's cold.
Speaker 1: I think you're just aging at a preternaturally high rate cold.
Speaker 1: I mean I would wear shorts if I was biking in this weather.
Speaker 1: Nope But anyway before we get into the tech news roundup it time for things of the day.
Speaker 1: What do you got so?
Speaker 0: Way back at the first time we went to gamer X Right.
Speaker 0: There was a demo going on in a little in the room the sort of like the artist alley equivalent Right of this cute little pixely game involving a spider webbing stuff up.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah Yeah, and that was like the most amazing tiny game I had ever seen.
Speaker 0: and this tiny game was made With this engine called Pico 8. and what Pico 8 is if you don't know is a video game engine Basically simulating a video game console that never existed.
Speaker 0: It's like they made up a video game console that never existed.
Speaker 0: that is very simple and pixely somewhere Slightly better than an Atari 2600 but nowhere near an NES sort of situation I assume without the like chase the beam type nonsense, right?
Speaker 0: No, it's.
Speaker 0: it's you know, but it's it's modern programming wise like with Lua and such.
Speaker 0: It's made to be very easy to program.
Speaker 0: you can make bright and colorful simple games and other programs with it and this really amazing spider game was made like.
Speaker 0: I was shocked at how amazing this game was for the limitations afforded by the Not actually a real physical console the Pico 8 And the developer of that game was I don't know how to pronounce their internet name Which looks like bridges with the e removed
Speaker 1: British dev Right
Speaker 0: But yeah, so ever since then that game amazed me so much.
Speaker 0: I followed this person on Twitter and they recently began tweeting Links to their YouTube channel, which has basically nobody watching it of them.
Speaker 1: I'm the fifth person to like this 13 views guys.
Speaker 1: Come on, right?
Speaker 0: And these are the most amazing and complete Pico 8 dev Tutorials and also pixel art.
Speaker 0: right because you need to both skills to make games in Pico 8.
Speaker 0: You need the pixel art skills and also the programming skills But it's not very high levels of either one because it's low resolution and simple programming, right?
Speaker 0: It's like you need skills, but not that much right, but this person is made that amazing spider game and has increased their skills two years worth in that time and is still Maybe the Pico 8 master of the world as far as I can tell because I don't know any other Pico 8 masters.
Speaker 0: So if you want to program amazing simple games for Pico 8 or just be amazed at someone else doing it You need to watch this.
Speaker 0: this is like even though I'm probably never gonna make a Pico 8 anything I still watch this whole video.
Speaker 1: dude watching this already.
Speaker 1: They've convinced me to want to at least make like the simplest possible make a Tetris or something I don't know, right?
Speaker 0: But yeah, there's more than just this one.
Speaker 0: We're gonna link to the one video but check the whole channel and you can see a lot more.
Speaker 0: I got good stuff.
Speaker 0: I feel like there.
Speaker 0: it seems like they're continuing a whole series.
Speaker 0: That's gonna keep going and So it'll be worth your while.
Speaker 0: yeah a great way to just learn programming in general, too.
Speaker 1: So a lot of you are probably familiar with a song.
Speaker 1: Hey, mrs.
Speaker 1: Robinson, like mrs.
Speaker 1: Robinson is a song that people know.
Speaker 1: if you if you don't know anything about music if you hear the song of like Oh that song the song that like dad and grandpa always listen to but it's a song Scott always A lot of our listeners are like a full generation younger than even us.
Speaker 1: So, do you know the story of how that song was written?
Speaker 0: Simon and Garfunkel made a song or what it's about?
Speaker 1: vaguely, so On the dick of that show.
Speaker 0: dick have it.
Speaker 1: I've never seen this show.
Speaker 1: I don't know anything about this dick.
Speaker 0: Have it is Oh No incredibly famous person.
Speaker 1: This is not my interest in music focused mostly on Composition and classical dick have it wasn't music shows.
Speaker 1: It was a late show, which I also don't care about.
Speaker 1: Okay?
Speaker 1: Yeah, but anyway Paul Simon was on the show 1970.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: And this is a short segment where Paul Simon Explains the origin of the song.
Speaker 1: mrs.
Speaker 1: Robinson Mm-hmm, and the origin of the song was actually not what I expected at all and it's kind of funny.
Speaker 1: So I recommend you watch this.
Speaker 1: It's just a really good short interview.
Speaker 1: this short segment where Paul Simon describes how the song Robinson was written What it means and you can take that information and do with it what thou wilt in the meta moment.
Speaker 1: the book club book is Emily Wilson's translation of the Odyssey by Homer.
Speaker 0: I'm doing a real bad job of continuing to read it after my finishing of the introduction, dude
Speaker 1: I am so as soon as you once I keep
Speaker 0: doing other stuff instead
Speaker 1: Read the first chapter like the first book of it and then you'll just get into a cadence because it yeah.
Speaker 0: But I got.
Speaker 0: actually I'm doing all this other stuff Like I don't like.
Speaker 0: that is not like it didn't even when I even when I had free time like oh What should I do now?
Speaker 0: There were three attractive PC games calling me and I went and did that instead.
Speaker 0: but following Telemachus through his Interactions with I find it surprising that you're like you're really on the Telemachus boat.
Speaker 1: When was the Odyssey?
Speaker 0: Odysseus boat?
Speaker 1: the first half of the stupid book is just Telemachus going around like where's my dad?
Speaker 1: And then it cuts back to.
Speaker 1: so where was Odysseus?
Speaker 0: yes a good part.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's I claps the Telemachus that siren.
Speaker 0: the Telemachus stuff is pretty excited Because in this modern context I guess I meet up with Agamemnon or Agamemnon's wife at some point.
Speaker 1: Well right now He's hanging out with Menelaus.
Speaker 1: Actually, just hang out with Menelaus.
Speaker 0: Is it Menelaus?
Speaker 0: Isn't that Agamemnon's wife or something?
Speaker 1: Menelaus is not Agamemnon's wife.
Speaker 0: Who is Menelaus?
Speaker 0: That was someone important.
Speaker 0: I forget.
Speaker 1: He's a king.
Speaker 0: I At this point I knew who Menelaus was and I forgot.
Speaker 1: you'll find out a lot about him.
Speaker 1: what I forgot was I mixed up Calypso and Clemnestra and Cersei like the three of them.
Speaker 1: I got sorted out in my head now.
Speaker 0: Cersei's the witch.
Speaker 1: I know the other Calypso's the first goddess Odysseus was having sex with And it's interesting that this translation.
Speaker 1: It's not so much.
Speaker 1: Odysseus was trapped there longing for home while this goddess sext him.
Speaker 1: It was more like.
Speaker 1: Eventually, Odysseus got bored with this and wanted to go home.
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 1: There's a subtle change in the tone of that conversation That's right.
Speaker 1: I do feel like I would have stayed with Calypso to be perfectly honest.
Speaker 1: Of course Because half the other people talking about Odysseus.
Speaker 0: But rich people also think they're gonna stay on that island and then they don't.
Speaker 1: Yeah well Meanwhile, look at the reason the Telemachus part is so interesting because he basically just goes to all these other kings or people like his father and sees what their deal is and their deals are all pretty different.
Speaker 1: and Some of them got it going on pretty well.
Speaker 1: and anyway read this story.
Speaker 1: if you've never read the Odyssey read this translation.
Speaker 1: if The Odyssey bored you when you tried to read it a long time ago, and we'll talk about in the Ginkgo's book club.
Speaker 1: I don't want to really spoil anything about the Odyssey if you don't know what's going on.
Speaker 0: Spoil the Odyssey.
Speaker 0: Yeah I Love I just love you.
Speaker 0: spoil the Bible names.
Speaker 1: Anita's like yo Zeus, like.
Speaker 1: can you let Odysseus go home?
Speaker 1: And he's like, man, I want to let him go home.
Speaker 1: He's like the only smart human.
Speaker 0: just spoil us.
Speaker 0: just.
Speaker 0: well Dracula, but fucking Poseidon.
Speaker 1: Just what are you gonna do Frank?
Speaker 0: What do you want me to do about Poseidon?
Speaker 1: Like the half the stories of the Greek gods are yeah, but Poseidon is being a little piss, baby And I don't know what to do about it.
Speaker 1: What do you want me to do?
Speaker 1: I can't stop him.
Speaker 1: So, uh, yeah.
Speaker 1: Anyway, you should read that book and the previous book club book it which is still on the ignites website the fifth season by NK jemisin.
Speaker 1: if you haven't read that you should read that first because I don't know when Scott's gonna finish the finish.
Speaker 0: And other meta news.
Speaker 0: the most important meta news is that PAX East 2018 is ridiculously soon.
Speaker 0: Book my train less than a month ish away.
Speaker 1: I gotta write this panel.
Speaker 0: It is super duper soon.
Speaker 0: It is four days Thursday Friday Saturday Sunday and Thursday and Sunday are not sold out.
Speaker 1: you can totally go to those and as we've said Thursday and Sunday at PAX East are some of the best bang for your buck of Gaming convention.
Speaker 0: I think Thursday is just like a no-brainer to take off work and go for the one day Full packs day low attendance and you get the keynote Q&A the beginning.
Speaker 1: But Sunday if you can't take time off and you can't generally afford to go to cons It's one day where you could see the entire expo hall see some panels play a bunch
Speaker 0: of games and see the omega-thon finale But you'll get a few hours less than your other days of bags.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but you will see us on Sunday, won't you?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I got a really shitty panel time But better than no panel early in the morning at 10 30 a.m.
Speaker 1: Scott and I will be on Sunday April 8th in the arachnid theater doing the Fully evolved form of our 40 tabletop games.
Speaker 1: You must play panel, which is not just clickbait.
Speaker 1: There's legit learning and content in.
Speaker 1: here is just title is a trick.
Speaker 0: Yeah most articles that have clickbait titles that have clickbait content.
Speaker 0: we use a clickbait title to fill the seats and then have real content.
Speaker 1: and What we learned from?
Speaker 1: mag fast because we've been shying away from clickbait titles for a while.
Speaker 1: Holy shit, does the clickbait title fill the room?
Speaker 1: It works like yeah Why wouldn't it work?
Speaker 0: and you know, it works.
Speaker 0: just do you have the.
Speaker 0: are you shameless enough to do it?
Speaker 0: And rim is and Scott isn't.
Speaker 0: that's how it works.
Speaker 1: I mean remember we did our bad games panel that filled the goddamn room and they all thought we're gonna talk about like Avgn type stuff.
Speaker 1: Nope.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: So, uh, yeah, we'll see you at PAX East and also Even though it's four days.
Speaker 1: There's an open question.
Speaker 1: Will there be Wednesday pre packs gaming.
Speaker 1: Yes, and the answer is yes.
Speaker 1: So you could make PAX East a five-day con for all intents and purposes.
Speaker 0: Also in the meta you should go onto the internet and go if you mean you're listening to this podcast already or somehow If you're really sad watching any watching a live stream, you're one of those sad ten people watching this live.
Speaker 0: You should know that there's like a podcast.
Speaker 0: you can just get an mp3 and at least and it's still sad.
Speaker 0: So listen to us for an hour, but at least you could do it while doing something else.
Speaker 0: You don't have to look at our stupid faces if you're listening to the podcast.
Speaker 0: Well, if you are sadder than I think hope you are.
Speaker 0: you can watch a live stream of this instead on YouTube But also there are.
Speaker 0: we have many websites and social media accounts on Twitter and Instagram And even a Facebook page and we got a forum and you should go Because apparently you just love us that much.
Speaker 0: You should go on the internet to all the other places that we publish things and follow Subscribe and whatever you do there if that's something you really want to do.
Speaker 0: But if you take my advice, you'll unsubscribe not listen Never come to us again and go do something more valuable with your time Like play a good video game or watch an erudite movie or read the Odyssey Something like that.
Speaker 1: So I think it's time for the tech news roundup, mmm, so I put these in a vague order.
Speaker 1: We're just gonna go right through them.
Speaker 1: So first off the most important is the only tech news many of you care about right now is can I buy a GPU?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I talked about this before and you still can't buy a GPU yet.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: People are still mining their magic beans.
Speaker 1: So if you if you're trying to build a new computer, you're just aft.
Speaker 1: I just like I use 770 and just wait.
Speaker 0: I was so lucky and that my one computer was all busted, right?
Speaker 0: And then my HTPC was you know doing fine and I. but I needed to buy a new computer.
Speaker 0: So I did but I couldn't get a GPU for it.
Speaker 0: Even though the RAM was overpriced I was willing to pay for the overpriced RAM.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but cuz I heard a room wise RAM overpriced.
Speaker 1: I bought I paid.
Speaker 1: I paid so little for my RAM.
Speaker 0: How much was your RAM?
Speaker 1: I gotta go look again.
Speaker 1: all I know is I paid so little that I Originally just put 64 gig in.
Speaker 1: cuz why the fuck not?
Speaker 1: it was so cheap.
Speaker 0: I got 32, but the.
Speaker 0: I've heard that actually the GPUs are not there in shortage.
Speaker 0: It's that they can't make video cards because they don't have enough video RAM.
Speaker 0: I heard True or not though that could.
Speaker 0: it could be GPUs and RAM for all I know.
Speaker 0: But anyway What was I saying?
Speaker 0: right but I was lucky that my HTPC had a 1070 in it that I had bought at a reasonable price way back and so I just transfer that to my desktop and now my My HTPC just doesn't have a GPU in it.
Speaker 0: But that's fine because I rarely use the GPU in the HTPC.
Speaker 1: I mean my HTPC has a 460 in it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but the thing is I was thinking aha I'll go get a 1050 to put in that HTPC.
Speaker 0: now that I know it doesn't really need much more than that.
Speaker 0: Ah shit them 1050s are overpriced too those.
Speaker 1: So I I literally just lucked out and bought it.
Speaker 1: I basically bought my 1080 at the bottom possible price for a 1080.
Speaker 0: Here's the problem is.
Speaker 0: you think I can go get like a 950 or something, right?
Speaker 0: But here's the thing though.
Speaker 0: the 10 series like the 1070 Uses way less power way less than the 680 that I was replacing.
Speaker 0: I actually sold that 680 to a listener because the 680 couldn't go in the HTPC used too much power and was.
Speaker 0: Yet the 1070 is orders of magnitude faster.
Speaker 0: Maybe not but it's many many percent faster and use Electricity.
Speaker 1: that's why I was like, hey you want my 770 because that has pretty much the same problem.
Speaker 0: No Too much power.
Speaker 0: It's way not it's not efficient at all.
Speaker 0: There's your GPUs.
Speaker 0: nose fuck everyone with coins.
Speaker 0: Yep, you got your mining coins get fucked.
Speaker 1: Here's the news.
Speaker 1: that's interesting from a bunch of perspectives.
Speaker 1: Apparently a bunch of people are pirating features of Spotify, right?
Speaker 0: So if you get Spotify for free, which you can do it's very limited.
Speaker 0: First of all, it's loaded with ads.
Speaker 0: you have to listen to ads after you listen to music.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and you can only skip songs in a playlist like so many times if you like the radio mode.
Speaker 0: and eventually it's like Disables your skip button and you have to actually like do something else to skip around and listen to different songs and whatnot.
Speaker 0: Right as it turns out.
Speaker 0: Some of these features are implemented server-side and cannot be circumvented by.
Speaker 0: if you're not paying for a Spotify you know.
Speaker 0: but other features were implemented client-side and could be Circumvented if you simply don't use the official Spotify client and use some evil pirated Spotify client.
Speaker 1: So like here's here's a synthetic example.
Speaker 1: I'm not saying this is what they did, but this to give you some perspective.
Speaker 1: So say I got in Spotify.
Speaker 1: There's the skip button and when you hit that button It makes like a web a call to a web service that says hey skip to the next song Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: So the while you clicked on something in the GUI in the browser It called an API somewhere in the sky for Spotify to do a thing did a thing.
Speaker 1: So let's say that in the GUI I just disable that button.
Speaker 1: Well, the user is using Spotify.
Speaker 1: if I know enough information.
Speaker 1: I could just with like curl or something or basically any script hit that API directly Because it's accessible via the internet.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's on the internet the clients connecting to it somehow.
Speaker 1: It probably isn't Like cryptographically secure independent of that client.
Speaker 1: No, I mean sometimes they are.
Speaker 1: I've seen API's that are secure in that way, but Yeah, if the API works and you just disabled the GUI Anyone can hit that API and make it do its thing.
Speaker 0: So Spotify detected who was doing this.
Speaker 0: They saw that like free accounts were skipping songs rapidly or making patterns of API calls that were not API call patterns that you would see from the official Spotify client.
Speaker 0: and for those people they sent them a letter saying yo or email Saying hey, we see that you're using a pirated non-official Spotify client there.
Speaker 0: We disabled your Spotify account.
Speaker 0: use the real Spotify client again, and we will re-enable you.
Speaker 0: I saw this by just paying for Spotify.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I paid.
Speaker 1: I ended up paying for Amazon instead But it's equivalent.
Speaker 0: Amazon one does not is good for the.
Speaker 0: so here's the thing, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I had the Amazon one and Spotify and what I was doing is this uploading music to Amazon because you can't upload music to Spotify really and using Spotify to get new music and thus I would never need to get new mp3s ever.
Speaker 0: All right, cuz new music from Spotify I can stream it all.
Speaker 0: my existing library of mp3s from back in the day is 100% on Amazon.
Speaker 0: I'm good.
Speaker 0: What happened was is I then paid for YouTube red to get rid of ads on YouTube.
Speaker 0: YouTube red comes with Google Play music.
Speaker 1: Oh shit.
Speaker 1: I forgot it does so YouTube red.
Speaker 1: I just started paying for YouTube red like a week ago.
Speaker 0: YouTube red gives you free Google Play music as like if they they're the Same thing basically.
Speaker 0: In fact, I heard a Google executive say that they consider YouTube red to be a music service because it also comes with the YouTube Music app that lets you they use YouTube as a Pandora or whatever Like it has the app lets you like watch YouTube and audio only mode anyway.
Speaker 0: But yeah it gets rid of ads on YouTube and The Google Play music also sort of makes the Amazon music redundant because you can upload all your music there.
Speaker 0: So I uploaded all my music to Amazon to Google and then I stopped uploading it to Amazon.
Speaker 0: I stopped paying for that because the Google one.
Speaker 0: that way I'm not paying for three things.
Speaker 0: I'm paying for two things.
Speaker 0: Yep, cuz it wasn't gonna stop paying for YouTube YouTube red, right?
Speaker 0: So now I use Google Play music Which is free with YouTube red for uploading all my mp3s to the clouds like listen to them anywhere and I use Spotify for streaming Musics because really the music selection on Google Play music of streaming is not the greatest.
Speaker 0: However The other scary contender is Apple music which might be a contender for Spotify, right?
Speaker 0: There's so much stuff.
Speaker 0: I'm used to on Spotify.
Speaker 0: I don't want to give up but the Apple music is actually really good and works with an Apple watch and does fancy stuff and has a great selection.
Speaker 0: and so maybe for the streaming one as I did the free demo of Apple music and I was like Oh not bad, but it couldn't really completely kill Spotify.
Speaker 0: So like stuck with.
Speaker 1: now more interesting going down to this layer of there are like you can just do Spotify in a web browser.
Speaker 1: Sure, we have an app on a phone.
Speaker 1: The more interesting question is around like with the web.
Speaker 1: There's this fundamental contract that you could use any web browser to hit any URI and interact with it and it's on the server side to handle any sort of authorizations and Restrictions and walls and whatever.
Speaker 1: so I could use whatever browser I want.
Speaker 1: I can use whatever client I want.
Speaker 1: Should the similar principle be applied to services like Spotify?
Speaker 0: I mean technologically but also they emailed you and shut your account down.
Speaker 1: so she can do about true true But at the same time, uh, well, I mean one.
Speaker 1: they really should secure the API's themselves.
Speaker 0: How do you implement a no skip button API on the service end?
Speaker 0: I can think of some ways while still allowing people to say double click on a song to play it if it's you know A completely different song.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean the details of how I would implement that are pretty Too much for this show.
Speaker 1: Uh-huh.
Speaker 0: But the real point is not easy.
Speaker 1: Well, it's it's definitely some sort of risk-based security in that the risk of users doing this doesn't cost them much and it's easy for them to take a non technological means to Highlight the people who are causing the problem and force them to start paying or at least enable them to start paying.
Speaker 1: but I guess is there a future place for a right to Use your own clients for a service and it's up to the service to provide the API driven rules of engagement.
Speaker 1: What's the line between a website and an app and a service and a web and all these things and I have moral problem with it.
Speaker 0: I'm just saying it happens.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I just think it's interesting.
Speaker 1: I'm very interested that there are people who spent the time to figure this out and went so far as to make the pirate clients.
Speaker 1: So in some other news there are a bunch of LTE vulnerabilities hitherto unknown to the world that are now Well known to the world as affects everyone with a phone.
Speaker 0: Yeah, everybody.
Speaker 1: I didn't read into the details.
Speaker 0: But basically Android iPhones y'all got LTE everybody.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if you're on an LTE network, I think it says ten attacks were announced by this paper Ranging from things like snooping on text messages tracking individual users locations and more funnily spoofing emergency alerts.
Speaker 1: the only hope I have is that If these were that easy to execute people would already be executing the New York City Because that would be the most bang for your buck in terms of like sending a spoofed emergency alert.
Speaker 1: And I have not yet seen a spoofed emergency alert.
Speaker 1: But apparently based on what I'm reading in the summary on slash shot The only real barrier to enter it using these is you need to spend a few thousand dollars on a software-defined radio As in a radio device that can be modulated by software purely as opposed to having some sort of hardware Limitation and where it can transmit.
Speaker 1: I don't want to get into what that means because it's kind of complicated but we've talked about this on geek nights a long time ago about how a Purely software controlled transmitter is very dangerous to a lot of existing infrastructure because a lot of existing infrastructure in America relies heavily on the fact that consumers cannot get their hands on radios that can transmit certain kinds of information on certain frequency bands and software radios sidestep all of that.
Speaker 1: So, uh, yeah the real the only thing you can do unless you want to exploit these things is Treat LTL T off on your phone.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and I'm sure 3g is just so secure.
Speaker 1: The only real thing you can do is the thing you should already be doing Treat LTE data transfers like they are a completely open network Mm-hmm, if you're not using TLS on anything that you're sending or receiving then Assume that people are reading it
Speaker 0: get some VPN on your phone.
Speaker 1: You don't use SMS for anything you care about because that's just clear text.
Speaker 1: That is like the most trivial exploit and In terms of the location tracking if you actually care about not being tracked because you're doing something shady Put your phone in airplane mode before you do the shady thing Like that, that's all you can do right now.
Speaker 1: Hmm so in some other news, that's actually really good news YouTube.
Speaker 0: They made a bunch of changes recently and the ones that changes coincided with the time that they demonetized They because they before remember those in news about him.
Speaker 0: They were gonna demonetize people whose accounts weren't big enough.
Speaker 0: Yeah Well, they actually that was just a warning when that news happened that they were telling people they were gonna get demonetized.
Speaker 0: now They're demonetized.
Speaker 0: Yep, but then they released a bunch of new features to go along with that demonetization.
Speaker 0: I think they were probably all in the same patch maybe or something.
Speaker 1: Yeah now, I I'm pretty okay with the scope of the demonetization.
Speaker 1: I know that's an unpopular opinion, but the geek nice Channel is way way like my personal YouTube channel way above the minimum.
Speaker 0: Mine was not.
Speaker 0: I got to monetize which is actually good.
Speaker 0: It's not.
Speaker 1: life is a lot easier, but For a channel that is moderately popular and way above the line I'm making under 50 bucks a month.
Speaker 0: It's yeah, I mean even people who are big on YouTube don't make good money Unless you're mega big.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so the people my best estimate the people who were below the line were making Maybe a dozen dollars a month tops Reality.
Speaker 1: you can't expect a platform like YouTube to subsidize the monetization of very small content because The real problem the real thing they were trying to address is that a lot of small channels not the majority but enough.
Speaker 1: We're like right-wing Nazi racist bullshit.
Speaker 1: You can't risk ads appearing on that and you can't have humans vent Tens and hundreds of thousands of YouTube channels that have 18 subscribers.
Speaker 1: But anyway the change that's good.
Speaker 1: That's really good that no one should disagree with that YouTube added is They've added live captioning.
Speaker 1: so a live stream Will have pretty good live closed captions including theoretically this stream.
Speaker 1: right now I'm gonna see if I can watch them.
Speaker 1: I don't know if I can watch them on the like Special viewer.
Speaker 1: I got here for the live stream but they added it and I looked at our previous two live streams and the captions are Shockingly good.
Speaker 1: Mmm, despite the fact that me and Scott talk very fast and talk over each other and use a lot of proper nouns It has that shit down except it seemed to skip every time we said the word fuck.
Speaker 1: It's just skipped right over it reliably.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they added some other features But I forget what they were right now and only one of them other ones besides the captions was interesting But the captions are the biggest one.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: No, what's that extra?
Speaker 0: Finally, right?
Speaker 0: It's like there have been so many things over the years like do you pay for someone to transcribe geek nights?
Speaker 0: You tried many things and there's never been good results.
Speaker 1: Well, we really
Speaker 0: really wanted to get geek nights into text form so that people who are hard-of-hearing could absorb it and now we finally have a way that is freer and Better than all the previous ways short of paying a zillion dollars or someone actually do it by hand.
Speaker 1: Yep now it looks like we still don't have live captions but The other part of this is that the captions that come after the fact because our live streams all have captions like the next day I'd you clicked on them all to check.
Speaker 0: They're so good that I don't need to pay anymore because as you might recall not perfect But you know what if you otherwise can't hear they actually some mostly accurately represent what we are saying.
Speaker 1: so one we started crowdsourcing captions and some listeners stepped up and actually like Made captions for some of our lectures and they're really good.
Speaker 1: I'm really thankful for that.
Speaker 1: I also took a bunch of the patreon money for geek nights and I bought professional captions for several of our videos.
Speaker 1: I know that was many hundreds of dollars each.
Speaker 1: They were really good.
Speaker 1: Their turnaround was really fast.
Speaker 1: The YouTube captions are good enough to where I think we're just gonna let those go Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: What is interesting is one of the companies I paid to do this actually like Message me and thanked me for paying them because they said that basically that entire industry is completely disappearing.
Speaker 1: as AI driven captions like YouTube just do it automatically.
Speaker 0: I mean, it sounds good.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm pretty okay with that.
Speaker 1: So I feel like the next accessibility frontier for geek nights.
Speaker 1: I Might try paying someone to translate one of our popular lectures into Spanish.
Speaker 1: That's something that is that not happening.
Speaker 0: Is that the top language though that we're trying to reach?
Speaker 0: I feel like that is the top language that has a Downplay Spanish, but it's just like yeah, we should definitely go for I mean we go to all the languages.
Speaker 0: if we could write Look at the the Demographics of people visiting the videos and go in order from top to bottom of the demographics of people visiting the videos is all English-speaking countries.
Speaker 1: I feel like it's a catch-22 there, right?
Speaker 0: But I'm talking like do are we getting a lot of people from like China?
Speaker 0: we go Chinese that more, you know.
Speaker 0: So I'll tell you right now most blocked in China, uh, probably We're probably blocked in Thailand too.
Speaker 1: If they ever saw what we said about the king.
Speaker 0: Can Hong Kong get to us, you know You know Japan Korea India, you know, there's a lot of countries out there with a lot of languages.
Speaker 1: so in terms of underserved markets in video game designs specifically I feel like there is the biggest interest gap between people who want this content and Not that content not being provided for them in Spanish Partly based on the fact that pillow fight the company that I'm slightly involved with with our friends released a game.
Speaker 1: Spanish language was a day one like launch thing and the game is set in like the Cuban community in Florida and There's a big sense.
Speaker 1: There is a big response to that because a lot of games don't include Spanish language support.
Speaker 1: No There is.
Speaker 1: there are a lot of kids who would probably love to watch a lecture on how to design games in Spanish.
Speaker 0: Slay the spire has a lot of languages support.
Speaker 0: I just want to say good news.
Speaker 1: I still got to play it.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna play it this weekend.
Speaker 1: I think The other feature they added this that's concurrent to this.
Speaker 1: that's interesting is the live stream.
Speaker 1: right now If you're watching this there are people chatting in our live stream.
Speaker 1: There's actually 17 people in there right now.
Speaker 0: So say so.
Speaker 1: what they're also doing is they're keeping that metadata.
Speaker 1: So if you watch one of our live streams of geek nights The chat will update live like it did when the stream itself was live.
Speaker 1: That's a minor thing but that's I think an important thing for the future and for archives because imagine being able to go back to like on Twitch in the future and watch the overwatch championships from a hundred years ago and See the actual chats Instream from a hundred years ago.
Speaker 1: That's the kind of cool stuff like.
Speaker 1: it's a really.
Speaker 1: it's not an important feature that many of you care about now But you're gonna be really thankful for that feature in a decade when you watch some old YouTube video And see these vintage chats.
Speaker 0: Here's a news that's related but rim doesn't have it over there.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so what's going down to something going down on Twitch right now, right?
Speaker 0: There's this guy.
Speaker 0: I don't know his name.
Speaker 0: I forgot his name because I don't the article up and he has streaming fortnight.
Speaker 0: He's a used to Used to be a big halo eSports champion.
Speaker 0: But now he's streaming fortnight and he has a zillion subscribers and he's gonna make.
Speaker 0: he stands to make like 250 K I think and subscriber monies this month is the disrespect guy.
Speaker 0: No This is actually an okay guy, okay As far as I know he's an okay guy But what's happening is people are suspecting that what's?
Speaker 0: he doesn't actually have that many legitimate Subscribers even though he didn't necessarily as far as we know do anything awful.
Speaker 0: Apparently this is the story.
Speaker 0: that is probably what's going on.
Speaker 0: So if you have a twitch prime account Amazon Prime plus twitch You get some fortnight skins and stuff as like a gift.
Speaker 0: Oh right now.
Speaker 0: So people on eBay and such are buying and selling Amazon, you know credentials to people with prime that have not, you know Cuz a lot of people get Amazon Prime that are not using twitch, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, and if you get their credentials Link up get a twitch prime you can get those skins Right and you can just load up on skins and all kinds of stuff for fortnight if you can manage to get lots of Amazon Prime accounts, so And you know, it's not like kids who play fortnight have Amazon Prime,
Speaker 1: I think there's an article on Newsweek about this
Speaker 0: maybe but apparently what's happening is those accounts that are like bought and sold of twitch.
Speaker 0: a twitch prime account comes with a Once a month free Subscription to any twitch channel.
Speaker 1: So every month I go and subscribe all these channels subscribing to this one person.
Speaker 0: every month I go and subscribe to the twitch channel of my choosing and I lose nothing.
Speaker 0: I just click on a twitch channel and that person gets two dollars and fifty cents and and twitch gets two dollars and fifty cents from Amazon, which is their own money, I guess.
Speaker 0: but Yeah, it's like.
Speaker 0: all I had to do is click and I can.
Speaker 0: I can give two dollars fifty cents to one twitch channel per Every month like an AGD Q months.
Speaker 0: I'll choose.
Speaker 0: that's like two months out of the year.
Speaker 0: I'll choose them other months.
Speaker 0: I'll choose whoever I'm watching the most or someone I know or ever right.
Speaker 0: But yeah, these peep these bots or whatever that are like loading up on fortnight skins It's like well, they got free subs attached to them.
Speaker 0: They're all subbing to like this dude and also other people and they can see like a flood.
Speaker 0: This guy can see like a huge flood of subscriptions coming in like hundreds and hundreds at a time because you know He's got the auto notifiers.
Speaker 0: He can respond and thank.
Speaker 0: Striving it's like doesn't be a flood of them.
Speaker 0: Like oh my god.
Speaker 0: It's got a thousand descriptions all at once.
Speaker 0: What the hell?
Speaker 0: Right and now he's still.
Speaker 0: if that happens to him he stands to gain $2.50 for each one of those.
Speaker 0: but this twitch prime fortnight promotion stands to end soon at like in a month or so.
Speaker 0: People are suspecting that the end of the month this guy and others who are also been Unvictimized by this Stand to lose a shit ton of subscribers and all those Amazon prime things just stop Right because they're subscribed for one month and when the month ends like this subscriber count supposedly would just drop like a rock.
Speaker 0: So this is really really interesting.
Speaker 0: We'll see if they actually get paid out or not.
Speaker 1: Well, yeah you.
Speaker 1: the fundamental question here from a technology standpoint is that Whenever you set up a system where one party at no cost to them Can give a boom that has some monetary value to an unrelated account or person There will be massive immediate programmatic exploitation of that vacuum.
Speaker 1: it's like gifting arbitrage and I don't know.
Speaker 1: I feel like that has to have been baked Like people who designed these systems had to have assumed this would happen on purpose hoping that it would drive subscriptions.
Speaker 1: I can't believe anyone beat would be so naive as to not expect this kind of thing.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the guy looked up the guy.
Speaker 0: the guy's name is ninja.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I found him.
Speaker 1: The problem is there's this like piece of shit streamer who's in all the news for being racist?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't know if the if the ninja guy is a good guy.
Speaker 0: I don't know anything about this guy, but he's just in the headline for this larger story.
Speaker 1: Yeah, ninja kept popping up.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm Okay.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think that's the guy.
Speaker 1: anyway I'm organizing our news.
Speaker 1: So next news you might have noticed there was a Twitter bot purge.
Speaker 1: so Twitter has a problem in that basically there are Thousands and thousands and thousands of what are literally Russian like psyops bot accounts tweeting Nonsense to try to destabilize the American democracy like this.
Speaker 1: We know that's not even under dispute.
Speaker 0: Also other democracy.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, but other democracies too, but I'm focusing on the one that the one that's really affecting my day-to-day life right now.
Speaker 1: but This is not a new problem.
Speaker 1: We've known for a long time that there are a lot of Bot accounts on Twitter and that it's a big problem.
Speaker 0: I wonder if Russians are sending those all caps emails to do.
Speaker 1: I would not be surprised at all.
Speaker 1: So the deal is Twitter refuses to do anything reasonable about this and I think my the main reason for that This is not.
Speaker 1: this is pure speculation.
Speaker 0: There are then no numbers of how many accounts there.
Speaker 0: I will go way down.
Speaker 1: I suspect in my Personal opinion that a huge percentage of all the traffic on Twitter is bots.
Speaker 1: Bots tweeting at bots.
Speaker 1: Yep So the well, but then the side problem is that out of this bot churn.
Speaker 1: There's a surprising number of Humans who I think the way I want to describe this is the in ten years ago.
Speaker 1: I would say.
Speaker 1: the problem is you know We like there are things that don't pass the Turing test like.
Speaker 1: will this system pass the Turing test today?
Speaker 1: There are people who fail to administer the Turing test.
Speaker 1: It's like its own reverse Turing test.
Speaker 1: There are human beings who look at one of these like Russian bot accounts and think it's a legitimate person.
Speaker 0: People have always fallen.
Speaker 0: they see a website and they think that's a real download link.
Speaker 0: Yeah, people can't tell real from fake.
Speaker 0: They don't have that skill.
Speaker 0: It's very dangerous in a world.
Speaker 0: So we're in a world of deadly poison.
Speaker 0: It's it's like here.
Speaker 0: I've got a better example.
Speaker 0: Yeah in a in a field of mushrooms You better know which ones are poisoning which ones aren't right?
Speaker 0: We walk around and take for granted that we can just tell by looking at it.
Speaker 1: No, sir I walk around.
Speaker 1: I assume that everything I ever see on the internet is both malware and a lie.
Speaker 0: Right, but the point is we can walk around the mushroom field That is the internet and without been eat tons of mushrooms without ever getting poisoned.
Speaker 0: most people just get poisoned immediately and die but it just.
Speaker 1: it amazes me that like you me or Emily will like Look at a website and be like that is obviously a scam.
Speaker 1: and then there will be a person another human being who is Ostensibly as intelligent in us will look at the exact same website and say looks legit and put their credit card number in.
Speaker 0: They were not cooked in the fire.
Speaker 0: We have it.
Speaker 0: We have a great privilege of having been cooked in internet fires so most people do not have
Speaker 1: what Twitter did is they purged a huge number of like specifically identified bot accounts And what was interesting about this is that there was a huge outcry From Twitter users over the loss of all these legitimate people.
Speaker 0: Are you sure there weren't bots?
Speaker 0: So, here's what happened.
Speaker 0: the complaining also.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna summarize what happened where the bots also the ones complaining about the legitimate users the people who were complaining were Far-right supremacist like white supremacist.
Speaker 0: Are you sure they were just also bots that are right supremacist bots.
Speaker 1: now We're pretty sure there's a lot of people who are actually known people.
Speaker 1: Okay It seems like what happened is the real Nazis and the real Republicans noticed overnight that they lost Thousands and thousands and thousands of followers Because big percentage of their followers were these Russian bots Mm-hmm, and that is the outcry.
Speaker 1: if you see any news about people like talking about this Twitter purge.
Speaker 1: Every one of these accounts with few exceptions was a known bot account and now there's an outcry by people who are mad that these bot accounts are gone, but those people pretty much are almost exclusively far-right wing people and While these bots were also trying to target left-wing politics, it seems like on average people who are more liberal either didn't notice subscriber drops or Realized.
Speaker 1: they were bots and did not thus complain.
Speaker 1: The real problem is that these bot accounts are still ubiquitous not just on Twitter, but all across social media.
Speaker 1: It is obvious which ones are bots and yet very few entities are choosing to do anything about it.
Speaker 1: And I feel like the Underlying story is that this kind of information warfare is real is dangerous and the u.s In particular is doing almost nothing to combat it.
Speaker 0: I got a good solution.
Speaker 0: Here's how it works All right, everyone's Twitter account is temporarily suspended.
Speaker 0: All right everyone who comes and pays a visit to judge Scott and gets judged by judge Scott to be Having a Twitter account as their account reinstated the end.
Speaker 0: Yeah problem solved get out.
Speaker 1: I feel like spy agencies need to hire the kinds of people who aren't tricked by phishing And just use them to solve a lot of these problems.
Speaker 1: So in some other news, uh This particular news is not a danger to you because there's no way it'll come to pass but this is the kind of thing that comes up perennially and Generate.
Speaker 0: I usually hear this kind of news in the UK Yeah But it happened in the u.s.
Speaker 1: In Rhode Island of all things.
Speaker 1: basically Democrats in Rhode Island put forth a bill Now before you think that what I'm about to say is crazy or novel.
Speaker 1: bills like this have been coming up in American state-level politics since I was in middle school and we would like organize around writing campaigns to stop them.
Speaker 1: But the gist is Rhode Island.
Speaker 1: These the Democrats here But it is a bipartisan bill as far as I can tell want to force all ISPs that provide internet in the state to block Sexual content and offensive material.
Speaker 1: So Wikipedia and then anyone who wants to access that material can pay a fee of $20.
Speaker 0: Where does that money go?
Speaker 0: the state.
Speaker 1: that money goes to a state slush fund that I guess will be used.
Speaker 0: They're trying to fight.
Speaker 0: They're trying to make porn human trafficking or something trying to make a porn tax.
Speaker 1: basically There is.
Speaker 1: so there is no way this would pass musters.
Speaker 0: the Supreme Court Even the current right people always talk about freedom of speech with like Twitter blocks them.
Speaker 0: But it's like that's not.
Speaker 0: government says the show that this is government station is go.
Speaker 0: This is the First Amendment.
Speaker 0: this one First amendment, this is it.
Speaker 0: Here it is.
Speaker 0: Yeah, Italy you found here's used to go attack this.
Speaker 0: We don't love porn.
Speaker 1: This is the kind of thing that you don't even really need to fight because we these are the fights that we win by default.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like I am not afraid that this is going to become law and even with the conservative leading Supreme Court of the United States I'm pretty confident.
Speaker 1: This would not pass even the most minimal muster.
Speaker 0: No, this is this is not going anywhere.
Speaker 0: But yeah, but here you go.
Speaker 0: Here's your here's your First Amendment battle.
Speaker 0: That's actually happening.
Speaker 1: Yep So here's a kind of interesting story.
Speaker 1: The headline was oh, this story is huge this one 23,000 complicated HTTPS so TLS certificates X Meaning like destroyed shut down revoked or whatever After the CEO emails the private keys to someone.
Speaker 0: Okay, so here's so much going on.
Speaker 0: There's so much going on here.
Speaker 0: I've tried to read it and like figure it all out and here's probably I'm gonna just say right out probably incorrect But this is what I've gathered so far.
Speaker 0: There was a company called Semantic, right?
Speaker 0: It's semantic.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 0: Okay, and they were issuing certificates to people.
Speaker 0: They did a really shitty fucking job Really shitty fucking job.
Speaker 0: another company digi cert who also was in the certificate business, right?
Speaker 0: But semantic There was another company Called.
Speaker 0: what's the third company called?
Speaker 1: Uh So we got.
Speaker 1: did you serve.
Speaker 1: we got semantic?
Speaker 0: What's the other god?
Speaker 1: I'm looking for it.
Speaker 1: trust to co-trust to coach.
Speaker 1: I've never heard of before.
Speaker 0: but yeah Trustico was also issued certificates, but at one time issued certificates on behalf of Semantic, right?
Speaker 0: So it's like they were issuing semantic certs to people.
Speaker 0: right, but they're not now they're now they're just doing their own certificates.
Speaker 0: yeah, the Digi cert bought up semantic.
Speaker 0: the people at trust to co Contacted digicer and were like, hey Semantic was that we're doing a really shitty job.
Speaker 0: a lot of their certificates are compromised.
Speaker 0: Please revoke them.
Speaker 0: Yep, did you sir?
Speaker 0: It was like.
Speaker 0: No, we're not going to revoke those certs, right because what basically would happen is those people instead of just you know Renewing their certs when the time came and giving more money to digicer wouldn't maybe you know Perhaps by.
Speaker 0: I don't know why but they didn't do it.
Speaker 0: Yep, so The CEO of trust to co took the private keys.
Speaker 0: I don't know if these are the private keys on their side or the private keys on the client side But yeah, and also closure as much as we both know about TLS.
Speaker 0: I still have to like I don't know but he emailed private keys to.
Speaker 0: Did you sir?
Speaker 0: Which means well, we got to revoke these fucking things now.
Speaker 0: Yeah But why did trust to go have private keys, they're not supposed to have those.
Speaker 0: how did they even get them?
Speaker 0: I don't understand what the fuck is going on.
Speaker 1: Here's an analogy that's simpler.
Speaker 1: Let's say you lost your password to some like bullshitting website.
Speaker 0: Let's say you call the locksmith.
Speaker 0: Why did the locksmith keep a key to your fucking house?
Speaker 1: Yeah, or very specific this happens Have you ever tried to reset your password on a website and they send you your password in?
Speaker 1: If they usually they'll say all right set a new password Cuz.
Speaker 1: yeah, we can't give you your old password.
Speaker 1: if they if they can give you your old password Their system is way insecure and awful.
Speaker 1: They have just told you.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we are the worst and everything Forever.
Speaker 1: do not trust us, right?
Speaker 0: So here's the thing.
Speaker 0: is that you know the whole.
Speaker 0: the reason that when you get an SSL cert You need to go to one of these companies to basically prove who you are because not only does it encrypt It was just encryption.
Speaker 0: We can all just make our own keys and not even give a shit.
Speaker 1: I can self sign a certificate right now, right?
Speaker 0: The reason we have these other these authorities that sign certs is because we want to make sure that whoever has the certificate for your bank comm is actually somebody from your bank comm.
Speaker 0: otherwise Scott can go make a website your bank comm and make the little green thing light up saying yeah This is totally your bank comm lol.
Speaker 0: Whereas right now is if I was to hack your DNS and make you go to Scott server instead of your bank comm server I can't do anything and it's gonna have a red lock up there and you're gonna know hey, this is a fake my bank Comm.
Speaker 0: you're not fooling me and to log it in right?
Speaker 0: So that's why you need these third-party companies.
Speaker 0: But if these third-party companies are not trustworthy and start issuing certs to everybody and their mother This is how we get problems.
Speaker 0: and here we have an example of that problem actually happening.
Speaker 0: It's not just a hypothetical thing.
Speaker 1: It happened and part of this is there's.
Speaker 0: there's a lot of 23,000 websites compromised.
Speaker 1: there are a lot of like competing interests here.
Speaker 1: on one hand Setting up TLS certs with like a real chain of trust is a giant pain in the ass.
Speaker 1: Yep, that causes a lot of friction and like beardos will complain Look, oh, I don't want to have to get permission from someone.
Speaker 0: Let's encrypt it.
Speaker 0: lets you do it way easy.
Speaker 0: We're using it for our forum and it works great.
Speaker 0: It's just not you know, it's just clear that this is not Maximum trust.
Speaker 1: like if I went to my bank and my bank had a lesson let's encrypt.
Speaker 1: I'd be a little dubious of that because let's encrypt.
Speaker 1: as a company I don't necessarily know how well they vet the use of certificates.
Speaker 1: Like for example, if my bank has their certificate with their private key However, they've set it up If the private key is compromised such that some nefarious actor or some disgruntled employee from the issuing authority Could like sign another certificate that was just as valid then the bank is hosed and people can steal all my biz.
Speaker 1: Yep, so adding friction to the process by making people prove who they are and having Costs and fees in the transactions to prevent sort of like spam attacks on these systems You'll notice that some websites in the corner of the browser appear more secure than others.
Speaker 0: They have like, you know, even more green shit up there usually Ten pictures of locks and a picture of a vault and a picture of a security officer and the word secure in green letters.
Speaker 0: Yeah, all that shit means they paid more money and they went through more hassle to prove how how good they are.
Speaker 1: Yep, it is it is a hassle.
Speaker 1: so there's these all these competing interests, but the reality is that the trust infrastructure of the internet is still run pretty much exclusively by private companies who have a lot of deep failings.
Speaker 1: and When there's a problem like digit search doing a pretty good job as far as I can see like companies can fix it.
Speaker 1: But you have to be able to revoke certificates.
Speaker 1: But people are very leery of revoking certificates because that breaks things on the enemy.
Speaker 0: if they had revoked him That means 23,000 websites that were green would suddenly be red and all those customers would start complaining like what the fuck Everyone.
Speaker 0: it's like recalling a product.
Speaker 0: only the pain in the ass is harder than just buying something.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like shipping something back and getting a like a new.
Speaker 0: like I've had my fire extinguisher recalled like twice.
Speaker 0: It was really easy to get a new one or mail back the old one.
Speaker 0: It'd be a lot harder to go redo all my SSL bullshit.
Speaker 1: That's not what I do and imagine if you run like a giant website with like load balancers, which The interaction between TLS and load balancers is something that particularly pains me.
Speaker 0: Anyway, yeah.
Speaker 1: So anyway, this is all time.
Speaker 0: Have we gone through here?
Speaker 1: Oh, we can wrap this up pretty soon.
Speaker 1: Let's go through a few of the rest.
Speaker 1: So brief news in case you you know, you probably assume this is true But this is the evidence that it is true.
Speaker 1: PC sales are dropping like 2.7% year-over-year.
Speaker 0: I think most people, you know use their phone their tablet and their smart TV or whatever.
Speaker 0: Pretty much does everything that they do if they're not creating content or playing PC games.
Speaker 1: So that's not.
Speaker 1: PCs are dead.
Speaker 0: Expert people who are just consumers of content that are not high-end, you know GPU needing video games that can't be played on consoles are Not buying desktop PCs.
Speaker 0: They're getting rid of the one they got and that's it.
Speaker 1: and even more people who need a real Quinn quotes computer more and more are just buying a laptop, right?
Speaker 0: or you know A lot of people.
Speaker 0: Nintendo switch is real popular.
Speaker 0: ps4 is pretty popular.
Speaker 0: It's like and roku boxes.
Speaker 0: I've tweeted the other week like hey Maybe the GPU shortage is really just like.
Speaker 0: maybe Nintendo is Satoshi.
Speaker 0: and they mean they started the coin Because they knew this would happen in a long game.
Speaker 0: and now people are buying consoles.
Speaker 0: cuz well get a GPU So I need to play some games.
Speaker 1: But yeah I feel like the future of desktop PCs which we've predicted before is going to be just the old definition of the word workstation.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they are workstations.
Speaker 1: They are specialized tools elegant weapons from a more civilized age and you're only gonna have one.
Speaker 0: They're gonna be used for people who need to make things like programming or digital art use some Adobe Photoshop for real or play games.
Speaker 1: Yep, that are not.
Speaker 1: that the people who want to play PC games is the thing as opposed to console game.
Speaker 0: My only concern is that if you grow up with a tablet or iPhone and you know The reason I am a creator of digital things is because I grew up Using a desktop PC and learned how to program and all that stuff with it.
Speaker 0: If you don't grow up with a dangerous weapon, then when are you gonna learn to use the dangerous weapon?
Speaker 0: Yeah, are we people just like when all the people right now who Photoshop things are dead?
Speaker 0: Is anyone else gonna learn Photoshop?
Speaker 1: So enter I've been interacting just through like co-workers and people I know With like kids are in the single-digit ages right now.
Speaker 1: I do not know what generation they are But they are so alien to Millennials and Generation X that they're like a different race of beings.
Speaker 1: nine year olds today on YouTube are Shockingly sophisticated at YouTube.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but how are they at, you know, Brighton and see?
Speaker 1: but so One I think what is going to keep?
Speaker 1: because I think Desktop PCs will continue to serve the things that I care about for the rest of my life and the reason for that is that PC gaming is actually growing and While it's not it
Speaker 0: is
Speaker 1: well, it is not completely Filling the gap Like muggles using desktops.
Speaker 1: It's definitely growing Meaning that the PC market will shift more toward that specialized market meaning PCs will be more like the things that I want.
Speaker 1: but to the other thing that's driving PC usage other than like companies still and like corporate use is kids doing Media Production mostly around live stream.
Speaker 0: That's what I'm saying.
Speaker 0: is you gotta you know?
Speaker 0: people who are you know are doing production are getting them?
Speaker 0: But what about other people?
Speaker 1: but that's it that the kids like everyone.
Speaker 0: everyone's producing stuff.
Speaker 0: Everyone's making videos.
Speaker 0: Everyone needs this dude I think the most people making videos on their phones and shit.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but as soon as they get as soon as they get that taste.
Speaker 1: I've seen this progression of y'all like six seven eight year old small sample size But they get a taste of it from their phone.
Speaker 1: Then they want to make a real live stream and as soon as they need to stream the video game They're playing they need a computer and OBS and all this shit and they are figuring it out on their own The same way we did.
Speaker 1: Mmm, so that that generation I think is gonna fill in the gap and keep a healthy Workstation ecosystem but non workstation PC use I think is going to literally disappear.
Speaker 1: So This is just a nice interesting brief set flash if we're trying to get rid of it.
Speaker 0: didn't flash die a while ago?
Speaker 0: Yeah, but doesn't crunchyroll still use it?
Speaker 0: Barely, I don't know.
Speaker 1: I periodically have to do some bullshit to make crunchyroll work.
Speaker 0: I don't notice.
Speaker 0: because like all the browsers now they like include like a flash thing.
Speaker 0: So you don't need to go to adobe.com and get it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, just sort of you open up Chrome and you go to a website and it just works and it's like, okay so so a car?
Speaker 1: apparently in 20 early 2018 Only 8% of Chrome browsers Yeah hit a flash site on a daily basis, right?
Speaker 0: Cuz me once iOS decided we're not having flash.
Speaker 0: then all the websites removed flash.
Speaker 0: So now no one get.
Speaker 0: you know, there's not a lot of flash left.
Speaker 1: So HTML 5 video killed off a lot of flash to the only website I still go to that has flash seems to be crunchyroll.
Speaker 1: They'd better remove it because it's gonna be disabled by default in July of 2019 in Chrome And it's going to be removed completely in December of 2020 from Chrome.
Speaker 1: sounds good But I think that's only sorry.
Speaker 1: I left.
Speaker 0: I'm worried it to the thing that the only sad thing about the removal of flash is that we've got like 10 plus years worth maybe in 20 years worth of flash games and You might think of flash games like tiny crappy games.
Speaker 0: But it's like there's like a lot of worthwhile art that was created in flash.
Speaker 0: That is has value and it will not be accessible.
Speaker 0: They might like how many games are on congregate or like yeah, even before like homestay original homestar runner.
Speaker 0: It's like, you know, even though you don't want flash in our browsers, you know for actual everyday doing stuff Flash emulator.
Speaker 0: we need to preserve.
Speaker 0: the content that happened to sadly be created in flash is Very very valuable to the history of the internet and the human race.
Speaker 0: What is interesting our Western civilization?
Speaker 1: What is very interesting?
Speaker 1: Remember when we mentioned is that we were talking about name that beard because that Ross for teens that's flash.
Speaker 0: gotta preserve that beard.
Speaker 1: a Huge number of old flash games and old flash content are actually archived to some degree on YouTube.
Speaker 0: Right, but you can't archive say homestar runner on YouTube.
Speaker 0: It's an interactive experience.
Speaker 0: You'd have to like make a exe that is homestar runner dot exe that has the whole site and like that changed over time Too.
Speaker 0: so you'd have to have like an exe that like lets you choose your date and time of like.
Speaker 0: which version of the?
Speaker 1: Well, that is true.
Speaker 0: I don't even know if all of that was preserved by the brothers.
Speaker 1: That's just one website But a pale imitation of a lot of those things like.
Speaker 0: what about that game?
Speaker 0: We're like the dinosaur runs to the right and his lava come.
Speaker 1: even if some of those games are not playable in the near future in the very least there are plenty of people who are going like Because there's so much pressure to have a unique and novel live stream.
Speaker 1: a lot of yet live streamers are finding ancient flash games Playing them and live streaming them and those videos while they are not the complete experience.
Speaker 1: You can at least watch someone play that game and I found a live stream.
Speaker 1: That is literally someone just playing the entirety of name that beard.
Speaker 1: Yeah in a browser They just live streamed it.
Speaker 0: Yep, if you want to stream flash games Noble endeavor, but it is not as good as actually having the flash games.
Speaker 1: And with that I think we have concluded our spring 2018 tech news around.
Speaker 0: good because I hung.
Speaker 1: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat Lee for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 0: be sure to visit our website at front row.
Speaker 0: crew calm for show notes discussion News and more.
Speaker 1: remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 0: geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 0: But unlike those other late shows It's actually recorded at night and the patreon page runs.
Speaker 1: with this episode of geek nights are Craig Oliver Alan Joyce Rebecca Dunn hiding McNichol a shimmering ruby obelisk hanging in the sky.
Speaker 1: my state calm.
Speaker 1: Jeremy minor the geegee Cold guy Amanda to shed Shawn Yeager Matthew Smith Nicholas brand our captain Chinguac see four to one creations.
Speaker 1: No, I never ever wonder why we're here.
Speaker 1: Semper Fi bitch Shervin von Horrell rare Laval James David White Rochelle, Montanota Superboy rims has something funny here.
Speaker 1: Sailor Vista Don Schleich Jartavish and Joshua Joe star.
Speaker 1: Sam Cordery Clinton Walton Ren from New Zealand Ryan Perrin Drew open Lander Finn Chris midkiff Chris Knox Daniel Redman Sean Klein Chris Reimer and Thomas Hahn.
Speaker 1: And I'm hungry so I'm just gonna wrap this up right now so I will leave you with the thing.
Speaker 1: that is certainly a thing.