Speaker 1: It's Tuesday, February 27th 2018.
Speaker 1: I'm rim.
Speaker 1: I'm Scott and this is geek nights.
Speaker 1: tonight We're talking about meeple circus.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: So Rangers haven't been doing so well in the old hockey game.
Speaker 0: Nope.
Speaker 1: It's been pretty bad pretty sad.
Speaker 0: I mean.
Speaker 0: we have one Stanley Cup in 70 something years.
Speaker 1: Yep, and it's also never been good.
Speaker 1: Extra weird because my entire sentient life I have never ever experienced the Stanley Cup where my team wasn't at least in it Because the right wing is my entire life.
Speaker 1: and then the first year the Red Wings were ever not in the playoffs in modern history Rangers were there so it was fine.
Speaker 1: But this year Rangers and Red Wings are basically tied at not in the playoffs.
Speaker 0: We are in the tank roll.
Speaker 0: Thanks roll.
Speaker 1: And it was even funnier because last night was a game between the tied in points Red Wings and Rangers Which is always extra weird because on one hand I I'm primarily a Rangers fan because I've lived in New York for a decade like it's you let the pass go.
Speaker 1: I'm a Rangers fan.
Speaker 1: He moved.
Speaker 0: he moved to Arizona.
Speaker 0: I probably would.
Speaker 1: eventually the trouble is I instinctively cheer whenever the Red Wings score.
Speaker 1: so when the Red Wings won the game in overtime I Cheered while simultaneously booing.
Speaker 1: It's such a cognitive dissonance to see two teams.
Speaker 1: I Even if I say I am rooting for the Rangers this core part of me is like yes when the red and white jersey scores.
Speaker 1: What makes even worse is that there was a home game in the MSG So the Red Wings were in their away uniform.
Speaker 1: But the Red Wings the away uniforms of today are basically what the home uniforms were a decade ago.
Speaker 1: And for all my childhood hockey, so it was extra weird because it was like that's the home jersey.
Speaker 1: My brain associates with the Rangers and the home jersey my team associates with the Red Wings.
Speaker 1: My brain was just having trouble figuring out what to think during this game as a result.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm but the trade deadline ended today and You sold everybody now.
Speaker 1: They didn't sell everybody everybody.
Speaker 0: Not everyone was buying.
Speaker 0: You can't.
Speaker 0: you can't sell a stock if no one wants to pay what it costs.
Speaker 1: Take note Bitcoin people.
Speaker 1: someone has to be willing to pay for your Bitcoin.
Speaker 0: I got a Bitcoin.
Speaker 0: I want to sell it for the 20,000.
Speaker 0: It's supposedly worth wine giving you.
Speaker 0: Keep your nothing.
Speaker 0: I'll keep my $20,000 which is basically a car and I giving you a car for nothing Say I guess we'll get right into it.
Speaker 1: You got any gaming news.
Speaker 0: What was my gaming news already forgot?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I did art.
Speaker 0: Oh, I do remember.
Speaker 0: so the people who made FTL are coming out with this new game.
Speaker 0: That's that's all the rage.
Speaker 0: It comes out like what tomorrow or something real?
Speaker 0: Yeah today Ridiculously soon right?
Speaker 0: this game has been hyped up for a countdown on Steam until it unlocks if you pre-order it as a class.
Speaker 0: Yeah, anyway, so this game is called into the breach.
Speaker 0: I think yep, and if it's made by the FTL people So it's a rogue.
Speaker 0: you like the rogue like like we like And it's probably high quality because they seemed.
Speaker 0: it is a very good and it is a grid turn-based strategy game involving mechs.
Speaker 0: So imagine FTL except when you go to the next place instead of having like this spaceship battle thing going on you.
Speaker 0: instead you do a little tiny advance wars involving mechs and Then you do another one and basically when your people die They're like sort of like Fire Emblem.
Speaker 0: and when you got one when you got one guy left You can you basically run away and start the game over with that one guy and that one guy can keep leveling up even if You keep failing.
Speaker 1: I always wanted an advance.
Speaker 1: wars like game where?
Speaker 0: Victory and defeat weren't just this but of course that one guy that like you've taken on like let's say you go through and you Fail, but you save this one, dude.
Speaker 0: Then you keep you try again, and you fail, but you save the same dude because he's the most leveled up guy.
Speaker 0: That's you're gonna save right.
Speaker 0: you go through a third time, and you save that dude again.
Speaker 0: now He's way powerful and on the fourth go through that guy dies.
Speaker 1: Apparently there is a ton of stuff in the game.
Speaker 1: There's a quote here in this polygon article after just an hour in the game I'd already unlocked much more new content than in a dozen hours of the previous game FTL.
Speaker 0: right now.
Speaker 1: That's not to say it was any easier simply more generous and encouraging of experimentation.
Speaker 1: I also I will say I like FTL.
Speaker 1: it does not encourage experimentation.
Speaker 1: I am terrified of almost every decision I make in that game, so this is a game.
Speaker 0: That's coming out soon.
Speaker 0: I want to talk briefly about this other game That's the hotness these days called slay the spire, which I had been playing even though.
Speaker 0: It's just early access beta mode.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, I got to play that.
Speaker 0: so this game slay the spire is an early access.
Speaker 0: right now it is made by some people in the netrunner community and Basically, it's also a roguelike, but it's a roguelike deck building game.
Speaker 0: both of these are single-player PC games by the way And the way it works is like you know dominion.
Speaker 0: you draw a hand of cards You play as many as you can you throw out the rest you draw a new hand of cards, right?
Speaker 0: So what this is is like a little Final Fantasy battle And you get a hand of cards and you play them, and you're just.
Speaker 0: you're the only one playing cards.
Speaker 0: the bad guys Actually tell you exactly what the fuck they're gonna Do.
Speaker 0: it's like oh I can see that that guy is going to attack for 15 and that guy's gonna do some sort of Defensive move.
Speaker 0: this turn and you play your you have three mana And you play your player cards And then you throw out whatever you don't play and draw a new hand and then the things happen.
Speaker 0: And then you play cards again And as you continue through the game you remove cards from your deck adds add cards to your deck get relics They give you special abilities And you go on to the next battle in the next battle in the next battle and getting all sorts of stuff going on.
Speaker 0: Shopping for different you know potions and stuff go alright.
Speaker 0: This is also a way fun roguelike is basically playing dominion against the computer Also a roguelike.
Speaker 0: this game is way hot even though it's early access.
Speaker 0: It is already hot and it is way successful like there's a zillion streamers on Twitch for this game.
Speaker 0: Yeah, even though it's early access.
Speaker 0: so right now It is a single-player strategy.
Speaker 0: roguelike PC gaming time and those are the two games That you got play slay the spire and into the breach.
Speaker 1: yep I'm feeling this into the bridge even though cuz you know fire emblem has that mobile game that has like the mini grid battles.
Speaker 0: I've never.
Speaker 0: that is a garbage pain Microchess game.
Speaker 0: that is not a.
Speaker 1: I have never been a fan previously of the small grid style of advanced wars like games because they tended to Never involve even the remotest of interesting strategy.
Speaker 0: I still I still gonna bet you will enjoy this game.
Speaker 1: I Feel pretty confident this game's gonna break that trend for me.
Speaker 1: Just looking at these screen shot.
Speaker 0: You like the gym fire though That was small grids.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but so the gym fire the small grid was more about food management for the Army's verse and as opposed to it Fantasy empires was more about the like desertion rate of your troops based on their morale.
Speaker 0: I mean that isn't that just a different abstraction of the same food concept?
Speaker 1: No, the food was.
Speaker 1: you'll have food like the army when you attack someone you choose.
Speaker 1: It's one of those old like Koay games that was like here's how many troops I'm bringing and here's how much food I'm bringing with me.
Speaker 1: and then the bigger your army was the more food it burned through per day.
Speaker 1: And you might run out of food before you broke the siege and all that kind of nonsense.
Speaker 1: Nobody likes Jim fire, but me.
Speaker 1: that's there.
Speaker 1: That's the end result there, but I'm feeling this game.
Speaker 1: So in some other news if you didn't notice I play a lot of overwatch.
Speaker 1: it's kind of my main game now and One of the things that I always lamented was that overwatch didn't really include a capture the flag mode Even though capture the flag the number one mode in a character class-based FPS see competitive you say that.
Speaker 1: but actually capture the flag was the number one mode in an era that predates most gamers.
Speaker 0: Yes, but for me That's the number one mode that you played in Tia anything with a TF in the title and anything with the tribes in the title.
Speaker 0: Capture the flag was the default number one mode.
Speaker 0: all the other modes were secondary modes.
Speaker 1: yep, so Overwatch did introduce a capture the flag mode But it was just in the arcade team fortress 2 and it was broken and it was crappy and it wasn't really well thought out.
Speaker 0: They wasn't that the first mode they made.
Speaker 1: yeah, so they made there.
Speaker 0: I wasn't that the primary game mode There's.
Speaker 1: I don't actually really know why they didn't make the game CTF first other than that.
Speaker 1: I don't think CTF has Really any cache a with most modern gamers.
Speaker 1: It's just us old-timers.
Speaker 1: But the existing modes with the payload push in the zone capture and all that they're fine.
Speaker 1: But capture the flag I think has a lot more potential for good spectator experiences.
Speaker 0: Yeah I was.
Speaker 0: I always thought that CTF was the default mode because you carry into it your Childhood experience of playing literal capture the flag.
Speaker 1: most kids don't play capture the flag and how.
Speaker 0: that is the greatest thing.
Speaker 0: And now the fact that you know, of course, that's what you would want to do in the video game land, right?
Speaker 1: A lot of kids don't play capture the flag.
Speaker 0: Well, that's a crime.
Speaker 0: We should start competitive real-world.
Speaker 1: capture the flag Yeah, but with guns like paintball.
Speaker 0: How about with just nothing?
Speaker 0: just capturing flags?
Speaker 0: Yeah and jail.
Speaker 1: and When we played it we bet the rules for catching someone.
Speaker 1: it wasn't the rules.
Speaker 0: We changed the rules so many fucking times.
Speaker 1: We used touch football flags like flag football and You basically had to grab a guy's flag and then he was out.
Speaker 0: We're doing an episode and capture the flag.
Speaker 0: That is that I'm writing that down cuz I was gonna tell a story of.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna save it right down.
Speaker 1: I write it down right now tonight's episode and capture the flag coming soon Because if we don't write it down right now, it will literally never happen.
Speaker 1: someone remind us In fact, it will curse us if we if I say if we say oh, we'll remember to do this We won't.
Speaker 1: it guarantees that we will die before we make that episode.
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 1: So Blizzard did what they do in that whenever there's a mode that they introduced like Lucio ball or something and then everyone says oh this Mode is broken.
Speaker 1: This sucks or whatever.
Speaker 1: We don't care about it.
Speaker 1: They pay attention and they just quietly fix it.
Speaker 1: So they re-released capture the flag and they fixed Almost all the problems the previous initial iteration of capture the flag problems?
Speaker 1: Does it still have the problems that it still has?
Speaker 1: So are so let's see right now the things they change is probably more interesting.
Speaker 1: So now first team to capture three times wins in the time of the match.
Speaker 0: That sounds good.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if it is tied at the end of that time, so two flags each say yep Then it goes on to death.
Speaker 0: next flag wins God.
Speaker 1: No So the game restarts.
Speaker 1: you re-pick your heroes and it moves the two flags and the capture points To be basically right fucking next to each other in the middle of the map.
Speaker 1: Okay, and just go go go.
Speaker 1: It just ends almost immediately after.
Speaker 0: oh because the flag and the capture point are adjacent.
Speaker 0: Yes, you have to take the flag and just move it like an inch.
Speaker 1: They're like they'll be like a pillar and they're basically like 40 feet apart on either side of a pillar.
Speaker 0: So you have to rush to the middle grab the flag and slam dunk it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it doesn't move the spawn points.
Speaker 1: The spawn points are still way back, right?
Speaker 0: See basically everyone rushes to the middle to try to grab their flag and slam dunk it in the net.
Speaker 0: That's right next to the flag?
Speaker 0: Yep But also because I bring it all the way back to your spawn like usual.
Speaker 1: but also it means that killing even one person on The other team it's probably already game over because even if they get time to respawn they got to run all the way back.
Speaker 0: Are there any sort of like characters that can like sort of control the area and push the enemies back?
Speaker 0: So long enough for the fast person to move the flag?
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, there are and that's part of the strategy of those eggs.
Speaker 1: those options exist for both sides.
Speaker 0: Okay, what do you do about him?
Speaker 0: be faster rush in the middle?
Speaker 1: They also dealt with the problem where characters have movement powers like some characters can fly or teleport or whatever.
Speaker 1: so the rule they implemented was anyone can grab the flag and passive powers work.
Speaker 1: fine, but Special movement powers cause you to drop the flag.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm Yeah Which on one end I disagree with because in the old weapons factory days and like mega TF the super fast recon type flying characters They could just fly with the flag.
Speaker 0: I mean you have Scout and TF - it's.
Speaker 1: and they just rip and right back out.
Speaker 1: But I do see how that really violates the sensibilities of modern gamers and I can swallow my bile Because it is actually pretty good the way they've implemented it.
Speaker 0: I think the way you want to do it is just the way tribes to did it where it's like.
Speaker 0: yeah You got jetpack.
Speaker 0: So does everybody?
Speaker 0: Yeah It's fine for you to jetpack with that flag and get into a strike because guess what here comes some more strikes.
Speaker 1: But blizzard escalated real quick.
Speaker 1: They didn't just fix most of the problems with CTF.
Speaker 1: They made it a ranked competitive mode.
Speaker 1: yeah, so now there's the only mode worth playing.
Speaker 1: and the only thing I have to say is that I've been solo Rando queuing the competitive capture the flag and I know for a fact I know capture the flag like I know my own blood.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: Problem is as far as I can tell 100% of the other human beings playing this capture the flag mode are in fact dogs chewing on controllers.
Speaker 1: Good God can people can people younger than us?
Speaker 0: Not You then be quickly ranking out of the dog with controller would rank and getting to a higher tier.
Speaker 1: So in a capture the flag mode One person even with the you know, like the they've let the movement powers worked out or at everything Cannot on their own swing the game.
Speaker 0: So it's another crappy ranking mode that based only on wins and losses and not based on individual performance based on teams.
Speaker 1: The thing is remember everything in overwatch the ranked systems Almost every complaint anyone has is around the fact that the game is designed from its very core To be a game.
Speaker 1: or you have a team of six.
Speaker 1: as soon as you are saying put me on a team with other people You're already violating a fundamental contract of the game.
Speaker 0: Does it separate your rankings for solo play from your rankings?
Speaker 0: for I have a prepared team play?
Speaker 0: Uh, no, but match make but rocket League gets that right?
Speaker 0: You have a separate rank in every different mode in rocket League.
Speaker 0: So if you prepare teams you get ranked separately from your solo, right?
Speaker 1: So instead what the matchmaking does is it will whenever possible if you come in with a four stack or a six stack Put you against another group of equivalent size with the same number of randos.
Speaker 1: So if I make a team of five, I'll go up against another team of five.
Speaker 1: We both get the Russian roulette of the Hanzo that's gonna join not join the team chat and proceed to sit in the corner crying Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: So, yeah, this is pretty interesting how it's shaken down and I hope they've already talked about more changes They're gonna make to CTF.
Speaker 1: They're really they're pushing CTF way harder than I expected which is real interesting because this is the mode I actually care about a lot.
Speaker 0: That's the mood.
Speaker 0: I care about a lot, too.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if it I will I will tell you if it gets good enough to where it's worth you playing it.
Speaker 1: It's not there yet.
Speaker 1: It's not.
Speaker 0: it still cost too much money.
Speaker 1: What do you care?
Speaker 1: You got money?
Speaker 0: I mean by furniture.
Speaker 0: Actually, I too need to buy Someone on Twitter was like hey, New York City friends.
Speaker 0: I'm coming to New York Can I get a couch?
Speaker 0: and I was like my couch literally has a giant hole in it.
Speaker 1: We were at a friend's house someone else playing a game night the other night over the weekend and they had just bought a new couch.
Speaker 1: I was grilling him about that patch but anyway things of the day we got.
Speaker 0: So I'm pretty sure everyone's seen this on the internet already, but it's so good.
Speaker 0: It's got me thinking today.
Speaker 0: I saw the link earlier, but I washed it.
Speaker 0: poor rim got here.
Speaker 0: So there's a game that's old by now.
Speaker 0: I actually called papers, please if you haven't played papers papers game.
Speaker 1: just play it.
Speaker 0: It is a way good single-player PC game.
Speaker 0: I think it might be on other platforms.
Speaker 0: I don't even know but PC is best Master race.
Speaker 0: so go on your PC and play papers, please if you haven't already But I'm pretty sure you have.
Speaker 0: it is a game where you are in a fictional but obviously Eastern European East Germany country where there is a you know, very You know big brother government and you are at.
Speaker 0: you're in charge of inspecting people's passports and such trying to come into the country at the border and you have instructions and you're Inspecting to make sure documents are legit and you let people in or turn them away.
Speaker 1: the games like the the give you a sense of this game.
Speaker 1: Literally you in the game will.
Speaker 1: someone will hand you their passport.
Speaker 1: you look at it and flip it over like look through the stuff.
Speaker 1: Then if you're not sure you pull out this giant book in game Put it on the table.
Speaker 1: that covers your whole stupid table Like it's in the way and a problem and you're flipping through it trying to figure out what to do based on the rules.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so it's a great game.
Speaker 0: And for some reason even though the game is way old.
Speaker 0: There is now an official short film of the game.
Speaker 0: So if you whether if you've played the game You will appreciate this short film very very much And if you haven't this short film will convince you to go back and play it.
Speaker 1: the games real good And also it's it's more real and disturbing than you might expect.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: And if you haven't played you just got to play this game.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm, so Apparently if you skate as an ice skate on really thin ice thin like like an inch I mean that's thin but it's not Super thin like.
Speaker 0: when I think of thin ice I think like, you know that little tiny sliver of ice that forms that rhyme of ice Like jump across.
Speaker 1: as a kid in the elementary school playground I think you crash through it
Speaker 0: like there's a puddle and it's a really cold day and there's just like this little tiny sheet of Ice floating on it and if you poke it crackles, you know, it's like it's like cornflake thick.
Speaker 0: So that's thin ice.
Speaker 1: Apparently there is this sport in I guess Norway called Nordic skating or anything.
Speaker 1: any sport Involving cold and snow is in Norway or wild ice skating and basically they just ice skate on Super thin ice through the wilderness like down rivers, isn't this?
Speaker 0: I mean an inch isn't Ridiculously dangerous, but it's still dangerous.
Speaker 0: Yeah, what if you fall in?
Speaker 1: so if no one's there you're dead.
Speaker 0: Oh, okay I'm just checking that.
Speaker 1: but the cool the cool things about this are one don't Actually explains in pretty good detail like What the deal with this is and like why it works and why he doesn't just fall through and why if you tried to do It you probably would fall through.
Speaker 0: maybe he's super light and maybe he's doing it in a certain way.
Speaker 0: There's a lot of science distributing his weight across more ice and not pushing it into a single spot in the ice.
Speaker 1: Also, just the way ice forms.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: I'm just guessing.
Speaker 1: Yeah, what kinds of Pressures are being exerted?
Speaker 1: like it's risk kind of complicated actually.
Speaker 1: Oh, in fact the video just said it's complicated Mm-hmm, but the craziest thing about it is the sounds that Thin ice make when you skate on it.
Speaker 0: This is this video is really cool just for that Because usually when you skate in an ice rink, there's nothing under the ice.
Speaker 0: It's a floor and we skate on thick ice like three four or five inches.
Speaker 0: It's just ice.
Speaker 0: the sat the vibrations in the set the the view and the sound waves from you skating don't really go into the Water or come out of the water.
Speaker 0: very much, right?
Speaker 0: but if it's thin ice like an inch then the sounds can go in the water and come back and sort of echo against the Bottom of the ice and they sound cool.
Speaker 1: Yep And I use this as my thing of the day instead of the kid pissing on the elevator because while that is a plus We're still not sure how if that's a fake video or not.
Speaker 0: I am more than 50% convinced It's fake, but if you didn't see elevator piss boy, you got to see it even though it's fake.
Speaker 0: It's still worth.
Speaker 0: Just go into it.
Speaker 1: It's like a sub thing of the day.
Speaker 0: go into it a mat, you know Thinking it's probably fake.
Speaker 0: not definitely but probably yeah.
Speaker 1: In the meta moment, we're going to be live at PAX East 2018.
Speaker 1: Oh my god.
Speaker 0: Why is it so soon?
Speaker 1: Oh my god I haven't even like plan.
Speaker 1: apparently there's a Amtrak discount for packs Really?
Speaker 1: Yeah, so cuz every year around this time I'm much of a discount.
Speaker 1: I don't know cuz you have to call them.
Speaker 1: You can't just like do it on the Amtrak website feeling a boat bus.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'll probably Amtrak.
Speaker 1: It's just so much faster and more chill.
Speaker 0: It's like an hour and a half faster, okay, but it's like 10 bucks to ride a bull bus.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like even with a discount.
Speaker 0: What's the Amtrak gonna be?
Speaker 1: It's like 60 bucks.
Speaker 0: Yeah So and I gotta go two ways.
Speaker 1: that's a lot of money saves for you know, 90 minutes true But partly I'm gonna see what this discount is, but I digress.
Speaker 1: we're gonna be a pack.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna be ten bucks each way.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well, I got I got.
Speaker 1: I got the rewards program with Amtrak and I got a lot of free Amtrak's coming my way.
Speaker 0: It's not rewards.
Speaker 0: you paid for those when you paid.
Speaker 1: But we will be there on Sunday doing the like full final for real version of our top 40 tabletop games.
Speaker 0: Right, it's only sounds like a clickbait panel, right?
Speaker 0: Cuz it's like oh we're gonna go listing top 40 games.
Speaker 0: But actually what we're doing is it's we're just gonna use that as an excuse to talk about 40 different gaming Concepts that are worth knowing.
Speaker 0: and it's just those games just examples of those kinds to give you an idea.
Speaker 1: The way not a ranking thing.
Speaker 1: the way we write this panel is for every game.
Speaker 1: Oh a game only makes this list if there are two Noteworthy interesting things about the game's mechanics and it can't be the same thing as any other game on the list And it's a lot of games that we don't actually like at all Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: So yeah, that'll be fun.
Speaker 1: And otherwise PAX East is for goddamn days and it looks like Thursdays and Sundays aren't even sold out yet.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you can go to PAX East Thursday or Sunday for like 50 bucks.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that ain't bad.
Speaker 0: I mean on Sunday you're getting a short day.
Speaker 0: So it's not.
Speaker 0: you're sort of getting ripped off.
Speaker 0: And if you and you're gonna get a less crowded expo and if you go on Thursday, it's gonna be way not crowded.
Speaker 1: Yeah, keynote Q&A.
Speaker 0: He's one day off work.
Speaker 0: If you live in the area go on Thursday It'll be way less crowded to get the keynote and the Q&A and everything and you get a full PAX day.
Speaker 0: You can stay till midnight.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know.
Speaker 0: and then I guess it's gonna be pre pax tabletop gaming on Wednesday.
Speaker 0: Will there be when?
Speaker 0: Wednesday night?
Speaker 1: damn The problem is this is why we don't go to a lot of other conventions anymore.
Speaker 1: All the paxes are like just broadening into.
Speaker 1: eventually our lives will just be packs.
Speaker 1: Lisa I'm going where the pool goes Otherwise in about a moment.
Speaker 1: the book club book was the fifth season by NK jemisin.
Speaker 1: It was fantastic the current book club book, which I'm gonna update because I started reading it.
Speaker 1: Finally is Emily Wilson's translation new translation of The Odyssey by Homer.
Speaker 0: I haven't gotten much farther in that but I did reread it.
Speaker 0: pop-up book of the Odyssey.
Speaker 0: Oh, it's completion because it didn't take very long.
Speaker 1: So the intro is fantastic, but now I've actually burned quite a bit of a ways through the actual Odyssey itself This translation.
Speaker 1: I went back and read the first like the beginning of the Odyssey in the old translation.
Speaker 1: I read from high school.
Speaker 1: It feels way different to read it.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm If you've never read the Odyssey it It's just very plain and feels very like.
Speaker 1: Alright, if he's doing this thing and this jerks up to no good It's just.
Speaker 1: there's something about it that I really like and I don't want to really spoil all that till we do the book club Show, but if you've never read the Odyssey read this translation.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: And if you have read the Odyssey read this translation.
Speaker 1: Anyway, it's the book club.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: And if you're not reading our book club books, I don't know.
Speaker 1: read a book read a book Any any of them.
Speaker 1: any book?
Speaker 0: Read not no no audiobook unless you're blind.
Speaker 1: That's okay, then not a sports page.
Speaker 1: So this is a game people circus that I Heard I don't know when I first heard about it cuz it's pretty new like it's weird.
Speaker 0: It feels like the term meeple circus like is just like the first time I heard it.
Speaker 0: It didn't feel new.
Speaker 0: it felt like There's always been a meeple circus.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the meeple circus of every tabletop game ever because pretty much anyone who plays tabletop games What do you do when you're bored because Joey Jojo takes forever on his fucking turn?
Speaker 0: It's like whenever it's your turn when it's not your turn in a tabletop game.
Speaker 0: You're sitting there and in front of you you're playing settlers.
Speaker 0: You got a bunch of little houses or meeples and you play with them.
Speaker 0: That's just what you naturally do a meeple circus.
Speaker 0: The actual game does.
Speaker 1: if you've ever played settlers, you know exactly how high you can stack all your pieces, right?
Speaker 0: It is a game in which you stack wooden board game pieces competitively.
Speaker 0: Now there are the official game.
Speaker 0: It's not like a thing you do while you're bored.
Speaker 1: now There are a lot of tabletop games like via Paletti or Jenga or Rhino hero.
Speaker 1: that involves some sort of stacking Component.
Speaker 0: there are lots of construction games and destruction games.
Speaker 0: We've reviewed many of them on geek night and a lot of them have similar problems the one problem being well one person knocks it Everyone else win.
Speaker 0: that's kind of lame.
Speaker 1: or one person knocks it down via Paletti And now we have a really hand-fisted and kind of crappy scoring mechanism to determine who won.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that really removes the skill component.
Speaker 1: So meeple circus is one of the rare stacking pieces games that has a pretty legit win condition and is about your skill of stacking and Doesn't seem to have a very low skill cap.
Speaker 1: Because many of the games that try to solve this problem end up having such a low skill cap that over the course of a Pax everyone in our group is playing perfectly in.
Speaker 1: the game is boring.
Speaker 0: So pretty much how it works is the app.
Speaker 0: It's an app controlled game, but the app does not actually do much.
Speaker 0: The app is mostly a timer.
Speaker 1: It just plays a song.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's a timer with a circus song.
Speaker 0: So the circus has three acts right and in the first act you got a pretty simple circus.
Speaker 0: you don't have a lot of pieces to work with and You know, you build.
Speaker 0: everyone is simultaneously making.
Speaker 0: you know It says like it's like the timer starts and everyone has to build their circus and you're trying to arrange the meeples in Such a way according to the rules that they are worth the most points for you.
Speaker 0: For example, there might be bonus points for putting a purple guy on top or something Right, like you get you if you get a red guy But you have a measuring stick for how high is your red guy on the ground?
Speaker 1: and some guys can't be on the ground They don't get points.
Speaker 1: some guys can't be under another guy.
Speaker 1: Yeah, some guys are just animals.
Speaker 0: each meeple has different rules.
Speaker 0: There's camels and elephants and sticks and balls and barrels and all sorts of like.
Speaker 1: the strong man.
Speaker 0: There's a strong man.
Speaker 0: There's a. there's this generic acrobats.
Speaker 0: There's all kinds of different meeples.
Speaker 0: They all do different things.
Speaker 0: You want to stack them in different ways?
Speaker 0: And then you go after.
Speaker 0: you do that Everyone gets points.
Speaker 0: you do round two Which is pretty similar to round one.
Speaker 0: only now everyone has even more meeples and it gets a little crazy Because
Speaker 1: you're doing this draft mechanic where you know What's likely to like what the scoring things are like what will be scored and then you're sort of drafting to collect pieces Like I'll take this card that gives me two of the blue guys and an elephant.
Speaker 0: Yep So you do round two?
Speaker 0: It's the second act of the circus and then the third act of the circus.
Speaker 0: This is where shit gets crazy right and the third act of the circus.
Speaker 0: everyone goes Individually one at a time not simultaneously.
Speaker 0: and while you're doing this Not only do you have to construct something according to the same rules and get the most points?
Speaker 0: Not only do you have even more meeples than before but you have to do some sort of performance aspect, right?
Speaker 0: For example, what was one of them?
Speaker 0: We say like hop every time you place a certain thing or something.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so basically in the first two rounds everyone builds their thing simultaneously.
Speaker 1: when the timer runs out whatever is standing That's what gets scored.
Speaker 1: But then in the third one you all take turns Being the audience and they'll end like the person have a rule like clap your hands every time you place a piece.
Speaker 1: So I place it.
Speaker 1: please clap my hands place a piece clap my hand.
Speaker 0: You guys actually do a performance for the third act of the circus and that gets you points if you succeed at it If you if you miss up clapping once.
Speaker 0: this is why the other people aren't doing it simultaneously.
Speaker 0: They're judging you're clapping.
Speaker 0: They're like, yeah be clapped.
Speaker 0: Nope.
Speaker 0: She didn't clap.
Speaker 1: No, the good news is they're all objective things.
Speaker 1: There's no ambiguity.
Speaker 0: Very well-written.
Speaker 0: you're not gonna be able to like unfair.
Speaker 0: You're never gonna have a question of like.
Speaker 0: was that a clap?
Speaker 0: You know, it's like.
Speaker 0: no it's pretty clear.
Speaker 1: the most fun part of that piece of the game is that one.
Speaker 1: everyone People tend to choke in that part and that's just really funny.
Speaker 0: to have one shot.
Speaker 0: You still got the timer.
Speaker 0: You're all by yourself.
Speaker 0: Everyone's looking at you.
Speaker 1: Yeah when I mess up in the first round No one really notices they're busy with their own crap and you're performing right?
Speaker 0: It's like.
Speaker 0: it's like more circus role-playing even though you're still just stacking meeples together.
Speaker 1: But - you don't say anything if you're in the audience.
Speaker 1: if the person messes up their performance Like if they forget to clap once I can write it like a role play the audience.
Speaker 1: No, no, the audience just be quiet.
Speaker 1: Don't let him know.
Speaker 1: so they keep doing it not realizing that they failed long ago.
Speaker 0: Oh, no, but I could.
Speaker 0: I could just boo at their bad circus.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah satisfied that clown sucks And if Dumbo comes out, yeah.
Speaker 1: So the game was set up in the first look area at PAX, which is a pretty good area in general.
Speaker 1: It's kind of an aside But I think it's worth it to talk about it.
Speaker 0: It's an area that was created at Unplugged and it's unplugged the table top PAX.
Speaker 0: We scooped up some games from Essen like board games that aren't like published widely in the u.s.
Speaker 0: Yet the kind of games you can't get at your game store.
Speaker 0: There's only a few copies so far like preview copies stuff like that games that are like the newest newest hotness.
Speaker 0: They're not gonna be in the library.
Speaker 0: No one's gonna bring them to PAX.
Speaker 0: these are like the only copies you're gonna see for like maybe another few months before they come out in the game store.
Speaker 0: and Here they are at PAX.
Speaker 0: They're set up already on tables where they have a permanent home.
Speaker 0: You sit down and play them when no one else is playing a minute and unplugged.
Speaker 0: These games were highly trafficked in a very visible area.
Speaker 0: You couldn't sit down to play any of them because everyone was board game fans playing them all the time.
Speaker 0: But it packs out.
Speaker 0: they were in the back and hidden and no one noticed them or cared about them and they weren't on the printed Books in the map or anything.
Speaker 0: So you could totally go over there if you knew what was what and play them to your heart's content.
Speaker 1: So I really like meeple circus and I think a lot of people would probably enjoy they should buy it But I don't think it's a game that I would buy myself.
Speaker 1: The the few problems I see with it based on talking to people who have played it a bunch more or people who were saying Forcers observing people playing this game over the course of entire packs is that if you play this game more than occasionally You can pretty much get to the point of Perfectly stacking every time.
Speaker 0: and I played the game one time and I got the maximum points Available to me.
Speaker 0: based on the cards that were available in the game.
Speaker 0: I could not have gotten any more points than I was gotten and it reminds me actually a lot in that way With potion explosion.
Speaker 0: Yeah and potion explosion is a game with a fun gimmick.
Speaker 0: It's marble machine and meeple circus is a fun gimmick an app and stacking all kinds of cool meeples.
Speaker 0: But there's a you the way the mech scoring mechanism works.
Speaker 0: This is the maximum score you can get and you either hit the maximum or you don't.
Speaker 0: and potion explosion It's two potions a turn and a meeple circus.
Speaker 0: is just all your meeples stacked correctly?
Speaker 1: What did you draft and what gets scored?
Speaker 0: Yep So as long as you're a stacking skill is up to snuff and you're not a small child Or someone, you know who can't stack meeples for some reason You're going to get the maximum points and the game comes down to the drafting part.
Speaker 0: So it's just the drafting part and I think you know on the one hand that reduces the replay value of meeple circus itself.
Speaker 0: But on the other hand, I don't think the game is actually a problem.
Speaker 0: I think the problem is simply that the game needs more pieces to make it harder.
Speaker 0: It needs an expansion or something to where it's like, alright, no, no No, literally you're gonna have so many meeples and so many things going on that are so ridiculous.
Speaker 0: You cannot score maximum points, you know But you got to calculate what the best you think you can do is and then it's like, alright This is the best I think I can do but I could get one more guy standing on a wall.
Speaker 0: Do I go for it or not?
Speaker 1: You know me know the app is going to do Like we've all been watching the Olympics lately, you know the figure scene and all that.
Speaker 1: So I think of it if the game had a little more components.
Speaker 1: It has this aspect.
Speaker 1: now Which is?
Speaker 1: this aspect breaks down among skilled players that you choose how ambitious you want to be and You can if you increase your maximum score by trying something that's very difficult That might pan out or you might knock it down at the last second and score nothing.
Speaker 1: Yep So if you added a few more pieces I think you could extend that feeling.
Speaker 0: the game needs to give you more pieces and more scoring mechanisms to the point at which Nobody can possibly get the maximum score possible with their own meeples unless they're a god Perfect balance and not right.
Speaker 0: plus, you know the imperfections of the meeples themselves and the table You're playing on and all that comes into play Such that you have to figure out how much you're gonna risk.
Speaker 0: Are you gonna go for that crazy move where you get four perfectly round things all stacked on each other or not?
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: Are you gonna go for it?
Speaker 0: How high do you want to make?
Speaker 0: put a stick vertically?
Speaker 0: Which you're not allowed to do actually.
Speaker 0: but you know just to get your red guy even higher You're gonna put another elephant up at the top.
Speaker 1: So there is one problem with the game.
Speaker 1: Wait a minute.
Speaker 1: I'm looking at the back of the box.
Speaker 1: I think it shows a stick vertical.
Speaker 1: It totally does.
Speaker 1: There's a vertical stick.
Speaker 0: I think there was a rule that there's like pieces had to be played in a certain way.
Speaker 1: So this is a problem with the game.
Speaker 1: the rules as they are in the printing that we had access to Oh, they're not real well-written enough are ambiguous to the point that they are unusable and we had to make a lot of value judgments as to how Pieces could actually be played.
Speaker 1: Can I lay this elephant on his side about about upside down?
Speaker 1: Can I put the stick vertically?
Speaker 1: people's people who taught us the game said things were not allowed that are clearly drawn on the back of the box.
Speaker 1: So that is a problem and I don't know if there's official errata or anything yet.
Speaker 1: We didn't look into that.
Speaker 1: We kind of just didn't care.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's not.
Speaker 0: it's not a game.
Speaker 0: That's so serious that it's worth your time to look into that.
Speaker 0: But yeah There are some questions like can an elephant be laying on its side or does have to be standing up?
Speaker 0: it can definitely be on Its head or standing up but can it be on its side?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I put my camel's humps down.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, the pieces are well designed though in that they're mostly capable of similar equivalent scores.
Speaker 0: Yeah There's like a highly varied an interesting collection of different kinds of meeples that have interesting shapes like, you know You set a camel up.
Speaker 0: It's like okay You got this round ball that will roll around.
Speaker 0: You just put a camel and put the ball between its humps and now you know the guy standing on that.
Speaker 0: and now you got A guy standing on a ball and you got points, right?
Speaker 0: Or you can be like me and balance a guy standing on a ball like a badass.
Speaker 1: Now the game does have an app and it's sort of required but all the app does.
Speaker 1: the only thing it does is Play the timer of how long you have on your turn, but the circus music is essential.
Speaker 1: It plays.
Speaker 1: some did it did it?
Speaker 1: did it style circus music?
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm, and it has.
Speaker 1: no it has some symbols like shh and they'll come in in different intervals to sort of tell you when you're running out of time But I will admit I actually would have preferred to just have a countdown timer Telling me exactly how many seconds I had left because I didn't play the game enough times to internalize What the like.
Speaker 1: everyone seemed to be very worried.
Speaker 0: time would run out And I think part of it was that we were keeping the app off to the side.
Speaker 0: We should have put the app front and center on the table so it could be more visible.
Speaker 1: true true But still the that gives you a lot more time than you think but you'll have to play it a bunch to Enter.
Speaker 1: never.
Speaker 0: I was never rules.
Speaker 0: I played, you know, somewhat hurriedly not super rushed, but I always came in under the clock.
Speaker 0: It was never At least not as I maybe I'm remembering.
Speaker 0: wrong because I have my memory is awful But I don't remember.
Speaker 1: one time I knocked my thing over and I couldn't rebuild the entire thing in time before the time ran.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but you can still build how just get as many points as you can.
Speaker 1: I built something.
Speaker 1: Yeah, wasn't great No, but I feel like I don't know if I want to own this game because I own a lot of games and I don't Know how much play it would get if I tried to play it a lot.
Speaker 0: I feel like this is kind of game where it's like if someone else busted out I'll play it if there's an expansion.
Speaker 0: I definitely want to play it again for sure.
Speaker 1: I want to see an expansion that it adds a round where you have to do a dexterity like flick kind of thing.
Speaker 0: But yeah, I feel like if I bought it, it wouldn't get played really very much at all.
Speaker 0: But the one case where I would buy it is if I was in some sort of family situation with small children Anyone who is below a school any situation where you can have a lot of players who are below the skill cap?
Speaker 0: Who will not get perfect?
Speaker 1: You know stacking every time like if I hosted game nights for like different people on a regular basis as opposed to just like our Local friends, I would probably have this and bust it out.
Speaker 0: It's the kind of game where like people are.
Speaker 0: I don't know who's gonna want to play this game over and over and over again But you can playing it for the first time is a hell of blast.
Speaker 0: So as long as you keep playing it with different people all the time You definitely want to.
Speaker 0: you know get a copy because it does make a spectacle.
Speaker 0: definitely got to go into a gaming library.
Speaker 0: It's got to go at a convention.
Speaker 0: It's got to go to school It's got to go at a meet-up.
Speaker 0: If you
Speaker 1: set this up somewhere like in the middle of a like mid-tier convention or like a meet-up or something It'll gather a crowd of people who will just want to watch Mm-hmm like it
Speaker 0: and people who want to play it like one two three times You know, so children might get hooked on it and keep playing.
Speaker 0: but I think adults will play a few times and be done.
Speaker 1: Yeah I met some people at PAX who had played it to the point that they had completely ruined it and there was no further Replay value at all.
Speaker 0: But but I think an expansion that's complex enough could make it fun for quite a while.
Speaker 1: I feel like one.
Speaker 0: actually if you added in stuff like you just said like the Looking mode one like flick like round one do a stack.
Speaker 1: round two do a trick.
Speaker 1: Round three do a stack.
Speaker 1: round four the performance that involves a stack and a dexterity move, right?
Speaker 0: So I think think the way you do it I think you would set it up like all.
Speaker 0: right You make your stack you score it and then you have to do the trick.
Speaker 1: after The stack.
Speaker 0: your trick is gonna mess up your thing.
Speaker 0: Yeah, or do it separately.
Speaker 0: It's like okay you have to make a stack and you have to set up a trick and execute the trick separately like okay I'll make a seesaw here and flick a guy and he has to.
Speaker 0: you know I'll make a human cannonball over here and get a guy to hit another guy.
Speaker 0: good.
Speaker 0: I did it and I'll make my stack Something like that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't know.
Speaker 0: but at least as it is Despite its minor flaws in terms maybe add like another act to the circus and that's the area.
Speaker 0: do a trick.
Speaker 1: So it's like stack trick in act two and then act three, you know I don't know because the game the game took a while to play but a lot of that was debates over what was legal placement.
Speaker 0: Do again to the point not take long at all because rounds one and two are completely simultaneous.
Speaker 0: So no matter how many players you have round one and two will always take the same amount of time Which is less than 15 minutes.
Speaker 0: Yeah If you include the scoring and then the round.
Speaker 0: three is gonna increase linearly based on how many players you have But it only goes up to how many players.
Speaker 1: five maybe two to five.
Speaker 0: Yeah So if you have five players, you know, it takes maybe what it's gonna take you another I don't know 30 minutes at the most People.
Speaker 0: so that means that puts this game under an hour with five players.
Speaker 1: I people at PAX explicitly said they do this if they have a four-player game Two of the people will do their performances in the third round simultaneously and each one has a judge.
Speaker 1: Yeah, then they swap.
Speaker 0: that'll speed things up.
Speaker 0: It'll literally cut the time in half But you will lose the enjoyment of seeing everyone's performance.
Speaker 1: Yep, but you do not need the app.
Speaker 1: That is one thing to make clear.
Speaker 1: The app is just a timer XCOM.
Speaker 0: You need the app.
Speaker 0: You do not need it in meeple circus because when I said they'll probably want to use I sat down at the table.
Speaker 1: I was like, I want to play this game and then the guy who's gonna teach us is like our idea Have the app.
Speaker 1: and immediately I was like, maybe I don't want to play this.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: But then he was like, no, no No, it's just a timer.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: You don't actually need it.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's a pretty good game.
Speaker 1: There's a lot of people who probably should buy it.
Speaker 1: It's not one.
Speaker 0: I did the most thing.
Speaker 0: I just can't believe.
Speaker 0: no one did this earlier.
Speaker 1: I know right?
Speaker 1: It's A lot of Americana style board games that do this in a very simple.
Speaker 0: I'm sorry about this specific thing of make a game out of the fact that everyone stacks meeples all the time.
Speaker 0: Yeah, everyone does this thing.
Speaker 0: Maybe we should make it the right way.
Speaker 1: Why the meeple?
Speaker 0: I've been stacking meeple since 2000.
Speaker 0: Oh something why did it take until?
Speaker 0: 17 for this game to come out?
Speaker 1: But if any of you do have it and you bring it to a PAX, I'll probably play it at least once.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'd play like once.
Speaker 1: yeah at a convention This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Speaker 0: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 1: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 0: Geeknights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 0: It's actually recorded at night
Speaker 1: And the patreon patrons for this episode of geek nights are Craig Oliver, Alan Joyce, Rebecca Dunn, Heidi Me Nicola, Shimmer and Grubby Obelisk, Hanging in the Sky, MyStady.com, Jeremy Minard, Len Kije, Cold Guy, Amanda Duchette, Sean Yeager, Matthew Smith, Nicholas Brando, Captain Chinguacasi, 421 Creations, No I Never
Speaker 0: Ever Wonder
Speaker 1: Why We're Here, Semper Fi, Bitch, Sheraton Monhoro, Rare Laval, James David White, Rachelle Montanona, Superboy, Rim Says Something Funny Here, Sailor Vista, Don Schleich, Char Tovish, and Jojo Joestar, Sam Cordry, Clinton Walton, Ren from New Zealand, Ryan Perrin, Drew Opendlander, Finn, Chris Midkiff, Chris Knox, Daniel Redman, Sean Klein, Chris Reimer, and Thomas Hahn.
Speaker 1: You saw I uploaded a Rims Rant.
Speaker 1: We got some final thoughts on Black Panther coming to the patrons in the near future continuing the Castlevania show.
Speaker 1: stay tuned for that.
Speaker 1: and I am still working on the final production to do the next episode of Utena The Nanami Cow episode.
Speaker 1: I've already pulled out the clips.
Speaker 1: I made some frames to try to minimize the copyright fighting that I have to constantly do to keep that show online Which is literally at least once a month.
Speaker 1: I have to file like two or three counterclaims, but it's coming Stay tuned.
Speaker 1: and now I leave you with clown college.
Speaker 0: You can't eat that.
Speaker 0: Well, I got everything I was supposed to get.
Speaker 0: I'm not going to enroll in that clown college though.
Speaker 0: That advertisement had no effect on me whatsoever.
Speaker 0: Hey Homer, the section you're supposed to be monitoring is on fire.
Speaker 0: Clowns are funny.
Speaker 0: Yes, homie That's it.
Speaker 0: you people have stood in my way long enough.
Speaker 1: I'm going to clown college.