Speaker 1: It's Tuesday August 14th 2018.
Speaker 1: I'm rim I'm Scott and this is geek nights tonight handicapping in games.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: So a big ol thunderstorm came through New York.
Speaker 1: So once you have to deal with the situation here on the subway where like you come on the tunnel is Viking.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, I took the subway because it was crazy humid and I wore suit today.
Speaker 1: but I'm on the subway and Pretty much every cell phone on the subway car starts making the hey, there's a flash flood alert sound.
Speaker 0: Yeah, everyone just fucking ignores this.
Speaker 0: one day It's gonna say hey actual emergency and they don't have a higher alert level to go to.
Speaker 0: so there is one higher alert.
Speaker 0: There's stupid wolf crying now.
Speaker 1: So honestly, I'm fine with the flash flood alerts because they're.
Speaker 0: I've seen flash floods over there Yeah, but they're not flash floods like in the desert.
Speaker 1: Well now but I mean a tornado crazy like f4 tornado While that's bigger and scarier than like a tiny tornado.
Speaker 1: tiny tornado still kills you if it hits your house.
Speaker 0: Sure, don't get hit by tornado.
Speaker 1: but the scary thing I didn't realize this was a problem and it's really sad to me that it's a problem.
Speaker 1: apparently the weather service is really working on Changing the nomenclature around these alerts because most Americans do not understand even the simplest weather alerts.
Speaker 0: It's not like anyone teaches people you just I was taught.
Speaker 1: I was taught this in elementary school.
Speaker 0: No, they never taught us.
Speaker 1: I figured we literally took a class.
Speaker 1: I'm like tornado watch tornado warning.
Speaker 1: No, what is a flash flood?
Speaker 0: No, I figured it out all based on common sense.
Speaker 1: Well, yes, but here this that's what bothers me.
Speaker 1: I was taught it but it is trivial to figure out from common sense and it's weird to me that there are people adults functioning in society who are Unclear on the difference between a tornado watch and a tornado warning.
Speaker 0: So basically any weather in the United States any weather related thing?
Speaker 0: That's a watch means the conditions are ripe.
Speaker 0: This thing could happen.
Speaker 0: warning means it's fucking.
Speaker 1: Fart watch is when rim ate a whole bunch of leafy greens and a whole bunch of bullshit and his stomach is rumbling.
Speaker 1: Yeah, my stomach's rumbling.
Speaker 1: fart warning is after the first person has smelt it.
Speaker 0: Yes I Warning means I. I just heard up and I called it in the weather station has a microphone on it and the Noise was detected.
Speaker 1: but fart watch means like so just so you know, like if you see rim in the room.
Speaker 1: You don't have to flee yet.
Speaker 1: But keep an eye out.
Speaker 0: you see right you're in a room and you see a rim and you see a bowl and you see an empty can of beans Empty Like what you eat today.
Speaker 0: 400 granola bars Ten Rico lines.
Speaker 1: Yeah, fucking okay.
Speaker 1: the only other thing cuz we're gonna talk about cons cuz a bunch of packs announcements just happen if you ever notice that you get really farty at conventions and Your throat hurts because it's a dry ass convention center.
Speaker 1: So as a result, you're eating a lot of cough drops, guess what cough drops cause farting?
Speaker 1: The pectin in case you didn't know.
Speaker 1: I learned that terrible lesson and it does not stop me from using cough drops.
Speaker 1: now I just know why I'm farting.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm Or you psycho semantically fart more when eating cough drops because you've learned this information.
Speaker 1: but you too you too.
Speaker 1: so in the news, uh Pax West which is coming up pretty soon like too soon two weeks.
Speaker 1: I still gotta like rewrite I gotta update the panel at least all my flights like everything's sorted out.
Speaker 1: We're set but they announced way later than usual.
Speaker 1: the keynote At least I feels like it's way later.
Speaker 0: I don't actually have data Yeah, but it just feels like they announced it later than they used to.
Speaker 0: but even though it may not be the case
Speaker 1: though what I can say is that as someone who has presented that literally ever every packs I've ever gone to and I've gone to every packs except two of the packs Australia's
Speaker 0: and packs seven and oh,
Speaker 1: yeah and before 2008 which there are not that many of four
Speaker 0: or five six and seven.
Speaker 1: but One thing I have noticed is that the packs Selection process for panels has gotten closer and closer to packs as time has gone on like significantly.
Speaker 1: So like I'll get the panel acceptance emails way way way way later than we used to and I don't know why I don't really Care that much, but it's something I've noticed.
Speaker 1: But anyway, the packs West keynote speaker probably will be pretty good because it is the game director of Ba of work with Warcraft World of Warcraft.
Speaker 1: Yes I'm looking at the tweet So I was trying to part because it's just game director of at Warcraft at at Blizzard and there were three ads in a row.
Speaker 0: I'm pretty sure it's World of Warcraft and not Warcraft the RTS, right?
Speaker 1: I assume so I don't know a lot about that side of Blizzard because I don't play any of those games as I did hear rumors of like Warcraft the RTS making a comeback, but I'm pretty sure it's about World of Warcraft.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so battle for Azeroth and all that stuff is coming.
Speaker 1: But basically Ian has a cost.
Speaker 1: us is going to be the keynote speaker Which probably gonna be worth.
Speaker 0: the battle of Azeroth is the seventh expansion for World of Warcraft.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right.
Speaker 0: So it was announced for Blizzcon in 2017.
Speaker 1: right because I will admit that There's a lot of the recent packs keynotes have been more missed than hit but a couple of them.
Speaker 0: I think it comes out like friggin today.
Speaker 1: Yeah Not that I'm going to play it.
Speaker 1: I know better.
Speaker 0: Why would I play World of Warcraft?
Speaker 0: expect raise the level cap from 110 to 120 and I'm gonna be level one.
Speaker 0: But yeah, so the thing is usually when someone from a big game studio does the packs keynote They're gonna announce something and it's just an ad goddess.
Speaker 0: So I noticed I'm pretty sure this is true.
Speaker 0: I read it when one place only is that it used to be that you would get Wow and you get a Wow account but you would have to buy these expansions.
Speaker 0: that would add like you couldn't go to the places to do like say, you know, the Frozen Thrones if you didn't buy the frozen throne?
Speaker 1: It makes sense because as much as you want a game company just keep expanding things forever.
Speaker 1: unless they can monetize that work It just cost them money.
Speaker 0: Mean Wow is a subscription game, but you had to buy these expansions in addition to paying the subscription for.
Speaker 0: well But it seems like now if you make a Wow account They give you every single expansion ever except for the battle for Azeroth that you got to buy.
Speaker 0: So I guess if you buy battle for Azeroth and then you keep and you pay the monthly fee You will have everything and you won't have to buy all those old expansions anymore.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so this makes me think.
Speaker 0: and the fact that he's doing this keynote and Wow.
Speaker 0: Yeah your theory right.
Speaker 0: I'm feeling like they're gonna say he's gonna come out and be like wow is over.
Speaker 0: this is the last expansion or We're gonna start something new Wow - or something out, right?
Speaker 0: There's gonna be a big shift in the Wow zone right and people haven't been playing MMOs for a while.
Speaker 0: MMOs have been Sort of done as well.
Speaker 0: There's.
Speaker 1: it seems like there still is a pretty strong core Demographic playing them.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but I feel like that demographic is in clear increasingly heavily isolated from the rest of gaming discourse.
Speaker 0: Another kind of game that's been played a lot lately are these are these ones?
Speaker 0: I forget what the one is called that people are playing.
Speaker 0: I installed it and almost played one mission But then didn't I just went to the main town?
Speaker 0: The MMO is basically a game where in the town it's an MMO and then you just group up and go on.
Speaker 0: It's like basically raids only like no world to explore.
Speaker 0: It's literally just a town and you go to the spot in the town and then it just Teleports you and your group to a mission.
Speaker 0: So not that different from so it's sort of your land, right?
Speaker 0: It's basically like a lobby and then you use the lobby to get teams or your guild or whatever and then you go and you Know fight a monster or something somewhere.
Speaker 1: and so the why the the MMOs I've played for more than an hour Are literally a text mud.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm not counting those.
Speaker 1: I'm calling Ragnarok one.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the realm of pirates.
Speaker 1: Here's the realm Ragnarok online puzzle pirates and I played the D&D one for almost an hour.
Speaker 1: Oh, there was that one time We played it together and then we quit.
Speaker 0: one time at PAX.
Speaker 0: They gave us a free disc in the in the in the in the swag bag.
Speaker 0: That was for the Lord of the Rings MMO.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah I didn't know.
Speaker 0: I installed it and I played it for free and I made a dwarf and I walked around it.
Speaker 0: I I walked around some snowy places a dwarf And I know I didn't.
Speaker 0: I hit some things with a hammer or an axe and then I uninstalled it.
Speaker 1: No, I didn't play it but I did play the D&D one and I remember the.
Speaker 1: The immediate problem was that I think we've tried to play together and I was standing in a spot in town And I said I'm there and you said you were also there and it turned out.
Speaker 1: the town was just sharted and we couldn't actually Meet each other and then we just kind of quit.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't like MMOs.
Speaker 1: Anyway in some other packs news packs South's dates were announced.
Speaker 0: I guess we got to get some hotel.
Speaker 1: Yeah luckily pack South remember pack South is the chill packs.
Speaker 1: if you Cannot afford to go to the mothership packs packs.
Speaker 0: Even if you live in I guess if you live in Boston, but if you live Just far enough away from PAX East that you'll need a hotel.
Speaker 0: So if you live in like anywhere in the Midwest you live in Western Mass you want to go to PAX East?
Speaker 0: You probably don't want to drive all the way down 84 every day.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right or whatever.
Speaker 0: the road is the mass pike you want to right?
Speaker 0: You know stay in a hotel in Boston, which means you're going to pay PAX East hotel cost.
Speaker 0: It would be cheaper for you to go to pack South pack South is my favorite non-west not Australia not unplugged packs.
Speaker 1: Really all I'm saying is PAX East is the worst packs Like it is the.
Speaker 1: yeah I like PAX East but it is of the.
Speaker 1: PAX is the worst in every possible regard.
Speaker 0: at pack South The big companies are not there as much.
Speaker 0: They're still there.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean that's where Nintendo had fucking the switch and Zelda.
Speaker 0: They didn't have that at the other houses, right breath of the wild.
Speaker 0: But you had to wait in like a line to play that.
Speaker 0: but nothing else had a line and it's way cheap and it's way Lot crowded.
Speaker 0: So if you don't like crowds, it's the packs to go to.
Speaker 1: there's real good cheap food Like there as opposed to paxi except on Sunday.
Speaker 0: Yep You can just it's not.
Speaker 0: you can always get a table and tabletop.
Speaker 0: It's February and it's not cold.
Speaker 1: You can in fact it leans heavily tabletop because of the extra space they have.
Speaker 1: Yeah You can escape the the cold in February and in my experience The keynotes at pack South have been above average compared to the other paxis concerts above average.
Speaker 0: It also has the super mariachi brothers.
Speaker 0: It also has that dungeon thing that some people seem to like that Larpy.
Speaker 1: That's the kind of thing that really can't happen at other paxis.
Speaker 0: Nope cannot but it still fills up like crazy.
Speaker 0: I think I have to make reservations for it or some shit.
Speaker 1: But and also for the first time ever my birthday will be at a pax.
Speaker 1: If our if our panel is on the day, that is my actual birthday.
Speaker 1: I will have my birthday party in the panel room.
Speaker 0: Okay, you just have your own birthday party Yeah, so
Speaker 1: remember back when we ran kinetic on one time cuz you know smaller cons like kinetic ons turnstile is like 12,000 people maybe like nine to twelve thousand people like not a big con relative to like paxis, but Local cons get a lot of weird panel submissions like often from people who don't quite understand how panels work.
Speaker 1: But I got a submission number of years ago.
Speaker 1: This kid literally submitted his own ninth birthday To the panel submission.
Speaker 0: Why didn't we accept that?
Speaker 1: I did.
Speaker 1: I put it on the schedule.
Speaker 1: It was like Alex's ninth birthday party.
Speaker 1: I put it for an hour in like a hundred person panel room.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm and People kept coming up and asking at our info desk.
Speaker 1: Like hey, I don't remember this.
Speaker 1: you really don't remember this.
Speaker 1: No, I have pictures from it.
Speaker 1: Okay, it was the kid like that we smile.
Speaker 1: in fact I had staff smuggle the cake in because they couldn't bring it up the escalators because the Convention center staff were like no outside food.
Speaker 1: so I brought it in the elevator with my staff biz and this kid just had his birthday party and 70 people showed up to the panel Partly out of morbid curiosity.
Speaker 1: and when it turned out it literally was this kid's birthday party.
Speaker 1: They just totally celebrated it with him.
Speaker 1: It was awesome.
Speaker 0: I wouldn't you?
Speaker 1: yeah, so I remember this though I don't know how you don't remember things.
Speaker 1: Anyway, we will probably see you in San Antonio in about 156 days.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm gonna figure what panels to do there.
Speaker 0: All right, so The big.
Speaker 0: there's some gaming news because Gen Con happens a bunch of gaming news and even though we don't.
Speaker 0: we don't suggest anyone.
Speaker 0: Go to Gen Con unless you live real close to it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, even professionally like we don't perform there for a reason Yeah, but they still all the tabletop companies in America announced their shit at Gen Con so day.
Speaker 1: It'll be unplugged Right.
Speaker 0: So one thing that actually wasn't announced at Gen Con but happened to show up in the mail Just like a week ago was yellow and Yangtze the sister game to our favorite game ever Tigris and Euphrates.
Speaker 0: It's almost the same game only with a hex map.
Speaker 0: But also the rules are changed to accommodate the hex map.
Speaker 0: But also the rules are changed to streamline it and they are changed in such a way where it's the same game But it's also not the same game and
Speaker 1: we're gonna do a real full review of it later because we have to play it a lot and say
Speaker 0: it's sort of like cricket and baseball.
Speaker 0: you're like That's the same game.
Speaker 0: It's like.
Speaker 0: no, it's not.
Speaker 1: But as you may know Tigris and Euphrates is in our opinion one of the best tabletop games ever designed.
Speaker 1: Like I cannot I cannot understate how high of an opinion I have of Tigris and Euphrates.
Speaker 0: Dr.
Speaker 0: K Rainer Knizia made Tigris and Euphrates and also made this game 15. how many years after 15 16?
Speaker 0: Oh my god 17 years pretty sure the episode in fact.
Speaker 1: I think when we reviewed Tigris and Euphrates on geek nights the year was 2005, right?
Speaker 0: But I mean the first time you played.
Speaker 0: it must have been 2002.
Speaker 1: we reviewed it first because we'd already played it so much know.
Speaker 0: when did the game come out?
Speaker 0: go to board game game.
Speaker 1: I'm just looking to see when we reviewed it.
Speaker 1: November 22nd 2005. we reviewed on one geek nights episode Soulcalibur 2, Tigris and Euphrates, Puerto Rico, Carcassonne and Alhambra.
Speaker 0: So you basically just killed all the games.
Speaker 1: Yeah Well our things of the day were the Nintendo Finger assistant.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the thing that never came out.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 1: and the dangers of masturbation.
Speaker 0: Whatever that is, you'll go blind.
Speaker 1: Whatever that is is gone.
Speaker 1: You'll go blind.
Speaker 0: Everyone knows that.
Speaker 0: The game came out in.
Speaker 1: It is shocking to me that radar kinesia revisited this game and put such effort into making a Sequel to it.
Speaker 1: that is different and good But feels very much the same in terms of like the way that I process information in my brain while I play it.
Speaker 1: It's brain feel is very similar to Tigris and Euphrates but the actual higher-order heuristics to play it and be good at it are Vastly different even on your first play.
Speaker 0: The game came out in '97.
Speaker 0: I don't know if it came out in '97, but it won the Meeple's Choice Award in '97 And it won the deutscher spiel prize best family adult game in '98 and was recommended for the spiel de char in '98 But did not win.
Speaker 0: So it's been basically 20 years like the 20th anniversary base of abouts.
Speaker 1: So yeah, so yeah.
Speaker 1: well like I said we're gonna do a full review But our first impressions are it is real fun.
Speaker 0: If you like T&E you're gonna like a game That's very similar to T&E.
Speaker 0: Yeah And you've probably played T&E so much that even if T&E is in the end after we play both games a whole bunch Well, you already played one of them a whole bunch after you play Y&Y enough to accurately judge it.
Speaker 0: It may turn out that T&E is a better game But it's like.
Speaker 0: well you've played so much T&E right and even though that game never gets old You can get even less old if you mix it up a little bit with a hex map and some different rules.
Speaker 1: But I've played T&E so much in my life And yet I still have not even bothered to use the alternate map or the extra monuments.
Speaker 0: We don't need those.
Speaker 1: I have not even like attempted to play with those because the base game is still inexhaustible.
Speaker 1: but Yellow and Yangtze is Equivalent, but different.
Speaker 1: like it does not replace T&E and I do believe there is value in owning both and playing Both regularly, I think they'll scratch slightly different itches.
Speaker 1: And if I had to guess and I'm guessing because we've literally only played it once The primary difference in terms of how you approach the game Whoa Well is that we'll go in terms of like.
Speaker 1: the way it plays out is that T&E Could have big gambles and big risks and big swings late game Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: Yellow and Yangtze has no big swings.
Speaker 1: It is a Methodical march toward the game's conclusion, right?
Speaker 0: Oh the other thing is that in yellow and yangtze.
Speaker 0: There's a lot more Political things you can do but they're limited.
Speaker 0: in the right We don't score big points or is.
Speaker 0: in T&E You can't really do too much political stuff really because you have to sacrifice a lot.
Speaker 1: I'm not not as directly.
Speaker 0: yeah, and if you succeed in T&E you get a basically a fistful of cubes.
Speaker 0: There's really not a lot of ways to get a fistful of cubes and why and why.
Speaker 0: but what's very fascinating Is that yellow and yangtze and it's very hard to hold anything in Y&Y.
Speaker 1: the the specific changes that are pretty subtle are Almost a catalogue of the minor complaints we had about T&E.
Speaker 1: Like there's a really fiddly rule that many players are feeling this has been removed.
Speaker 1: Yep There's no fiddliness.
Speaker 1: many people who play T&E even if they play a lot never encounter the situation these two situations the situation where you want to place a leader that would happen to connect two kingdoms and The situation where you want to place a tile that would connect more than two kingdoms.
Speaker 1: and Y&Y has specific Surgical solutions to those fiddly bits that are really really good Like they add to the game and one of them you might even be able to backport into T&E.
Speaker 0: Maybe I wouldn't.
Speaker 0: I wouldn't do so though.
Speaker 1: I might attempt it once to see if it changes the game Just the one where you can play a tile and it won't trigger a cop.
Speaker 0: Anyway, it gives you one lousy point.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the other big thing is that in T&E if your leaders got knocked off the board You gonna save anything for the episode about Y&Y?
Speaker 1: I think we'll have a lot to say once we play the game more but the other like sort of surgical change was that in T&E if your leaders get knocked off the board, you're kind of done.
Speaker 0: Like it's real hard to get back on Late game it's hard to get back on Unless you have a fistful of red tiles.
Speaker 1: In general knocking people off the board is very powerful in T&E.
Speaker 1: in Y&Y when leaders are off the board They have a minor power.
Speaker 1: So You almost have a little bit of a boost to get back on the board.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: That is a really get some points Yeah Anyway, so the major big news from Gen Con from Fantasy Flight Games who gave up on Netrunner and is usually Doesn't make good games.
Speaker 0: You're right Fantasy Flight is this weird company.
Speaker 0: They got bought by Asmodee, right and the CEO of Fantasy Flight is resigning which is good because I basically that's like the toy.
Speaker 0: He's basically the Twilight Imperium guy.
Speaker 0: Tells you a lot about what Fantasy Flight does.
Speaker 0: but it's like.
Speaker 0: all the games that Fantasy Flight themselves have made have turned out bad And it's like as publishers.
Speaker 0: they as my in my opinion.
Speaker 0: They haven't really done great.
Speaker 0: It's just that there are certain games that they publish that weren't made by them and those games are often good because People go to them to get things published because they're a somewhat big board game publisher.
Speaker 0: Yep, right?
Speaker 0: They've got the pipeline They've got the supply chain as like they often screw things up, but you know on the publishing side But it's still you can't root, you know It's still.
Speaker 0: the game made by someone else is still good right.
Speaker 0: the fact that they publish teeny doesn't make teeny a bad game.
Speaker 0: They publish citadels.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Anyway, Citadel is a great game.
Speaker 1: So they gotta know we've broken it and we never need to play it again.
Speaker 0: So Fantasy Flight, you know usually has things printed in China and brought over on the boat, right?
Speaker 0: Usually.
Speaker 0: but they've developed over recent times this print-on-demand Facility I guess near where they are in Minnesota or whatever and they used I remember when they developed it because they started printing like prize Cards for netrunner with that and you could tell those cards were different in lower quality Yeah, but now it seems like they're printing like top quality cards there that you can't tell that They're not the the real deal, but more importantly
Speaker 1: they've clearly come up with a clever Printing process to do something specific, right?
Speaker 1: So no one's really done, right?
Speaker 0: So Richard Garfield the creator of magic among other games has had this game idea where you would.
Speaker 0: instead of making decks right for your customizable card game or collectible card game you would buy a deck and You'd open it up and inside would be a deck that's ready to play and you can't customize it.
Speaker 0: and but Everyone who buys a deck has a completely different deck or at least somewhat different Right.
Speaker 0: So me and Rand go to the store and we buy two decks and they're not the same.
Speaker 0: We go to a different store and buy another deck and it's not the same.
Speaker 1: So it's not like me where there's 12 decks or whatever.
Speaker 1: I buy them and but there's billions of possible decks.
Speaker 0: I think they said there's like six factions or something or some number of factions and each deck is gonna have three of them.
Speaker 0: But you're not gonna just cuz you have a faction doesn't mean you have the same cards from that faction.
Speaker 0: It's like a few hundred cards in the game.
Speaker 0: So you're only gonna get like 60 of those cards in some random Combination right and it's like well some decks might be stronger than others some might be weaker But this is like.
Speaker 0: this is a new thing in tabletop gaming.
Speaker 0: This is not something that's been done before.
Speaker 0: that just for that alone.
Speaker 0: good or bad.
Speaker 0: That's exciting.
Speaker 0: Yes, a new kind of game.
Speaker 1: We have to pay attention to it, right?
Speaker 0: So they're publishing this game And it seemed it called key forge.
Speaker 1: Oh here with a vast array of creatures artifacts abilities and over 104 quadrillion possible decks, right?
Speaker 0: So I watched a short demo video of the game and it seems like not the worst card game ever.
Speaker 0: from the little I was Able to see and I read some articles.
Speaker 0: I read a thing Richard posted on Facebook talking about how he designed it a little bit.
Speaker 0: That was pretty fascinating.
Speaker 1: Oh, I saw that but I didn't read it yet.
Speaker 0: So I feel like I'm gonna buy one or two decks.
Speaker 0: and this is like hey you want to play a two-player game Right.
Speaker 0: It's like well you bust out two decks You can sort of master them if you want to be competitive or something, right?
Speaker 0: But you can you know?
Speaker 0: Maybe eventually all your friends will just have their one deck and then when you meet someone at a convention if they have one It's like hey Right a lot better than you know, even netrunner at least socially maybe not as a game Yeah, but socially right it has.
Speaker 0: it has a purpose.
Speaker 0: if you know If everyone has a deck it's like two people waiting for the big board game to finish so that they can join in.
Speaker 0: Play a key for it right better than playing a hive a little gonna take you a little longer.
Speaker 0: be a little better of a game maybe.
Speaker 1: Anyway, see is I got a town which is a pretty good two-player like.
Speaker 0: It sounds good.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but even though I think we're done with a town.
Speaker 1: I think we've solved it I find anyway, well, we've talked about any time another time.
Speaker 0: So that's key Forge.
Speaker 0: What FFG is done is since I guess Richard Garfield gave him this great idea and they were able to make this technology To print these decks at the printing press they decided hey, let's use this to make other games.
Speaker 0: So they had Cory who is the guy who made games.
Speaker 0: He just he's a Fantasy Flight employee.
Speaker 0: He's made games like the Battlestar game, which I don't like.
Speaker 0: I basically don't like anything Cory's ever made.
Speaker 0: I don't know if nothing is a bad person just saying bad for us.
Speaker 0: I don't like any game Cory's ever made.
Speaker 0: so They had him make a game called.
Speaker 0: What's it called?
Speaker 0: discover So what this game is.
Speaker 0: it's a co-op game where you're basically trying to overcome obstacles to go on an adventure or something like that and It's also sort of.
Speaker 0: it sounds like it's sort of a storytelling game sort of like Arabian Nights the choose your own adventure one.
Speaker 0: But you buy this game.
Speaker 0: it comes in a box.
Speaker 0: Every box is different.
Speaker 0: You're gonna get different ponds different tiles different.
Speaker 0: right.
Speaker 0: one box could have an adventure in the jungle and another box could have an adventure In the mountains.
Speaker 0: another box could have an under-the-sea adventure.
Speaker 0: You don't fucking know right and that gives you.
Speaker 0: so if you like this kind of game, which I probably won't but maybe you will It's like wow, they're gonna get people to buy like more than one copy of this game.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: usually when you got a board game like this you buy a copy and ever and one person owns a pandemic and everyone Keeps playing it.
Speaker 0: now You could buy multiple copies.
Speaker 0: if you're a super nerd Every time you're bored of the one you got you can go buy another one right.
Speaker 0: also You could get all your friends to buy one.
Speaker 0: Yeah instead of just one friend buying one right.
Speaker 0: so Being a good like Swap and trade community the point is oh, that's a good idea.
Speaker 0: Yeah one trade it with someone else's.
Speaker 0: That's a real good.
Speaker 0: I didn't even think of that.
Speaker 1: You just bring it to every packs and swap with someone.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like you play it swap it with someone else who's got a copy just and then it's like alright Why wouldn't you as long as not missing any pieces ruined or anything?
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like man.
Speaker 0: That's good, but yeah, this is really Ingenious to you know they got to use this technology on a different kind of game genre.
Speaker 0: What other game genres will they use it on if it proves to be successful?
Speaker 0: Oh, man, yeah I I mean I would just like to see the simplest Like.
Speaker 0: they're already going in the deep end with this with like the unique decks and the unique games.
Speaker 1: I would look for a game like imagine Shogun or like a basic war type game, but just the map and the.
Speaker 0: That's my idea.
Speaker 0: You're just you're just passing off my ideas.
Speaker 0: I had the same idea.
Speaker 0: Yeah, just keep it simple.
Speaker 0: Just have a war a basic war game.
Speaker 0: Right a good war game solid game and just only thing that's unique is the map so that every time you know Maybe give you five maps in the box and every box is five unique maps.
Speaker 0: And it's like you trade maps with people that you know.
Speaker 0: the trading reserves idea.
Speaker 1: I feel like you have one more unique aspect than just the mat because we already have Expansions to a million million games.
Speaker 0: that here's a different board.
Speaker 1: Here's a different map.
Speaker 1: I have like four formula day expansions up there.
Speaker 0: Yeah, imagine a formula day just like random racetracks.
Speaker 1: actually that could be pretty fun.
Speaker 0: Yeah, or like you know you everyone gets different D&D characters in their RPG box.
Speaker 1: Oh the RPG world would be interesting.
Speaker 0: I'm just saying yeah the procedural generation at the printing press is gonna make some good stuff in the tabletop world.
Speaker 0: This is the thing to pay attention to.
Speaker 0: this is the height of current tabletop tech.
Speaker 0: that must not be overlooked.
Speaker 1: So when someone finds the god deck of Key Forge Will that just be like this priceless artifact?
Speaker 0: well no so.
Speaker 1: apparently if you write the bidding chains If you read a Richard Garfield's article for serious people will have a way to balance a handicap.
Speaker 0: right serious players There's gonna be some sort of like mechanic called bidding chains where you I guess you bid a number of chains.
Speaker 0: I guess it's and the details aren't.
Speaker 0: he doesn't say the details But in my guess is that it's like when you sit down to play you would bid like I'm gonna beat you by three And that you know.
Speaker 0: it's like if your deck is strong you have an incentive to bid higher Right that and then to sort of balance things out when you know your deck is strong.
Speaker 0: So this book is going over to it.
Speaker 1: than that though because I'd always bid low.
Speaker 1: I don't.
Speaker 0: I'm sure this is gonna be some.
Speaker 0: it's gonna work in some reasonable way.
Speaker 1: I suspect what'll happen is serious.
Speaker 1: people will do this mechanic Which I don't know how it works yet, and everyone else will ignore it and just have OP decks or no or non OP decks Yeah, or what?
Speaker 0: if you just meet someone who plays casually, but they happen to have this OP deck Then you buy it from them.
Speaker 1: I wonder I think real OP decks.
Speaker 1: There will be a secondary market?
Speaker 0: well Not it.
Speaker 0: well if there's any competitive scene though You're gonna have to do the bidding thing and if that balances it out Then it doesn't matter what deck you have though.
Speaker 0: what it'll be really interesting Deck will be the one you have and have learned and mastered the most.
Speaker 1: what will be very interesting to me Is that if done properly most people even people who play a lot of tabletop games are fucking awful at bidding like bidding is Such a rare skill.
Speaker 0: people who play competitive card games seriously and go to tournaments are excellent at bidding.
Speaker 1: I don't know if you're excellent at bidding.
Speaker 1: They're excellent at all.
Speaker 0: the Play netrunner against top tier game.
Speaker 1: Oh yeah, but what about magic?
Speaker 1: how many man?
Speaker 1: How many top tier magic players are good at bidding?
Speaker 0: the top tier ones are gonna bid your head good?
Speaker 1: They're real good, but they don't have to be good at bidding to be good at magic.
Speaker 0: People who win magic grand prix's are excellent gamers.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, but even fuck out.
Speaker 0: even excellent gamers They're better than you.
Speaker 1: even excellent gamers.
Speaker 1: I find are Awful at bidding and valuation anyway.
Speaker 0: But yeah, so it'll be interesting.
Speaker 0: That's what gave us the idea to do a show in handicap.
Speaker 0: such we hadn't done which I thought we did.
Speaker 1: But anyway things of the day, so this is just a tweet, but it's pretty good.
Speaker 1: It's just.
Speaker 1: I love the justice But it's the photograph of the top of a urinal somewhere.
Speaker 0: And does it have a sticker from a computer like yours does?
Speaker 1: no It does not have my my your.
Speaker 1: my toilet has g-skill ram in it, okay And also my marker wave has nice.
Speaker 1: We should get.
Speaker 0: we should get like one megabyte g-skill ram That's worth nothing and just stick it in the top just over decker deck it.
Speaker 1: I showed.
Speaker 1: Anyway the serial number on this urinal is Legendary.
Speaker 1: if this is photoshopped, I don't even care, but I want to believe that it's not because the serial number is For you to PN2.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: It's perfect.
Speaker 1: This is exactly what I needed in my life.
Speaker 0: right now It also might not even it might even if it's not photoshopped.
Speaker 1: someone could have made that sticker and put it on a toilet Which is a plus because that is on the level of the kind of prank One of my favorite pranks in the world.
Speaker 1: with this dude not a good night for flying.
Speaker 1: This is much more subtle.
Speaker 1: this dude busted into a mall at night and there was an Italian restaurant and they had this like metal fake wrought-iron thing that had like grapes and like Tomatoes like kind of carved on it Bit bit by bit over the course of months.
Speaker 1: He cut the fruit the vegetables off and replaced them with bananas That he had sculpted until eventually this Italian restaurant had this like wrought-iron grade that had nothing but bananas on it And no one ever noticed.
Speaker 0: No, I would.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's a good prank.
Speaker 1: that's the kind of thing I like anyway, so what do you got?
Speaker 0: So there's this Twitter account and the Twitter account.
Speaker 0: It's one of those Twitter accounts where it's like, you know It's not.
Speaker 0: it's not a real person, right?
Speaker 0: It's just sort of photos of you know, it's a sort of character, right?
Speaker 0: So there's a Pokemon called electrode.
Speaker 0: an electrode is basically it looks like a pokeball.
Speaker 0: it's red and white ball Yeah, and it's kind of angry and if you get near it explodes and it's got like the snarky face, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, but there's another Pokemon called ditto and ditto is like this blob and it becomes any other Pokemon.
Speaker 0: The thing is if ditto becomes a Pokemon it looks exactly like the Pokemon is copying except except it's got the different face Right, which is pretty much two dots and a smiley.
Speaker 0: So apparently Because Pokemon is just so enormous.
Speaker 0: They've made plushies in the past Because there's a whole line of Pokemon plushies That
Speaker 1: are not
Speaker 0: electrode and not did I'm sure they've made both electrode and ditto, but they've also made plushies that are ditto as Can get an electrode ditto plushie, which is an electrode plushie with a stupid face on it Or a poly with a bit even better a poly world plushie with a silly face on.
Speaker 0: And so somebody took one of these ditto electrode plushies Which is ridiculously cute and they made a Twitter account where they would put the ditto electrode in places and photo it in various cute scenarios on an almost daily basis and they just open an Instagram account also.
Speaker 0: so you got your pick.
Speaker 0: so it's ditto as electrode and Even better friend ditto as poly world and some other ditto friends.
Speaker 1: It's good stuff.
Speaker 0: It's like the cutest Twitter account That's going right now.
Speaker 0: It's like Pusheen level of cuteness.
Speaker 1: It is definitely Pusheen adjacent.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think there's even like a magnetite.
Speaker 0: That's Pusheen and I'm not sure it's a magnetite.
Speaker 1: Anyway ditto as Pusheen there.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if you want to look at cute pictures of a plushie like, you know at amusement park on the beach in the mall Happy Wednesday having a cake going to sleep playing with a dog This is the Twitter account for you.
Speaker 1: So in the meta moment the geek nights book club book is no longer Homer's Odyssey But it is now the Space Odyssey the 2001 Space Odyssey.
Speaker 1: So yeah, we have a book club.
Speaker 1: You should do it.
Speaker 1: We are doing a panel at PAX West on Monday morning, which Monday badges almost sold out.
Speaker 1: There's only 16 days before PAX.
Speaker 1: God, it's really coming up Good times.
Speaker 1: so on Monday at 10 a.m.
Speaker 1: Pacific time.
Speaker 1: We were doing the 40 tabletop games.
Speaker 1: You must play Otherwise, we'll just be there playing games cuz it's packs And that's what we got.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: So Handicapping, I don't think we've never done this specifically.
Speaker 0: I mean, I guess we haven't done a main bit that was called handicapping But I feel like we've talked about it many many times in the show in the past.
Speaker 1: Well, it's interesting is very a lot of gay especially tabletop games.
Speaker 1: Rarely if ever have this concept.
Speaker 0: no, but so handicapping in games is Mostly you see it in games like bowling and golf and these are games that are individual sports.
Speaker 0: But you're like.
Speaker 0: tennis is an individual sport.
Speaker 0: Yeah But in tennis you're directly competing against another human being like in the actual tennis match, right?
Speaker 0: You beat them and that's your measure of who's better me or you?
Speaker 0: when you play golf Yeah, you can you play the same course as someone else at the same time, but there's no like direct Competition between you both playing.
Speaker 0: are you bowl?
Speaker 0: It's like I bowl and you're bowling in the same lane as me at the same time, but there's no direct battle.
Speaker 0: So the real measure in these sports is not whether you beat someone else at that exact moment.
Speaker 0: Right because nothing you do influences their game except psychologically, right when they see your score up there on the board or whatever, right?
Speaker 0: It's that you are trying to improve yourself.
Speaker 0: You're competing against yourself and You know you.
Speaker 0: so it's like well if I did better than I did before then I've Succeeded.
Speaker 0: and therefore when you want to compare people at these sports you would use a handicap.
Speaker 0: So it's like well, look, I'm an old man, right?
Speaker 0: Obviously, I'm not gonna get a 60 at the golf course.
Speaker 1: But handicapping is also used in direct competition games to allow two people with vastly different skill To play a competitive feeling meaningful game against each other, right?
Speaker 0: Well game, you know a game like power grid would have a catch-up mechanisms built in.
Speaker 0: it's not handicapping It's.
Speaker 0: the game is designed in such a way to give the player who's behind more power.
Speaker 1: Handicapping would be the player who is better at power grid starts with less money, right?
Speaker 0: Hey anything like that.
Speaker 0: handicapping is like an external almost artificial interfering or Unbalancing of the game intentionally, right?
Speaker 0: It's like you starting Monopoly with less money.
Speaker 0: It's like they can't be a rule of the game that like you arbitrarily start with less money.
Speaker 0: It's not fair, right?
Speaker 0: But it's like that's what.
Speaker 0: what do you think handicap in golf?
Speaker 0: I'll give you 20 strokes, right?
Speaker 0: It's like you just start with a score of negative 20 and I start with a score of zero.
Speaker 0: It's not fair.
Speaker 0: It's you you insert some artificial unfairness and misalignment at the start of the game.
Speaker 0: So that way you you can basically say, ah, you know, yeah, obviously I beat you but I didn't beat you by 20.
Speaker 0: Yeah means I was playing worse than I'm supposed to and you're playing better than you're supposed to.
Speaker 0: so we say that you beat Me, right?
Speaker 1: So for example, I'm really good at ping-pong But my dad is unfucking beatable at ping-pong and he taught me how to play.
Speaker 0: I'm sure there are people who will just destroy your dad ping-pong.
Speaker 1: I'm seeing them on YouTube, but I've done well back when I was in the like New York Finance tournament scene Which I am NOT anymore.
Speaker 1: I actually haven't played ping-pong in like seven years.
Speaker 1: But my dad when he was teaching me the way he would do it is I would win if I got even one point against him Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: And once I started beating him now, I'd win if I got two points against him Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: I never got better than a handicap of you need five points against my dad.
Speaker 0: He's real good.
Speaker 0: He'd been playing it for a long time.
Speaker 1: Yeah in firemen just hanging out Like what are you gonna do when there isn't a fire?
Speaker 1: Yep gonna play ping-pong?
Speaker 0: They didn't have video games.
Speaker 1: Yep, but the tricky part about handicapping is that unless it's done Methodically and unless the data you have about the players to determine the handicap is some objective useful measure Handicapping is really hard to do.
Speaker 1: Like you're not gonna be able to make a fair handicap in a game without a lot of data and a lot of rigor.
Speaker 0: Handicapping Precisely is extremely extremely difficult, right?
Speaker 0: Usually in bowling It's like you just know your own handicap that you keep track of over time, right?
Speaker 0: and it's and usually it's only It's up to you and sort of the honor system to show up at the bowling alley and enter it in.
Speaker 0: if you're in a League the league will track it for you over time.
Speaker 1: or it's used in situations where there is a formal ladder.
Speaker 1: There's a formal ranking system of some kind and handicaps are determined based on that system.
Speaker 0: But even when there are handicaps like well the best person still wins.
Speaker 1: so I learned something interesting just now Where the turn handicap comes from?
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm, you know Because I didn't and now I do.
Speaker 0: I mean I can sort of guess the etymology.
Speaker 1: So you're probably really wrong.
Speaker 1: the term handicap derives from hand in cap Uh-huh referring to a system wherein players place bets or money into the cap of a neutral arbiter to reach an agreement.
Speaker 1: What for the relative value of items being traded?
Speaker 1: I feel like we could.
Speaker 1: I Just read this Wikipedia article.
Speaker 1: We could definitely make a simple tabletop game that uses this mechanic.
Speaker 1: I've never seen this mechanic used anywhere.
Speaker 1: Uh-huh.
Speaker 1: So it's an old English.
Speaker 1: I'm just gonna read it.
Speaker 1: It's one paragraph.
Speaker 1: This is kind of fascinating.
Speaker 1: Okay an old English trading game.
Speaker 1: Two players want to trade possessions.
Speaker 0: Like I want to trade you my car for your Nintendo switch.
Speaker 1: Yeah, something like that.
Speaker 1: an umpire Decides whether the items have the same value.
Speaker 0: they don't.
Speaker 1: a car is worth way more and if not What the what that umpire believes the difference is?
Speaker 0: Well, it's a $20,000 car and it's a $500 switch.
Speaker 0: So we'll say 19. it's basically a three nineteen five hundred.
Speaker 1: It's three-way gambling.
Speaker 1: So the players the two players who want to trade and the umpire Agree to forfeit money into a cap.
Speaker 1: Okay The players didn't put their hands into the cap and then they either leave their hand open or closed To signal whether or not they agree with the valuation or disagree with the valuation that the umpire decided.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm if both players agree the difference in valuation is paid and The items are traded and the umpire collects the forfeit and there's a little bit more to it.
Speaker 0: But basically one I don't get it.
Speaker 1: So one person bets on what the difference in value is and the other end the two players have put up stakes that may or may not have different value and then you who like each of us would forfeit the amount of money.
Speaker 1: that is the difference and Then we'd agree whether or not I forfeit nineteen five.
Speaker 0: you forfeit nineteen five.
Speaker 0: now We've got like twenty.
Speaker 0: you got a zillion dollars in there.
Speaker 0: Oh, okay, then what?
Speaker 1: So the?
Speaker 1: apparently this was played in the 14th century And That's it.
Speaker 1: There's not that much more information here.
Speaker 0: I still don't get it.
Speaker 1: I feel like I can put this in a game.
Speaker 0: I don't get it.
Speaker 1: I feel like there is a way to make this a game mechanic.
Speaker 0: You haven't explained it.
Speaker 0: I don't understand.
Speaker 1: I think I need I'll find a diagram or something.
Speaker 1: I'll link to.
Speaker 0: okay anyway.
Speaker 1: so Handicap says handicapping systems are actually pretty common in video games, especially fighting games.
Speaker 0: Well, I mean, I don't haven't seen them in recent fighting games But back in the day when you played Street Fighter They would like these stars at least on my home version of Street Fighter 2 championship edition.
Speaker 0: Oh, and it's like you would.
Speaker 0: we would always leave it at three because he felt like that was the default.
Speaker 1: We left it at whatever the default was because we had no idea what it was, right?
Speaker 0: It wasn't explained very well.
Speaker 0: But I guess if you increased or decrease the stars I don't know which you would get like more or less health or do more or less damage than normal and this way a very Good player could play against a weak player and still have like a close Battle, so it's funny.
Speaker 1: You don't know which because I googled for this and I found on the Super Street Fighter 2 Message board on game facts ten years ago.
Speaker 1: Someone asked do more stars make you stronger or weaker.
Speaker 0: Yep What does it say?
Speaker 1: Uh Someone said more stars means more power.
Speaker 1: I think three stars is considered normal.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think I remember Someone else.
Speaker 1: I think four stars is normal.
Speaker 0: Okay, someone else.
Speaker 1: Yep, but more stars made you stronger.
Speaker 0: So basically if you were the crap if you're a little kid and playing against someone who's actually good The good player would go one star Yeah, and the kid would get like ten stars.
Speaker 1: Smash Brothers has the mechanic where you can start.
Speaker 1: You can make a player start with a higher percentage.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you can also I think give people more stocks.
Speaker 0: I think I'm not mistaken.
Speaker 1: I think there's a bunch of handicapping mechanisms in Smash.
Speaker 0: Yeah, no one ever uses them.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I Definitely the tournament scene doesn't I?
Speaker 1: I get the impression that video games and eSports Both professional and amateur have zero interest in handicapping.
Speaker 0: Well, no because if you're doing an actual tournament, right of say, you know Street Fighter it's like well everyone has to have the same freaking thing.
Speaker 0: You can't be having more help.
Speaker 1: But I've seen in especially in amateur casual sports Even tournaments with cash prizes will in would incorporate handicapping in like golf and tennis and all sorts of sports.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well, that's that's very common even when they're a different situation.
Speaker 1: significant cash prizes.
Speaker 1: But if there was a significant cash prize in an eSport, I feel like no one involved would be willing to entertain a handicap.
Speaker 0: No Not at all.
Speaker 1: I wonder just.
Speaker 1: it seems like there's no difference other than a difference in culture.
Speaker 0: Well, it's.
Speaker 0: it's a cultural but it's not.
Speaker 0: it's also not just the cash prize right?
Speaker 0: think about this.
Speaker 0: Like let's say I'm running a geek night's golf tournament right to get money for the charity of geek?
Speaker 0: Yes, and people pay to get in and we give out some prizes from sponsors, right?
Speaker 0: Being the champion of the geek night's Golf tournament doesn't mean anything.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right.
Speaker 0: So if you're the United's Golf Tournament champion, that doesn't mean anything, right?
Speaker 0: But if you suck at golf and say let's say Tiger Woods is also coming to the tournament You want to have it?
Speaker 0: Why would you pay to enter my golf tournament if you have no chance of winning a prize, right?
Speaker 0: It's like you want.
Speaker 0: you want to basically feel like if you go out there and play your best round That you're gonna win something, right?
Speaker 0: It's like you don't want to show up and already see that there's a pro there who's there for the charity who's gonna win everything.
Speaker 0: So it's like you're there for the prizes.
Speaker 0: I'd say Evo if you're there to play Street Fighter You're there to see who the best Street Fighter in the world is.
Speaker 0: they don't use handicaps in the PGA Tour Right to where they're trying to find the best golfers are right?
Speaker 0: They don't use handicaps of us open where they're trying to see the best tennis player is or the US Open of golf.
Speaker 0: They only use handicaps at these tournaments and events where it's about the prizes or some other thing and not Being the champion doesn't have any meaning.
Speaker 1: but one thing I've noticed sort of it.
Speaker 0: It'd be okay to use handicaps in say your local softball league, right?
Speaker 0: But it would not be okay to use handicaps at the softball Olympics.
Speaker 1: So this might be anecdotal.
Speaker 0: some team some countries that have really really bad a softball could probably use it.
Speaker 1: Well, it might be.
Speaker 1: no this is anecdotal but I get the impression forget tournaments even in casual video game play where?
Speaker 1: Handicapping mechanisms exist.
Speaker 1: I find that even when players have disparate skills There seems to be a still a strong resistance to using these features.
Speaker 0: Uh-huh I think there shouldn't be those.
Speaker 0: those are the situations that these features are perfect for.
Speaker 0: I think part of it is because the features Aren't up front and don't describe themselves.
Speaker 0: Well, yeah, right.
Speaker 0: They don't present themselves in a way that you know.
Speaker 1: The Street Fighter 2 one right.
Speaker 0: the user interface is not presented in such a way that you know It makes people go and find it's usually like in a sub menu or something, right?
Speaker 0: What if instead right you were to say load up Smash Brothers and it'd be like, okay, you know Who's?
Speaker 0: who is player one player one's a little three.
Speaker 0: You just you told the game.
Speaker 0: player one is a five-year-old Right player two is an e-sport champion and player three is just someone who's played a lot of video games.
Speaker 0: Right if you could just tell the game that and it just adjusted accordingly.
Speaker 1: Or if the game you registered a profile and over time the game itself calculated your handicap Right and or you would just.
Speaker 0: you know, even if you didn't have profiles you just start playing Right and as long as you don't switch controllers, you just keep playing and over time, right?
Speaker 0: You don't even know it's handicapping.
Speaker 0: you just say, you know Balance mode on because you're you know that the player is playing aren't playing seriously and have disparate skill levels, right?
Speaker 0: You just you agree.
Speaker 0: Okay It's on and then as you you might play the first match and the best player is gonna destroy you and then starting in match To match three as you go on suddenly having these close exciting matches now, right?
Speaker 0: so
Speaker 1: overwatch and also
Speaker 0: if as your skills would increase because you're you know Even though you would be able to stay alive longer see what that good player is doing learn from them And then the handicap for you would start to decrease to make up for your skill increase.
Speaker 1: So this isn't straight handicapping but overwatch does something very fascinating like that.
Speaker 0: Remember initial D had the in the arcade.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah If you hell if you secret there's a secret feature.
Speaker 1: if you held down the brake When you started the mail the race it set everything up.
Speaker 0: No, I think you still held down the clutch when you turn the car on.
Speaker 1: No you held down the brake.
Speaker 1: There was no clutch.
Speaker 0: I think there were anyway.
Speaker 0: No, there's no clutch.
Speaker 1: There's a shifter.
Speaker 1: You didn't have to hit a clutch There was something.
Speaker 0: Anyway, the point is that yeah an initial D arcade game if you just play default without knowing it Basically gives a speed boost to whoever the car and back is.
Speaker 0: So whoever's losing the race basically gets boosted so much that they will be on the ass of the person first.
Speaker 0: It's only a two-car race, but rubber band mechanics are not handicapping.
Speaker 1: No, they're adjacent and they serve a similar purpose in some ways, but they They readjust themselves over the course of a single game.
Speaker 1: they're not based on your past history.
Speaker 1: They just try to make the game 50/50 no matter what at all times.
Speaker 0: Well, it's a little bit a little bit But they don't like.
Speaker 1: if I'm better than you and I'm ahead of you It keeps you close to me, but if you pass me it keeps me close to you.
Speaker 0: But if I'm really good at power grid And I just managed to stay ahead the whole time you bouncing off the bottom probably isn't gonna be enough.
Speaker 0: But you had.
Speaker 0: if you intelligently bounce off the bottom then you could get ahead.
Speaker 1: But it's still not handicapping.
Speaker 1: it is something different.
Speaker 0: it is different.
Speaker 1: so an example.
Speaker 1: That's also not strictly handicapping.
Speaker 1: that I think is the best.
Speaker 1: I use this all the time in talks.
Speaker 1: I used to use this even in finance.
Speaker 1: dance.
Speaker 1: dance revolution has the simple idea that We can both play the exact same song.
Speaker 0: yeah different people choose different their own difficulty level.
Speaker 1: yep And it does two gratings.
Speaker 1: your letter grade is based on how well you did based on that difficulty.
Speaker 1: So we could both get.
Speaker 1: so I could do baby mode and get an A and Scott does maniac mode and also get an Egg because we both did really well Relative to what we expected right, but if you did maniac mode you get an a.
Speaker 0: your score number is gonna be Astronomical.
Speaker 1: keeps track of both.
Speaker 0: compare because you're you guys got your bed so many more notes to hit usually And you know more difficult in DDR.
Speaker 0: There's more arrows that yeah I've never seen a song where there's more a great where the greater difficulty had less steps.
Speaker 0: So there's more arrows which means you get a higher streak which means you can get more chain.
Speaker 0: You know perfects, which you know.
Speaker 0: it's more opportunities to get points.
Speaker 0: You're always gonna have a higher score and a higher difficulty in DDR.
Speaker 0: yep, and well again No, unless you miss all the arrow.
Speaker 1: not strictly handicapping by most of these definitions But it does serve the purpose of allowing two players a disparate skill to have a reasonably interesting Competition with each other.
Speaker 0: well DDR again is also a lot like golf and bowling where you're not competing Directly against the other person.
Speaker 0: you're not like interfering with their arrows like it's tennis or something right.
Speaker 0: you know if there's Tetris where you're You couldn't drop anything on anyone else, then that would be like golf and bowling, but because I said tennis before that was wrong.
Speaker 0: But DDR is like golf and bowling.
Speaker 0: it's individual It's you just dance and they just happen to be next to you, but you're not.
Speaker 0: you're not interacting in any way in the game.
Speaker 1: Well, let's just step on each other.
Speaker 0: It's just am I better at dancing the song that I was the last time I did so?
Speaker 1: what overwatch does Again, it's adjacent to all these things.
Speaker 1: It's it's also adjacent to matchmaking.
Speaker 1: if you make a custom game like you and a bunch of your friends well matchmaking is the reason I think a lot of people avoid handicapping.
Speaker 0: We just don't put people of disparate skill levels in the same game together.
Speaker 0: That's a good point.
Speaker 0: you can just matchmake instead of handicap.
Speaker 0: with online play the handicapping would only be necessary for local play.
Speaker 0: There's no place tournament play where you don't want it.
Speaker 1: one thing that handicapping would do better than matchmaking is handicapping would More routinely allow low skill players to interact with the strategies of high skill players.
Speaker 0: I think that a good thing that games could do if you have low player counts Even if you're if you're a a game that's not popular yet And you don't have enough people playing online to matchmake.
Speaker 0: well or be you just have an off hour of the day where your game Is medium popular and like you're not able to get enough people for your matchmaking system is to then incorporate be like okay?
Speaker 0: You know we don't have enough people playing right now or ever Right?
Speaker 0: then you put turn handicapping on to make the matchmake happen, and then if you've got enough players We don't need the handicap don't do it.
Speaker 1: If you make a custom game is it randomly assigns your teams.
Speaker 1: you can set them in advance.
Speaker 1: you play your match Whichever team won.
Speaker 1: the better players from that team based on the game's metric are swapped into the team that lost From and the worst players on that team are swapped into the team that won.
Speaker 1: and Every game you play with the same group of people it continuously rebalances.
Speaker 1: Just among those two teams.
Speaker 1: there were kind of strike mods that did that back in the day Yep, where you keep and they were awful because I figured out how to game them to get myself put on the good team.
Speaker 0: I remember what people would do is we'd be like Like you would play a match, and then you would like vote balance.
Speaker 0: They'd be like mods on the server Yeah, and everyone would be like yes.
Speaker 0: No yes.
Speaker 0: No yes, no.
Speaker 1: you notice All the people on the winning team would vote no and all the people on the losing team would vote yes And if there's a simple majority voting yes Then he would shuffle up the teams According to score.
Speaker 0: basically put the first place player the strongest player on team one the second strongest player on team two the third place Player on team one and just go back and forth with it to sort of split the teams in half that way According to your stats from the most recent game.
Speaker 1: so arguably some board games have a very very primitive form of handicapping Mm-hmm in the sense that usually in a board game.
Speaker 0: There's all.
Speaker 0: sometimes the youngest player goes first.
Speaker 1: That's what I get into in games.
Speaker 1: usually in a board game The player who goes first is either at an advantage or a disadvantage just by the nature of games Unless the games are perfectly somehow simultaneous symmetrical, but most games aren't like that.
Speaker 1: so typically Games will say something like the more experienced player goes first or whoever won the previous game Goes first.
Speaker 1: that is technically handicapping.
Speaker 1: It's just very limited in scale.
Speaker 1: I feel like board games could actually do a little bit more with that like a tiny like.
Speaker 1: imagine a board game that came with some easy mechanism if you play a game like teeny repeatedly with friends where Whichever one of your friend is one the most games and it even gave you a way to keep track of that Goes first or goes last or
Speaker 0: I mean too many games.
Speaker 0: I think have the baby modes right and I'm done with baby modes.
Speaker 0: I'm super anti baby mode because people play the baby mode right like a grecula comes like family mode, right?
Speaker 0: It's like you play a simpler version of the game or so I would do it with like a six-year-old right or in some cases not a simpler version of a game But a completely different game that happens to use the same pieces.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right or effectively a different game even though you may not realize it Because it looks similar and feels similar and then people play that and then they can never advance to the real game from that Right because they're just the baby game is nothing like the real game.
Speaker 1: Well, cuz it's a different game if you want to write semantics.
Speaker 0: So, uh, I think it'd be much better to just get people playing the real game and have a handicap.
Speaker 0: It's like okay fine, you know, you want to play a grecula, but you're a six-year-old you can play it.
Speaker 0: You can understand that.
Speaker 0: well, maybe not six.
Speaker 0: You're a ten-year-old.
Speaker 0: You can understand the rules.
Speaker 0: You can get the game going but you Are gonna lose to me guaranteed pretty much unless you're a genius or something.
Speaker 0: Let you start with like a pile of wheat.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: It's like I saw.
Speaker 1: I was watching a boy.
Speaker 0: You know what?
Speaker 0: You never have to feed your people.
Speaker 0: Otherwise, it's the same.
Speaker 1: I was watching a biking channel and it's a pretty good YouTube channel.
Speaker 1: I have linked to it a couple times before.
Speaker 1: but they got one of those cheating bikes that has the hidden motor Mm-hmm, and they wrote it to see what it was like.
Speaker 1: and they were like, wow, it's weird Yeah but they actually made a good point about a pretty good legitimate use for that.
Speaker 1: and the legitimate uses say you're a Serious biker and you have a more amateur biker friend.
Speaker 1: you could use that to have long-form races with friends while giving your friend a Mechanical advantage to keep it interesting like to let them have a chance of keeping up with you Right or I mean even without a race.
Speaker 0: It's like okay.
Speaker 0: I want to go and ride.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I want to ride.
Speaker 1: my friends are doing centuries and I can only go 70 miles, right?
Speaker 0: I want to ride a hundred miles.
Speaker 0: My friend can only ride like 40 because they're weak.
Speaker 0: we'll just give them a motorized bike and now the friend is gonna make the hundred and they can.
Speaker 0: we can all stay together and Get the enjoyment and see all the sites even though our physical fitness levels are different.
Speaker 0: It's not a competition at all.
Speaker 1: matchmaking says only play games with people of the same skill.
Speaker 1: Handicapping says you get to play that everyone plays the same game and we just change how we determine the winner.
Speaker 1: or And then rubber banding and all those other things are more like let's make sure the game is always close No matter how skilled or unskilled the players are.
Speaker 1: so there's a lot of different nuances.
Speaker 1: I think the moral of the show because I can smell food in there and I'm really hungry and I'm trying to wrap this up Is that
Speaker 0: All
Speaker 1: of these different kinds of ways to make disparate skill players have a fun time are tools in your chest
Speaker 0: And you should have your air hockey problem.
Speaker 0: Yep to solve the air hockey problem But I think the handicapping is the least used in the nerdy games the video games the tabletop games.
Speaker 0: You know the.
Speaker 0: the rubber banding has been used quite a bit especially in the board games Even though arguably rubber banding isn't rubber banding and good players will take advantage of it.
Speaker 0: The matchmaking has been used extensively in the board game department and the handicapping has been barely touched in any nerd gaming Department whatsoever and we need to bring that in and it ultimately you need to bring it in big-time.
Speaker 0: Definitely there is a such thing as too much.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but it's severely underused.
Speaker 1: right now The tricky part is again And this is what actually it's homework for all of you listening to geek nights because you You listen to our show for a lot of the like game design stuff.
Speaker 1: We talked about Pick a game you like and cut.
Speaker 1: try to come up with a way to handicap it because frankly it is really difficult Like really really difficult.
Speaker 1: I mean any except for solitaire games.
Speaker 0: I mean any any any board game where there's victory points.
Speaker 0: You can just start by the basic give someone victory point true Just like you start with ten points you go a cargo zone.
Speaker 0: We'll just give you.
Speaker 0: I can beat you by twenty here.
Speaker 0: You got twenty four.
Speaker 1: Here's one.
Speaker 1: How would we candy handicap advance wars so you and I could play with each other?
Speaker 0: you could just basically run through like turns of the game and Let me go like conquer a city while you sit there do nothing.
Speaker 1: Oh just like start you with extra biz.
Speaker 0: I think advance was actually does.
Speaker 0: let you start one person with more money.
Speaker 1: It actually does.
Speaker 0: it also start someone with more money.
Speaker 1: It also has a number of we never played.
Speaker 0: it also lets because it's asymmetrical.
Speaker 0: you can let someone have the strong OP character So actually could be Sturm and you could be like, you know, someone crappy.
Speaker 1: Ah, but so, you know, we should have done that.
Speaker 1: We never did.
Speaker 1: We always played on symmetric maps.
Speaker 1: We should have played on the maps that are.
Speaker 1: one player is like way strong.
Speaker 0: We played two versus one.
Speaker 1: We'd.
Speaker 1: I've tried, you know, I've done that.
Speaker 1: I did that before at RIT with not you because you wouldn't do it.
Speaker 1: I think was Greg and Scott.
Speaker 1: forget who I did it with but I won every time anyway.
Speaker 0: Well, I think those maps were designed in such a way that the one had more stuff to account for the fact that they were Yeah, and the three were small small three small ones versus one big one.
Speaker 1: Here's the big three small ones versus one small one, even if you find an easy way like, okay We'll move victory points.
Speaker 1: The hard part is how do you do it?
Speaker 1: Methodically to make the handicapped game fair and balanced right?
Speaker 0: I think there's a different skill.
Speaker 0: I think you just have to play the game a few times and See what the scores are and be like, okay My average score was this.
Speaker 0: your average score was that.
Speaker 0: so on average?
Speaker 0: I beat you by ten.
Speaker 0: So we're gonna give you ten points to start the nice game Right and we'll give you five because you lose.
Speaker 0: I keep I keep winning right, you know.
Speaker 0: Just see what everyone's average scores are.
Speaker 1: So if you want our real starting spot That's not your super perfect for if you want a real challenge This is something that if you if you solved this problem, you could probably make a lot of money.
Speaker 1: There is no good or effective handicapping system for tennis?
Speaker 1: No, not really and a lot of people have been trying to design one for a long time.
Speaker 0: It's hard.
Speaker 0: if you can if you can crack the tennis not I tried if you could I mean if I tried and failed I mean if you could do it then you could bet on tennis and win and get money at the casino yeah, but you could also like.
Speaker 1: This is a problem that if you can solve it you could probably make a career out of being the person who handicapped.
Speaker 0: I mean the fundamental problem is like, okay, so I play tennis against Federer.
Speaker 0: I'm what's my handicap?
Speaker 0: a thousand.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna get zero points.
Speaker 0: I'm not gonna even be able to hit return the ball.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so, how do you handicap that?
Speaker 0: Yep, take you can cut his arm off You break his knees You can give me a robot body.
Speaker 0: There's not really much you can do.
Speaker 0: he can he can go easy on me.
Speaker 0: It's like okay you put in a rule if he hits the ball harder than this You know, I hit the ball as hard as I can.
Speaker 0: if he if he hits the ball harder faster than that We have a speed gun there.
Speaker 0: Well, like he loses the point.
Speaker 0: He's gotta keep handicapping boxing like all right.
Speaker 1: I'm there and Mike Tyson punches me if I die Before.
Speaker 1: if I live until the ambulance shows up I win.
Speaker 1: Scott was dead before he hit the ground.
Speaker 1: rim died after he hit the ground.
Speaker 1: So we're him won the tournament between rim Scott and Mike Tyson.
Speaker 0: Well, it's you fight against one punch man If you can make it through half of the punch if the pinky hits you and you're alive and then you die in the ring finger.
Speaker 1: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott.
Speaker 1: special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening.
Speaker 1: music can't leave for web design and brand.
Speaker 0: Okay for the logos be sure to visit our website at front row.
Speaker 0: crew comm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 1: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays and make comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 0: But unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night and the patreon patrons for this episode of geek nights are Craig Oliver, Alan Joyce, Rebecca Dunn, Heidi Meade Nicola, Shimmering Ruby Obelisk, Hanging in the Sky, Kajar Tovish and MyStady.com.
Speaker 1: That's M Y S T A D Y dot-com, Jeremy Minor, Linky G, Jay Bans, Scootalonely, Roberto Kingsley, Kelly Snyder, Amanda Duchette, Sean Yeager, Matthew Smith, Nicholas Brandau, Mr.
Speaker 1: Strong Strachan, 421 Creations, Chris Reimer, and Tom Izzan, Shervin Von Horrell, Rory, James David White, Rochelle Montanona, Superboy, Tripwire, Sailor Vista, Don Schleich, Joe Shiro, Joe Starr, Clinton Walton, Run from New Zealand, Ryan Perrin, Drew Openlander, Finn, Chris Midgiff, Daniel Redmond, Sean Klein, Chris Reimer, and Tom Izzan.
Speaker 0: I'll crump with you, sweetie pie.