Speaker 0: It's Thursday, December 6th, 2018.
Speaker 0: I'm Rem.
Speaker 1: I'm Scott.
Speaker 0: And this is Geek Nights tonight.
Speaker 0: You guys love these fucking food shows, so we're talking about food we don't like.
Speaker 0: Cuz it's Thursday.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: And of course, I got a picture of Burger King up here because that's way below the line of food I will eat.
Speaker 0: So, uh, yeah.
Speaker 0: Ski season has started up.
Speaker 0: I might go skiing this weekend, my first ski trip of the year.
Speaker 1: Good luck with that.
Speaker 0: And the one cool thing is, you know, I live in New York, of course.
Speaker 1: Final episode of Geek Nights, everybody.
Speaker 0: And the deal with New York is that there is, in fact, pretty good skiing within a, like, a day trip of New York City.
Speaker 0: Not good skiing, not great skiing, but, like, pretty good skiing.
Speaker 1: There are mountains in New York State.
Speaker 1: It snows here.
Speaker 1: It's north enough to be cold and snowy during half the year.
Speaker 0: There are some mountains that are, like, a half hour away, but, like, there's literally no reason to go to them.
Speaker 0: Like, that'd be like going to a roller coaster park that has one roller coaster.
Speaker 0: Like, they're not.
Speaker 0: And, like, a crappy one at that.
Speaker 0: But you get up north, the nearest mountains that are worth going to, there's Hunter Mountain and there's Wyndham Mountain.
Speaker 0: I've gone to Wyndham Mountain twice in my life.
Speaker 0: That place is such a garbage, like, never go to Wyndham Mountain.
Speaker 0: What a piece of shit mountain.
Speaker 1: But... Is the actual mountain itself bad or just the company that owns the mountain is bad?
Speaker 0: So the mountain itself is okay.
Speaker 0: It's about equivalent size to Hunter Mountain.
Speaker 0: It just has way less lift capacity, so it has way longer lines.
Speaker 1: So what if you bought Wyndham Mountain and, like, upgraded it and made it fancy?
Speaker 0: Yeah, except all the...
Speaker 1: Like turning an old bowling alley into a disco night-night bowling alley.
Speaker 0: So that could be possible, but basically the deal is that the investors who invest in this sector seem to have focused on Hunter Mountain, and Hunter Mountain...
Speaker 1: Why are people investing in mountains?
Speaker 0: Ski resorts make a lot of money.
Speaker 1: How much money could they possibly make?
Speaker 0: Enough money to where Hunter Mountain...
Speaker 1: Only open part of the year.
Speaker 0: Well, actually, they do stuff in the summer, too.
Speaker 1: Well, they're always trying to do stuff out of season.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they do, like, music festivals.
Speaker 1: They're trying to do everything they can to make money from that real estate.
Speaker 0: Actually, when I saw Meatloaf, it was at Pine Knob, which was the ski mountain I learned to ski on as a kid in Michigan.
Speaker 1: I'm sure that's his most memorable performance.
Speaker 1: Hey, Meatloaf, remember that time you put a concert at Pine Knob?
Speaker 0: I'm pretty sure.
Speaker 0: what he would say is,
Speaker 0: "What?".
Speaker 0: Is he still alive?
Speaker 1: I haven't heard from him in a long time.
Speaker 0: I assume he is still performing.
Speaker 0: Let's see.
Speaker 0: Meat...
Speaker 1: I haven't heard from him in years.
Speaker 0: He's not dead.
Speaker 1: I haven't seen news that he's dead, so I assume that he's alive.
Speaker 1: But I have not heard anything about him.
Speaker 0: I would know if he was dead.
Speaker 1: Just go to his Wikipedia page.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'm going to his Wikipedia to see if he is active.
Speaker 0: Uh, year's active.
Speaker 0: He's still active.
Speaker 1: What is he doing?
Speaker 0: Concerts.
Speaker 0: Where?
Speaker 1: What was his last concert?
Speaker 0: I'm gonna find out right now.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna go to Google News.
Speaker 0: Let's see.
Speaker 1: What's his next concert?
Speaker 0: Meatloaf Concerts.
Speaker 0: Autobiography tour.
Speaker 0: Oh, that's Todd.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: Concerts.
Speaker 0: Won't sing on his new tour.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: Okay, this is an article from July of this year.
Speaker 1: That's recent enough.
Speaker 0: Yup.
Speaker 0: Uh, let's see.
Speaker 0: I think the tour he is doing or did recently, he is not singing.
Speaker 1: What's the point, then?
Speaker 0: Uh, yeah.
Speaker 0: Why indeed?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I will follow up.
Speaker 0: I will find out if it's still possible for me to see Meatloaf in concert one more time.
Speaker 1: Are you going to see Meatloaf play the piano?
Speaker 0: You see, he'll stand on stage.
Speaker 0: He'll just rev a motorcycle the entire time.
Speaker 0: But anyway, Hunter Mountain just built, like, a whole new side of the mountain.
Speaker 0: Like, they cut a bunch of new trails.
Speaker 1: They built a mountain.
Speaker 1: The elemental stone has pulled new rocks out of the ground.
Speaker 0: So, they basically, they cut new trails into the side of the mountain that they weren't using.
Speaker 0: And they made a whole bunch of, like, blue square trails, which in U.S.
Speaker 0: ski culture means intermediate trails.
Speaker 0: Meaning, the trails that normal people ski on.
Speaker 0: Which means, if I go to Hunter Mountain now, all the people who are only okay at skiing are going to be using this whole other side of the mountain with its own lift and they're going to be out of the bottom of the mountain I ski on.
Speaker 0: Meaning, I can ski a lot more because there's going to be way less lines to get to the hard part of the mountain.
Speaker 0: Meaning, it's going to be a real good time to ski there and I'm probably going to go there this weekend.
Speaker 0: And it's ski season and I'm really excited.
Speaker 0: So, if any of you want to ski with me at some point, I'll tweet when I'm going.
Speaker 1: Do not do this.
Speaker 1: Everyone who participates in any sporting event or activity with rim always gets injured every time.
Speaker 0: The rule is very specific.
Speaker 0: Anyone who ever rides a bike with me in Australia is definitely going to the hospital.
Speaker 1: I would not ski with rim either.
Speaker 1: You should not ski period, but definitely don't ski with rim.
Speaker 1: That's even worse.
Speaker 0: So, no one who has been skiing with me has ever had to go to the hospital.
Speaker 0: One person who was skiing with me busted their thumb up pretty bad once, but required aspirin and, like, a half hour to chill out and then was able to ski the rest of that day and the rest of the trip.
Speaker 1: No one who has ever stayed at home.
Speaker 0: That was our friend, Chris Reimer.
Speaker 1: No one who has ever stayed at home and played Smash Brothers this weekend has ever been out in the cold and the wet snow.
Speaker 0: I'll bet more people have died in the course of playing Smash Brothers than have hurt themselves doing a sports activity with me.
Speaker 1: That's because they were playing with someone with anger issues who punched them out after they cut their ass.
Speaker 0: Or they're just really bad at Smash Brothers.
Speaker 1: You know what to do this weekend, people.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: It's warm and toasty by the fire.
Speaker 0: So anyway, the biggest news, of course, is that Tumblr has banned pornography and has implemented an algorithm to identify this pornography, and the algorithm has basically identified literally fucking everything on Tumblr except Nazis and white supremacists.
Speaker 1: I've also heard that people are just going around and reporting everything, even things that aren't reporting literally every Tumblr post to sort of mess with the...
Speaker 0: Yes, which is brilliant and wonderful because the system they put in place to flag posts is terrible.
Speaker 0: This is actually pretty big news.
Speaker 0: Like, this is a big deal.
Speaker 0: Tumblr just basically destroyed itself because it's not, like, there's a lot of weird angles.
Speaker 0: One angle is, the main reason they're doing this is they got delisted from what, like, the Apple Store?
Speaker 0: They were in trouble because...
Speaker 1: No, the main reason they did it is... The deal is even the Apple Store ties into it, but the main reason they're doing this is because they want advertising money and advertisers will... The big advertisers will not buy ads on a site with porn where their ad could be next to porn.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: And secondary to that, there is a lot of child porn on Tumblr.
Speaker 1: There is a lot of stuff on porn that is not good.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: But the problem is, Tumblr never really put in any sort of system to in any way control the content on their platform.
Speaker 1: Nope.
Speaker 0: So, now they're in a weird situation where they want this sweet, sweet advertiser money, and the only way to do that is to basically remove porn from their system, but this is extra complicated by the fact that it's not just porn.
Speaker 0: It's basically the things that, like, bullshit basic advertisers would consider to be harmful to their own brands, which tends to include things like non-pornographic LGBT content, or basically anything interesting.
Speaker 0: Like, what is their rule?
Speaker 1: Anything sex-related in any way.
Speaker 0: Yes, but also things that are not in any way sex-related, like... What do they say specifically?
Speaker 0: Female-appearing nipples.
Speaker 1: No, female-presenting nipples.
Speaker 1: Yes, female-presenting nipples.
Speaker 1: If the person who the nipples belong to is a female-presenting person, regardless of their actual sex or gender or whatever, then those nipples are not okay.
Speaker 0: Yes, even if those nipples are not presented in a sexual context.
Speaker 1: So even if there was a trans man who was presenting as male, their nipples, which are genetically female nipples originally, right, those are okay?
Speaker 1: Because they're male-presenting nipples?
Speaker 0: As long as they're male-presenting.
Speaker 0: But here's the thing, the Tumblr should not be weighing in on that kind of thing, and also...
Speaker 1: I think I've talked about it in the show before, there's a great Instagram account that's literally just photos of individual nipples, and you have no idea the sex, gender, or anything of the person the nipple belongs to.
Speaker 0: That's good stuff, that account.
Speaker 1: It's very good.
Speaker 1: That nipple could belong to anybody.
Speaker 0: But the fact that, in particular, American society and the kinds of people that these basic advertisers want to target consider a female-appearing nipple to be sexually offensive, irrespective of whether or not it's presented in a sexual context, because they just assume that female nipples are sexual in all contexts.
Speaker 0: And also, they flagged and have a history of flagging just anything that's LGBT-related as being sexual.
Speaker 0: Which is clearly not true.
Speaker 0: So Tumblr is going to disappear as a platform.
Speaker 1: The main problem is simply the same thing that upsets me always, is that there is a wealth of important historical content and information that will be destroyed, presumably, and we cannot save all of it for... It's like a Library of Alexandria situation, just like when GeoCities went down.
Speaker 0: I saw the beacon go up, and Twitter was like, "What will happen to all these hilarious hentai
Speaker 0: gifs?".
Speaker 1: Exactly.
Speaker 1: There should actually be some sort of records preservation law.
Speaker 1: that's like, "Hey, if you start some service and collect a fuck-ton of important works, you are not allowed to do this.
Speaker 1: You must preserve
Speaker 1: them.".
Speaker 1: That might disincentivize people from creating things like Tumblr, because they will then be required to preserve those things for all time.
Speaker 0: Meanwhile, the Geek Nights forum...
Speaker 1: It will trap everyone who has already created a thing.
Speaker 0: Remember, the Geek Nights forum, the original one, is still on the internet.
Speaker 0: We are paying money to keep it up as long as we can.
Speaker 1: All of Geek Nights and all our forum and everything have been preserved.
Speaker 1: Even the IRC channel, which I don't think anyone uses, I had an automatic logging thing saving all the logs from it somewhere, which is why I'm sort of anti-Discord and whatnot, because I can't do that on Discord.
Speaker 1: I talked to Discord developers at PAX.
Speaker 1: They said, "No, you can't do
Speaker 1: that.".
Speaker 0: Yep, we actually talked to them at length about Discord.
Speaker 1: If they at that time, when I talked to them two or three years ago at PAX West, had said, "Yes, here is how to do that," we would be so Discord right now?
Speaker 0: So, the other issue that this brings up, because we can't cover this topic, this would be a whole show if we went deep into these problems with Tumblr, but one thing it brings up is the fundamental problem of the modern internet in that nobody has a monetization model that works.
Speaker 1: I do.
Speaker 1: You pay me fucking money.
Speaker 0: Yes, pay for a site.
Speaker 0: If Tumblr costs like a dollar a month, all these problems would have been solved.
Speaker 0: I would probably pay the dollar.
Speaker 1: That's not enough money for them, though.
Speaker 1: They're so greedy, they want more.
Speaker 0: So, here's the problem number two.
Speaker 0: A lot of services, in particular things like Twitter, could eminently run at a modest profit indefinitely with very small subscription fees.
Speaker 0: The problem is, those platforms exist originally, because people invested money in these platforms, and they expect massive returns.
Speaker 0: And the money that these platforms could make in a traditional, sustainable business model could never satisfy the terrifying greed of the people who invested in the first place.
Speaker 0: The other indictment that I have about this is that at no-- Who owns Tumblr now, Verizon?
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like Verizon.
Speaker 1: Didn't Verizon buy Yahoo or something?
Speaker 1: Right?
Speaker 1: I forget.
Speaker 0: So, white supremacist bullshit and Nazi stuff is not banned by this new policy.
Speaker 1: Nope.
Speaker 0: Because advertisers don't care that much about that.
Speaker 0: In fact, they probably would like their ads to be alongside that content, because that's the zeitgeist of America.
Speaker 0: So, the only benefit of this entire situation is that I think with the death of Tumblr, so too dies that particular Tumblr call-out culture, because those people will have nowhere else to go.
Speaker 0: There's no other platform that will let them have their fights about how the headcanon they made up for some particular Steven Universe character-- They could do it on Twitter.
Speaker 0: But those people don't tend to, and people ignore them on Twitter.
Speaker 0: Tumblr people will engage with them.
Speaker 0: I feel like that whole culture is going to disappear overnight, and nothing will be lost.
Speaker 1: There are some new sites, isn't there?
Speaker 1: Like a pillow something or something?
Speaker 0: Even Pornhub was like, "Yo, come to our platform.
Speaker 0: We will help you
Speaker 0: out.".
Speaker 1: Oh yeah, people don't know this.
Speaker 1: I knew this for a long time, and people were surprised by it.
Speaker 1: But the way Pornhub works is that you go there, you make an account, and you upload images, text, videos.
Speaker 1: You just upload porn of whatever medium it is.
Speaker 1: It might just be pictures of telephones, because that's your-- And then people find your porn and watch it.
Speaker 1: And you're supposed to have legal porn that you upload.
Speaker 1: You're either a porn company that has free samples of your legal porn with links to your actual pay site, or you're a person who makes porn at home, and you've got the right paperwork so that you don't get in trouble because you proved that it's not child porn, that sort of thing.
Speaker 1: You do some live streams of yourself, or your friends, or who knows.
Speaker 1: That's what it's supposed to be.
Speaker 1: But you can just make a Pornhub account.
Speaker 1: Even though your URL will be Pornhub, and the site will probably have porn ads on the side of it, you can just upload whatever the fuck you want.
Speaker 1: You can upload your webcomic on Pornhub.
Speaker 1: You can upload geek nights on Pornhub.
Speaker 1: You can livestream your video games on Pornhub.
Speaker 0: And more importantly, their business model is around sharing that revenue with the creators of that porn.
Speaker 1: Right, because they make a lot of money on Pornhub.
Speaker 1: They've got people signing up to pay for accounts, and they also have a lot of ads for the people who don't have accounts.
Speaker 1: You know, ads for porn, but there's still ads that pay money.
Speaker 1: They're not ads for Coca-Cola.
Speaker 1: And then they share that money with the people who make the content, just like YouTube does.
Speaker 0: The first basic company like Coca-Cola, who's like, "You know what?
Speaker 0: Just put my ads next to the porn.
Speaker 0: It's probably going to do really well in the long
Speaker 0: run.".
Speaker 1: I don't know why.
Speaker 1: They're so worried about doing this because of a very, very small, loud number of people.
Speaker 1: But it's like, okay, what's the family, whatever group?
Speaker 0: The Parents Television Council.
Speaker 1: So they find out that Coca-Cola is buying ads on porn on the internet, and they have a letter-writing campaign.
Speaker 1: It's like, "They're not going to stop drinking fucking
Speaker 1: Coca-Cola.".
Speaker 0: No, they're not.
Speaker 0: They're going to go to Pepsi because Pepsi's the brand that's anti-porn and pro-white supremacy.
Speaker 1: That's not how it works.
Speaker 1: They're still going to be drinking it, right?
Speaker 1: You're so worried about these letter-writing campaigns.
Speaker 1: Companies don't have the balls to just fucking ignore it when you know how many people it is.
Speaker 1: You know that it's just a manufactured thing.
Speaker 1: Why do they keep listening and obeying when a small number of people manage to organize?
Speaker 1: It's like you should understand the will of the quiet masses.
Speaker 1: Those are your market researches.
Speaker 1: You're paying all this money for market research, and you listen to a bunch of old ladies writing letters.
Speaker 1: Come on.
Speaker 0: But just this fundamental problem is that all these internet services rely on revenue streams that literally cannot work in the real world.
Speaker 0: We've solved this problem.
Speaker 0: We have not implemented any solutions to this problem, and it's only going to get worse.
Speaker 0: In some other news, I don't know how many of you are paying attention to what happened in France, but the barricades went up, and there were giant riots and fires and pitched battles and bullshit.
Speaker 1: Are you sure you're not reading a 200-year-old news article?
Speaker 0: I've been to Paris a couple of times, and all I want to say is that we don't think a lot about how Parisians interact with their government, but the barricades come up more often than you realize.
Speaker 0: Let's go read about the history of Paris, and you have this vision of Jean Valjean and all this nonsense.
Speaker 1: No, that's their go-to move.
Speaker 1: It's not a dramatization.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that still happens today, and this was another one of those.
Speaker 0: You can read these articles because, gig nights, we were not news.
Speaker 0: We were commentary.
Speaker 0: I hope you already know this was happening, and I'm not going to explain the details of who the yellow vests are, but the reason this news is interesting is that the way right-wing media is trying to spin this is that the common people of Paris rose up against this ridiculous environmental legislation because they have practical ideas about the economy.
Speaker 0: No.
Speaker 0: But that's not what happened.
Speaker 0: The problem is, these kinds of laws, like these fuel taxes, or like in New York City, like right now, once again, we can't afford to pay for our subway because of conservatives upstate, so we're forced to once again raise prices on MetroCards to pay for the subway.
Speaker 0: The problem is, if you tax the users of systems like the normal people, those people are the ones least equipped to pay, and you don't actually solve the problem.
Speaker 0: You're putting the cost of solving a global problem on your poorest citizens.
Speaker 1: You should tax the car people to pay for the train to disincentivize people from driving a car, and make them want to take a free train.
Speaker 0: You should tax the rich people to subsidize the train so the poor people who have cars will naturally migrate to the mass transit.
Speaker 0: You tax the people who are causing the problem, and the people who are causing the problem are always the companies and the rich people.
Speaker 0: Not even the people driving the cars.
Speaker 0: The people driving the cars are doing so because they are incentivized to do so by a massive system of subsidies paid for by the rich people who have a vested interest in keeping this going.
Speaker 0: Anyway, read this news article and internalize it, and if anyone tries to tell you that, well, two things.
Speaker 0: One, if anyone tries to tell you that these people were fighting against environmental regulation, they are lying to you and they probably read bad sites.
Speaker 0: And two, I feel like the US could learn from this, and I feel like if the left in the US would throw up the barricades a little more often, we might make some more progress in our government.
Speaker 1: The problem is that historically speaking, there are some countries, like France or South Korea, where protest has been effective.
Speaker 1: South Koreans, in the late 80s, they were still a military dictatorship and then they fixed it.
Speaker 0: Mostly.
Speaker 1: They vote now, right?
Speaker 1: But it's like they've been voting less long than I've been alive, but they got their vote by protesting.
Speaker 1: They had student protests and they actually were able to change their government with student protests.
Speaker 1: In France, they also have been able to change their government with more violent protests and revolutions.
Speaker 1: In the United States, protest, while it has been totally cool and happened many times, it has not been nearly as effective.
Speaker 0: Here's an example.
Speaker 0: Occupy Wall Street didn't have an endgame that was achievable and specific, nor did it actually cause enough problems for people to be forced to deal with it.
Speaker 0: The yellow vest thing got to fucking shut down Paris, so the government had to do something.
Speaker 0: Occupy Wall Street should have shut down Wall Street.
Speaker 1: There have rarely, very rarely, has the US government or even more local governments responded directly to protests.
Speaker 1: Usually, they quell the protests and then they continue with business as usual after things quiet down.
Speaker 0: So all I'm saying is, if you didn't really...
Speaker 1: That is why we don't have a culture of protesting more, because when it works, then people keep doing it.
Speaker 1: In places around the world where it works, people do it and it keeps working and they have a culture of doing it.
Speaker 1: In the United States, we keep trying it and it's not as effective, therefore we don't do it more.
Speaker 0: So all I'm saying is, don't just remember, "Oh yeah, something happened in
Speaker 0: Paris.".
Speaker 0: Actually read a news article about this and think about what is different in that situation from what's going on here, and make decisions accordingly.
Speaker 0: These protests are a big deal and a lot of people are trying to spin them in ways that are not accurate to the real situation.
Speaker 0: Last and not least, my favorite people, the Satanic Church, are with the Satanic Temple.
Speaker 0: There's a bunch of different Satanists.
Speaker 1: The best of all temples.
Speaker 0: The Satanic Temple is a pretty cool organization.
Speaker 0: Seriously.
Speaker 1: There's a lot of different kinds of Satanists, but these are the good ones.
Speaker 0: Yes, but they've been winning a lot of fights lately around putting up their satanic... Basically, satanic nativity scenes.
Speaker 1: Listen, if you're going to invest in that badass fucking statue of Baphomet or whatever, you better get some fucking use out of it and they sure as hell are, or you're not just going to keep that shit in a garage somewhere.
Speaker 1: You've got to let the world see it.
Speaker 1: Let us behold its glory.
Speaker 0: The Satanic Temple is an example of very effective forms of protest because they're actually... It's working, because here's what they do.
Speaker 0: Someone puts up a Christian religious thing somewhere in a public space.
Speaker 1: Like usually a manger.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like a manger in a town square.
Speaker 0: Or the baby Jesus.
Speaker 0: No, I'm an atheist, but that's fine.
Speaker 0: I don't care.
Speaker 0: I'm happy that people can express their religion in a public space, but any religion has to be able to do that, but in most places, only Christians end up doing it.
Speaker 0: So the Satanic Temple will show up and say, "We want to put Satan there next to the baby
Speaker 0: Jesus.".
Speaker 1: That's right.
Speaker 1: "I want to put my menorah next to the baby
Speaker 1: Jesus.".
Speaker 0: It's very difficult for them to lose any lawsuit around this because of the First Amendment.
Speaker 0: So as a result, the places that only have Christian stuff have basically two options.
Speaker 0: They either have to let the Satanists put up their thing, or they have to let nobody put up anything religious.
Speaker 1: Those are the only two legal options.
Speaker 1: This is like, you know, unless you get some crazy Christian judge somewhere, but then you just appeal to the next judge.
Speaker 0: Even a ruined Supreme Court has a hard time shutting this down.
Speaker 1: They're like, "No, the Supreme Court won't even hear that
Speaker 1: case.".
Speaker 1: They'll be like, "Yeah, unless for some reason there's a crazy judge in the second-to-last appellate court or whatever that messed it up and was a crazy
Speaker 1: Christian.".
Speaker 0: So basically, either all the religion in public spaces gets removed, or religious freedom actually happens, and any religion gets to show up.
Speaker 0: Those are both wins.
Speaker 1: Either one works.
Speaker 1: Yeah, either no more mangers.
Speaker 1: Sorry, you Christian people who are so mad about it, but you're all mad now.
Speaker 1: You can have your manger.
Speaker 1: We can laugh at you being mad.
Speaker 1: Or we get to put our badass Satan right there in the town square.
Speaker 0: So to tie this into the previous news, activism, where either outcome in court gets the actual goal to move forward, is the best kind of activism.
Speaker 0: The Satanic Temple isn't just funny and clever.
Speaker 0: It is very effective in the area in which it is working.
Speaker 1: What I'm saying is that in the United States, going in the street and yelling has not been as effective as it has been in other places.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but meanwhile, putting up statues of Baphomet has been pretty effective in the narrow realm.
Speaker 1: Are there any other countries where people put up statues of Baphomet?
Speaker 1: No, because we're the only one with freedom of speech in our Constitution.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we're also the only one...
Speaker 1: Not the absolute only one, but we're the only people who have it.
Speaker 1: so...
Speaker 0: Well, also we have a particular issue with Christian hegemony and there's a whole other thing that we don't have time to talk about because it's time for... Things of the Day!
Speaker 0: So you know when you see a picture of an old-timey boxer, they're always holding their hands up in this ridiculous position.
Speaker 1: Yeah, one fist forward with the other one behind it.
Speaker 0: Yep, and their fists are up and they're like, "Fists of
Speaker 0: cuffs!"
Speaker 0: and "They've got a handlebar
Speaker 0: mustache!"
Speaker 0: and that kind of thing.
Speaker 0: So here's a ten minute long video... Too long.
Speaker 1: Just explain it to me in two sentences.
Speaker 0: It's actually complicated enough that it warrants a ten minute video.
Speaker 0: It is way more complicated than I thought as to why they did it that way.
Speaker 1: I'll make a saved you a click for it.
Speaker 0: So the best way I can describe it is that this was the fighting stance during that era of boxing, but the reason that was effective is that Nobody wore gloves.
Speaker 0: So while you could technically punch someone as hard as you could in the face, you would probably break your hand permanently in the course of doing so.
Speaker 0: So as a result, boxers wouldn't do it because they would win the fight and lose the career.
Speaker 0: Like, they'd be over.
Speaker 0: They'd ruin their hand.
Speaker 0: So if they hit someone in the head, they couldn't hit them as hard as they could punch.
Speaker 0: So head hits weren't actually that effective.
Speaker 1: You could punch them straight in the front of the face.
Speaker 0: Even then, that's tough.
Speaker 0: Two, the style of fighting back then also allowed grappling.
Speaker 0: So if you just tucked in like this, the other guy could get way closer to you than you were comfortable with and potentially grab you.
Speaker 0: So you had to have the one hand out to keep them at bay with little jabs and protect yourself and counter punch, and the one hand back.
Speaker 0: So if they come in and you get in the right situation, you can do a full punch to the gut and that other hand otherwise is protecting the gut.
Speaker 0: But there's actually more to this story than just that.
Speaker 0: This video is worth watching.
Speaker 0: So anyway, now if you watch the video, you will know why boxers stand like this.
Speaker 0: And also, I just really like the aesthetic of people standing like this.
Speaker 0: I think it's hilarious.
Speaker 0: So what do you got?
Speaker 1: So here's some people, and in their bathroom, they've got a rat in the bathroom.
Speaker 1: And they want to get the rat out of the house.
Speaker 0: But they don't want to kill the rat.
Speaker 1: It seems like they don't want to use any of the methods I'm already aware of, not even the humane ones, such as the trap or the bowl full of oil or any of these other things.
Speaker 0: They don't want to hurt the rat.
Speaker 0: They just want the rat to be out of their apartment.
Speaker 1: They came up with a new way to get rid of the rat.
Speaker 1: And what's most interesting about this video is not only is it a great video of how they get the rat out of the bathroom and out of the house, it was posted in Sports Reddit appropriately.
Speaker 1: Don't worry, the rat is not harmed other than being thrown out of his nice bathroom home and onto the outside.
Speaker 0: Yep, he bounces down the stairs a little bit, but he's clearly fine and just angry at the bottom.
Speaker 1: The rat, I mean, if you're just a little rat, you're fine going down the stairs.
Speaker 1: You're not a Scot falling down the stairs.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if a river or a Scot fell down those stairs, we would be dead.
Speaker 1: Yeah, a rat can go down those stairs no problem.
Speaker 0: The rat's just like, "Son of a
Speaker 0: bitch.".
Speaker 1: He's just like, "Ah, I want to go back to the bathroom.
Speaker 1: I was happy in
Speaker 1: there.".
Speaker 0: This is a gift that is, in effect, a team sport.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: In the Metamoment, the Keaton House Book Club book, which we've been busy but will read soon, is 2001 A Space Odyssey, following out from Emily Wilson's translation of A Hameric Odyssey.
Speaker 0: Otherwise, we were just at the Penny Arcade Expo, PAX Unplugged.
Speaker 1: The unplugged version where it was no video games allowed.
Speaker 0: Where we did not one.
Speaker 1: Except for the illicit board games on SNES in the classic cardboard room.
Speaker 1: Don't tell anyone.
Speaker 0: I saw people playing there, like all PAX.
Speaker 0: That looked real fun.
Speaker 1: Why not?
Speaker 1: We played Wheel of Fortune and Family Feud a lot.
Speaker 0: I feel like we should stream some Family Feud maybe over the holidays.
Speaker 1: Let's do it.
Speaker 0: I'll set that up.
Speaker 0: Anyway.
Speaker 1: Are you working between Christmas and New Year's?
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: I've earned all my fucking vacation days.
Speaker 1: I have nothing.
Speaker 1: I have had two jobs in a row where everyone gets off between Christmas and New Year, and RIM has had zero jobs.
Speaker 0: Dude, when they announced that Wednesday was going to be a holiday because of George H.W.
Speaker 0: Bush's death and funeral and everything, I got an email within an hour that basically said, "Yeah, wall markets are closed.
Speaker 0: We are not.
Speaker 0: Everyone still has to come to
Speaker 0: work.".
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 0: So I had to go to work.
Speaker 1: What if you're a trader, though?
Speaker 0: That's a different company, technically.
Speaker 1: I know, but I'm saying.
Speaker 0: I ain't a trader.
Speaker 1: There's nothing to do.
Speaker 0: You might be trading all the other markets that aren't in the US.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but even when the market's closed, on Labor Day, people don't go to work.
Speaker 0: Some people do.
Speaker 0: International trader.
Speaker 0: Anyway.
Speaker 0: So we did three hours of panels at this PAX, and one of them is already on the internet because PAX was kind enough to put that panel in the biggest panel room.
Speaker 0: that was live streamed.
Speaker 1: That was not main events.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: So we were live streamed on PAX2, and the VOD for that is on Twitch.
Speaker 1: Twitch.tv/Pax2.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: The VOD of that is just on the internet.
Speaker 0: You can just go watch it.
Speaker 1: That's P-A-X, the number two, not P-A-X-T-W-O.
Speaker 0: There is a link to it on our website.
Speaker 0: By the way, we have a website.
Speaker 0: You can go to it, and there's stuff there, including our awesome forum, which you should join, because the United's forum is notable in these trying times in that it is 100% Nazi free.
Speaker 0: It is against our terms of service to be a Nazi dipshit in our forums.
Speaker 1: And the way we do this is very simple.
Speaker 1: Because our forum is not enormous, with hundreds and hundreds of people applying, we manually approve or reject every single person who wants to make an account.
Speaker 0: Meaning you have to type a sentence.
Speaker 1: Type text.
Speaker 1: Which means if we ban someone, they cannot get back in.
Speaker 1: So if there's a Nazi, we can just delete their post and kick them out at the end.
Speaker 1: And if there's a non-Nazi, well, you know, it's like, hey, you're in.
Speaker 1: Good job.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: It's a pretty good forum.
Speaker 0: You should join it.
Speaker 0: There's a lot of stuff going on in there.
Speaker 0: So we will be at the next PAX after MAGFest, where we're doing a bunch of panels.
Speaker 0: Stay tuned for that announcement.
Speaker 1: MAGFest is New Year's, and then there's a MAGFest, and then PAX South is what, two weeks after that?
Speaker 0: Yeah, and then PAX East is right around the corner after that.
Speaker 1: Let me check my calendar.
Speaker 0: They're so close together.
Speaker 0: I got a lot of panels to write in the next few weeks.
Speaker 0: But at PAX South, we were doing at least one panel, and that panel is a brand new one, never before done anywhere.
Speaker 0: Nostalgia versus game design.
Speaker 0: I'm starting to write it.
Speaker 0: I'm feeling pretty good about it.
Speaker 0: This is going to be a fun panel.
Speaker 0: This is going to be a lot like the panels we ran around PAX West, PAX East, circa 2010, 2011.
Speaker 0: It's like classic Geek Nights style.
Speaker 0: I'm feeling this panel pretty big.
Speaker 0: Beyond that, expect some live streams, expect some stuff going on.
Speaker 0: Stay tuned for on the Geek Nights Patreon.
Speaker 0: Me and Emily are going to be doing a parallel podcast where we're going to review and comment on every single Disney animated feature in chronological order.
Speaker 0: From beginning to now.
Speaker 1: When's the last time you saw Snow White?
Speaker 0: That's it.
Speaker 0: We're going to watch them all again.
Speaker 0: What we're going to do is we're going to record us recalling what we remember about them, which some of these will be funny because I haven't seen them since my age was in the single digits, and then we're going to watch them.
Speaker 1: Have you even seen all these?
Speaker 1: Have you seen Sleeping Beauty?
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Ever?
Speaker 0: When I was a little kid.
Speaker 1: There's got to be some you haven't seen.
Speaker 0: Some recent ones, probably.
Speaker 0: I never saw Pocahontas.
Speaker 1: Me either.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I just never saw it.
Speaker 0: I don't need to.
Speaker 0: I think I was in middle school when it came out.
Speaker 1: It's going to keep it that way.
Speaker 0: I think it was in sixth grade, I want to say.
Speaker 0: We've even played the music from it in the middle school band, but I had never seen it.
Speaker 0: That was the first time I had to play a mellophone.
Speaker 0: Also, fuck mellophones.
Speaker 0: It's like a harder trumpet.
Speaker 0: They're just not fun to play and they don't sound that good.
Speaker 0: So, yeah.
Speaker 0: Otherwise, food we hate.
Speaker 0: I don't know why you guys love these food shows so much, but I was looking for a show to do tonight, and I haven't yet set up the call-in show, which we will be setting up.
Speaker 0: We'll be doing those starting next year.
Speaker 0: Stay tuned.
Speaker 0: But we do a lot of food shows, and there's a lot of food that I hate is a strong word, but there's food that we both will eat but do not like, and there is food that both of us will not eat.
Speaker 0: So I'm curious.
Speaker 0: What's the line, Scott?
Speaker 0: What is the worst food bar?
Speaker 0: Now, again, we're not counting about starvation situation.
Speaker 0: Let's assume that we are not starving to death, that we have access to food.
Speaker 1: It sounds like one of those scenarios from a Japanese adventure game.
Speaker 0: There are nine doors.
Speaker 0: There are nine fast food restaurants, and you will die in 48 hours.
Speaker 1: What puzzle do I have to solve to get the good food?
Speaker 1: Do I have to play the game twice to get the really good food?
Speaker 1: Unlock the secret ending food?
Speaker 0: You've got to eat the Arby's on a Tuesday, or it doesn't unlock the best ending.
Speaker 0: So we're assuming that we are not starving to death, and that within 24 hours of whatever situation we're talking about, we can access better food.
Speaker 0: So I'm curious, Scott.
Speaker 0: What is the worst food you would eat?
Speaker 1: Lowest quality food?
Speaker 0: Yeah, lowest quality or worst type of food?
Speaker 1: I mean, it just has to be...
Speaker 0: Because they're two different things, I think.
Speaker 1: I mean, I'm not starving, so it means I can go without food.
Speaker 0: But it's either you eat this food for dinner, or your next meal is breakfast.
Speaker 1: So I'm still hungry.
Speaker 0: You're hungry, but you're not dying.
Speaker 0: You've got to skip dinner or eat this food.
Speaker 0: What is the worst kind of food you will eat, in terms of preference?
Speaker 0: Like food you don't like.
Speaker 1: Something I don't want to eat, but I'll eat it anyway?
Speaker 0: You don't want to eat it.
Speaker 0: You don't like it.
Speaker 0: You'll eat it anyway, rather than skip dinner.
Speaker 0: I think that's an interesting line to explore.
Speaker 1: I guess I won't eat a McDonald's.
Speaker 0: I would skip dinner before I'd eat McDonald's.
Speaker 0: I'd definitely skip dinner before I'd eat Burger King.
Speaker 1: I wouldn't eat a Burger King either.
Speaker 0: I would never eat a Burger King.
Speaker 1: Well, I guess I might just eat a fry from McDonald's.
Speaker 0: What do you eat?
Speaker 0: a fry from Burger King?
Speaker 1: It's a fry.
Speaker 0: Have you had a Burger King fry in your life?
Speaker 1: I mean, it's a very small amount of potato and hot oil.
Speaker 1: It's not really any different than getting a fry from any other, you know.
Speaker 1: Other places might have more potato or better oil.
Speaker 0: So I would not eat a McDonald's dinner, like a burger, or anything they make.
Speaker 1: Absolutely not.
Speaker 0: But I would eat a McDonald's breakfast, or even a McDonald's hash brown, in that situation, rather than skip dinner.
Speaker 0: But I would not eat a McDonald's hamburger under any circumstances.
Speaker 1: McDonald's has an apple you can get.
Speaker 0: So an apple, you'd eat an apple instead of dinner?
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's an apple.
Speaker 0: I think that's fine.
Speaker 1: I would not eat an apple.
Speaker 0: So what's the bottom?
Speaker 0: Because an apple's not that bad.
Speaker 0: You like apples.
Speaker 1: I do like apples.
Speaker 0: What's the worst food you would eat instead of skipping dinner?
Speaker 0: What's the bottom?
Speaker 1: I won't eat a can of tuna fish.
Speaker 1: That's gross.
Speaker 0: Oh, no.
Speaker 0: No, no, no.
Speaker 0: Of course, you saw that millennials are killing canned tuna.
Speaker 0: No one will eat that bland, garbage canned tuna.
Speaker 1: It smells awful.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: It's funny.
Speaker 0: The article was literally like, "Millennials won't eat tuna
Speaker 0: anymore.".
Speaker 0: But then the details were, "Millennials want to buy actual tuna and shred it themselves, fresh, rather than buy garbage canned
Speaker 0: tuna.".
Speaker 1: Yeah, well, it's too much money and it's not good for fishes.
Speaker 0: Yup, it's also not good.
Speaker 1: I guess I would eat some fish that wasn't too fishy.
Speaker 0: So what's too fishy?
Speaker 0: What's your line?
Speaker 1: Well, because you get fish.
Speaker 1: You buy fish sticks, right?
Speaker 1: Fish sticks are too fishy.
Speaker 1: You buy it from the grocery store, like frozen fish sticks.
Speaker 0: I would eat frozen fish sticks.
Speaker 1: They smell way fishy and gross.
Speaker 0: See, I like fishy fish.
Speaker 1: I don't like fishy fish.
Speaker 0: I like a really fishy fish.
Speaker 1: No, no, no.
Speaker 1: If it's too ocean-y, you know, it's like that doesn't taste good.
Speaker 0: I like that kind.
Speaker 0: I'll just eat anchovies straight up.
Speaker 1: I mean, I like anchovy, but those aren't too fishy.
Speaker 1: They're salty and it's a different flavor than anchovy.
Speaker 0: They're pretty fishy, too.
Speaker 0: You usually don't eat a lot of anchovy.
Speaker 1: There's this smell you get when you go to a low-quality seafood restaurant.
Speaker 0: Oh, but I love that fishy fish.
Speaker 1: You buy a crappy piece of fish that is low-quality or frozen.
Speaker 1: It's just like plain, boring, white fish of some kind.
Speaker 1: It smells way fishy, like it's got ocean all over it.
Speaker 1: I don't like that.
Speaker 1: But if you just take the fish and you just decrease that fishy level to the point at which I can eat it without being like, "Ew," even though I might be like, "Eh," right?
Speaker 1: And that, I guess, is the food that I like the least because you can just adjust that level of fishiness to the point at which I will eat it to not go hungry rather than be hungry, but I'm still not happy.
Speaker 1: I would rather eat something else.
Speaker 0: I think my line is not the Arby's roast beef sandwich because I will never eat one of those again in my life.
Speaker 1: See, the thing is, I love Arby's, but at Arby's, I do not eat roast beef at all.
Speaker 1: Ew.
Speaker 1: I would not eat -- I used to.
Speaker 0: I used to every day.
Speaker 0: Remember, kids, when we were young -- I would eat McDonald's before I ate the roast beef at Arby's.
Speaker 0: When I was in high school, like sophomore year, I would drive.
Speaker 0: I'd just walk out of the school around lunchtime, drive to the mall, go to the Arby's in the mall, and eat like a roast beef sandwich and some curly fries and a Jamoca shake.
Speaker 0: And that was my lunch.
Speaker 1: At Arby's, the thing is, I would go right now to an Arby's to eat -- The chicken fingers.
Speaker 1: The chicken fingers and, of course, the curly fry.
Speaker 1: Curly fries.
Speaker 1: Because while that curly fry isn't, say, really any different than McDonald's fry, it does have, A, a little bit more potato.
Speaker 0: Two, it's got flavor powder, which you seem to hate in other contexts.
Speaker 1: B, a curly shape, and C, a flavor that is not just oil and salt.
Speaker 0: I think the line for me, in terms of quality and type combined, is I would order Arby's chicken fingers and curly fries.
Speaker 0: I would eat that rather than go hungry.
Speaker 1: Even though those fried chicken fingers have a very small amount of chicken.
Speaker 1: They're way better than a chicken McNugget.
Speaker 0: Way better.
Speaker 0: But anything -- I would not eat a fast food worse than that for dinner.
Speaker 0: But I consider a White Castle burger to be better than that.
Speaker 1: I would not eat almost anything at White Castle.
Speaker 0: I'd eat a White Castle burger right now.
Speaker 0: No.
Speaker 0: Like, I would just eat that on purpose.
Speaker 0: In a non-dire situation, I would eat a White Castle.
Speaker 0: No.
Speaker 0: The only reason I don't, honestly, is that all the White Castles in New York are disgusting.
Speaker 1: The one near me went out of business, and so there was a regional office also here.
Speaker 1: It also went closed.
Speaker 1: The last time I ate at a White Castle -- There's a cool building over there that still has a castle on the corner of it.
Speaker 0: I went to one in the Bronx.
Speaker 1: It used to be the regional office.
Speaker 0: I went to one -- I worked at the hospital.
Speaker 0: I went to one in the Bronx that was kind of near one of my offices.
Speaker 0: And, like, the interior of it, one, had, like, bulletproof glass and a metal detector and a cop.
Speaker 0: And then inside of it, it was filthy.
Speaker 0: And I ate there once, and I vowed to never eat there again because the environment was too disgusting.
Speaker 0: But otherwise, I like the sensation of eating a White Castle burger.
Speaker 0: But I would not eat a McDonald's burger under any circumstances.
Speaker 0: I would definitely go hungry.
Speaker 1: Well, some people in our chat have mentioned Taco Bell, a place that I will never eat.
Speaker 1: Taco Bell is okay, though.
Speaker 1: I will not eat it.
Speaker 0: Taco Bell is just a low-quality but perfectly serviceable taco that arguably probably doesn't have much meat in it, if any meat.
Speaker 1: I will not eat a Taco Bell.
Speaker 0: I would eat a Taco Bell.
Speaker 0: I would not.
Speaker 0: Why not?
Speaker 1: Taco Bell's fine.
Speaker 1: I mean, there are places I would eat -- I would rather sooner eat Taco Bell than White Castle, but that doesn't mean I will eat Taco Bell.
Speaker 0: Taco Bell is higher-quality food stuff than White Castle.
Speaker 0: The ingredients are fine.
Speaker 1: But I still won't eat there.
Speaker 1: It's still below the line.
Speaker 2: I'd say it's above the line.
Speaker 0: I would eat at a Taco Bell.
Speaker 1: It's just closer to the line than White Castle is.
Speaker 0: I'd eat at a Taco Bell before I'd go hungry, but I would not eat at most.
Speaker 0: gennaro delis in midtown Manhattan.
Speaker 1: Depends on what I get at the gennaro deli.
Speaker 0: The one by Grand Central?
Speaker 1: I don't know which one.
Speaker 1: The big one?
Speaker 0: On 41st Street?
Speaker 0: We've walked past this place many times in our lives.
Speaker 1: There's a lot of gennaro delis.
Speaker 0: But every time we've walked past this one, you've always pointed it out and said we should never eat there.
Speaker 1: Maybe.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 0: You don't remember this?
Speaker 0: No.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: It's called the stage doors.
Speaker 0: It's on 41st and Pershing Square.
Speaker 0: I feel like the next time we walk by, I'm going to point it out.
Speaker 0: I would not eat there under any circumstances.
Speaker 0: I've also seen it closed down by the health department multiple times.
Speaker 1: I won't eat at a place that I know has issues.
Speaker 1: In New York City, it's a lot easier to know when places have issues because they have a grading system going on.
Speaker 1: Some places don't have that.
Speaker 0: Here's a question.
Speaker 0: What is the worst food you've ever eaten on purpose?
Speaker 1: What do you mean?
Speaker 1: Unhealthiest?
Speaker 0: Whatever you mean by worst.
Speaker 0: The worst food you've eaten on purpose in your whole life or in your adult life?
Speaker 1: There have been a couple times.
Speaker 0: Because as a kid, I would eat Cheetos.
Speaker 0: I like Cheetos and Doritos.
Speaker 1: There have been times where we deep fried various things and ate them.
Speaker 1: There are also times, I think at least a couple times in my youth where you've played that game where you combine a bunch of beverages into some concoction and dare people to drink it and someone sips it and it's whatever.
Speaker 0: I only ever played that game in the context of watching other people do it.
Speaker 0: I was never dumb enough to do it myself.
Speaker 1: I don't remember really the details.
Speaker 1: I just remember it being a thing.
Speaker 1: Because I have specific memories.
Speaker 0: The worst food I ever put in my mouth on purpose was that off-brand big boy on the New York State Thruway on that terrible trip we took to Rochester that one time.
Speaker 0: To this day, that meal stands out as the worst food I've ever put in my mouth on purpose in my entire life.
Speaker 0: It was not good.
Speaker 0: It filled my stomach, but it did not sate me.
Speaker 0: It's like in Chrono Trigger, but you're still hungry.
Speaker 0: I just felt worse.
Speaker 1: I mean, I have eaten at McDonald's, Burger King, and such in the past, just the very, very deep past.
Speaker 0: When was the last time?
Speaker 0: Because I ate a McDonald's breakfast occasionally when I ski.
Speaker 0: The last time I ate a McDonald's burger?
Speaker 1: The last time I ate a McDonald's...
Speaker 0: I think was before the year 2000.
Speaker 1: Maybe...
Speaker 0: It was definitely high school.
Speaker 1: So in the year 2000, I ate ice cream from a McDonald's in Israel.
Speaker 1: And in my seventh grade, I ate...
Speaker 0: Nando's chicken is perfectly fine.
Speaker 1: Why would you not eat at Nando's?
Speaker 0: I would eat Nando's chicken before I would eat at any other fast food restaurant on earth.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I would give up Chipotle before I give up Nando's.
Speaker 0: I avoid Chipotle.
Speaker 1: I go to Chipotle.
Speaker 0: When I go to Chipotle, I never get meat.
Speaker 0: I only get the sofritas.
Speaker 1: I like sofritas.
Speaker 1: I get them the most, but I also get other things, like the limited-time chorizo.
Speaker 1: They're trying to make it the big rib of Chipotle, the big rib of Chipotle.
Speaker 1: It's a good strategy.
Speaker 1: But it's not McRib.
Speaker 1: Which I would not eat.
Speaker 0: The worst thing I ever put in my mouth ever, though, on purpose was... I like energy drinks, but remember when there was that cocaine energy drink?
Speaker 1: Oh, right, you tried that.
Speaker 1: Didn't you try the Four Loko also?
Speaker 0: Four Loko didn't actually taste bad.
Speaker 0: It's just bad for you.
Speaker 1: You tasted it, though.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it tasted fine.
Speaker 0: You know what it tasted like?
Speaker 0: It tasted like a bad 40 mixed with a Red Bull.
Speaker 1: Oh, one time, I was drinking some apple juice.
Speaker 1: It was just grocery store brand apple juice.
Speaker 1: But I didn't notice until I sipped it that it had something growing in there.
Speaker 1: Ooh, ooh.
Speaker 1: There was some sort of solid, floaty, cloudy mass in the cup at the bottom.
Speaker 1: But also, it tasted like poison.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so I like Red Bull.
Speaker 0: I like energy drinks.
Speaker 1: I didn't drink much of it.
Speaker 1: I just was like bleh.
Speaker 0: So I bought that cocaine energy drink because I was like, "Okay, it's just like another energy drink.
Speaker 0: I will try
Speaker 0: it.".
Speaker 0: And when I opened the can, I could smell it a little bit.
Speaker 0: And part of my brain said, "This is
Speaker 0: poison.".
Speaker 0: I suppressed that little part of my brain.
Speaker 0: I took one sip.
Speaker 0: It tasted the worst... It was the worst taste I have ever experienced in my entire life.
Speaker 0: That big boy meal tasted like sadness.
Speaker 0: This tasted like death.
Speaker 0: I literally spit it out and I threw it away.
Speaker 0: And I never looked back.
Speaker 1: One time in a dim sum, was it Mike Lynn?
Speaker 1: He was like, "Hey, hey, hey.
Speaker 1: I'll try to get these white people to eat weird foods at the dim
Speaker 1: sum.".
Speaker 0: That didn't work on us.
Speaker 0: I'd bite each one and be like, "I don't like this, but
Speaker 0: okay.".
Speaker 0: So he got pig's ear.
Speaker 0: Pig's ear's okay.
Speaker 0: I like to nibble on a pig's ear.
Speaker 1: So I nibbled on the pig's ear and it tasted like pork, which is fine.
Speaker 1: It tasted just fine.
Speaker 1: The problem is it was so fucking chewy, I could not chew it to a point at which I could swallow it.
Speaker 0: That's the same problem I had with tripe.
Speaker 0: I do not like tripe.
Speaker 0: I will not eat tripe.
Speaker 1: Then I had a tasteless mass of cartilage in my mouth.
Speaker 1: Then I spit it out after I had extracted all of the pork flavor.
Speaker 1: Tripe tastes good, but it's basically just...
Speaker 0: It's like meat gum.
Speaker 0: If I could treat it like gum but spit it out, I'd probably eat more tripe.
Speaker 1: That also happens to me sometimes with very poorly cooked steaks.
Speaker 1: I'll chew them.
Speaker 0: Then you get that little meat gum remainder.
Speaker 1: I get some part of it, or maybe the whole thing if it's real bad, where I cannot chew it sufficiently to the point where I can swallow it.
Speaker 0: You spit it into a napkin and bite it.
Speaker 1: All of the meat flavor has been extracted.
Speaker 1: Then I spit out this gray mass into a napkin.
Speaker 0: Yup, I've done the gray mass into the napkin before.
Speaker 1: It's like, "Well, this isn't a good
Speaker 1: steak.".
Speaker 0: You know where I would commonly do that?
Speaker 0: With about 10% of a steak on French bread.
Speaker 1: Actually, I never had that problem with steak on French bread.
Speaker 0: Usually not.
Speaker 0: There'd always be a little bit, but sometimes I just swallow it.
Speaker 0: It was near the line.
Speaker 0: That steak on French bread was probably the best value per dollar of food we had in our entire lives.
Speaker 0: This chat's got a lot of opinions.
Speaker 1: People like food shows for some reason.
Speaker 0: I don't understand anti-nando sentiment.
Speaker 0: Nando's is pretty good.
Speaker 1: If you like food shows so much, send us more food show ideas for Thursday.
Speaker 0: One thing I've noticed, though, is that as I've gotten not just older, and not even necessarily wealthier, but living in places where I have more access to better quality food, irrespective of price, if I go to a crapo Chinese place in Flushing, it's really high-quality Chinese food that's very flavorful.
Speaker 0: I can't eat the non-flavorful Chinese food in Michigan.
Speaker 1: But if you had only lived in Michigan, you could.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I could.
Speaker 0: I used to eat Chinese food that by my modern palate tastes like nothing.
Speaker 0: It tastes like just MSG on cardboard.
Speaker 1: You can't eat Seattle pizza.
Speaker 1: You can't eat Dunkin' Donuts bagel.
Speaker 1: Nope.
Speaker 0: I can't eat a Dunkin' Donuts donut.
Speaker 1: I can eat a Dunkin' Donuts donut.
Speaker 0: When was the last time you ate a Dunkin' Donuts donut?
Speaker 0: This year.
Speaker 0: They are not worth eating.
Speaker 0: I would go hungry before I'd eat a Dunkin' Donuts donut.
Speaker 0: I'm out.
Speaker 1: I'm biking.
Speaker 1: It's morning.
Speaker 1: I want some sugar.
Speaker 1: Oh, look.
Speaker 1: They're selling sugar.
Speaker 0: I'll buy it.
Speaker 0: Scott, it's New York.
Speaker 0: There's probably a real donut within like a half a mile of wherever you are.
Speaker 1: In New Jersey.
Speaker 1: The biking group.
Speaker 1: The biking group stops at the Dunkin' Donuts.
Speaker 1: You should have brought food with you.
Speaker 1: I did, but I wanted to buy a sugar other than the sugar I was carrying.
Speaker 0: Dunkin' Donuts, I would go hungry.
Speaker 0: You know, back to our scenario.
Speaker 0: I would go hungry and skip dinner rather than eat Dunkin' Donuts food.
Speaker 1: A donut is just a sugar ring.
Speaker 1: It's fine.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't need the sugar ring.
Speaker 0: I will not eat a sugar ring that tastes like just sugar and ring.
Speaker 1: That's what it tastes like.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it tastes like a ring of cardboard with sugar on it.
Speaker 1: No, it's just sugar and it tastes fine.
Speaker 1: It tastes like sugar.
Speaker 1: Sugar tastes great.
Speaker 0: It's unsatisfying.
Speaker 1: It's not like it's hard or anything.
Speaker 1: The bagel tastes like nothing.
Speaker 1: The bagel I won't eat.
Speaker 0: I can't eat just a bagel that's just bread.
Speaker 0: It's like, alright, this is basically just Wonder Bread in the shape of a bagel.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I will not eat a bread ring, but I will eat a sugar ring.
Speaker 0: I won't eat a sugar ring anymore.
Speaker 1: Alright, don't.
Speaker 0: I just can't.
Speaker 0: It just doesn't satisfy me.
Speaker 0: Don't think.
Speaker 0: I feel better by avoiding it than eating it.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: Do what you gotta do.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's why I'm gonna come and avoid Dunkin' Donuts.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 0: Alright, I think we might have killed enough time.
Speaker 1: Mustn't kill time, boy.
Speaker 1: Cherish it.
Speaker 1: You must cherish the sugar ring.
Speaker 0: Alright, I guess the last thing.
Speaker 0: What are the foods you just don't like?
Speaker 0: Like, let's just try to list the foods we don't like.
Speaker 0: Neither one of us are picky eaters.
Speaker 0: We eat a lot.
Speaker 1: There are foods that I like or might like but won't eat.
Speaker 1: Actually, I've never tried it, but I'm pretty sure shark fin soup probably tastes good.
Speaker 1: So, my guess would be that it tastes great.
Speaker 1: I will not eat that.
Speaker 0: It's been served to me, and I have a rule generally that...
Speaker 1: I know that foie gras tastes great because I've had it, but I'm not gonna order it.
Speaker 0: It has been served to me, and my rule is, if I have ethical concerns about a food, but unbeknownst to me and without my input, it is prepared for me, I will usually eat it so it doesn't go to waste.
Speaker 0: And in those cases, in that context, I have had rabbit, even though I don't want to eat rabbit.
Speaker 0: I have had shark fin soup, even though I don't want shark fin soup.
Speaker 0: Was it good?
Speaker 1: I haven't had it.
Speaker 0: No, it was kind of bland.
Speaker 1: I've been told it was rich.
Speaker 0: Well, yeah, you can make it rich, but I've had better soups.
Speaker 0: It wasn't...
Speaker 1: Did you have a bad shark fin soup or shark fin soup?
Speaker 1: just bad?
Speaker 0: This was shark fin soup served to me illicitly in Hong Kong at a rich person's thing.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 0: It was good, but it was not good enough to justify the cruelty.
Speaker 1: It wasn't foie gras good.
Speaker 0: So foie gras has been served to me twice without me ordering it in my adult life.
Speaker 0: One time, Emily and I were at a super fancy French restaurant having a very expensive, fancy date night, and the waiter just comes over and hands us something and puts it on the table, and it's a pâté of some kind and walks away.
Speaker 0: And we just both assume, "All right, I guess they just serve this to
Speaker 0: us.".
Speaker 0: We immediately eat it, because it wasn't that much.
Speaker 0: It was one of the most delicious things I've ever eaten in my life.
Speaker 0: The waiter comes back and is like, "Oh, sorry, that was for another tête,".
Speaker 0: and it's gone, because we've already eaten it.
Speaker 0: We've eaten it in the 30 seconds before we realize he delivered this very expensive foie gras to the wrong table.
Speaker 0: We just ate it.
Speaker 0: He was a little miffed that we just ate it.
Speaker 1: Why wouldn't you?
Speaker 1: You put food on my table, I eat it.
Speaker 0: Yup.
Speaker 0: And it was really, really, really, really, really delicious.
Speaker 0: Of course.
Speaker 0: But I will never order foie gras.
Speaker 1: It's a fatty goose liver.
Speaker 0: If I ever had to make an exception, I would be willing to entertain ordering foie gras if I knew that it was hunted as opposed to farmed.
Speaker 1: It won't taste as good.
Speaker 0: It would arguably taste better.
Speaker 1: Just like veal won't taste as good.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I try to avoid eating veal, but it ends up being one of many ingredients in many Italian dishes.
Speaker 1: Like a meatball that has veal in it?
Speaker 0: I will never order a veal by itself.
Speaker 1: I try to avoid eating veal.
Speaker 1: I haven't eaten it probably in years, unless it's been, say, in a meatball.
Speaker 1: But I will, super rarely, as in less than once a year, order a veal because it tastes real good and it's less evil than foie gras while still being very evil.
Speaker 0: At least farmed foie gras is awful.
Speaker 1: It is less evil than a nortolin bunting, which I won't eat.
Speaker 0: I would never eat a nortolin bunting.
Speaker 0: I would consider de-friending someone or disowning a family member who ate nortolin bunting because that just feels like it's done for the sake of being awful.
Speaker 1: It is.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: You're exactly right.
Speaker 0: It can't be good.
Speaker 0: If you like Armagnac so much and you want to have this experience, just get a regular pheasant and cook it in Armagnac.
Speaker 0: It's not going to be different.
Speaker 1: I won't eat anything that's too smart like dolphin.
Speaker 1: I won't eat anything harmful like a monkey brain.
Speaker 1: I won't eat an octopus because it's too smart.
Speaker 0: So I have a problem.
Speaker 1: I also won't eat squid tentacles even though squids are stupid.
Speaker 0: They're not as stupid as people say, Scott.
Speaker 0: I've learned some things about squid.
Speaker 1: Yes, but they're stupider than an octopus.
Speaker 0: Arguably, they're similarly intelligent in a different way.
Speaker 1: Either way, I'm not eating them.
Speaker 1: so it doesn't matter why I don't eat them because the tentacles, even regardless of their smartness, tentacles are just too damn chewy.
Speaker 0: That's just because you got bad ones like scallops.
Speaker 0: You don't like mediocre to average or even above average scallops, but I know you for a fact like good scallops.
Speaker 1: Well, at least the scallop isn't smart at all.
Speaker 1: It's just a shell that opens and closes.
Speaker 1: As far as I know, a scallop is dumb as a brick.
Speaker 1: It just opens and closes.
Speaker 0: So all I'm going to tell you...
Speaker 1: And it's a little white blob that shimmies.
Speaker 1: It doesn't do anything.
Speaker 0: You can use this information...
Speaker 1: You can't open a lock like an octopus.
Speaker 0: I provide you information.
Speaker 0: You can use it as you see fit.
Speaker 0: Octopus tentacle that is good.
Speaker 0: octopus tentacle is as good and as different from regular octopus tentacle as the good scallop is from the regular scallop.
Speaker 1: I'm still not eating a takoyaki even though it's probably fucking delicious.
Speaker 0: Takoyaki is so good.
Speaker 1: I'm not eating it because...
Speaker 0: It's one of my favorite foods.
Speaker 1: It's made of octopus.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but it's so good.
Speaker 1: Find me a proven dumbass octopus.
Speaker 1: Maybe I'll try one.
Speaker 0: Yeah, just jerk octopus.
Speaker 0: Like find one who specifically did something bad.
Speaker 1: Oh, like yeah, even though it's smart, we can see...
Speaker 0: Find one who committed a crime.
Speaker 0: If they're smart enough, they know the difference between good and evil.
Speaker 1: Even though it's smart, we can see.
Speaker 1: this is clearly a bad octopus that deserved to be eaten.
Speaker 0: I won't eat natto.
Speaker 0: That shit's disgusting.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it smells bad.
Speaker 0: I won't eat vegemite.
Speaker 0: That shit's disgusting.
Speaker 0: I ate it once.
Speaker 0: It doesn't taste good, so I don't need it anymore.
Speaker 0: I've tried vegemite.
Speaker 0: I've tried marmite.
Speaker 0: Marmite is a...
Speaker 1: I haven't tried the marmite.
Speaker 0: Imagine vegemite, but like grosser and more gooey.
Speaker 1: I'm not eating that.
Speaker 0: Like bitter.
Speaker 0: Like runnier.
Speaker 0: Like imagine runny vegemite.
Speaker 1: That is worse.
Speaker 0: It is so gross.
Speaker 1: I will not eat that.
Speaker 0: Because I had vegemite before and you hadn't when we were in Australia.
Speaker 0: And you really wanted to try it.
Speaker 1: I was in Australia.
Speaker 1: That's the thing to do.
Speaker 1: You know what I learned?
Speaker 1: If you go to Australia, Pat, you don't need to worry about the vegemite.
Speaker 1: You just got to get the Tim Tams.
Speaker 1: Tim Tams are the thing you want from Australia, not vegemite.
Speaker 1: They should really decrease their telling tourists about vegemite, which I think they do just as like a trap.
Speaker 1: And they should increase telling tourists about Tim Tams.
Speaker 0: But even then, the real secret of Australia is the big brekkie.
Speaker 0: Tim Tam.
Speaker 0: Tim Tams are okay.
Speaker 0: Tim Tams are like... They're basically like... They're equivalent of some of that New Jersey, Pennsylvania high food that we enjoy.
Speaker 0: Or at least that Dave Riley and Joel White enjoy.
Speaker 0: In fact, I remember you, me, and Sherba went to that grocery store to buy that vegemite.
Speaker 1: I'm the one who wanted to go to a grocery store.
Speaker 1: I always like to go to a grocery store wherever I go.
Speaker 1: I went to the grocery store in Aruba, went to the grocery store in Australia, grocery store in Israel.
Speaker 1: If I'm coming to your country, I'm going to the grocery store.
Speaker 0: I don't like tripe, like I said.
Speaker 0: I just don't enjoy tripe.
Speaker 0: I don't like chicken feet and all those kinds of things.
Speaker 0: I'll eat them, I just don't like them.
Speaker 1: Chicken feet, I'll eat it, but I won't order it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't like them.
Speaker 0: But if they're there, I might eat a couple.
Speaker 1: I'm down with it.
Speaker 1: You order some chicken feet and dim sum, it's like I'll bite one.
Speaker 0: I'll eat a little bit.
Speaker 0: But there's not that many foods I don't like.
Speaker 0: It's a pretty short list.
Speaker 1: I'll eat almost any food.
Speaker 1: It's just beverages, I'm very limited in the beverage department.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'll drink a lot of things too.
Speaker 0: I got this really good dog cushion.
Speaker 1: Oh, you know what I don't like.
Speaker 1: that is a normal food that other people like?
Speaker 1: Is artichoke.
Speaker 1: I don't like artichoke.
Speaker 0: What the fuck is wrong with you?
Speaker 0: Tastes bad.
Speaker 0: I don't know, artichoke is one of my favorite foods.
Speaker 1: Tastes bad.
Speaker 0: Don't eat it.
Speaker 0: Like artichokes and brussels sprouts and all those things?
Speaker 1: Brussels sprout is great.
Speaker 1: Brussels sprout is the best.
Speaker 1: Brussels sprout is like top tier vegetable.
Speaker 0: Have you ever had, what about artichoke dip?
Speaker 1: No, it's also bad.
Speaker 0: But you like guacamole?
Speaker 1: Tastes nothing like artichoke.
Speaker 0: Okay, yeah, but they're a similar type of food.
Speaker 0: in the end, artichoke dip.
Speaker 0: I guess artichoke dip is more like spinach dip and less like guacamole.
Speaker 1: Spinach dip's okay.
Speaker 1: I like spinach.
Speaker 0: I like spinach a lot.
Speaker 0: I'll eat spinach.
Speaker 0: As a kid, I would eat like a quarter pound of spinach dip by myself.
Speaker 1: I try to avoid eating raw spinach and raw kale that has not been cooked because in addition to the bacterial disease E. coli problems of eating just any uncooked vegetable.
Speaker 0: Yeah, listen to our friend Pete, cook your lettuce.
Speaker 1: Cook all vegetables.
Speaker 1: It has the additional problem of fucking up your stomach.
Speaker 0: So, it doesn't actually, from what I've read, it doesn't actually cause that problem more than a lot of other cooked foods?
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: The danger's overblown.
Speaker 1: It's still more than zero.
Speaker 1: My stomach is-.
Speaker 0: Well, spinach is also really good.
Speaker 0: Like, I really enjoy it.
Speaker 1: It's all right.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Nothing's gotten, really no lettuce can really compare with arugula.
Speaker 1: Arugula is the king of lettuce.
Speaker 0: I really, really don't like American cheese because it doesn't taste like anything.
Speaker 1: Depends, right?
Speaker 1: So, if you go and you get, say, Kraft Slice at Singles, those taste like nothing.
Speaker 0: Why would you ever eat American cheese when Colby exists, Colby Jack exists, Jack exists, Cheddar exists, Havarti exists?
Speaker 1: If you go to the deli counter and you ask for, say, I guess the minimum American cheese that has flavor would be Land O'Lakes American.
Speaker 0: But I'm saying the highest quality American cheese from the best deli in the world is still mediocre compared to even like an average Cheddar or an average Monterey Jack.
Speaker 1: You can get good American cheese.
Speaker 1: It has a flavor.
Speaker 0: Well, yes, it's good in respect to American cheese, but the stat for American cheese is a whole caps out real low.
Speaker 1: No, it's- The best American cheese is worse- It's just a different variety of cheese.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and it's flavorless.
Speaker 1: No, you haven't had a flavorful high quality American cheese that has a flavor.
Speaker 0: If I blindfolded you, I don't think you could tell the difference between good American cheese and really, really shitty like Colby Jack.
Speaker 1: Go get some really shitty Colby Jack and get like, I guess I already said Land O'Lakes American has flavor, so get that.
Speaker 1: I can tell it apart with my eyes closed.
Speaker 1: Get yellow or white, it's just food coloring.
Speaker 1: It's not any different.
Speaker 0: All right, now we've definitely killed enough time, so- Okay.
Speaker 0: This has been Geek Nights with Rim and Scott.
Speaker 0: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design, and Brando Kay for the logos.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at frontrowcrew.com for show notes, discussion news, and more.
Speaker 0: Remember, Geek Nights is not one, but four different shows.
Speaker 0: Sci-Tech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays, and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: Geek Nights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: Geek Nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.
Speaker 0: And the Patreon patrons for this episode of Geek Nights, in order of the amount of money they give us on a continuing basis, with a couple added in because of past mistakes where they weren't being listed due to issues in the way Patreon shows rewards and such.
Speaker 0: Anyway, the patrons are Craig Oliver, Alan Joyce, Hygen McNicholas, Schiminger Rubiablos, Hanging in the Sky, Jar Tovishin, Link E, GMI, Stake Day.com, J-Bands, Kudalone, Roberto Kingsley, Sean Yeager, Matthew Smith, Nicholas Brinder, Mr.
Speaker 0: Strong, Strashin, 421 Creations, Chris Reimer, and Thomas Hahn, Shervin, Ron Harle, Rory, Rochelle Montanona, Superboy, Sailor Vista, Don, Shilai, Joe Shrove, Joe Starr, Clinton Walton, Ren from New Zealand, Ryan Perringer, OpenLadder, Finn, Chris Midkiff, Dan the Redman, Sean Klein, Chris Reimer, and Thomas Hahn, and now I leave you
Speaker 2: with... [MUSIC] [MUSIC].