Speaker 1: It's Wednesday, June 13th, 2018.
Speaker 1: I'm rim.
Speaker 1: I'm Scott and this is geek nights tonight.
Speaker 1: Uma, Musume a pretty derby.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: So as many of you know, we complain a lot about the city of Boston here on geek nights Because I've been playing about any city that's not in New York.
Speaker 0: Yeah But when we complain about most or as big or bigger than New York when we complain about most we don't go to those places.
Speaker 0: We complain that they're.
Speaker 1: they're not as big as New York.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I can't get a bagel at like 5 a.m That's correct.
Speaker 0: But if I went even Tokyo, which is probably bigger than New York, I'd complain.
Speaker 0: the train stopped running at night.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well the train stopped running almost the train to be on time the rest of the day.
Speaker 0: So I guess it evens out.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but it'd be just as crowded as the four.
Speaker 0: five More crowding depending on when you go.
Speaker 1: The seven is getting to the point where I need someone to help push everybody into the car.
Speaker 1: Come on, basically Yeah, I also got the bicycle.
Speaker 0: it's a good news today though it rain.
Speaker 0: I couldn't use it cuz I had to end my day at a different office And I didn't want to ride from one of us to the other on a bicycle.
Speaker 1: No, cuz I have to set up my shit if I want to park the bike at that other office every building like Independent of my company.
Speaker 1: the buildings have their own management companies and those are the people that actually have to follow that New York City law.
Speaker 1: So every building I have to comply with like that building's bike policy.
Speaker 1: So I can like register the bike and do all this bullshit.
Speaker 1: so I only did that for one building.
Speaker 1: but Boston we complain about for different reasons the specific things we complain about with Boston That are within the city of Boston's control because the third thing is that it's always too cold there.
Speaker 1: Is that one?
Speaker 1: But the city of Boston has in my personal opinion the worst drivers of any city on earth.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm Boston's to this day the only city I've ever been in where I've seen a person in a car drive Backwards up a one-way street the wrong way.
Speaker 1: more than once.
Speaker 1: I think I've seen that happen At the majority of patches I've been to in Boston.
Speaker 0: I mean, you know, it's it's right in Boston you have the problem of.
Speaker 0: the roads were designed in ancient colonial times.
Speaker 0: Yeah It's like the very bottom of Manhattan with the colonial roads.
Speaker 0: before you go farther north There's the grid made in smarter, but you also have this weird social contract for people in Boston.
Speaker 0: Just don't respect the idea of following basic rules except that it's the whole city and not just one part.
Speaker 1: Yeah But even that like people I've.
Speaker 1: no I don't understand nowhere else on earth.
Speaker 1: Just do people just suddenly start driving backwards long distances.
Speaker 1: Like where does that happen?
Speaker 1: I didn't even have to do that in fucking Istanbul confirmation, but uh Let's say let's keep an eye out for the next time we see that happen and I suspect we'll see it happen in Boston.
Speaker 1: But number two is Boston Forces all the conventions there the nerd conventions to have ridiculous fake security.
Speaker 1: and it's gone to the point like it's kind of why we stopped going to animate Boston because it's too much of a hassle to deal with.
Speaker 1: and If I had to stop going to a PAX PAX East in Boston is the one I would drop first.
Speaker 1: I would rather go to San Antonio than the one in Boston and there's an article about this because The city of Boston itself is having problems with the security.
Speaker 1: so the city both forces events to have this completely fake security.
Speaker 1: that causes huge problems, especially for nerd conventions and The security they have mandated is breaking their own rules.
Speaker 1: So there's this article in this like Universal Hub, which is like a local Boston thing.
Speaker 1: I think it's like Boston's Gothamist Like.
Speaker 1: I don't really know the deal with it, but I see people in Boston retweeted a lot and no one else talks about it.
Speaker 1: But it actually has an article about this situation.
Speaker 1: and basically during PAX East there were some doors that were locked that Can't bet.
Speaker 1: according to some rules in Boston cannot be locked when there are people in the convention center.
Speaker 1: But they were locked because people kept trying to walk in those doors Instead of going through the metal detectors that were only in like two or three places.
Speaker 1: now they shouldn't have any metal detectors and all those doors should be open, but Basically the city of Boston is now fighting with the city of Boston and it's a fight between like whoever makes that bullshit security happen and the BPD licensing detectives because apparently there's all these licensing rules around buildings having doors open or closed and They got involved because a bunch of cops noticed that at PAX East There was a huge crowd of people trying to get out a door that was not only locked but duct-taped shut
Speaker 0: Like how our country is so fucked up and yet we're spending courts and judges and lawyers time because someone didn't open a goddamn door Even though they definitely should have opened that door.
Speaker 1: But yep, that door should be open.
Speaker 1: That's the.
Speaker 1: that's the important part.
Speaker 0: The point is look how small potatoes this is.
Speaker 0: This is such a small potato that like a baby you would make one french fry for the baby and they still be hungry.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's how small that potato is.
Speaker 1: so I Guess I hope the city of Boston loses and the metal detectors disappeared some point Even though I know that's gonna be the result.
Speaker 1: What I really hope for is that packs will someday just leave Boston and then I'll never have to go there for a nerd convention again.
Speaker 1: That's that's what I actually want.
Speaker 0: thing that is unrelated to nerdery almost entirely but you know, it only happens every four years, but people in the US at least might not be aware because The United States did not qualify for the World Cup which begins tomorrow.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah the World Cup Football people don't even know because we didn't qualify in this country and we don't care in this country.
Speaker 0: But it's kind of a big deal.
Speaker 1: So anyway in the actual anime and animation news.
Speaker 1: very briefly just because not everyone seems to be aware of it.
Speaker 1: There is an anime con where we will probably go to it because it's in New York and we can literally take this Doing this in the news because I'm not announcing that we're doing anything at it.
Speaker 1: I'm saying that if you want an anime con That's probably the packs of anime cons based on the first one that happened.
Speaker 1: The second one is happening and it does not overlap with packs unplugged so you can actually go to it.
Speaker 1: It's November 16 17 18th in the Jacob Javits Center in New York City.
Speaker 0: So if you live near enough to New York City worth going otherwise, probably not Yep, but still probably worth going if you're close enough, but something interesting I noticed because there are cons that are bad where you shouldn't go even if they're right next door.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but the one trouble with having a nerd con in New York City.
Speaker 1: Like as much as I want packs to leave Boston I do not want them to get a New York City because a con in New York City is fucking awful Unless the only attendees are people who live in New York City.
Speaker 1: Like there aren't gonna be hotel blocks for people in New York that are affordable or anywhere near the convention.
Speaker 0: Yeah this time of year.
Speaker 0: Yeah hotels are not the cheapest.
Speaker 0: if you want to have a convention in New York City The best time is February where hotel prices can go down from usuals of 500 to like 150 a night in places like downtown And such.
Speaker 0: but no one wants to come here in fucking February Because it's fucking cold and snowy and you'll get caught in a blizzard and your flight will get delayed and you won't get home on Time.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's why it's 150 a night As long as you're not staying in the touristy area where it's always 500 a night for a place with cockroaches.
Speaker 1: Yep, so it's happening.
Speaker 1: We'll probably be there.
Speaker 1: But the thing I noticed is that the panels cuz I always there's some panels and I haven't submitted anime panels anywhere in a while.
Speaker 1: Like I had to think about what anime panel or even do.
Speaker 1: but The panel slots are an hour long and there's no gaps.
Speaker 1: So the actual panel slots are actually 45 minutes long like by default.
Speaker 1: So all the panels at this con are actually like really short format.
Speaker 0: There's gonna be a lot of panels.
Speaker 0: Yeah, which changes up my own methodology not like a short convention It's just when you make the panel slots 45 minutes with 15 minute breaks instead of one hour of 15 minute breaks.
Speaker 0: First of all, the schedule looks real nice.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but second of all You can cram in a lot of panels one per hour.
Speaker 1: I wonder like I don't know why they did this.
Speaker 1: I didn't even know this was the thing until like three days ago.
Speaker 1: but the 45 minute panel slot is interesting because Anime cons in particular though gaming cons largely have this problem now - most of the panels are Some industry person or panel is going to talk for five minutes and go straight to Q&A and then give away some swag.
Speaker 1: So you really lose nothing by making the panel slots shorter Like nothing is lost.
Speaker 1: by having them shorter the same amount of content will be provided.
Speaker 1: but for us it's interesting because Like everything we've ever done at a con we'd use the entire hours.
Speaker 1: I'd actually have to think of it.
Speaker 1: We might change the kinds of topics we talk about.
Speaker 1: We'll see.
Speaker 1: But anyways anime cons happening and in some other news being puppycat is getting its second season as mine is I Just said some other news.
Speaker 0: So the thing is right.
Speaker 0: is the the cartoon hangover with our Frederator?
Speaker 0: I'm not even sure what the difference is They seem to be one in the same as far as I can tell But they you know They make a lot of cool cartoons that we like like a Bravest Warriors and the being puppycat and a bunch of other stuff No one knows.
Speaker 0: At first they would post these things on YouTube and then I saw some of them because I kick-started and they would email me links To watch them on other sites and then eventually like they were posting like their YouTube channel Which I'm still subscribed to it wouldn't actually be posting full episodes And they'd be like links to some other site where you can watch them.
Speaker 0: and it was like it was very confusing.
Speaker 0: There was no easy and straightforward way to just watch all the new episodes of the shows We like as they come out in full and because of that I sort of fell off their bus because they made it too hard to stay on that bus.
Speaker 0: So Another thing that really hurt them was that they didn't put out content consistently, which is understandable because they were making Animated TV, you know quality episodes as good as like, you know and an episode of Adventure Time yet They were just some little indie place that didn't have a TV network or anything.
Speaker 0: It was going straight to YouTube.
Speaker 1: Now if they were just on YouTube, that's fine.
Speaker 0: Like I'm already used to these sort of ad hoc schedules So it's understandable that they would not be putting out content super regularly, but they were putting it out Super irregularly.
Speaker 0: like when was the last Be In Public At episode over a year ago?
Speaker 1: Something like that.
Speaker 0: and people like paid money in Kickstarter for these things.
Speaker 0: It's like alright But now they've it's.
Speaker 0: this seems to be at least as set in stone as they can possibly be.
Speaker 0: There's gonna be a full season of Be In Public At.
Speaker 0: episodes that are made.
Speaker 0: they're coming.
Speaker 1: the episodes are going to here.
Speaker 1: There's important differences like changes.
Speaker 1: The episodes are gonna be half-hour full-length episodes now Yeah, but they're going to.
Speaker 0: it's still like the same creative team behind the story and stuff like that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, Natasha is actually there's a showrunner.
Speaker 1: Natasha Leggery is actually favorite crazy person.
Speaker 1: We came to a shared understanding that we like a lot of the same things.
Speaker 1: Anything I like weird internet shit.
Speaker 0: well I can see the actual.
Speaker 0: you've got another think coming work and the animation of the show is going to be done by OLM which is Pokemon the studio that makes animates Pokemon.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it looks like it.
Speaker 0: So, I mean if they can animate all those episodes of Pokemon reliably I'm sure they can animate episodes of Be In Public At reliably if they get paid which I assume they're gonna be paid.
Speaker 0: So Yep, so I wonder how much it costs.
Speaker 0: like how much do we have to save to make them animate what we want?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 0: But what's interesting is so the crazy like how much would it cost to get them to animate one 30-minute episode of you guys?
Speaker 0: The anime.
Speaker 1: but apparently the creative team is actually gonna be living in Tokyo to work on the production of this season together with them.
Speaker 0: That's interesting.
Speaker 1: The only pretty only bad news here is I'm gonna read two sentences from the article that Can be waiting a long time between now and episode one.
Speaker 0: They should have just kept their mouth shut until they had her already.
Speaker 1: No, I could live with that.
Speaker 1: I think there's a trailer or something.
Speaker 1: But here's the problem.
Speaker 0: There is.
Speaker 1: The series will be available Through crunchyroll sounds good.
Speaker 1: parent company elations verve streaming platform.
Speaker 0: Okay, so gonna be in.
Speaker 1: it's not gonna be on crunchyroll.
Speaker 0: It's in the same place.
Speaker 0: It's hard to watch as all their other stuff.
Speaker 0: It's gonna be the place.
Speaker 0: I don't seem like two episodes of bravest warriors and haven't seen the rest.
Speaker 0: Yep, because I think I left off where the horse went of the dimension or something and that I think I saw it all.
Speaker 0: There was more stuff after that.
Speaker 0: that I'm pretty sure I haven't seen because it's on some weird website Probably this one you just mentioned.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I mean the ways I watch shows today are crunchyroll Netflix Like.
Speaker 1: I just have those subscriptions Amazon Prime.
Speaker 1: I just have that.
Speaker 1: that's how I like.
Speaker 1: I watch a lot of anime on Amazon cuz it's just there.
Speaker 1: Shows like venture brothers like the other kinds animation.
Speaker 1: I like.
Speaker 1: I just buy them on Amazon.
Speaker 0: How much does that cost?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: like 20 bucks a season.
Speaker 0: So how many seasons of say like, you know of that show are there?
Speaker 0: like seven.
Speaker 0: so he's paying $140 to watch seven.
Speaker 1: I used to pay $140 for one fucking season of anime and also More to the point.
Speaker 1: I pirated the first season six seasons adventure brothers.
Speaker 1: So I felt like I can give them the 20 bucks.
Speaker 0: That sounds like a better plan.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's fair.
Speaker 1: Like I'm paying for the shows that I'm continuing to watch But if I could watch them on a platform that I actually used other than Amazon I would Yeah, and I just I wish shows like this would just be on YouTube or be on crunchyroll.
Speaker 1: I do not want there to be a lot of streaming platform.
Speaker 1: I think I'd be like four.
Speaker 0: I think that they like made.
Speaker 0: they made this deal with this other platform because they weren't making enough money on the youtubes.
Speaker 0: But it's like guys.
Speaker 0: that is a problem.
Speaker 0: Just go on YouTube take the pittance of YouTube money and then sell the merch.
Speaker 0: look how much you know.
Speaker 0: The we love finds got all those like cat bugs and puppy cat plushies and shit and you know what?
Speaker 0: I can't imagine that sales of those are going up because I see when I see that booth at cons It has less of those things at it than it used to.
Speaker 0: why?
Speaker 0: because you're not making a bunch of fans And you're not getting fans because no one can see your shit.
Speaker 0: You're better off making an army of fans and then making money later.
Speaker 0: Then you are trying to make money off the fans you got see less in comic books.
Speaker 1: So speaking of the monetization models of anime I want to.
Speaker 1: there's two issues Around something that has been creeping into my Twitter timeline called otaku coin.
Speaker 1: Luckily most of the people who run into otaku coin run into it in the context of someone else saying it's a scam and them Saying wait, what's this thing?
Speaker 1: But for those of you who are unaware, why are you even talking about this?
Speaker 0: You're you're making people aware of this when we should really.
Speaker 0: just if the more you talk about it the more you inflate it.
Speaker 0: He's not mention it so that goes away.
Speaker 1: you say that a lot, but there is no evidence.
Speaker 1: that is true in media.
Speaker 1: In fact, there's more evidence that Positive coverage from biased outlets coupled with lack of negative coverage from other people not talking about something is way more dangerous and that negative attention generally does not increase the scope of Adoption.
Speaker 0: Yeah, cuz look you have.
Speaker 0: you basically have people.
Speaker 0: even if there's one person saying oh my god otaku coins Oh my god, if everyone else just shuts up otaku will be a small thing.
Speaker 0: less people even know it exists.
Speaker 0: See you say The evidence is the opposite by everyone continuing to even mention its name.
Speaker 0: You know spread its name and everyone knows what the fuck it is.
Speaker 0: All right, that's not good.
Speaker 1: Well aside from the lack of evidence to back anything you just said the deal with otaku coin.
Speaker 1: Is that in my personal opinion?
Speaker 1: It's just a scam.
Speaker 0: It's everything.
Speaker 0: anything.
Speaker 0: coin is a scam.
Speaker 0: We know this already.
Speaker 1: We know this a lot of other people don't.
Speaker 0: how do you not don't go do any bullshit with fucking coins?
Speaker 1: God, dude the SEC made a website that was a fake coin.
Speaker 1: that was like obviously like the fakest shit and If you click to try to buy any it takes you to another SEC page.
Speaker 1: that is like yo, you just got tricked.
Speaker 1: Let me tell you how these things are scams.
Speaker 0: Yeah They should have.
Speaker 0: this is because people spread all this kept talking about bitcoins.
Speaker 0: people just shut up and ignored the Bitcoin.
Speaker 0: No What happened?
Speaker 1: if people who are critical of something just shut up then you've seen it all.
Speaker 1: ground to the grifters.
Speaker 0: You shouldn't shut what you know.
Speaker 0: It's not that you should shut up completely is you should not mention the name of the evil thing You should be like don't you know?
Speaker 0: saying don't do any coin bullshit.
Speaker 0: But when you have all these, you know news articles like Bitcoin Bitcoin Bitcoin actually saying the name of the thing.
Speaker 0: It's like people can Beetlejuice, right?
Speaker 0: It's suddenly like the Google traffic on the thing goes up.
Speaker 0: I mean all the people on Facebook will start, you know.
Speaker 0: So if you believe that sky has a carry-on effect where all the marketers will try to get on top of it.
Speaker 0: You know and everything and people start writing articles about it because it's a big term.
Speaker 0: Right, don't say the word and then it won't become a big deal.
Speaker 1: Okay again aside from the fact that there's zero evidence to back up all your baseless assertions deal with otaku coin.
Speaker 1: is that the scam here is That they want to get nerds to use these coins to choose like which anime get funded like it's supposed to be this Democratization of anime production that the coin is the currency to tell the anime industry what shows should be invested in.
Speaker 0: How do you get the coin?
Speaker 1: So that's the part I'm not gonna get into because it's all just a fucking scam.
Speaker 0: You just buy.
Speaker 0: you just buy them with real money.
Speaker 0: I don't even know Why don't you know you?
Speaker 0: what you could do is you could just say hey, here's a website.
Speaker 0: Here's a bunch of animes listed.
Speaker 0: Donate real money to the ones you want made.
Speaker 0: Why do you need these coins as an intermediary?
Speaker 0: What effect do they have?
Speaker 1: Wait, see donating money to corporations nakedly already runs into weird tax issues.
Speaker 0: So you're basically just using a coin to avoid taxes.
Speaker 1: No, it's way worse than that the real issue.
Speaker 1: So the real issue here the fundamental the the core premise coins aside is a problem and this is Increasingly becoming a problem in all fandoms like the Star Wars fandom is because total horseshit.
Speaker 1: now We're gonna talk about some horseshit anime in a second.
Speaker 1: But so the problem is that fans of anime and fans of movies and fans of things these days Feel like because they're a fan of something that they should have some agency and ownership around the production of the thing They're a fan of.
Speaker 0: and that's utterly wrong.
Speaker 1: And that is a big part of why there's such a horrible toxic community around pretty much every fandom these days.
Speaker 0: Well, that's because you know part of it is big just because nowadays the tools of production are democratized.
Speaker 0: Yeah, anyone can make stuff right.
Speaker 0: so in a world where anyone can make stuff, right?
Speaker 0: Even though you don't have the resources to make you know, something real.
Speaker 0: I mean you you guys.
Speaker 0: you could theoretically if you spent all fucking day sitting at your computer Learning everything and working crazy hard and somehow eating only ramen or whatever Eventually make a real legit movie, but good luck
Speaker 1: Yeah, but it's not just that it's that fans will like they'll get invested in like they think a character should be treated.
Speaker 0: No But I say like because you can create stuff right and be in by creating stuff and usually creating fan works Utilizing other people's stuff.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right you.
Speaker 0: now you're not just conceiving.
Speaker 0: the people who are pure Consumers are no longer just pure consumers.
Speaker 0: You're writing your fan fictions of Harry Potter.
Speaker 0: You feel like you're part of the Harry Potter deal and you can't make your fan fictions contradict the cannon.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so if the cannon is messed up and it doesn't go with your fan fictions anymore Now you're mad and such and such right?
Speaker 0: So it's like you, you know, if we're all working, you know instead of having the Original creators used to have this status of I write everything and you consume and you don't make anything.
Speaker 0: All you do is consume whereas now they've been demoted to more of a you know Lead leader among the partners who create in the same world, even though they didn't say that people just do it.
Speaker 0: Anyway, they just do it because you can't stop them, right?
Speaker 1: everyone's got a copy of Adobe Premiere and Photoshop and it and a word processor and also create on in and you can't stop or the Individual people involved in production are now more accessible to randos Like they might have a Twitter like you.
Speaker 1: look in the credits and look up someone's name and Google them and find their Facebook And start harassing them.
Speaker 1: and also your head cannon didn't reach out.
Speaker 0: Well, and also in the olden days, right if I read a book and the book doesn't jive with you.
Speaker 0: First of all, even if you complain no one can fucking hear you because you don't have the internet to complain on.
Speaker 0: right.
Speaker 0: But to that - that doesn't really disrupt your day, right?
Speaker 1: It's like someone in the chat was like we went from.
Speaker 1: the author is dead - we killed the author.
Speaker 0: It doesn't really mess with your day, right?
Speaker 0: Whereas consider say a video game especially right if you're playing a video game.
Speaker 0: that video game is like You know, especially an online video game and you're in the community of that game.
Speaker 0: You're playing it maybe even competitively.
Speaker 0: You're heavily involved.
Speaker 0: if they change the rules of the game, you know The author's the people who run the game.
Speaker 0: if League of Legends adds a character removes a character changes a rule Makes a patch nerfs like someone nerfs a card in a card game, right that actually affects your day Because you're so involved in it, right which is different from back in the day where someone changed something.
Speaker 0: You know the old the creator changes something it affects your life none.
Speaker 1: so I my take on otaku coin is that it's trying to combine the ridiculous buzz around cryptocurrencies, which are mostly scams in my opinion with entirely fan desire to control the industry that makes the things they watch.
Speaker 1: and They they're basically feeding into two very powerful forces among people who live in basements and generally don't have many Prospects in life so that if they have no control over their lives and they're just involuntarily in their basement being sad watching hentai Or whatever they can take their special magic cryptocurrency and use that to get the anime titties.
Speaker 1: They want produce, right?
Speaker 0: What's gonna happen if you someone spends a zillion otaku coins to get a specific anime titty produced?
Speaker 0: I think.
Speaker 0: and then that anime titty is not produced.
Speaker 1: Yeah, or what if it's produced but it's the wrong anime titty?
Speaker 0: It's three titties like.
Speaker 0: What are they gonna do then?
Speaker 1: so Do not engage with the otaku coin.
Speaker 1: if you know anyone.
Speaker 1: don't engage with any coin ever But except like actual real money just because it's a coin But because it feeds into this toxic idea that people who are fans of things Gain, some sort of inherent ownership in the things of which their fans.
Speaker 0: if anyone believes in coin, right?
Speaker 0: Tell them All right, you believe in coins.
Speaker 0: You think they have value?
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: I just made Scott coin.
Speaker 0: you work eight hours a day.
Speaker 0: It's your full-time job.
Speaker 0: I'll pay you in Scott coin.
Speaker 0: Why don't we make Scott coin?
Speaker 0: I mean I could make it right now, but yeah, we could issue.
Speaker 1: we could issue it to the bad the stream and the patreon.
Speaker 0: Sure, everyone you get a billion Scott coins.
Speaker 0: They're worth nothing.
Speaker 1: I'm saying we only issue like six of them.
Speaker 1: Just six why?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: see what happens but anyway things of the day.
Speaker 1: So I found this really cute comic and I think you've probably seen it around.
Speaker 0: people retweet it Hadn't until you tweeted it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's.
Speaker 1: uh, I Seen some of these comics before but now I see where it came from.
Speaker 1: It's just poorly drawn lines They don't.
Speaker 0: they seem not so poorly drawn.
Speaker 1: They're better drawn than anything I could ever draw.
Speaker 1: Sure, but I Don't know.
Speaker 1: This is my type of very simply humor.
Speaker 1: It's like Perry Bible Fellowship adjacent.
Speaker 1: Is how I described this type of humor?
Speaker 0: humor adjacent?
Speaker 1: Yeah All right, just be a crab don't fuck this up.
Speaker 1: I really like this comic and I hope you do too.
Speaker 0: Somebody got.
Speaker 0: oh, so this thing happened like a little while ago.
Speaker 0: It's not the newest news But it's it's actually like continuing to snowball a bit.
Speaker 0: It didn't just stop when it hit its end.
Speaker 0: So late last year some I think some girl somewhere She made his Twitter account called like weezer Africa and she basically just wanted weezer The rock band to cover the song Africa by Toto, you know the song That song so which is a meme ish song.
Speaker 1: well The song is these days the songs really like on the upswing in terms of being used in memes and it's been stuck in my Head for like a year now for some reason.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: No, it's it's a big song in meme land along this day No one seems to live with like ocean man.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and a couple other and sandstorm Anyway, but this person really really really wanted weezer to cover the song and it started a Twitter account Weezer to cover this dedicated solely to this purpose.
Speaker 0: And so and then they started cleverly tweeting they made really clever tweets Trying to encourage weezer to cover the song and then they got followers and then they got like wrecking.
Speaker 0: somehow people discovered this Twitter account that was dedicated to one purpose and one purpose only.
Speaker 0: and Like, you know radio stations, I think some morning shows talked about it or it was written up in some You know local schmo papers and you know, I started to get attention, right?
Speaker 0: And then over time there's only it took like a few months right.
Speaker 0: eventually Like it actually got noticed and weezer Hosted a cover on Spotify of a different song by Toto.
Speaker 1: That was not Africa That is a plus that responds.
Speaker 0: And then they actually did eventually cover.
Speaker 1: Africa looks like weezer finally bless the reins.
Speaker 0: Yes, exactly.
Speaker 0: And now they're going even further.
Speaker 0: they're like performing it somewhere with the guy from Toto on Jimmy Kimmel apparently.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's yesterday, right?
Speaker 0: It's it's like getting bigger and bigger all the time.
Speaker 0: So I didn't find out about it until like maybe a week before They actually did the cover and like I sort of put it out of my mind and it didn't become a thing of today.
Speaker 0: And then it happened and I saw that news and then I forgot about it.
Speaker 0: But the fact that it's still going and like I can't believe it's snowballing.
Speaker 0: It seems like the kind of thing that was like, ah, they covered it the end.
Speaker 0: No, it's not the end It's gonna keep going.
Speaker 0: What other song will they cover next?
Speaker 0: I feel like who else will attempt to make a Twitter account with one Small dedicated purpose and fail because this is the only person who can ever do it and have it be a thing.
Speaker 0: It'll hit the peak when Rick Astley maybe in like ten years someone else can try this again when everyone's forgotten about this and try to make someone do something with a one Twitter account or whatever it is.
Speaker 0: in ten years.
Speaker 1: The two possible peaks for this are either Rick Astley covers Africa or There is a world tour concert of a ton of famous acts and all they do is each cover Africa.
Speaker 0: We should have Toto cover Weezer Ooh Dara Day cover everything and then Dara Day covers everyone else and then everyone else does a sandstorm.
Speaker 1: Is Toto even like still around?
Speaker 1: I guess they're still around.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 1: Like.
Speaker 1: I don't know what bands are alive or dead or like.
Speaker 0: If you live in New York City, meta moment All right, so into the meta moments All right.
Speaker 0: So this Saturday if you live in New York City and you can get on the seven train and go to Queens On Saturday night, there is a free concert Zero dollars.
Speaker 0: You don't even need a fucking ticket You just walk your ass right up and the concert is.
Speaker 0: I can't believe they're still alive, which is why I just thought of it.
Speaker 0: Performers of such great hits as Celebrate Jungle Boogie What really?
Speaker 0: Cool and the gang is for free free concert in Flushing Corona Park this Saturday night.
Speaker 1: Maybe we should go.
Speaker 0: I was gonna go, pike over.
Speaker 1: I might go All right, yeah in the rest of the meta moment We will see you hopefully at all the PAX's that are coming up right now.
Speaker 1: It's summer Just chill time.
Speaker 1: try to make some YouTube videos.
Speaker 1: be warned.
Speaker 1: We're only really making YouTube videos when it rains.
Speaker 1: So if you really want like a lot of Utena episodes to come out in a hurry You got to hope that it rains like every goddamn weekend, but we are continuing the Utena series.
Speaker 1: Geek Nights presents Utena.
Speaker 1: We did put an episode out.
Speaker 1: I'm already doing pre-production for episode 17 Which is an actual non-nanami like good dual episode and Otherwise follow our YouTube stuff and join the Geek Nights forum.
Speaker 1: there's been a slight uptick in forum activity recently as a few people when I say a few like two people but
Speaker 0: Oh honest rim appeared what
Speaker 1: have both expressed that they're used because the Geek Nights forum We had it used to be way bigger and people kind of scattered to the line
Speaker 0: goes up and down and up and down.
Speaker 0: Usually like what will happen is like a listener will come and hang out for a while when they make an account and then go away, yeah, but You're all fucking lurking.
Speaker 0: there's a shit ton of lurkers cuz I can see you.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I can see your numbers at least how many of you.
Speaker 0: there are a lot of you But the people there are people who have to get into the point where you make a habit of keeping it open in a tab And like constantly reloading it like once a day and once you get to that point That's when you're.
Speaker 0: and a lot of people have that habit, but they never post because they're lurkers.
Speaker 0: But then there's other people who have that same habit and also aren't afraid to type Yeah, and we need more of those people cuz that's like 10% of the people.
Speaker 1: one of my favorite things is when someone says something controversial or that might that could clearly cause an argument and you see a little icon that shows like eight people all Simultaneously type.
Speaker 0: it shows you when someone is typing Which is great because a lot of times I'll write a long post and then delete it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, not post it and people hold.
Speaker 0: someone knew that I was typing something.
Speaker 0: Yeah They're waiting for it and I never got posted or I come back later and I write it again.
Speaker 1: But the forums getting at this slight uptick in activity and the sentiment seems to be that Other places people had gone to for their like fandom specific talk have gotten increasingly Toxic for all the same reasons.
Speaker 1: We just talked about what they're talking.
Speaker 0: I think I think this is a general effect and also a summer effect.
Speaker 0: Is that people who have kids around school?
Speaker 0: Well, it's like people who kids are at school.
Speaker 0: People in the summer are going out and doing stuff and not sitting home posting online, right?
Speaker 0: And just in general people who had people were good.
Speaker 0: people have better shit to do than post.
Speaker 0: That like posting an online communities tweeting Facebooking Instagramming.
Speaker 0: None of these things like necessities in life.
Speaker 0: You could just never do any of those things.
Speaker 0: Most people never do any of those things and the benefit of doing those things is actually not that great.
Speaker 0: Well, I just do it because I like doing it.
Speaker 0: Yeah It's the same as well.
Speaker 1: You know the other thing that geek nights used to complain about a lot and we do less now that we live in the city Where these don't exist.
Speaker 1: Homeowners associations the people who run homeowners associations tend to be the worst people with the least to do, right?
Speaker 0: So the people who post online are the worst people who at the least to do.
Speaker 0: And then the people who just really enjoy doing it like us.
Speaker 1: but the fact course we're not the best people but the fact that the geek nights forum has a Higher barrier to entry than most other online community.
Speaker 1: Well, the reason is right is because if you're dumb you get run out of town on the horse.
Speaker 1: He rode in on right obvious reasons.
Speaker 0: number one to become a member you have to be Accepted right?
Speaker 0: you you put an application and you write down a reason for joining and a lot of people I think may have been Valid joiners, but their reason for joining wasn't like.
Speaker 0: some people have written stuff like want to talk about video games And that was probably a real person.
Speaker 0: I've rejected that.
Speaker 0: I'm just like.
Speaker 0: first of all, I can't guarantee you're a real person Yeah and second of all That's not.
Speaker 0: you need to prove to me that like you're a geek nights listener who's actually interested in joining the community So at least a human being right.
Speaker 0: somebody, you know Someone wrote something as simple as like.
Speaker 0: I want to talk to other gig nights listeners.
Speaker 0: That's enough.
Speaker 0: I can tell that this is a real human being who wrote a complete set and Tell us you want to join the ivory tower.
Speaker 0: right, you know something like that where I can tell aha, you know We've maintained a very high.
Speaker 1: like the community like the.
Speaker 1: the activity ebbs and flows But the community is pretty high bar Like you cannot get away with being a shithead in here.
Speaker 1: You get run out of town pretty quick and you get run out of town for by your own shame.
Speaker 1: Very few people have ever been banned from this forum.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: No, it's it's usually just people who are The bad kind of person.
Speaker 0: it's not a comfortable place for them.
Speaker 0: Yeah It's the same way that like land is an uncomfortable place for a fish.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if if you need the if you need toxic misogyny to breathe you can have a lot of trouble breathing in the gig nights for us.
Speaker 1: So, uh, let's talk about Uma Musume.
Speaker 0: All right, so we saw this show first on when we did our judging anime by its cover Which we're gonna do it.
Speaker 0: We're gonna do it again soon.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: Now we've watched some of it.
Speaker 0: I watched one or two episodes that are remember.
Speaker 1: I watched one and a half episodes.
Speaker 1: I saw all I need to see right?
Speaker 0: So what the show is is basically what I thought it was gonna be was like a sports anime where the characters Happen to be girls, but they're horse girls not not like centaurs, but they're like cat girls But they have horse ears and horse tail now already.
Speaker 1: I feel like that was a lost opportunity.
Speaker 1: I was actually kind of disappointed that they were just girls with horse ears anyway And they participate in horse races like Kentucky Derby only Japan.
Speaker 0: Yep, whatever their horse racing equivalent is And they all they go to school for horse racing and that sort of thing.
Speaker 0: So I thought it was gonna be like a sports anime.
Speaker 0: I really like your pedal or high-q.
Speaker 1: I felt it was gonna like.
Speaker 1: I really love it was gonna follow the battle athletes template.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I thought it was gonna be a sports anime.
Speaker 0: only it just happened to be.
Speaker 0: you know The characters happen to be these, you know horse girls and I thought we would learn about horse racing And taking care of horses, but that that characters happen to be this way to appeal to otakus, right?
Speaker 0: And I watched it and I was 50% correct, I'd say at least 50% correct.
Speaker 0: the thing I did not count on was That reveal in the second half of the first episode.
Speaker 1: Is that the show like?
Speaker 0: there's some perversion going on which totally saw that coming?
Speaker 1: Yeah, we'll get back to that.
Speaker 0: That's obvious.
Speaker 1: It's not the kind of perversion I expected and it's arguably way worse.
Speaker 1: Yes, but I expected.
Speaker 0: the thing I did not expect is that it would also be an idol show.
Speaker 0: I dad did not know that at all.
Speaker 0: But apparently the deal is that when you if you win a horse race then you go that horse girl gets to go on stage and perform at their idol song or whatever.
Speaker 0: Even the really quiet horse who's the fastest girl ends up going on stage and singing like without any Cowardice at all.
Speaker 1: So on one hand you can make this like Metanarrative argument that the show is about the dehumanization of the idol like the process of creating idols in modern pop Music production.
Speaker 0: they compete and fight with each other in order for the chance to sing on stage.
Speaker 1: They're commoditized.
Speaker 1: the reward They're given is just being more productive for the company that groomed.
Speaker 1: that like you can make this whole argument.
Speaker 0: But no, it's just for otaku fan service.
Speaker 1: Yeah, this show is so people who want to see cute horse girls interacting in a semi moe.
Speaker 0: semi sports Like half moe is one horse is one horse girl for every different possible personality.
Speaker 0: So there's gonna be your favorite one.
Speaker 1: It's the harem show where there's no self insert character.
Speaker 1: It's just the harem interacting with itself, right?
Speaker 0: The plot is basically like the school has the elite horse racing team and then there's the joke horse racing team.
Speaker 0: And of course the joke one is gonna eventually become the super one.
Speaker 0: And the joke team is basically two joke girls the main character and the best horse racing girl who just Who's like the champion who just quit the good team for some reason.
Speaker 0: and you know when the the new girl is?
Speaker 0: oh my god, she came from the you know, the the What's it called the sticks and she took the train into the city of Tokyo for the first time.
Speaker 0: just like every other anime She doesn't know how to use the subway Transfer student and oh my god now she's moved to the big city.
Speaker 0: She's a horse from the country right obvious main character.
Speaker 0: but the the main What's it called?
Speaker 0: Hey, whatever.
Speaker 0: No, the one is the super fast horse girl.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah the one who's like the number one most popular horse.
Speaker 0: Yeah, she's like all super quiet this one.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and there's like a mystery of why silent Suzuka, right?
Speaker 0: Why did she quit the super team to come to the joke team?
Speaker 1: There's probably a plot there.
Speaker 0: I'm not gonna watch much more of this But when it when the the main character comes to the city for the first time she randomly encounters some pervy, dude This is the part that bothers me the show.
Speaker 0: I mean she takes him in the face like a horse and he doesn't die though.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it looked like he did it first.
Speaker 0: Oh, she can run super fast cuz she's a horse, but it looks like a girl except for the tails and ear.
Speaker 1: Well, so we got to talk a little bit about the conceit of the show because the conceit of the show is our real life.
Speaker 1: Universe exists and the souls of horses from our universe get transferred Randomly as far as we can tell Into pregnant women in this other mirror universe.
Speaker 1: that is the same as our universe Except all horses are just horse girls.
Speaker 0: I thought that it was there.
Speaker 0: My mom fucked a horse.
Speaker 1: Yeah, didn't you watch the?
Speaker 1: the intro explains this?
Speaker 0: No, I did not.
Speaker 1: Yeah souls of horses end up from our world end up in this world like that's it.
Speaker 1: they just get right past that.
Speaker 0: Also the all the horse characters have names that are similar to the kinds of names that race horses have.
Speaker 1: I saw most actual names of race horses from really what's her name like special week.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they're all real horses, which means I Hope that both of these nuts is gonna show up be the real main character and like that isn't far.
Speaker 0: both of these nuts Both of these nuts appears in a movie.
Speaker 0: somebody let me know and I will start watching again.
Speaker 1: No, it does a lot of cute things right like when the girls use a phone They like hold the earpiece up to their real ear and then they like bring it down to talk like it solved the problem Of why is that cat girl holding a cell phone next to the side of her head instead of her ear?
Speaker 1: but What bothers me and the main reason I'm not gonna watch the rest of the show at all other than the fact that it's kind of just dumb yeah is that It wasn't perverted in the ways.
Speaker 1: I expected it wasn't just like that low-key fanservice you get from these.
Speaker 0: I think there is some horses with big boobs or yeah sexy legs or whatever.
Speaker 1: I kind of expected that to be the level of like creepy fanservice But it wasn't.
Speaker 1: the creepy part was that we're introduced to this character who's an important recurring character who?
Speaker 1: straight up assaults the main character in Episode one like multiple times and that is already normalized in the show as well.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's a horse girl.
Speaker 1: You got to like check out her whatever.
Speaker 0: you got a groper legs yeah, see how strong she is and then person to me become is like the coach of the crappy team and Somehow is obviously some sort of genius who's gonna help them all win.
Speaker 1: Yeah His strategies that character should not still be in the show and suddenly all the.
Speaker 0: but they totally trust him even though He just groped them yeah multiple times in the first episode Like the narrative around that character, and they don't resolve it in any way.
Speaker 0: It's just like what we trust him now.
Speaker 0: I guess he's our coach.
Speaker 0: He's gonna help us win.
Speaker 1: if that scene in the first episode had instead been He died when he was kicked and we never hear of that again.
Speaker 1: That would have been fine, but the fact that he is an important character that his relationship with all these girls.
Speaker 1: That alone is actually a reason to just not watch this show as we agree.
Speaker 1: like I'm not gonna watch any more of the show I watched enough to be able to review it.
Speaker 1: It's light-hearted Generic anime high production value.
Speaker 1: look at all these girls that are acting in a school.
Speaker 0: There's also tons of like music because they sing whenever someone wins a race.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's really well animated like everything about.
Speaker 1: it's beautiful.
Speaker 0: It's really colorful because yeah I do appreciate like.
Speaker 1: it is really really colorful, and there's a lot of characters, and it's pretty typical anime.
Speaker 1: But I can't say that I recommend it to anyone to actually watch.
Speaker 0: if you're an otaku who likes idols and shit and doesn't mind Some you know all these girls getting groped by this dude, and oh you know only being mad once.
Speaker 0: yep
Speaker 1: Like I don't the fact that they just let that go and don't bring it up again Not cool, then
Speaker 0: you can watch this show if you're you know if you're the kind of otaku who will buy a body pillow unironically and have it in your bed and the shows the shows for you.
Speaker 1: or I guess if you're On the other side of the coin you can just watch Monstume or Sume and get like an actual centaur.
Speaker 1: Yeah, go full go.
Speaker 1: if you're gonna go horse anyway Why don't I go all the way just have like a giant centaur?
Speaker 0: if they were centaurs the show would be better.
Speaker 1: because yeah Well, then when she kicked that dude He would have actually died and that would have been the end of that stupid arc.
Speaker 0: if a horse kicks you you'll probably die.
Speaker 0: Yeah I Think that there's one nice scene where it's like.
Speaker 0: she's at the train station And she's like one.
Speaker 0: she got off this train too early or late like a station away from her.
Speaker 0: She's just like no I'll just run and she just runs to the next station faster than all the cars cuz she's a horse.
Speaker 1: that's one thing I do appreciate though.
Speaker 1: the show is very married to its core conceits and Little kind of like my little pony actually did this to very small details That relate to those things.
Speaker 1: like their horses they run whatever are Appropriate and always right.
Speaker 1: like the consistency of the treatment of those little world details is extreme to the point that the Kanji for the word horse in the show is Basically the real kanji for the word horse except it removed like two of the legs Like little details like that.
Speaker 1: I really appreciate when a show has this almost slavish consistency on these really dumb minor points But otherwise, I don't think the show is actually worth watching and I don't think anyone should really bother watching it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if you want to watch a sports show you can watch you a pedal where the last episode that I saw Basically, they spent the it was they were 50 minutes from the finish line of the second day of a three-day race and at the End of the episode they had still not crossed the finish line But they had done flashbacks of the three characters who could possibly cross that finish line first.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean initial D for all I love it.
Speaker 1: It's a bunch of non race episodes and then an episode that's getting ready for the race.
Speaker 0: Well the problem in initial D you're racing a bunch of different people in the separate races and your pedal It's pretty much there.
Speaker 0: There's all these other races, but they only care about this inter high race for every high school in Japan races against each other.
Speaker 0: They don't care about any other race.
Speaker 0: So it's pretty much.
Speaker 0: there'll be a few episodes like half a season of you know Characters developing and setting up and then the rest of the show for another season and a half is just the race and then They do it again three times cuz high school is three years.
Speaker 1: No Yep easy anime review.
Speaker 1: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Speaker 0: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 1: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 0: But unlike those other late shows It's actually recorded at night in the patreon.
Speaker 1: patreons for this episode of geek nights are in order the amount of money They give us on a continuing mazes Craig Oliver Alan Joyce Rebecca Dunn hiding me Nicholas shimmering Ruby obelisk hanging in the sky my stadium.
Speaker 1: calm Jeremy minor link Eiji Roberto Kingsley Kelly Snyder cold guy Amanda Duchette Shawn Yeager Matthew Smith Nicholas Brandau mr.
Speaker 1: Strong distraction for two one creations.
Speaker 1: No I never ever wonder why we're here.
Speaker 1: semper fi bitch sure front horrell Rory James David white Rochelle, Monta.
Speaker 1: No, no Superboy tripwire sailor Vista.
Speaker 1: Don't you like?
Speaker 1: short option Joshua Joe star Clinton Walton Ren from New Zealand Ryan parent drew open ladder.
Speaker 1: Finn Chris midgift Daniel Redmond Sean Klein Chris Reimer and Thomas Hahn.
Speaker 1: uh Yeah, like I said, you want to watch horse animates either this or monster who?
Speaker 1: super hey, and now I leave you with.
Speaker 1: I hear the drums are going tonight But she hears only whispers of some quiet conversation.
Speaker 1: She's coming in 1230 flight.
Speaker 1: The moment wings reflect the stars that guide me towards salvation.
Speaker 1: I stopped an old man along the way open to find some old forgotten words.
Speaker 1: He turned to me as if to say Do Let it take some time to do the things we never had.