Speaker 0: It's Tuesday July 17th 2018.
Speaker 0: I'm rim.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott and this is geek nights tonight.
Speaker 0: We're talking about PUBG player unknowns Battlegrounds.
Speaker 0: because we are in no way late to this party Let's do this.
Speaker 0: The kids got to understand that the older you get the later you're going to be to every party.
Speaker 1: No, you just don't get time for that action.
Speaker 1: Yeah, even counter-strike.
Speaker 1: I didn't play till beta Eight something like that six.
Speaker 1: I don't even know.
Speaker 1: so I started.
Speaker 1: somebody was playing counter-strike before me.
Speaker 0: I was playing counter-strike before the p90 but not that long before the p90.
Speaker 1: Playing it before the UM for sure.
Speaker 0: I remember when they added the p90.
Speaker 1: remember when they added the UM.
Speaker 0: And then I remember when the p90 was ridiculously overpowered.
Speaker 1: Remember that also cuz p90 was my favorite.
Speaker 0: It was a good time that p90.
Speaker 0: I remember those days.
Speaker 0: Those are good days.
Speaker 1: 90 is like the number one gun of you know gun fetish fanboys.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's I mean gunslinger girls.
Speaker 1: I think whenever I see like some, you know, like especially yeah, especially anime but like it is any sort of military fanboy stuff It's always p90.
Speaker 0: It's always that bullpup.
Speaker 0: You know the one from counter-strike the.
Speaker 0: oh god, I remember what was called the stair hog.
Speaker 1: It's either.
Speaker 1: you can get an aug and pub G in a crate.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I've seen one.
Speaker 0: I've never.
Speaker 0: I've never got.
Speaker 1: I let the other guy have it cuz there's no point in me taking it.
Speaker 0: I usually get the scar like that's the weapon I end up using the most.
Speaker 1: I actually rarely see that.
Speaker 0: I find it a lot.
Speaker 0: It's not great I don't like it, but I end up with it a lot to the point that I think about it.
Speaker 0: Hmm last time I saw it.
Speaker 0: I looked at it.
Speaker 0: I was like, yeah, you know what?
Speaker 0: Nah Nah, I'll pick up the shotgun instead and that let me tell you that worked.
Speaker 0: Not at all.
Speaker 0: No fuck shotgun shotguns are worth.
Speaker 0: Anyway, that's the main vid when we talk about the fact that we're playing pub G but we got some news cuz it's Tuesday All right, so Mario tennis is out and it's guy.
Speaker 1: it's not.
Speaker 1: it's got some problems.
Speaker 0: Yeah, this is this is the second weakest Mario tennis offering from Nintendo.
Speaker 1: so it has a lot of it's like it's.
Speaker 1: it's better than the.
Speaker 1: it's not.
Speaker 1: it is Mario tennis Right, but there's a lot of not the bullshit DS one is real.
Speaker 1: There's a lot of things they messed up.
Speaker 1: I'm sure we'll review it at some point.
Speaker 1: But so I'll just talk about the news here the news being that they are going to actually update it and they're gonna nerf Bowser Jr.
Speaker 1: Who is Opie?
Speaker 1: Yep, and they're gonna adjust the way the trick shot works is right now.
Speaker 1: You can basically just keep trick shotting over and over always return the ball no matter what
Speaker 0: with a trick shot no matter what and that
Speaker 1: will fill up your charge meter to max and then you can use the power shot and then Contend and repeat using the trick shot again, and that's pretty much the strategy for winning.
Speaker 1: It's similar to snaking in Mario Kart Basically the exact same problem.
Speaker 0: It's not fun like trick shots are not that fun?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't really like them.
Speaker 1: actually you can play in the mode that has no meter and it removes the trick shot And I actually kind of feel like the thing is.
Speaker 1: the problem with that mode that I found is that it Chainchomp and certain characters are actually more powerful because without some sort of super shot or zone shot It's like they can almost always get to the ball and return it Yeah, and you know with with relative ease, but
Speaker 0: the trouble is and I even ran into this I haven't even played Kid Koopa because it's money even though he's like my character.
Speaker 0: I love the shit out of that kid.
Speaker 0: I don't like him being in the stupid clown car like I don't like the aesthetic so I ended up playing Rosalina instead.
Speaker 1: I play As you do who is also an OP character with these nasty hooks and shit.
Speaker 1: Yeah, which has always been the case in Mario Tennis.
Speaker 1: I still feel even in Mario Tennis for n64 boo is like tricky and he would.
Speaker 1: he hits the ball It curbs like a motherfucker.
Speaker 0: I do miss Older.
Speaker 0: Mario tennis is though like I just play older Mario.
Speaker 0: I feel like as our friend group.
Speaker 0: That's probably what we should do.
Speaker 1: I have it.
Speaker 1: We can just play at any time.
Speaker 0: But yeah, this is interesting for a bunch of reasons.
Speaker 0: so one obviously the game needed to be nerfed like that.
Speaker 0: like there's problems with the game's core design, but Why didn't Nintendo pick up on that before they released the game?
Speaker 1: This game is.
Speaker 1: you can just sort of tell that it was obviously released too soon.
Speaker 0: They sort of rushed it out, which is missing textures and all this.
Speaker 1: It's very unlike Nintendo to put out a product like this.
Speaker 0: I mean when we played that preview like it really didn't feel good.
Speaker 0: No had problems and like the netcode doesn't really work like playing multiplayer.
Speaker 1: I wouldn't have bought it, but I Pre-ordered it and forgot.
Speaker 1: Well, I pre-ordered.
Speaker 1: the reason I bought it was because You know that the demo even though it had some problems I wasn't gonna play online.
Speaker 1: those are online problems.
Speaker 1: Mostly I was like, oh well, the tennis part is still good I'm gonna play this locally so I don't care.
Speaker 1: and then when I actually got it I found out you couldn't even play like actual tennis.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so we'll talk about a full review.
Speaker 0: But the other problems with the game aside from the fact that Nintendo Clearly didn't play test this with anyone who tried to be good at the game at all.
Speaker 0: This isn't like overwatch or like someone figures out a very difficult strategy.
Speaker 0: It becomes the new meta over time.
Speaker 0: This was like day one.
Speaker 0: you can just snake and it's invincible and if you don't snake you lose.
Speaker 0: but aside from that like you can't actually play real Matches of tennis you
Speaker 1: can either play like this sort of tiebreaker only quick man Like
Speaker 0: not even normal tennis card
Speaker 1: or you can basically play this one set match where it's like you get two games And then you win it.
Speaker 1: Play like you can't play like a five-set match and like feel the other player out and anything like that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like it's really actually not fun and shit.
Speaker 0: as much as that seems like a really like minor point it actually really Really makes playing local multiplayer not fun.
Speaker 1: if I had known you couldn't play like five sets I thought I would even question that like.
Speaker 1: oh, of course, it's Mario tennis.
Speaker 1: You can be able to play a match of tennis.
Speaker 1: if I would have known you couldn't play a match of tennis I wouldn't have bought it.
Speaker 1: Yep, but there was no way to know that but I could.
Speaker 1: I guess I could have waited one day instead of pre-ordering.
Speaker 1: I could have waited a day and then bought it.
Speaker 0: Yep I too was over optimistic.
Speaker 1: I was just inconceivable that you would not be able to play a tennis match.
Speaker 1: Yeah That's like if you bought a racing game and it only had one lap races and you couldn't do a three-lap race.
Speaker 1: It's like Nintendo.
Speaker 1: It's like you wouldn't be conceivable that that would be me.
Speaker 0: You also can't pick the map Yeah, but I guess I assumed that Nintendo would have the problems.
Speaker 0: They always have meaning Online play is garbage.
Speaker 0: never do it.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm, and there'd be some like single-player mode.
Speaker 0: I won't care about and those things were true.
Speaker 0: But on top of that like nothing else really works.
Speaker 1: That's the only thing it's like.
Speaker 1: I actually like the single-player mode in old Mario tennis is because it was literally just play tennis against the computer into as and learn and get better at playing tennis until you Can beat the hardest AI?
Speaker 1: Whereas now the single-player mode is like this adventure with all these garbage Challenges in it that are annoying as fuck and I quit after like yeah one try like.
Speaker 0: I guess Ostensibly they make you because the the real skill in the game as it is today is one You have to trick shot literally every shot But two you have to return Fancy shots with frame per semi frame perfect timing like this very particular timing and you have to get really good at that.
Speaker 0: But all the single-player doesn't really make you good at that.
Speaker 0: It makes you good at that in these weird contrived situations and there isn't really a good single-player against just like normal tennis and The hardest AI in some very very short games and just play lots of them But that's not fun.
Speaker 0: and then or playing local multiplayer.
Speaker 0: Also was actually really hard to make work like we had a lot of trouble getting the right controllers and Nintendo really just was sloppy in this game to a degree that I'm not pre-ordering any more first-party game.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna wait one day.
Speaker 1: Yeah, at least Except for Metroid Prime for this.
Speaker 1: That's a shoe it.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna wait.
Speaker 0: How could measure it Brian for not be a shoe I'm gonna let you play it for a few days.
Speaker 0: Let me see what you say.
Speaker 1: Just be Metroid Prime.
Speaker 0: I'm not.
Speaker 0: I'm a little worried about this.
Speaker 1: You didn't play the other Metroid Prime's.
Speaker 1: No Somebody.
Speaker 1: well, you don't need to play the new one.
Speaker 0: Yeah, maybe maybe the new one.
Speaker 1: Why would you play one?
Speaker 1: You haven't played the other one?
Speaker 1: Why not?
Speaker 0: This might be better.
Speaker 0: I mean, I skipped a whole bunch of Zelda's and then I played Breath of the Wild.
Speaker 0: It was great.
Speaker 0: I don't feel like I need to play Skyward Sword.
Speaker 1: No, but well think about this.
Speaker 1: You're like, oh I played Breath of the Wild It was great.
Speaker 1: Yeah, guess what?
Speaker 1: You missed out on a whole bunch of great.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean I didn't even finish Twilight Princess cuz I got bored about a third of the way through.
Speaker 1: I mean, it wasn't as great but it wasn't that good wasn't that fun.
Speaker 1: It's still good.
Speaker 0: Yeah The fact that I got bored during it was enough to tell me that it wasn't for me.
Speaker 0: Hmm Breath of the Wild I feel like I'm gonna play again.
Speaker 0: Anyway, Mario attendance is a lot of problems.
Speaker 0: Nintendo didn't like play tested.
Speaker 1: They've missed.
Speaker 1: I've been talking about too much Mario tennis.
Speaker 1: Let's obvious issues and we still get we'll do an episode of Mario tennis.
Speaker 1: Yeah, stop talking about Mario tennis.
Speaker 0: So jack box party pack five.
Speaker 1: It's coming.
Speaker 1: There's still.
Speaker 1: they're gonna make it and so far They've revealed one of the games is gonna be in it.
Speaker 1: It's a rapping game and the way it works Is this you put in a word any freaking word you want and then it puts your word that you chose at the end of?
Speaker 1: A rap phrase that it is generated by the game.
Speaker 1: And then you must then enter an entire rap phrase that rhymes with the last word of your new rap phrase That you write in entirety must rhyme with the single word that was put at the end of a random previous phrase.
Speaker 1: I'm feeling that I like the box games and then a text-to-speech thing does the rap in a hilarious way.
Speaker 1: And then I think there's some sort of voting on whose is the best or whatever because originally like.
Speaker 0: there's a bunch of different ways To play these jack box games and obviously half of the party fat games are just garbage.
Speaker 0: Yes, but the ones that are good?
Speaker 0: It seems like you're paying for what you're.
Speaker 1: they're basically throwing darts at the wall and you're buying all the darts and half of them Hit.
Speaker 0: yep.
Speaker 0: but the ones that are the most fun seems are the ones like this where they basically are in enough context and prompting to make a Situation that is both competitive but more importantly is just an excuse for you to be funny with all your friends Mm-hmm, and it guides your less funny friends into being more funny.
Speaker 0: I feel like this rap battle is gonna be right in the same feel as TKO, which is still the pinnacle of jack box.
Speaker 0: See I'll probably just buy it.
Speaker 0: I just buy every jack box game.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: So overwatch league playoffs weren't just on the internet.
Speaker 0: They're also on something called Disney XD.
Speaker 1: That's a the Disney Channel that shows cartoons and shit.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I guess I didn't actually know that existed.
Speaker 1: still That's where this Disney Channel and then this Disney XD.
Speaker 1: It's a cable channel where they show cartoons.
Speaker 1: I'm sure that is where Gravity Falls was aired.
Speaker 0: Oh, wow As far as I knew Gravity Falls was aired on this pirate ship.
Speaker 0: Gravity Falls and overwatch league are on the same channel Yeah, which is weird, but the interesting news here is that the overwatch league playoffs?
Speaker 0: we're just on Disney XD and They got a shit ton of people watch it.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm like What was the number?
Speaker 1: is the highest ratings for Disney XD?
Speaker 0: 127,000 viewers.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: That's like the numbers you see on Twitch.
Speaker 0: Yeah, Twitch had about a hundred thousand users.
Speaker 0: What's interesting is that as far as I can tell I read a bunch of like other people talking about this because I didn't even I had no idea until this news that they put this on TV.
Speaker 1: Anyway, I didn't either.
Speaker 0: and Yeah, apparently that many people watched it there despite there being basically no advertising whatsoever About it being there.
Speaker 1: I mean probably people flipped through the channels and saw overwatch.
Speaker 1: I'm like, holy shit.
Speaker 0: Yeah When is someone gonna be putting like fortnight on a network like this?
Speaker 0: Cuz for tonight is the most popular thing.
Speaker 1: I'm surprised it isn't.
Speaker 0: yeah I'm actually really surprised for tonight could just be on like primetime TV.
Speaker 0: I think at this point probably.
Speaker 0: So I guess there are a lot of kids who just have cable still and will watch eSports on cable Instead of on Twitch for some reason.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: But I am curious about or maybe there's kids who play video games on their Playstations or the switches or whatever and you don't know about.
Speaker 1: they're not twitch YouTube.
Speaker 1: They're still.
Speaker 1: they're not technically advanced.
Speaker 0: You know, it could be like they don't even Brandon even have a PC.
Speaker 1: They might they.
Speaker 0: maybe you have a phone or a tablet only it might be the demo like it might like.
Speaker 0: look at the demographic of people who go to Mid-tier local conventions like they don't know that PAX even exists.
Speaker 0: They go to a local gaming con and that's it.
Speaker 0: So if like a game studio goes to that gaming con and does a panel that is like like they would never encounter that Otherwise, even though it's just literally streaming on Twitch somewhere.
Speaker 0: So maybe it's that this is fascinating That there that this demographic exists in numbers that it does it.
Speaker 0: I I greatly underestimated the demand for eSports on cable Especially on Disney XD.
Speaker 0: So in some other news Trogdor is a fantastic thing.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: Like I want to make that very clear.
Speaker 1: It burninates the countryside.
Speaker 1: We've been fans those horrible peasants and cottages.
Speaker 0: I mean we Scott and I. it's not an exaggeration to say that we were literally fans of Trogdor from his inception.
Speaker 1: Yes, I saw Trogdor the day he was released to the internet.
Speaker 1: We were already.
Speaker 1: I was burninated.
Speaker 0: We were already pretty deep into the brothers chaps fandom well before Trogdor existed, correct?
Speaker 0: So this Kickstarter game is legit like Homestar runners actually had a pretty big Renaissance if you haven't been paying attention trying hard Yeah, but it's kind of working.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like a little bit a little bit they have maintained a pretty sizable fandom Despite the fact that the type of humor that was originally homestar runner was from a much earlier time.
Speaker 0: I mean, I don't still why I don't watch any new homestar runner No, but I still strong bet on Twitter, but I watch like a while.
Speaker 0: actually a few weeks ago I ended up watching the uku lele.
Speaker 0: Okay, like I just watched an old home star runner and it was about.
Speaker 0: in terms of modern comedy sensibilities It was basically on the level of hey So it's still there.
Speaker 0: But they make it a tabletop game.
Speaker 1: is Trogdor the board game and basically this board games on Kickstarter?
Speaker 1: You can pre-order it and get either the wooden meeples or the plastic miniatures Like way over double its goal.
Speaker 1: Yeah going up and the game seems mediocre.
Speaker 1: It's a game where Basically, you're cut.
Speaker 1: What's a cop game?
Speaker 1: you take turns controlling Trogdor the burninator trying to burninate the peasants and the Thatcher of cottages and all the tiles on the board.
Speaker 1: and Meanwhile, there's some I guess AI Controlled nights who and peasants who make things less burninated.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and it's co-op.
Speaker 0: I like how there's a peasant meeple and then there's a fire thing to put on the peasant.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So it's like the theme and the end of this game is high.
Speaker 1: Larry is and great.
Speaker 1: the actual game does not appear to be Good, so there's no reason to buy it or play it.
Speaker 1: Don't laugh at the video of it and you're good to go.
Speaker 0: I guess board games are now on the level of like when all the great graphics literally no gameplay era of Pretty much has been going on for like a couple years now already at least.
Speaker 0: but the Ghostbusters Kickstarter game fruit was like the real Genesis of this even before then.
Speaker 1: but like people now especially Kickstarter There's a big you know faction of the board game community, especially online where they really like their board game collectors.
Speaker 1: They care about miniatures.
Speaker 1: They care about the quality of the cardboard and you know, they're putting shit in sleeves.
Speaker 1: It's like.
Speaker 1: but more importantly, you know, maybe they do play games But they actually aren't super deep into playing games and game mechanics and winning in competition.
Speaker 0: Well, there's a parallel thing going on that I've been reading a lot about around how a huge percentage of people who buy tabletop Games today in this like niche extended market core market like not mass market.
Speaker 0: We're not talking about that I'm monopoly.
Speaker 0: but a huge percentage of even people who do care about game mechanics buy games and Literally never bring them to the table.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: And there's a lot of reasons why we even did a packs pen a lot at one.
Speaker 1: I have one game on my shelf.
Speaker 1: I haven't played.
Speaker 0: I At one point bought a copy of castles of burgundy because it was on super sale.
Speaker 0: only to discover That not only did I already own castles of burgundy, but it was still in its shrink-wrap in my closet.
Speaker 0: So if anyone wants a copy of castles of burgundy, I accidentally bought another one.
Speaker 0: I so this is a thing.
Speaker 0: but the confluence of people don't actually get games to the table.
Speaker 0: that often and People want to collect makes a perfect storm of games with literally garbage game mechanics.
Speaker 1: and it does not matter Tons and tons of games coming out these days that are just all you know.
Speaker 1: physical physically fancy But don't have much game going on because that's the hard part.
Speaker 1: It's like if you told me Scott make a board game But what matters most is the fancy pieces and the rules don't matter.
Speaker 1: I'd be like what roll and move and let's make some fancy miniatures.
Speaker 0: We're gonna have like a four pound like Lead-filled pewter miniature of the Baron Harkonnen, right?
Speaker 1: It's good.
Speaker 1: It's so easy.
Speaker 1: It's it's a piece of cake.
Speaker 1: right now It's like I'll get make a game.
Speaker 1: That's actually good.
Speaker 0: Yeah, this game comes with an entire Wooden ship.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like oh, yeah.
Speaker 1: It's like it's easy to make game.
Speaker 1: that is physically.
Speaker 0: what's the game?
Speaker 0: It's basically just mousetrap.
Speaker 1: So there's a lot of games like that out these days and there's a lot of people are into that and I feel like they're You know, even though they're in the same Community space they're actually completely have nothing in common with people.
Speaker 0: actually There's a really there's a neat way to tell these games and like to tell this demographic Cuz there's games you see at packs that are demoed a lot But you very much the hard one or the music card one.
Speaker 0: Oh god With the machine I care so little about that game that I'd literally the one the harmonics made.
Speaker 1: Yeah, honestly, that was the omega-thon final those garbage that was drop mix.
Speaker 0: Yep drop mix was the Megathon finale in packs history No game, but all kinds of fancy shit is the only packs omega-thon finale that was worse than that one was the one that actually Failed.
Speaker 0: Yep, even though that one would have been good if it hadn't failed, but it failed.
Speaker 0: so it failed.
Speaker 0: It was the worst one, but you see games like this.
Speaker 0: You know, I always get back to that Ghostbusters game But I'm not even gonna bother using that as the example anymore because there's so many games like it.
Speaker 0: But you can tell because they have a big Kickstarter.
Speaker 0: They have tons of sales a lot of people know about the game and the games are very highly reviewed But you literally never see them on the table at a PAX.
Speaker 1: Well, just look on the shelf at the game store and you can see all these fancy schmancy games and stuff.
Speaker 1: But it's like the games.
Speaker 1: they actually get played a lot All right, you know back in the olden days or olden days.
Speaker 1: Yeah It's like people play fucking settlers in Carcassonne and take it to ride which are way way way less fancy But get played a lot lot lot more.
Speaker 0: Yep But I do feel like part of this is a response to the fact that I hate to say this.
Speaker 0: the tabletop Market is pretty saturated already and the rate of games being released both from Indies and big publishers is only accelerating and the skill game space is definitely like Super-saturated right now and the euros are super saturated.
Speaker 0: This space of collect games that are primarily aimed at collectors and IP is probably way easier to grow For a lot of reasons,
Speaker 1: I mean, you know, they're making what sells
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I feel like these are selling - they're you're actually
Speaker 1: play games don't buy a lot of games.
Speaker 1: They buy a few games and play them.
Speaker 0: There are some people who play games and buy a lot of games.
Speaker 1: some Yeah, but not many.
Speaker 1: not enough to build a business around.
Speaker 0: Yeah, definitely not.
Speaker 0: But anyway things of the day.
Speaker 0: so I Am actually a big fan of the American national anthem, but not for reasons you'd think no, it's awful.
Speaker 0: I like it because it's awful.
Speaker 0: Okay, kind of like imagine a Sci-fi or a fantasy world where there's like some Byzantine style Archaic Ancient civilization that has like traditions and weird stuff.
Speaker 0: They go beyond memory and beyond recorded history and they have weird old rituals that no one knows where they came from.
Speaker 0: I feel like singing the American national anthem is gonna be that if America survives another thousand years.
Speaker 0: Our national anthem is fucking awful.
Speaker 0: The lyrics are awful.
Speaker 0: If you get past the first verse they get pretty fucking racist.
Speaker 1: No one sings that part because no one knows it But it keeps going after the part that people sing and it's it's not good and it's racist.
Speaker 0: past that part Yep, it's racist and it has other problems.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 0: Also if you know anything about music It's weird and it's really hard to sing.
Speaker 1: Right?
Speaker 1: Well, they shoehorn some poem that was not musical into a song Yep, but also the way it wasn't like.
Speaker 1: they had a song and then wrote lyrics.
Speaker 1: They had lyrics that were whatever and they refused to change those at all.
Speaker 0: So in high school, I used to do a lot of arrangement just like I used to arrange songs like partly sometimes for money Sometimes for class whatever.
Speaker 0: but when you're arranging songs for people to sing not even just writing them Just arranging them like writing the parts.
Speaker 0: However, you're gonna do it.
Speaker 0: You take into account that most humans sing in a set range of notes And not many people can sing outside of those ranges.
Speaker 0: Well, and you fatigue people who try to sing outside of those ranges.
Speaker 0: You don't generally write a vocal part that crosses all these ranges.
Speaker 1: I mean you might do that If you're know that.
Speaker 1: gaha, I'm writing this song for a such-and-such singer who has a mad range.
Speaker 1: I think I can make this song balls out and you say oh I'm writing this song.
Speaker 0: The US national anthem is like the opera and the fifth element like normal humans cannot fucking sing this song.
Speaker 0: no, and even worse even if you like have a decent range.
Speaker 0: if you're not a You're asked to sing the national anthem at like your high school sports ball game.
Speaker 0: Unless you're a like trained musician as opposed to someone who knows how to sing You'll even make a mistake of.
Speaker 0: you'll start to sing in your national register.
Speaker 0: Oh say like that that'll already start you too high to have a chance of hitting those later.
Speaker 1: You'll notice a lot.
Speaker 1: if you go to like baseball games or you know at big stadiums or things like that Where there's people singing they start low.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you gotta start low start lower than your.
Speaker 0: But anyway to not belabor the point this video in very good detail explains why It is so hard to sing why so many people forget the lyrics.
Speaker 0: it has a compilation of some of the most amazing Fails in the history of people singing the national anthem and it's just a great video.
Speaker 0: I love the fact that our national anthem is so utterly representative of how archaic and fucked up our government is and I'll take control of the government.
Speaker 1: You can change the national anthem.
Speaker 0: I feel like we can only change the national anthem if we fix our government by Fundamentally restructuring it and I feel like our penance is that we got to keep this thing as long as our government works the way It does.
Speaker 1: but also I can changing.
Speaker 1: it doesn't seem to be an issue.
Speaker 1: We can change it when you change the daily savings.
Speaker 0: But I do like the idea that it's almost like this test like can The Lord who's going to take over the space whatever in the future?
Speaker 0: they have to pass the archaic test of singing the ancient song.
Speaker 0: So do you got for me?
Speaker 1: so they tore different home is happening right now You know, even though I like bicycling watching bicycle racing is Not super exciting because it's like, okay, it's people bicycle Whatever But it's still cool, you know, because it's basically bicycling.
Speaker 1: But yeah, because the Tour de France that basically bike everywhere in France.
Speaker 1: it's crazy how far they bike and how high they bike.
Speaker 1: it's it's insane.
Speaker 1: and Since you're biking everywhere You're just biking on the fucking road mountain roads here past a farm there and in a city here like random person Just hanging out picnicking and like watches you go by.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know, so, you know things can happen.
Speaker 1: It's not like there's a wall around all the roads in France while this race happens.
Speaker 1: so somebody and this is not the first person to do this, but I think it's the first person to do at the Tour de France and I think someone else did at a different bike race And I think it was toward it polone.
Speaker 1: But anyway, I saw it on YouTube here this person while the Tour de France Peloton is going by this road They come down the hill on a mountain bike and jump over the Tour de France.
Speaker 0: Now I will point something out as a mountain biker.
Speaker 0: This is Probably I mean, I don't know exactly what I'm sure they practiced it and set it up and everything.
Speaker 0: This is actually way less dangerous than you might expect assuming the person doing it knows what they're doing.
Speaker 1: Right the person.
Speaker 1: if the person practiced they knew they could make this jump.
Speaker 1: they'd done it before They knew they would clear over the the riders.
Speaker 0: cuz on a mountain bike like you know, you can do it very consistently.
Speaker 1: It's not like some mega jump where there's you know, like big margins, right?
Speaker 1: It's like if you practice this you're gonna make it Yeah, but if they had fucked up which is still a non-zero chance and gone right into all those You know, that would have been whoo.
Speaker 0: I think the most likely things they would have fucked up would be They would still land in the same place that they landed.
Speaker 0: cuz they're gonna land in the same place no matter what.
Speaker 0: But they would have landed sideways or upside down and killed.
Speaker 0: Well, it's possible.
Speaker 1: they could like if they had hit the brakes and slowed down they could have landed short.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you'd have to be.
Speaker 1: if you practice that much you would not do that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, cuz I'm in the way a mountain bike you basically do the same trail over and over again Like you do it slow and learn it and just like, you know car racing you memorize a true route And you do it consistently and increase your time or decrease your times.
Speaker 0: So this is while this isn't as dangerous as it looks it is still dangerous and you I'm not saying you should do this.
Speaker 1: No, but you can also notice the riders in the tour.
Speaker 1: They don't slow down for shit.
Speaker 1: No, they don't even flinch They just keep on going.
Speaker 0: This is one of those things where because no no harm No foul because no one was hurt.
Speaker 0: This is awesome.
Speaker 0: If someone had gotten hurt other than the person doing the stunts, I would have been way less cool with this totally different news.
Speaker 0: Yeah Things okay, you know in a related thing of the day because there's another video.
Speaker 1: Oh, no, hold this closure.
Speaker 0: If you watch this video, she is fine.
Speaker 0: Like I double checked that the person is not a snuff film.
Speaker 0: This is not a snuff film.
Speaker 0: It very likely Video.
Speaker 0: so this person this was sold to me by FARC as Someone tried to ride over a drawbridge as it was opening.
Speaker 1: That is not the case.
Speaker 0: Well, it technically is the case.
Speaker 0: No, technically the drawbridge is opening.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and this person Attempts to bike over the drawbridge while it's opening.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: That is technically true.
Speaker 0: However, it is not an awesome Blues Brothers moment.
Speaker 0: This person is either drunk or stupid.
Speaker 0: It's really hard to tell.
Speaker 0: I suspect they might actually be both.
Speaker 0: it kind of looks like they were looking at their phone But basically they buy they bump into the guard arm that is down telling you yo don't go over this Bridge, it looks like they clearly intentionally go between them.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but they mess up and hit them on the way.
Speaker 0: Yeah And then they just turn sideways and literally just bike into this hole and disappear The hole that the drawbridge is about to crush.
Speaker 1: Yeah not not the.
Speaker 1: not the hole in between the two pieces of road and not the cool part one at the bottom where that's because The road is lifting up.
Speaker 1: It's like at the bottom of the lifting road a space is appearing and they go into that space and then they slowly Sink into it and then you don't see what happens after that.
Speaker 0: well if you want so the video is really long.
Speaker 0: but basically eventually you see a bunch of people walk over and be like whoa, and slowly help the person out of the hole.
Speaker 0: the Drawbridges like this usually have a human controlling them.
Speaker 0: Like there's usually a tower nearby.
Speaker 1: Yeah, this is some automatic thing.
Speaker 1: That's like on a schedule, right?
Speaker 1: It's just there's a human being who's like sitting in the tower opening the thing.
Speaker 0: The only reason this person is fine is that the person who controlled the bridge saw them bike into it and Basically hit a button to stop the bridge from moving Which actually was seemed to lift up enough for the boat to get through.
Speaker 0: Yeah, which is real lucky because I Could imagine a situation far worse where the boat is gonna crash into the bridge and the person in the control tower literal trolley problem.
Speaker 1: They had to either kill the person who or let a possibly horrific Accident or a boat to kill someone on the boat probably because boats can't slow down.
Speaker 0: There aren't just boat breaks.
Speaker 0: No So, yeah again I only use this as my second thing of the day because I confirmed that the person was fine.
Speaker 0: She had minor injuries.
Speaker 0: I guess the moral is if you're gonna bike somewhere stupid.
Speaker 1: if a thing comes down and says drawbridge train tracks Do not go stop.
Speaker 1: Stop.
Speaker 1: Oh my god, don't fucking go.
Speaker 0: Oh, no, no.
Speaker 0: more importantly if you're gonna bike somewhere, you're not supposed to bike.
Speaker 0: Practice it Be good at it and commit to it.
Speaker 0: like the person.
Speaker 1: There were no red lights saying Tour de France do not jump.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I will.
Speaker 0: there was a conceptual red light because there is.
Speaker 0: there is a voice of the heavens.
Speaker 0: That's at least saying, you know, it's probably a bad idea what you're about to do jumping over the Tour de France Like do not do this.
Speaker 0: But if you're gonna do this at least commit to it, don't just like derp into a pit and almost die.
Speaker 1: Well, I think the thing is the prisoner jumped over the Tour de France.
Speaker 1: I think they may have spent a night or so in jail.
Speaker 1: I think the person who fell into the drawbridge should have also spent in jail may have spent a night in the hospital.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so don't go to either.
Speaker 0: They're not good places to be Yeah, but if you're gonna go to jail, please do it for something awesome.
Speaker 0: That didn't hurt anyone.
Speaker 0: All right, let's see in the moment Kinetic on which we were not had for the first time in like 10 gods at more than 10 years too many years we.
Speaker 0: So we went to Kinetic on for a decade plus and we ran the entire panels department like this entire goddamn floor For the better part of a decade and we passed the torch.
Speaker 0: We couldn't do it anymore.
Speaker 0: We weren't there this year.
Speaker 1: I still want to go to Hartford as far away.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's a perfectly good summer weekend.
Speaker 0: I got stuff that I do want to return to Kinetic on to do panels again because I actually really like doing panels at Kinetic On but I cannot commit to taking vacation days to doing Kinetic on anymore.
Speaker 0: There's just too many paxes.
Speaker 0: We we do a lot of paxes.
Speaker 0: that really adds up.
Speaker 0: like I can't even deal with pecs dev every year anymore.
Speaker 0: So for the first time in more than 10 years We didn't go to Kinetic on but apparently went fine and we may return to do some panels next year.
Speaker 0: But the next convention we will be performing at will be pax West the real tags the convention Like if if we had to drop every other convention we go to this is the last one we would drop.
Speaker 0: I think the only thing that'll stop us from being at pax West every year is us dying.
Speaker 1: So I'll happen someday.
Speaker 0: We will be there doing a panel.
Speaker 1: We've done will die first rim or pax West?
Speaker 0: I'm pretty sure you're gonna die before me, but I'm not sure if pax will die before.
Speaker 1: I wouldn't bet on that.
Speaker 0: I am confident you will die before me.
Speaker 0: You want to bet you want to put.
Speaker 0: you want to put some money in like in a state escrow?
Speaker 1: Yes, because if I die, I don't give a shit about money.
Speaker 1: So that's the only way I'll lose.
Speaker 1: the bet is if I'm dead you wanna have a time team.
Speaker 0: Put in $1,000.
Speaker 0: whoever dies first the other person gets it and all the interest.
Speaker 1: No, because then I lose $1,000 now while I'm alive.
Speaker 1: you can take that.
Speaker 0: if you're confident Then I'm gonna die before you.
Speaker 0: you're gonna get $1,000 plus a high-yield investment on that.
Speaker 1: No, this bet means I lose $1,000 no matter what I need to basically lose no money.
Speaker 1: And then if I die, I still lose nothing, but if you die, then I get money.
Speaker 1: So what you should do is you should buy life insurance on yourself.
Speaker 0: for me I have a substantial life insurance, but it's not going to you.
Speaker 1: that's not fair.
Speaker 0: if you If you give me $1,000, I will also get.
Speaker 0: I'll get like a million dollars for you too Because I'm confident.
Speaker 0: I'm I'm pretty confident.
Speaker 0: You won't just murder me for the money.
Speaker 1: Mmm a million.
Speaker 0: you say yeah I'm pretty sure you won't murder me for that.
Speaker 0: Mmm pretty confident.
Speaker 0: Also pretty confident you're gonna die before me.
Speaker 1: Anyway, I wouldn't have to go to work though.
Speaker 0: I Am so confident you're gonna die before me.
Speaker 0: Mmm, but I digress.
Speaker 0: anyone who knows anything about poison Let me know at least one of the panels we're doing at pecs West is the 40 tabletop games You must play which we did in the past.
Speaker 0: We've done versions of this and other cons.
Speaker 1: We did it once.
Speaker 0: We've done it twice.
Speaker 1: Oh, no.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but we've tweaked it a few times.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna tweak it a bunch more.
Speaker 0: I got some ideas about it But the reason we're doing it here as a repeat as opposed to doing a brand new panel as much as I wanted to do a brand new panel, maybe we'll still do another brand new panel stay tuned, but We're actually doing this one in the streaming
Speaker 1: theater.
Speaker 1: for oh my god.
Speaker 0: So it's gonna live stream on pecs is twitch.
Speaker 1: We got it.
Speaker 1: We got a very bad time.
Speaker 1: Slides the very first panel on Monday morning.
Speaker 1: Yeah when nobody cares.
Speaker 1: But we're in the official pecs one of the official pecs streaming rooms on one of the two or more.
Speaker 1: I don't know how many pecs streaming twitch channels.
Speaker 0: you will be able to see this panel Only things that stream our main theater and the two big panel room.
Speaker 1: So there's three channels three channels.
Speaker 1: So we're probably on.
Speaker 1: I imagine.
Speaker 1: I think we're pecs - we're on the third channel.
Speaker 0: We're either pecs two or pecs three.
Speaker 1: Okay,
Speaker 0: we'll have details later But that does mean we're gonna up the production value of the panel a little bit and based on the feedback from the last two Times we ran it it will be different in some ways but parts of it are not gonna change because they're perfect.
Speaker 0: Like I'm not gonna take Dune off the list.
Speaker 0: There's a lot to say about Dune.
Speaker 0: so yeah, stay tuned and Otherwise, hopefully we'll see you at pecs unplugged pecs out mag fest.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I put out a new episode of anime judging.
Speaker 0: We judge the summer anime all of it.
Speaker 0: We reviewed it all before it came out.
Speaker 0: So if you want to know what anime to watch I'm pretty sure we're right about all these shows.
Speaker 1: you trust someone with just going based on gut instinct and almost no knowledge.
Speaker 0: I'm actually feeling a lot of the shows like if you watch it minor spoiler.
Speaker 0: We're gonna give a lot of these shows a couple episodes.
Speaker 0: We're gonna watch a few of them More so than we have said.
Speaker 0: we'll watch from any season hither to.
Speaker 1: and the book club book is the Odyssey and I should be Able to finish it by Thursday.
Speaker 1: Yes, the Kindle says I only have like a few hours left so I can read.
Speaker 0: well I didn't read any the last weekend because I was busy.
Speaker 1: It says I can only have a few hours so I can just read it before I go to bed.
Speaker 1: And it usually overestimates like usually when it says three hours, it means I'll try to burn through it tonight tomorrow.
Speaker 1: I forget how many hours it said but it's single did try to burn through some ready.
Speaker 0: So third so most likely Thursday, we'll talk about the Odyssey.
Speaker 0: So read the fucking Odyssey.
Speaker 0: It's a really important story.
Speaker 0: new translation.
Speaker 1: What's your name?
Speaker 0: Emily Wilson?
Speaker 0: Yeah, also follow her on Twitter because when she talks about the Odyssey on Twitter, holy shit, is it great?
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm, and if you live anywhere in like the New York area and you are a biker Or even if you're not a biker, but you bike sometimes like if you could bike 10 or 20 miles But if you can bike you can bike 10 or 20 miles.
Speaker 1: You just don't think you can but you totally can.
Speaker 0: Yes, unless you're like really older and firmer have a problem But you could bike 10 or 20 miles where there's like rest stops Cars like following everyone to help you out if there's a problem and you have many hours to do it.
Speaker 1: Right, even if you go slow as balls, right as slow as my mom You will make 20-something miles in like what 10 hours, but you'll make it.
Speaker 0: So this weekend the Harlan Valley rail ride is Super goddamn fun.
Speaker 1: There are tons of bike rides all over the place, right?
Speaker 1: Especially in around New York that all over the country when me Scott and Emily will be at this one There's tons of organized bike rides, but this one of the many, you know that I've done this one It was the most luxurious and awesome.
Speaker 0: So there is a 23 33 45 57 72 80 and two different hundred mile routes.
Speaker 0: We're just gonna camp in this field on Saturday.
Speaker 0: then on Sunday, we're gonna do the ride.
Speaker 0: It's gonna be awesome.
Speaker 0: So if you want to go to this thing, we'll be there.
Speaker 0: We got nothing to do on Saturday, but dick around in upstate New York in this park.
Speaker 0: Maybe play some games Maybe go to swim at the lake there.
Speaker 0: Yeah, hang out with some cows and some horses.
Speaker 0: Good time.
Speaker 0: We'll be there.
Speaker 0: so pub G.
Speaker 1: So pub G came out.
Speaker 1: It was a big deal and it's a real good thing.
Speaker 0: The pub G didn't come out when we were in college.
Speaker 1: Yes I didn't pay a lot, you know, I didn't play it right away because it was like this early access game That was getting huge.
Speaker 1: It was number one on Steam.
Speaker 1: it was the biggest deal ever and I just didn't get into it because it was 50 bucks and I didn't have time to get into it.
Speaker 0: It was I wanted to play it and money wasn't even an object It was just.
Speaker 0: I knew I did not have time to commit to it because pub G the best way to describe it.
Speaker 0: If you don't know anything about player unknown battlegrounds, it's the hard more.
Speaker 0: It's the hard mode version of fortnight, right?
Speaker 0: Even though really fortnight is the ripoff tf2 of pub G, right?
Speaker 1: So if you don't know it's an FPS and the way it works is a whole bunch of people get thrown onto a map Which is a giant giant map and between 90 and 100 people.
Speaker 1: It's an island Yeah, and you basically go around collecting, you know armor weapons ammo vehicles Whatever you need and then when you meet people you fucking murder them or be murdered by them and the last person alive is the winner And they get the chicken dinner.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: So here's the deal the man just like battle royale the movie only with less people more people.
Speaker 0: So the the things that made the important points about this game or that one.
Speaker 0: This is an old school FPS, this is one of those old school.
Speaker 0: What do you mean?
Speaker 0: old school that?
Speaker 1: so your old school is quake where everything's fast, right?
Speaker 0: This is not the.
Speaker 0: that's not the aspect of old school because there were slow.
Speaker 0: FPS is back then too, right?
Speaker 1: But those have been like the old FPS like that were like maps or mazes.
Speaker 1: This is one of those is a military fan.
Speaker 0: This is This is our school mod type.
Speaker 0: FPS is because old-school mods of FPS is Like those quake one and quake two mods and make it TF and all that nonsense.
Speaker 0: They were Characterized by having a million fucking buttons.
Speaker 0: You could bind to a million different complicated.
Speaker 1: It doesn't have that many it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it does.
Speaker 0: You just don't know.
Speaker 1: this is just a military fanboy.
Speaker 1: FPS.
Speaker 1: People cared about realistic weapon stuff and you know actual.
Speaker 0: but instead of a hit scan bullets they're actually like ballistic and they have TV, but But Eventually, you'll you're gonna start looking up the keys to hit to do complicated things.
Speaker 0: You didn't even know you could do like change how the sights work on a gun.
Speaker 0: Yep Like you can hold you can bind a key.
Speaker 0: like you can crouch you can lay prone you can crawl you can lean.
Speaker 0: I don't lean yet.
Speaker 0: I feel like I should start leaning.
Speaker 1: leaning is pretty important.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't lean at all.
Speaker 0: It's a problem.
Speaker 0: It's got melee.
Speaker 0: It's got all sorts of nonsense.
Speaker 0: There's a lot of buttons and a lot of stuff to Learn before you can actually be good at it at all like.
Speaker 0: so on one hand it's like counter-stroke semi realistic weapons and Like super dead like one bullet will pretty much just take you out.
Speaker 1: sort of it has.
Speaker 1: that's one of the.
Speaker 1: it's weird great cuz.
Speaker 1: Fundamentally, right.
Speaker 1: and if you look at the big picture of this game, right?
Speaker 1: I love it and I knew I would write which is why I played it eat when it went on sale After we and especially, you know the seeing the the maker the creator of the game at the PAX East keynote reaffirmed like alright Yes, everything I thought about this game was correct.
Speaker 0: I would know was great.
Speaker 0: He's really smart and he talked a lot about like why he made this game, right?
Speaker 1: But so on the big picture of the game, everything is like totally awesome.
Speaker 1: Right you parachute onto this island.
Speaker 1: the parachuting is way fun.
Speaker 1: It's one of the only things I'm okay Especially cuz like I only mess up.
Speaker 1: I only mess up if it's a parachute really far away from the plane.
Speaker 0: But then you look around and you're like, oh good I'm by myself or sometimes you're parachuting and you see like a bunch of other people parachuting Well, I've been playing I've been playing squad only I stopped playing by myself.
Speaker 1: I like myself is lame.
Speaker 0: I like playing by myself.
Speaker 1: I also like playing with squads and self is lame Anyway, but then right you you go around and collect stuff and it's all like you're exploring this map.
Speaker 1: It's all kinds of fun.
Speaker 1: You're collecting loot.
Speaker 1: You're you know, getting better weapons reload configuring your guns, you know, that's way fun.
Speaker 1: Especially it's like this.
Speaker 1: it's big.
Speaker 1: It's like it's so big.
Speaker 0: You've got this like for example of the maps that desert map like if you don't get our car Like you just can't get to the other side of the map.
Speaker 1: Not only is it big but like you go to a building this buildings and like multiple stories with like tons of rooms in them It's like yes, like like like it's it's hyper realistic.
Speaker 1: one building in this game will be as big as like a whole counter-strike.
Speaker 0: yeah, so Imagine like that.
Speaker 0: that feeling alone is really fun.
Speaker 1: Like this is bigger than tribes.
Speaker 1: tribes isn't isn't even big.
Speaker 0: You're thinking about your strategy.
Speaker 0: Like should I go ahead?
Speaker 1: Tribes of the pub G mode.
Speaker 0: Should I go ahead for that city?
Speaker 0: There's probably a lot of people there.
Speaker 0: Maybe I'll just cut through the woods.
Speaker 1: better loot there though.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'll cut through the woods I won't find any loot, but this is a weird remote part of the map.
Speaker 0: There's gonna be no one out here or I'm literally.
Speaker 0: just I land on this island by myself and get a jet ski and leave the Island when I'm ready.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so then there's a circle that appears and the circle is what makes it interesting because there's only a few maps Right ones.
Speaker 1: the new one is like a small one.
Speaker 0: Well, the two and there's two things that are important here.
Speaker 0: There's one there's the circle and there's the random plane route rival that.
Speaker 1: Yeah So the the the the the flight that everyone jumps off of with a parachute is different every time and it's hard to fly far Away from the plane in your parachute.
Speaker 1: So people start in generally along that line.
Speaker 0: that starts.
Speaker 0: you look at the map there's a hundred people with you on the plane and You decide when are you going to jump off the plane?
Speaker 0: and when you're on the plane You'll see like a seating chart and you'll see people disappear as they jump off the plane.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like it goes over the military base a million people.
Speaker 1: So the starting distribution of players is different every time.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's more dense along the line more dense in the in the cities with lots of loot.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: And then there's a circle that appears once you're on the ground and if you're outside that circle when the time runs out Then it these.
Speaker 1: this electric fence that's like virtual electric fence will come in and if you're outside of that circle when the fence Comes in you start taking damage and eventually die.
Speaker 1: the circle appears in a random location and then it gets smaller and smaller and smaller at intervals and those inner those smaller.
Speaker 0: each one of those is also in a Random location within the current circle.
Speaker 1: Yes So basically the game is different every time even though it's on the same enormous map because a the map is enormous.
Speaker 1: B You're starting in a different place and see the circles are different which shows like as the game goes on It's like alright.
Speaker 1: Well, the game is ending this time like in the water or on a bridge and then this this time the game is like everyone's.
Speaker 1: You know coalescing around this building or this, you know This this, you know Maybe big city the game ends on or just in the woods is what happens most of the time Right?
Speaker 1: or this rock formation and that really changes how the game goes.
Speaker 1: Based on the terrain that everyone's being forced into at least the survivors are forced.
Speaker 0: Now at close and moderate range like in a firefight, it's very counter-strike II in terms of the skills.
Speaker 0: Yep but The firefight because counter-strike as a game Starts at the point the firefight broke out.
Speaker 1: basically You're already you're like you're already really close to someone.
Speaker 1: like even if you just spawn in counter-strike and you're both at your spawn points You are hella close.
Speaker 1: Yeah If you're that close in pub G like you're gonna die.
Speaker 0: like pub G is a game where like you're walking through the woods you Hear one gunshot in the distance.
Speaker 0: You're like Where's that?
Speaker 1: Yep, it's going on.
Speaker 0: Someone's nearby Hey They'll be here soon Like you hear a bunch of gunfire and like some people play like scavengers like to hear a bunch of gunfire and this are creeping In to catch someone looting like that.
Speaker 0: There's a lot of dynamics, but the real strategies in the game come down more to things like real world overland movement and like really realistic Technics seeing someone else before.
Speaker 0: they say you matters way more than your counter-strike head clicking skills.
Speaker 1: Yep I mean You know the people will do stuff like they'll they'll stay inside the wall as it comes in and then they'll aim Outwards.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and because they know
Speaker 0: a lot of kills by being along a road They know
Speaker 1: that people are coming from that city and if because they're they have to run that those people didn't make it to the Circle in time they're coming in from that general direction Will shoot them as they come in.
Speaker 1: my favorite thing that ever happened is Another strategy is oh, we know people are gonna camp there to shoot people as they come in.
Speaker 1: Let's go shoot them Yep, or in the back because they're looking outward.
Speaker 0: There's a fire watchtower up there and it's in a good spot.
Speaker 0: I'm pretty sure someone's camping up there doing what we just described.
Speaker 0: Let's toss a little grenade up there and I hear it explode and someone's just dead.
Speaker 0: good game.
Speaker 1: Yeah There are how many times I've been like in a building and I'm pretty sure no one knows I'm in here as I haven't moved Or made any noise.
Speaker 1: Yeah, a grenade comes in the window.
Speaker 1: It's like well, all right, so Do I attempt to run revealing that I'm in here and then go out run out the front door where I will be shot or Do I like try to sit here and survive the grenade?
Speaker 1: Even if I survive the grenade, I'm now damaged and they come in and shoot me Even though maybe I can get some shots on them that way.
Speaker 1: It's like, you know, it's like that kind of thing.
Speaker 0: Yep, so it means the game is really more about things like literally managing your time.
Speaker 1: Can you pick up a grenade and throw it back?
Speaker 0: I have no idea.
Speaker 0: I don't in kind.
Speaker 0: It's pretty rare that I get a grenade thrown at me So I haven't really Interacted with them in that level.
Speaker 1: It happened to me a lot when I would just camp in houses.
Speaker 1: now that I run around It doesn't happen as much.
Speaker 0: But so that they like threat assessment like you're driving along the road and you see some houses up in the distance Like you got to think about what if someone's in that building will they do anything to me?
Speaker 0: Do they care?
Speaker 0: or they just because they're just just as afraid of me as I am of them?
Speaker 0: probably well not.
Speaker 1: if they're good They're.
Speaker 0: yeah, it depends.
Speaker 1: But I feel like the good players are going around hunting everyone and aren't afraid at all.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but I'm basically afraid of everybody.
Speaker 0: I'm trying to hunt people more and I'm having fun with that.
Speaker 1: I've been playing in squads more because then when I get in a squad with good people they carry me.
Speaker 0: But you're thinking of things like so I got to get inside the circle.
Speaker 0: Where do I go?
Speaker 0: Like you're pulling off the map.
Speaker 0: if you're playing with a squad Usually like someone's got the map up like and picking waypoints like alright, we're gonna head here.
Speaker 0: We're gonna head here.
Speaker 0: Yeah, someone else is like covering teams.
Speaker 1: That's the team.
Speaker 1: stuff is so fun.
Speaker 1: You can put waypoints on the map and then your friends can see that on their map and you can sort of you know Communicate really nicely.
Speaker 0: So let's talk about that.
Speaker 0: There's there's a couple.
Speaker 0: there's a few ways to play.
Speaker 0: There's a third person mode, but fuck that noise.
Speaker 0: No, don't play third person.
Speaker 1: I've heard the third person is like the the way to win.
Speaker 1: But at least they keep the third people their third person perspective people separate from the first person.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I tried it.
Speaker 0: It's not fun.
Speaker 0: It just feels really I didn't even try it.
Speaker 0: It's really not fun.
Speaker 0: I'm only an FPS person but so you can play solo which is fun in its own way.
Speaker 0: It's just Hundred people.
Speaker 0: last man solo.
Speaker 1: I think is more fun if you're actually good.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's very.
Speaker 1: it's very unnerving cuz you're just alone.
Speaker 1: It's a good way to learn sort of basic skills like no I didn't learn a lot doing solo cuz I just died.
Speaker 1: And but when I played in a team people could tell me stuff and would give me pointers.
Speaker 1: I just have some wiki's.
Speaker 0: I started playing solo and I started getting like.
Speaker 0: I'm not saying I'm good But I can usually make it to the last 10 or 15.
Speaker 1: Oh, I can make it to the last but not really I make it there.
Speaker 0: I don't just hide I kill a few people on the way and I take risks.
Speaker 0: I take a lot of risks.
Speaker 0: The game's not fun if you don't take risks.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah I mean, what do you want?
Speaker 1: you're playing a game and what do you spend your time?
Speaker 1: crouched in the closet?
Speaker 1: And then you die that way.
Speaker 1: What did you just do for 20 minutes when I'm getting really close?
Speaker 0: What was the point like one time?
Speaker 1: How is that fun?
Speaker 0: There are only five other people left alive and the circle is getting real small.
Speaker 0: So I was in the second story of a building that was right on the edge of the circle.
Speaker 0: I just hit up there prone.
Speaker 0: I'm fucking gonna move and I was just gonna hope and hope and grenade came in through the window.
Speaker 1: Yep, that was the enemy.
Speaker 1: That's how would you camp in the building?
Speaker 1: grenade comes in the wind?
Speaker 0: Nope But you can also play two player like duo squad.
Speaker 1: You can do two people.
Speaker 1: you can do three four two people is the default Scott and I stream two people.
Speaker 0: That's pretty fun.
Speaker 0: Cuz it's very like you.
Speaker 0: like you can do basic Simple tactics like I'll cover the windows on this building while you go in or I'll look at the map While you're covering me like that kind of stuff before people's really where it's at It's.
Speaker 1: it's just great to have four people, you know, you don't get outnumbered by some bigger squad.
Speaker 0: Yeah, four people is.
Speaker 0: I've only played four people a few times.
Speaker 0: it's real fun.
Speaker 1: I play four people the most.
Speaker 1: once I once I realized you don't actually need I thought at first I thought you needed to bring Three friends.
Speaker 0: Oh, no, you can join.
Speaker 1: you can just join a random group of four people.
Speaker 0: once I learned that that's all I do Yep, but it's four people is especially fun when you play with friends Because four people like you could.
Speaker 0: you're on voice chat You're just playing.
Speaker 1: it's fun when you play with friends or you randomly get put with people are actually good.
Speaker 1: But I actually was worried I'd get put with like shitheads from the internet But that actually hasn't happened.
Speaker 1: I've usually been with like good people.
Speaker 1: I haven't had any awful experiences.
Speaker 1: But then again, I'm a dude.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that is true I have.
Speaker 0: I think part of that is that there is a pretty high barrier to entry for this game.
Speaker 0: like Imagine if you'd never played like counter-strike or like those kinds of games and you'd never played.
Speaker 0: those are made like Super realistic games and you've only ever played like Call of Duty.
Speaker 0: You're fucked if you try to play this game.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like you're not gonna have a good time.
Speaker 1: So I mean, you know the it's not necessarily a negative But the only negative things I see in this game is simply that a I don't like the military, you know realism stuff I do.
Speaker 1: I I just like.
Speaker 1: I like more.
Speaker 1: I don't want it to be so Simple and arcade II like it's Team Fortress 2 But I like the counter-strike level of the way weapons work where I don't want to have to adjust the sides And worry about this ballistic shit.
Speaker 1: It's like if I click on someone I should shoot them, right?
Speaker 1: It's like come on.
Speaker 0: So I like that realism.
Speaker 1: I mean, I understand it.
Speaker 1: I understand that other people like it.
Speaker 1: It's just a matter of taste, but it is not.
Speaker 1: it is not my preference.
Speaker 0: Here's the reason why it needs to be that way.
Speaker 0: in counter-strike the sniper rifles were Way too dangerous and the only reason they worked is because you can't get that far away from people.
Speaker 0: I think it would be cool if they just a counter-strike style AWM in this game Where you could just click and it'll always kill the person.
Speaker 1: I think it would be cool.
Speaker 1: Just don't have sniper rifles scopes.
Speaker 1: You can see but no guns that are actually any accurate at that range like the fact that sniper rifle exists.
Speaker 0: because Sniping like you can interact with this game in very different ways but you can't necessarily specialize because Every game is so different that even if you get wanna snipe like sniping is really fun or interacting with snipers is really fun like sometimes like a sniper takes a potshot at me and misses and then it's a game of Me trying to
Speaker 1: figure out where the hell they are figure
Speaker 0: out where they are serpentine get out of sight like get over a ridge And then it's not like.
Speaker 0: now I gotta go kill them.
Speaker 0: It's well, I got away from the sniper.
Speaker 0: Good luck.
Speaker 0: Have fun sniper.
Speaker 0: I will probably never encounter you again.
Speaker 1: You know this stuff going on there, but you know, I just you know, the the realistic weapon shit is not for me Military fanboys.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I also like.
Speaker 0: so there's where there's so much of this game like vehicles.
Speaker 1: Yeah, because the maps are so vehicles are just fine.
Speaker 0: So you can literally like get in a car and drive it around with your friends or like a jet ski.
Speaker 0: There's all like.
Speaker 0: there's so many different vehicles.
Speaker 1: The other thing is like the inventory stuff.
Speaker 1: It's like it's alright.
Speaker 1: You need to have some amount of inventory thing because part of the game is about going and getting loot and like upgrading your weapons.
Speaker 1: Stuff right, but so, you know, it's a. it's just like the complexity of it is just like one smidge too much Right to where it's like, oh you got to have the right bullets for that gun.
Speaker 1: I like that and then you have to remember Which bullets go with the wedge gun.
Speaker 0: they don't help you out if you're holding away if you're holding a weapon if you have one Then it shows a silhouette of the weapon when you look at the thing on the ground.
Speaker 1: It's not it's it's still Bit I can't?
Speaker 1: I don't even know that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like I don't even know what the hell Like.
Speaker 1: what gun do I'm even holding right?
Speaker 1: It's like you have to be a military fan boy to know.
Speaker 1: Oh, I'm holding the with the tele m4 apart from an M16 and know what kind of ammo they take.
Speaker 0: It's like if you don't know that stuff Which is weird that I know some of that stuff.
Speaker 0: The easy way is if it shows a silhouette pick it up one of your guns uses it.
Speaker 1: Yes, I'd even notice.
Speaker 0: but anyway, the point is but I like that element because here's a counterpoint.
Speaker 0: You can't pause the game.
Speaker 0: It's pub G. It's live.
Speaker 0: You're just going.
Speaker 0: yeah, so like the real world Imagine if you literally were pet teleported like jumped out of a plane naked into a town You've never been to.
Speaker 0: ran into a house.
Speaker 0: you hear gunfire outside and on the ground is a pile of guns and bullets.
Speaker 0: you gotta really balance your time between Carefully picking up the right things you want versus.
Speaker 0: grab a bunch of shit get somewhere safe figure it out later.
Speaker 0: I like that aspect a lot.
Speaker 0: I've been killed a couple times Fucking around in my inventory when I thought I was safe.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that happens often, right?
Speaker 0: I do like, you know getting killed fucking around your inventory watching someone else kill someone wait for them to go loot the body.
Speaker 0: There is there fucking.
Speaker 1: there's still ways you can keep that aspect without Of oh my god.
Speaker 1: I'm fuck your.
Speaker 1: I'm inventory.
Speaker 1: while I was shot without having to be a military fan boy I know which ammo goes with which gun.
Speaker 0: you don't need to.
Speaker 0: the game literally just tells you it's not Super-elegant.
Speaker 0: I think It's not super-elegant or obvious.
Speaker 0: I think the way they did is actually pretty elegant because it keeps the realism But it gives you very clear and say right as you can.
Speaker 1: I'm saying get rid of the realism fuck realism.
Speaker 1: But I don't give a shit about.
Speaker 0: yeah, you just want to be some fortnight.
Speaker 0: kid is what you want.
Speaker 1: No, I don't.
Speaker 1: that's too stupid a game.
Speaker 1: I need to be counter-strike level.
Speaker 1: We're just I you know, let me pick up the ammo like quake where I shouldn't have to touch.
Speaker 1: You played counter-strike At least a year ago.
Speaker 0: No, I still play counter-strike.
Speaker 1: I want to play counter-strike where I parachute out of a big plane Onto a giant map and then I play counter-strike and only one person survives.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Anyway, I like.
Speaker 0: I like pub G a lot.
Speaker 1: Yeah, no, it's great It's so.
Speaker 0: here's the other things are important about this game because of all the factors we talked about Irrespective of Scott's complaints about the military fanboy.
Speaker 0: It's nice.
Speaker 1: Just I don't you know, it's not bad.
Speaker 1: They do a good job.
Speaker 1: That's not for me but I still play the game because all the other parts outweigh that one thing.
Speaker 0: like everything's pretty tight and there's a Lot of complexity that you don't have to engage with.
Speaker 0: if you really don't want to like well You're not gonna win.
Speaker 0: if you don't you'll you'll do well, but I'm not gonna win it.
Speaker 1: I'm not gonna win anyway, so it doesn't matter.
Speaker 0: but I guess it's a game where Losing and winning are pretty much equally fun.
Speaker 0: Once you get above the point of you just die immediately and don't know why naked in the wilderness Like once you get past that point losing at this game is actually super fun.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't really don't give a shit about like.
Speaker 1: I've never won and I don't really care, right?
Speaker 1: It's like encounter strike if you just keep losing and losing and losing.
Speaker 1: eventually you want to quit and find a different team and pub Gee, I expect to lose I lose and I don't care I just keep playing the.
Speaker 0: the emergent stories the emergent gameplay the narratives of winning and losing like this game is Such a triumph in that regard like literally every game of this I play is
Speaker 1: Completely different from every other
Speaker 0: has at least one story to where like if I'm hanging out with people who have also played pub G I can tell the story and it's usually funny or interesting in some way and Not many games can generate that consistent level of interesting stories.
Speaker 1: I mean the only games that don't really have much of a story are the ones where you Land in the hotbed area and die right away Yeah Or occasionally.
Speaker 1: but if you I've landed in a hotbed area and not died right away and then a good game happens Yep.
Speaker 1: And the other thing is like you plan and then you won't even realize like you just playing and playing and playing Oh
Speaker 0: shit, there's only ten people
Speaker 1: and then it's like oh my god Look how small that fucking circle is and you don't even realize that like you're now entering the danger zone
Speaker 0: or cuz you're like like.
Speaker 0: Well, I had one game where it's just so happened that The circle was basically following me So I was basically always in the center of the circle.
Speaker 1: that circle is what even though you're on the same map doing the same Exact thing with you over and over again the random circle of the random plane flight change the game so much.
Speaker 1: Every time is completely different and it's like relative to where you happen to land, right?
Speaker 1: It's like even though you know, you get different circle every time but your landing spot is different.
Speaker 1: Maybe the circle keeps focusing on you.
Speaker 1: You don't move around a lot that game.
Speaker 0: You just start us chill out Like close range weapons and you hole up somewhere right.
Speaker 0: grenades can't get into the window.
Speaker 1: some other game you play.
Speaker 1: the circle appears Real far away from you and now your whole game is like this journey to get over there without dying.
Speaker 0: Now your game is like, oh fuck I need a car.
Speaker 0: like you see a car coming down the road and like Brigands you try to like fucking kill the people in the car and steal it Right.
Speaker 1: Your car can run out of gas.
Speaker 1: You gotta get more gas for it.
Speaker 0: My so I was.
Speaker 0: this was like one of them of the most fun I ever had.
Speaker 0: I was playing solo and I was in a big desert map and like the circle just started on the like I started on the edge Of the map and the circle was the opposite side.
Speaker 0: like I'm fucked there's no cars or anything near me.
Speaker 0: and then a car from a little bit even further away to the north comes driving by on the road and I see the car coming and I take some potshots and rather than just ignore me dude stops and gets out of the car.
Speaker 0: Why so?
Speaker 0: and he comes after me.
Speaker 0: So I just sneak out of the building and like sneak all the way around and get to the car and I see why he Got out of it.
Speaker 0: It was mostly out of gas.
Speaker 0: I had a gas can I filled it up?
Speaker 0: I drove
Speaker 1: away and
Speaker 0: just as I get in the car and start driving away I hear a machine gun open up and the dude is in the window of the building clearly panicking Because the fact that I got his car means there's no way he will make it to the circle and I basically killed him.
Speaker 0: That was so fun.
Speaker 0: Like the bullets are bouncing off the back of the car and I'm just trying to get away and I totally got away.
Speaker 1: Yep, crazy shit like that happens.
Speaker 1: It's like epic stories like every single time you play and live for more than 10 seconds.
Speaker 1: Yeah, which is why you know, it's like, alright, I'll put up with some military fanboyism for that.
Speaker 1: I guess it's not.
Speaker 1: it's not the most extreme military fanboyism I've seen.
Speaker 0: so if you if you're okay at the game Games last you in 10 and 20 minutes.
Speaker 0: Like that's about how long you're in there.
Speaker 1: Yep If you're when your first star and the thing is you don't have to chill out while the game finishes You can just leave and join a new one.
Speaker 0: basically when you die You have two options.
Speaker 0: you can either Start spectating and like watch the person who killed you and see if they make it because I did that a couple times or watch The rest of your team if they're still alive.
Speaker 0: It's real satisfying when like you get killed and you feel salty about it but then you see that the person you killed who killed you is Like a super expert who goes on to win the entire thing and you were just one of many That they took out or you can watch the death cam and it shows all the Context that led up to your death like the person who killed you and it's way earlier in the timeline than you might expect.
Speaker 1: I think it's like 30 seconds before you died or something is some amount of time.
Speaker 1: It shows the person who killed you for their perspective for like X seconds up until the point you died.
Speaker 0: It's pretty cool.
Speaker 0: so like literally like one of the ones I watch is I See this guy like fucking around in his inventory and like just dicking around in this house and then he hears a gunshot.
Speaker 0: that's me because I fired a shot at something.
Speaker 0: and then you see him like look and then creep over to the window and like Lean and he sees naked rims stay like off in the distance and then he like leans again And he keeps like lean lean like looking and when he's confident that I don't know he's there then he very very carefully Like gets his gun out fucks with his sight aims at my head like holds his breath and just headshots me And I didn't see any that rid.
Speaker 0: as far as I was concerned.
Speaker 0: It was naked.
Speaker 0: rim is walking through the woods and no one knows he's there.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm It's such a fun game.
Speaker 0: It's pretty definitely.
Speaker 0: do not buy it unless you Think you'll have enough time to play it though.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like you have to base like I don't there are other games.
Speaker 1: I have that I'm playing like every day But like pub G I can only play like if it's now.
Speaker 1: I have hours to sit down and play games.
Speaker 1: right now No one's here and I got nothing to do.
Speaker 1: it's game time.
Speaker 1: if you have time like that where it's game time Yep, you're gonna make it a thing at least once a week, then you can buy this game.
Speaker 1: But otherwise don't.
Speaker 1: also the game has Microtransactions.
Speaker 1: you loot crate shit cuz that it just ignore him.
Speaker 1: It's a hundred percent cosmetic.
Speaker 1: So I am buying absolutely none of it.
Speaker 1: I think there was actually you know, I twitch prime.
Speaker 1: you get all this free stuff.
Speaker 1: There's like a dead mouse pub G thing you can get for free.
Speaker 1: right now I'm not even getting that free loot crate that I get for free.
Speaker 1: Maybe I'll get it and not open it for now, even though it's disadvantage.
Speaker 0: I'm just being naked.
Speaker 0: I didn't even put on the default clothes.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm using the default clothes and I'll never use non default clothes and that's just how it's gonna be.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna commit to being naked.
Speaker 1: I'll see how much how much pub G money I can accrue and never spend.
Speaker 0: cuz it's someday if I ever win a match It'll be that fucking naked guy.
Speaker 1: Do you get more pub G money if you win?
Speaker 1: is?
Speaker 1: I don't even how it works I don't know.
Speaker 0: I never I'm speaking.
Speaker 1: I forgot one awesome thing about this game that we build to us.
Speaker 1: things about the game number one.
Speaker 1: This is red circle that appears in the map.
Speaker 1: Sometimes.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, and just bombs.
Speaker 1: If you're in that red circle and you're not in a building bombs and shit fall out of the sky.
Speaker 1: So you kind of want to not go in the red circles and it sort of creates interesting player movements, right?
Speaker 1: You know, especially it tends to.
Speaker 0: it's really in a game where the red circle appeared over a city.
Speaker 1: So me and the rando squad everyone starts running out of the city.
Speaker 0: We camped outside the city and they got flushed out by the bombs.
Speaker 0: We killed like four people.
Speaker 0: It was awesome.
Speaker 1: The other thing is that there's this sometimes the airplane comes and drops a crate.
Speaker 1: when the airplane drops a crate it parachutes down.
Speaker 1: It's a red box and then smoke comes out of it.
Speaker 1: That red crate is full of the best loot like level 3 armors level 3 helmets guns.
Speaker 1: You can't get anywhere else.
Speaker 0: It's also a giant sign saying hey noobs are gonna run toward this thing and be very easy to kill right.
Speaker 1: So like there been you think Scott who's not good at the game and never will be would never go anywhere near a deadly crate.
Speaker 1: but actually there been like two or three times and we're like, I've been on a team the crate just lands near us like Or the crate lands kind of near us and then we go in camp and see if anyone goes for it and then shoot at them.
Speaker 1: it's like the crate is like it creates like these events of Awesomeness that happen in these individual places if you're not in the center of the action Suddenly, aha.
Speaker 1: Here's a hot spot of action near this crate full of loot.
Speaker 1: so You know it mixes it up and I wish they would.
Speaker 1: I think the game could actually do with like just only one just one More thing that could happen on the map besides the red circle in the crate Just like a third thing.
Speaker 1: that would be four would be too many.
Speaker 1: But it's like a third special event that could happen on the map randomly Just to stir things up a little bit, you know, yeah, there's some weathery stuff like.
Speaker 0: there's stuff like that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the weather happen is different every time.
Speaker 1: the weather moves along but the weather only matters a little bit.
Speaker 0: It depends like in a rainstorm people can't hear you like it's.
Speaker 0: you can book it fog.
Speaker 1: You know, I can see you.
Speaker 1: Anyway, but yeah, it's a is a good old FPS.
Speaker 0: We're gonna.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna keep playing it semi regularly for a long time.
Speaker 1: I think yeah, I mean, I don't think it's going anywhere.
Speaker 1: It's still super popular.
Speaker 0: It's like a weekend thing and like an evening thing like I'll play overwatch every day But I'll play this like every weekend at least.
Speaker 0: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Speaker 1: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 0: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 0: But unlike those other late shows It's actually recorded at night and the patreon patrons for this episode of geek nights are Craig Oliver Allen Joyce Rebecca Dunn Heidi McNicholas shimmering rubiobolus king in the sky chart Kajar tovish in my state calm Jeremy minor link eg scoot alone.
Speaker 0: Lee Roberto Kingsley Kelly Snyder cold guy Amanda do shot.
Speaker 0: Sean Yeager Matthew Smith Nicholas brand L. Mr Strong strachan for 2-1 creations Chris Reimer and Thomas on.
Speaker 0: Shervin von Horrell Rory James David white Rochelle, Montanona Superboy trip wire sailor Vista Don Schleich Joe Joe Joe star Clinton Walton run from New Zealand.
Speaker 0: Ryan Perrin Openlander Finn Chris mint gift.
Speaker 0: Daniel Redmond Sean Klein Chris Reimer and Thomas on.