Speaker 1: It's Monday November 26th.
Speaker 1: I'm rim.
Speaker 1: I'm Scott, and this is geek nights tonight.
Speaker 1: We're talking about the technology of working from home.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: Rim said he had no opening bits whatsoever.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean so because I convinced my family here comes in opening bit even though.
Speaker 0: He said he didn't have it.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna convince her basically.
Speaker 1: I've gotten to the point to where my family will celebrate traditional holidays on Non-traditional days such that I can avoid the hassle of traveling on Thanksgiving or Christmas and As a result this Thanksgiving.
Speaker 1: We just stayed home and cooked some bib and bop.
Speaker 0: So when I got when I got off the train back in New York in Grand Central Walk, it wasn't a very crowded train I was walking back down the platform towards the main Grand Central area like
Speaker 1: you do and
Speaker 0: You know there's all these pillars in the middle of the platform like
Speaker 1: there are
Speaker 0: you know?
Speaker 0: There was a woman leaning with her back against one of the pillars and a friend next to her trying to tell her not to do something and The friend who was leaning on the pillar was really wanting to do something and the other friend was like no don't do this.
Speaker 0: It's like put salt in your eyes like what I don't know what and I was like What is this person trying to do?
Speaker 0: the woman was attempting to and then succeeded to?
Speaker 0: Pull down her pants and do some numbers On that pillar and it wasn't one of the pillars far away from the station.
Speaker 0: They were like one pillar away from the Grand Central.
Speaker 1: It is weird how frequently drunk women do that in the city.
Speaker 0: I'm like if you I've seen that just made it to the escalator right.
Speaker 0: there is a bathroom at the bottom.
Speaker 0: You could have made it.
Speaker 0: I saw you made it long enough for your friend to try to stop you.
Speaker 1: I saw two inebriated ladies come out of a brunch in Manhattan like a couple months ago and Both of them did something along those lines just right in the middle of the street, and that was that.
Speaker 1: I don't know why this happens today.
Speaker 0: I was you know leaning on the subway like you do and you uh Should I did?
Speaker 1: I need to be there to convince you not to do something?
Speaker 1: No?
Speaker 0: Because I was carried there there.
Speaker 0: these.
Speaker 0: uh because I was carrying something right I accidentally pushed the Recessed push in case of emergency button.
Speaker 1: Oh, I'm always afraid I'm gonna push that back.
Speaker 0: It's a recessed button, so it's real hard to push back.
Speaker 1: I'm still always afraid like especially on the air train I'm just gonna touch it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, despite leaning in that same spot on many trains that I've never accidentally pushed it.
Speaker 0: But today, I think is either my umbrella or a corner of a box I was carrying well went into the recess and pressed the button, so I'm just leaning on the Subway not paying attention to anything and suddenly I hear a voice.
Speaker 0: That's like some Sutton Sutton.
Speaker 0: What's your emergency?
Speaker 0: yeah, and I'm like It like took a few seconds.
Speaker 0: so like delayed it like what.
Speaker 0: yeah I'm like oh, it's me.
Speaker 0: Oh, it's the thing is right here, and I was just like oh, I think I leaned out of accident.
Speaker 0: Sorry, and he's like no problem that meanwhile the other day.
Speaker 1: I was waiting for the train in Queensborough Plaza and The train wasn't moving and there was some problem in one of the cars.
Speaker 1: like someone passed out or something like something went down and The conductor just kept announcing on the PA and the entire station.
Speaker 1: police police Come up and assist at the front car like and he kept doing it.
Speaker 1: and meanwhile there were like four cops in the station Downstairs doing that like fake bag check thing Like they could clearly hear this and clearly were pretending.
Speaker 1: They didn't hear it.
Speaker 1: yep That's how they do yep, and I just proceeded to get on an end train and make my way to work.
Speaker 1: cuz I don't got Time for that mm-hmm, but I do have time to find a bathroom before I put my pants down.
Speaker 1: So So yeah probably not gonna have a show on Wednesday because PAX is Thursday, that's a good reason.
Speaker 1: yeah I got a pack and like get shit together, but more on that in a minute, so it's Monday got some news.
Speaker 0: I do have a news.
Speaker 0: so this is something I've been complaining about since Oh 2008. no that ten years later is starting to see some action on right.
Speaker 0: so Back in the day when at the iPhone 3g came out And I bought an iPhone on the first day the iPhone 3g was available and the App Store went live Yeah, iPhone one did not have an App Store.
Speaker 0: You could not get apps on there other than by the web until the iPhone 3g came out and they added the App Store.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so on that day I was like man.
Speaker 0: this some bullshit that if I want to make an app for the phone I just bought even though I bought it because of the best phone and I still have iPhone.
Speaker 0: It's still some bullshit that if I want to make an app for it I not only need to have a Mac.
Speaker 0: you can literally still only develop iOS apps with a machine running OS X. You cannot develop iOS apps using even a machine running iOS.
Speaker 0: whoever heard of a computer.
Speaker 0: They can't make apps for itself.
Speaker 0: You also can only get it onto the device if you do it through Apple.
Speaker 0: Right if you're just beta testing you can use like this test flight thing and some people have used in test flight to do beta Tests on a wider scale, but mostly you need to get it in the App Store where Apple will then take a cut.
Speaker 0: They have a monopoly on software that runs on their platform, right?
Speaker 0: Kind of it's kind of sort of the same situation.
Speaker 0: or back in the day You had NES cartridges and then you had Tang and Tetris.
Speaker 0: Yep, right And you know, it's like oh you got to pay a license fee if you want to be able to sell.
Speaker 0: and yes Gotcha.
Speaker 1: No, it's interesting.
Speaker 1: and it because you know Because one of the things about Apple in the stores that wallets a monopoly on their platform.
Speaker 1: They're not the majority platform.
Speaker 1: Android is way bigger install base.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it depends on how you measure and what locales.
Speaker 0: and yeah, yeah, but Anyway, the point is is there is a lawsuit that's like hey, that's some bullshit.
Speaker 0: And that lawsuit is now reaching the most Supreme Court of the land.
Speaker 0: It's like they had.
Speaker 0: they spent like an hour today listening to people argue about this.
Speaker 0: And I
Speaker 1: feel like regardless
Speaker 0: of the legal argument Which I know nothing about because I'm not a lawyer The principled argument is I am fully against Apple and I hope they law the judges will say Yes, you must make it so that anyone anywhere is free to create software and put it on to an iOS device.
Speaker 0: if they so Choose fuck you.
Speaker 1: See at least Android has that not that I would ever do it.
Speaker 1: There's pretty much any.
Speaker 0: that's the thing is like I don't really care if other if I would never almost never Go to a website.
Speaker 0: That's like hey guy Give me some money.
Speaker 0: I'll give you iOS app for you to side load.
Speaker 1: I would only I have exe will give you many things.
Speaker 0: I would only do that with the absolute most trustworthy of websites, but like for tonight example of that probably I want to make a software and put it on my phone and I just don't want to buy a. Do that.
Speaker 1: so what's the line between a general-purpose computing device and a specialized one in terms of whether or not you should have an absolute right to Install software on it.
Speaker 0: I think it can be simply defined like does the Nintendo switch count?
Speaker 0: I think it should.
Speaker 1: Evelyn on the switch, I think we.
Speaker 1: I think a phone should count.
Speaker 0: I think we can define it based on The capabilities of the chips that are in there.
Speaker 0: right like you know if you've got say a alarm clock The chips in there are not really capable of doing very much if you program them.
Speaker 0: If I sell you a refrigerator and in that refrigerator is like an ARM CPU That can run pretty much any fucking code, and there's a screen on your fridge and some buttons all right.
Speaker 1: Here's a. here's a counter example.
Speaker 1: What about a smart stove like a range topper an oven where?
Speaker 0: Messing up the software could blow up your apartment building If you but I mean I could blow up my apartment building just with the knobs on my stove.
Speaker 0: So it doesn't really make a difference does it right if you allow me to do it via code?
Speaker 1: to this day I'm vaguely afraid of blowing up the apartment building with gas Right if there was just happen on the Upper West Side you saw a big explosion.
Speaker 0: if there was some sort of regulated Safeguard on you know blowing up yourself with the knobs on the stove right and like for example in the shower.
Speaker 0: It's like there's certain laws about the the water flow on the the faucet right yeah for wasting water And it's like aha you can remove the flow limiter, which you really shouldn't which is illegal to do right.
Speaker 0: It's like okay.
Speaker 0: Well if you had a computer-controlled shower, you shouldn't be able to unprogram the flow limiter.
Speaker 1: Alright so.
Speaker 1: but what I would say is that say they like a balloons this lawsuit.
Speaker 1: I don't think they should have to make it easy for you to install stuff.
Speaker 0: They don't have to do anything They just have to allow.
Speaker 0: no they just have to make it Possible so that I can go and write some code and install a app.
Speaker 0: You know should not make it easy in fact because then a bunch of morons will go installing a bunch of shady Exe.
Speaker 0: look look at links and emails yep, then say yes.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: Yes when it says Like they already do in Windows right they shouldn't have to make it easy.
Speaker 0: They just need to make it possible.
Speaker 1: So in some other news you might have seen this and we'll probably do a show like.
Speaker 1: there's a lot to say here and a lot to process.
Speaker 1: so start thinking about the fact that supposedly a Designer baby has been made like the thing that everyone worries about and wonders about for the future of humanity may have been done.
Speaker 1: and There's a bunch of ethical considerations that we all need to argue about for the next 20 years.
Speaker 0: I know doesn't seem to care.
Speaker 0: yeah Well, it's like fuck it.
Speaker 1: China's government probably cares in a very specific way.
Speaker 1: China like people in China Probably have specific opinions on it China's a much less regulated place in some regards so you can see why that's the kind of place where this might happen.
Speaker 1: first I don't know.
Speaker 1: on a high level I'm very conflicted and ambivalent about this kind of thing Because on one hand people have written many sci-fi stories about how this would be like the worst yep.
Speaker 0: But I mean when you look at what we've done with vegetables.
Speaker 0: You really haven't done too bad.
Speaker 1: Yeah We've got some good vegetables.
Speaker 1: I can eat like cucumbers and gourds that are not poisonous.
Speaker 1: hmm at least not that poisonous.
Speaker 0: It's like if we make a person that doesn't get diseased.
Speaker 0: What's wrong with that?
Speaker 1: ah but what?
Speaker 1: many of the arguments are.
Speaker 1: what if then people start designing their babies towards some contemporary?
Speaker 1: Pop culture beauty standard?
Speaker 0: or those babies then will have another pop culture beauty standard that they will impose on their babies.
Speaker 0: Who will then have a different culture and a different beauty standard that they will impose on their babies?
Speaker 1: What if desirable traits are actually linked to less well-known undesirable traits that only manifest later on and we've ruined our gene lines?
Speaker 0: I mean, it's just data.
Speaker 0: so they can always bring back.
Speaker 0: They can always make Scott Rubins.
Speaker 0: even a thousand years from now They'll have my DNA.
Speaker 1: That's why in Gundam seed the coordinators needed the baseline like human stock to refresh themselves because they basically made themselves sterile over time.
Speaker 1: hmm Let's say if it I mean if I did Gundam seeds the example you can always you can.
Speaker 1: new type Gundam in general new types Coordinators just better x-men just better.
Speaker 0: It's like oh, no.
Speaker 0: We made people who aren't fertile enough.
Speaker 0: all right We'll try to make some people that are better at being fertile with like you know really big Vagina holes that babies slip out of real easily.
Speaker 0: I don't know what makes someone more fertile.
Speaker 1: I mean, I guess what's gonna be interesting here Is that if this can be like a shit ton of sperm look at the size of those nuts?
Speaker 1: I mean, I guess because we can't like debate this in the news part of the show.
Speaker 1: But I feel like we're at the point now that this appears to have been really done That and that it could theoretically be done at some scale.
Speaker 1: It's time to actually have those debates for serious as opposed to just talking about in the context of anime and dystopian sci-fi.
Speaker 0: I think part of the problem also is that you know we have an institute is some sort of world order.
Speaker 0: so even if you Know one country decide something other countries just aren't gonna fucking do it.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, so then you narrow the scope.
Speaker 1: What should the United States do about this for example?
Speaker 0: is the problem right?
Speaker 0: let's let's say you know one country does it another country doesn't know and Country a has new types and country B. Doesn't?
Speaker 1: well then it's literally returned into the Gundam seed universe.
Speaker 0: right, but colony drop happens Unlike the Gundam seed universe where humans somehow managed to put up a good fight against coordinators.
Speaker 1: Well the only reason they do is because there weren't that many coordinators.
Speaker 0: well, so they had some coordinators on their side.
Speaker 0: Yeah Yeah, the coordinators will just kick the ass of non coordinators.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean if it gets to like I'll just be smarter better faster.
Speaker 0: What are you gonna?
Speaker 0: Do about it?
Speaker 0: Yeah, you bet right it become arms race if you don't have some sort of way to stop it.
Speaker 1: so The one interesting question for Tuesday episodes of geek nights is how does this play into the fairness in sports and doping?
Speaker 1: If I design a human to be like the perfect long-distance runner, I know it doesn't even have a brain.
Speaker 1: It's just a body and you feed it and if you put it on a track.
Speaker 1: It'll start running.
Speaker 1: Hmm does that count?
Speaker 1: is that okay?
Speaker 0: That may be among the first things they try to do.
Speaker 1: it's just lungs legs and like eight hearts.
Speaker 0: Realistically speaking that may be.
Speaker 0: one of the first things they try to do is to make Athletically superior people that don't need drugs or anything yep.
Speaker 1: I feel like that is what they're gonna do first in general.
Speaker 1: We'll see we'll talk about this more.
Speaker 1: so Get into the forum and start arguing about this because it's time to actually argue about it when it isn't a theoretical.
Speaker 1: In some other news you might have noticed.
Speaker 1: We're not gonna dwell on this too much, but someone posted in the forum Scott's complained about this forever.
Speaker 1: I've talked about it forever.
Speaker 1: We all like we knew this.
Speaker 1: I'm right about multiple things again, so basically some library in NPM Was changed ownership to someone who just put fucking malware in it steal bitcoins.
Speaker 1: because this library was used in like Bitcoin payment things and wallets and it totally worked.
Speaker 1: and It looks like a lot of stuff might actually be compromised and this whole story here You can read about.
Speaker 0: they don't hurt people who have coins so fuck them.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I also only hurt people using NPM so fuck them.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I guess I don't like this problem is so widespread.
Speaker 1: I don't know what to do about it.
Speaker 0: It's like this could happen with say like almost any of the other package management systems.
Speaker 0: for any of the other You know programming languages or OSes that are out there, right?
Speaker 0: I was like you could slip a nefarious package into Ubuntu apps.
Speaker 0: you can open a various package into fucking Any of the Linux distribution thing?
Speaker 0: Big Python has pi pi and you could even done this way back in the day with pearl.
Speaker 0: pearl has that like the oldest?
Speaker 0: yes That's one thing pearl has.
Speaker 0: they have the oldest best like programming language package manager thing Right at any time.
Speaker 0: anyone could have slipped nefarious things But meanwhile even in the Python one the only thing people have managed to do is put in like misspelled ones.
Speaker 0: So if you accidentally go like pip install and you type it wrong You'll install a bad version of a thing instead of the real thing.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right No one's managed to do this kind of attack.
Speaker 0: And the other problem is that unlike all Those other thing programming language package managers out there The JavaScript one delivers code to user computers.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right The other one does not really well this much.
Speaker 1: this is solved Trivially by if you're doing something that matters Regardless of the packaging system you use and you're using any open source components at all.
Speaker 1: You need to do code reviews and due diligence And if you don't have the capabilities to do that in-house You should be hiring someone else to make your software for you.
Speaker 0: The other thing you need to do is if you're doing making some serious, you know softwares You need to do some sort of.
Speaker 0: There are various like sites that will do this for you and help you out.
Speaker 0: You can do it yourself.
Speaker 0: You just make some sort of local mirror of the package repository, right?
Speaker 0: So this helps you keep the package repository up in case it goes down.
Speaker 0: It helps you.
Speaker 1: well, it also means you can take in like means your version 8 of food or whatever And then you can have a QA team when version 9 comes out like vet it and verify it eventually make it available.
Speaker 0: Well, you can also create your own Packages and not not have to deploy them publicly.
Speaker 0: you can deploy them to your own private version and then install them.
Speaker 0: So you can be like NPM install thing I made and it'll work Even though no one else if anyone else in the world tries to do that It won't work because it's only on your private copy of NPM that yeah that you're running.
Speaker 1: I feel like NPM is like the perfect storm for this kind of problem because I feel like there's a lot of people Who don't have sufficient development expertise in-house using it to hack something together and make it work.
Speaker 0: I've said this for many moons and I still believe it that the reason node.js and NPM were created is because they were front-end web developers and designers right who didn't want to have to learn Linux or Anything actually programming.
Speaker 0: they wanted to avoid all learning, right?
Speaker 0: They already knew JavaScript because they were using it for like making a pop-up window add on your site Right, and they didn't want to have to learn anything new.
Speaker 0: so rather than learn they would rather work and build tools to make it.
Speaker 0: so they Use JavaScript for everything and not have to learn another language Which would have taken much less time than building NPM and node.
Speaker 0: and then they made.
Speaker 0: they tried to copy all of the infrastructure that all the other languages had and since anyone who was actually any good at programming was Not doing that was already using another language.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and anyone who knew anything about UNIX was already using UNIX.
Speaker 0: They had all the people working on node or people who knew less and they did a really bad shitty job.
Speaker 0: And now a whole bunch of other people use it and now it's super popular, but it's still garbage.
Speaker 1: I'm very much a fan of having front-end development some sort of mid-tier and then real systems on the back end.
Speaker 0: You know, it's just like hey, you know if your job is to make something look good You know, if you also have the skills to know UNIX stuff, man You are a very skilled person who has skills across a super wide range of things.
Speaker 0: Yep, and that is a rare person.
Speaker 0: yet there are many many people who are quote full stack and are doing everything from design down to sysadmin and Not all of those people actually have deep knowledge of that wide variety of skills and they fuck up one side of the other.
Speaker 0: Yep, but now it's one thing A lot of people who know how a lot of UNIX and they're forced to make a website and it's real ugly and awful.
Speaker 0: It's what I do when I make a website.
Speaker 1: if you're making like it's real Like a video games not going to steal your bitcoins if you fuck it up.
Speaker 0: I mean cuz I hope not it could.
Speaker 0: yeah I can make a video game with JavaScript true less.
Speaker 0: It's in a web browser or something.
Speaker 1: Yeah So and one last news and this is sort of I was.
Speaker 1: I just stumbled upon this recently.
Speaker 1: Apparently there is people like.
Speaker 1: people have perceived a problem.
Speaker 1: You know how concert tickets sell out and there's scalpers and demand.
Speaker 1: and like that old story Pax is coming up this weekend.
Speaker 1: And of course packs badges sell out.
Speaker 1: same old story.
Speaker 1: But people seem to be mad that there are bots doing this same thing for Sneakers and for physical goods,
Speaker 0: okay So and
Speaker 1: it's the literal like to the point that lawmakers are looking to
Speaker 0: ban it
Speaker 1: Like trying to ban the idea of having a bot during retail shopping as opposed to a human.
Speaker 0: You know lawmakers love to go on about capitalism and free market and stuff.
Speaker 0: Why don't the people selling the sneakers jack up the price?
Speaker 0: so this doesn't happen?
Speaker 1: Yeah Like that there is.
Speaker 0: I don't think there are arguments to be see when it comes to the tickets Right, there are arguments to be made like hey, I'm putting on a concert here.
Speaker 0: This is art for the people.
Speaker 0: It shouldn't be only art for the rich people, right?
Speaker 0: Some people of lower income should be able to have access to but then it's not.
Speaker 1: but then it's on you If you're providing the art.
Speaker 1: say a concert.
Speaker 0: they do they do.
Speaker 0: they go through great efforts like Broadway shows have lotteries and stuff.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but that's it.
Speaker 1: You control that and do something like a lottery.
Speaker 0: But the point is there arguments to be made about.
Speaker 0: right the prices, you know need to cover a wide range.
Speaker 0: They shouldn't just let the market sort it out.
Speaker 0: They should do things to fight against the invisible hand because there is a greater purpose, but for sneakers I don't see any.
Speaker 0: I mean, it's like we're not.
Speaker 1: sneakers are art.
Speaker 0: I'm saying though that owning sneakers is not art.
Speaker 0: you can anyone can I can you can see all the sneakers?
Speaker 1: Well, I guess here's the problem.
Speaker 1: the problem with sneakers and like it's tickle me Elmo or the things people are mad about here Is that the only reason those things are in limited supply is because of artificial scarcity to begin with.
Speaker 0: that's one reason.
Speaker 1: not any sort Of like intrinsic problem.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and They can just make more of them.
Speaker 1: Like you can't make more PAX West.
Speaker 1: No, you can't make more buildings just up here in Seattle.
Speaker 0: It's also not a you know, a necessity of life and it's purely a luxury good.
Speaker 0: Nothing wrong with every sneaker caught that's rare costing a bajillion dollars.
Speaker 1: But I'm also of the mind that in general like if there's a site like Amazon or whatever that's selling something and Someone else wants to buy that at a retail price and resell it themselves.
Speaker 1: That's just like basic babies.
Speaker 1: first arbitrage.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's what should happen, you know, but also the person who made the shoe should sell it for more.
Speaker 0: So it doesn't happen.
Speaker 1: Ah, but if they just sell it for more it does get in a situation where only rich people can afford it.
Speaker 0: So it's a sneaker.
Speaker 0: That's perfectly.
Speaker 0: Oh, no only people can afford Ferraris.
Speaker 0: Oh, no No, it's like okay, it's the Ferrari of sneakers.
Speaker 0: he gives a shit.
Speaker 0: that's what's supposed to be.
Speaker 1: I guess it just.
Speaker 1: it's weird to me that I keep seeing like so many different areas of life All hair is as long as there is another shoe.
Speaker 0: that is not.
Speaker 0: if every shoe is zigz for Ferrari of shoes That would be a problem.
Speaker 0: The point is yes, you can't buy the newest limited Air Jordan whatever but guess what?
Speaker 0: There's tons of shoes that are way cheap.
Speaker 0: You can buy.
Speaker 0: I would be shoeless.
Speaker 1: at what point is this different than someone like going to Walmart and buying all the things Nothing or hiring a bunch of hobos to stand in line and buy all the things for you perfectly fine.
Speaker 1: I feel like every area of life has the same fundamental problem of supply and demand don't always line up and People.
Speaker 0: every area invisible hand is not strong enough.
Speaker 0: It's not moving Importantly, I feel like in Areas, they're not lowering.
Speaker 0: They're not doing.
Speaker 0: they're not moving Prices or supply and demand as they need to.
Speaker 1: the people who care and are mad about that thing Literally don't understand that the same problem is everywhere and all their ideas for how to solve it won't work and could never work.
Speaker 0: What I the only thing that I simply don't understand right is companies are trying to keep profits like up.
Speaker 0: They're trying to grow right.
Speaker 0: if I made suppose Nike why would I keep making all these limited shoes?
Speaker 0: Why not just pretend they're limited?
Speaker 0: no one will fucking know.
Speaker 1: they'll figure it out.
Speaker 0: The bots will figure it out and then make a fuck ton of shoes and charge $500 each forum.
Speaker 0: you could figure out doing it over and over.
Speaker 1: just by looking at the supply chain alone You could probably figure out what they were doing.
Speaker 0: Okay, so now that all these people we thought I just said limited edition.
Speaker 0: I didn't say how many.
Speaker 0: no every shoe is limited edition.
Speaker 0: I don't make them forever Right, so, you know what would happen?
Speaker 0: All the sneaker collecting kids would all have every shoe because they'd be available.
Speaker 0: they would all spend $500 each.
Speaker 0: They'd have nothing to complain about.
Speaker 0: everyone got every shoe They wanted.
Speaker 1: now that would only work once Because as soon as it's not a limited quantity a lot of people wouldn't be that interested anymore because it's not unique.
Speaker 0: I think they'd be just fine.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I Mean, I think the bigger problem is that companies try must grow forever as opposed to just being a sustainable business.
Speaker 1: I'm saying which is why I'm a big fan of like benefit companies and co-ops.
Speaker 0: I agree with that but that the point is is I'm saying look if you're gonna stay with the capitalism Which I want to get rid of you're not even doing it, right?
Speaker 0: That's what I'm trying to say.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I would like to get rid of the capitalism, but you're doing it and you're not even doing it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but I guess I don't it as even though I get burned by bots doing arbitrage on things like concert tickets I don't think it's worth legislating because I think the Consequences of trying to legislate that will be more harmful than just that being the state of the free market.
Speaker 1: Because frankly if that because if the bots like mess things up too much then the bots bought all the tickets the musician got paid and no one goes to the concert and Then they just do another concert.
Speaker 1: It might even increase demand for concert tickets in the long run.
Speaker 0: I think one there.
Speaker 0: I think there are other solutions and some of them may be legislative But I just don't think you should employ them in the case of sneakers and you might want to employ them in the case of Concerts, for example, maybe you could have some sort of rule at a concert where it's like, okay If you haven't shown up for the concert
Speaker 1: a half
Speaker 0: hour before this time Any on any vacant any tickets that haven't been scanned right as of a certain time, but
Speaker 1: should you regulate that?
Speaker 1: What if I?
Speaker 1: what if I as a venue don't want to deal with that hassle?
Speaker 0: I think we might should.
Speaker 1: we should legislate legislate something that's purely entertainment.
Speaker 1: Not a necessity of life It's the arts.
Speaker 1: you could see the concert online fine.
Speaker 0: Are you are you in favor of government funding of the arts?
Speaker 1: I'm in favor of government funding the arts.
Speaker 0: I think legislation for the arts is even less than government funding.
Speaker 1: So and now I would say that maybe Regulation would apply to the performance of government funded arts.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: Yeah all arts.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but sneakers are art.
Speaker 1: No, yeah, why not?
Speaker 1: Why why you?
Speaker 0: why are you?
Speaker 0: because you don't need to own the sneaker to Concert to experience the music.
Speaker 1: Yes, you do.
Speaker 1: It's probably better to experience it with good headphones at home.
Speaker 1: No, it's it probably is.
Speaker 0: it depends on the music.
Speaker 1: Oh, so it depends.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: Okay, whatever.
Speaker 1: That's not for you to decide anyway, it's time for Things of the day.
Speaker 1: What do you got for me?
Speaker 0: So there's this guy on YouTube and his channel is called man eating food.
Speaker 0: That's a real good name for a channel and every video is literally just this man eating food.
Speaker 1: Oh, this is so I want to eat this right now.
Speaker 0: earliest videos that he put up He just kind of spills him.
Speaker 1: he's like De-saltory about it.
Speaker 0: in the earliest videos he put up He was just doing like eating a thing just like a norm just like a food.
Speaker 0: It would be like man eats cereal or man eats a bagel or whatever, right?
Speaker 0: And it's just like a video of him eating.
Speaker 0: and it wasn't like the Korean mukbang kind of thing where you're sort of watching someone eat and sort of getting this like Secondhand pleasure from watching when they're like, oh, they're experiencing.
Speaker 0: Oh my god, it's not that right?
Speaker 0: It's literally just this guy.
Speaker 0: He eats a food.
Speaker 0: the video and it's real short, but he puts up a lot of content.
Speaker 0: the way He looks up at the camera right more recently He's put up videos where he's been combining foods and it's a lot is a big series of ice cream plus and the ice cream First of all is ample Hills ice cream.
Speaker 0: So ample Hills is a New York ice cream Company, you know store and there's a few of them.
Speaker 0: one recently Somewhat recently Oh like in the summer opened in my neighborhood and I had a big long line.
Speaker 0: The line is not there now because it's cold, but it's still open.
Speaker 0: And let me tell you it was worth the way in line.
Speaker 0: Holy fuck.
Speaker 0: That is some awesome ice cream.
Speaker 0: So I noticed that that is the ice cream he has.
Speaker 1: but he found the one way possible to improve that ice cream.
Speaker 0: This man in this one particular video that I will point separate as a lift above all his other videos He is doing the most rim thing I have seen someone do.
Speaker 0: that is not rim.
Speaker 1: If only he was a skeleton.
Speaker 1: while doing this And blowing a trumpet This man takes ice cream and then he puts croutons on the ice cream advanced crackers and then he eats Just the way he like looks like he looks up a little bit right into the camera.
Speaker 1: just he's about to take a bite.
Speaker 0: This is just one of a series of ice cream plus and I'm sure if his channel will continue and have many other things plus other things.
Speaker 0: Enjoy don't eat croutons with some salad.
Speaker 1: I'm going to eat croutons on ice cream tonight.
Speaker 0: Croutons are for a salad.
Speaker 1: only I will take a picture of it.
Speaker 1: No, I might.
Speaker 1: I might have run out of croutons.
Speaker 1: good, but I think we ate them all last night with the chili.
Speaker 0: Croutons are not for chili.
Speaker 0: They are for salad.
Speaker 1: So to fit in Scott's theme because this video is four hundred and forty one views and 18 likes.
Speaker 1: right now I have a video that I found yesterday That has 30 views Two like.
Speaker 0: we're trying to see who can get the least viewed.
Speaker 1: One of them is my like and it was uploaded a year ago.
Speaker 1: this video is Yeah, that's surprising and this dude Basically just shows something interesting that can happen in the old SNES game Gemfire one of rims games.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's a rim game.
Speaker 1: You know those games like the Ko Shibu Sawa games where yet like no, but no Bunga's ambition Nobunaga's ambition or arrow biz you got like a map with a bunch of numbers and you're doing things like calling board meetings and moving numbers around.
Speaker 1: So Gemfire is one of those games where you basically like Build armies and have like vassals and families and you're trying to go.
Speaker 0: It looks like a map of Britain.
Speaker 1: and yeah, and you have this vaguely British fantasy world.
Speaker 1: You're trying to do a thing.
Speaker 1: So the game has a really complicated system where you'll have like vassals that are in your family and you can like Steal vassals from other families and like get them to do stuff and like your family will do things.
Speaker 1: and the games actually pretty simple.
Speaker 1: But what this guy shows is something kind of fucking crazy.
Speaker 0: It doesn't look simple.
Speaker 0: if you'd like look at it with your eyeballs But if you play it's simpler than it looks like.
Speaker 1: I'll do a live stream someday and show you this game is actually way Simple like I can beat it from any standpoint.
Speaker 1: But basically you can only play as like four or five different families in the game.
Speaker 1: But this ridiculously complicated system of vassals really never matters that much Except if you do something weird and the guy does it He basically causes a giant family to lose its last vassal.
Speaker 1: Okay, and what happens is crazy.
Speaker 1: There are so every family has like a crest and like there's all these people in the game.
Speaker 1: They don't fucking matter at all.
Speaker 1: But in this one weird circumstance Every single goddamn territory whoever lives there forms their own goddamn new family Because he did some bullshit in the game that is almost impossible to pull off and the game handles it and makes like 30 new Families.
Speaker 1: every one of them has a unique crest.
Speaker 1: that was in the game waiting for this moment to happen.
Speaker 0: What if you do it twice of the 30 more credits?
Speaker 1: It's crazy.
Speaker 1: This would be like if you program sieve like sieve five or sieve six so that in this like one in a million Situation where a weird thing happened that could only happen if someone was like really gunning for it and was super obscure.
Speaker 1: If you had put all the crazy information in the game necessary to fully handle this ridiculous situation Like they wouldn't better off just having the game crash then bother with this.
Speaker 0: How did this guy know this would happen?
Speaker 0: Uh, they read the code of gemfire in advance.
Speaker 0: So do you read a strategy guide or something?
Speaker 0: So strategy guide was written by developers or had tips from developers.
Speaker 1: So as far as it cuz I've played this game and like like I could speedrun this game like not even joking.
Speaker 1: Not with like.
Speaker 1: I could even do a little bit of RNG manipulation because I played the game so much.
Speaker 1: but basically You don't need to bother with any of that shit to win the game and as best I can tell there was a dedicated community of people in the 90s who were obsessed with the characters in the game and the vassals and like trying to make other families farm and the game.
Speaker 1: and this trick just shows that the Accommodated this to the nth degree.
Speaker 1: and I'm just kind of shocked and amazed that this works In the moment.
Speaker 1: no show on Wednesday because on Thursday, we're going to PAX unplugged the second packs unplugged ever.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there's some bad news.
Speaker 0: There's awful city of Philadelphia.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: The only reason you should go there packs unplugged.
Speaker 1: Yep Philadelphia is filled with some violent people who live as far as I can tell short and brutish lives.
Speaker 1: Gritty might kill you if you show up in Philly.
Speaker 1: So beware, but uh PAX unplugged is gonna be awesome.
Speaker 1: It's the tabletop only PAX.
Speaker 1: We are doing two panels on one on Saturday one on Sunday.
Speaker 1: Otherwise, we're just gonna be playing tabletop because it's tabletop con.
Speaker 1: and if you can't see us at PAX unplugged We are also going to be live in San Antonio at PAX South doing a brand new panel.
Speaker 0: nostalgia versus game design will be escaping the harsh winter of the Northeast for the Slightly mildish weather of the south and even more crazily just by the mid south.
Speaker 1: So by happenstance, it's a brand new panel.
Speaker 1: We're doing.
Speaker 1: it happens to be about nostalgia in game design.
Speaker 1: Oh, it's just like.
Speaker 1: that's the one they picked and we're doing the panel on my birthday and It's our birthday packs and it's our 50th packs panel.
Speaker 0: you counted them.
Speaker 1: I counted them.
Speaker 1: to be sure.
Speaker 1: I'm doing our 50th packs panel on my birthday.
Speaker 1: Okay, so maybe I'll bring a tiny cake and share it with the audience after the panel or something.
Speaker 0: you buy your own birthday cake.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'll know.
Speaker 1: you know what I'm gonna do.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna bring a tiny birthday cake.
Speaker 0: I should buy you a poison birthday cake.
Speaker 0: It was also your last.
Speaker 1: I Feel like I'm just gonna eat a fucking piece of cake While we're doing the panel and not share it with anyone in the audience because that's way funnier and it was boys.
Speaker 1: Oh Yeah, and the booklet book is a space Odyssey.
Speaker 1: We'll do the show sometime before the end of the year probably Hopefully.
Speaker 0: hopefully I'll definitely have a time to read.
Speaker 0: but you know late December it ain't a long book.
Speaker 1: I feel like I can burn through when I actually start reading it.
Speaker 1: I've just been busy Yep, and also we will be at of course magfest.
Speaker 1: Before packs unplugged but but before pack south but after packs unplugged and we're doing a bunch of panels there.
Speaker 1: It's gonna be fucking awesome as always.
Speaker 1: It's magfest magfest.
Speaker 0: You don't spend your time with us.
Speaker 0: we're only doing that shit to get in for free.
Speaker 0: just come to magfest cuz.
Speaker 1: The only trouble is so.
Speaker 1: a lot of our panels are only videoed by magfest and not by us.
Speaker 0: and You don't give a shit just come to magfest.
Speaker 0: You don't need to see us there.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 1: people seem to like our panels.
Speaker 0: go to magfest to magfest.
Speaker 0: Don't go to magfest to see our go to magfest for both.
Speaker 1: No, so I can work from home, but I tend not to.
Speaker 1: And part of that I think is just that I live like it's a 10-minute commute Like if the subway is messed up, it might take me 15 minutes to get to work.
Speaker 1: So it's almost easier to work out of my office.
Speaker 1: But and I when I think about it in my entire life It's only recently that like I can feasibly work from home and be Like a hundred percent as effective at home as I would be at work like ten years ago Really couldn't like I could not get the access.
Speaker 1: I needed to fully work from home.
Speaker 0: Hmm.
Speaker 0: I mean, I don't really you know, I mean, I feel like most jobs That are office jobs Other than having to talk to someone else in person, right?
Speaker 0: Well, you don't necessarily need to do.
Speaker 1: you could do a phone or a video conference or who knows what with the caveat that in Many industries you'll run into old people who don't know how to do that or aren't capable of doing that.
Speaker 0: like that problem.
Speaker 1: in my life I've worked with people As in past jobs who literally like we're not really capable of dealing with instant messaging.
Speaker 0: They're supposed to be an IT person who helps them.
Speaker 1: No more like they just like they won't respond and won't work that way.
Speaker 1: and like unless you call them on the phone They've like won't understand you or listen to you.
Speaker 0: Oh that they should be fired.
Speaker 1: I've run into that a lot in my life.
Speaker 0: someone who is more capable should be hired in their place.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well should being able to use this messenger be a requirement of modern office work.
Speaker 1: Yes Yeah, a lot of people would get fired today.
Speaker 0: Everyone uses slack.
Speaker 0: now if you can't slack, how do you keep your job?
Speaker 0: Yeah, you probably fail even if it wasn't a explicit requirement.
Speaker 0: if you failed at slacking I think you would lose most jobs.
Speaker 1: I feel like I've had a small company.
Speaker 1: that'd be one of my tests.
Speaker 1: like I would just IM you to be like to Like do the last round of the interview and if you couldn't do the interview on IM I feel like you wouldn't be capable
Speaker 0: Email you before I hired you and if I could tell by your emails if they said please advise you would not be hired.
Speaker 1: Going forward, please advise dot-dot-dot.
Speaker 0: Oh not hiring this one.
Speaker 0: Yep Judge you based on your email.
Speaker 1: Why is there a font in your email?
Speaker 0: You are not going to be hired.
Speaker 1: Yep But I guess what.
Speaker 1: one thing I'm interested in like.
Speaker 1: Despite the fact that like technology has made it trivial for any office job to be done remotely Why are almost no people able to or allowed to work from home the majority of their time?
Speaker 1: Why does everyone still go into their office and like play hearts and fuck around on Twitter and excel?
Speaker 1: like why Doesn't everyone just work from home?
Speaker 0: Why don't they give us a million vacation days?
Speaker 0: Why don't they do all sorts of things?
Speaker 0: because his old fuddy duddies still have all the power?
Speaker 0: the end?
Speaker 1: No, I don't think it's just that.
Speaker 1: I definitely have found that a lot of people Just aren't capable of being productive if they're at home Like you don't trust you're not gonna be any more productive at home than you were at work.
Speaker 0: What's like what do I do when I'm at work?
Speaker 0: watch YouTube?
Speaker 0: What do I do at home?
Speaker 0: watch you see?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 0: doesn't matter where you keep me I'm gonna do the same thing, but I guess I actually do do work at work.
Speaker 1: But I can be mostly effective at home except for the weird situation where being like visible and like walking over and like grabbing people and talking to them or like chance media like literally like bumping into people and Like in the elevator has actually been a big part of how I get work done Mmm, but then again, I've sort of like higher profile role now than I used to have like when I worked at a broker.
Speaker 1: I literally did not to need to be in the office at all to do my job because I had a VPN to the office I had like video chat with anyone I needed to.
Speaker 1: I had a physical phone plugged into my router that Literally acted like I was in the office with like weird redundancy and all this nonsense.
Speaker 0: Hmm, huh?
Speaker 1: Yeah, nothing to present the show.
Speaker 0: I mean, this is your idea.
Speaker 0: But I mean, I just don't think it's like a technological thing.
Speaker 1: Well, I think the problem is you don't do work.
Speaker 0: Why would I do work?
Speaker 1: Most people do work at work.
Speaker 0: What the fuck are you doing?
Speaker 0: Should be doing as little work as humanly.
Speaker 0: every work you do right.
Speaker 0: someone hires you for a job.
Speaker 0: They pay you X dollars, right?
Speaker 0: They're expecting your work that you do to be worth more than X dollars.
Speaker 0: Thus they profit by hiring you.
Speaker 0: You're getting ripped off when you work.
Speaker 0: They're giving you money that is worth less than the work that you are doing that they are taking from you.
Speaker 0: Ah, you should be your number one goal at work should be to do as little work as humanly possible So that you could maybe even profit by being in the office.
Speaker 0: So the money you get from them is worth more than the work that you do for them.
Speaker 0: That would be like.
Speaker 0: that's like the ultimate goal at work.
Speaker 0: So do as little as possible get as much as possible.
Speaker 1: So I cuz if you do this is why I would never trust you to work for me.
Speaker 0: If you work hard, you are just a sucker who is being ripped off, right?
Speaker 0: So whether you work from home or not, if you have balls like me, you'll do the same amount of work.
Speaker 0: So it's not about observing me or catching me not doing work because I've never done any work and people don't catch me And they don't see I'm not even trying to hide it and they still don't fire me and I still do enough work where they Say wow, you're doing a great job.
Speaker 1: Let's take the non Scott case.
Speaker 1: then Imagine people who do like, you know, the 20 or 30 hours of actual work and the rest of the time.
Speaker 1: They're just like looking at Twitter suck Like.
Speaker 1: no, you have regular people at work non tech job even like someone who's at an office and like does the TPS reports?
Speaker 0: Okay, quit.
Speaker 0: Why are you doing that's what your life's gonna be TPS reports.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: So what a life.
Speaker 1: What did.
Speaker 1: it's kind of amazing how good the technology is to let that person literally Effectively be in the office if you have a job where there is no special equipment that you need.
Speaker 0: For example, maybe you're a printer and you're printing books.
Speaker 0: You need to go to where the giant book printing machine.
Speaker 1: What if we made remote robots where?
Speaker 1: cuz me like?
Speaker 1: it's not a process you can necessarily automate.
Speaker 1: I had a remote robot arms to control the thing that makes the books in the office.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we don't.
Speaker 0: we don't have those and that's no you don't have those.
Speaker 1: What do we have?
Speaker 1: the McDonald?
Speaker 1: what if you?
Speaker 1: what if you imagine a McDonald's where the person who's taking the order is at home on a screen like just wearing a shirt?
Speaker 0: if It is a device such as making burgers that can be done by Remote controlled robot then it can also be done by automated robot.
Speaker 0: We don't need the person.
Speaker 0: No, if it needs to be done.
Speaker 1: No, I would argue that's not true.
Speaker 1: There's a lot of tasks that can be done by a robot where the person is not directly proximate to the actual robot.
Speaker 1: Maybe they're in another room So theoretically they could be in another building But the automation is not there.
Speaker 1: like some tasks require a little bit of human discretion.
Speaker 1: It can't be fully automated.
Speaker 1: yet There's a lot of tests that involve a human manipulating an object via machines.
Speaker 0: sure I still feel like you know, if your job is say blacksmithing right unless you have your home a forge at home Which you're fucking awesome.
Speaker 0: Then you're great.
Speaker 1: There's a lot of YouTube channels of people at forges.
Speaker 0: at home They are but if you don't have a forge at home, you need to go to the forge to go to work, right?
Speaker 0: You can't really work from home.
Speaker 0: But if your job is office work because we have turned all paper into digital things You can work from home because you don't need some.
Speaker 0: you have access to all the same paper digital paper That everyone else has no matter where you are on earth as long as this internet.
Speaker 1: I think I've maybe printed four things in the last year of working at my office and those four things for forms I had to sign.
Speaker 0: I bought a black and white laser printer When I'm you know moved to New York, maybe even in beacon.
Speaker 0: How old is this thing?
Speaker 0: The point is it's pretty much only ever been used to print materials for tabletop games and RPGs.
Speaker 1: Yep Use my color laser printer Which I bought because I only print things like maybe once a month to print the things for packs Print things for tabletop games.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: I'll probably die before this thing runs out of color ink.
Speaker 0: It'll dry up.
Speaker 1: Hey, well, it won't dry up.
Speaker 1: It's a laser printer.
Speaker 0: It could still dry.
Speaker 1: It's it's already dry.
Speaker 0: toner can go bad.
Speaker 0: It's not gonna go bad.
Speaker 0: It can happen.
Speaker 1: It doesn't really happen.
Speaker 1: It happens.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I bought a. very well I got an office printer pretty cheap.
Speaker 1: Actually.
Speaker 0: It's a pretty good printer, you know, they don't really make shitty ones.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well cuz I bought an office printer as opposed to a home like inkjet whatever.
Speaker 0: Well, the point is is that there's almost nothing an office person needs to do That requires them to leave their home.
Speaker 0: If you have a computer you can do all information related work All right.
Speaker 1: So what?
Speaker 1: what are the jobs that cannot be in the foreseeable future actually done work from home?
Speaker 0: Like for example, well, I mean if you unless you're talking about if you want to you want about the jobs that are like can't be automated because like Pilot can't work from home, but I can.
Speaker 1: we already have pilots who work from home Drone pilots.
Speaker 1: they work from an office in Texas flying on the other side of the earth.
Speaker 0: Sure, that totally works.
Speaker 0: You can't?
Speaker 0: we don't have a commercial air.
Speaker 1: There's no technological.
Speaker 1: There's no reason why we couldn't.
Speaker 0: why don't we?
Speaker 1: Pa there's a lot of reasons why that actually seems like a really good idea.
Speaker 0: This is a really good idea.
Speaker 1: I think so.
Speaker 1: from what I've read.
Speaker 1: the main reasons why are that?
Speaker 1: in the event that that system fails You need a pilot to like be physically on the plane to be able to take over manual control Like they could just sleep on the plane though.
Speaker 0: They don't need to yeah, they just sleep in it.
Speaker 0: And there's the thing that like wakes them up.
Speaker 0: if that you know, yeah.
Speaker 1: But then the argument is if they just sleep on the plane they'll never actually practice the skill of like flying the plane anymore or They'll have to go.
Speaker 1: they'll have to like take training classes to remind themselves and keep their skills fresh to be able to Pilot it in the future in case they ever need to pilot it that one time.
Speaker 0: There's a problem Yeah, but also there'd just be so much automation so they wouldn't have to know that much.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but what if the automation fails?
Speaker 0: Don't fuck it up.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but sometimes things happen like the air train over, you know, it's a train It's much less than a plane.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but if the air train fails it just stops Right and you just get out of it.
Speaker 1: Yes, it doesn't go down doesn't fall off the tracks.
Speaker 0: That's true.
Speaker 0: But the point is is that automation is already that good, right?
Speaker 0: We just got to wait and then eventually the plane will fly.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and then we get to the sci-fi story.
Speaker 1: We have human we have jobs that robots have done for so long that humans don't know how to talk about labor that talk About automation.
Speaker 0: you're trying to work from home.
Speaker 1: Here's here's why I think because the technology is there for like almost every office job on earth to be done remotely.
Speaker 1: I think the main reason why it's not comes down to two fundamental problems.
Speaker 1: one Many companies don't trust their workers to actually do work if they're at home.
Speaker 0: Why do you hiring?
Speaker 0: People if you don't have enough work for them to do?
Speaker 1: I Think it's more that the people who are good enough to trust a hundred percent tend to take higher paying jobs elsewhere and move To cities where there's no incentive for them to work from home because their commute so short.
Speaker 0: Mmm, I haven't sent it to work from home.
Speaker 0: You know my commute.
Speaker 1: sure I actually am not like it.
Speaker 1: I'd almost just rather go to the office cuz I could get to the house.
Speaker 1: I go to Manhattan have lunch somewhere different.
Speaker 0: No, no, why if I go?
Speaker 0: if I will have to go to the office, right?
Speaker 0: That means I can't say for example, you know play Zelda Right.
Speaker 0: I have to.
Speaker 0: my activities when I'm not working are very limited to like YouTube only.
Speaker 0: No, also if I go to the office, that means I have to like buy lunch or bring a lunch.
Speaker 0: Sure, it's a pain in the ass.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna buy lunch.
Speaker 1: Anyway, I don't bring lunch or make lunch.
Speaker 1: I buy lunch every day.
Speaker 1: I'm going to deal with the devil today.
Speaker 1: I graduated college.
Speaker 1: I will buy a hot lunch every day my entire life.
Speaker 1: How much it cost me.
Speaker 1: that is worth more to me than almost anything.
Speaker 0: if I stay home I could.
Speaker 0: that time I'm not working can be productively used.
Speaker 0: so well I could.
Speaker 0: I could make a lot.
Speaker 0: I could do laundry.
Speaker 0: I can cook in my kitchen that I own Right, I can bake a bread.
Speaker 1: See I actually do do work the entire day.
Speaker 0: I can get so much shit done during the non work time.
Speaker 0: I could read a book can't read a book at work Right.
Speaker 0: all the stuff that I could do if I work from home that I could not do if I work at the office.
Speaker 1: so what's interesting is Like my work from home situation is such that I can do even all the things that people complain about not being able to do.
Speaker 1: Like there's a system.
Speaker 1: well, I can type anyone's name and bam instant video chat like right there at their desk.
Speaker 1: Everyone has a webcam.
Speaker 1: You're not allowed to not have a webcam.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I could do that.
Speaker 0: We have Google Hangout I get and I we have slack.
Speaker 0: I can contact anyone at the whole company As long as they're working.
Speaker 1: that we have like an internal system where I could even like make a room and have like ten people Like all automatically like it's all built in.
Speaker 0: you have Google Hangout.
Speaker 1: It does that Yeah, and like I can literally just be like hey Let's just like let's talk about Overwatch in this private room with video chat while we're dicking around like between things.
Speaker 1: I think the other reason why a lot of this doesn't happen is that as soon as a company has everyone working from home That company has no reason to hire really anyone in America or anyone who wants any amount of money to do that job.
Speaker 1: They can just literally outsource it to the lowest bidder anywhere on earth.
Speaker 1: They should who is capable of doing that job.
Speaker 1: they should which will have the exact same problem as automation and They save so much money on rent.
Speaker 0: They don't have to have a jew that huge is building Yeah, and yet they don't.
Speaker 1: and yet companies like Amazon will still put their fucking office in like Queens.
Speaker 0: I don't know why I don't understand it.
Speaker 0: There are new companies for example get lab which is competing with github, but they're not doing poorly, right?
Speaker 0: It's not like there's some you know, like yeah weak-ass thing.
Speaker 0: It's like there are a few hundred employees I think 300 something a hundred percent remote.
Speaker 0: everyone in the whole company is remote their work wherever on earth.
Speaker 0: they pay you I think according to where you live and not according to see.
Speaker 1: that's the key because a lot of a lot of This comes down to the fact that a lot of people who are good enough to do these like high-paying jobs remotely Also want to live in major cities and as a result need a lot of money.
Speaker 0: But if everyone work from home, right?
Speaker 0: So now you have a major city and the major city no longer has office buildings.
Speaker 0: It only has.
Speaker 0: that wouldn't be nearly enough apartments stores parks and apartment.
Speaker 1: I think if you converted every office office building in Manhattan into apartments our rent wouldn't go down at all.
Speaker 0: No But I'm saying is like what would the city be like if there were no office buildings?
Speaker 0: it'd be a dense paradise.
Speaker 0: Everyone is literally the only people are working on computers that are in their apartments or in Starbucks's or even better We were.
Speaker 1: a lot of the offices would probably be replaced with co-working spaces for those few times You do need like a conference room.
Speaker 1: There's like a place where you just rent one out and go for it.
Speaker 1: What's interesting is that all the people who do job like the people I work with in my company and just people I work with In general who do your kind of work?
Speaker 1: Engineering as opposed to like what I do.
Speaker 1: They work at home all the time and it totally just works.
Speaker 0: I work from home.
Speaker 0: They now let me work from home whenever I want and I work from home less than everyone else in my department.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'm like, all right.
Speaker 1: I have a lot of engineers that work from home like three days a week.
Speaker 1: They're just as productive.
Speaker 1: It's totally fine.
Speaker 1: Like working from home in technology.
Speaker 0: I do the same little amount of work.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like if you can just enough to keep my job And then be told that I'm doing a great job.
Speaker 1: This is why I like again.
Speaker 1: This is why I would never hire you to work for me.
Speaker 0: I was doing a great job though.
Speaker 0: You'd be so satisfied with the amount of work I do.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it depends cuz the two hours that it's been working.
Speaker 0: I'm super productive and I get all the.
Speaker 0: all the tickets are done.
Speaker 0: I don't need everything you wanted me to do.
Speaker 1: I don't think you could get all the tickets.
Speaker 1: I would open done.
Speaker 0: Oh, you think you can actually open.
Speaker 0: no one seen no job.
Speaker 0: I have been at all three.
Speaker 0: four of them because I had one for a long time Has been is to give me enough work that I could actually not do it.
Speaker 0: They just can't give me enough work because I get it done so fast.
Speaker 1: No Well speaking of which I think we finally we killed enough time so we can end the episode.
Speaker 1: It's been about an hour and I'm really hungry as I'm gonna heat up that chili.
Speaker 0: I'm also very hungry.
Speaker 1: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music Kat Lee for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Speaker 0: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 1: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays and make comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 0: But unlike those other late shows It's actually recorded at night.
Speaker 1: and the patreon patrons for this episode of geek nights right before we head off to packs Unplugged and I'm sorry if I sound distracted, but I'm watching the Rangers game while I do this Craig Oliver, Alan Joyce Heidi McNichol a shimmering Ruby obelisk hanging in the sky charge chart a vision my study comm link He gee, oh, no, someone's hurting the game.
Speaker 1: J fan scoot alone Lee Roberto Kingsley Sean Yeager Matthew Smith Nicholas brand new mr Strong stretch in 4 to 1 creations Chris Reimer and Thomas Hahn Sheriff about horrible Rory Rochelle, Montanona Superboy sailor Vista Don Schleich Joe sure Joe star Clinton Walton rent from New Zealand Ryan parent or open lander Finn all caps one exclamation mark Chris midkiff Daniel Redmond Sean Klein Chris Reimer Thomas
Speaker 0: on
Speaker 1: and the rail.
Speaker 1: No, they didn't actually score.
Speaker 1: So, uh, I'm really sorry for what I'm about to do to all of you but The thing I'm about to play Your moment the thing I do at the end of every episode Has been stuck in my head on a loop for a week And this is your last chance to stop listening before it is stuck in your head on a loop possibly forever.
Speaker 1: So all I have to say is that you have the stars to guide you Amigos.
Speaker 0: We're three caballeros three gay caballeros, they say we are birds of a feather.
Speaker 0: We're happy amigos.
Speaker 0: no matter where he goes the one two and three goes.
Speaker 0: we're always together.
Speaker 0: We're three happy chappies with snap piece a rap piece.
Speaker 0: you'll find us beneath our sombreros.
Speaker 1: Oh We're brave and we'll stay.
Speaker 1: so we're bright.
Speaker 1: there's a peso.
Speaker 0: we say so Get ours here beside us To play.
Speaker 0: as we go We sing and we Samba.
Speaker 0: we shall take em, but what means hi Caramba?
Speaker 0: Oh, yes Oh stormy weather.
Speaker 0: We stand together Like We may be when some Latin baby says yes Oh.