Speaker 1:
Speaker 0: It's Monday August 6th 2018.
Speaker 0: I'm rim.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott and this is geek nights tonight.
Speaker 0: keyboard shortcuts.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: So I'm not one to complain about the heat.
Speaker 0: I'm the opposite of that.
Speaker 0: I'm pretty much always complaining that it's not hot enough.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't complain.
Speaker 0: I'd like it to be really.
Speaker 1: I don't ever complain about heat or humidity because even if it does get a Point where it's even slightly uncomfortable, but I just remember that anyway I just imagine it being cold again, and I'm like well.
Speaker 1: I'll take this.
Speaker 1: yeah, no question It's like even a hundred.
Speaker 1: something degrees is more comfortable than like 40.
Speaker 0: Yeah, in fact 40 is the worst because if it's like zero I can go skin fuck ski.
Speaker 0: if it's a hundred I can enjoy the heat, but if it's like 40 I both can't ski and can't go outside.
Speaker 0: But I think you can do nothing.
Speaker 1: even though I like heat the thing that I actually don't like is the bright sun with its evil burn.
Speaker 0: The bright Sun is that like.
Speaker 0: that is literally the primary aspect of why I like the heat.
Speaker 1: I want it to be dark and a hundred degrees.
Speaker 0: I do enjoy that.
Speaker 0: One of my favorite things on earth is to go for a long road or a long bike ride in the middle of the night When it's really hot at night.
Speaker 1: the point is today.
Speaker 1: It was one of those situations where it was nice and super toasty everywhere to the point at which most people were uncomfortable.
Speaker 1: I was very comfortable, but in the Sun you could feel it like burning.
Speaker 1: you you probably could have cooked food outside.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I like that.
Speaker 0: I like that.
Speaker 0: I like to run.
Speaker 0: It's like shorts.
Speaker 1: No shirt I like it was.
Speaker 1: I like that.
Speaker 1: it was warm But then I had to go in the shade and I was disappointed in the shade.
Speaker 1: good that it was colder But I was happy in the shade that it was less bright And it was a I had to basically couldn't.
Speaker 1: it was either too bright and warm enough or slightly cold and but not bright.
Speaker 0: But so I've been trying to run half marathons like every weekend.
Speaker 0: I'm trying to get my times down.
Speaker 1: Is that healthy?
Speaker 0: Yeah, there's a full marathon.
Speaker 0: see like there's some evidence that if you do that a lot it'll cause joint damage.
Speaker 1: How far can I bike before it counts as a marathon?
Speaker 0: Ah biking so far You'll be worried more about things like incontinence and impotence.
Speaker 1: I mean, that's just gonna happen when I'm old anyway.
Speaker 0: Yeah, biking can cause specific issues there, especially if you use a fancy narrow-ass bike seat, but I digress.
Speaker 0: so I Started my run on Saturday like I usually do but it was hot And more importantly I thought the rain ended like the air quality be good.
Speaker 0: The air quality was actually really bad and caught is real bad Yeah, and I hit about the 10-mile mark and my lungs were just like hey rim.
Speaker 0: Yeah now you should stop You're gonna be in bed You're gonna not have a good time if you don't stop.
Speaker 0: and I did stop and then I was just exhausted and tired for the entire Rest of the day Probably because of the ozone in the air.
Speaker 1: Well, you were all getting drinking poison.
Speaker 1: I went to that.
Speaker 1: I just went to bike around and I just went to the park cuz whatever Run should we actually between?
Speaker 0: all of us drank relatively little poison?
Speaker 1: More than zero poison.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we all had like one beer.
Speaker 0: a couple of people had to one home a giant mug of poison yeah, and Giant gypsy toast covered in fruit and jam and it was amazing.
Speaker 1: Anyway, and also it's Cavazas, I biked around the park.
Speaker 1: I'm just whooshing around in a circle and like my legs are like, whatever You're just going to stupid.
Speaker 0: I will not use fair Celsius.
Speaker 0: Fahrenheit is superior and I'll fight you.
Speaker 0: That's the hill.
Speaker 0: I'll die.
Speaker 1: Anyway, am I?
Speaker 1: and but like every time I went up the hill my my lung was like My leg was like Isn't even barely a hill?
Speaker 1: I'm not.
Speaker 1: you know how many gears we can go lower than this.
Speaker 0: to quote a legendary comedian Don't breathe no more.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that was when he's talking about having a heart attack.
Speaker 0: But there's there's the point when your body instead of cuz pain is normally a suggestion like hey You should probably knock this out like stop this like this is this is not good.
Speaker 0: But then there's when the body instead of saying hey stop it the body gives a directive.
Speaker 1: There's one guy was biking and I passed him on the way into the park.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and he was playing Some really awful like 2000s pop song.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and then I didn't see him again.
Speaker 1: But then I kept going around and I did.
Speaker 1: I caught up to him and he was playing staying alive And then so I tried to like bike next to him so I could listen.
Speaker 1: groove to the stand a lot Yeah, and then we got to the hill and then he was way slower And I like.
Speaker 1: I tried to slow down to hear more music, but I couldn't slow down that much.
Speaker 0: So a real sad thing.
Speaker 1: happy weird like if I hit the brakes.
Speaker 1: just this guy.
Speaker 0: So This dude was biking.
Speaker 0: He was like our age and like seemed fit and he was honored like a kind of normal bike.
Speaker 0: But I beat him over the RFK bridge on foot and he was biking the entire time both up and downhill On the uphill.
Speaker 0: He was clearly in the wrong gear and didn't know how bikes work.
Speaker 0: So he was.
Speaker 1: he was like jumping into like so many wrong gear people and I don't know how to help them.
Speaker 0: And if they're it's not even like you only had one gear he had.
Speaker 1: No, I don't stop I don't even think about helping someone if they don't have a gear.
Speaker 1: but the other thing is that if I see someone in a Bad gear and I want to help them like even if I try to help them like they don't Listen, and even if and if I'm afraid especially if they're not a man that it'll be mansplaining Yeah, I don't.
Speaker 1: it's not an explain It's like how do you balance that?
Speaker 1: not wanting to mansplain but also want genuinely wanting to help people because if they did stop And listen to me and I gave him like a two-minute lesson on how to use the fucking gears They could go whoosh in.
Speaker 1: their life would be so much better.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I gave up on helping people.
Speaker 0: I only talk to people if I'm making fun of them for their the fact that they only have one gear.
Speaker 0: Usually my advice will be you know You could go a lot faster uphill if you had more than one gear and they get really mad and then I bike away.
Speaker 0: They can't catch me because they only have one gear.
Speaker 0: But usually when I'm running Fixie dudes will go real slow like I'll pass them because they can't bike faster than I can run uphill But then they'll pass me on the downhill cuz on a bike.
Speaker 0: This dude not only couldn't get up the hill because he was in the wrong gear But then he couldn't go down the hill at speed.
Speaker 0: I think he was braking the whole time So I basically ran down the RFK faster than him.
Speaker 1: Was he just not afraid to pass you cuz it's too narrow?
Speaker 0: Oh, no, he I left him in the dust.
Speaker 0: Okay, I actually stopped at the bottom of the bridge partly because the ozone.
Speaker 0: That's when I hit the 10-mile mark and I was running out of steam.
Speaker 0: So I waited to the bottom of the bridge like catching my breath and drinking water and he came down like four minutes after me.
Speaker 1: well, so if He has to go down the stairs.
Speaker 0: Maybe he was clumsy with the bike on the stairs He might have been he might have been but he even on the downhill before we hit the stairs Never got up with me.
Speaker 0: It was the first time in my life I passed a biker on the uphill on foot and then they did not catch up to me on the downhill.
Speaker 1: You know someone slow when I'm coasting not even pedaling uphill and I'm passing them.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I ran into that too.
Speaker 1: That happens more than you would think.
Speaker 1: Somebody's pedaling a bike next to me but they don't know how to bike and they don't know how to use gears even if they're fit.
Speaker 1: and I stopped pedaling and Still my velocities remains greater than theirs and I just keep going past them without the moral of this.
Speaker 0: Is that the most assured way to enrage a New Yorker or at least to get our interest in a negative fashion in the way?
Speaker 0: Is to be slow in any capacity?
Speaker 0: you're moving slowly on in on foot or on a bicycle.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that is a problem.
Speaker 0: So there's actually a lot of tech news.
Speaker 0: I don't think we'll go into these too deep, but I'll start with Scott's this Vanity Fair article, right?
Speaker 1: So basically, I think Steve Jobs daughter Lisa the one that the Lisa computer was or was not named after I think she wrote a memoir.
Speaker 1: There's the excerpt of it, which is mostly the parts about Steve Jobs that's on Vanity Fair.
Speaker 1: That's the only part you're gonna be interested in for tech news, right?
Speaker 1: yeah, but it's you can see what you can like.
Speaker 1: this is the most learn what Steve Jobs is really like kind of thing and This really matches my Basically existing assumptions based on his like public persona.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and also my assumptions about all Silicon Valley douche bag And all rich people which is fuck them.
Speaker 0: yeah, I You know, I think there should be a maximum wage.
Speaker 1: I Think there should be a lot of things.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but yeah, if you're interested, you know, if you're interested at all and you know Steve Jobs, although I do not like him was a very important person in the history of technology and was the you know Primary reason that Apple computer is the first trillion dollar corporation to ever exist Yeah, and is now basically evil cyberpunk Co number one.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they're like number three, I think the biggest.
Speaker 0: Anyway, well, no, they have the.
Speaker 0: they have the largest wine is calf.
Speaker 0: That does not mean they're actually the biggest important person regardless.
Speaker 1: You know, you should.
Speaker 1: you should learn about him.
Speaker 1: They care about technologies and this is about as close to learn about his personality.
Speaker 1: You know someone who was half shared half his DNA is or whatever.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah right in the summary here It describes him as mercurial and it sounds about right.
Speaker 0: I'm sure I read this Mercurial.
Speaker 0: things will happen.
Speaker 0: So there's some other news.
Speaker 0: if you were paying attention today You might have seen a lot of articles that all said leak says Microsoft's gonna charge a monthly fee for Windows.
Speaker 1: I didn't see that.
Speaker 0: This was all over the internet like a little while ago.
Speaker 1: Okay, I guess I actually did some work today.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, we both have newest jobs and we're both actually doing work.
Speaker 1: I read plenty in it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but So one that is not true and the mean.
Speaker 1: if it was I definitely would find a way.
Speaker 1: every time there have been throughout Microsoft Windows history There have always been like oh no Windows is gonna be even eviler now.
Speaker 1: Oh, no, oh no, and in the?
Speaker 1: oh, no never happened really Yeah.
Speaker 0: Or some of the things that a lot of people say oh they'll do this evil thing Were things they should do like forcing people to upgrade Like I think they should force people to take their patches.
Speaker 1: Fuck you I think so, too.
Speaker 0: So the actual story here and it really is funny how many?
Speaker 0: Scare mongering articles really had no idea what the deal was.
Speaker 0: It's pretty straightforward.
Speaker 1: I gotta get it clicks and I get it clicks of the real story.
Speaker 0: So Microsoft is probably going to offer a managed service for Windows PCs aimed at companies.
Speaker 0: This is not aimed at like you and your house or your tiny company.
Speaker 0: This is aimed at a company that's big enough.
Speaker 1: I mean Windows is already dying in the end people's houses because everyone just uses their phone and tablet.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so even if they they did this people would just like stop using the desktops all together.
Speaker 1: They would just all go to.
Speaker 1: yeah.
Speaker 1: So why would they do?
Speaker 1: why would they kill off the remaining whatever they got left?
Speaker 0: Yeah, cuz the only reason to run Windows is that new surface tablet that's smaller.
Speaker 1: That's supposed to be way good like surface go.
Speaker 0: if you don't need the like high performance of a regular surface device.
Speaker 0: This thing's great.
Speaker 1: It actually seems pretty good from what people are saying.
Speaker 1: I haven't seen one.
Speaker 0: I would consider getting it when my laptop dies because it could do everything my current laptop does better.
Speaker 0: It's actually way faster than my current laptop But I'll probably get the one with like the video card like the real surface.
Speaker 0: But anyway, so the only people who use Windows at home are gamers because it's really the only PC gaming platform like there's no other way to play PC games or people who are making content and don't want to run a Mac.
Speaker 0: And frankly if you're making content you probably want to use Windows because you can get real hardware.
Speaker 1: like a lot of people these days They're using like hackintosh, which is a PC, but you install OS X Yeah, or they're some getting like some external GPU nonsense, or they're who knows yeah.
Speaker 1: But anyway the real story is managed service or dealing with the slow beginning the most expensive Mac and dealing with it.
Speaker 0: so a company could basically pay Microsoft a monthly fee like per desk and have a Windows desktop that Microsoft will manage for you meaning group policies and Patches and updates and if an update breaks something they'll take care of it.
Speaker 1: I think a lot of companies will jump on this because a lot of companies has to be cheaper than your IT guy or better enough that it's worth paying the extra.
Speaker 1: or you know the math just has to work out and you'll switch to it because
Speaker 0: a giant company
Speaker 1: even if you have an IT guy you might even keep the IT guy on and Pay for this because now your IT guy can spend all their time doing something else.
Speaker 0: Yep, because a lot of companies will not pay for an IT person
Speaker 1: dealing with the shitty phones Yeah shitty network to
Speaker 0: administer like their internal Active Directory or the internal desktop PCs like a lot of companies struggle with this and This is I think a really good thing for Microsoft to offer because a lot of companies offer this service on top of Microsoft.
Speaker 0: They'll basically come into a company and provide managed IT services and I suspect a lot of those companies do a bad job.
Speaker 0: so Microsoft can both take the VIG and Cut these middlemen out of the equation and provide the service directly.
Speaker 1: I mean, this is the thing that's always right anytime your business is based on someone else's platform.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right if you sell Accessories for a Toyota car Right, you know what?
Speaker 0: I might start selling Toyota.
Speaker 1: a might include that accessory as a feature in the cars.
Speaker 1: to begin with Right be.
Speaker 1: they might offer it as an add-on and now no one's gonna buy your third-party one Yeah, or they just might buy your whole company.
Speaker 1: That's what you want.
Speaker 1: And this happens all the time I remember.
Speaker 1: the one I remember the most is some fancy Visual Studio plug-in back in the day and it was like Microsoft is gonna at threatened to add the feature to Visual Studio.
Speaker 1: And then the basically they worked it out and Microsoft bought the plug-in company instead and then added the feature to Visual Studio.
Speaker 1: Right, so it's just you know, it's not necessarily a software feature, but it's still a service for a particular product.
Speaker 1: It's like well, we'll just offer the service with the product.
Speaker 0: So that's all this news is there's nothing to be afraid of.
Speaker 0: if you somehow heard that Microsoft is gonna charge a monthly fee for Windows.
Speaker 0: Click even one article get one sentence into any article and you could have figured out what the real story is in some other news.
Speaker 0: Google according to a bunch of leaks Apple Google Microsoft and Google.
Speaker 1: All right, cover all the bases here.
Speaker 0: They.
Speaker 0: basically we're gonna launch a censored search in China.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm way back in the day.
Speaker 1: way back They were in China and China was like you must censor the Google search and Google said no We're just gonna stop putting Google in China And that's why Chinese people use Baidu or QQ or whatever the other.
Speaker 1: the alternative things are.
Speaker 1: So I think it's Baidu right.
Speaker 0: the confidential project dragonfly Was leaked to a group of Google employees wider than the tiny group of Google employees who were working on.
Speaker 1: Tiny group of people at Google who are sudden had changed the previous Google policy and we're now willing to do this.
Speaker 0: We're willing to make a censored search engine.
Speaker 1: other Google employees We're the ones not willing to do this found out that other Google people were evil and we're doing this.
Speaker 0: It seems that a lot of like Google employees freaked out demanded the project to be canceled.
Speaker 0: a bunch of people threatened to quit.
Speaker 0: There's a lot of like.
Speaker 0: there's a lot of interesting stories about what's going.
Speaker 0: this is like developing news.
Speaker 0: This is still ongoing.
Speaker 0: So this article will sort of cover the baseline of where we are.
Speaker 1: But I mean even if they managed to complete it with the team of people who had no ethical more qualms Yeah, and then they deployed it then everyone would find out and quit.
Speaker 1: you'd have the same problem later.
Speaker 1: Wouldn't it be just be better?
Speaker 1: Right?
Speaker 1: It's like come on.
Speaker 0: Yep So there's all sorts of drama about this and this is a good thing.
Speaker 0: I'm actually very happy that people inside Google are both willing to leak this to the public and Actually quit their jobs or threaten to quit their jobs over it.
Speaker 1: Well, you got a company is big enough.
Speaker 1: There's always gonna be Pete right?
Speaker 1: It's like in a small company like mine.
Speaker 1: I don't think there's any people at my company who have any Disagreements on yeah.
Speaker 0: All right, like you don't hire someone who disagrees with your business model, right?
Speaker 1: But when your company is massive, you're gonna have all kinds of people right that what that you know.
Speaker 1: The the what's it called guy worked at Google right the whole.
Speaker 1: what was his name?
Speaker 1: That could be any number of people now the whole the guy who wrote the sexist thing Oh, yeah, and all the Google people fought each other.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: It's like they were all Google employees.
Speaker 1: It's just so big, right?
Speaker 1: It's like if I even if I was the CEO of Google I couldn't personally screen everyone to make sure they weren't a piece of shit.
Speaker 1: This is the second time My only job and I wouldn't even get to it that this happened to Google?
Speaker 0: because a couple months ago a bunch of good A bunch of other Google employees working on project Maven.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm and Maven was the project to make AI for drone kill bots Yep, and Google employees were like, yeah, we'll quit.
Speaker 0: This is fucked.
Speaker 0: We do not want to do this and as best I can tell Google actually is Letting the contract with the Pentagon.
Speaker 0: I think was the Pentagon with the US government run out and they're not going to continue the project.
Speaker 0: tons of employees threatened to quit Practitioned so these two stories is the only thing right?
Speaker 1: Is that like?
Speaker 1: threatening to quit is good Especially if you're a valuable employee who's they really really need?
Speaker 0: there's a subtle point there I think.
Speaker 0: a big part of why or if you have enough employees that you can threaten to quit a big part of why?
Speaker 0: I think Google employees in particular and this is just a pig In both these instances are willing.
Speaker 0: it's not just they have a ton of money It's that people with these sets of skills are in desperate demand right now Across industries, but these people can all snap their fingers and work for any other company.
Speaker 1: in this I think a better Thing to do than quit though, right sabotage.
Speaker 1: Why did you figure me out?
Speaker 1: Is that?
Speaker 1: some people say oh you should stay and that way you still.
Speaker 1: you're still in the system and you can still work to Make things better.
Speaker 1: Well, there's some people say quit you shouldn't be working for an evil system.
Speaker 1: I say stay in the system and sabotage.
Speaker 0: Well, wasn't that the plot of Rogue One?
Speaker 1: Yes, I mean, yeah There is a.
Speaker 0: I would say there is a time and a place for that.
Speaker 0: Neither one of these stories are at the line where I would directly advocate sabotage.
Speaker 1: No, if they but if they had actually launched the Chinese Google, yeah, and then that's the first I heard.
Speaker 0: so Why am I the real like awesome thing?
Speaker 0: if Google were the company it was 15 years ago The awesome thing to do would be to have the secret project launch their sensor search engine in China.
Speaker 0: Get adopt like make it the biggest search engine in China and then three years down the line Open the goddamn floodgates and spill the beans on everything inside China.
Speaker 1: China just turn the site off.
Speaker 0: Yeah But they could get the data out pretty quick like set it up such that they could blow their load and leak information All over China.
Speaker 1: I think what's more likely what they would do is if they had managed to secretly develop this.
Speaker 1: yeah, they would put it out in China and know and brand it and put it on infrastructure as such that nobody would know Google Had made it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't know the brand.
Speaker 1: Google would be called something else.
Speaker 1: It would just be a suspiciously good Chinese search engine.
Speaker 0: But if you work in technology and a lot of the people listen to Monday gig nights, too my only advice to you is if your company is doing something that is unethical and It's a beyond a certain line of unethical
Speaker 1: You
Speaker 0: have a responsibility to not do the thing, right?
Speaker 1: Even though you know whistleblowing is technically supposed to have protections But in reality you're gonna take a huge personal reality.
Speaker 1: if you blow the whistle on things that are big enough You just get fucked but I'll fucking do it.
Speaker 0: Anyway, yep, like if your company's doing stuff with ice, you should make a big deal about that and threaten to quit.
Speaker 0: but anyway things of the day.
Speaker 0: So a long time ago.
Speaker 0: I did a thing of the day about this marble machine.
Speaker 0: You've seen it around the internet like rims paying big attention to this.
Speaker 0: Yeah cuz I've been following this guy.
Speaker 0: so The marble machine was this amazing YouTube video and it was made by this dude who has this band called winter gotten.
Speaker 0: and they do Like cool concerts and everything.
Speaker 1: a winter got and not winter garden not winter garden.
Speaker 0: winter got on.
Speaker 1: Oh winter garden is a theater yeah, so winter gotten.
Speaker 0: and Basically, the dude has been Continuously making YouTube videos every week for a long time.
Speaker 1: I probably made a bunch of money from them.
Speaker 0: Yeah on He's made.
Speaker 0: basically the problem with that original marble machine as amazing as that video was is that it was basically a glass cannon.
Speaker 0: That thing could run once and it barely ran.
Speaker 0: Like it is so cobbled together.
Speaker 0: It couldn't go on tour.
Speaker 0: It's in a museum now and it's retired like it can't be used again.
Speaker 0: I'm sure you could reset it with enough effort, but it wouldn't be easy Yeah, and it's hard to make it go and he can't travel with it.
Speaker 0: So his goal was to Learn all the skills necessary to make a new marble machine that is robust and can go in a world tour Mm-hmm, and he's been like.
Speaker 0: I've watched videos in this channel where he like learned how to weld from scratch and then welded.
Speaker 0: He learned CNC he learned 3d printing he learned modeling.
Speaker 0: and if you watch all these videos.
Speaker 0: they're so meditative and so fascinating and Now is a good time to start watching them because the machines starting to come together And unlike a lot of the series where you might watch like someone building a machine Usually those series are retrospective on something that already succeeded.
Speaker 0: We don't actually know if this will work.
Speaker 1: It's gonna work eventually.
Speaker 1: He's not gonna stop until it works as he's making them.
Speaker 1: someone who's this determined is gonna keep going until it works.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it will happen.
Speaker 1: Eventually.
Speaker 1: It's just a matter of when will it be this year next year Also some of the videos.
Speaker 0: he fails like he fucks up.
Speaker 1: Yeah That's what happens when you work on something.
Speaker 1: Sometimes you fuck the fuck
Speaker 0: up and he learned stuff along the way and if you watch them like you could learn these same skills Because he goes from nothing and he asks people and looks on the internet and like oh This is how you weld and now I'll try to weld and that was a really.
Speaker 1: just go on YouTube Yeah, or go to welding school, which is probably a better idea.
Speaker 0: So this is so.
Speaker 0: I'm linking to this because this is the video where he makes the flywheel and it's it's Really?
Speaker 0: I like flywheels like it All right.
Speaker 0: I Specifically like flywheels.
Speaker 0: the very end he holds the clock up and he gets the flywheel spinning and he sees how long it'll spin a long time.
Speaker 0: When this has a world tour, it's definitely coming to New York and I'm actually keeping my eye out.
Speaker 1: I'm Number one fan.
Speaker 1: You're gonna get his autograph.
Speaker 0: He's got over a million subscribers.
Speaker 0: He's pretty big.
Speaker 0: now kiss his foot.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'm a big fan of this guy and I will go see this in concert.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so what's your thing of the day?
Speaker 1: So last week I had a thing of the day where it was like some jousting on the front of boats.
Speaker 0: Everyone I have showed that video to three seconds in goes.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, that's real good.
Speaker 1: Here is in Germany a place where they I guess they do play some ice hockey in Germany, but not much.
Speaker 1: Yeah So they have ice rinks in Germany, but in Germany they play soccer.
Speaker 1: That's their sport.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they didn't do too well this World Cup, but they usually do much better.
Speaker 1: They're pretty good at soccer.
Speaker 1: I think I read somewhere that like if you can't if you add up all the soccer leagues in Germany I think was it isn't called like the Bundesliga or something that there's like Thousands of soccer teams all in these leagues.
Speaker 1: who it?
Speaker 1: I get they have more soccer teams like than God anyway And that's just in Germany.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, but here is people playing, you know I mean, they don't play ice hockey, but here they are with with an ice rink.
Speaker 0: Well, a lot of fans will describe soccer as slow grass hockey.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but here they are playing foot soccer.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and it's awesome, yeah, it's awesome because it is based on watching this video as dangerous as you could imagine Ice hockey is as dangerous as you can imagine.
Speaker 1: This looks more dangerous than the only reason ice hockey looks less dangerous is because the people doing it are professionals who practiced not Stabbing each other with skates.
Speaker 1: Yeah, also to imagine if a bunch of chumps go out and tried to play ice hockey You didn't know what the fuck they were doing.
Speaker 1: There would be blood on the ice very quickly.
Speaker 0: This basically has all the ridiculousness of ice hockey But what it does not have is the grace of ice hockey because ice hockey is a clever balance of brutality and grace.
Speaker 0: This is just the brutality and people falling over over and over and over again Mostly the second part.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but also this short clips got linked to.
Speaker 0: I mean your thing today is basically an animated gif.
Speaker 1: Yeah But I couldn't find.
Speaker 1: I mean sure I'm sure if you knew what to search for you could find a full video But this is all spoilers.
Speaker 0: They score a goal and someone falls over.
Speaker 1: This is all I could find.
Speaker 1: Yeah in the meta moment with my minimal effort.
Speaker 0: The new geek nights book club is going to be the Odyssey.
Speaker 1: That's another Odyssey.
Speaker 1: we'll do all Odyssey.
Speaker 1: the Space Odyssey went from the Greek Odyssey to the Space Odyssey lots and lots of Odyssey's.
Speaker 1: so just yesterday I went to the theater to see 2001 a Space Odyssey in 70 millimeter.
Speaker 1: How was that?
Speaker 1: I hadn't seen it.
Speaker 1: But first of all, we went to get a rep us.
Speaker 1: then we walked over to the theater and it was fucking crowded.
Speaker 1: I couldn't even believe it's been playing all week and like it wasn't 100% full, but it was very full.
Speaker 1: Yeah, nothing looks as good as I mean no no.
Speaker 1: current HD screen of digital.
Speaker 1: This is as good as 70 millimeter film because the film is enormous And also, you know the acoustics of that particular theater insane.
Speaker 1: so it was very loud.
Speaker 1: like when the when the when the When the monolith goes when they're on the moon like everyone puts their finger in there Just like the astronauts because it was so fucking loud.
Speaker 0: I haven't seen that movie in a long time.
Speaker 1: I hadn't seen it in a long time, but I saw it again and knowing what I know I've been learning more and more about it recently because I read like the first forward and the chap first I guess I should buy a Kindle copy of the book.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think a paper versions actually a few cents cheaper.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but anyway, but So I didn't realize right that this movie was actually made in the mid 60s And it came out in 68 before anyone landed on the moon.
Speaker 1: Right, I can't.
Speaker 1: before Star Wars and I'm sure I mean, it's not I can't really spoil.
Speaker 1: I mean, I've seen the movie.
Speaker 1: It's not spoilers, right?
Speaker 1: There's no way you can spoil something.
Speaker 1: the the the statute of limitations is far gone.
Speaker 0: Odysseus makes it home and murders all the suitors, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah But yeah, the ending of the movie is obviously very Evangelion esque, but I cannot think of anything older that has that kind of psychedelic messed up non concrete ending Maybe.
Speaker 0: maybe like some Stanislaus lamb short story might or something.
Speaker 0: I mean short stories maybe but like not movies or TV or anything like yours that not like a full like a movie.
Speaker 1: So it makes me wonder.
Speaker 1: we'll talk about this more in the book club episode.
Speaker 1: Is this the original terrible secret of space?
Speaker 1: Maybe if you know any older Previous terrible secrets of space.
Speaker 1: Let me know.
Speaker 0: Otherwise, we are going to be live.
Speaker 0: the PAX West schedule just went up and the PAX website went down like immediately.
Speaker 0: So we will be there all weekend like the whole con just doing stuff playing games.
Speaker 0: We will not be a pecs dev this year.
Speaker 0: We're skipping it.
Speaker 0: I want to go.
Speaker 1: Ben Brode is doing the keynote.
Speaker 1: It's gonna be a good one.
Speaker 1: I really want.
Speaker 1: I read a preview of his keynote where he asked a basic interview with him asking about the stuff He's gonna talk about and it seemed way good.
Speaker 0: Yep, but sometimes they put the keynotes from dev online So they're not privileged.
Speaker 1: I've never seen one.
Speaker 0: It depends some panels at pecs dev that people who run them agree that it can be made public.
Speaker 1: I don't think he's gonna reveal any secrets or anything.
Speaker 0: Probably not.
Speaker 1: doesn't seem like he's gonna talk about that kind of stuff.
Speaker 1: So we'll see.
Speaker 0: it is public.
Speaker 0: I will definitely make it a thing of the day Yeah, or I'll just link to it as a news whatever little show on it if it's real good.
Speaker 0: But on Monday at 10 a.m.
Speaker 0: We will be 10 a.m.
Speaker 0: Pacific time.
Speaker 0: our panel the 40 table-to-top games you must be labor day, you know It's labor day will be live streamed on either pecs 2 or pecs 3 one of the two Non-main theater pecs twitch streams.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm We will probably not take questions in the audience meaning we'll definitely not take questions from the twitch stream.
Speaker 1: I was the twitch stream good guy.
Speaker 0: I Used to take questions from the twitch stream on behalf of like for the panels back when I did that.
Speaker 1: I want to answer.
Speaker 1: if you want to ask questions while twitch streaming wait for me to just twitch stream something on my own.
Speaker 0: Well, you know what I did for that is I let all the stupid questions fly by and I only took the one that was Good, I mean even so yeah.
Speaker 0: Otherwise, yeah that the next kind we get after that is like packs unplugged.
Speaker 0: and then Magfest which we will be at pretty sure.
Speaker 1: magfest is going to announce its dates Imminently, so if you want to go to magfest magfest has traditionally been around New Year's.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's not hard to guess the dates of magfest if you were to bet on them Vegas would not take your money because the odds of you being right are so good.
Speaker 1: It's gonna be within - it's gonna be a Thursday through a Sunday.
Speaker 1: It's gonna be early in January.
Speaker 0: It's gonna be between.
Speaker 1: they got like three weekends to choose.
Speaker 0: It'll be at earliest the very end of December and at latest Probably like the first weekend in February.
Speaker 1: like that is the way we never go to February.
Speaker 1: So gonna be January and and even late January's a crack is unlikely.
Speaker 0: So they're probably gonna announce it real soon.
Speaker 0: So if you want to go to magfest jump on that because they do sell out of badges now And they might well, they need to sell out of hotel rooms now.
Speaker 0: Well, they definitely sell out of hotel rooms.
Speaker 1: You're gonna have to stay in a hotel far away and take a shitty shuttle all the way.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's gonna suck which is a 24/7 con.
Speaker 1: You know, I think they just announced the dates really just now.
Speaker 0: Pat just pointed out that they just announced the dates like just this second while recording the podcast.
Speaker 0: gonna find out I'm going to their Twitter.
Speaker 1: Magfest the time on the tweet.
Speaker 0: Let's see man.
Speaker 0: three hours ago.
Speaker 0: Magfest is January 3rd through 6.
Speaker 1: Oh shit.
Speaker 1: Looks like I bet wisely.
Speaker 0: Yes, if you do not have a total hotel for magfest go get one.
Speaker 1: right now You're not watching the stream, which you shouldn't be.
Speaker 0: if you're watching the stream go there right now.
Speaker 1: The rest of the stream it's not gonna be.
Speaker 0: retweet this right now Because they don't sell out as fast as PAX East, but they sell out.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: So a long long time ago August 7th 2007 okay.
Speaker 0: We did a geek nights episode 11 years ago on FPS key bindings.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: Oh, we probably talked about how uses weird shit in the bottom right area because so the way he played doom or whatever.
Speaker 0: in the news of that episode We announced that like valve was releasing 24 old games on Steam and we're really excited about it.
Speaker 0: And Best Buy did.
Speaker 0: what is Best Buy?
Speaker 0: do Best Buy?
Speaker 0: Oh that does not link to the article.
Speaker 0: So, I don't know.
Speaker 0: Best Buy did something and there's literally no way to know what it was.
Speaker 1: All right, we can listen to the episode.
Speaker 0: Yeah And in January 21st 2008 we did an episode on keyboards.
Speaker 0: But what?
Speaker 0: we have never talked about our keyboard shortcuts and we realized we actually have a lot to say about keyboard shortcuts.
Speaker 0: Yeah,
Speaker 1: well, I mean the thing with keyboard shortcuts right is like there's sort of this thing that's like People who could use them to greatly improve their computing efficiency
Speaker 0: seem to refuse to don't
Speaker 1: or whatever and then also simultaneous to that There's a lot of people more and more who can't write.
Speaker 1: young people don't even use a keyboard computer with a keyboard anymore.
Speaker 1: They got a phone or a tablet or a gaming console or whatever.
Speaker 0: There aren't keyboard shortcuts on tablets, right?
Speaker 0: There are gestures, but I find that most people don't use gestures either.
Speaker 1: It's weird cuz like as a PC person you think all these kids playing Fortnite.
Speaker 1: you imagine them sitting at their computers like no They're not Fortnite on their phone or on their ps4.
Speaker 1: Who knows what.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna try it out You know what?
Speaker 0: I'm gonna play it on my switch.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm not playing it.
Speaker 0: But yeah, probably more up your alley than G.
Speaker 1: young people do not use keyboards at all Really, and even if they do not a lot of them can type properly.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there's only the ones who got into PC gaming.
Speaker 1: somehow.
Speaker 1: Usually the ones who don't live in America is be more likely to be when we say properly.
Speaker 0: I don't even care if you type like the proper proper way.
Speaker 0: It's just.
Speaker 0: can you type fast?
Speaker 1: Yep without looking.
Speaker 0: Yep While these kids are pretty fast on their phones They cannot type as fast as me on a keyboard.
Speaker 1: also old people, right?
Speaker 1: some of them can type especially if they were even if they were typewriter people.
Speaker 1: right and they.
Speaker 1: but they Don't use keyboard shortcuts.
Speaker 1: Like they're not you know, I is they do, you know only the ones who would be like eunuch Santas.
Speaker 1: Those are the only kind of old people who'd use keyboard truck.
Speaker 0: There's another kind of old person use keyboard shortcuts.
Speaker 0: These are the people who are very good at the most basic nonsense on computers And I say very good making air quotes.
Speaker 0: The kind of person whose job is to mess with Excel spreadsheets and type documents in Word.
Speaker 1: Even those people are very mousy.
Speaker 0: those people are very mousy But I've noticed that a lot of them tend to be told a set of keyboard shortcuts that they memorize.
Speaker 0: And if those keyboard shortcuts ever change or don't work, I think they are fucking paralyzed.
Speaker 1: I think people know ctrl C ctrl V.
Speaker 0: Yeah But they'll learn like ctrl I are or like.
Speaker 0: they'll know a thing to like In like a test like inserting a row in a spreadsheet like some bullshit like that
Speaker 1: Anyway,
Speaker 0: and they won't know how to do the thing Unless the exact menu that they were taught is still there or the keyboard shortcut that someone told them still works.
Speaker 1: So the people use keyboard shortcuts a lot.
Speaker 1: is this narrow group of people?
Speaker 1: actually even it's not it's still a large group But percentage wise it's a small group of people who a are in an age where they use computers of keyboards often They can type properly or well it well enough and also are computer savvy enough and interested in computing efficiency enough that they bother to learn and Muscle memorize shortcuts so that they don't have to touch the mouse and they could do computing things faster.
Speaker 0: now.
Speaker 0: I think most of the people who do this are Honestly Professional the kind of person who needs a PC to be a workstation like artists who are making arts.
Speaker 1: Yeah, Photoshop people.
Speaker 1: They know all these crazy shortcuts and Programmers they know whatever their text editor is.
Speaker 0: they know mad shortcuts Yep, but what's interesting is that for a lot of those use cases like especially like video a heavy video editing a lot of times people have Specialty input devices like.
Speaker 0: I have my shuttle that I use when I edit video But all that shuttle is doing while it has like the shuttle and the like all the like fancy dial type things.
Speaker 0: The rest of it is just a bunch of keyboard buttons that I've bound to do.
Speaker 1: keyboard shortcuts I mean pretty much everything's just a cube, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah Yeah, so the the thing with keyboard shortcuts, right?
Speaker 1: Is that they increase?
Speaker 1: you don't even realize how much they increase your computing efficiency.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right.
Speaker 1: if you want to have a race, right.
Speaker 1: and it's like okay accomplish pretty much pick any computing task Right.
Speaker 1: and it's someone who actually knows how to use keyboard shortcuts and someone who has to use the mouse all the time.
Speaker 1: The mouse person is going to lose pretty much everything all the time.
Speaker 1: Keyboards are just faster Just about everything.
Speaker 1: So I guess The keyboard shortcut I probably use the most is ctrl L. why cuz you're in a browser the most?
Speaker 1: So the key word shortcuts in the browser this this three that I use more than anything control L Highlights all the text in the location bars.
Speaker 1: you press ctrl L and start typing URL.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you really think you're gonna beat me by going up to with the mouse to the location bar and like clicking on it.
Speaker 1: I've already typed the URL and press enter Even if you can type as fast as me if you don't press ctrl L and you click there instead You've already lost right?
Speaker 0: So the keyboard shortcuts I use more than anything are ctrl Z Undo and ctrl Y though can redo.
Speaker 0: redo though actually in a lot of Adobe software redo Will only work once or undo will only work once it depends.
Speaker 0: You'll have like a separate like ctrl shift Z to step backward.
Speaker 0: Yeah, yeah But again already that's getting into professional Expert use cases and specialized.
Speaker 1: I'm at the browser right.
Speaker 1: the thing that everyone's using on a computer the browser.
Speaker 1: ctrl T for a new Tab ctrl W to close the current tab.
Speaker 0: control shift T is fucking wizardry to the shocking number of control.
Speaker 1: shift T open the last tab that got closed.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: You guys realize if you close a browser window And have another browser window open and in ctrl shift T It'll reopen that browser window and you keep hitting ctrl shift T. It keeps opening old tabs.
Speaker 1: you had net that you closed in the order.
Speaker 1: you closed them.
Speaker 1: Yep, you can do ctrl N for a new window.
Speaker 1: You could do all right and alt.
Speaker 1: left will go forward and back but backspace is also back.
Speaker 1: backspace is a really convenient back button.
Speaker 0: I Was that the hill I will die on and UX.
Speaker 0: the backspace key should never have done anything in a web browser ever.
Speaker 0: Well, it does other than backspace a character.
Speaker 0: That was the most bullshit UX design decision Anyone has ever made other than making the stairs Steeper on the eighth floor of my building and the shortcuts within Chrome Firefox, whatever.
Speaker 1: It's all slightly different.
Speaker 1: But yeah, like ctrl L works in just about every browser There's three categories of keyboard shortcuts.
Speaker 0: like really put a fine point on this.
Speaker 1: there's the Completely generic effectively universal control s saves on every piece of a software ever.
Speaker 0: Yep there's the ones that are common to the applications that normal people use regularly like web browsers.
Speaker 0: and then there's the Specialized shortcuts for professional workflows, which is actually the most interesting use case that really only professionals do and like normal people seem to be Incapable of.
Speaker 0: so like it's interesting watching people fumble through like Adobe software.
Speaker 0: Like when I first started learning how to edit video I would do everything with the keyboard because I didn't really know the best way to approach my task Like what kind of insert do I want to do?
Speaker 0: So the fact that there is a visual UI is very good for tasks They're new to you or tasks that are not commonly done by you.
Speaker 1: Well, also it's very convenient.
Speaker 1: you hover your mouse over an icon and it shows you Oh, you know, you could press this key instead of pressing this button with the mouse.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and it's like you go into a menu to be like your file menu and it just.
Speaker 1: all the shortcuts are listed in the Menu, so now you can learn if you keep clicking on the same menu option.
Speaker 1: It's like oh, there's a shortcut for this.
Speaker 1: I'm not gonna go up here anymore.
Speaker 1: And there's always that one really disappointing menu option that has no text next to it.
Speaker 0: Yep, it's like well, I guess I have to go to the menu for this but it's good because it allows discovery like it allows the person to learn the interface.
Speaker 0: and Frankly while there are like Adobe Audition and Premiere are good examples There are.
Speaker 0: I could literally bind keys to do goddamn anything.
Speaker 0: I can bind Macros look like I'm macros later and like really complex stuff, but the reality is Most super complex workflows.
Speaker 0: I don't do often or maybe I'll do once in the course of a project.
Speaker 0: I don't need a dedicated button there.
Speaker 1: I think it's very rare that you need anything.
Speaker 1: That's not the default, right?
Speaker 1: It's like unless you're have a job where you've you know have some complicated thing and even have a complicated thing.
Speaker 1: It's like.
Speaker 1: you should probably just have a piece of software that does it not need to program a macro.
Speaker 0: Yeah well like for example I like my I have this shuttle device is basically just a keyboard with labels on it and some fancy controls and the key bindings I have are the things I do all the time and every project.
Speaker 0: things like insert video from the preview area into the sequence I'm working on or Like set an in-point or set an out point or remove an in-point or an out point like really odd basic stuff that otherwise I would be clicking constantly to do
Speaker 1: or you could just use the keyboard.
Speaker 0: Well because most of what I'm doing also is scrubbing and navigating back and forth through the timeline I can just scrub with the mouse wheel But I still use the keyboard for all the other buttons.
Speaker 0: Mouse wheel scrubbing isn't frame by frame if you want to do certain things.
Speaker 1: Mouse wheel is very very good.
Speaker 0: It's not frame by frame on broken Mouse.
Speaker 1: Also you hold down some various buttons in the keyboard to adjust the speed of the scroll or I just twist the shuttle and The further I twist it the faster.
Speaker 1: I don't need to have some weird device for no reason.
Speaker 0: Yeah, cuz you basically don't do any complicated video editor But the point is that you just like to buy fancy shit.
Speaker 1: I have keyboard binding break shit to buy new shit fancy shit.
Speaker 1: This was like $40 and you just like to buy nonsense stuff.
Speaker 0: My keyboard costs way more than this thing.
Speaker 1: mine, too.
Speaker 0: But I also have keyboards but basically the things that I do semi commonly.
Speaker 0: I do have keyboard bindings too, but these are all like professional use cases and When I want to undo I still just hit ctrl Z. why wouldn't you on my tablet?
Speaker 0: I hit the top left button is undo.
Speaker 0: in the top the bottom left button is redo Because I draw something and it's wrong and I undo.
Speaker 0: draw it again wrong.
Speaker 0: draw it again now.
Speaker 1: It's good Yeah, so one thing that I do right is is in most keyboard shortcuts in you know Cuz you press keys in the keyboard and unless you have a piece of software like vim I think vim is the only one that's modal.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right the most of the buttons on the keyboard have a automatic function like you press L. It types the letter L. Yeah, you always need to combine it with alt or control or window key or something You know to to have a shortcut happen, right?
Speaker 1: and what really shocks me to this day is they still make keyboards where the Easiest button to hit that doesn't do anything is caps lock.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right.
Speaker 1: I always change caps lock into control with the defaults.
Speaker 0: Why are you changing from a default as Scott spent like 20 minutes telling me you should never customize anything?
Speaker 1: I don't because what I do is I just buy a keyboard where the keyboard has a control there instead of a cap.
Speaker 1: So rather than just making a simple software change to remap So it's actually not a simple software change fucking.
Speaker 1: if you in Windows if you want to change caps lock into control Edit the goddamn registry, mr.
Speaker 0: Fancy pants needs his custom fucking keyboard to move.
Speaker 1: how often you use caps lock?
Speaker 0: More often than you would.
Speaker 1: why are you using caps?
Speaker 1: What's wrong with you?
Speaker 0: for this for the dumbest possible reason right?
Speaker 1: The reason is troll is a button you're hitting all around.
Speaker 0: it is.
Speaker 0: I work in Finance and I am typing ticker names into case sensitive systems.
Speaker 1: Sometimes also, I'm way bad at typing.
Speaker 1: I never use right shift.
Speaker 1: I use left shift all the time.
Speaker 0: I Shifts equally.
Speaker 1: I never use the right shift shift.
Speaker 1: I probably never.
Speaker 0: I use right.
Speaker 0: I use left shift way more often than right shift, but I probably have never pressed the right shift.
Speaker 1: I always.
Speaker 1: I think it's a completely unused button on my keyboard.
Speaker 1: You might like if you look at the number of times been pressed.
Speaker 1: It might be zero.
Speaker 0: Uh, I think I've hit pause fewer times than I've hit right.
Speaker 1: Maybe I should like consciously try to start using the right shift key to capitalize letters on the left side of the keyboard like It's supposed to.
Speaker 0: yeah, pause and scroll lock.
Speaker 1: The point is caps lock is useless.
Speaker 1: You should.
Speaker 1: if you're on a Mac It's actually way easy to turns caps lock into control or command.
Speaker 1: and that brings me to something else Which on Windows you've got control and you go window key, but window key is used for like lock the computer with window L. Yeah, you don't really use it in a piece of software, right?
Speaker 1: So you got control use control for and all is to usually to go into the menu or to type funny characters and Unicode.
Speaker 0: So what's fun is in all the professional software I have you basically can make any combination of control alt shift All is y'all a lot of times used with control.
Speaker 1: But usually you're gonna combine control and shift before you combine control and all.
Speaker 1: all is like the last one.
Speaker 1: And but on Mac they give you command and option and all are the same thing base, right?
Speaker 1: But they give you command in addition to control and it really sucks on a Mac Even though you get used to it eventually.
Speaker 1: is that in Mac apps like if you're in their browser, it's not control T It's command T. It's not control W. It's command W. It's like, okay I'll just replace control with command right but then you open up say a terminal on a Mac and in bash Right that you want to go to the end of the line with.
Speaker 1: you know control E. Well, guess what?
Speaker 1: It's not command E is control E.
Speaker 0: It's why I don't use a Mac.
Speaker 1: Yeah Well, it's one reason right but it's like so when you're on a Mac I sort of have it in muscle memory now, even though I rarely use a man.
Speaker 1: Yeah that you know in which apps command which apps are control, but it's like well What do you change caps lock into command or control?
Speaker 1: Right because if you you know, it's like I change it into command use usually But that means anytime I open an app where I got to use control I got to move my finger way further and find this other weird-ass button.
Speaker 0: You just use the defaults and just learn to live with them.
Speaker 1: But that's I'm saying is that even if you didn't change caps like in anything on a Mac.
Speaker 1: Yeah in a browser You're gonna be pressing command.
Speaker 1: It's kind of amazing in a terminal.
Speaker 1: You can be pressing control.
Speaker 0: It's both sad and amazing to me that Windows and Mac diverged on this sort of fundamental thing and Stayed that way forever, right?
Speaker 0: And while Mac had the open Apple button, which they got rid of and then Windows added the Windows key so I would argue that way more people use PCs and way more people like were used to the windows the way of doing things.
Speaker 0: and meanwhile Mac Early days probably had a vested interest in keeping it weird because once someone was used to a Mac You didn't want it to be easy for them to go back to a PC.
Speaker 0: You want them to try to use a PC get annoyed by it and stay in Mac land forever.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm Well, that's the thing.
Speaker 1: So few people use keyboard shortcuts that this is no longer a thing that people are annoyed by keeping them in one zone or the other.
Speaker 0: Yeah Now one thing that's really sad that I see a lot among older people is that older people really seem to love macros.
Speaker 1: I Don't know about this.
Speaker 0: I see the business analysts tend to do this all the time.
Speaker 0: They they will.
Speaker 0: they will literally like forget.
Speaker 0: I'm not talking about Excel Keyboard shortcut problem.
Speaker 1: that sounds just like a hammer.
Speaker 1: have a hammer everything.
Speaker 1: It looks like nails problem.
Speaker 0: So people will make complex macros sometimes with custom software though.
Speaker 1: Luckily.
Speaker 1: This is the only kind of programming they know how to do.
Speaker 0: This did seem to be a dying thing But it seems like it's coming back.
Speaker 0: a lot of gamers will use software to bind Macros to their mouse and keyboard buttons to do things in games when the game does not provide a single Button that you could bind to do that thing.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm and Gamers seem to be the only good use case for this but usually seem people seem to only use macros when they have a Repetitive task and they don't know how to script or automate it.
Speaker 0: So they Script or automate hitting a keyboard shortcut a bunch of times in a row things like that.
Speaker 0: It's usually the wrong solution to a problem.
Speaker 1: a lot of times in the office You're gonna hear someone like typing like chicken chicken chicken chicken.
Speaker 1: Oh my god They might be pricing like something like down control V down control V down control V down control V. It make like ten lines in turn like typing detected, right?
Speaker 1: And it's like you can hear that and you can tell this person knows Enough that they can do it.
Speaker 1: They've improved the efficiency a little bit, but they don't really know.
Speaker 1: I could do this with literally like what pressing two keys?
Speaker 0: It's like getting really good at chopping down a tree.
Speaker 0: with an axe you're still not gonna be faster than a chainsaw.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like you don't know a chainsaw exists.
Speaker 1: See you master the axe.
Speaker 0: Yep No, I get no again Like I have done that sometimes like if you just have like a thing and you want a really quick Like oh, I got it like space.
Speaker 1: Yeah, sometimes it's faster to just control V five times.
Speaker 1: Yeah, sometimes it's not.
Speaker 1: there's a lot.
Speaker 0: Well, there's the line that you hear to chica chica chica chica chica chica chica.
Speaker 0: If you hear one more after that someone's going about something the wrong way.
Speaker 0: Yeah But it is.
Speaker 0: it's weird how I see a lot of people not knowing these shortcuts but Simultaneously like especially browsers, especially control shift.
Speaker 1: if nothing else you need to learn the basic keyword shortcuts of the browser.
Speaker 1: You should be able to browse the web without ever touching the mouse except maybe to click on a link and even then it's not Necessary it's not necessary.
Speaker 1: But there's some websites where you pretty much only pretty much I only click all I use the mouse for in a browser clicking on Nothing else anything else.
Speaker 1: I do the keyboard and that means I can browse.
Speaker 1: that's how I can read so much internet so fast.
Speaker 1: Part of it is I scroll with the keyboard or I search the page of the keyboard.
Speaker 1: I go to different pages with the keyboard.
Speaker 0: now what I don't do is I never like.
Speaker 0: it's a complex software like Audition all these Adobe things like Photoshop type stuff.
Speaker 0: I never change what the keyboard shortcuts are.
Speaker 0: I learn what the keyboard shortcuts are and just use them.
Speaker 1: That's right.
Speaker 0: And if I want if I want a key to do something special It's not.
Speaker 0: it's never because I want to change the key binding to like insert from A to Q. It's always.
Speaker 0: I want to bind a key to something very complex like basically one step short of a macro or you want to bind a key to something that does not have a default binding because a lot of professional software will let you bind keys to things that does not have a default for Because by the time you even know that thing exists You're already a very advanced user and you're gonna like you're doing something weird or something custom.
Speaker 0: There's a lot of things that don't have default binding.
Speaker 1: Usually I feel like if you ever encounter a situation like you have to customize something that's probably a sign That like hey, this is not the way that everyone does.
Speaker 1: this is you know Either a the thing we're trying to do is not a thing people do.
Speaker 1: you shouldn't even be doing it.
Speaker 1: It's probably something else you can do to accomplish your goal or be the way you are trying to accomplish Your goal is is actually some other way.
Speaker 1: That's way better.
Speaker 1: You just don't know it, right?
Speaker 0: But like here's an example I could bind like there's all like there's a billion billion bindings in audition.
Speaker 0: Only some of them are defaults and there's actually different sets of defaults.
Speaker 0: Like you can set it to act like other software Yeah, which is a common thing.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like okay We want to get people to use this software who are used to something.
Speaker 0: I want Excel to act like Quattro Pro, which just set my age.
Speaker 1: It's like I got used to Quattro Express or whatever.
Speaker 1: It's like why I don't want to have to get used to Excel.
Speaker 1: now It's like alright.
Speaker 1: Well the Excel people added a feature so you can do that.
Speaker 1: But yep, you should just get used to Excel instead.
Speaker 0: I'm looking for an example.
Speaker 0: Like there is a keyboard shortcut a default one for in audition Decrease brush opacity.
Speaker 1: Mmm, isn't that for Photoshop?
Speaker 0: Uh You realize you can draw on Waveforms and on spectrals and do things with them in audition, right?
Speaker 1: Okay What is opacity translate to like amplitude or what?
Speaker 0: it depends on what you're doing.
Speaker 0: You can you can select with a degree of equivalent opacity Areas of a spectral display and then apply transformations to just that area.
Speaker 0: Yeah But there is no default binding to razor all clips Uh-huh, but you could just decide to bind a key that doesn't have a default selection to that.
Speaker 0: if that's a thing you do commonly But normally that's a thing that someone who doesn't do that Commonly would click on something in the UI to do.
Speaker 1: the point is is that the number of people who learn keyboard shortcuts use them Commonly and use them.
Speaker 1: Well is not enough.
Speaker 1: They the advantage of you if you mess.
Speaker 1: if you get keyboard shortcuts for the applications You use the most into your muscle memory your computing experience will be Insanely improved.
Speaker 1: you don't even realize it's like it's insane how much faster you will get shit done If you just learn the goddamn shortcuts and stop resisting.
Speaker 0: So if you ever find yourself doing the same thing more than like three times in a row It's.
Speaker 1: it's possible to do everything on a computer no matter what with keyword only except interact with a flash website maybe Through.
Speaker 1: I recommend if you can just unplug your mouse.
Speaker 1: don't use any mice and try to see if you can.
Speaker 0: Just that's a good so fun idea.
Speaker 1: just browse try to browse the web and do your daily browsing without the mouse at all.
Speaker 1: Just unplug it.
Speaker 0: This gave me an idea for a game that we could make a game show out of in live stream I mean, but I would I can browse the web.
Speaker 0: Oh, no, no, we would be the arbiters.
Speaker 0: We've got other people do it.
Speaker 0: Mouseless horse, you know the game a horse in basketball Where you make a shot and then the other person has the exact same shot.
Speaker 1: There's a game called vim horse.
Speaker 1: It's probably older than you.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so I'm saying we could apply this to For people who are not computer experts because it's way more fun that way you put them in front of a computer no applications are open and You give them increasingly complex tasks and they have to solve.
Speaker 0: they have to do them without using a mouse And you see who fails first, right?
Speaker 1: And obviously those people are gonna take forever.
Speaker 1: But if you're good at it, it would take you.
Speaker 1: you can actually beat someone who's got a mouse easily.
Speaker 1: Yep, if you knew them, so learn them.
Speaker 0: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott.
Speaker 0: special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brand ok for the logos.
Speaker 1: be sure to visit our website at front row crew Com for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 0: remember geek nights is not one but four different shows Sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: geek nights is distributed under a creative commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 0: But unlike those other late shows it's actually recorded at night and the patreon patrons for this episode of geek nights are Craig Oliver Alan Joyce Rebecca Dunn Heidi McNicholas shimmering Ruby obelisk hanging in the sky.
Speaker 0: charge option.
Speaker 0: my stage calm.
Speaker 0: Jerry minor Linkagey Kelly Stoddard Matthew Smith Chris Reimer Joe sure Joe star ran from New Zealand.
Speaker 0: Mr.
Speaker 0: Strong's traction fin scoot alone Lee Daniel Redmond Roberto Kingsley Nicholas Brandau Shervin Mount Horrell Don Schleich Rochelle, Monta, Nona drew up and Lander Chris midkiff Rory Jay bants Clinton Walton sailor Vista Ryan Perrin Thomas Han Sean Klein James David White and Sean Yeager.
Speaker 0: that really tripped me up guys.
Speaker 0: And anyway now I leave you with Decent.
Speaker 1: I'm freezing cold But I can't watch a duck mask and I don't man.
Speaker 0: Can I deal on fall outside?
Speaker 0: Please fun on your fan In new fresh wind air.
Speaker 1: I'll talk to be that out Oh.