Speaker 1: It's Wednesday July 25th 2018.
Speaker 1: I'm rim and this is geek nights.
Speaker 1: tonight We are reviewing the anime cells at work.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: So yeah, we did that bike ride.
Speaker 1: We also had to camp in a pretty heavy rainstorm.
Speaker 1: I think you had to get up while the rain was still going to start.
Speaker 0: So what happened is I you know before the night before I'm like.
Speaker 0: well You know if it rains as long as it's not raining so hard that I can't bike at all.
Speaker 0: right It's not won't be.
Speaker 0: and it's like because what am I doing after biking?
Speaker 0: It's not like it as long as I can bike safely.
Speaker 0: It doesn't matter if I'm wet It's not like I'm going.
Speaker 1: so in my opinion no Amount of rain by itself makes biking unsafe.
Speaker 1: I have bikes home from work in New York like seven miles.
Speaker 1: They're in Driving sheeting rain.
Speaker 0: I have been caught in driving rain.
Speaker 0: the problem is there Occasions where if the rain is too much he can't go as fast.
Speaker 0: if you're got to go up a steep hill And it's raining might slip and fall down because not enough traction You could see.
Speaker 1: if you're going in a straight line uphill You could slip in the rain.
Speaker 1: your tires were already in a bad state saying it can happen.
Speaker 0: No, it could be a slippery patch.
Speaker 0: You know going over a metal thing.
Speaker 0: There's.
Speaker 0: you know the rain could be so much You can't even see You could be.
Speaker 1: I biked home once in rain where I actually couldn't see.
Speaker 0: I would stop and wait till I could see and then You could have a situation where it's flooded and it's too deep.
Speaker 1: So one time me and Ken were biking through the woods.
Speaker 1: This is back in us in high school, and we're following the trail, and we're pretty far away from home and just horrible thunderstorms going and we come to a place where we basically cross a river and the Clinton River and it's flooded.
Speaker 1: so we just kind of biked through it and it was basically I was biking in water that was up to my neck while I was on the bike and We totally made it to the other side.
Speaker 1: It was totally fine.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'm not doing that.
Speaker 1: The only drawback was Laughter.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna bring my all my stuff Through the water.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, see this was an error.
Speaker 1: remember before cell phones let alone smart phones And I would.
Speaker 1: why would I carry my wallet when I'm in high school biking around?
Speaker 1: So the only thing I had in my pocket was a key to get back into my house.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm but anyway.
Speaker 0: So when I woke up the rain wasn't too bad And I was getting ready to go and then I like see I'm supposed to start at 7.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I didn't have to start to like 830 at 645.
Speaker 0: It starts raining like more.
Speaker 0: It's not raining.
Speaker 0: It's like borderline.
Speaker 0: We're like mmm, right?
Speaker 1: I was in the tent and I was lately or listen to that rain thinking Yeah, I ain't getting up yet.
Speaker 0: So I go over to the P.
Speaker 1: I wouldn't even get up and go.
Speaker 0: pee already registered.
Speaker 0: I went to the registration booth and I was like hey if I go and the rain slows me down too much And I don't make it back in time.
Speaker 0: They're like, oh, yeah, I just call us this number.
Speaker 0: Well, I will bring you back to the beginning.
Speaker 0: We'll parachute you to a further destiny.
Speaker 0: We'll do whatever you want and I'm like, oh, okay.
Speaker 0: So I'm just like fuck it.
Speaker 0: I came out here.
Speaker 0: I just started biking.
Speaker 0: There's no one else out there But there's like the one person waving me on like alright, go ahead and I go out there and I encountered this tree and It's not a boy like an end like it's not an enormous tree.
Speaker 0: it was maybe like, you know five inches Diameter, you know, but nice solid big solid solid tree, you know, not a you know as a young tree But not a baby just born tree ain't no twig, you know.
Speaker 0: And it was across the path and I could have just picked up my bike gone over and kept going.
Speaker 0: But I'm like, nope, I got to move this tree.
Speaker 1: So yeah Cuz there's gonna be hundreds and hundreds of bikers behind you.
Speaker 0: that well the bottom of the tree is sort of still Not completely detached and the top of the tree as all as many branches that are Interfering with these still living trees on the other side of the path.
Speaker 0: So I can't move it very effectively.
Speaker 0: and then one person comes up behind me and I wave at them and he you know It's another guy biking.
Speaker 0: He comes and we both move the tree.
Speaker 0: He's much stronger than me.
Speaker 0: Armed apartment.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and now there's no one else and we took us a while to move the tree.
Speaker 0: No one else came Nobody.
Speaker 0: so we just start biking together.
Speaker 1: He's going on the same path as me Because my route actually went the opposite direction to start.
Speaker 1: so I wouldn't have even encountered the tree.
Speaker 0: So I just hung out with this dude Chris from Ohio.
Speaker 0: It apparently does this right every year.
Speaker 0: He's apparently 20 years older than me and we went about the same speed.
Speaker 0: No, but then when there was like maybe 10 miles left, I was like bleh and he was still just fine.
Speaker 1: So, you know almost cuz I ride a hybrid and but it's a fancy like it's a light hybrid.
Speaker 1: But most people don't think that you could get a fancy hybrid, but I'm biking doing my thing.
Speaker 1: Almost a dozen people came up behind me on the road bikes road next to me on this 80 mile ride and Turned and said basically the exact same thing.
Speaker 1: I can't believe you're doing this on a hybrid.
Speaker 0: I saw lots of hybrid bikes.
Speaker 0: I don't know why anyone would say that to you.
Speaker 1: So I did not see a single hybrid bike on my route until I joined the 40 mile route at the end On the 80 mile route at no point.
Speaker 1: Did I say a hybrid?
Speaker 0: I saw hybrid but I didn't.
Speaker 0: I guess I don't know What route I was on.
Speaker 1: cuz yeah until there until my route bumped into like the people who are going my route had this section That is that was exclusive to the baby.
Speaker 0: This is the baby hundred.
Speaker 0: Yeah Which is basically go out of your way in his loop to go to a high school Then go all the way back and rejoin everyone else at the end.
Speaker 0: Meanwhile, my 80 did we didn't see we saw almost nobody out there.
Speaker 0: my that rest stop had like a few kids And no I'd like manning, you know a table full of snacks and nothing else.
Speaker 1: My 80-mile route did all the two hard parts of the real hundred But then it skipped this like 20 mile section at the end.
Speaker 1: That was not hard, but I didn't.
Speaker 1: I'm glad I didn't do that last 20 miles.
Speaker 0: hmm Anyway, but yeah, and then I saw a former co-worker.
Speaker 0: They're just like, oh, you know free foods.
Speaker 1: one thing I thought was funny though is one hundred percent of the people who made a comment about my hybrid.
Speaker 1: I passed and never saw again.
Speaker 0: So It's not a race.
Speaker 1: No, but I like to go fast.
Speaker 1: I'd be a good time.
Speaker 1: I averaged about 14 miles an hour including breaks, which is pretty good for a ride like that.
Speaker 1: But anyway, it's anime day So we're not gonna talk about biking anymore Unless we're talking about a biking anime and there's a lot of news cuz that's DCC just happened Mm-hmm, even though you should probably never go to use it.
Speaker 0: We're usually mad short on Wednesday news.
Speaker 0: Now we got a big pile of Wednesday news.
Speaker 0: We're gonna use it all up and then we're gonna be out in two weeks.
Speaker 0: You won't have any.
Speaker 1: so let's start with yours.
Speaker 0: So the San Diego Comic Con.
Speaker 0: they have the Eisner Awards.
Speaker 0: So the big news of the Eisner Awards this year is that for the first time ever?
Speaker 0: What would actually award?
Speaker 0: did they give Rumiko Takahashi?
Speaker 1: This is your news.
Speaker 1: I didn't read shit.
Speaker 0: Yeah, whatever award she got is an award of the voter.
Speaker 0: I give voters choice a Hall of Fame.
Speaker 0: So I guess she's the first woman in the Eisner Awards Hall of Fame.
Speaker 1: Well, the headline says it best awards honor female manga creator writer for first time.
Speaker 0: Yep, so also I mean there are other awards that females have won.
Speaker 0: It's not like the first time a woman's ever won an Eisner Award But it is the first time a woman has won Hall of Fame and also the first time someone's won best writer.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's actually a tie for best writer.
Speaker 0: But Tom King Tom King who's a Batman guy and Marjorie Liu the first woman and to ever win best writer.
Speaker 0: I think her book Monstress also won like best continuing series and the Tea Dragon Society, which I had thought about buying a few times Because I've seen it.
Speaker 0: I love the art and I didn't realize it was also webcomic.
Speaker 0: It won like two or three awards.
Speaker 0: So yeah, like monstrous and Tea Dragon Society were big winners here and also another big winner was the Akira 35th anniversary edition.
Speaker 1: Best publication design.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Also, I think best US edition of foreign material.
Speaker 1: Oh, no.
Speaker 0: Oh, no, I think it was best.
Speaker 0: No best US edition of international material.
Speaker 0: Asia was my brother's husband which volume 2 is coming up.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, I gotta read that.
Speaker 0: but it was best archival collection comic books and also Best publication.
Speaker 1: best US edition of international material went for run for it stories of slaves who fought for freedom.
Speaker 0: Yeah They separate the Asia Categories.
Speaker 0: that because otherwise manga I guess would always win or manga would never win because they'd always pick a French thing.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know.
Speaker 0: or a bond doesn't a what everyone call it.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean like how the comics industry in the u.s.
Speaker 1: Just pretends that all of Asia doesn't exist because otherwise their numbers are meaningless, right?
Speaker 0: You know, it's also I guess to keep manga from beating some you know, some manga cover winning best writer.
Speaker 0: That's you know, anyway the point is so if you don't know when Akira was first published in English in the US it was from Dark Horse and Otomo the creator of Akira.
Speaker 0: he helped them flip it so it would be left to right and he also isn't.
Speaker 0: I guess he's better Than zero in English.
Speaker 0: I mean, I can't I don't know how good at English But I think he had some input in the translation and like the redoing of the the sound effects and stuff like that.
Speaker 0: and then there was That Dark Horse Edition took a while to come out.
Speaker 0: I bought it when I was at RIT still was still coming out.
Speaker 0: I think I finished getting it near and beacon.
Speaker 0: I don't remember.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I vaguely remember all the six volumes.
Speaker 0: Anyway, they put it out again Kodansha put it out again and it's pretty much a reprint of almost the exact same thing.
Speaker 0: I think there were some differences but not major differences.
Speaker 0: The new one is The first English Edition is basically the same only as the Kodansha Edition But it's been flipped over.
Speaker 0: so it's finally right to left instead of left to right.
Speaker 0: And also it comes in a fancy box and that's what that publication of it right.
Speaker 0: that is what won the awards.
Speaker 0: So yeah, if you haven't read Akira and you've only seen the cure you Mean you're missing out on like best one the best manga's comics that has ever been.
Speaker 0: so I don't know.
Speaker 1: on the actual story It's readily available.
Speaker 0: I don't know if it's available digitally But whatever price they're charging for that box if you don't have any version of it is totally worth it.
Speaker 1: Like even we as much as we're trying to remove physical objects from our personal possession It's worth it to own a Kira or at least have it long enough to read it.
Speaker 0: Have you even read it?
Speaker 1: I read the first Two volumes when you're gay and I never actually finished it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you don't know.
Speaker 1: Yeah So in some other news, that's actually pretty interesting.
Speaker 1: So if you recall there was the New York comic-con, which was pretty rinky-dink in the early days and slowly got bigger.
Speaker 1: We used to like go to it and do panels.
Speaker 0: I went to it.
Speaker 0: Maybe two times.
Speaker 1: I went to it almost every year because they kept giving me the free badge every year and then I'd stop Responding and taking the free badges and then eventually they stopped emailing me and then they wanted nothing to do with us but near a comic-con basically got more Painful to go to and less fun every year there ran.
Speaker 1: We're not gonna get into that.
Speaker 1: but there is also a New York anime festival.
Speaker 0: We started off as its own thing that I went to once.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I went to it a bunch of Two times.
Speaker 0: Well, maybe we went to.
Speaker 0: I don't remember.
Speaker 1: we went to it even the last year.
Speaker 1: it existed even semi-independent, right?
Speaker 0: So right.
Speaker 0: All right, so it was.
Speaker 0: we went to it when it was.
Speaker 0: it was Right, and then it was incorporated into New York comic-con in the gym the same bill the same way that an amoeba Incorporates a poor bacterium into itself, right?
Speaker 0: It was in the same building, but it was in a different area of the same building.
Speaker 0: It was sort of like it was like two conventions were going on in the same building at once But there was a separate area with its own panel rooms and a little stage and its own little biz.
Speaker 0: that was physically Adjacent and your one ticket got you into both things Except the New York anime festival park got the short end of every possible state was like, you know, it was like segregation.
Speaker 1: It was so the funniest thing was it was more crowded not human rights violating.
Speaker 1: It was more crowded than the comic-con part more people were trying to go to the anime part.
Speaker 1: They're the panels are all completely full because they didn't give a no space.
Speaker 1: basically Fans of anime really wanted to go to the New York anime festival But the New York comic-con only makes us money from the Hollywood comic.
Speaker 1: You don't make any money from fan panels Nope, so they basically just got rid of.
Speaker 1: the thing
Speaker 0: I remember most is that at the when it was when you enter the incorporated one The thing I remember the most is that we were doing our panel and the panel before us were people from Krypton future media And there was the creator positive me who is like the software not the.
Speaker 1: the character It was like was on that panel and I talked to him about like what computers he has a good panel Yeah, but yes The New York anime festival was basically destroyed by the comic-con and the comic-con itself is in our opinion Unattendable because it's just.
Speaker 1: it's an awful.
Speaker 1: It's like SDCC but lower rent.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: So Independently of that there's a new anime convention We've talked about run by all the smart people who used to run things like the New York comic-con New York anime festival back when they were a lot better like real smart people.
Speaker 1: But the news here is that the New York comic-con is bringing back their anime festival But this time they're doing it partnering with anime Expo which runs basically the worst anime convention.
Speaker 0: Anime Expo is going to run a Different convention at the same time as New York comic-con the same weekend in a different location.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so you're gonna have I mean you're gonna have to go from the Javits down to P or something here 94 ride a bike down the path, I guess.
Speaker 1: so here's the thing I'm gonna point out.
Speaker 1: they put this convention in a place that no convention should go.
Speaker 1: There's no subway.
Speaker 1: There's no good buses.
Speaker 1: There's no hotels.
Speaker 0: There might be a bus.
Speaker 0: I don't know but it's not.
Speaker 0: it's not an easy place to get to.
Speaker 0: the only convenient way to get to this place is with the two B's boat I Think as a helicopter pad next to it too.
Speaker 0: You can take a helicopter there.
Speaker 0: Yeah, even if you know if you never have a car, it's not good to go.
Speaker 0: It's not a place you can go easily even with a car.
Speaker 0: is you can take a taxi would get you there an uber.
Speaker 0: But point is you're not gonna be able to switch between New York comic-con and this new New York anime festival replacement thing easily but even worse because The if you are running it are the are the anime Expo people the read right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, like I'm confident even if you go I mean, maybe we'll be wrong.
Speaker 1: We don't know.
Speaker 1: I suspect it's gonna be a shit show and it's not gonna be fun.
Speaker 0: No And it's basically if you buy a badge to New York comic-con you can just go to this thing because it's included.
Speaker 0: But they're also gonna sell a badge to just the anime thing.
Speaker 0: But I don't know if that badge will get you into New York comic-con.
Speaker 0: I think it will get you into just the anime part.
Speaker 1: Okay, so tickets for Thursday are 20 bucks Or they're 15 bucks if you have a New York comic-con badge.
Speaker 0: Oh for Thursday Yeah, but what about the by the Friday's 15 Saturday's 20 Sunday's 20?
Speaker 0: I thought it's just free if you have a New York comic-con.
Speaker 1: No tickets will be available to fan very people with verification accounts.
Speaker 1: So they're doing so.
Speaker 1: you have to have the account the special one That's verified that you would use to buy a New York comic-con badge.
Speaker 0: So if you got to pay extra and you know, no one's going over there Yeah, you could basically you get a five dollar discount if you already bought a goddamn New York comic-con badge to go to this For the money you got to spend to get over there.
Speaker 1: I do not know Why this is happening?
Speaker 1: Well, no, I do know why.
Speaker 0: well It's like a lot of the big cons, you know packs was did the best of spreading out all over the place.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but it seems like the other cons even.
Speaker 0: you know, magfest is like oh We got to have a magwest and Otakon Otakon Vegas and it's like the cons are starting to just start more Things going on there on.
Speaker 0: they can't get bigger.
Speaker 0: They start opening more conventions in more places and that's not a good idea.
Speaker 0: So anime expo has never had another con in other place.
Speaker 0: They're trying to open up a con in a different place.
Speaker 1: I think there's even more factors going on.
Speaker 1: There is crazy huge demand for conventions of nerdy stuff anime conventions gaming conventions comic conventions.
Speaker 1: The demand is insatiable and enormous and there's literally no place in America that can actually host these events effectively But simultaneously.
Speaker 1: the only way to make money from these things like real money unless you're packs and you know the secret sauce like packs does really Well for themselves But especially comic cons is to basically get people into your stupid event and pay for a badge and out as fast as possible.
Speaker 1: You don't want people hanging out in your convention for four days like they do it the good cons that fans actually want to go to.
Speaker 1: so there's this constant tension between The things that cons can do to make money and cater to the industry versus the things that fans of cons as Opposed to people who hear about a con and go to one for one day Once and I feel like this is gonna be yet another one of those not fun corporate style cons I don't think it'll affect they're good anime con in New York at all And we'll see how it goes, but I'm definitely not going to it October 4th through 7th.
Speaker 1: Nah, no In some other con news that's even sadder and worse.
Speaker 1: you've probably seen a lot of Talk about world con.
Speaker 0: so we've talked about world con in the past on geek nights.
Speaker 0: If you don't know world con is basically sort of like the oldest school original sci-fi con that there has ever been.
Speaker 0: fantasy sci-fi con there's ever been and it's been around forever and It's the litter.
Speaker 0: It's like think you know think about the most Stereotypical con of like old crusty dudes with beards.
Speaker 0: This is it and what the way it works is like it travels around to a different place every year Which makes it world con and it's usually you know, what they give out what the Hugo Awards there.
Speaker 0: Yeah, or is it then?
Speaker 0: now the Hugo is one of those awards.
Speaker 1: you go awards.
Speaker 0: Remember is where it's the Hugo ones, right?
Speaker 0: it's not the the other one right.
Speaker 1: the Hugo Awards the whole ballot thing.
Speaker 1: We've talked about this.
Speaker 1: I'm right.
Speaker 1: the way they vote on them there It's like you got to go to world con and remember that is the thing where basically Gomer gate people who called themselves the sad puppies tried to sabotage it and continue.
Speaker 0: That's the kind of person who goes to world con.
Speaker 0: it's where it's weird like the people who go to world con will be like the world's best most famous sci-fi fantasy authors and sad crusty dudes with beards, but anyway the Thing the reason world comes in the news yet again because usually when it surprised it still exists.
Speaker 0: Like who's who's keeping this thing of how people go?
Speaker 1: It's really it's well known and popular.
Speaker 1: I've been going for 76 years.
Speaker 0: Where is where even is it this year?
Speaker 1: I don't know cuz I'm not gonna go.
Speaker 1: I like even way back when we won the parsec award.
Speaker 1: We didn't even go to get the award.
Speaker 0: That wasn't at world con.
Speaker 0: No, it wasn't.
Speaker 1: but we said even when we win awards, we don't show as a dragon con.
Speaker 1: I think it was dragon cast dragon.
Speaker 1: I'm never going to dragon got either but basically they.
Speaker 1: The gist of this story and I'm not gonna get into all the details of it cuz you can read this is that they have people who set up their panels and people who go to Fan run conventions at least kind of expect this low bar of how panels are run at conventions.
Speaker 1: It's very rare that fan conventions have well organized well run panel content Or at least the people who organize the panel is very rare that they're good people who know what they're doing running this stuff.
Speaker 1: So a lot of the problems that happened are literally the same problems that pretty much every fan con has but they're Exacerbated by the fact that the people they that the the unqualified people are scheduling the panels for our Hugo nominees professional authors like people who are Professional and serious and have fandoms and know what they're doing who aren't gonna put up with the crap that generally goes on at fan conventions simultaneously.
Speaker 1: I Run Worldcon are probably on average old sis had white dudes that They did things like dead naming authors.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they did things like just finding or making up bios about them and just putting on the website.
Speaker 1: They also apparently took suggestions for panels, which some cons do.
Speaker 1: it's always weird when cons like collaborate with people to run Magfest kind of.
Speaker 0: does that What do you mean?
Speaker 1: suggestions like the majors thing like they come to us?
Speaker 1: They're like art.
Speaker 1: everyone tell us the panels you want to do and then well from there Separately allocate people to be on those panels.
Speaker 1: Oh, I see a lot a lot of like sci-fi cons do that.
Speaker 1: It's not really a thing in gaming cons except the magfest mages, but I digress.
Speaker 1: but they basically Took the suggestions from a lot of the authors a lot of the Hugo Award nominees But then they didn't schedule any of the people who happen to be women or persons of color.
Speaker 1: Somehow they scheduled all these white dudes and they made all these arguments about how well we scheduled based on what we expect the attendees the core audience of Worldcon to see.
Speaker 1: and It's bull.
Speaker 0: I think they're basically saying I what I want to see.
Speaker 0: I believe I'm the core audience.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so I think it's a combination of both Sis head white dude.
Speaker 0: not clearly the people in the People clearly in the guest relations department aren't bad because they're inviting all these guests.
Speaker 0: It's just the person in the panels department is a shit.
Speaker 1: Well, they're inviting these guests, but they're not actually putting them on any panels.
Speaker 0: So they could be.
Speaker 0: that I'm saying if if that imagine if the panels person was in charge of guest relations Those people wouldn't have even been at Worldcon.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right.
Speaker 1: so now I suspect that I've I had a guess.
Speaker 1: I'd say that half of this is incompetence and then A quarter of it is says head white dude ignorance and another quarter of it is active malice.
Speaker 1: That's my guess of the ratio of all these problems.
Speaker 1: because not to name names of any particular conventions but I want to give a brief litany of Things like this that have personally happened to me or me and Scott at conventions.
Speaker 1: We showed up at a convention once that scheduled us without telling us.
Speaker 1: That put a bio of geek nights on their page that someone wrote on their own without Consulting us and they found a logo that wasn't our logo, but was close enough.
Speaker 1: So sure we showed up at a convention once that Scheduled us.
Speaker 0: I don't remember any of this.
Speaker 1: These were all.
Speaker 1: all of these were at one particular convention.
Speaker 0: Okay?
Speaker 1: we showed up one year and they Had actually scheduled the same panels.
Speaker 1: We did the previous year.
Speaker 1: that year again instead of the panels They told us they scheduled and I remember sitting there for now for a few minutes going through their schedule Finding the panels that looked like they were ours and just showing up to them assuming we had to run them.
Speaker 1: I have been adjacent to panel staff that did things like Worldcon did like literally going to someone's Facebook page copy pasting Information from their profile and just putting it on the convention website.
Speaker 1: So a lot of these things happen Commonly at low-rent conventions or poorly run conventions usually because the people running the panels departments have no idea what they're doing.
Speaker 1: I mean, they're either not paid or they're paid at best Minimum wage for the small amount of time they actually work.
Speaker 1: But usually they're just not paid even if the cons are for profit.
Speaker 1: So you can read this article if you want to see the real utter shit show that this was.
Speaker 1: but the result was all these Authors were like, you know what screw it.
Speaker 1: We're not even coming now.
Speaker 1: Never mind.
Speaker 1: You had your chance.
Speaker 1: We're not even gonna bother attending.
Speaker 1: and now Worldcon has responded by basically saying they're tearing apart their panels department And they're starting over with the programming even though that's obviously too little too late and I am confident They will not be able to find people who are competent to Solve this problem in time.
Speaker 1: and I don't think any of those authors are gonna change their minds and decide.
Speaker 0: Listen Worldcon and the Hugo Awards only have any respect because people you know I guess give it respect.
Speaker 0: right publishers put on their books like Hugo Award nominee Hugo Award winner authors continue to go to.
Speaker 1: Well, why does the Worldcon go to the publishers?
Speaker 0: I don't.
Speaker 0: why don't these a publishers, you know It's like stop respecting the Hugo Award as an award that matters and stop putting it on your books.
Speaker 0: Just ignore it right authors.
Speaker 0: Just ignore it.
Speaker 0: Stop going to Worldcon.
Speaker 0: I guess it's easy to say is not an author someone's gonna tell me like I shouldn't tell them what to do and they're probably Right, yeah, but I think there's an easy.
Speaker 0: Easily just kill world, you know The.
Speaker 0: the power of the author is it can definitely just kill Worldcon.
Speaker 0: make something else.
Speaker 0: make your own goddamn award.
Speaker 0: You could buy them out.
Speaker 0: They I know Worldcon has like one of those stupid crazy governance systems also, right?
Speaker 0: Somebody could also stage an operation where you could basically Brigade, you know the evil Brigades of Worldcon and take it over.
Speaker 0: Let's get enough people to go there and and you know work within their constitution or whatever and you just take that thing over right?
Speaker 1: That makes it very subtle.
Speaker 0: I was a group of Awesome, not old white dude sci-fi fantasy authors.
Speaker 0: I would get together with my publishers and my fans and do exactly that and this is it.
Speaker 1: but there's the same voice from the Worldcon reading between the lines of what you said.
Speaker 1: if the Hugo Awards were a Big deal in terms of like books actually selling in things Publishers would just game the system.
Speaker 1: I Feel like the fact that no one appears to just use money to game the system except those Gilmer Gators Implies that it isn't worth their time or money to do it.
Speaker 1: But the other thing is if Worldcon is serious about this and they want the Hugo Awards to be treated with respect You could hire one person who knows what they're doing to do this part for your convention like pay him up.
Speaker 0: They think they know what they're doing.
Speaker 0: Dudes.
Speaker 0: I mean you ever met an old crusty dude with a beard?
Speaker 0: if they who wants to get advice from someone else Well, the other thing someone else knows better than they know.
Speaker 1: So I'm gonna quote from this article because apparently you send an email To a lot of these people of color who are and women who are never tried to give a suggestion I'm like board game strategy to a grog Nard.
Speaker 0: They think they know best.
Speaker 1: Yeah Quote there's a generation of new Hugo finalists who are exciting to the nominators, but completely unfamiliar To the attendees.
Speaker 1: So the one of their core arguments was the white dudes who come to Worldcon Don't care about all that content.
Speaker 1: so the convention has to cater to the people who actually attend.
Speaker 1: but That is why so many anime cons have such shit programming because they cater to the status starting our own convention.
Speaker 0: Let's just get a bunch of money and buy Worldcon.
Speaker 0: Whoever like it has to be owned by someone.
Speaker 0: we can just buy it.
Speaker 0: They have a price.
Speaker 0: Let's buy the whole thing and rescue it.
Speaker 0: I know of two and we can piggyback on it's like it's like legacy.
Speaker 0: I know of other conventions and then we can just get.
Speaker 0: you don't even have to run it because we're white dudes We should find some not white not dudes to run it.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and then we can just protect it.
Speaker 1: But more importantly you got to do what pecs does or what we used to do at kinetic on and actually we did really well I think is Even though the attendees of a con say they want X they don't know shit.
Speaker 1: They don't know what they want.
Speaker 1: You trick them you use you.
Speaker 1: it's top down at conventions the people who run the convention Set the tone and set the stage.
Speaker 1: if they schedule things they can make those things.
Speaker 0: It's not just conventions You know, it's all everything in life.
Speaker 0: You tell people what they want.
Speaker 0: You make people want what you want them to want.
Speaker 1: but anyway things of the day, so Mike Tyson's punch-out is a super good game that I like.
Speaker 1: but one you do one funny thing about it.
Speaker 1: Well, two funny things about it.
Speaker 1: So one the Nintendo Entertainment System like the NES its core system if you don't put special chips in the cartridges It's not really actually more powerful than an Atari 7800 like they're similarly powered equipment and Early NES games aren't really better than Atari 7800 games.
Speaker 1: But then they did this thing with these MMC chips these memory mappers and there's this whole story of like the MMC 3.1 and the MMC 3 and how they could make different games that did different cool things.
Speaker 0: Well, I mean, that's why the NES was able to live so long right?
Speaker 0: the NES that at the beginning had games like baseball Yeah And then it also had games like Kirby's adventure and Mario 3 and it's like how did that same console do both of those games?
Speaker 1: And the answer is you just put more chips in the cartridge.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's basically right.
Speaker 0: It's like.
Speaker 0: that's why the NES could live so long whereas, you know other systems I had pretty much like the same shit going on from beginning to end.
Speaker 1: but there's this special of all those chips.
Speaker 1: The MMC 2 was special because only one game ever used it because I think there were more than one one game Mike Tyson's punch-out.
Speaker 0: and even if you were a kid not knowing anything about technology You knew that punch-out was just different from all the other Nintendo games.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there's a lot of it is tell.
Speaker 1: Yeah, because it did.
Speaker 1: there's a lot of weird stuff with Mike Tyson's punch-out.
Speaker 1: But one of the cool things about it is that there's this crowd in the background Like this giant kind of dynamic crowd that's moving around and sharing and stuff and people are good at the game.
Speaker 1: The crowd's movement and react and the things they do.
Speaker 1: like someone takes a picture Someone reacts in the crowd a camera flash at like those kinds of things In the early parts of the game the fighter himself like the guy you're punching to death Would like twitch before he punched you.
Speaker 1: and that's how you play the game.
Speaker 1: But later the only way to predict what they were gonna do is to notice these cues from the crowd.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well because RNG.
Speaker 0: but you can tell what the RNG seed is based on what the crowd is doing because they only got one RNG seed.
Speaker 1: it was arguably on purpose to to provide this sort of natural feedback mechanism to make the game difficult But also make it so that you could naturally start to figure things out.
Speaker 1: But there's one dude in the background wearing sunglasses who just sits there.
Speaker 1: He only sits in one spot like he's not copied never does anything in the whole game Except in one fight against one person.
Speaker 1: There's one move where he will lower his sunglasses and go oh Right before a thing happens, and if you just so happen to punch at the moment He does that with frame perfect timing.
Speaker 1: He will never put his sunglasses back up and in fact the crowd freezes and it turns out that if the crowd freezes the game freezes and once you win or lose this fight the game soft locks and Cannot be continued.
Speaker 1: and if you lost the fight macho man Just keeps twitching his pecs forever.
Speaker 1: and this video explains in detail.
Speaker 1: Yeah, super macho man.
Speaker 0: Not regular macho man is Randy Savage Snap into a slim Jim?
Speaker 0: super macho man is a different person.
Speaker 1: yes So this video is a pretty good explanation in three minutes of how and why this happened and how they fixed it.
Speaker 1: and how they?
Speaker 1: Fixed it is pretty funny.
Speaker 0: So you got a thing of the day yeah, so you know ever I think most at least english-speaking children right.
Speaker 0: they they learned at the foot of the doctor Seuss not dr.
Speaker 1: Sweet.
Speaker 0: no dr.
Speaker 1: Seuss with the grown-up beats.
Speaker 0: It's a cat in the Hat yeah And the ham and the egg anyway my favorite dr.
Speaker 0: Seuss.
Speaker 0: I don't know about you.
Speaker 0: What's your favorite dr.
Speaker 0: Seuss?
Speaker 1: You know it's really hard to say oh My god.
Speaker 1: I think I actually like the Lorax the most.
Speaker 0: my favorite is also Lorax.
Speaker 0: I'm mostly right why.
Speaker 0: because he speaks for the trees and there's also those animated Lorax Which is totally creepy.
Speaker 1: yeah, but I really liked it because of how creepy it was.
Speaker 0: I love that Lorax.
Speaker 0: I love the book Lorax and the movie Lord.
Speaker 1: I also really like the what the switcheroo machine the one with the stars on the chests and The non stars on the chests.
Speaker 1: I don't know you don't remember that one.
Speaker 0: No anyway Lorax is number one dr.
Speaker 0: Seuss book.
Speaker 0: there is if you ask Scott anyway, so here is an article and what the hell's.
Speaker 0: this is like a real like journal of Ecology or something right and it's written by a bunch of anthropologists, and they are basically provide this incredible You know very well supported scientific Anthropological argument that the Lorax is probably the specific kind of monkey.
Speaker 0: because what happened is dr.
Speaker 0: Seuss apparently had writer's block around what like 1970 something and Went to some like place in Kenya.
Speaker 0: and when he was in the place in Kenya He was bored and wrote like 90% of the Lorax in like one night or something like that.
Speaker 0: and the Lorax and the the trees the tuff of the trees from the Lorax have great resemblance to specific monkey and specific kind of tree from Kenya.
Speaker 0: and Yeah, that's pretty cool.
Speaker 1: This goes into.
Speaker 0: somebody would care about it that much this goes into in such shocking detail in such serious scientific evaluation Just like it's not just like a tweet like yo, I'm pretty you know check it out It's sort of like whoa.
Speaker 0: you wrote a whole scientific journal article about this.
Speaker 1: Why it's pretty good.
Speaker 1: Yeah in the meta moment if you're a fan of the geek nice book club You might be happy to know that we talked about Emily Wilson's translation of Homer's Odyssey.
Speaker 1: I'm just waiting for Scott to pick the next book.
Speaker 1: And depending on what?
Speaker 1: Depending on what he picks.
Speaker 1: because Scott said something to me the other day and what he said was I feel like I should pick A bad book.
Speaker 1: no Cuz all I'm gonna say is that if you pick the wrong book I'm going into the forgotten realms with the next book.
Speaker 0: Oh, you know what actually you know.
Speaker 0: you see you always used to threaten to go to Senor God I can and send your mouth.
Speaker 0: No you always threatened to go.
Speaker 1: Oh yeah to do ma.
Speaker 1: yes I kind of I'm kind of feeling reading the account of Monte Cristo again.
Speaker 1: that good translation, right?
Speaker 0: But you know a forgotten realms as bad as it would be it is short.
Speaker 0: It would take me like a day to read about how minster actually If I follow my rule of picking.
Speaker 1: I'm glad that you were actually actually able to name two things from Forgotten Realms.
Speaker 0: there was also the guy you hate with the two Swords.
Speaker 1: Oh drizz door and fuck those drizz books.
Speaker 1: if you there's a hierarchy of people who like Forgotten Realms There's the quote unquote good books.
Speaker 0: Then we all know that if you pick a Forgotten Realms book It's gonna be a froufrou elf book with some elven bard sword guy.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they're basically called elven bard sword.
Speaker 0: yeah That's what rim played.
Speaker 0: That's what I played.
Speaker 1: That's what I read.
Speaker 0: That's who you are.
Speaker 1: That's the top tier though the Volo stuff is pretty fun and also Volo not Volo.
Speaker 1: But the tier under that is drizz.
Speaker 1: drizz.
Speaker 1: like when I was 14 and these books were the best I looked down on the drizz kids like I. what are you reading?
Speaker 1: this dreck?
Speaker 1: I'm reading this high-caliber elven bard shit, and you're reading about this dark elf who's so dark.
Speaker 1: Oh my god.
Speaker 0: At least can we read like a mind flayer book or something?
Speaker 1: But then there's a tier below that and the tier below that is the clerics quintet.
Speaker 1: I would not make you read that.
Speaker 1: Hold it book about a beholder or something That'd be like pool of radiance style, which is also not actually good.
Speaker 0: I mean none of its good right.
Speaker 1: actually though I'd probably pick a planescape book cuz if I had to pick the best D&D book ever It's probably pages of pain, which is well.
Speaker 0: I mean isn't the best game the Planescape torment?
Speaker 1: yes, so please gave torment and the book pages of pain are very similar and adjacent to one another.
Speaker 0: It starts with some dude waking up being like what the fuck is going.
Speaker 1: basically yes, and it actually is.
Speaker 0: it actually plans get tournament and just the Torment tournament and torment just the video game version of that book.
Speaker 1: so it is adjacent to our car recent book club as well.
Speaker 0: Get into some Greek myth, it's a oh I figured out what book it's gonna be.
Speaker 1: oh you figured it out You can reveal now.
Speaker 0: You're gonna wait till next episode.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 1: That's fine.
Speaker 1: otherwise Because you're listening to this episode of geek nights You're obviously a fan of our anime reviews, or you got tricked because we're but we did already Review.
Speaker 1: the show we're about to talk about on.
Speaker 1: geek nights judges anime by its cover our YouTube show.
Speaker 1: That is on YouTube right now.
Speaker 1: You can go watch it so you can both listen to our review of this anime Before we watched it and now you're about to listen to our review after we watch three episodes mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: So yeah, let's get right into it.
Speaker 1: I think So.
Speaker 1: cells at work right.
Speaker 0: so I actually knew about this before the judging a little bit.
Speaker 0: There's basically.
Speaker 0: I don't know if I think it's a manga right.
Speaker 1: it is based on a manga right.
Speaker 1: so that what it is A shonen manga that runs in.
Speaker 1: let's see kodansha.
Speaker 0: I feel like there have been other things started in 2015. other anime and manga in this genre before.
Speaker 1: well wait the genre of Gajinka or the genre of like.
Speaker 1: let's go inside the body and see what it's not.
Speaker 0: it's almost two different genres, right?
Speaker 0: There's the one genre of the sort of Educational anime manga such as muyashiman where it's like.
Speaker 0: okay You know this is an anime manga with sort of a normal generic plot But we're gonna spend a lot of time educating you about a thing right, but educating you in a Extremely superficial manner right.
Speaker 0: well somewhat super well yashiman is pretty goddamn superficial You know.
Speaker 0: it's like.
Speaker 0: the amount of education you get varies a lot right you could say.
Speaker 0: initially educates you about cars But actually As Awful as it is I'm gonna make a true statement.
Speaker 0: Yeah, is that true bra teaches you more about underwear than initial D. Teaches you about cars.
Speaker 1: that is both awful and 100% accurate.
Speaker 0: So there's the educational aspect, but then there's also the okay.
Speaker 0: take a thing that is not a whole system.
Speaker 0: That is not people and Personify it right.
Speaker 1: so basically make it an analogy to teach you about the thing, but also be entertaining right.
Speaker 0: so instead of showing You you know just an educational film about the human body It's like well all red blood cells will be characters all white blood cells be characters.
Speaker 0: all the platelets would be characters.
Speaker 0: all that Right.
Speaker 0: well turn all the cells in the human body into characters and put them in a world You know that looks like a fantasy world civilization city kind of place complex you know and Have them behave in such a way that matches the way the human body works to some extent You know and such-and-such.
Speaker 1: so the Yeah, so the show basically follows this red blood cell who follows the trope of.
Speaker 1: she gets lost all the time Which just gives us an excuse to see all these different.
Speaker 0: It's really easy sort of trope of like.
Speaker 0: okay in the first episode you want to sort of show you around.
Speaker 0: Have you meet all these characters at least for one second each show you all the parts of the body.
Speaker 0: We'll have the red blood cell get lost.
Speaker 0: and then the second episode.
Speaker 0: I didn't watch the third episode.
Speaker 0: There's only three episodes.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I only watched a little bit of the third episode because I just start doing this show.
Speaker 1: yeah Well, there's only three out.
Speaker 1: like the fourth one food poisoning isn't even out yet right.
Speaker 0: and basically that each episode the plot is Red blood cell gets lost red blood cell encounters some harm that is coming to the body White blood cell and she has a crush on.
Speaker 0: yes and a white blood cell and many other cells Come to the rescue and solve the problem.
Speaker 0: restoring health to the body.
Speaker 0: yeah, and then there's another episode.
Speaker 0: It's completely episodic.
Speaker 0: There is no connection between the episodes other than recognizing the characters at least so far.
Speaker 1: the one connection I can point out is that whatever body.
Speaker 1: This is is not doing well.
Speaker 0: No, they in episode one they let you know that the body is immunocompromised To some extent and then doesn't seem to have hemophilia, but it has a shortage of Episode one.
Speaker 1: I think you guys want like pneumonia the person.
Speaker 1: episode two they get a big old cut.
Speaker 1: all this bacteria comes in.
Speaker 0: Didn't put on any neosporin or band-aid.
Speaker 0: what the fuck's wrong with you?
Speaker 1: Flu is episode three and episode four is food poisoning.
Speaker 1: so I suspect this person is making poor choices.
Speaker 0: I hope you get some poop in episode four.
Speaker 1: I think we definitely will.
Speaker 1: there's gonna be some poop poisoning.
Speaker 1: But the thing I like this show like I'm actually gonna keep watching it like it's not.
Speaker 1: It is definitely better than attack on Titan.
Speaker 1: yeah sure because things actually happen like.
Speaker 1: Shows like this can very easily be very bland and very surface level and like not go anywhere.
Speaker 1: But they actually.
Speaker 1: I'm not gonna speak to the accuracy of the analogies to any significant.
Speaker 0: It's what the hell do I know about biology, but the basics way less I know.
Speaker 0: I know even less than this show is teaching.
Speaker 1: this show is Deeply Invested in making the analogies way more complex than you would expect.
Speaker 1: Like it goes way Deeper like I'm not saying they try to teach you words.
Speaker 0: like they try to teach you about the different types of white blood cells Like oh, that's a lymphocyte and that one's a killer Macrophage that one's a macrophage, and it's shockingly detailed in that regard.
Speaker 1: like I like how the platelets Cute little kids and everyone when the show tries real hard to be cute And it kind of works because they are really cute like you things.
Speaker 1: But I think that the most interesting part of this is that it also doesn't go out of its way to Overexplain things like.
Speaker 0: the analogies will just sort of fit so that you are gonna be a super stickler about like.
Speaker 0: if you actually know Anything about biology and you're one of those people who's like it's not exactly really accurate well You're gonna be pissed off at this show.
Speaker 1: But it's also way more accurate than you would otherwise expect.
Speaker 1: yes in like there's a naive White blood cell like a naive T Cell in episode 3 and he's scared doesn't know what to do and then a dendrite cell is like listen, dude It's okay And he tells him what to do and then he evolves into the like the right cat like it.
Speaker 1: That's kind of what happens in the immune system.
Speaker 1: Like.
Speaker 1: it follows that to a pretty deep level, but it also it'll use proper nouns in a plausible context But it won't then always just have a character explained like the spleen is where X happens.
Speaker 1: It sort of lets you the viewer figure these things out on your own.
Speaker 1: I actually really appreciate that because in the first episode the red blood cell gets lost and she accidentally goes into the spleen and There's this very tranquil looking woman.
Speaker 1: Who's like may I help you?
Speaker 1: and she's like I think I'm lost.
Speaker 1: she's like yeah I think you are and the red blood cell leaves.
Speaker 1: and that's really funny Because the spleen basically destroys old red blood cells and recycles their parts.
Speaker 1: So the red blood cell wandering in there.
Speaker 1: that was funny and I feel like that's gonna come back later.
Speaker 1: But the show like a less well-done show would have explained what the spleen does right there and instead of being funny You just would have dragged out this boring.
Speaker 0: In episode 2 the cute platelets make a big like a mesh Yeah to cover up the wound and then all the cells get stuck on it and make a big scam.
Speaker 0: It's like oh my god, we're stuck here like yeah, you be stuck here for like three days.
Speaker 1: Yep But I actually like to show like.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna keep watching it.
Speaker 1: it's cute it's light-hearted.
Speaker 0: It's not like the kind of show that I'm gonna watch religiously like if I'm not gonna like be like, oh my god Is there a new episode?
Speaker 0: I gotta watch it right away, but it's sort of like I watch this.
Speaker 1: Why not if I'm sitting around not doing much this you show.
Speaker 0: there's worse things you could watch like more attack on Titan.
Speaker 1: Okay, I really like to tag on Titan but more happens in one episode of this show that happened in like the last Five episodes of attack on time.
Speaker 0: There's only one thing in the show that super super bothers me a lot.
Speaker 1: All right I'm curious.
Speaker 0: So basically you sort of have this.
Speaker 0: One thing that bothers me only a little bit is that even though you got this biological aspect going on?
Speaker 0: Yeah, the show really is just sort of a generic monster of the week or that some bacteria or virus or whatever To be fair really how our bodies are.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they're just fighting something every episode, right?
Speaker 0: It's still like a monster of the week.
Speaker 1: It's a shonen show.
Speaker 1: the fighting is actually pretty well done Like the white blood cell just fucking carries a knife and stabs him to death like it's pretty yeah.
Speaker 0: But the thing that gets me the most is that in those fight scenes I think Emily's bothered by the same thing.
Speaker 0: I think you're gonna say the white blood cell cuts up some bacteria Which is the monster with this knife?
Speaker 1: and what comes out of that monster?
Speaker 0: and then the white blood cell is then covered in blood.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so yeah, wait, so wait.
Speaker 0: Hey, yeah How does this is that blood that is on the white blood cell itself?
Speaker 0: a whole bunch of even more?
Speaker 0: Microscopic cells that are themselves personified.
Speaker 0: if we were to zoom in even more I have two things to say about that.
Speaker 1: cuz Emily How the fuck does that work?
Speaker 1: we were watching it together and Emmett's no goddamn Every time he stabbed a motherfucker Emily was like that doesn't make.
Speaker 1: Well Here are the two things I would say about that.
Speaker 1: So one thing I would say is that in the fiction of this world, maybe the cells watch an anime about Smaller cells and all the things that make up bacteria and viruses and there's little dudes running around But you know what.
Speaker 0: even if they do it's not blood - you were the size of bacteria So to cut one red stuff wouldn't come out at no point.
Speaker 1: Did they did anyone say that was blood?
Speaker 0: Yeah, they did Pretty sure.
Speaker 0: I saw a subtitle that was like, oh you got blood on you.
Speaker 1: I would argue that that is cytoplasm from the destroyed bacteria or the Stuff that's inside of a virus.
Speaker 0: cytoplasm would not.
Speaker 0: if they were that small Cytoplasm wouldn't be like that.
Speaker 0: They'd actually be able to see the components, right?
Speaker 1: What do you think?
Speaker 0: cytoplasm is just goop?
Speaker 1: Kinda, there's a structure.
Speaker 1: There's like a skeleton.
Speaker 0: if you were that small that you were a cell you could see molecules like individual ones.
Speaker 1: I think you underestimate or overestimate the smallness of those molecules.
Speaker 1: I'm going with the fact that that is cytoplasm and Remnants of proteins from the lysing or whatever that happened to those cells and I'm confident that that is how that fiction is gonna work and I'm just gonna let it go.
Speaker 0: I'm just saying that that's kind of messed up.
Speaker 0: Why they made was a conscious choice to put that there because it's in every episode this happens.
Speaker 0: also, you know the All the bacterias are just like monsters and they're dragon ball monsters and I love that.
Speaker 0: No, but there seems to be some connection between them like in the second episode when the bacteria the pneumonia comes.
Speaker 0: they're like It's like they knew the ones that came in the earlier episode and got killed like there's some relation between them.
Speaker 0: Well again, I think the person that this show is about is there some like boss bacteria that's outside waiting just to get this body.
Speaker 1: I feel like the only fiction that makes sense is that the body this is in is actually the body of that hobo in the Santa Claus out.
Speaker 0: I think this body more.
Speaker 0: I think the body is in a hospital which is the only way that would explain it like having the same Bacterias keep coming at it all the time.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna go with the fact that this canonical is linked to Rick and Morty and it's that hobo There's.
Speaker 1: there's a whole episode in that show where basically they make Jurassic Park.
Speaker 0: It's the hobo get a pneumonia and then an abrasion and then a food poisoning.
Speaker 1: actually kinda the the hobo is basically the host of Jurassic Park and you shrink down and go into Jurassic Park, but instead of dinosaurs, it's inside of the body.
Speaker 1: So and it's kind there is heavy Adjacency between that episode of Rick and Morty.
Speaker 1: in this anime is all I'm saying.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and it would make sense.
Speaker 0: I feel like if you're a person who's just like an anime fan who watches a lot of anime This is probably gonna be like a show.
Speaker 0: that's on your list for this season.
Speaker 1: I still ran the RIT anime club.
Speaker 1: the second the fourth episode was out.
Speaker 1: We would show this at the club.
Speaker 1: Yeah, this would be a no-brainer.
Speaker 0: We would show the show right but isn't a anime.
Speaker 0: It's like a B anime.
Speaker 1: it's like if scrap princess is a B plus this is a B and in my mind B means Solidly solidly entertaining, but I won't go out of my way to watch it if I have something better to watch.
Speaker 0: I think what it is is that it's so light is that it's almost like convenient which is a benefit.
Speaker 1: But it also moves because a lot of shows that are light like my Ashiman as much as I wanted to like it I got bored by it.
Speaker 0: It's not a lot happens.
Speaker 0: But the thing is it doesn't happen because it's so light and episodic It doesn't have any sort of anything important or big tying it together.
Speaker 0: Well, so it's like it's only three episodes, right?
Speaker 0: But there isn't he.
Speaker 0: there's nothing to like.
Speaker 0: care about the old like.
Speaker 0: literally the only plot is what the the red blood cell love.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, I literally don't care if the red blood cell dies.
Speaker 1: No, all I want to see are individual scenes of the cells in a ride.
Speaker 0: There is no big plot to care about.
Speaker 0: so there's no like investment.
Speaker 1: Let's see I'm gonna show the door bad.
Speaker 1: Okay, so here are the names of the manga volumes in order?
Speaker 1: Pneumonococcus Cedar pollen allergy, that's very Japanese.
Speaker 1: influenza scrape wound food poisoning.
Speaker 1: So I guess I skipped over the allergy one for the episode which I guess makes sense though I because I guess mast cells and all that would come up in there Erythroblasts and yellow sites what?
Speaker 1: Cancer cells part one.
Speaker 1: Oh cancer cells part two.
Speaker 0: This person's definitely in the hospital.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I knew that.
Speaker 1: Wow Wow the H. Pylori Antigenic shift this cancers.
Speaker 1: There's a further cancer cell arc later.
Speaker 1: I feel like this person is not gonna make it.
Speaker 0: No, they're already immunocompromised.
Speaker 1: on that episode one I told you if this show ends Eventually with the person's dead and like social order breaking down and it turns into Mad Max inside of this rotting body I will turn this into an a-minus anime.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah All the bacteria come in and win the end.
Speaker 1: cuz shows like this never go there.
Speaker 0: if this shows the app I said apocalypse like a regular real anime where everyone dies at the end if this show goes there.
Speaker 1: I'm telling you a - anime That would be super cool.
Speaker 1: That would be great.
Speaker 1: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Speaker 0: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 1: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 0: But unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night And the patreon patrons for this episode of geek nights are Craig Oliver Allen Joyce Rebecca Dunne Heidi McNicholas shimmering Ruby obelisk hanging in the sky guitar topish in my state.
Speaker 1: e.com.
Speaker 1: Jeremy minor link Iji scoot alone Lee Roberto Kingsley Kelly Snyder cold guy Amanda Do shet Shawn Yeager Matthew Smith Nicholas brand out mr Strong distraction for two one creations Chris Reimer and Thomas.
Speaker 1: on.
Speaker 1: Sherman von Horrell Rory James David White Rochelle, Monta Nona super boy trip wire sailor Vista Don Schleich Jojo Joestar Clinton Walton Ren from New Zealand Ryan pair drew open letter.
Speaker 1: Finn Chris midkiff Daniel Redman Sean Klein Chris Reimer and Thomas, huh?
Speaker 1: today By now I don't believe that anybody feels the way I do Back.
Speaker 1: be be be be be be be be be be be be be be be Sure sure sure sure sure sure sure sure.
Speaker 1: then everybody feels feel fee-free and all the roles we have to walk away And al chuckles.
Speaker 1: There are many things that I would like to say ♪.
Speaker 0: Because maybe you're gonna be the one that saves me ♪ ♪ And after all, you're my one ♪.