Speaker 1: It's Tuesday, June 19th 2018.
Speaker 1: I'm rim.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott and this is geek nights.
Speaker 1: tonight we got a double feature with cockroach poker and Cocker lock and poker Royale With cheese.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: It has been Gloriously hot in New York the past few days.
Speaker 1: I'm very happy with this situation.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there's a little thunderstorm though, but it was at night.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Also, I like thunderstorms I miss.
Speaker 0: I like thunderstorms at night when I'm inside.
Speaker 0: I if I'm outside then I don't like them But if I'm inside they're the best.
Speaker 1: but I guess my walk actually my favorite the one there's like.
Speaker 1: I want to live in cities for the rest of my life.
Speaker 1: in fact, I want to live in New York City for the rest of my life, but The one of the I gotta be I gotta become New York old man.
Speaker 0: where then people say look at that old New York, man.
Speaker 1: Yep, I want to be that guy who's so old that like I know about the subway before whatever future stuff I'm sure old Michigan man.
Speaker 0: You're not old New York, man.
Speaker 1: I can if when I'm 80, I'll just spend enough time in New York to where I'll qualify as old New York, man.
Speaker 1: No, but So the thing that I miss from living in Michigan in the burbs.
Speaker 0: Hey, like I said, Michigan man Is.
Speaker 1: that is this thing where whenever there's a big thunderstorm or like a tornado cuz they'd be tornadoes all the time It's not like when that one tornado Appeared for a brief instant in Brooklyn and everybody lost their shit.
Speaker 1: This was like tornadoes were every week.
Speaker 1: But what a normal person does when there's a crazy thunderstorm?
Speaker 1: as they stay inside or maybe they go into their basement People in Michigan do is you open your garage door and you sit in the garage and watch the storm.
Speaker 0: I do that, only I do it from a window.
Speaker 1: It's not the same.
Speaker 0: You gotta be you're basically also Had a garage in my whole life.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I uh, I do also miss.
Speaker 0: I've actually never ever.
Speaker 0: I've always I've been to people's houses with garages plenty of times.
Speaker 0: I never once actually lived in a place that had a garage.
Speaker 1: I've only ever lived in two houses that didn't know they all had garages, but I've only lived in two places that had Detached garages everywhere.
Speaker 1: I live.
Speaker 1: the garage was connected to the house.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I know that everyone I knew had an attached garage.
Speaker 0: So it's like I. I oh no, I guess my grandparents had a tiny little Unattached garage that was on.
Speaker 0: it was on the alley though in the back.
Speaker 1: My grandpa pulled a scam though.
Speaker 1: Oh an alley.
Speaker 0: I lived in a house that had an alley a long time ago But anyway The point is I went to people's houses with garages enough that I knew that when you had a garage You always entered your house from the door.
Speaker 0: that goes into the house from the garage.
Speaker 0: Nobody entered their house like through the actual front door.
Speaker 0: But then it's like I'm like, why don't these people fucking ever use the front door?
Speaker 0: They keep using the garage all the time actually, so I got a good.
Speaker 0: It's like even like even if you walk somewhere.
Speaker 0: shouldn't you then use the front door and not the garage?
Speaker 0: Do I understand we just get out of your car?
Speaker 0: Well, if you walk somewhere, but it's like we used our front door if you want somewhere.
Speaker 1: Why not use the side door?
Speaker 0: We didn't have us.
Speaker 0: if you only have a side door if you have a house with a garage like Architecture Did not have a side door.
Speaker 1: that in front door in the back door side doors are as far as I can tell.
Speaker 1: I'm not sure If this is true like other shibboleths But I've really only encountered side doors in old houses in the Midwest and nowhere else.
Speaker 0: There are plenty of side door houses in the in the suburbs in Connecticut Like a sliding glass door like a door wall.
Speaker 1: No, no, it's like another front door that's on the side.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah Yeah, that is it doesn't just go into the garage, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so what my grandparents house?
Speaker 1: they built their house like.
Speaker 1: they built it themselves and The road moved at some point.
Speaker 1: So they had a front door that went to a foyer and a living room that was pointed nowhere once the road moved.
Speaker 1: So that door basically never got opened again.
Speaker 0: There was a point not replace that door with a wall or They just left it.
Speaker 0: So there was vestigial a door that you can't actually open.
Speaker 0: So there was this living room because now someone can break in that door that you've let rust.
Speaker 1: There's a giant living room with a foyer and like a closet and all this stuff and this giant ass porch.
Speaker 1: That's just like.
Speaker 1: it's like a wing of the house that no one ever even went to anymore.
Speaker 1: that door Like.
Speaker 1: I opened that door once and it like creaked as I pushed it open with all the fries.
Speaker 0: You could actually open it without a hammer.
Speaker 1: It's really well made house really well made door.
Speaker 1: My grandpa made it but they had a detached garage, but the garage was a scam.
Speaker 1: It had a garage door that could not be opened.
Speaker 1: It was actually a gigantic multi-story woodworking shop that was illegal to build on the land.
Speaker 1: So my grandpa had a permit to build a garage and he one of the walls just had a group.
Speaker 1: There was a wall and behind the wall was a garage door That just looked on the outside like a real garage door that could not be open.
Speaker 0: one of the bread books I have I think there's a story where the guy was trying to build some sort of bakery on his property.
Speaker 0: They didn't let him so he moved Because it was some sort of HOA kind of fight, but then they had this cookbook about bread.
Speaker 0: He's talking about fighting with the people in Portland or thereabouts.
Speaker 1: But the front door became a side door and then what they used as the front door was the old side door.
Speaker 1: But you know what it went to because the garage was fake and not attached carport.
Speaker 1: Mmm I don't run into carports too much anymore except in I guess in some cities.
Speaker 0: So I learned the other day the ultra ultra ultra mega stupid evil rich people in the city.
Speaker 0: they have a thing nowadays Where you bring your car on the car elevator?
Speaker 0: It's a car elevator.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I saw one of those in Queens that will bring your car to your apartment.
Speaker 0: So you live on the 80th floor of some mega building?
Speaker 1: Oh, no I when I was talking to the car elevator where you drive up to one of those like rebuilt brownstones like those tiny.
Speaker 0: No, you live in the mega Down.
Speaker 0: no, we're talking you in the skyscraper over there that the stick okay, and you they bring your car to your floor in your apartment and it's Separated in such a way that no fumes or sounds or anything will actually get into your apartment.
Speaker 1: That's convenient but that means that it's very easy to get the guillotine in there.
Speaker 0: you can put things in your car and Take them out of your car without having to like go all the way down to the garage because your car is in your apartment.
Speaker 0: So like you can unload your groceries right from the back of the car and such and such and then when you want to drive Somewhere you just put your car.
Speaker 0: just you just push it.
Speaker 0: I don't know what you do push the button or something and then your car goes back down and then you go back down with It.
Speaker 0: I guess you can get in the car and probably ride it down and then go straight out.
Speaker 1: So here's what I don't get about that.
Speaker 1: if you're that rich Why are you driving?
Speaker 0: Oh I mean your chauffeur can do the same thing and then they can unload the groceries.
Speaker 0: But then you get out of the car and you're already in your apartment.
Speaker 0: you can't.
Speaker 0: you don't even need the umbrella to go to the front door of the building because you're in your car the whole time and You get out and you're already in your apartment.
Speaker 1: I feel like Most people who are that rich would go once like that.
Speaker 1: They just leave from the helicopter on the roof.
Speaker 0: I'm just saying this is a thing that rich people have in some of the mega buildings in the city And I'm sure the other mega buildings that come from the future Want to compete with those.
Speaker 0: for rich people money will be providing the same.
Speaker 1: The elevator I was talking about the one I saw in Queens is you drive your car to the tiny driveway and then the driveway Just sinks down and then a cover comes over the time.
Speaker 0: It's not That's not.
Speaker 1: I saw one of those like out in Queens and there's like way out.
Speaker 0: I mean that's nice, but that's not.
Speaker 0: that's not a rich person.
Speaker 0: That's just.
Speaker 0: it's not a wealthy person.
Speaker 0: Might be a rich person.
Speaker 1: It's not a wealthy person Yep, so in the news the Overwatch League, which I watched the games But again, I literally do not care who wins.
Speaker 0: I got one New York to win because they are called New York.
Speaker 1: Yep, I want New York to win because I want other people to say all that New York team.
Speaker 0: and as far as I know So far the New York team has not had any revealed shit heads on it getting suspended for being a dick.
Speaker 0: I think some of the other teams have on top of that the New York team.
Speaker 1: if they had much better than all the other Teams, it's a joke.
Speaker 0: That's just by.
Speaker 0: is that by chance?
Speaker 0: I think it's by chance because the New York team is I believe all Koreans.
Speaker 1: I think it's more by Moneyball.
Speaker 1: I think it's a Yankees situation.
Speaker 0: The point is is that the New York team has nothing to do with New York beyond its name.
Speaker 1: So the New York stiff whatsoever for tiebreakers is plus 83.
Speaker 1: The next team down the valiant is 36.
Speaker 1: So that gives you a sense of the differential numbers.
Speaker 0: in terms of their records New York Well, at least that means overwatch has a high skill cap.
Speaker 1: Yeah, New York went 34 and 6 for the season.
Speaker 0: Uh-huh was the next best record 27 and 13.
Speaker 1: Uh-huh, and it's all real close in that middle tier but Down to the bottom.
Speaker 1: so Florida mayhem was second to last.
Speaker 1: they only won seven games.
Speaker 1: Yeah good but The Shanghai Dragons already have set a record Like so it's the first year of the real.
Speaker 0: are they?
Speaker 0: oh?
Speaker 0: are they oh?
Speaker 1: and they're oh and 40.
Speaker 0: They have not won.
Speaker 0: a single man did not win a single match even against the Florida team.
Speaker 1: No, the Florida team beat them every time they competed.
Speaker 0: They couldn't even win one match against.
Speaker 0: in the map breakdown meaning Individual matter they draft these players originally.
Speaker 1: Ah, I don't know.
Speaker 0: I do not know why I don't know how the teams were constructed originally.
Speaker 0: just sort of appeared right?
Speaker 1: I didn't watch any.
Speaker 0: I don't think.
Speaker 0: I don't think they like published any of that information.
Speaker 0: I didn't.
Speaker 1: I only watched games that happened to be on like like.
Speaker 1: Oh overwatch.
Speaker 0: Yeah, me too.
Speaker 0: So like I would turn out like I would open up twitch be like.
Speaker 0: is there anything streaming right now?
Speaker 0: And if I saw it there, it would usually be on the front of twitch.
Speaker 1: I ended up seeing some Spitfire and some Philadelphia, but I didn't actually see any Shanghai dragons games.
Speaker 0: I did not see any Shanghai dragons.
Speaker 1: I want to go back and find when Shanghai played New York and watch that game and that's what I'm gonna do tonight.
Speaker 1: I think all right go.
Speaker 1: That's like watching the Buffalo Sabres play against literally.
Speaker 0: I think what you want to do is watch Shanghai versus, Florida and see.
Speaker 0: you know What the difference is that made.
Speaker 0: that made Shanghai so bad?
Speaker 0: Yeah, cuz Florida is still bad couldn't even win one like.
Speaker 1: not one game.
Speaker 0: Like I haven't even played over.
Speaker 0: one won a hockey game or two.
Speaker 0: like I've never played overwatch And they should.
Speaker 0: I mean I'm not I haven't played FPS is in a while But knowing this I feel confident like I could be a somewhat okay addition to at least the bench.
Speaker 0: Oh, it's got Shanghai team.
Speaker 1: I'll say this I'm confident despite having not played FPS is in a long time and having not played over.
Speaker 1: I'm also confident.
Speaker 0: I wouldn't probably even hit anyone with a single bullet on the New York team.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm pretty sure if you did the competitive ranking now.
Speaker 0: I'm also confident if I join the New York team I wouldn't sandbag them so badly that they would lose.
Speaker 1: I think you would.
Speaker 0: they're so good.
Speaker 1: I think you would Sandbag them so bad.
Speaker 0: the uh not against Shanghai.
Speaker 0: It's hard to say One bad player can really ruin it to me and the rest of the people in all.
Speaker 0: New York against Shanghai.
Speaker 1: I think we go in Only if you stayed in spawn.
Speaker 0: don't go out of spawn if it's me playing basketball with LeBron Michael Jordan Magic Johnson Shaq Against you know the Phoenix Suns.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we're gonna win.
Speaker 0: That's what I'm saying, but I'm pretty sure if you don't pass me the ball.
Speaker 0: I get in someone's way occasionally.
Speaker 1: I'm pretty sure if you just picked up overwatch and played it today like if you just went home and Did the ranking matches for the current competitive season pretty sure you'd be silver?
Speaker 1: Which is already better than a huge percentage of overwatch players, which is terrifying.
Speaker 1: Meanwhile silver is considered like unworthy of playing with.
Speaker 0: well I'd have to I'd have to I'd.
Speaker 0: I probably have to ask professor you you know what the strats are?
Speaker 1: yeah Honestly Basic team coordination and basic FPS skills.
Speaker 1: I get you a long way in this game.
Speaker 1: Like you would do better than a lot of people.
Speaker 1: So yeah, Shanghai, I don't know what happened, but the playoffs are in July the brackets are out.
Speaker 0: When did the season start?
Speaker 0: I don't even remember but It feels like it's been going on a long time.
Speaker 0: like did this take longer than a year?
Speaker 1: No, but they did.
Speaker 1: 40 matches took a while like at the teams going.
Speaker 0: It's a lot of matches for not a lot of teams.
Speaker 1: New York and LA are the division winners who are Seated in the tournament and get the buys or whatever gonna buy.
Speaker 1: yeah, and the wildcards are Boston LA London and Philadelphia.
Speaker 0: It's nice to know that things like like the last time I checked the standings.
Speaker 0: It was a New York and London.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so it's nice to see that the the teams weren't so static and just like it wasn't a foregone conclusion.
Speaker 0: What's gonna happen?
Speaker 0: like even though it seems like New York's gonna win?
Speaker 0: They could lose.
Speaker 1: also there was a race for the wildcard slots the soul and definitely if you like other than the top.
Speaker 0: You know those middle teams is you know, always a lot of action going on.
Speaker 0: Well, you know what the kind of like.
Speaker 0: it's a lot like the NFL in that way We talk about.
Speaker 0: it seems like NFL playoff.
Speaker 1: You need a bad team or a bad experience sometimes to remind you what it's like.
Speaker 1: Shanghai is the super agree Of this Cleveland Browns.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you need a Cleveland Browns.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you need a Newman.
Speaker 1: So in some other news and this one's really funny to me because I don't care I also don't care but Fortnight like it or not.
Speaker 1: Just like that decide the game is good or bad.
Speaker 1: It doesn't matter It's the biggest game.
Speaker 1: now like you cannot it is big.
Speaker 1: There's reasons why it's big.
Speaker 1: It's gonna be minecraft 2 in terms of like pop culture.
Speaker 0: Well, you know, you don't have to worry though cuz it's not gonna be the game forever.
Speaker 0: World of Warcraft wasn't the game forever, you know, no game has ever lasted forever.
Speaker 0: Replace you're like better serious games or games games that are big enough even though they may rise and fall.
Speaker 0: Oh, you know games that have at some point been big enough.
Speaker 0: Yep Once you reach this sort of critical point where your game was at some time large it lives.
Speaker 0: now It won't be.
Speaker 0: it won't stay the biggest but it lives like World of Warcraft no longer anywhere near the biggest.
Speaker 0: It's alive.
Speaker 0: It is solidly alive.
Speaker 0: rocket League is solidly alive.
Speaker 1: Solidly alive is gonna survive.
Speaker 0: this pub G is decreasing But it will.
Speaker 0: then it will eventually reach a point where it much like counter-strike It is just solidly alive, you know hardstone solidly.
Speaker 0: All these games are just.
Speaker 0: they go up they get big then they go back down and they stabilize And we're only the people who are dedicated to them.
Speaker 0: Stay there and don't move very much or they keep coming back to that game Even though they may visit other games from time to time.
Speaker 0: and that's what fortnight's gonna do.
Speaker 0: It's big right now.
Speaker 0: It'll go back down and then it will solidify just like the rest.
Speaker 1: but an important thing about Fortnight and this is actually a really big deal is that it's doing something.
Speaker 1: that one we've said people should do a long.
Speaker 1: That one panel we didn't video.
Speaker 1: we talked about this a bunch But more games are doing it and we're better positioned to do it.
Speaker 1: for tonight is on every goddamn platform There is.
Speaker 0: well because it's built on the Unreal Engine which is on and it's made by the company that makes the Unreal Engine Is what can build for every console and every mobile platform and everything you can play on your ps4.
Speaker 1: Yeah, my brother your Xbox or your cell phone.
Speaker 0: My brother's into it.
Speaker 0: He was.
Speaker 0: he was trying to like get me to join.
Speaker 0: Oh hell no He's trying to get me to join on.
Speaker 0: he's playing on his phone or his iPad.
Speaker 0: He was trying to eat.
Speaker 0: like sent me a met like one of those messages I think.
Speaker 0: if I joined I think I think he would have gotten loot or something.
Speaker 0: But then he's like no you switch.
Speaker 0: he's.
Speaker 0: now he's playing it on the switch instead of it on the phone.
Speaker 1: because the switch probably Honestly, having looked at the game.
Speaker 1: I think the Nintendo switch is the best form factor for the game not PC.
Speaker 0: Yes, though, right?
Speaker 1: Ah Yeah, it's an FPS in the same way that Team Fortress 2 is an FPS, okay But yeah It's like he's sweet.
Speaker 1: He now plays it on the switch instead like the switch is in my opinion having not really played the game other than like looking At it.
Speaker 1: It is the best platform for the game.
Speaker 0: I mean, it's also free.
Speaker 0: So it's like we could try it.
Speaker 1: But Game has cross play and that it doesn't care what platform you're on.
Speaker 1: It's just everybody play.
Speaker 1: you have an account everybody play.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the people on phones are playing against people on PC, right?
Speaker 1: You can use your same account.
Speaker 1: You can have an account.
Speaker 0: Rocket League does that you play against PlayStation people on.
Speaker 1: when you're on PC You can play on the switch and also play on the phone with your same account and track it like it's all the same.
Speaker 0: Well, cuz you've done suck.
Speaker 0: if you got a bunch of because it's free to play a game If you got a bunch of loot and then suddenly you switch platforms and your loots gone.
Speaker 0: The news I got the same hearthstone cards on my iPad as they do on my PC.
Speaker 1: So the news and this is pretty important if I didn't I would be fucking Bad news because Sony is kind of effed here.
Speaker 1: All the crossplay works on all the platforms except the ps4.
Speaker 0: I don't understand why the ps4 is the one Rocket League worked like Xbox is the one left out for Rocket League.
Speaker 0: you could Rocket League.
Speaker 0: It was like PC and PlayStation and then I think Nintendo switch did get in.
Speaker 0: I'm not sure but like those are the only two they played together.
Speaker 1: So here's the deal It's like.
Speaker 0: why would they leave it out now?
Speaker 1: What?
Speaker 1: what they've specifically blocked is you if you have an account in fortnight?
Speaker 1: you can either play only ps4 with that account or Any and all other platforms combined forever?
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm, you cannot.
Speaker 1: if an account has ever played on a switch You can't use that account on a ps4.
Speaker 1: and if you've ever played on a ps4 You can't use that account on your switch, but if I'm playing on PC, am I gonna play against people who are on ps4s?
Speaker 1: I don't actually know.
Speaker 1: cuz no, I don't no one cares about that.
Speaker 1: Sony Okay, so he's refused to even allow crossplay between ps4 rival counsel.
Speaker 0: Okay, so that answers that for several other games, but rocket league they allow it But not anyone.
Speaker 1: Xbox switch fortnight.
Speaker 1: That's not the news.
Speaker 1: The news is that they're locking the accounts out.
Speaker 0: So a bunch of people got Nintendo switches and they said oh, I want to play on switch now instead of PlayStation On PlayStation and they won't let them log in on switch because their account is locked to PlayStation.
Speaker 0: And I'm pretty sure they want to play on switch.
Speaker 0: They have to buy all new loot.
Speaker 1: I'm pretty sure the reason for this is that fortnight is the example.
Speaker 1: now like fortnight is gonna be one of the things that breaks the idea of platform exclusives for real because it's that big and Nintendo has their first party stuff, but they're not gonna release their games on other platforms.
Speaker 1: They don't need to worry about that Sony.
Speaker 1: if fortnight becomes just popular in and of itself and it's the game and Kids don't need a PlayStation 4 to play it.
Speaker 1: They're not gonna buy a PlayStation 4.
Speaker 0: They'll just buy whatever plays fortnight.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: I just need a thing that plays fortnight.
Speaker 0: I don't care which thing it is.
Speaker 1: And if there's a cross play if the world gets to the point to where the biggest games work on any platform Sony is the one who's hurt the most by that I think because Microsoft PC gaming master is Microsoft.
Speaker 1: the Xbox They could easily.
Speaker 0: any cross-platform game is effectively a PC game that has been ported to everything.
Speaker 1: Microsoft.
Speaker 0: if they write for a PC game that's been ported everything's.
Speaker 0: if you have a game that is running on one of those multi-platform Engines, it's a PC game.
Speaker 1: It's a Microsoft.
Speaker 1: the way the Xbox is.
Speaker 1: they could easily turn the Xbox into just a like.
Speaker 0: Microsoft seems to be trying to turn Windows 10 into a Xbox.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and I think they're gonna go down that road real.
Speaker 1: eventually.
Speaker 0: you got Xbox.
Speaker 0: you got Xbox apps and settings.
Speaker 0: Yeah, Windows 10 already.
Speaker 1: I think eventually Windows PC will also be effectively Xbox and I bet they'll sell an Xbox.
Speaker 1: That's actually just a Windows PC with set hardware Like.
Speaker 1: I think that's coming.
Speaker 1: Sony does not have that luxury and Sony is very very deeply invested in the idea of platform exclusives and some reason for their platform to be special and I think Sony's fucked in the long Run because of all this.
Speaker 1: Well, I think what's also gonna happen right is oh people are mad Sony fanboys are mad People are like, I think this is gonna really hurt Sony.
Speaker 0: I think this specific thing I could think there could be a lawsuit coming for sure.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and I think so I bet Sony's gonna back down but I bet backing down is actually bad for them in the long run.
Speaker 1: I think not.
Speaker 1: backing down is also bad for them in the long run.
Speaker 1: I think it's just bad for Sony in the long run.
Speaker 0: the two major things I see coming in the in terms of Cross-platform.
Speaker 0: this in the in the not-too-distant future is one all the companies that make games.
Speaker 0: They want you to stream games and not buy them so that they can control that everything and not have any piracy and etc.
Speaker 0: Etc, and they're gonna push for that even if people don't want it or even if it sucks because everyone's internet connection sucks.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right.
Speaker 0: So they're gonna try to get that but they won't be able to because internet connections are too bad.
Speaker 0: And the other thing that's gonna happen is you're gonna see people are gonna start using things like Apple TV Steam link, it's a you know, the you know Chrome Whatever's.
Speaker 0: and now basically all games will be phone games.
Speaker 0: You just play your phone game on the TV.
Speaker 0: You won't need the switch like that's.
Speaker 0: the next generation of console is basically No console.
Speaker 0: you just whatever device you have just streams to the TV because everyone already has these fucking things, right?
Speaker 0: It's like I'll just play a phone game and chromecast to my TV.
Speaker 0: Congratulations.
Speaker 1: iOS is now on par with a ps4 and frankly even the like super serious PC gamers.
Speaker 1: I feel like they'll have a sweet PC gaming rig They spent $6,000 on but then it will stream to all the other devices in their local cloud.
Speaker 1: so we'll see what happens with this.
Speaker 1: Sony is Really really trying to avoid making a definitive statement Because they realize they're F on this and the statement they released was kind of like it was pathetic Even by the standards of stone is off.
Speaker 1: Sony press releases In some other news that really affects Scott.
Speaker 0: So this is actually like a weird news because it's a surprise but also not a surprise.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well, it was not a surprise, but I think the surprise was that it happened.
Speaker 1: So suddenly Yes, the timing came.
Speaker 0: the timing came earlier than expected.
Speaker 1: I thought that you saw this coming in the long run and I expected a situation where they Can't like.
Speaker 1: the game continued to exist but they were making less and less money on it and we're like like Fewer updates come out.
Speaker 0: So anyway, yeah back in the day, right?
Speaker 0: We came to the city.
Speaker 0: We were going to board game night and board game night had problems, you know, people were slow.
Speaker 0: They weren't playing to win.
Speaker 0: yet.
Speaker 0: teach rules.
Speaker 0: I discovered netrunner.
Speaker 0: I just saw this really cool fucking game on the board game geek list, right?
Speaker 0: I bought it.
Speaker 0: I played it.
Speaker 0: I thought it was just a two-player card game.
Speaker 0: Nope It's actually what you wanted your whole life.
Speaker 0: that already existed and you didn't know.
Speaker 0: again a customizable card game like magic Except you don't have to collect the car as an aside.
Speaker 0: I noticed something interesting Net runner and it was cyberpunk and it was a great game.
Speaker 1: netrunner and overwatch were both the games We dreamed of when we were young and now that we're old they both came out and we each could only pick one.
Speaker 0: So I said, holy shit, I didn't realize that's what this was that this was more exactly what I wanted.
Speaker 0: So I got way into it and I started going to netrunner instead of going to board game night.
Speaker 0: So netrunner when I the first netrunner I just like I didn't even realize the deal with it that it was a. you know originally that it was a Richard Garfield game for the 90s that went away and came back even though when I saw that original box Art I was like, I remember seeing that in the store.
Speaker 0: Yep, never bought it anyway.
Speaker 0: But the first one thing I noticed very early on I think it was the very first netrunner tournament I went to when I saw the prize playmat that they were gonna give to whoever won the tournament.
Speaker 0: It was one of the first tournaments.
Speaker 0: I don't think the very first one had play mats.
Speaker 0: There were three different logos on the fucking playmat from companies right those fantasy flight games who actually made that the new current Soon to end netrunner right who also makes x-wing and such and such and are now owned by asthma day.
Speaker 0: There was a logo for Wizards of the Coast which made sense because they made the original netrunner Richard Garfield and such.
Speaker 0: And there was a third one which is now also relevant for our Talsorian games.
Speaker 0: You know our Talsorian games and I do not.
Speaker 0: they made the cyberpunk 2020 RP tabletop RPG which is now getting a video game version coming soon, right?
Speaker 0: It's all in the news that everyone's excited about right?
Speaker 0: because that original netrunner card game The theme of it was in that cyberpunk universe, right?
Speaker 0: So they had some legal right to it.
Speaker 0: So kind of fantasy flight games was licensing netrunner from both Watsy and our Talsorian.
Speaker 0: in order to produce this thing They were paying this license fee, which is what fantasy flight games mostly makes most of their money on.
Speaker 0: they have a Star Wars license.
Speaker 0: They had.
Speaker 0: they previously had the games workshop license.
Speaker 0: What are the licenses?
Speaker 0: do they have?
Speaker 0: Oh the the Game of Thrones license is big for them.
Speaker 0: They still have that, right?
Speaker 0: That's what fantasy flight games mostly does.
Speaker 0: is they like get licensed properties and make games based on them?
Speaker 0: Oh, they got some.
Speaker 0: they're currently publishing T&E, I guess whatever Some other things Citadel's anyway, so when I saw that I said man this game.
Speaker 0: if any of these three people Mostly the not the FFG one They're the ones who are making the game but it's like any of these two other people just pull the plug on this at any Time.
Speaker 0: we have no idea the licensing agreement is there's any moment.
Speaker 0: Watsy could just be like, you know We don't want you doing that.
Speaker 0: run it no more the end Right, so netrunner went on and it rose and it you know waxed and waned at various points, right?
Speaker 0: It's you know, it's been waning slightly.
Speaker 0: I haven't played it that much in the past six months or whatever.
Speaker 0: But you know, I'm still buying all the cards and following along with the community and seeing what's up.
Speaker 0: You know and if I'm really got nothing to do then I go.
Speaker 0: I still go play netrunner.
Speaker 0: you know, I met a lot of people playing netrunner as good times and Suddenly we see a news on the fantasy flight website like a week or two ago Jacking out netrunner is done.
Speaker 0: We did not we were did not renew the license with Watsy.
Speaker 0: and it's like on the one hand I totally saw that coming years ago.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but on the other hand, it's like whoa.
Speaker 0: You just announced like this new box that's coming at the end of the year.
Speaker 0: You're in the middle of a cycle of cards, right?
Speaker 1: It's like you're gonna release that last box apparently rain and reverie.
Speaker 1: Yes expansion exactly.
Speaker 0: So they got all this stuff going on it.
Speaker 0: This did not, you know The none of the play testers like we're like.
Speaker 0: we stopped getting new cards to play test.
Speaker 0: Like there was no Whiff of this.
Speaker 0: so obviously we'll probably never find out what the story was or it will be greatly.
Speaker 0: We'll have to get inside in front of the story.
Speaker 1: Monetization stream was drying out.
Speaker 0: There's a lot of suspicions that all make sense.
Speaker 0: So it's hard to know which one is right, but clearly FFG Wanted to keep this license active.
Speaker 0: obviously because they had didn't look like they were planning to end it and They weren't able to reach an agreement with Watsy and or art alsorian games to continue the netrunner license.
Speaker 0: So they're stopping the game the end once they release that box.
Speaker 0: It's all over.
Speaker 0: So there's a few things happening.
Speaker 0: number one The community is forming its own Organization to keep netrunner alive because the community is way strong and the game hasn't waned to the point where it makes sense to kill The game.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean you've got all the cards.
Speaker 0: Yeah I mean if you look at some of the other FFG games that did wane like the Cthulhu one or the Lord of the Rings One.
Speaker 0: they like reduced the production schedules and did other things to slow the game down But keep selling product and to fade it out.
Speaker 0: They did not do that with netrunner.
Speaker 0: They were going.
Speaker 0: they were still going at full steam when it when this happened.
Speaker 0: Another thing that's happening is that all those they're not reprinting anything because they can't they don't have time.
Speaker 0: So that rain and reverie box.
Speaker 0: I've heard.
Speaker 0: there's a lot of reports that have no evidence behind them But they're like man.
Speaker 0: Canada's only all of Canada's getting 200 boxes the end.
Speaker 0: Yeah stuff like that is going around the rumor mills.
Speaker 0: So there's gonna be a mad dash if every netrunner players like go and get one of these.
Speaker 0: So they can have a full set of netrunner which you're gonna need because there'll be no way in the future to get any netrunner Unless you find someone who's selling theirs or something like that.
Speaker 1: Just republish the game or remove all the Android IP.
Speaker 0: Well, the Android I don't care.
Speaker 1: I'll be honest.
Speaker 1: This is the thing that I'll I don't give a shit about.
Speaker 1: the.
Speaker 0: well No FFG the Android IP that is what FFG owns.
Speaker 0: They made a game.
Speaker 0: They made a game called.
Speaker 1: That's the part I care about the least.
Speaker 0: they made a game called Android that you can play.
Speaker 0: They also made what's it called?
Speaker 0: You got your infiltration.
Speaker 0: That's Android.
Speaker 0: Yeah it's a lot of the art and that and characters are the same as a netrunner.
Speaker 0: that FFG fully owns the Android IP.
Speaker 0: I'm not exactly sure like why they can't make a game just called Android the card game and have it have the same rules as netrunner and tweak it a little bit and Just stop calling it netrunner.
Speaker 0: Like I'm not sure which part of it is licensed from Wodsy Right that they have to.
Speaker 0: you know, it's like they've already changed the rules so much from the original netrunner.
Speaker 0: It's not like a and we know you can't patent game rules.
Speaker 0: Well, I think what's really interesting when I step back Oh, you can only patent game rules, but I don't forget.
Speaker 0: but at the point when
Speaker 1: I step back a little bit There's this situation I think where non collectible card games have an obvious monetization model of both the collector's market Like the primary market the secondary market that brings value from like card investment in trading or whatever and the draft tournaments Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: So there's like three main play and mercy.
Speaker 1: They tried to make drafting for netrunner and no one was in Revenue streams that were highly effective and the addictive nature of the games also feeds that cycle.
Speaker 1: and but with a non collectible game the draft tournaments never seem to work out for obvious reasons the Monetization model for this.
Speaker 1: there's no secondary market.
Speaker 1: So the primary market is every player buys every set once right?
Speaker 0: It's a subscription model.
Speaker 0: Basically.
Speaker 0: It's like World of Warcraft you pay $15 every month or two to make sure you have all the cards and then you all everyone has all the cards.
Speaker 0: and I think Really?
Speaker 0: I would really like to see a digital card game.
Speaker 0: do this.
Speaker 0: Imagine if hearthstone was.
Speaker 0: just pay ten bucks a month and you'll have every hearthstone card.
Speaker 0: and it's about playing the game It's not about gambling.
Speaker 1: But anyway in terms of like a non collectible game like this I feel like the only that you can't make enough money To keep a big property going and support a community effectively.
Speaker 0: You definitely make less money overall even if your player base is enormous But you make more money with a crappier game.
Speaker 0: you make steady money And if your game is good enough you get what netrunner had which is a big community that stays Invested.
Speaker 0: the thing is FFG.
Speaker 0: The reason netrunner even waned at all Throughout its life is simply because FFG not producing enough cards not being active enough in the you know The competitive community managing turn being active in the competitive community probably cost more than producing the cards.
Speaker 1: Maybe shocking how it's like.
Speaker 0: Basically, right, but it's basically like they didn't even put effort into like putting it.
Speaker 0: You know updating ban lists quickly or communicating with people or letting us know when things are happening or it's like, you know I feel like if you did had this model and you just managed it and actually had someone.
Speaker 0: You know, there are people whose only job was netrunner and they would communicate Extremely rarely wouldn't answer questions.
Speaker 0: It's like this isn't the biggest game You know, we got magic and you got Pokemon are bigger.
Speaker 0: At least you get was probably bigger, right?
Speaker 0: It's like you should be really really active in working with your you know players.
Speaker 1: I would suspect if this my if this business model can actually work in the long run Tying it to it to a mass-market IP as opposed to a core market IP is felt like Game of Thrones Is probably a much better.
Speaker 0: I have a Game of Thrones card game.
Speaker 0: It never did.
Speaker 0: as well as netrunner I know and I wonder why it's not as good as a game.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but at the same time Certain mass-market IP.
Speaker 1: you don't need to make that good of a game to make money with it.
Speaker 0: I mean, I'm sure I'm sure they make money on the Game of Thrones game.
Speaker 0: It used it before netrunner came.
Speaker 0: that was their biggest card game.
Speaker 0: The fantasy flight makes most of their money on x-wing because this is the biggest profit margins.
Speaker 0: but I sell a piece of plastic for like 30 bucks or so.
Speaker 1: get the eSports model.
Speaker 1: a game like this the community Tournament structure and the semi professional and the professional and the competitive community has to be supported But also has to itself be a primary driver of revenue or there just won't be enough money to justify all the effort to do Something like this.
Speaker 0: I'm telling you make a digital digital card game where you pay a subscription fee And you have all the cards and then you have tournaments online with entry fees and real prizes and then every prizes.
Speaker 1: So what you do?
Speaker 1: every?
Speaker 0: you go to city just like Mario Tennis has those tournaments, right?
Speaker 0: You sit down you say I want to play a tournament.
Speaker 0: Boom You pay the entry fee you're in you play then you get a prize at place that rules like in this tournament.
Speaker 1: These are the rules for decks in this season.
Speaker 1: These are the rules for decks.
Speaker 0: if you could change the rules every goddamn day the restricted list changes.
Speaker 0: You don't have to worry about cheating, you know, there's so many things that are solved.
Speaker 0: You know made a miracle by having a digital card game.
Speaker 0: You never made digital netrunner because the community did it, right?
Speaker 0: It's like the community did a real shitty job.
Speaker 0: I refused to play because it was so shitty.
Speaker 0: even the second version that came out with which is jinteki.net So shitty I refused to do it.
Speaker 1: I think the other thing that really hurts games like this is that if they're physical The vast majority of players will not have other players in their area.
Speaker 0: That's what I'm saying.
Speaker 1: digital Yeah, but that's a very different game.
Speaker 1: at that point It's a very different business model.
Speaker 1: It's a very different company that has to be involved you both at the same time.
Speaker 1: I wouldn't bother with a physical to be honest digital only.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm I mean it depends, you know, sometimes, you know the in the digital game you can do stuff You can't do in the physical game right exactly like Hearthstone does.
Speaker 1: but then the in-person tournaments are tablet-based.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean this one.
Speaker 1: Yeah but anyway things of the day.
Speaker 1: I love nonsense like this, but this is just Wall because Waluigi's been in the news lately because he's not in smash which I think is a girl.
Speaker 0: that is that is What is that?
Speaker 0: He's an assist trophy?
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm not feeling that.
Speaker 1: I want Waluigi.
Speaker 1: I want like a Waluigi Protagonist main character.
Speaker 0: You can already be Kid Koopa.
Speaker 0: You're your boy.
Speaker 0: Why do you want to be anyone else?
Speaker 1: Cuz I really like Waluigi as a character.
Speaker 1: Uh-huh.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: There's something about Waluigi.
Speaker 0: Anyway, this I play Luigi in Mario Tennis.
Speaker 1: then this is the waka Pella chorus singing for the longest Waluigi time.
Speaker 0: I don't think they're that good.
Speaker 1: I think it's okay.
Speaker 1: I think it's pretty good.
Speaker 1: it does as the it has the appropriate amount of true Waluigi because To be fair a little bit of Waluigi goes a long way and distilled Waluigi is actually toxic to humans.
Speaker 0: That's what if you had the actual voice actor of Waluigi, which is the same guy who does the Mario voice?
Speaker 0: What's his name?
Speaker 1: I don't actually know.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it does like.
Speaker 0: if you had the actual Waluigi voice doing this then it would work.
Speaker 0: But it's like because you can.
Speaker 0: it's not a good enough Waluigi impersonation.
Speaker 0: It falls flat for me.
Speaker 0: It's pretty good though.
Speaker 0: It ends up sounding like other people, you know, cuz it strays too far.
Speaker 0: So you gotta think of the day?
Speaker 0: I do so.
Speaker 0: here's this awesome dude who plays guitar You know, he likes to play metal songs and he's got a guitar pedal which you know There's like 10 bajillion guitar pedals in the world that are all funky and weird ways and people mostly just use normal ones.
Speaker 0: Yeah But anyway, this guitar pedal is one of the coolest I have seen.
Speaker 0: what it does is it turns your guitar into?
Speaker 0: Hatsune Miku, it's pretty crazy.
Speaker 0: It is pretty good You just you play guitar, but what hatsune Miku singing comes out and you don't hear any guitar.
Speaker 0: That's I don't even know how the hell they did that because you get to control not only the notes But also the word she's saying.
Speaker 0: I'm sure the video explains it.
Speaker 0: I only watch enough of the video to see it working.
Speaker 0: I didn't watch the whole video because it's too long.
Speaker 1: Yep So in the minute moment the book club book is Emily Wilson translation of the Odyssey by Homa.
Speaker 1: We're gonna be at PAX West is our next big convention.
Speaker 1: I hope we'll see you there.
Speaker 1: Pax unplugged.
Speaker 1: badges are still on sale.
Speaker 1: You should go to PAX unplugged.
Speaker 0: I don't know why badges are on sale.
Speaker 0: Why didn't you buy it?
Speaker 0: You know, we you're wasting your time watching our stupid listen to our stupid podcast.
Speaker 0: Shouldn't you be spending your time?
Speaker 0: Unplugged.
Speaker 0: With all I know no one wants to go to Philadelphia, but this is the one time it's okay.
Speaker 1: Also, it's pretty cheap to go to PAX unplugged.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm, and it's all full packs.
Speaker 1: Like there's a main theater.
Speaker 1: There's panel rooms.
Speaker 1: It's just all tabletop, which that's all I really want out of packs.
Speaker 1: Anyway, yeah, I Do like playing.
Speaker 1: I sometimes like going into like the PC area and playing a little bit of Counter-Strike, but mostly on tabletop at PAX's.
Speaker 1: so Cockroach poker.
Speaker 0: so at speaking of packs We were at PAX East and I was working in tabletop walking around looking at what games Looking around and I saw some people playing this game and the game looked mad fun.
Speaker 0: And I said what the hell game is that?
Speaker 0: and they said it's cockroach poker.
Speaker 0: They explained it to me a little bit.
Speaker 0: So then the next day we're hanging out playing some games and I'm like I can go to library and see if they got cockroach poker cock poker And see if it's there.
Speaker 0: and it was not there.
Speaker 0: So the other day I was reminded of it.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah that game so went on Amazon and I searched for cockroach poker, you know The South American jungle website and I saw two different ones.
Speaker 0: So I said, oh no, should I get the original one or this upgraded looking lock-in locker or cocker lock-in poker?
Speaker 0: Royale, right.
Speaker 0: so I go on board game geek and people are commenting like yeah There's actually a reason to own both of these and you know, there's don't just buy, you know, buying two is not redundant.
Speaker 0: It's not one of those situations like yeah you buy carcass own and then you buy carcass own with an expansion, right?
Speaker 0: It's like no, it's actually is different right?
Speaker 0: So I said well, they're cheap and tiny perfect for kind of game for me.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'll buy both.
Speaker 0: So I bought both and yesterday we played both.
Speaker 1: They're pretty good.
Speaker 1: So designed by actually designer.
Speaker 1: I'd never heard of Jacques Zimette from Luxembourg Other games, but I don't think I've played any of them.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm Bambaleo bad bunnies Defecent seven.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: I've played any of these so you check them out.
Speaker 0: But anyway, so here's the deal.
Speaker 1: These are this one has the best name Ella fantastico So cockroach elephant.
Speaker 0: so cockroach poker has a lot to do with cockroaches not a lot to do with poker It's a bluffing game.
Speaker 0: So basically way works is you put a card out there, right and you don't tell anyone what the hell it is.
Speaker 0: You deal out the whole deck, you know.
Speaker 0: any first player puts a card out there and you aim the card at a specific Opponent, so maybe I aim it at rim.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and it's phased down and I say rim.
Speaker 0: This card is a cockroach.
Speaker 1: So I have two choices.
Speaker 0: right now There's eight different freaking animals in the deck.
Speaker 1: this cockroach rat, you know, so I have a choice now.
Speaker 1: I can either Accept the card or refuse the card.
Speaker 1: But then before once I decide that I have to say if I agree with what Scott said It is or I disagree, right?
Speaker 0: So basically your choices are pass the card along and try to it's like.
Speaker 0: I don't know if you're bluffing or not.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna try instead in To bluff someone else, right?
Speaker 0: So if you bluff someone else you look at the card now You know what it is and then you try to give it to someone else and you do the same thing again.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if you think you know, like I know Scott's lying or I know Scott's not lying It doesn't matter which it is is if you are certain Or relatively certain that you know what the other person is as lied or not.
Speaker 0: If you know what that card is without looking at it you call them out and if you are correct They take the card and if you're wrong you take the car.
Speaker 1: I might say Scott I accept this card and I believe I agree that it is a stink bug and I flip it over.
Speaker 1: if it is a stink Bug Scott has to take it back and it goes in front of him and if rim thought so in that case rim thought I was not lying.
Speaker 0: He thought I you know was telling the truth and you were.
Speaker 0: if I was so yeah.
Speaker 0: And then if I was lying though, he would have to take the card.
Speaker 0: Yep and basically the best part about this game is you just keep doing this over and over until One person has four bugs of the or four creatures of the same type in front of them
Speaker 1: or one player runs out of cards in their
Speaker 0: or someone runs out of cards and the way you run into cards is because if You take a card in front of you you start the next turn.
Speaker 0: So if you just keep bluffing wrong or getting burned even if you're.
Speaker 0: you know All your creatures don't match up into a set of four.
Speaker 0: You are playing more cards from your hand than other people and you because you're getting you're on the wrong end of the bluff too Much.
Speaker 0: you're getting figured out.
Speaker 0: So that's that's just regular cock poker.
Speaker 0: The interesting parts of the game is that you start off and you don't really have much to go on except for reading people Psychologically and you see your hand of cards.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I see seven stink bugs.
Speaker 0: Yeah It's just eight of eight different creatures for six.
Speaker 0: I think it's a 64 card deck, right?
Speaker 1: I think so.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there's nothing special.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's just like eight different creatures and there's eight of each.
Speaker 0: and that's it.
Speaker 0: So you can count everything but as the game goes on there's more and more face up.
Speaker 0: So like you see seven bats and so and you got three bats in front of you and someone pushes a card at you and says It's a bat.
Speaker 0: Is that the eighth bat?
Speaker 1: yeah It's a better low But so it's a little bit of a not a card counting game because all the information you could have is visible.
Speaker 1: Yep, either in your hand or laying in front of people and it's a bluffing game But it's not the like.
Speaker 1: try to.
Speaker 0: it's not like Sheriff Nottingham We're like, it's more like Liar's Dice is the sheriff of not without the luck.
Speaker 1: telling The truth is safe and lying is risky in this game.
Speaker 1: It's always risky.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you're trying to get the other person to second-guess so it's one.
Speaker 0: very doesn't matter whether you're lying or telling the truth.
Speaker 0: If you pass a card at someone it could come back to you either way.
Speaker 0: You just need to Say a thing and push the card in such a way that they will get it wrong or take the risk on to themselves And push it on.
Speaker 0: just push the car.
Speaker 1: So the real decision is who do you target?
Speaker 1: because they might then?
Speaker 0: Retargeted the card might hit everybody right when there's only one person left to be targeted.
Speaker 0: They can't retarget it because everyone knows what it is.
Speaker 0: They have to decide bluff, you know true or not.
Speaker 1: The best part about this game is that Scott will pass me a card.
Speaker 1: He'll be like it's a cockroach and I'll be like I do not accept this card and I look at it And it doesn't matter what it is and I'll pass it to someone else and say it's a stink bug.
Speaker 1: I Saw one card get every day got past the maximum number of times and everyone said it was something different.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: I love that aspect of the game.
Speaker 0: It's like what the hell is that the final person is supposed to think about this card.
Speaker 0: Yep, right.
Speaker 1: It's not the most in-depth game.
Speaker 1: It's definitely just a bluffing game.
Speaker 0: Yeah It's not you.
Speaker 0: if you there's no way you can Analysis paralysis or anything because it's like you don't have a lot to go on.
Speaker 1: it's like BS or liars dice.
Speaker 1: Like it's that liars dice.
Speaker 0: I think it's liars ice without the luck part.
Speaker 0: Yeah Cuz liars dice you literally roll the dice and could get lucky and get like a whole shit ton of ones in there.
Speaker 0: You can't get lucky and like strategically.
Speaker 1: The game is pretty random unless people have really obvious tells or very bad at bluffing Yep, and it ends up being a little bit of a watch.
Speaker 0: I couldn't figure out any great hero sticks for achieving victory.
Speaker 1: I had a shockingly effective heuristic and someone's gonna lie.
Speaker 0: if you're just reading people though It's just really.
Speaker 1: but it worked a hundred percent of the time until I explained it and my heuristic was I'll tell all of you It only worked if a card got passed to someone else first before it came to me.
Speaker 1: Whenever someone looked at a card and then gave it pushed it to me.
Speaker 1: if they looked at it for more than four seconds I assume they were lying.
Speaker 1: and if they looked at it for less than four seconds I assume they were telling the truth and in my experience playing this game twice that was 100% reliable.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: So this cockroach poker Royale, which is not the same game.
Speaker 0: It's not an expansion I believe you mean cocker lock in poker Royale, right?
Speaker 0: It is a upgraded and tweaked version of the original game.
Speaker 0: So it's mostly the same except they got rid of a few bugs which caught but gave me a problem because Scott lied and said this I spider.
Speaker 0: I passed a card to someone.
Speaker 0: I said spider and spider was not in the royal version.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it was like oops.
Speaker 0: But basically they cut out some animals.
Speaker 0: they put in a crown version.
Speaker 0: So there's one rat King one cockroach King one, you know, it's that one scorpion Count as like the animal of the type, right?
Speaker 0: But they also.
Speaker 0: you can now say royal instead of saying cockroach or stink bug and that means it's an.
Speaker 0: I'm not telling you What kind of animal it is, but I'm telling you it has a crown and it's just the same as otherwise.
Speaker 0: But if you take if you end up taking a crown in front of you, however, it gets there.
Speaker 0: There's a penalty pile so you actually can end up getting more cards.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if you so it's like you kind of want to pass the crowns and make people take them, right?
Speaker 0: But if you take if you take a crown got a royal rat from your hand and try to pass it off You could immediately have that in front of you if you'd the other person calls you and gets it, right?
Speaker 1: so the royale version basically adds a swingier Higher risk situation to the game.
Speaker 0: It also has these two special cards.
Speaker 0: Yep That are basically sort of like foils that you can sort of confuse people with like this one.
Speaker 0: That's always false no matter what you say.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and there's.
Speaker 0: and there's one that is always Is always it's always true royal Right.
Speaker 0: So if you say royal it's always wrong, but you say anything else and it's right.
Speaker 1: But the mechanics with these cards are if you get caught with it Like if you're if you take it and you're wrong about it you take it into your hand.
Speaker 1: You got to play the thing you were wrong about in front of you if you have it.
Speaker 1: if you don't have it Daddy to in front of you.
Speaker 0: Yeah So you basically there's just a whole bunch of cards that let you hurt people more but could end up hurting you more.
Speaker 0: because like Anytime you pass a card to someone in this game It's like you just want that person to pass the card along.
Speaker 0: You don't want them to guess because if they guess It's like they got it.
Speaker 0: You got a 50/50 shot of that card coming right back in your face.
Speaker 1: So the game is highly social like it's very easy to just sort of interact and hang out and play at the table.
Speaker 0: It's easy to learn.
Speaker 0: It doesn't take long.
Speaker 0: Yep, you can play with two to six people, but I wouldn't recommend two.
Speaker 0: I think three to three to six is where it's quick to play.
Speaker 1: the game goes on for a little while because there's like.
Speaker 0: I think it went on for a little while because you had four players.
Speaker 0: So there's more cards in your hand.
Speaker 0: I think if you had six players, it might go.
Speaker 0: well It might go.
Speaker 0: I'm not sure if we go longer or shorter Because on the one hand to be harder for somebody to get four of the one thing in front of them when they spread out More.
Speaker 0: but on the other hand someone could run out of cards in the hand real fast.
Speaker 0: So they keep getting targeted Yep.
Speaker 0: And it's keep targeting that person who's only got a few cards in the hand.
Speaker 1: once someone's got three rats Like everyone just starts throwing like hey, here's a rat you could actually.
Speaker 0: so we could actually for example conspire Right.
Speaker 0: Let's say I start the game and sitting to my you know, I got Emily and and Chris next to me and I say Hey, let's make rim lose.
Speaker 0: So basically we could set up a thing where I always passed.
Speaker 0: Oh, no, we couldn't because as soon as you took a card you would start Yep, but we can set up a thing to where whenever whenever possible.
Speaker 0: So basically three fourths of the time the politics of where you direct a car.
Speaker 0: We always make rim the let we always don't accept the cards and always pass it to rim last Basically forced to agree or disagree.
Speaker 1: you don't want to be involved.
Speaker 1: Yes, like really you just do not want cards to ever come in front of you.
Speaker 0: It is really no benefit to actually like playing.
Speaker 0: your best bet is to sit there and do nothing.
Speaker 0: Yeah, cuz there's only one loser.
Speaker 0: It's not like one person wins is one loser and everyone else wins equally.
Speaker 0: So just don't be that loser this.
Speaker 1: so I recommend this game either either.
Speaker 0: It is possible if you're not the first player in the game.
Speaker 0: It is possible for you to sit there and do nothing the entire game and then win.
Speaker 1: I would recommend either of both of these games to anyone who goes to conventions and you need games to like get to the table While you're waiting for everyone to show up or like in between two serious games bust this out.
Speaker 1: This is also a great game to bust out while you're eating dinner or something at a con.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't know if you should buy.
Speaker 0: whether you buy the royal one or the regular one.
Speaker 0: It's like the royal one does add some complexity.
Speaker 0: role one.
Speaker 0: in my it wasn't Necessarily more fun than the regular one.
Speaker 0: The regular one was just sort of so polished and pure.
Speaker 0: So I don't really see them like.
Speaker 0: one is better than the other.
Speaker 0: they seem kind of equal but slightly different.
Speaker 1: I would say.
Speaker 1: the royal one is swingier more random and there's higher risk in any given hand.
Speaker 1: That's the only difference between the two.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like I'm not like if you I'm sitting there and I'm about to play and I have to pick one of the two I guess like a coin toss, right and it depends in the group I think.
Speaker 0: definitely though there is an advantage of.
Speaker 0: if you have people haven't played it before you probably mean Right.
Speaker 0: if they're intelligent gamers you could just go straight to the royal one No problem, but the regular one is not a baby mode.
Speaker 0: So it definitely helps to play the regular one first and then play the royal one.
Speaker 0: It'll be a much easier Transition.
Speaker 1: I would also say though that this is an excellent game to bust out for non gamer Friends or for a family.
Speaker 0: also great for you could probably play this.
Speaker 0: a very young people I imagine probably like I don't know ten-year-olds could play.
Speaker 1: I think I think six to ten-year-olds could play.
Speaker 1: six-year-olds would play randomly and have problems But I think they could do it below.
Speaker 1: that would still be trouble.
Speaker 0: but young kids can play this game I'm not sure, you know, but you could.
Speaker 0: there's definitely a very young.
Speaker 0: I'm not sure.
Speaker 0: What does it say on the box for age?
Speaker 1: It says let's see Two to six players ages eight and up.
Speaker 1: community says six and up.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean you can.
Speaker 0: you can definitely the especially the non-royal one.
Speaker 0: You can play with young people cuz like.
Speaker 0: You know, how are they gonna mess the game up right?
Speaker 0: You know, it's it's not hard.
Speaker 1: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Speaker 0: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 1: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays and my comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 0: But unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night and the patreon patreons with this episode of geek nights are Craig Allen Joyce Rebecca done.
Speaker 1: How do you mean Nicholas?
Speaker 1: You're gonna be out last hanging in the skies cuz shower topish in my state.
Speaker 1: I'm Jeremy minor link He G Roberto Kingsley Kelly Snyder cold guy Amanda Duchette Shawn Yeager Matthew Smith Nicholas Brando mr.
Speaker 1: Strong stretchy for two in creations.
Speaker 1: No, I never ever want to wear her separately.
Speaker 1: bitch tripping but horrible.
Speaker 1: Rory James David Wright white Rachelle Mountain known as Superboy tripwire sailor Vista dodge like Jojo Jo star Clinton Walton Ren from New Zealand Ryan parent or open-liner Finn Chris Midgiff Daniel Redmond Shawn Klein Chris Reimer and Thomas.
Speaker 1: on here's some Waluigi I And it's more than I hoped for.