Speaker 0: It's Tuesday April 24th 2018.
Speaker 0: I'm rim I'm Scott and this is geek nights.
Speaker 0: We are back from PAX East with a Tuesday episode talking about quantitative easing the game and Yogi the game.
Speaker 0: Let's do this So with all the games that we're playing right now or that we want to be playing because it's really gaming season hard lately.
Speaker 0: PC gaming always gaming season, but it's exploding even more And I think it's partly just that.
Speaker 0: a bunch of games that I am specifically interested in are all available at the same time.
Speaker 1: I mean, it's not just games.
Speaker 1: It's all media.
Speaker 1: This has been a problem since geek night started it that the rate of media creation has gone up so high.
Speaker 1: Even though you like all these things you do not have time to consume even a small fraction of all the.
Speaker 0: there were droughts in anime where I like.
Speaker 0: there wasn't a lot of anime I care to watch and There's a ton again because now over the past say like two three years the problem has gotten even worse.
Speaker 0: yep, but PC gaming is having it to a degree that I can't deal with.
Speaker 0: I Haven't even played like slay the spire enough to where I'm done with it.
Speaker 1: I do the daily thing every day.
Speaker 0: I do too that games real good.
Speaker 0: But I completely forgot that that battle tech game the one that is literally just the pen and paper and dice game actual battle time PC is Coming out one like today.
Speaker 1: I think I think is out now.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I Completely forgot about it to the point that I don't even remember if I kick-started it.
Speaker 1: I don't think I did but I think well I saw it at a PAX booth and then a kick-started it and I saw it Again at a PAX booth and then I had faith in it and then I said, okay And then why are they?
Speaker 1: even though I had already paid for it.
Speaker 1: I got faith in it afterwards.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: I know I read I Exactly one review from someone I trusted who said and I quote it's just regular old battle tech That's it.
Speaker 1: Well, I said I think it was gonna be.
Speaker 0: that's all I wanted.
Speaker 0: That's all I've wanted for like 20 years.
Speaker 1: It's like playing the new xcom game.
Speaker 0: only Max, yeah But it's the mech logic and the mech mechanics that I know and love and don't have time to bust out fucking mech maker and make a mech for three hours and then Fill in a bunch of dogs.
Speaker 1: It takes three hours to make a man You can just print out pre-made mechs.
Speaker 0: We never did that.
Speaker 0: We always spent forever making our goddamn like Team of us 80-ton and a 60-ton and all our nonsense and we'd all have to look through the books.
Speaker 0: I remember how whatever worked Mmm, everyone wanted a targeting computer.
Speaker 0: So we banned it.
Speaker 1: Everyone bans targeting computers plus two on everything.
Speaker 0: Yep We also I remember specifically We only looked at tonnage and we never looked at money because it was just too much of a pain in the ass to keep Track of money.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm, which is kind of a problem because you could just make the most expensive back anyway.
Speaker 0: Despite all this What did I spend all last night doing?
Speaker 0: Getting a regional doom - like actual original code in DOS box Playable on my PC.
Speaker 0: Yes, you get the steam doom - it is but it's the steam doom - is one of the first things I ever bought on Steam.
Speaker 1: Yeah, me too.
Speaker 0: Okay, and it is just DOS box Yeah, meaning I had to like configure the controls.
Speaker 1: No, you when you install the steam doom - it I mean yeah sets up some DOS box.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but what you do is you just go to the directory where it's at Yeah, and you notice in that directory.
Speaker 1: There are some precious wad files.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, then you get some Z do whatever.
Speaker 1: Nope, whatever the newest hotness is.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so I've done that before.
Speaker 0: I've played doom a lot on the newest hotness.
Speaker 0: Whatever Z doom Jen all those different dooms.
Speaker 1: I felt like playing doom in its original Unadulterated purest form because you can set you can take those new ones and say play it without any mods just play doom.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's not the same.
Speaker 1: It is if you tell it.
Speaker 1: Yeah make the resolution 320 by whatever.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and don't you can use this shade, you know, just another thing I had to do is yeah I had I had this custom com file.
Speaker 0: I used to use to remove vertical mouse input while I was playing.
Speaker 0: Okay, so your guy wouldn't move forward and back when you move the mouse forward and back by accident because he can only aim left and right and I won't.
Speaker 0: I didn't fix that.
Speaker 0: I figured I'd play With even less than I had back then.
Speaker 0: the other thing I had back when I was a kid is I had modded my own Doom to add a crosshair on The screen to help my aiming.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm, and I didn't go in and like mess.
Speaker 1: with that You mean aiming and doom is pretty easy.
Speaker 1: You don't really need a crosshair.
Speaker 1: All I'm gonna say is having placed the imp in the middle of the screen.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you're gonna hit.
Speaker 0: having played doom to deathmatch with you I feel like you do not have a solid grasp on what it takes to be good at doom.
Speaker 1: I mean good enough a doom I could beat it.
Speaker 0: Could you could you be doomed to you?
Speaker 1: Why not?
Speaker 1: nowadays I just go.
Speaker 1: I just you know, my strategy is not the best But I is your strategy.
Speaker 0: the way I usually play which is slow and steady hoarding items minimum ammo usage forever Except for in certain parts.
Speaker 1: then I space Lee it's mostly that strategy But it's certain parts.
Speaker 1: I switch to the run really fast get to the exit on my god strategy.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: I Gotta say though playing doom - felt real good.
Speaker 0: And if no if there weren't other games to play I feel like I might have been satisfied with games like doom.
Speaker 1: Why not?
Speaker 0: It's also it reminded me of something of how utterly fucking fast that game is.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and Which we saw again.
Speaker 0: We were at magfest playing quake one deathmatch.
Speaker 0: Even that game is fast.
Speaker 0: Anyway, I digress.
Speaker 0: battle takes coming out.
Speaker 1: I Feel like is out.
Speaker 0: we're gonna play a ton of it and I feel like you should get on this train early Because if enough of you have this game like imminently then in the forum I think we can organize some games because frankly I don't want to play battletech single-player on a plane against humans.
Speaker 1: I don't know if the multiplayer is in there yet or not.
Speaker 0: Uh, I saw some notes about how there's Kick.
Speaker 1: we kicked it enough to the point at which I think it's was like the stretch goal was reached.
Speaker 0: Says there's a service you have to use and it links to your steam account if you have.
Speaker 1: yeah I just don't know if it's in there yet, but I haven't tried it.
Speaker 0: I will figure it out.
Speaker 1: I'll play in some battles like when I go home.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm not doing nothing else.
Speaker 0: I gotta go to work tomorrow.
Speaker 1: That's a problem.
Speaker 0: You got any news other than battle tech.
Speaker 1: I do have a news so homebrew people everywhere real excited.
Speaker 1: an exploit has been found for the Nintendo switch and all and video Tegra based Systems.
Speaker 0: I wouldn't care as much except I just want to put an emulator with every like NES and SNES game on there.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but anyway, so here's how that.
Speaker 1: here's the deal is that this is not a perfect tag You know, it's not you know, wonderful and elegant and whatever.
Speaker 1: But it can't be fixed with a firmware by Nintendo.
Speaker 1: all they can fix future switch models like but they have to.
Speaker 1: they can't fix the ones you've already got because this involves basically putting the USB port into like some debug recovery mode.
Speaker 1: so you can either open your switch and like Hit some pins or on the right side on the side of the switch where the joy con connects That's basically a USB port that the that the joy con is making contact with on the on the side of the switch.
Speaker 1: Yeah you can short out some pins on there to put the USB port in a certain like mode and Then you pump it full of data and then there's an overflow and then you can get the switch to run any code you Want which means you can just get it to run Linux or whatever the fuck and that's that.
Speaker 0: Yeah
Speaker 1: so this is good news because it means they'll probably be like some kit you can buy where like you slide something down the side of your switch and then you push some buttons and then Suddenly your switch is running, you know some home brew software thing, but then you're probably gonna be giving up on like like even though you know you can basically always do this exploit.
Speaker 1: there could be a situation where you Nintendo sends out a firmware that then sees that you have shit installed on your switch and then ruins your switch, right?
Speaker 1: So even though you could just exploit it again you I don't know if you can exploit it again if it's wrecked.
Speaker 1: So it's still something that they can ever patch.
Speaker 1: so what you can do is my strategy is I'm gonna wait basically until the switch is Rip right done no more games for switch.
Speaker 1: something else is out.
Speaker 1: That means no more firmware updates for switch, which means ah now I can totally unlock this switch No problem, right same thing right now wheeze wheeze are done, right?
Speaker 1: They even shut off the wheeze store.
Speaker 1: Yep, so we home brew is a real deal.
Speaker 1: if you got a we sitting around Homebrew that is.
Speaker 0: but unlike the Wii the Nintendo switch like the hardware is really nice and the form factor and yeah No, that's the.
Speaker 1: this is the.
Speaker 1: you know, I mean people have gotten PSPs and stuff before.
Speaker 1: but it's like, you know The switch is like.
Speaker 1: that is some nice hard portable hardware with all sorts of fancy biz.
Speaker 0: You'll be able to play the shit out of some ROMs.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like SNES ROMs Especially, you know, you can start making games for some labos or whatever.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah the labos forever.
Speaker 0: I haven't even touched a labo yet.
Speaker 1: I have a bunch of labos in my house that are.
Speaker 1: Open my labos tomorrow and stream some labo.
Speaker 0: Ooh, maybe I'll stream some doom - I got nothing to do tomorrow.
Speaker 1: So I'm gonna be streaming some battle tech and some labo.
Speaker 0: Yeah but anyway things Of the day.
Speaker 0: What do you got?
Speaker 1: Remember I think I had a thing of the day a while ago.
Speaker 1: We're like there was a cheese person like guessing it cheese like.
Speaker 1: they gave him two cheeses and then guess which one was fancy Which one was cheap and which ones they were?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I remember that video.
Speaker 1: I think that same channel also did a video that was like guess the meats and it was all these deli meats and I learned About.
Speaker 1: you know some fancy deli meats.
Speaker 1: I didn't know about.
Speaker 0: I like it fancy deli meat.
Speaker 0: Here
Speaker 1: is a video from a different channel is a BuzzFeed video where a high quality French baker of bread Reviews and judges the free bread from various crappy American restaurants like Olive Garden Red Lobster and Outback Steakhouse Without knowing which restaurants they come from or anything
Speaker 0: based on the first four seconds of this video.
Speaker 0: I feel like it's good.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so You know I'm into it.
Speaker 1: This is a good video.
Speaker 0: So if you ever wondered what would happen if you just started screaming at your hard drives The this video is pretty great Because the answer is they will have tons of problems.
Speaker 1: Are they that sensitive to vibration that even the screams will fuck them up?
Speaker 0: Yes vibration Really really impacts the performance of spinning discs.
Speaker 1: So when they started making cases of those little rubber nubs those actually mattered.
Speaker 0: that mattered a lot.
Speaker 0: Well, so it depends.
Speaker 0: there's.
Speaker 0: there's a lot of complexity here.
Speaker 0: So it partly depends on the frequencies of vibration.
Speaker 1: Did he try yelling at some that were just screwed down and some that were in rubber nubs and some that were just sitting on The table.
Speaker 0: Well, no because in this case the shouting well will affect the inside of the drive irrespective.
Speaker 1: Well, the air vibrates and the air hits the side of the hard drive.
Speaker 1: Yeah That vibrates.
Speaker 0: videos great because you see this dude literally just going up to a j-bot and just like screaming into it.
Speaker 0: How loud do you got a scream as loud as a normal human and you see these huge latency spikes?
Speaker 0: Immediately.
Speaker 1: You sure this isn't some kind of setup where?
Speaker 0: no this is a hundred percent legit.
Speaker 0: This is Sun like doing this part of a PSA kind of thing, I guess.
Speaker 0: But I can say this is true and it's kind of relevant to your son.
Speaker 1: Son is Evan and bought by Oracle a long time ago.
Speaker 0: Well son is fish works team.
Speaker 1: I thought son is dead.
Speaker 0: It's Oracle's fish works team.
Speaker 0: Well, yeah, but this is the that like Oracle This dude is well known in IT circles.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 0: Anyway, the cool thing about it is that done as a neighbor fool.
Speaker 0: Wait, that would have been great.
Speaker 0: But way back when I bought that NAS and I was talking about how there's normal net like there's drives.
Speaker 0: You can buy hard drives that say this is for a NAS and then there's more expensive drives You can buy that say this is for a professional NAS.
Speaker 0: The difference between those two?
Speaker 1: they got rubber nubs on the inside.
Speaker 1: Yeah, sort of charge you a hundred bucks for a rubber.
Speaker 0: No, the fancier ones are louder hotter use more power But they are more resistant to vibration.
Speaker 1: Are they spinning faster?
Speaker 0: Uh Depends depends on exactly.
Speaker 1: how are they avoid?
Speaker 1: How are they preventing the Do?
Speaker 1: they have like little shocks on the inside like when you bring it's usually at some sort of physical charge.
Speaker 1: You all that money for some Springs.
Speaker 0: It's not just Springs.
Speaker 0: It's a little more complex than that.
Speaker 0: Oh, they are the pneumatic shocks Hydraulic shot, but that's also why if you consumer NAS is don't really have more than five slots maybe six.
Speaker 0: because if you have more than that the Synchronous movement of the heads on all the drives and the spinning of all the drives combined will cause Vibrations that cascade with each other and cause similar effects, but just put shocks in the NAS.
Speaker 1: Each drive is bouncing and flowing individually.
Speaker 0: It's not enough.
Speaker 1: Just get good NAS of SSDs.
Speaker 1: It'd be so much smaller.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, the SSDs of course are not affected by this.
Speaker 1: I can't wait until we have like multi terabyte SSDs like eight terabyte SSD hundred dollars Cuz.
Speaker 1: then I'll have this NAS like seven of them and it'll be this tiny little box I can put in the closet where no one even knows and Wi-Fi will be so fast by then It won't even matter.
Speaker 0: I remember when a 16 megabyte flash drive was amazing and expensive and I remember when the first one like the first SSD I bought was 12 gigabytes and I paid a lot of money for that thing.
Speaker 0: in the meta moment The geek nights book club book is still Emily Wilson's modern translation of the Odyssey by Homa.
Speaker 1: I guess I'll be reading some of that this week Nothing else.
Speaker 0: I suspect you didn't read any since the last time still hanging out with Nestor.
Speaker 1: Well, I read I got a pile of reading and I read some comics and now it's all right.
Speaker 0: No, you got you got to uh, Odysseus finally.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it won't take me that long.
Speaker 1: That book goes fast.
Speaker 0: Yeah, once you once you get past now, she could just sort of it just sort of flies by And a bigger percentage of it is.
Speaker 0: he's already home.
Speaker 0: Now.
Speaker 0: what then I remembered?
Speaker 1: I thought that was just like the end part.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there's a lot going on.
Speaker 0: That's a long bit that happens there.
Speaker 0: Oh, really?
Speaker 1: I thought it was just like final chapter.
Speaker 1: He gets I don't remember.
Speaker 0: he shows up and like disguises himself and known.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I thought that was all the last chapter right and bit by bit.
Speaker 0: He's like planning his bullshit.
Speaker 1: It's not just one chapter at the end.
Speaker 0: There's more going on.
Speaker 0: Okay, it's still good.
Speaker 0: I'm really digging it If you're here because you saw us at PAX East 2018 and you're curious about that video of that panel we gave.
Speaker 0: well, guess what?
Speaker 0: It's on YouTube.
Speaker 0: link to it right here and you made a mistake.
Speaker 1: First of all, you wasted your time at precious packs time seeing the panel in person when you could have just seen it on YouTube.
Speaker 1: Second of all, you made another mistake.
Speaker 1: you went on YouTube and watch the panel when you could have been doing something better with it But you could have been playing one of those board games that are just hearing about the 40 tabletop games You must play is on YouTube from packs.
Speaker 1: I recommend playing them instead of watching this YouTube.
Speaker 1: well You got to watch the video to find out what they are or click go to the video click on a random time Look at the slide pick that game and play it.
Speaker 0: fair warning though As we said in the panel some of those games aren't that good or we don't actually matter.
Speaker 1: There's still games that you should play good or bad.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: The panel is pretty dense.
Speaker 0: Actually, if you click on any random spot in the YouTube video, you're gonna see the name of a game.
Speaker 1: That's what I'm saying.
Speaker 0: So beyond that packs West is the next big convention we're gonna be at so stay tuned After the summer and it during the summer.
Speaker 1: we just go.
Speaker 1: Ah, it's warm.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: You'll see us at packs West.
Speaker 0: You'll probably see me at packs dev with Emily.
Speaker 0: probably not.
Speaker 0: Scotty tends not to go to dev.
Speaker 1: You want to pay for it?
Speaker 0: I might get you a free badge and give me some more vacation days.
Speaker 0: if you get a free badge Oh, you come give me some vacation because I ain't getting your free hotel.
Speaker 0: It's expensive.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, right pay for that, too.
Speaker 0: But We geek nights will also be at Zenkai con.
Speaker 0: not this weekend, but is it next weekend?
Speaker 1: I think it's next.
Speaker 1: I don't know when the hell it is.
Speaker 1: I'm not going there.
Speaker 0: May 4th through 6th.
Speaker 0: I will be there for not be with.
Speaker 0: I will be there on the fifth and six.
Speaker 0: I'm doing I think three panels an anime one and two gaming ones.
Speaker 0: I think I forget what nope.
Speaker 0: two anime ones in a gaming one.
Speaker 0: I will post the schedule when I get a chance.
Speaker 0: Zenkai con is a pretty good con.
Speaker 0: I'm not you.
Speaker 0: it's not the kind of con.
Speaker 0: You should fly to Pennsylvania to attend.
Speaker 1: You should only go to this thing if you are already very close to it But if you live within like a couple hour drive of Lancaster, Pennsylvania.
Speaker 1: I guess if you're a car person, you should definitely go to Zenkai con because it's a pretty good going to.
Speaker 0: if it's convenient It's a pretty legit.
Speaker 0: It's real convenient from New York.
Speaker 0: It's like a trivial Amtrak ride that takes me right to the con.
Speaker 1: Yeah, no, okay.
Speaker 0: Well, I'm gonna be there with many of the people we had review con with and we're just going to play board games all weekend.
Speaker 1: You know, I don't need to go to Zenkai con and play board games.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well you got to go where we are to play board games.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna enjoy some good weather go biking or something not spend it inside in the summertime.
Speaker 0: It's May.
Speaker 0: it's not gonna be that great out yet.
Speaker 1: All right, I got one more thing in front of us a meta moment as I tweeted out from the geek nights Twitter account The geek nights logo website, etc.
Speaker 1: Design wise I've been fine for ten plus years, but are a bit long in the tooth Yep, so why do some rebrand and get some updating?
Speaker 0: it definitely reeks of like web 2.0 point one.
Speaker 1: Yeah We want to update that biz, you know, and we want all kinds of stuff.
Speaker 1: We want to get a new website.
Speaker 1: We want to get you know avatars and all the social media accounts graphics to use on YouTube videos that they're all look uniform.
Speaker 0: Why are you up?
Speaker 1: Graham Graham has to use on Twitch channel Game now 13 fucking years after you started the show cuz I got time now for this.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but anyway, so I tweeted on the geek nice Twitter account.
Speaker 1: Hey, if anyone knows the graphic designer right hit us up.
Speaker 1: and what happened was I got a lot of tweets from people who clearly are desperate graphic designers who searched Twitter for graphic design Saw the tweet replied to it And pretty much the people fell into a few different categories.
Speaker 1: right category Number one person who actually seems okay graphic design But clearly only ever does it for eSports customers and has an eSports style Which I guess if you want to go with an eSports Style then any of those people would work.
Speaker 0: welcome to my livestream like and subscribe, right?
Speaker 1: But I don't know if that's our visual style that goes well with geek nights to person who is clearly a you know Person who is a good person and maybe even knows who we are or is otherwise like.
Speaker 1: a person that I wanted to Choose but clearly is still not yet pro graphic designer.
Speaker 1: They're still you know The lower level maybe is still in college or something right and looked at their portfolio and it was not Super ultra pro level like I'm looking for.
Speaker 1: so I was kind of like me.
Speaker 1: Right, it's like I could just get.
Speaker 1: I have friends who are more experienced right it wasn't?
Speaker 1: they weren't talented or skilled They're all way better than me But they were.
Speaker 1: you know, it's like I'm looking for someone who's top tier, right?
Speaker 1: Like.
Speaker 1: I guess it's unfair to be comparing them to like top design agencies But that's kind of what I want if I'm gonna put in the effort, right?
Speaker 1: I want like the you know, something that will last 30 years.
Speaker 0: I guess case in point.
Speaker 0: We're gonna pay.
Speaker 1: it's not like right Obviously paying real money like thousands of dollars maybe even more who knows, right?
Speaker 1: and the third category was Desperate no talent person who's just right if someone's come?
Speaker 1: and I realized if someone's comings like Beg for grab if someone's oh, I was asking the listeners of geek nights for recommendations of graphic designers.
Speaker 1: But all of us getting was graphic designers recommending themselves.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and if you had to recommend yourself and you don't have a constant line of work It could be because you're not the best graphic designer If someone really is super ultra Pro like I'm looking for.
Speaker 1: they have work.
Speaker 0: I got a couple contacts with some good firms that do it and I got a follow-up to get a quote.
Speaker 1: So I've seen some websites that are the places where the pro graphic designers hang out.
Speaker 1: But they want to charge you a few hundred bucks to put a posting on there with your job listing.
Speaker 1: So it's like Do I want to pay that few hundred bucks to put the listing?
Speaker 1: that would probably work because I could just write the creative Brief put it up there and then you know get people from saying hey, you know with pitches and stuff and that might work But a few hundred bucks.
Speaker 0: Yeah Well divide a few hundred bucks by five and just put it on fiverr and get like 40 people to write.
Speaker 1: I don't want the fiverr level of person right?
Speaker 1: I want if I want the the dribble level of person.
Speaker 1: So we'll see how that goes.
Speaker 1: but if anyone out there knows or is a Not necessarily the highest possible s-rank a graphic designer But like a a rank right someone who has experienced talented, you know, etc.
Speaker 1: I tried to contact the people who made like to take this and penny arcade logos, but their contact form is broken Which either means they have the money or but the point is that's the tier we're looking for.
Speaker 0: They either have plenty of work and they don't notice that it's broken Or they don't have enough work and they're wondering why no one likes them anymore.
Speaker 1: But yeah, that's that.
Speaker 0: so yeah We played a bunch of games recently and we're gonna see her at PAX East.
Speaker 1: he played game.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but we're gonna review two games, which we are normally hesitant to do, but I don't follow.
Speaker 1: the games are so tiny.
Speaker 0: I don't think there's a full episode worth for each.
Speaker 1: That's.
Speaker 1: the problem is that you know There's a lot of a lot of the content.
Speaker 1: when you don't have a lot of time to consume content, right?
Speaker 1: You often have small amounts of free time and in a small amount of free time You can instead of consuming a piece of a large amount of content like say playing the first hour of Chrono Trigger And then never finishing it You just find a small piece of content.
Speaker 1: but a small piece of content like a game that takes 20 minutes Isn't something you can do a whole geek nights episode about?
Speaker 1: so so we're gonna mix them up.
Speaker 0: So QE That's what he stands for the game.
Speaker 0: Just called QE like you'll hear Tabletop nerds who found out about this game or know about it usually because the Kickstarter they'll just say QE like hey You want to play QE?
Speaker 1: What is QE?
Speaker 1: It is quantitative easing which is a word I've heard before.
Speaker 1: but what does it mean?
Speaker 1: So the gist of the game, what does quantitative easing mean if someone says that in real life?
Speaker 0: It actually means pretty much the same thing that happens in the game.
Speaker 0: Okay, so in this game You are all Sovereign nations and you're in charge of those sovereign nations sovereign banks.
Speaker 0: Okay, you can print.
Speaker 1: I'm like the chairman of the the Fed.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you can print money.
Speaker 0: cool You can just be like.
Speaker 0: you can print infinite money.
Speaker 0: This is imagine playing Monopoly where everyone has infinity dollars to spend all the time.
Speaker 1: How is this game not stupid?
Speaker 0: So this games core can see this is this is one of those like toy games.
Speaker 0: This is a very very very very simple game that Largely serves to illustrate a couple of interesting points.
Speaker 1: I'm asking these questions facetiously.
Speaker 0: I play oh, yeah and Partly just to make this experience happen.
Speaker 0: So basically you are sovereign nation.
Speaker 0: you can print unlimited money and you take turns.
Speaker 0: look as a group a series of Failing.
Speaker 0: giant companies will appear and you bid on who is going to bail them out.
Speaker 1: so whoever bids the most money is so basically there's a company going out of business say an airline and The UK and Germany in the US and Japan are all like, all right We're gonna bail out this, you know Airlines so they don't go out of business.
Speaker 1: and then everyone says how much money they're gonna spend to bail them out and the company Says oh, well that US is gonna spend the most to bail us out.
Speaker 1: We will move our airline to the US and be bailed out by them because we went to these other countries.
Speaker 1: They would give us less money.
Speaker 1: and that's that.
Speaker 0: so you just go around.
Speaker 0: one like it'll be a player's turn.
Speaker 0: No have to get into all the details that we will be able to explain all the details.
Speaker 0: There's not that much to this game.
Speaker 0: No But everyone secretly bids.
Speaker 0: one player will openly bid and that sets the lines They write on number on a piece of paper.
Speaker 0: It can literally be any number any positive It could be.
Speaker 1: it could be one.
Speaker 1: It can't be zero.
Speaker 1: It's not positive.
Speaker 1: It could be nine nine nine It could be 69 it could be 420.
Speaker 0: Kickstarter shows someone writing two billion.
Speaker 1: It could be six six six.
Speaker 1: It could be a hundred infinity.
Speaker 1: It could be any positive integer.
Speaker 1: Everyone else biggest infinity is not an integer.
Speaker 1: But you know you get the idea.
Speaker 0: everyone else bid secretly.
Speaker 0: the person who publicly bid then takes everyone secret bid Looks at them all Determines the winner based on who bid the most Gives them that card that they just bid on which is where the victory points is the end of the game and That's it.
Speaker 0: You just keep doing this.
Speaker 1: All you're doing is there's a card that is worth victory points.
Speaker 1: you bid a positive integer of money.
Speaker 1: You have infinite money on it.
Speaker 1: Whoever bids the most gets the victory points and every turn one player sees all the bids.
Speaker 0: but no one else does right.
Speaker 1: So you have some amount of information because every turn there's a one public bid and every turn you know You bid and you know whether you won or lost and you know What the public bid was.
Speaker 1: and on your turn when you're making the public bid you see all the other bids.
Speaker 1: So you get information about what other people are bidding but not all the information.
Speaker 0: I saw rounds where I wrote 50 and I was the one like running the auction and the bids I received Ranged from zero to all.
Speaker 1: right All right, you can do zero when it when you're not the public bid.
Speaker 0: No, so That's it.
Speaker 0: you just bid on these things printing Unlimited money until they've all been auctioned off, right?
Speaker 1: So the things you're bidding on are worth victory points.
Speaker 1: at the end of the game Some of them get bonus victory points.
Speaker 1: if you make sets or if they match our country It doesn't matter has a particular kind of thing.
Speaker 0: They're trying right.
Speaker 1: someone's like the airline specialist.
Speaker 1: They get more points from Airlines.
Speaker 1: Whatever the point is you bidding on things that are worth victory points.
Speaker 1: But here's the game.
Speaker 1: after all the things have been bid on.
Speaker 0: whoever has the most victory points wins Except Whoever bid the most total money is eliminated from the game before you score, right?
Speaker 1: So whoever is second place wins.
Speaker 1: Well, it's buta babel.
Speaker 1: Well, it's actually possible that you would bid the most money and not have the most victory point.
Speaker 1: that is easily possible But basically so because you got to imagine well If it was just most victory points wins you would try to bid is the highest possible number every round.
Speaker 1: Try to bid as close to infinity as you can every round To guarantee that you winning the victory points and at the end you win.
Speaker 0: So I guess the fiction here is that whoever was eliminated printed so much money that they ruined their own sovereign nation's currents.
Speaker 1: Well, you might think well, here's my strategy.
Speaker 1: I'll just bid second, you know, and every time I'm bidding on something I'll bid less than the person who's gonna bid.
Speaker 1: I'll figure out based on the info I know what the high bids gonna be and one under that good fucking luck playing played this game with smart people.
Speaker 1: Well, if you do that if you always bid like a dollar under the high bid, guess what?
Speaker 1: You won't win any victory points.
Speaker 1: Someone else with the high bid will take the victory points.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you need to make the high bid and win some victory points But you need to make those high bids in all those high bids when added up.
Speaker 1: You got to make them low right And that way you actually acquire some victory point cards with some bids.
Speaker 1: But when other people bid and acquire victory point cards that you want then to be spending more than you're spending when you're getting victory Point card, but just this concept of whoever spent the most is eliminated Then we score is so well.
Speaker 1: It prevents the game from being stupid and allows you to have this mechanic of bid whatever the hell you want because it's like Okay, I'll be whatever hell I want two billion.
Speaker 1: Oh, you just lost the game because now we're all bidding like 50 and 100.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it'll never add up to two billion ever But it ends up being really fun as a toy game like.
Speaker 0: I want to play this again, and I feel like it's something I'll bust out periodically because it doesn't take long to play at all and You can be clever like in our first playthrough.
Speaker 0: We saw such things as someone made the opening bid $1 So no one else had any measure to gauge how much to bid would be.
Speaker 1: great Is if like the person to your I forget writer like whatever, you know Like if you're the first person to bid openly and one of the bids is like ridiculously high and it's secret But you know and you give that person the winning thing and then you view that it's like they bid a billion you start bidding Like next round.
Speaker 1: you're just like a hundred million on.
Speaker 1: you could just also bid high numbers knowing you'll never have more money than that Right, but you'll totally win all these victory points Right, and if they keep going if they keep going with the number they started with like billions and billions.
Speaker 1: It's like I It's.
Speaker 0: it's cool though, like.
Speaker 0: I'm glad this game like the Kickstarter succeeded.
Speaker 0: It's it.
Speaker 0: it's such a simple toy game and I feel like if I ever give a lecture Where I need to illustrate these kinds of principles, right?
Speaker 0: This is way better than the dollar auction.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I really like these games.
Speaker 1: where?
Speaker 1: Buddha bevel was the same one.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like your tower of the gods build a tower.
Speaker 1: Whoever builds the highest tower wins, but whoever has.
Speaker 1: if your tower is too high God is offended and you lose.
Speaker 1: so it's the highest tower that does not offend God from being too tall and It's like.
Speaker 1: I really like that like oh, it's a race, but you don't want to be too fast.
Speaker 1: It's a contest, but you don't want to be too strong.
Speaker 0: Strongest within a limit instead of a rubber band or a catch-up mechanism.
Speaker 0: It's just a hard and punishing gate at the very end of the game.
Speaker 1: Yep It's like, you know, can you step on the accelerator, you know, how hard are you gonna step on it?
Speaker 1: Step on it as hard as you can but then hit the brakes and don't step on it too hard, right?
Speaker 1: It's like you got to push it down faster than the other guy like a game of chicken So that it breaks.
Speaker 0: but like that's the whole game.
Speaker 0: it's so simple.
Speaker 0: I think the only other mechanic is whoever bid the least money you get some bonus points.
Speaker 0: There's those other bonus points Once once each go-around.
Speaker 1: you want to bid zero once because you get a bonus point for bidding zero once per go-around.
Speaker 1: So like we played four players So basically on 25% of the turns I bid zero so that I can collect those bonus points.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think I won.
Speaker 0: you pretty much got it.
Speaker 1: I think I did win.
Speaker 0: Well, cuz I forgot to do that one round.
Speaker 1: I almost forgot to do it one round and then I remembered I Actually, I didn't know the rule until round two, but luckily I bid zero in round.
Speaker 0: What was also fun is people who did not want to win an auction would often just write some bullshit on their cards.
Speaker 1: I mean, yeah, we basically had a rule of if there isn't a clear number on your card, then it's a zero Yep, so I would draw like a middle finger.
Speaker 1: Yeah, or a genital talia.
Speaker 0: Yeah, those things are a lot of bids of 69.
Speaker 1: I won with some bits of 69.
Speaker 1: Yeah and 420 and some other nice bids, but it was an interesting experience.
Speaker 0: Enjoyed this experience and I would play it again as a high fun factor per second of time played and it's fast.
Speaker 1: the problem I think the only negative thing about this game is that if you're looking for optimal play, right?
Speaker 1: There will be there has to be so much you could do probably like a doctoral Mathematic thesis on optimal play in this game some game theory your PhD level stuff
Speaker 0: comes down And to
Speaker 1: actually implement that
Speaker 0: math
Speaker 1: in real time as you play this game Unless you're some sort of actual genius would be impossible.
Speaker 1: And if you did play with such a genius, it would be frustrating as hell and eliminate all the fun.
Speaker 0: Well much like Timbuktu This game would be very different if there was a player aid where you could keep track of information.
Speaker 0: Oh indeed And I would like to try playing it with that to see what happens.
Speaker 1: because Timbuktu that would eliminate the memory aspect Which would be fine, but but it might cause an analysis paralysis problem.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't think you want to.
Speaker 1: well, I don't think you have the math to like Exactly calculate your but you know, but yeah, I could use it to make some pretty intense heuristics though I think I definitely could improve Greatly, but I wouldn't bother wasting my time.
Speaker 0: Replay like exact dollar amounts, right when we replayed Timbuktu at review con without the play raid The game was very different because I could not keep all of the relevant information in my head and take my turn quickly.
Speaker 0: Nope, but with the player sheet, there's literally like the game is just like no decisions are made complete tangent.
Speaker 1: There was an article I didn't read recently But I saw the headlines and said summary that talked about some sort of people that have a condition where they basically remember almost every detail of their lives.
Speaker 1: Like I don't know how that works or if that's made up our.
Speaker 1: if true That would person would be excellent at board game.
Speaker 0: So our Scott Becker wrote a non Prince of Nothing book that is about that and what the hell it would be if you remembered Everything.
Speaker 1: but I think that said that this is like there are like 60 something people like that.
Speaker 1: I don't know if it's true or not.
Speaker 0: Well, if our Scott backers book is any indication it is a living hell.
Speaker 1: I'm sure it is not pleasant, but you'd be great at board games Especially memory ones like say Scrabble or Timbuktu.
Speaker 0: so before we get to yogi as an aside this game is in board game geek, of course cuz every games in there and The forum has forum threads in it like it does.
Speaker 0: I Forgot why I never look in the board game geek forum unless I'm looking for a rule Like a rule clarification because the first thread I saw is what are the industry tokens for?
Speaker 1: it's explaining the rules.
Speaker 1: Yes, I learned that right away.
Speaker 1: It's one of the first things I learned like literally Did you not read the rules?
Speaker 0: and then there's a bunch of questions about it?
Speaker 0: The next one what is the endgame tiebreaker, what do I do if there's a tie?
Speaker 0: we've tied in two games.
Speaker 0: and then the next post is a Quote the rule book.
Speaker 0: in the event of a draw the player with the lowest total bids is the winner.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that makes sense.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: I got a fact.
Speaker 1: that would be my first guess without the rule book.
Speaker 0: yep, and then the most fascinating thing and This one has a bunch of comments.
Speaker 0: Someone said possible variant to remove player elimination.
Speaker 1: What player elimination?
Speaker 1: Hey Player elimination.
Speaker 0: has anyone ever considered introducing a native score for the players spending the most of the end of the game rather than eliminating them from the game completely.
Speaker 0: now Two problems with this person's statement problem.
Speaker 0: The first the literal whole point the core conceit of the game.
Speaker 0: Is that elimination?
Speaker 1: Yes, also Okay, fine.
Speaker 1: Give me some matter of negative score for being the person who bids the most.
Speaker 1: guess what my strategy is As close to infinity.
Speaker 0: every single round of iron to the ninth power to the ninth power I have every single power to the.
Speaker 1: I now have every single victory point in the game.
Speaker 1: Congratulations.
Speaker 1: What negative score are you going to give me if it isn't negative infinity?
Speaker 1: I now have one more victory point than all the other players and I win.
Speaker 1: actually in that strategy Lemon if a lab you want to allow people to bid any number you must eliminate the person who bids the most for it to Have any sense whatsoever?
Speaker 1: Person does not understand math or games.
Speaker 0: I'm sorry, but I just I kept digging through the for the discussion about this game in particular.
Speaker 0: We're really sad Yeah, and they were all like that do not?
Speaker 1: oh.
Speaker 0: and also people who think they have degenerative strategies who clearly just don't really Understand the game.
Speaker 0: Maybe if maybe one of them is the PhD that I spoke of I don't know I got some ideas for not degenerate strategies But if there is a player at a table who is not particularly clever, they are a plus strategy.
Speaker 1: Well, obviously if somebody bids too high and reveals They're too high bids Then the strategy is bid as much as you can with that while bidding less than that and a big giant number.
Speaker 1: You know about yep, right?
Speaker 1: but otherwise You know if everyone's bidding sort of close to each other It's just sort of like mmm bid more on the ones that are worth more points for you.
Speaker 0: Now if you want to play this game because it was like a fancy wooden Kickstarter and I guess you could be into that if you want Why would you need a fancy wooden thing for such a simple game?
Speaker 1: You could.
Speaker 1: you don't need to buy anything to play this game.
Speaker 1: You just need some dry erase.
Speaker 1: You don't even need dry erase, but dry erase would be better.
Speaker 0: There's a play that everyone seems to play.
Speaker 1: You just need some pens some papers and you know, that's about it Pens paper.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: I this game impressed me enough to where we added it to the top the 40 games You should play panel at the last second because I wanted to tell them what other game is like this, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah bid anything go nuts.
Speaker 0: yeah offend the gods don't.
Speaker 0: So we played another really like game.
Speaker 0: that's basically tabletop twister, right?
Speaker 1: So I was walking around enforcing and when I walk around enforcing, you know I tend to try to chat people up and see what games they're playing and usually people playing a game that I know You know, it's like I'll just sort of ignore them.
Speaker 1: or maybe if it's a game I really know like teeny of it like a teeny Yeah.
Speaker 1: but when I'm mostly looking for games where a the people look like they're actually having fun and not just sitting there reading rules or Doing boring stuff right and to to game.
Speaker 1: I never seen before.
Speaker 1: so I saw some people walking around and One dude had a card like in his ear and another dude was on the card in his nose And this other gamer had like card.
Speaker 1: they were like they were there.
Speaker 1: hand like foot was up on the table And I'm like whatever this is.
Speaker 1: I got to know what this is and it did not disappoint No, so it was in like a tabletop library.
Speaker 1: It packs is a little tiny card game comes a little tin.
Speaker 0: It's called yogi.
Speaker 1: It's called yogi as in yoga as in dalsim right from Street Fighter.
Speaker 1: It is a game where basically the cards tell you what to do and it'll say for example You'll pick up a card and it'll say make sure this card is always touching your right thumb and it's like alright.
Speaker 1: from then on That card must always touch your right thumb at all times.
Speaker 1: It was never going around.
Speaker 1: if at any moment that card ceases to contact your right thumb you immediately lose.
Speaker 0: I was doing real well in our first game, but I had won.
Speaker 0: I had to have a card touching my elbow side of my elbow down on this card.
Speaker 0: Oh Turn and turn.
Speaker 0: I kept getting all these cards and all these turns and I kept this elbow on the table and then at one Point I looked down because I forgot the card was there.
Speaker 0: It's been a while and I see this card on my elbow.
Speaker 0: I'm like, what's that?
Speaker 0: I lived in my elbow up to look at it and I was eliminated.
Speaker 1: Yep So basically all you do is keep adding cards, right and as you add more cards, you have to do all these things simultaneously.
Speaker 1: It's contorted.
Speaker 1: and the thing is you even have to draw the next card without breaking any of the rules while you draw the next.
Speaker 0: now the nice thing is it comes with these little trays where you can Slide the card out just by putting friction on the top of it and pulling.
Speaker 0: Yes, but that did not help as much as you expect.
Speaker 1: It says if you are unable to draw the next card you lose.
Speaker 1: right, you know, so That's pretty much the whole game.
Speaker 1: It's twister, but it's a little bit more accessible because you could I guess play it if you Only have arms and a torso.
Speaker 1: I don't but it wasn't too much leg action that I remember.
Speaker 0: it is also Pretty inaccessible in that many of the if you have any dexterity problems whatsoever.
Speaker 1: Yes It's not super accessible, but it's better than twister.
Speaker 1: It needs a lot less space than twister.
Speaker 1: It needs a lot less equipment than twist.
Speaker 0: I hurt my neck a little bit because I had to hold doesn't it now in my ear and I was I had my neck down The entire time.
Speaker 1: it doesn't involve any sexual things like twister.
Speaker 0: Does you know you're not touching other players?
Speaker 1: Touch other people right but it's and it's a lot actually more complex.
Speaker 1: It's not just like right foot blue It's like it's actually more detailed than that.
Speaker 1: It's like ah, this must you know be touching this in such a way.
Speaker 0: I guess what it does is Unlike say Jenga is a good example.
Speaker 1: some of the cards aren't giving you like rules about touching the card.
Speaker 1: Some of them are just giving you general rules.
Speaker 1: left hand must always be below right hand, right?
Speaker 1: So now for the rest of the game your left hand has to be closer to the one I closed.
Speaker 0: cover.
Speaker 0: Never display your lower teeth.
Speaker 0: Yep That's really annoying.
Speaker 1: Yeah and if any moment you reveal someone sees your bottom teeth they call you out and you're supposed to plate.
Speaker 1: you cannot play this game with People who are jerks because the jerks will just win and make it a miserable experience.
Speaker 1: You need to play by the honor system and report yourself for violating the rules.
Speaker 1: Nobody playing this could possibly Monitor all players equally and catch them in the act of like.
Speaker 1: if I reveal my bottom teeth for a second I'm technically out but if no one saw it, it's like come on, bro, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know, you can't be doing that.
Speaker 0: So the game is good.
Speaker 0: compared to say like Jenga is the example I'm gonna use because Jenga is a game where it's an exterior game and you go until someone messes up and you play whatever.
Speaker 0: But the game has a lot of build up to the until you get to the point to where skill matters.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm this game and twister actually only round one and Yogi is comfortable and it's only slightly comfortable.
Speaker 1: like the game ends pretty quick real I guess if people are really really good yogis you could go long.
Speaker 0: even then the game Fundamentally limits.
Speaker 0: I don't think you could get past seven or eight cards.
Speaker 1: I think it may be some super super dextrous person But even then and a lot of it also it depends on what cards you get because sometimes you get cards that go well with Each other.
Speaker 1: they don't require like the same body parts to hear.
Speaker 0: and there was one like I wear glasses So I was sticking cards in my glasses to hold him next to my ear to hold him on my eye to hold him on My nose.
Speaker 0: Yeah, fill in my glasses with cards.
Speaker 1: Well some people, you know, I had a card the first time.
Speaker 1: I think I won the game or came close I don't remember but on my card sort of didn't interfere with each other.
Speaker 1: But then the second time we played like the third or fourth card It was like foiled by like the first card I had and it's like.
Speaker 1: well I can't do both these cards at the same time.
Speaker 1: I lose.
Speaker 0: So there is a skill component but it's also a little pretty significantly random because it has the problem of all dexterity games where where there's player elimination where it goes around and Generally, whoever went first is at a disadvantage because they're drawing cards earlier, right?
Speaker 1: So I might be eliminated on my fourth card and then the next person is eliminated on their fourth card And now the only player left has only done three cards and does not need to attempt a fourth card.
Speaker 1: Yeah, because everyone else is already lost.
Speaker 0: now You could probably mitigate that by modding the game a little bit like I could imagine.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you say all right If everyone fails at a fourth card then go back to three cards and try again or you max it out at six cards And then you just you'd replace any one card with your new card something like that.
Speaker 0: So you could come up with something clever.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but the game is not particularly deep.
Speaker 0: It's not particular like this.
Speaker 0: It's just fun enough and cheap enough to where I would recommend it as a party game.
Speaker 0: I would reckon I would definitely.
Speaker 1: this is one of those games.
Speaker 1: you're gonna buy it You're gonna play it with your people until you get bored of it And then you're gonna bust it out.
Speaker 1: Okay, and then it when there's new people you busted out again and ago.
Speaker 1: Oh my god, you have a super blast of time.
Speaker 0: But then I put this in my bag right next to banana grams and spot it, right?
Speaker 1: But then it runs out.
Speaker 1: I'm like spot it which can keep going.
Speaker 1: Yo runs out and it runs its course with some people after like maybe, you know half-hour Yeah, even that.
Speaker 1: and then the other problem is there aren't?
Speaker 1: it's cheap.
Speaker 1: There's not a lot of cards in that box.
Speaker 1: You're gonna sweet real played it twice.
Speaker 1: We saw repeat cards.
Speaker 1: You're gonna see all the cards and then it's boring.
Speaker 1: So maybe try to make your own yogi deck with more cars to the game's credit.
Speaker 0: The cards were pretty consistent in their general level of difficulty That is true and they were more complex and more difficult than I would have expected or would have even thought to design into a Similar game.
Speaker 1: Yes, if I had to sit there and actually think of yogi cards I would not think of ones as good as the ones in actual yogi like for exact the example We used to keep left hand above right hand.
Speaker 1: elevation wise this card is touching two hands.
Speaker 0: Yep, yep two hands touching This card covering one eye not just touching cover.
Speaker 0: right thumb always pointed down.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm Oh Man, I just really you know you go crazy with if you played this game.
Speaker 0: We have a rule you can always trade a card with anyone at any time But you have to maintain all the non traded cards rules during the entirety of the trade.
Speaker 0: This game is it's like twister just play with it.
Speaker 0: It's treated more like a toy and a party game and run with it and I think it's pretty fun.
Speaker 1: Also, you know when you're sitting around a table and a cramped packs fully clothed.
Speaker 1: It's not the easiest I think.
Speaker 1: if you played it in like an open area like a room with lots of space nice and naked Well naked or you know wearing definitely naked more comfortable and stretchy clothes We got rid of the second.
Speaker 1: if we wanted the naked part where she could play twister You're not touching anyone.
Speaker 0: you play yogi You know in more Trend and kickstart the erotic version of yogi.
Speaker 1: sure if you play more custom You know and more comfortable flexible clothing in a more open space Then that would give people the advantage of being able to get more cheating to have large numbers of Bracelets and a bandana and a baseball cap?
Speaker 0: I don't know cuz I feel like I could just wear.
Speaker 1: it's fair as long as everyone is equal access.
Speaker 1: Yet you you might.
Speaker 1: I think you might want to make a mod where you too could have bought The bracelet that I am where I think would be cool.
Speaker 1: You'd have a mod and we're before the game starts.
Speaker 1: this there's like one item per player and like what you do a draft.
Speaker 1: Yeah, one extra item and everyone drafts one item and the other items go away.
Speaker 1: So it's like I'll take the bandana you take the bracelet someone else takes the glasses or whatever.
Speaker 0: It's not bad.
Speaker 0: What do you have on knife?
Speaker 1: I have the yoga mat.
Speaker 0: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at front row crew comm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 0: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a creative commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 1: But unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 0: It's actually recorded at night and the patreon patrons for this episode of geek night.
Speaker 0: Ah Craig Oliver Alan Joyce Rebecca done.
Speaker 0: How do you mean Nicholas?
Speaker 0: You'll be obelisk hanging in the sky.
Speaker 0: my steady calm.
Speaker 0: Jeremy minor Mankiji Kelly Snyder a cold guy.
Speaker 0: Amanda Duchette Shawn Yeager Matthew Smith Nicholas brand out.
Speaker 0: Mr.
Speaker 0: Strong Strachan 421 creations.
Speaker 0: No, I never ever wonder why we're here.
Speaker 0: Semper Fi bitch shirt about horror.
Speaker 0: Lavelle James David White Rochelle, Montanona Superboy rim says something funny here.
Speaker 0: sailor vista Don Schlegs chartavish and Joe Shiro.
Speaker 0: Joe star Clinton Walton Ren from New Zealand Ryan Perrin drew open Lander Finn Chris mink.
Speaker 0: if Chris Knox Daniel Redmond Shawn Klein Chris Reimer and Thomas Hahn This is stuck in my head.
Speaker 0: So now it's stuck in your head.
Speaker 1: one, two, three four five six seven.
Speaker 1: Step the alligator king to his seven sons.
Speaker 1: I'm feeling mighty down.
Speaker 1: Whichever of you can cheer me up will get to wear my crown.
Speaker 0: His first son brought seven oyster pearls from the bottom of the China Sea.
Speaker 1: The second gave him seven statues of girls with clocks where their stomach should be.
Speaker 1: Third son gave him seven rubies from the Sheik dung of down there beneath.
Speaker 1: The king thought the rubies weren't cherries and he broke off seven of his teeth.
Speaker 1: The fourth son tried to cheer him up with seven lemon drops.
Speaker 1: the king said I'm sorry son since that Ruby episode I just haven't got the chops.
Speaker 1: the fifth stunt brought the king perfume in seven fancy silver jars.
Speaker 1: The king took a whip and it broke out in spots cuz it smell like cheap cigars.
Speaker 1: The sixth son gave him seven diamond rings to wear up on his toes.
Speaker 0: The king snagged his foot on the wall.