Speaker 1: It's Monday January 22nd 2018.
Speaker 1: I'm rim.
Speaker 1: I'm Scott and this is geek nights.
Speaker 1: tonight We're back after the longest hiatus in geek nights history to talk about Scott's crashy computer.
Speaker 1: Let's do this But I will say that I too had an error where I had a crash.
Speaker 1: you do Remember the computer not the previous one that looked like that one down there But the one that was one before that with the silver case with the door on it that we used to record geek nights on with Our door and all that nonsense.
Speaker 1: No, that was the computer that Crashed a few times while we were recording geek nights.
Speaker 1: great That was the one that had a lot of weird crash issues that I resolved by Unplugging all the USB connectors on the case.
Speaker 1: that case was a piece of shit.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: Took me a while to figure that out though Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: But yeah Welcome.
Speaker 1: there's probably some people who?
Speaker 1: Subscribed to this because they saw us at one of the many conventions we performed at recently.
Speaker 1: I'm sorry And then we just didn't do any shows and our website didn't update for a whole month because we've been going to a lot of Conventions and things.
Speaker 0: I'm not sorry.
Speaker 1: Yeah This I think this literally is the longest hiatus geek nice has ever had good because we had four consecutive weekends of travel.
Speaker 0: Can we extend this hiatus?
Speaker 1: Well, you're here and we're both hungry, but we're doing the show anyway.
Speaker 1: the problem is We have more Tuesday content.
Speaker 1: Then we could possibly get out in the rest of this year on our current schedule.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we don't have a lot of Monday content unless we do tech news roundups.
Speaker 1: Actually, we got a pretty good cue a Wednesday content.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm and Thursday.
Speaker 1: I'm sure we can make that happen.
Speaker 1: So really what is the problem now?
Speaker 0: Yes, we will bail on the Thursday episode.
Speaker 1: I got a good Thursday.
Speaker 0: Listen if you can make it to March you can do your at the annual tech news roundup of March.
Speaker 1: Oh, it's so soon.
Speaker 1: That's why I'm feeling it.
Speaker 1: I'll jump the gun.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know how you got this far.
Speaker 0: You kept bailing on Monday episodes.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I feel like we should just change the format of Monday.
Speaker 0: All right What's the format gonna be tech news roundup?
Speaker 1: No?
Speaker 0: Any I'm okay with changing the format.
Speaker 0: I'm not okay with tech news, right?
Speaker 1: How about tech opinion?
Speaker 1: like we pick some topic and we purely talk about our own personal opinions on it as it's hard to have An opinion about something as objective as a computer.
Speaker 1: What about use of technology and tech transfer and all that stuff?
Speaker 1: Like here is a technology and that has pros and cons and issues.
Speaker 1: Do we have any strong opinions about how it should be regulated or used?
Speaker 0: My opinion all the things is the same which is let's get to cyber dystopia as quickly as humanly possible.
Speaker 1: I would still be a kind of sucks.
Speaker 1: I don't want to be like eating hot dogs out of the garbage while I'm using my neural network to hack a corporation.
Speaker 0: That's who your cyber dystopia character is.
Speaker 0: That's a shame.
Speaker 1: Be a character is section 9 agent Our monkey hair, you know, my cyber dystopia character is hot elf because that is an option thanks to shadow, right?
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 0: There you go.
Speaker 0: Now you're ready for the cyber dystopia hot elf man, but I'm just hot elf in Seattle and it's not a dystopia.
Speaker 1: I'm in the elite and it's awesome.
Speaker 0: That's what it's a cyber dystopia because hot dog trash guy is still there.
Speaker 0: You're just not him.
Speaker 1: Yeah, no, I'm in Seattle.
Speaker 1: It's totally cool.
Speaker 1: I'll work on dunk Lisanne's presidential campaign or whatever.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna be tropical Aramaki with the Hawaiian shirt.
Speaker 1: So yeah, we are back if you subscribe to this because you thought we were entertaining at a convention.
Speaker 1: This is when you learn the truth.
Speaker 1: If you sigh warned you.
Speaker 1: if you saw us at magfest and you're here because you're waiting for the list of the 40 tabletop games You need to play that video is done and the list is on YouTube.
Speaker 1: But I'm not publishing it for like another week because I just published two other videos.
Speaker 1: So stay tuned.
Speaker 0: you do whatever you want.
Speaker 0: I don't give a shit.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we're uh, we're back We're doing stuff and stay tuned for a whole bunch of content cuz we're actually really wrapping up our content creation.
Speaker 1: Anyway, it's all meta after that.
Speaker 1: So you got any tech news.
Speaker 1: on this tech news Monday.
Speaker 0: It's older news, but it checks out Since we've been on hiatus so long.
Speaker 0: There's a news back in December.
Speaker 0: I wanted to talk about.
Speaker 0: we didn't have an opportunity to do so, yep, so I don't know.
Speaker 0: people know if you're not computery.
Speaker 0: people's think I'll SSH and it's used to control one computer from another computer, right?
Speaker 0: It's like I'm sitting at this computer, but I want to use that computer.
Speaker 0: that's in another room another building Another part of the world, right?
Speaker 0: I learned about it back in college when I would be in my dorm or my apartment and I want to use a computer in The lab I would connect it with these secure shell.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but this is an IT.
Speaker 1: We actually I use telnet for a lot of that because we're old but anyway, so it's a way to securely do it.
Speaker 0: There are many unsecure ways before tell
Speaker 1: that is literally just the keys you type are in the clear over the internet including your point
Speaker 0: Is secure shell is mostly a thing that works really well and is designed for Unix Linux Starnix machines also max kind of a little bit, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, and if you're on Windows It's really hard to SSH into a Windows machine.
Speaker 1: You'd have to like install some like SSH server and it's all weird and then it's got us like it's got to pass through to the bullshit.
Speaker 1: windows Come at.
Speaker 0: it doesn't work nicely Right, and then if you try to SSH from a Windows machine, that's a little easier.
Speaker 1: Well, because you download putty he would download putty.
Speaker 0: There's a program called putty.
Speaker 0: Putty that was an SSH client for Windows.
Speaker 1: So I assume your news is that we no longer need to download putty.
Speaker 0: and the thing about downloading putty Is that putty while it worked just fine?
Speaker 0: Had a lot of issues, they're really old-fashioned gooey kind of kind of annoying to use.
Speaker 0: There are a lot of people would make forks of putty like tabbed putty or a kitty was one that I used is pretty popular.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I pretty much like putty just never integrated well with any windows.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and the thing is putty is not.
Speaker 1: he had his own keys like you want to use.
Speaker 1: It's hard to trust putty.
Speaker 0: It's like everyone uses it and you could pretty sure you can trust it.
Speaker 1: But then you go to the putty website you're like, really?
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like you get putty from the shady fucking website shiark.greenend.org.uk and the most common question people ask about this is is that really the official putty site?
Speaker 0: Yes, yes it is so Thankfully is a huge huge change for anyone who uses SSH and Windows.
Speaker 0: Windows is going to come with or may already be coming with a Not just an SSH client that's built in.
Speaker 0: open SSH the real SSH client One true SSH client and server opening.
Speaker 1: it's gonna work this with the keys and all the stuff the same way.
Speaker 0: My Linux just fucking built into Windows so you can go to a Windows machine.
Speaker 0: That's brand-new your mom's Windows machine, whatever.
Speaker 0: Just open up the command line and type SSH space and connect to somewhere and be good to go No more putty death to putty rip putty.
Speaker 0: I think the Whatever your putty was made - 2018.
Speaker 1: the really interesting part about this is Why didn't this happen ten years ago?
Speaker 0: Cuz Microsoft Yeah, but they noticed that people are actually using.
Speaker 0: they finally made a somewhat good thing with that Linux on Windows Thingy that you can get.
Speaker 0: yeah, they're like, whoa If we actually do a good job of this people actually use it and stop using the sigma and garbage.
Speaker 0: The competition wasn't exactly stiff.
Speaker 1: There are two kinds of people people who have tried to use sing when and people are happy.
Speaker 1: So anyway ever try to compile something in Sigmund.
Speaker 0: I successfully compiled things in Sigmund but the point is they Realize that if they do a good job of this, it's like people actually fucking use it.
Speaker 0: So I go, okay We'll do it.
Speaker 0: It's not gonna.
Speaker 0: you know, you know, I think it's a lot of it Also has to do with the new CEO right Microsoft.
Speaker 0: Yeah new things.
Speaker 0: well also I just wouldn't have it in the Bill Gates days when it was and the or the Bald guy days if I had to guess.
Speaker 1: actually the reason I really think this is had bomber.
Speaker 1: Yeah, this is happening now is that there was a brief period where Linux on the desktop Wasn't really a viable competitor for Windows But it it almost was like it was pretty close for a lot of basic use cases.
Speaker 1: if you're a corporate user No one's playing games and you just needed like some office shit and like spreadsheets You could make a case to use like open office and Linux and that era rapidly disappeared.
Speaker 1: And I feel like Microsoft is comfortable with the fact that Windows is the only viable alternative to OS X. So as a result, they do not need to in any way worry about Linux on the desktop ever returning.
Speaker 1: If they and in fact, I'm pretty sure if a non Windows non Apple Desktop OS ever becomes viable again.
Speaker 1: It will not be Linux or even POSIX based.
Speaker 1: It'll be some totally new thing.
Speaker 1: but what is funny is that they brought this in and we're all excited about it, but and Anyone who works like crap?
Speaker 1: Oh IT help desk in a company.
Speaker 1: They did take away telnet.
Speaker 1: Hell that isn't in Windows anymore.
Speaker 0: And you might think good still get it.
Speaker 0: Can't you get it from the Go to this like Windows thing?
Speaker 0: Alright, so if you don't know I'm sure you can find a video online explaining this to you But if you go in Windows go to the area in the control panel where you can like add and remove programs and there'll be Some link on the left side that rims gonna go to it so we can find out exactly where it is.
Speaker 1: Remember any of this stuff is link on the left side.
Speaker 0: That's like add Windows features or something turn Windows features on and off.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's the ones you go to turn Windows features on and off and you'll get this Look at all this nonsense.
Speaker 0: It's an old-school dialogue.
Speaker 0: They're telling that client exactly and has all these fucking checkboxes in it Tftp.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's what I'm telling you.
Speaker 0: This is a secret thing where you can get stuff that is built into Windows software.
Speaker 0: That's just not automatically installed into Windows software.
Speaker 0: so you can go to this check this dialogue and all you gotta do is click check boxes or unclick them to add more features to Windows if you need them.
Speaker 0: if you're not a tech person you can ignore this window forever.
Speaker 0: If you are a tech person this window holds untold treasure.
Speaker 1: now You might ask but rim and Scott didn't you just say that telnet is unencrypted into your garbage?
Speaker 1: And yes, that is true.
Speaker 0: You can use tone that for other things like playing a mud or whatever.
Speaker 1: There's the you.
Speaker 1: the only reason anyone uses telnet is that play mud.
Speaker 1: you're on a shitty not anymore.
Speaker 1: Now these go to a web browser and connect to the mud through the web browser.
Speaker 1: There's some sort of like web browser.
Speaker 0: just has a JavaScript town that client in it.
Speaker 1: No, possibly Definitely.
Speaker 1: I mean if it's a modern mud.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm pretty sure modern muds Do not even bother with the telnet protocol listing on port 22 or whatever about that, but it's not 20.
Speaker 1: I forget what I actually 23 I forget.
Speaker 1: reported 22 is this is yeah.
Speaker 1: Anyway, anyway Telnet is used by Mostly like low-level IT people because they're stuck on a shitty Windows box for which if you're doing like real IT You kind of need like a Linux box to do that kind of stuff.
Speaker 1: They want to see not just if they can ping something because being usually doesn't work through modern firewalls like people block ICMP.
Speaker 1: They want to connect to a remote port and see if something comes back to prove that they can connect to it.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm, and there's really no way to do that in Windows unless you write some code or use telnet or download an application.
Speaker 1: But most of the applications that do that well cost money or on Linux.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: So in some other news You might know and this will come up in the main bit about Scott's crashing computer.
Speaker 1: But I bought my Nvidia GTX 1080 some time ago when I built my new computer Mm-hmm, and it was probably like $500.
Speaker 0: I could look I forget how much I paid probably around 500 I imagine but that's usually what an 8 an Nvidia 80 series GPU costs.
Speaker 1: And I got to tell you it was worth it because I did some benchmarking based on like rendering.
Speaker 0: Everybody knows the 1080 is godlike.
Speaker 0: You don't got it.
Speaker 0: You don't got a. you didn't make it.
Speaker 1: what you bragging about What I'm about to say is it is almost definitely better than you need.
Speaker 1: you do not need one.
Speaker 0: Yeah, 1070 is pretty real good.
Speaker 1: Yeah, 1060 is pretty fun.
Speaker 0: I've actually like.
Speaker 0: I thought 1060 is not good enough, but no actually Actually, so if you want to get like real, you know forget the actual benchmarks you see around the world.
Speaker 0: Right, if you're playing a modern video game a 1060 is gonna get you the the FPS like the 4050 FPS Maybe to make it playable.
Speaker 0: just fine.
Speaker 0: The 1070 is gonna get you that rock-solid 60 FPS v-sync that you can play it super smooth with all the settings the 1070 will also get you.
Speaker 1: if you have a high Res monitor you can run at that res.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, and 1080 is gonna get you god mode 4k screen 140 FPS.
Speaker 0: You don't need the 1080 and my
Speaker 1: current computer
Speaker 0: and going
Speaker 1: on I can play overwatch on the like fully like I've literally turned everything up to the max 100% and I can simultaneously stream that overwatch and Also encode that overwatch with a different setting as a video on my hard drive.
Speaker 1: I have also played overwatch in epic mode while rendering video out of Premiere.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: It's ridiculous You don't need it.
Speaker 1: But if I wanted to buy that 1080 today or God help me a 1070 It would cost a lot more than I paid.
Speaker 0: that makes no sense.
Speaker 0: GPUs and computer things are like cars value goes down over time.
Speaker 0: Why would the value of a GPU possibly go up?
Speaker 1: So the last time this happened to me we were in our IT and I needed more RAM desperately and there was an earthquake in Taiwan and RAM got real fucking expensive.
Speaker 0: It was rare and there wasn't a lot of variety in RAM in those days.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there was like there was almost a year where unless you had a lot of money.
Speaker 0: There's also the RDRAM debacle haha, oh RDRAM.
Speaker 1: But so Scott, why can't we buy video cards right now?
Speaker 0: There's them fucking coins.
Speaker 0: If I see anyone mining any fucking coins, yeah, I'm gonna cut you don't take your GPUs.
Speaker 0: That's all I'm gonna do.
Speaker 1: stupid aetherium.
Speaker 1: and yeah as we were talking for the show It ain't the Bitcoin bitcoins bad.
Speaker 0: See that's the thing is you might wonder.
Speaker 0: Well, wait Why is it only now that you can't buy a GPU on Newegg?
Speaker 0: bitcoins been around for years now?
Speaker 0: It's like this is why because of the way Bitcoin is GPUs don't really help you mine Bitcoin that much right?
Speaker 0: So no one gives a shit.
Speaker 0: if we don't who cares about actual real-deal Bitcoin gives a shit about GPUs?
Speaker 0: It's all these newfangled coins that are based on aetherium and those other slightly different coin algorithms.
Speaker 0: GPUs help you mine those real easy like so people are now Buying all the GPUs and so gamers who just want one 1080 just one.
Speaker 1: Does one help a nerd?
Speaker 0: go on Newegg?
Speaker 0: You can't get one or it's like a thousand dollars.
Speaker 1: All right, here we go.
Speaker 1: 1060s going for 400 this one gaming g4 GTX 1080 like a normal one.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm nine seventy nine.
Speaker 0: Good God It's some horseshit right here.
Speaker 0: the TI one $1,500 just make a lot.
Speaker 0: I mean mining these coins is only for money laundering.
Speaker 0: We just make it illegal and have death penalty and be done with it.
Speaker 1: now I want to be very clear.
Speaker 1: there is a. there is a time and a place for animate.
Speaker 1: There is a time and there's a place for blockchain like technology and distributed ledgers and all those things.
Speaker 0: There is also a time and a place for it's fine, but you don't have to have some mining aspect.
Speaker 0: Don't give the coins to someone just for burning electricity.
Speaker 0: give the coins out for someone who's so mining.
Speaker 1: There's different ways to mine coins or to extend the ledger like proof of work versus proof of stake and all these other algorithms.
Speaker 1: That's not the point.
Speaker 1: The point is that once again The real world has a pressure on a thing that is otherwise a very niche audience and as a result that niche audience is dwarfed by this completely unrelated use case.
Speaker 1: and A lot of nerds are saying why doesn't the government do something?
Speaker 1: Why doesn't nvidia do something?
Speaker 1: So I got a story for you.
Speaker 1: Scott just now like earlier today Pointed me at a link to some film on Amazon and told me to buy him three packages of this film.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, so I got this instant camera I talked about and even it's a long time ago, but finally I got a camera that shoots this Polaroid like square film.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's pretty cool.
Speaker 1: It's it's instant camera though much like Tide Pods.
Speaker 1: Do not bite the film.
Speaker 1: It'll burn you.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't know about that.
Speaker 0: No, there's there's some Recommend biting any kind of film.
Speaker 1: We talk about the film in my thing at the day.
Speaker 0: don't fight that yeah, but Amazon Oh as the best price for this film, but they only let you buy daddy three packs.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So to get around this and I so I bought three packs and then I tried to add three more to the cart and it Said no, so I checked out I got the delivery then I went to Amazon and I added three more to the cart and it said yes.
Speaker 0: But then when I actually click the checkout button it said no One step further right.
Speaker 0: so then I'm like, oh rim buy me three packs done and done.
Speaker 0: It's like, okay see Nvidia is thinking of applying the sort of one GPU limit to you know, and I think you can see why this is not effective.
Speaker 0: and the thing is I'm.
Speaker 0: I was Waiting and hoping for 1180s to come out which I guess should come soon.
Speaker 0: But there's all these all these coin.
Speaker 0: people buy them up, right?
Speaker 0: I got to get in on that initial order and make sure I get an MSRP, you know, 1180.
Speaker 1: Yep Anyway, so in some other news, this is sort of a this is like Brock.
Speaker 1: I'm bringing up all these stories that I've just seen but this has been happening off and on but it's happening with Such frequency now that Google and Apple are actually rerouting their buses to protect their employees.
Speaker 1: if you don't know in the places where Companies like Google Apple Amazon San Francisco Mountain View basically evil land, California Also known as Silicon Valley the civil infrastructure of mass transit Pretty much everywhere in America outside of New York City and parts of Boston is garbage, right?
Speaker 0: So basically it costs even more to live in Silicon Valley than it does in New York But there's no subway to take it away.
Speaker 0: No subway does know nothing.
Speaker 0: So everybody lives in these, you know far away places where they can barely afford to live and then the companies themselves Provide buses because the city can't do it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, bring their employees to work.
Speaker 1: Istanbul's like that and it's a nightmare Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: So basically the real answer is the government should fund mass transit with taxpayer dollars and also bands.
Speaker 0: they should also yeah, but I was gonna say allow tall buildings so that you can have cheaper housing or Ban people driving into cities and put transit centers in suburbs.
Speaker 0: ban cars.
Speaker 1: Yeah done Because these companies have such value in their employees and their business models They can totally afford.
Speaker 1: just build their own Transportation infrastructure.
Speaker 1: if the city's won't do it and this is a problem get your cyber dystopia.
Speaker 0: It's a corporate town.
Speaker 1: yep, so the Corp man can take the Corp bus to his Corp job and live in his Corp house and everyone else in the City is basically fucked in traffic.
Speaker 1: So people have been attacking the buses.
Speaker 0: Good job.
Speaker 1: Like I don't think that's the right solution.
Speaker 0: Why not?
Speaker 1: Why?
Speaker 1: how will that solve the problem?
Speaker 0: Maybe Google will stop providing the bus if it's dangerous?
Speaker 1: No so what Google is doing is actually they're using algorithms and doing things to Reroute the buses and randomize their paths to try to avoid these attacks.
Speaker 0: All right good It's hard to tell you're causing real suffering to the to the man.
Speaker 1: good job, but here's the problem.
Speaker 1: by providing these services They're actually making one of the problems better.
Speaker 1: They are reducing the traffic and they are providing public transport.
Speaker 1: There's providing for a certain sub Segment of the population.
Speaker 0: it should make it intolerable for them to be there.
Speaker 0: So they get their asses out, but where are they gonna go?
Speaker 1: They'll have the same problem anywhere unless they go to New York, huh?
Speaker 0: Yeah companies belong.
Speaker 0: Why don't you build the Google train?
Speaker 1: But we all have to ride on it because it's a you know A public thing the MTA all I'm saying my only point about this news because this could be a whole show on its own.
Speaker 1: I want to do a show on it, but Scott doesn't want to Because he's boring.
Speaker 0: I just say it's not a Monday show.
Speaker 1: I can't think of you a Monday show.
Speaker 0: It's not a Monday topic.
Speaker 1: I think tech transfer is a viable Monday.
Speaker 0: moral and morals Google if this was happening in Fucking Kansas City's is a non tech company.
Speaker 0: It wouldn't even be onion in the news at all.
Speaker 0: You wouldn't even hear bad.
Speaker 1: I think it would still be a Monday thing.
Speaker 1: No, I would.
Speaker 1: I would treat it as a Monday thing anyway.
Speaker 1: the fact that these attacks are escalating is something to pay attention to because the divide between people with technology jobs and Literally everyone else in America is growing faster than it's shrinking.
Speaker 0: It's already grown to near.
Speaker 1: I mean Scott and like people like us our salaries go up and up and up and anyone who doesn't have a tech job Their salaries are going down and down down.
Speaker 0: everyone who works in my company Even the not intent people I assume gets the same raises every year.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: So there is.
Speaker 1: This is not coming to a head but it's reached an escalation point and I fear it will soon reach an inflection point.
Speaker 0: good I can't wait.
Speaker 1: So, uh, it's mother news.
Speaker 0: You might have noticed that many news is he got here?
Speaker 1: I could just stop and go right into.
Speaker 0: I do.
Speaker 0: I try to skirt around it not being a tech news roundup.
Speaker 0: I just doing a bunch of news in the front One news limit.
Speaker 0: I see what you did there.
Speaker 0: All right, I'm gonna let you get away with that.
Speaker 1: All right, I'll do one more.
Speaker 1: I close my dad This one's short.
Speaker 1: I've been the slashdot tab a. So, you know how there are have been a ton of huge Ridiculous security breaches for the last few years like ruining people's lives destroying credit like mass chaos.
Speaker 1: You want to know the real reason why these keep happening?
Speaker 0: Because no one gives a shit.
Speaker 1: They well a lot of people give a shit but the only people who don't give a shit are the actual investors in these companies because studies show that the stock prices of Companies are completely unaffected by security problems full stop.
Speaker 1: Hmm, meaning there is literally no incentive to be secure Because it will not affect your bottom line in any meaningful way possibly.
Speaker 0: Hmm So we just need a law that says if you have a security breach you're out of business.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you get in Yep for the CEO and the board.
Speaker 1: But anyway things of the day.
Speaker 1: I gotta tell you it's so exciting To have had a month-long hiatus from geek nights because I got like a hundred fucking things in the day queued up.
Speaker 0: I got some things a day.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna start off easy though.
Speaker 1: Alright, so this was a good one.
Speaker 1: What you think of the day?
Speaker 0: So this is just.
Speaker 0: you know, there's a thing that you tend to do in real life without thinking too hard about it Right?
Speaker 0: is you know, you'll have some sort of object that makes a noise, right?
Speaker 0: even if it's just tapping something like a pencil or whatever and you tap a song.
Speaker 0: or you know Maybe you got like a squeaky toy.
Speaker 0: You'll squeak a song with your squeaky toy, right?
Speaker 0: You know, maybe you're throwing the ball to the dog or some share.
Speaker 0: So here's somebody who got a Rubik's Cube which makes noise when you rotate it and They played a song while they rotated the Rubik's Cube.
Speaker 0: that song is El Cantina song from El Star Wars.
Speaker 0: pretty good and To make the video actually worth watching cuz like I could play the cantina song on a Rubik's Cube.
Speaker 0: Right, I could do that.
Speaker 0: they set the Rubik's Cube up in such a way that playing the song exactly once and So precisely results in a solved cube.
Speaker 0: good job.
Speaker 1: So you've probably seen a lot of movies especially classic movies where at the end There's a something something technicolor in the credits.
Speaker 1: Yep, you probably heard the word technicolor a lot in your life Especially if you watch if you want if you watched anything from the mid 20th century Yeah, like Wizard of Oz.
Speaker 0: You've seen the words technicolor in the opening and/or closing credits if it was in color.
Speaker 1: So Scott, what is technicolor?
Speaker 0: Isn't it like a certain kind of color film that they invented with certain cameras?
Speaker 1: It was.
Speaker 1: it wasn't a color film necessarily because their color existed long before technicolor.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm It was a process to be able to film things such that you could create a particular kind of color prints That was particularly vibrates.
Speaker 1: Okay, and particularly able to portray complex tones.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: And before they had better film,
Speaker 1: uh, yeah this video goes into very interesting depth as to why technicolor was important why the Wizard of Oz was important how they did it and the History of it and it's only like 10 minutes long Mm-hmm and it'll explain the deal of why technicolor was a big deal.
Speaker 1: compared to other color Technologies mostly other color technologies kind of sucks and even to early technicolor wasn't that great either.
Speaker 1: digital camera technicolor in a sense Allowed for an early form of what we now call color grading The ability for a. basically you could take a movie and give it a particular color aesthetic that could be different from other movies.
Speaker 1: Before technicolor pretty much any movie that came out in a given year just looked the way the film.
Speaker 1: Yeah They all looked the way the best film that was available in that year looks and you really couldn't do anything with it.
Speaker 1: And Wizard of Oz was not the first movie to use technicolor not even the best movie to use technicolor.
Speaker 1: It was the first movie to use technicolor For this kind of purpose and they went all out on doubling down on using technicolor to achieve a particular color aesthetic.
Speaker 1: Also, I learned some interesting things.
Speaker 1: remember when Dorothy walks out of her sepia tone house into the Wizard of Oz.
Speaker 1: That's not the actress.
Speaker 1: They have a different active actress who's wearing sepia colored clothes and is painted sepia color.
Speaker 1: And then when she goes out of frame the real actress walks in wearing normal clothes.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: This video is really good.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 1: So anyway in the meta moment We were at PAX unplugged.
Speaker 1: We were at magfest.
Speaker 0: We were at PAX South three daddy three convention.
Speaker 1: We were also up in Albany at a New Year's party and we were all.
Speaker 1: I was in Rochester Hanging out.
Speaker 1: We did a bunch of stuff saw some hockey games.
Speaker 1: I added a bunch of videos But we're finally back.
Speaker 1: So if you saw us at magfest, we're back in New York until PAX East.
Speaker 0: whenever the hell that is.
Speaker 1: Our panel from peck south is on YouTube right now.
Speaker 1: You can watch it.
Speaker 1: So if you sat in line and then watch it at PAX, well good game.
Speaker 1: You could have just waited till now.
Speaker 0: yeah, if you see a discussion on the internet anywhere where people are arguing about a game being unbalanced or some character being Opie or Whatever it is post a link to that panel in that thread.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: That's why I made that panel for.
Speaker 0: So if at least one person does that then it'll be worth it.
Speaker 1: Also, if you saw us at pecks unplugged or you want to learn how to play Carcassonne the board game like the full We fully teach it and then we teach you how to be so good at it that no one else will ever play with You.
Speaker 1: again, that video is also on YouTube and it's already got a lot of views.
Speaker 1: I worry that we're gonna ruin the meta of bass Carcassonne.
Speaker 1: good the book club book is the Emily Wilson right Emily Wilson Translation of the Odyssey.
Speaker 0: Yep, as in I have it.
Speaker 0: I just haven't started read.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna start reading it real soon because I'm really excited about it.
Speaker 1: I've just been too busy to read lately.
Speaker 0: now that my apartments mostly clean.
Speaker 0: I think I can actually oh my god 100% of my laundry won't even fit in the drawers.
Speaker 0: I did all of it But I think I can now start being productive that you know all the things that are done.
Speaker 1: when I was in college or those Early days living in Beacon I'd go to a con or like do stuff and I'd leave the house Just in this like vague disarray and when I came home, the house was in the vague same state of disarray.
Speaker 1: somehow in my more adult life The mere act of traveling somewhere ruins my house.
Speaker 1: It's gonna be like a week to unruin it.
Speaker 1: well Cuz
Speaker 0: like I'll take my luggage and plop it on the floor and then I got buried in the laundry because I had to go To work right away,
Speaker 1: but also in the old days when I went to a con I brought like a shitty camcorder and some board games.
Speaker 1: the man I got like Tripods and all this equipment.
Speaker 0: The main thing is that when you're in college You only got to go to class for like a few hours and some days you got like Fridays off Mondays off.
Speaker 1: Also, I skipped class, right?
Speaker 0: It's like now.
Speaker 0: I got to go to work fucking eight hours a day.
Speaker 1: I can't and I can't just skip work.
Speaker 0: So like Reason the college days felt so good.
Speaker 0: We actually had free fucking time.
Speaker 1: We had a term for that.
Speaker 1: if you ever hear Scott and I like might occasionally say hey Scott Does one have one of those days?
Speaker 1: Those days were the specific days where we were at our IT and we just fucking stayed in our apartment and Sat on our couches basically didn't do anything.
Speaker 1: It was so rare even in college that we had those days.
Speaker 1: I don't think I'll ever have one of those days again the rest of my life.
Speaker 0: those particularly in that one summer summer Puerto Rico Because we were only you were like just working at DiBella's and I was only taking like two classes.
Speaker 1: I knew cuz we had the main couch that we usually sit on to like watch stuff.
Speaker 1: I knew it was one of those days.
Speaker 1: if anyone at any point sat on the loveseat Because there's no reason to sit over there.
Speaker 1: Normally there's nothing to do over there.
Speaker 1: if I sat down over there It's cuz I had fucking nothing to do.
Speaker 1: But yeah follow us on YouTube where I got a bunch more panels from magfest that I'm uploading and I'm gonna release bit by bit over the next few weeks.
Speaker 1: and uh Judge anime by its cover.
Speaker 1: We actually did the next upcoming season.
Speaker 1: We recorded it Recently and it's gonna be on YouTube.
Speaker 0: It's the current season.
Speaker 0: That's actually airing right now.
Speaker 0: We were delayed because of all those conventions.
Speaker 0: doesn't matter I'm gonna upload it.
Speaker 1: There were two or three anime that I think we're gonna watch.
Speaker 0: I knows one.
Speaker 0: I'm definitely gonna was one.
Speaker 1: I'm definitely gonna watch.
Speaker 1: So, yeah Scott's been bitching about his computer crashing.
Speaker 0: I have.
Speaker 0: So I've talked about this on the show before You know, it's sort of as the tale goes on.
Speaker 1: but and the tale is not yet over We're coming in in the middle of a story.
Speaker 0: But basically my desktop for some reason kind of unstably right something something going on with it.
Speaker 0: So at first it was just sort of like some blue screens here and there and then lots of blue screens pretty much leave the house.
Speaker 0: come home see blue screen is like well, it's not good.
Speaker 0: and The problem with those blue screens was that I couldn't figure out where the hell they came from.
Speaker 0: Ram test Checked out.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 1: Yep Now let's contrast this with when my computer doing geek nights back in the day was getting crashy Like almost the exact same situation was going on.
Speaker 1: so I did the differential diagnosis like Scott is talking about.
Speaker 1: he was doing now like first I Had an extra power supply so I swapped him just to see if that made a difference and it didn't.
Speaker 1: so then I like Ran the RAM test and it tested fine.
Speaker 1: then I even took all the RAM sticks out and booted with just like one of them and it was fine.
Speaker 1: and then I pulled The video card and ran with the motherboard video and it was fine.
Speaker 1: Like everything I did it crashed at the same rate.
Speaker 1: Nothing was the cause until one day I plugged some headphones into the USB panel on the front of the computer and A spark happened.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm and the computer immediately blue-screened.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm So I unply pulled it out.
Speaker 1: I go huh and I unplugged all the linkages between the case and the computer and then the blue screens never happened again.
Speaker 1: old shitty cases.
Speaker 1: if you have a crashy computer the first thing you want to check is those front USB panels because they're cheap and if you wiggle them even a little bit and Break them and start shortening.
Speaker 1: It's gonna crash your computer.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so I went to the windows like logs trying to look for what caused these blue screen.
Speaker 1: How the windows logs are the special breed of useless, right?
Speaker 0: So it's like all.
Speaker 0: the different blue screens had different messages like security this and kernel panic.
Speaker 0: that and this and you know They weren't descriptive at all to this day are always different.
Speaker 0: If I went to the windows logs, it would just be like yeah abnormal shut down.
Speaker 0: You shut down him without shutting down the computer just turned off and it didn't actually tell me fucking anything.
Speaker 1: I just did this.
Speaker 1: they don't understand why windows logs are so shitty Like I. like it ask a simple question.
Speaker 1: like.
Speaker 0: they have a log system that seems to work fine.
Speaker 0: It's just they don't actually log the right info.
Speaker 0: the events that get logged are usually this ridiculous I remember always like yeah, we put we sent a dump to some file.
Speaker 0: It's like no one can read that.
Speaker 1: No, even normal stuff tell me why this computer rebooted.
Speaker 1: windows is like Meanwhile Linux.
Speaker 1: if I show my mom like Linux logs she can kind of parse what happened because it says what happened.
Speaker 0: Yep Anyway, so that was unhelpful.
Speaker 0: So one thing I tried is just replacing the motherboard.
Speaker 0: I'm like, well, it's sort of fritzy and it's probably the motherboard right.
Speaker 0: that makes sense Alright, so I replaced them.
Speaker 0: It was hard to get a compatible motherboard with the CPU because the socket is old and I. but I got one and It.
Speaker 0: first it seemed a lot better but then over time no back to its bad ways.
Speaker 1: now It's interesting.
Speaker 1: how did it's always hard to tell with this kind of situation.
Speaker 1: Was it really better or was it just your perception?
Speaker 0: Yeah, well, it doesn't matter.
Speaker 1: I also were you keeping a log.
Speaker 0: there were some times I reasons.
Speaker 0: I think I don't know if at that time I reinstalled windows, but that also helped for a time and then Over eventually, but she didn't help when my computer was crashing.
Speaker 1: One thing I did is I had a pay up little notepad next to my desk.
Speaker 1: It was actually a moleskine a because I didn't really use it for anything and I logged The time and circumstance of every time the computer blue screen.
Speaker 0: when I was definitely bought me a period of time where there were no Crashes whatsoever and then they started up again, huh?
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Anyway, that's actually fascinating.
Speaker 0: So then I realized I checked and some people on the internet were saying yo if you got some weird-ass hard drives Even it like SSDs, even if they're not like crashing they might be doing weird stuff and just causing crashes.
Speaker 0: So that is true.
Speaker 1: my Lenovo laptop the x230 it crashed a few times on me like years ago and One day I was on a business trip and suddenly the computer was fine.
Speaker 1: Like it crashed.
Speaker 1: I rebooted and everything seemed fine.
Speaker 1: I could not run notepad.
Speaker 1: Every time I ran notepad it would blue screen But everything else worked fine.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: So then I went into Windows Event Viewer and it was logging like Hundreds of weird errors per second all over the place.
Speaker 1: Uh-huh.
Speaker 1: Basically the SSD Was having some weird issues and was selectively corrupting like certain calls I guess was the best I could describe.
Speaker 1: so replacing the SSD a hundred percent resolved the crashes But it manifested as if you open notepad your computer blue screens.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so my computer has a ton of drives in it and I removed this this SSD in there.
Speaker 0: That's really old.
Speaker 0: It's only like 16 gigs.
Speaker 0: Maybe yeah, it's real tiny.
Speaker 1: I got a 32 gig one.
Speaker 1: That's from.
Speaker 0: I might not be 16, but it might be 64.
Speaker 0: It's just.
Speaker 0: the point is it's a really tiny SSD, but it's still SSD and I was using it for like, you know Swapping but still an SSD.
Speaker 1: watch out because early gen SSDs are pretty shitty and they're in many cases They might actually be slower than a modern spin in this.
Speaker 0: Anyway, the point is I wasn't using it that much so I just took it.
Speaker 0: All I did was unplug it.
Speaker 0: that relieved crashing for like a few months and then the crashing came back again, huh?
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 1: Oh if it if that alone had relieved the crashing for a while I'd still think that there's a voltage problem either on that motherboard or that type of motherboard Like.
Speaker 1: maybe they wear out like some sort of voltage regulator.
Speaker 0: So my plan was like PSU.
Speaker 0: So now I'm like, well, it's 2018.
Speaker 0: This computer's in 2012, right?
Speaker 0: I did, you know, it has a 680 which in 2012 was like a 1080 now, right?
Speaker 0: I bought basically top-of-the-line shit 32 gigs of RAM in 2012.
Speaker 0: So I was sort of like hoping it would last even more than the usual five years Right, and it's.
Speaker 0: I guess it's on six years now because it's 2018 But I still was would wish it would go to 2019 for all the money I spent on it, right?
Speaker 1: Well, I mean I want to do the same with mine.
Speaker 1: My computer is from 2009.
Speaker 0: I replaced it kinda recently, but I because it's been all crashy I've been like, well, you know, I'll just wait for the 1180s and get a new computer.
Speaker 0: But well, we'd already talked to the GPU bullshit.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but now there's also the Intel bullshit.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so it's not the best time to invest heavily in a top-of-the-line CPU until that shit gets sorted.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm Which could be a long time.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but if it's gonna be a long time, you're kind of forced to buy a new computer Right.
Speaker 0: Well also the thing is is like, okay So a new CPU still has this problem and is gonna take a performance hit right?
Speaker 0: Theoretically some future CPU will be re-architected and not have the problem and get the performance back.
Speaker 0: They said they're gonna fix this and CPUs going back right - I think they said has well But like my CPU came out like really really has well, they said I forget which one it was.
Speaker 1: Well, you know what?
Speaker 1: They're not fucking fixing Nehalem.
Speaker 1: So I definitely had to upgrade that thing.
Speaker 0: I think mine is like Something bridge ivy bridge.
Speaker 0: I'm not sure what your mine is.
Speaker 0: I have to look it up again But the point is mine was Nehalem.
Speaker 0: I think mine's a three seven seven zero K. go type that in and see what it says.
Speaker 0: 377 K. three seven seven zero K. I think that's what I have.
Speaker 0: Is that what I have?
Speaker 0: I think that's what I bridge.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's what I got Right, and I don't think that one's gonna get fixed Even though that CPU is actually despite being for 2012 is Pretty great.
Speaker 0: Like it's still real fast and I won't notice, you know such a huge enormous improvement for a new CPU.
Speaker 0: There's actually a site I don't forget what the URL is and they basically group CPUs into categories and the category they group in is not necessarily like best.
Speaker 0: second best third best It's if you have a CPU in this grouping.
Speaker 0: all these other CPUs in this grouping is not really worth upgrading Unless you're gonna go to the next group and my CPU is still in the highest group with the current i7.
Speaker 0: Yep All right.
Speaker 1: Yeah, mine was a 2.66 gigahertz.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but anyway.
Speaker 0: So I was like, you know, I guess I'll buy a new computer but it's like.
Speaker 0: well It's not a great time.
Speaker 0: You know 1180s not out yet the Intel CPU thing came in a really bad time.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right and the issue is unlike me.
Speaker 1: you're having the crashing issue But performance you see mostly performance is perfectly fine.
Speaker 0: If I can make this computer work.
Speaker 0: I would not need to upgrade.
Speaker 1: That's why my decision was easier.
Speaker 1: My performance was unacceptable.
Speaker 0: Yeah plus I think what I can do is I can take the 1070 out of my HD PC which doesn't need a 1070 and I was thinking I'll go buy like a 1060 for the HD PC.
Speaker 0: now that I see the 1070 is unnecessary over there, but Can't even get a 1060 for cheap these days.
Speaker 0: Yep Anyway, so I got new problem Which is that?
Speaker 0: what I've been doing is I've been really shutting the computer all the way down when I leave the house Which has been decreasing the crashing a little bit, right?
Speaker 1: Really?
Speaker 0: Yeah instead of just leaving it on all the time.
Speaker 0: But I got a new problem, which is that if I got headphones plugged in the front port Computer works just fine.
Speaker 0: If I don't have anything plugged in the front port I basically get these near somewhat close to constant very consistent messages like oh, we see you plugged headphones And no you didn't.
Speaker 0: we see, you know, we say headphones and no you didn't.
Speaker 1: Scott if you tried Disconnecting your motherboard from the case in its entirety.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna disconnect the front port.
Speaker 1: Yeah, disconnect the front port and all the all the case USBs But I need those you know, just use the back USBs.
Speaker 0: Oh, actually, I actually have a card a PCI Express card that has more.
Speaker 1: you I'm telling you try this get Disconnect your computer from anything that's built into the case and only use things that are built into the just gonna disconnect the front port Part and see if that stops the messages.
Speaker 0: Yeah but if it doesn't I would try fully fully removing the case from the other thing that I'm gonna try if this doesn't work is Buy the power supply that I would buy for a new computer.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, cuz power supplies.
Speaker 1: It's not like a year from now There'll be a better power and put it in this computer Right and then see if that's fixes things.
Speaker 0: My new computer and move the power supply.
Speaker 1: you could just use a voltimeter and like test your power supply.
Speaker 0: I mean, yeah, but it's pain in the ass.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So, yeah, I don't know what's gonna be with this computer.
Speaker 0: if there wasn't all these problems with the CPUs and GPUs I could just buy a new computer.
Speaker 1: now actually why you could get why don't you run it entirely outside of your case?
Speaker 0: It's a pain in the ass and I have a lot of room my apartment.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, but if there just be a test Yeah, how long I got to leave it out there?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: a month or two.
Speaker 1: Yeah Keep dusting it.
Speaker 0: Sure.
Speaker 1: It's just always interesting when you run into the situation of Don't want to upgrade because you have a play you can get like we always talk about like buy the best of a thing or The cheapest thing.
Speaker 0: so I bought the best thing.
Speaker 0: usually I'll buy Computers that were one step below the best.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's value and they would last five years, but five years ago I bought a computer that was top-of-the-line kick-ass computer because the pricing was really great right then and I wanted to last more than five years and because of this crashing issue is might not make it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I've been wish I was going next time.
Speaker 0: I'm not gonna buy a top-of-the-line.
Speaker 0: I learned my lesson.
Speaker 1: I've been going on a seven to eight year cycle, but that's because I buy a Even bigger computer when I buy them.
Speaker 0: Well, this was the even bigger computer.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there's my computer now is pretty fucking nuts And I feel like it's gonna be a decade before I have to buy another one.
Speaker 0: Anyway,
Speaker 1: but the problem is with that scenario, you know The the plan of like buying at the plateau every time is that if there's a problem then you have to make a really hard decision like when we
Speaker 0: were at our IT, I mean you buy a Toyota and it crashes you buy a Ferrari and it crashes.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right.
Speaker 1: But when I was at our IT Remember I bought the my top-of-the-line computer when I came to our IT that I spent Basically all the bonds my grandparents had bought for my entire life.
Speaker 0: I spent all of them to buy a computer right if you take it for if you buy a Ferrari and it lasts you five Times as long as a $20,000 car then actually that doesn't.
Speaker 0: it's not ridiculous?
Speaker 0: Yes, well the parable of but if it lasts is just as long as a $20,000 car.
Speaker 1: It's like well fuck the old parable of a poor person spends a lot more money on boots over time than a rich person Because they buy shitty boots.
Speaker 1: Yep, because they can't afford the good boots once.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but when I came to our IT I had spent a ton of money on an Athlon K7.
Speaker 0: Oh, baby.
Speaker 0: I had me some of those 800 megahertz.
Speaker 1: I think I had some of those that were gigahertz sock or slot a And that that computer was a dream.
Speaker 1: The problem was the motherboard exploded because the capacitor issue We had.
Speaker 0: that was the era where I felt like we made too many computers.
Speaker 0: That was where we didn't get our five years worth.
Speaker 0: Yeah, because Athlons were just so shitty exploding all the time and the CPUs were always fine.
Speaker 1: It was just like the motherboards.
Speaker 0: never there were so many other so many problems with them.
Speaker 0: They made all this trouble and then as soon as we got that Pentium It was worth it.
Speaker 0: We got back on the Intel train.
Speaker 0: Everything was good to go.
Speaker 1: Per dollar They were so much faster than an equivalent Intel.
Speaker 0: Yeah in those days.
Speaker 0: Yeah, because your choice is a Pentium 4 which is like.
Speaker 1: but when it exploded the problem was I didn't have a lot of money.
Speaker 1: I needed a computer to be at our IT like I was effed without that computer.
Speaker 1: My options were to buy a new motherboard to keep using the k7 800 that I already bought or spend only a little bit more money to buy a Modern Thunderbird gigahertz motherboard, but then I had to buy a new CPU.
Speaker 1: I ended up forgetting my dad to send me enough money to buy the Thunderbird gigahertz.
Speaker 1: that extra 200 megahertz was actually a big deal And but it was a hard decision like I do.
Speaker 1: it was a very difficult choice to make mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: So you're just gonna keep you get.
Speaker 1: I guess you're.
Speaker 1: what are you gonna?
Speaker 1: Do?
Speaker 0: I'm gonna try unplug in the front port when I get home.
Speaker 0: So had time to do until now and then see where we go from there.
Speaker 1: I would I would bet that unplugging the front port and possibly also unplugging the case USBs.
Speaker 1: We'll fix it.
Speaker 0: We'll see.
Speaker 1: That's my guess.
Speaker 1: I would bet I would bet a small amount of money that that will fix it.
Speaker 1: I'll bet you a dollar.
Speaker 0: No no I'm just gonna unplug that front for it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we'll see what happens.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we're back and Starting Wednesday.
Speaker 1: We're gonna review Mary and the witch's flower because we saw it in the theater.
Speaker 1: That's why we didn't do a show actually after we got back from PAX because we wouldn't saw that instead.
Speaker 1: yeah, and Then we got regular shows as usual.
Speaker 1: stay tuned.
Speaker 1: We're back on our bullshit.
Speaker 1: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Speaker 0: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 1: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 0: geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience But unlike those other late shows it's actually recorded at night.
Speaker 1: the patreon patrons for this resumed episode of geek nights are Craig Oliver Alan Joyce Rebecca Dunn Heidi McNichol a shimmering ruby obelisk hanging in the sky.
Speaker 1: My state calm.
Speaker 1: Jeremy minor a genuine bonafide electrified six-car monorail cold guy Amanda Duchette Shawn Yeager Matthew Smith Nicholas Brando captain Chinguakasi.
Speaker 1: four to one creations.
Speaker 1: No, I never ever wonder why we're here separate five bitch Shervin von Horrell rare Laval James David White Rochelle, Monta Nona.
Speaker 1: Superboy rim says something funny here Sailor Vista Don Shleich chartavish and Joshua Joe star Sam Cordray Clinton Walton Ren from New Zealand Ryan parent drew open.
Speaker 1: Lander Finn Chris midkiff Chris Knox Daniel Redmond Sean Klein Chris Reimer and Thomas Han.
Speaker 1: if you have noticed that I haven't been saying your name and you expected me to Check and see if you perhaps checked an option that says basically I don't want the reward for this tier because Several people have checked that option over time and I'm wondering if perhaps that is not intentional.
Speaker 1: But anyway, as you could surmise we're back.
Speaker 1: We're resuming geek nights.
Speaker 1: presents you Tana.
Speaker 1: Don't worry We just had to get a bunch of other stuff out of our queue first.
Speaker 1: But I literally am doing some pre-production will probably have it up before the end of February.
Speaker 1: things are coming along.
Speaker 1: We did a judge anime.
Speaker 1: I got a bunch of panel videos.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna restart the Q&A with a much easier format and I'm gonna let pretty much everyone who's a patron Ask the questions.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna change that because I really just want $1 patrons.
Speaker 1: You don't need to give us a lot of money, but tell ya stay tuned.
Speaker 1: Everything's back.
Speaker 1: Everything's good.
Speaker 1: working on our convention.
Speaker 1: The next convention will be at will be PAX East followed by Zenk icon and then I think it's just straight from there to PAX Prime.
Speaker 1: But now I leave you with.