Speaker 1: It's Monday, March 19th, 2018.
Speaker 1: I'm Rym.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott.
Speaker 1: And this is Geek Nights Tonight.
Speaker 1: It's a tech review roundup.
Speaker 1: We're reviewing a bunch of technology.
Speaker 1: It's not a cop-out.
Speaker 1: It's kind of a cop-out.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: So it was, uh, almost warm enough to run yesterday outside.
Speaker 0: It's cold.
Speaker 1: It's chilly.
Speaker 1: I went outside.
Speaker 1: It was at The Line.
Speaker 1: If it had been even one degree colder, I would not have run outside.
Speaker 1: If it had been even one degree warmer, I would have been a lot more comfortable.
Speaker 1: Basically, I ran, like, eight miles.
Speaker 1: And the only reason I didn't run my full distance is if I got in the shade or on streets that were windy, it was too cold.
Speaker 1: But if I was in the sun and the wind was not strong, it was very pleasant.
Speaker 1: So as a result, I had to, like, I ran this weird route.
Speaker 1: Like, I looked at the map on Strava.
Speaker 1: You can see me clearly, like, nope on some streets and, like, cross the street to be in the sun.
Speaker 1: It just needs to be warm now.
Speaker 1: Even though, uh, I think we're getting yet another snowstorm.
Speaker 0: That's what I heard.
Speaker 1: Yeah, meaning maybe I'll go skiing this coming weekend.
Speaker 0: At least I bought a new boot.
Speaker 0: My boots...
Speaker 1: Oh yeah, your boots, like, the bottom fell off.
Speaker 0: It's like, you know, it's the kind where it's all rubber.
Speaker 0: And even on the top of your toes, it's rubber.
Speaker 0: And then, without even, I was walking and I heard, like, this clicking noise.
Speaker 0: I looked down.
Speaker 0: There's literally, like, cracks and giant cracks and holes in them.
Speaker 0: And I'm like, what the fuck?
Speaker 0: These are expensive.
Speaker 0: And then I remembered, oh, I bought these, like, at my previous job.
Speaker 0: When I was working, like, downtown.
Speaker 0: That's how old these are.
Speaker 0: So I got new ones on Amazon that are way cozy.
Speaker 0: Zappos that are way cozy.
Speaker 1: Yep, yep.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'm doing this thing where I'm biking.
Speaker 0: Someone convinced me to do this and I foolishly agreed.
Speaker 1: I think it's a good thing.
Speaker 1: Like, I would, it's cool and I would consider doing it, but I didn't.
Speaker 0: You would not like it.
Speaker 1: Why would I not like it?
Speaker 0: Because you are the kind of person who likes to do athletic things in a fast way.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: And in an individual freewheeling way.
Speaker 1: I do like very organized intense activity.
Speaker 1: Like, I run races and everything.
Speaker 0: I think it's sort of weird because I think what the problem is, is, like, there's all these different levels of groups, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So the group that I'm in is basically, like, a bunch of old people.
Speaker 0: We're all like doop doop doop doop doop doop doop.
Speaker 0: It's all relaxing.
Speaker 0: Some of the other people are huffing and puffing, but I'm not.
Speaker 0: I'm just like doop doop doop.
Speaker 0: And then, like, the A group, which is all, like, you know, the Lance Armstrong type dudes.
Speaker 0: I think that, like, it's like, you're faster than me because you're all trying to be athletic.
Speaker 1: But I'm not as fast as them.
Speaker 0: No, you would not, I don't know if you would be able to stay with them, right?
Speaker 0: So it's like, you know.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean, there was a time.
Speaker 0: They're all, like, whoosh and you're all like with your hybrid bike.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: The real problem is I'm aerodynamically limited by that bike.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So, yeah, a bike in ten weeks in a row and I'm only allowed to miss two times.
Speaker 0: If I miss more than two times, they kick me out.
Speaker 0: So I'm missing packs no matter what, obviously.
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 1: Meaning you can't miss anymore.
Speaker 0: Well, I can miss one more, but I can't miss any more than that.
Speaker 0: So it's like I could go to Passover with my family, but then oh no.
Speaker 0: Then I really can't.
Speaker 0: I'm having big trouble.
Speaker 0: And so I don't know about that.
Speaker 0: So, but yeah, I'm biking in the cold and even with See, this is what I don't understand.
Speaker 1: You say it was cold.
Speaker 1: That day, like if I had gone biking, it would have been shorts and like two layers on top.
Speaker 0: No, I wore, so two Saturdays in a row, I've been biking and I've worn, like, thermal pants thingies.
Speaker 0: The warmest socks.
Speaker 1: I biked to Radagast on Saturday last weekend.
Speaker 1: I didn't even wear gloves.
Speaker 0: The warmest socks I could find.
Speaker 0: and then I put in these toe warmer things that you open the packet and it's like, ah, right.
Speaker 1: And then I don't like those things.
Speaker 1: Actually, those things can be dangerous in winter sports.
Speaker 0: You follow the instructions anyway.
Speaker 0: No, no.
Speaker 1: So the reason they can be dangerous.
Speaker 0: And then I had covers that go over my shoes for the front.
Speaker 1: Oh, I've seen those things.
Speaker 0: But one of them, one of them interfered with my cleats.
Speaker 0: I only had it on one foot.
Speaker 0: I got a really crap cheapo ones at Amazon.
Speaker 0: I got to get the ones that are full boot shape.
Speaker 1: So you had a hot foot, cold foot.
Speaker 0: No, it actually, they didn't really help that much.
Speaker 0: They were sort of a bad purchase.
Speaker 0: They didn't work too well.
Speaker 1: I can see how they would work for, cause like my, I think everyone else had the full foot ones.
Speaker 0: I think those were much better.
Speaker 1: Cause my bike shoes actually are, to say that they are not insulated is an understatement.
Speaker 0: Mine are not insulated and they have big vents in them.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: It's almost like my foot is just bare in the wind.
Speaker 0: Yes, exactly.
Speaker 0: But anyway, and then I had like three layers on top and then two hats.
Speaker 1: It wasn't that cold, Scott.
Speaker 0: And then I had hand warmers and two gloves.
Speaker 1: Hand warmers?
Speaker 0: Two gloves on each hand.
Speaker 1: I don't even use hand warmers skiing.
Speaker 0: And meanwhile, my fingers were like freezing even though my hand was warm because of the hand warmers.
Speaker 1: What are you going to be like when you're 90?
Speaker 0: But then...
Speaker 1: You're just going to be like wrapped around a heat lamp?
Speaker 1: Like a lizard never moving?
Speaker 0: At lunchtime my fingers thawed, but I was still cold even when I got home.
Speaker 1: Yo Scott, on that day I biked to Radagast on a city bike without even wearing gloves.
Speaker 0: Yeah, what time?
Speaker 1: Like 10?
Speaker 0: Yeah, well I started biking at 7.
Speaker 1: Yeah, at 7 it was only 4 degrees colder.
Speaker 0: It was way cold.
Speaker 1: Maybe 5 degrees colder.
Speaker 0: Everyone was cold.
Speaker 0: It was freezing.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but were some people in your group wearing shorts?
Speaker 0: No.
Speaker 1: No?
Speaker 1: None at all?
Speaker 0: No.
Speaker 0: They're old people.
Speaker 1: Were there people in other groups wearing shorts?
Speaker 1: No.
Speaker 1: No one?
Speaker 0: Even the A people had like gone, you know because everyone there has all kinds of equipment.
Speaker 1: Yeah, yeah.
Speaker 1: I do have some heights I can wear in that kind of situation, but I usually only wear those if I'm doing like a long distance runner bike.
Speaker 0: Well we went to Scarsdale and Bank.
Speaker 1: Oh, that's a pretty good ride.
Speaker 1: So yeah, anyway, the deal with the show, we'll do the news.
Speaker 1: first, is we're going to review a bunch of technology that we've bought.
Speaker 1: A wide array of different kinds of technology.
Speaker 0: Actual electronic devices.
Speaker 1: And we're not reviewing anything about them except their technological capabilities.
Speaker 1: So before that, there is actually a bunch of news.
Speaker 1: So my news is that this made the news.
Speaker 1: For the first time, as far as anyone can tell, a self-driving car that was driving itself.
Speaker 0: So a robot with wheels.
Speaker 0: Yep, a robot with wheels.
Speaker 0: A wheeled robot.
Speaker 1: Well, no, no, no, no.
Speaker 1: Wheeled robots have killed a shit ton of people.
Speaker 0: Well, how is a self-driving car not just a wheeled robot?
Speaker 1: Because a self-driving car is a wheeled robot using public transportation infrastructure.
Speaker 0: So I took a wheeled robot from a factory and just put it out on the road.
Speaker 0: That's the same fucking thing.
Speaker 1: You can't do that though.
Speaker 1: Wheeled robots in factories.
Speaker 0: Stop me, I'll just do it.
Speaker 1: It'd be a lot like bumper cars.
Speaker 1: They just couldn't go.
Speaker 1: They actually rely on telemetry or cables to follow or QR code type signs everywhere.
Speaker 1: I have worked in places where there were those kinds of robots and they were very, very dangerous to be around.
Speaker 0: You don't say.
Speaker 1: Wow, that was a long time ago.
Speaker 1: There were some that weren't that dangerous to be around.
Speaker 1: There were these big, uh, imagine a lame talkie talkie.
Speaker 0: They just gave you a nice hug like, "Hey, how you
Speaker 0: doing?".
Speaker 1: They'd be like rolling along, puttering along, and if you're in their way, they'd stop and they'd just have this really cute voice that said, "Please move.
Speaker 1: You're blocking me.
Speaker 1: Please move.
Speaker 1: You're blocking
Speaker 1: me.".
Speaker 0: What if I just block it?
Speaker 1: They would just keep saying that forever.
Speaker 0: Move the tram car.
Speaker 0: Watch the tram car.
Speaker 1: Watch the tram car.
Speaker 1: So an autonomous passenger vehicle on a public road hit and killed a pedestrian.
Speaker 0: Was the pedestrian disobeying the light?
Speaker 1: They were crossing the street outside of a crosswalk, so they were jaywalking as far as the investigation has determined.
Speaker 1: There's a lot of things to talk about.
Speaker 1: The details of this accident are not that interesting.
Speaker 1: It's an Uber car that happened to do it.
Speaker 0: Well, those are the shittiest ones of all of them, right?
Speaker 1: I don't know what technology.
Speaker 0: That's what I've heard is that the Uber ones are the worst ones.
Speaker 0: The Google ones are way better.
Speaker 0: Actually, I heard the Apple ones are the worst.
Speaker 0: Uber is the second worst and the Google ones are the best.
Speaker 1: I don't want to get into those details, but Uber's response was to suspend all self-driving car testing across the board.
Speaker 1: Good.
Speaker 0: Fuck you, Uber.
Speaker 0: Uber's evil.
Speaker 0: Let Google do it.
Speaker 1: Irrespective of this.
Speaker 0: If a Google car and an Uber car come down the street, which one am I getting in?
Speaker 1: Which one are you vandalizing?
Speaker 0: The one that has Google Maps, right?
Speaker 1: The interesting thing is that this made the news everywhere.
Speaker 0: Of course.
Speaker 1: Self-driving car killed a person.
Speaker 0: How many people were killed by human-driven cars today?
Speaker 1: Today.
Speaker 1: Today, more than one person was killed by a human-driven car.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Not an AI, just an eye.
Speaker 0: Well, hopefully an eye.
Speaker 1: I stand by my strong belief that the current level of kind of shitty self-driving car is better than the average human driver.
Speaker 1: I'm pretty confident that is...
Speaker 0: People seem to argue against this because the limitations of the current self-driving car technology means it only works in a few scenarios and stuff like that, but it's like...
Speaker 1: In those scenarios, humans regularly kill each other.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 1: Like, in the controlled environment, slow driving in easy cities, people get hit all the fucking time.
Speaker 0: So, the main thing I brought to this point many times, and I just keep bringing it up again, is that people are gonna... They're so horrified of the self-driving car killing someone, which it did, which is gonna happen, but people are gonna, like, insist that the self-driving car be 100% safe before they let it go out on the road.
Speaker 1: I'm fine with that if we insist that human drivers have to be 100% safe.
Speaker 0: Sure, that's true, but the point is, as long as they're at least even marginally safer than a human driver, statistically, that means using them instead of humans will only save lives.
Speaker 0: Every single human you take off the road and self-driving car you put on the road is probably saving some fraction of a human life.
Speaker 0: Therefore, if they are safer, even only marginally so, which means they will still kill people, they'll just kill less people than humans, then we have a moral obligation to deploy them as much as we possibly can.
Speaker 1: With the caveat that there is a cold calculus of the cost and resources of deploying them and masks like that might take away from the resources spent on other initiatives around, like, healthcare, for example.
Speaker 0: Right, well, the resources of the whole world are deployed, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, but no, your point You can't bring the game of civilization into this one area of the car.
Speaker 1: But I'm saying there is a cold calculus there, but that, not getting into that, like, overarching and kind of pointless argument, on this low level, humans are terrible at cars, and the sheer number of humans killed by cars on a daily basis is terrifying.
Speaker 0: I want to renew my driver's license.
Speaker 0: I got the fanciest one.
Speaker 1: I got the fanciest one as well.
Speaker 1: They didn't mail it to me yet, but, uh, I got mine, like, a little while ago.
Speaker 0: Alright, the, what was required to renew the license after eight years of basically not driving was laughable.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so I didn't even have to take it.
Speaker 0: It was an eye chart that was maybe like five feet behind the person I was talking to.
Speaker 1: An eye chart that is the same everywhere, and you could have memorized.
Speaker 0: And he said, "Read the top line," and it was humongous letters.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: I read it.
Speaker 0: Look, I can- That was it.
Speaker 0: They didn't test my driving at all.
Speaker 1: I'm legally blind.
Speaker 1: Like, I'm not in the sense that I'm not allowed to drive a car without my glasses.
Speaker 1: Like, I have real bad vision.
Speaker 1: Despite that, if I take my glasses off and squint, I can still read the top fucking line.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: Uh, when I first got my New York State driver's license, they made me take the written test, even though I already had a driver's license.
Speaker 1: Like, they made me take the written test, so I took it.
Speaker 0: I didn't have to do that.
Speaker 1: I am of the mind that a human being who fails to get a perfect score on that test should never be allowed to drive ever.
Speaker 0: I agree.
Speaker 1: That test was questions like, "What do you do at a red
Speaker 1: light?".
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: I think the most- Who has the right of way at this four-way intersection?
Speaker 1: This really simple and contrived scenario.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: I think the most difficult question on the entire test was if you're turning left on an intersection that has a left-turn lane, and there's multiple lanes you could get into on the road you're turning onto, which lane are you obligated to get into if there's only one turning
Speaker 0: lane?
Speaker 0: The closest one.
Speaker 1: The closest one to what?
Speaker 0: Well, I mean, if you're in the leftmost lane, you're gonna- So, I'm gonna say- So, say I'm going forward- You're gonna end up in the five-lane road.
Speaker 1: Two lanes going one way, two going the other way, suicide lane in the middle.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: I'm turning left from the suicide lane onto another five-lane road.
Speaker 1: Into which lane do I pull?
Speaker 0: Uh, the one to the right of the suicide lane?
Speaker 0: You are correct.
Speaker 1: That was the answer.
Speaker 1: That was the most difficult question on the test.
Speaker 1: I had to think about it for a second as opposed to no seconds.
Speaker 1: But this story is going to reverberate Black Mirror-style forever.
Speaker 1: And I am not confident that a human in the same situation would have changed the outcome of this person's, uh, misadventure, shall we say.
Speaker 1: Pretty confident a human driving this car would have hit this person the same way.
Speaker 1: Especially because there was a human in the car with a steering wheel, gas, and brakes whose sole job was to sit in the car and intervene if the car seemed to be missing something.
Speaker 1: And that person did not, in fact, hit the brakes.
Speaker 1: So, uh, you got any news?
Speaker 0: I do have news.
Speaker 0: So the big news that's going on right now, uh, is this Facebook something story that everyone doesn't know what's going on.
Speaker 1: There's a lot of pieces to it.
Speaker 0: I could explain this story real easy, right?
Speaker 0: There was a professor in the UK, and this professor made a Facebook app that was sort of like a cute little questionnaire kind of app.
Speaker 0: It wasn't really a big deal, but when people went and signed up to use it in those days, wait, years ago, they clicked, like, "Yes, I agree.
Speaker 0: I give you permissions to get data from my Facebook account.
Speaker 0: Yes, yes,
Speaker 0: yes.".
Speaker 0: And now that app collected all this data from people's Facebook accounts.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: When it was active.
Speaker 0: So, nowadays, if you were to make a Facebook app, Facebook would not allow you to make an app that collected the amount of information that app collected in those days, uh, because they become much more restrictive.
Speaker 1: So a legacy app from the wild west.
Speaker 0: So, that app was gone, but the professor still had that data from that project.
Speaker 0: That professor then breaking, uh, basically in direct contradiction with the Facebook terms of service and the privacy policy that users agreed to when they, you know, with Facebook, gave that data, or sold it to a company in the UK called Cambridge Analytica.
Speaker 1: Now, it's worth noting that the EU, at least, has very strict rules around personal data.
Speaker 1: Way more strict than the US.
Speaker 0: Well, this is the UK, which is only sort of in the EU.
Speaker 1: Yes, the UK, however, also does have very strict laws and regulations around personal information.
Speaker 0: Anyway, anyway, so the point is Cambridge Analytica had this data, and Cambridge Analytica was a company that, uh, used its data to help, uh, win the US election for the current president.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: Who is, if you're not in America and don't know the difference, is literally evil.
Speaker 1: Like, we're in a real bad situation because of this.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so, but, this is like, so people who gave their data to Facebook and said yes to this still did not agree to this.
Speaker 0: Yup.
Speaker 0: Right?
Speaker 0: It's like, their data was used by a third party from Facebook in a way that the users did not agree to have it used, uh, and Facebook is like, no, it wasn't a theft.
Speaker 0: It was a, you know, basically a fraud.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Uh, so now there's all kinds of investigations and all kinds of hoo-ha, and Facebook is taking a big hit, and I saw some tweets that were like, why is Facebook people going to Cambridge Analytica before the authorities get there?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: That could just be a sensational tweet.
Speaker 0: Who knows?
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 1: I've seen, I've seen a lot of interesting implications around who really drove this use of the data and where the data was actually used.
Speaker 0: But was the professor up to?
Speaker 0: He's just a professor doing a research project and then sells or gives his data to some other company.
Speaker 1: There's a whistleblower involved who seems to, oh, there's a really good sentence in this article.
Speaker 0: One of the professor's assistants was, is actually, uh, they discovered is a Facebook employee now, and they're investigating that, what that person's up to.
Speaker 1: I'm going to wait to, uh, quote, I'm going to quote two short paragraphs from this, uh, Guardian article I'm going to link to for this.
Speaker 1: Uh, the Observer Report contradicts Cambridge Analytica's chief executive who said the company did not have Facebook data.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: Facebook waited more than two years after they discovered the breach before suspending Cambridge Analytica.
Speaker 1: It's not a breach, though.
Speaker 1: It's not a breach.
Speaker 1: Uh, Cambridge Analytica has denied inappropriate use of Facebook user profiles, comma, but a former employee who is now a whistleblower has emphatically contradicted that claim.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: There's a, the real issue here, like if you want to take away from this, is that understanding improper uses of personal data is nearly impossible, and the complexity of prosecuting it, getting any sort of recourse from it, this is going to tie up the courts for so long that I don't want to speculate.
Speaker 0: At least the UK courts.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Anyway, the point is, as we've said on Geek Nights many, many times, probably since the beginning of Geek Nights, there are zeros and ones.
Speaker 0: Any data that can be turned into zeros and ones will be, and any data that has become zeros and ones, once it is shared in a non-encrypted way, can and will be shared infinitely with no control by you, the law can't stop anyone.
Speaker 1: A control around data that is a EULA, a contract or a promise means basically nothing.
Speaker 0: For the same exact reason you can't keep an MP3 from spreading everyone and force them to buy your CD, the same exact rules apply, you can't keep everyone from sharing your phone number.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: So what do you do?
Speaker 1: Pure opinion, I think we do need a better and more nuanced regulatory framework around, if data is used in improper ways, ways to punish the people who so use.
Speaker 0: It will only work against people who are punishable, large corporations.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: Another part of this would be, if it is, if data usage like this is used for, say, evil political things or espionage type things, then CIA, FBI should probably come down with a heavy hammer.
Speaker 1: People should go to jail, extraditions.
Speaker 1: Probably the most important one, don't give stodgy apps permission to use your data.
Speaker 0: Yeah, also don't trust, you know, when you trust people, right, human beings, if I give RIM, if I tell RIM something, you know, even if he promises to keep it a secret, I'm now trusting RIM not to spread that to the entire universe.
Speaker 1: And if I share it with someone else, Scott is now transitively trusting everyone I trusted.
Speaker 0: Yes, this is how the world works.
Speaker 0: You cannot avoid this.
Speaker 0: You should opt to keep your data secret rather than share it.
Speaker 0: Even your most loved and most close person on Earth, you should not tell them your password or anything ever.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: Now, even now, like we have, so I will tell them.
Speaker 0: Unless you're dead, then you can tell them.
Speaker 1: We have a giant new NAS, which we're going to talk about in the second half of the show, but for, we are both administrators of it.
Speaker 1: So theoretically, we could go, like, I could just go, like, reset the password for her shares and, like, get into them or, like, do troubleshooting.
Speaker 1: But the actual accounts we use day to day do not have shared access.
Speaker 1: So even that thin barrier is better than nothing.
Speaker 1: Like, separate and if you have shared resources, like, Scott and I have some shared things we administer, but wherever possible, even though we could both, like, do things to screw over the other person, the day to day accounts we use are separate.
Speaker 1: But anyway, things of the day.
Speaker 1: What do you got for me?
Speaker 0: Uh, what did I have for you?
Speaker 1: Uh, you don't remember this?
Speaker 0: I'm trying to remember what my thing of day.
Speaker 0: Oh, I do remember what my thing of day was.
Speaker 0: So this is an old school thing of day from way back.
Speaker 0: You know, it's not actually old, like it's not being used again.
Speaker 0: But it's the kind of thing.
Speaker 0: It's the kind of thing of the day that we would use in the early days of Geek Nights.
Speaker 0: and I saw this and I said, man, that brings you back.
Speaker 0: This is a ball of matches.
Speaker 0: The matches that set on fire.
Speaker 0: They used to light a candle.
Speaker 1: 42,000 of them.
Speaker 0: 42,000 matches with, like, green at the end of them, which looks cool like green.
Speaker 0: And someone made a perfect sphere of these matches.
Speaker 0: And then they lit that baby up.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 1: There was an entire genre of pre YouTube video and early YouTube video.
Speaker 1: that was basically what would happen if you did this really inadvisable thing?
Speaker 1: Here's a video.
Speaker 1: Usually it ended with someone getting hurt.
Speaker 1: No one gets hurt in this video except the matches, I guess.
Speaker 1: And it looks really cool.
Speaker 1: It's a pretty good thing.
Speaker 1: I got a similarly low rent thing of the day.
Speaker 1: So this is just a very short scene from Rick and Morty.
Speaker 1: Like, nothing special there.
Speaker 1: Except someone has edited and replaced an object.
Speaker 1: that is the center of this very short scene.
Speaker 1: Whatever that object was is immaterial because they replaced it with a Bitcoin.
Speaker 1: And as a result this scene, this short 30 second clip summarizes basically every feeling I have about Bitcoin and cryptocurrency.
Speaker 1: In the moment, the booklet book is Emily Wilson's translation of Homer's Odyssey.
Speaker 1: Have you read any of it yet?
Speaker 0: I read the same amount that I read last time.
Speaker 1: You haven't even met Telemachus?
Speaker 0: No, but I know who that is.
Speaker 0: Odysseus' son.
Speaker 1: What's he do?
Speaker 1: Do you remember what he does?
Speaker 0: He looks for his dad.
Speaker 0: He goes around to like all these people saying, "Yo, where's Odysseus
Speaker 0: at?".
Speaker 1: I'm starting to realize that almost everyone we know read the Odyssey in high school.
Speaker 1: And I'm pretty sure almost every high school.
Speaker 1: really you didn't.
Speaker 0: There was a mythology class.
Speaker 0: I did not take it.
Speaker 0: I took other classes instead.
Speaker 1: We just did this in literature class.
Speaker 0: We had choices of classes.
Speaker 0: I took sci-fi class and I took Shakespeare class.
Speaker 1: 9th grade, we read basically all the Greek tragedies and the Odyssey.
Speaker 0: I took public speaking class.
Speaker 0: I took all these different classes.
Speaker 0: I didn't take the mythology one.
Speaker 1: That wasn't mythology.
Speaker 1: That was just literature.
Speaker 1: Antigone was just part of literature.
Speaker 0: We didn't have a literature class.
Speaker 0: We had choices.
Speaker 1: We had those too.
Speaker 1: I could have taken a dedicated Shakespeare class, but regular English class, you read a Shakespeare every year.
Speaker 0: We didn't have just English class.
Speaker 0: After 9th grade.
Speaker 1: We just had English every year and then 12th grade was...
Speaker 0: I took hippie literature class.
Speaker 0: 12th grade was all kinds of anti-war abuse.
Speaker 1: AP English.
Speaker 1: So anyway, but I get the impression that almost everyone we know who read the Odyssey in high school, they started them with the Odysseus part and just skipped the entire actual beginning of the Odyssey.
Speaker 1: because the Odyssey begins with Telemachus wondering where his dad went.
Speaker 1: You don't even meet Odysseus until well into the Odyssey.
Speaker 1: You get this cutaway to like, "What was Odysseus up to during all
Speaker 1: this?".
Speaker 1: So it's real good and I want to do the show on it kind of soon.
Speaker 0: I just keep the meta real short because the main meta is that PAX East is fucking soon.
Speaker 0: Soon as fuck.
Speaker 1: I made significant changes to our panel.
Speaker 0: And not only is it fucking soon, it's fucking four fucking days.
Speaker 1: Meaning, we gotta show up on Wednesday.
Speaker 1: There is pre-Pax Gaming.
Speaker 1: If you show up on Wednesday, there is official sanctioned.
Speaker 1: sit down in a space that is organized for this.
Speaker 0: God damn Hump Day and you're already at PAX that night gaming.
Speaker 1: We're gonna be playing Quartermaster General with like drinks and snacks in a tabletop gaming area on Wednesday.
Speaker 0: And Thursday while everyone's at freaking work and all these Bostonians are gonna be commuting, we're gonna be Paxing right next to them.
Speaker 1: Yep, Kino Q&A.
Speaker 1: Friday, same.
Speaker 0: Saturday, same.
Speaker 1: Sunday, the finale.
Speaker 1: And then Monday, I'm going home.
Speaker 1: I don't know what I'm gonna do.
Speaker 1: Like, let's see, I get four days of East, four days of West.
Speaker 1: That's eight days.
Speaker 1: Eleven when you add in South.
Speaker 1: Fourteen if you add in unplugged.
Speaker 1: Sixteen if I add in dev.
Speaker 1: I go to a lot of Paxes.
Speaker 0: You basically spend half a month a year at Paxes.
Speaker 1: I don't know what to do about this.
Speaker 0: Half a month to a month of every year.
Speaker 0: It's like one twenty-fourth of every year.
Speaker 1: This, friends and fans of Geek Nights, is why That doesn't count.
Speaker 0: Magfest also.
Speaker 0: That's only the Paxes.
Speaker 1: Which is also four days.
Speaker 0: We basically spend like a one-twelfth, almost one-twelfth of our lives at Paxes.
Speaker 1: So if you asked us to show up at a convention that you like, or you are a convention and you've emailed us over the years and asked us to come, that is why we either just don't respond, or when we do respond, we usually say,
Speaker 1: "Sorry.".
Speaker 0: Anyway.
Speaker 1: So, yeah, come see us at Pax East.
Speaker 1: It's gonna be awesome.
Speaker 1: And on Sunday, at ten thirty AM, we're gonna be doing a panel that we only did once before.
Speaker 1: We tried it out at Magfest at work.
Speaker 1: Now it's legit.
Speaker 1: Clickbait title, non-clickbait content.
Speaker 1: So let's get right into it.
Speaker 1: Scott had this idea, and it's actually a pretty good idea, because we buy a lot of technology.
Speaker 0: We probably shouldn't.
Speaker 1: But what we haven't done on Geek Nights, really, is do episodes reviewing technology.
Speaker 1: Like, I haven't, like, reviewed the ten eighty that I bought, like the particular one.
Speaker 0: It's a video card.
Speaker 0: What's there to review about it?
Speaker 1: Ah, price per dollar, like, or, not price per dollar.
Speaker 0: It's rather different from any other ten eighty.
Speaker 1: Price per, like, performance.
Speaker 1: I could've spent more to get, like, an overclocked one.
Speaker 0: It has HDMI out and a DisplayPort out and it works, and it plays games fast.
Speaker 0: And it renders the video.
Speaker 1: For most people, it is overkill, even if you're a crazy gamer.
Speaker 1: Like, if I didn't edit video all the time, I actually would've gotten a ten seventy instead.
Speaker 1: But, uh, anyway.
Speaker 0: I'd have a ten eighty, but I have a ten seventy because of the problems.
Speaker 1: So I have a ten eighty because I bought my video card before the troubles.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but the ten seventy's actually not causing me any troubles.
Speaker 0: Now I'm thinking like, "Hey, you know
Speaker 0: what?".
Speaker 0: I was like, "Man, I should buy a video card for the HDPC because I took the ten seventy out of
Speaker 0: it.".
Speaker 1: Just do the Steam stream.
Speaker 1: Hold out.
Speaker 0: But now I'm like, "You know what?
Speaker 0: I just won't buy a video card for that.
Speaker 0: I'll Steam stream only and, um...".
Speaker 1: Wait, and then eventually, maybe, buy, like, the twelve eighty.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Put it in your regular computer.
Speaker 0: Cascade's the old ten seventy.
Speaker 0: The ten seventy's plenty good for me.
Speaker 0: I'll just hold, stay put.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so I got a ten eighty here and I got a four sixty in the HDPC.
Speaker 0: I got an integrated one in the HDPC.
Speaker 0: My HDPC's way newer.
Speaker 1: Yeah, my HDPC is from early 2009.
Speaker 0: Mine's from, like, less than a year ago.
Speaker 1: So what we're gonna try out here is we're gonna review... Maybe it's a year old.
Speaker 0: Maybe it's older now.
Speaker 1: We're gonna review, in semi-random order, a bunch of tech we've bought and, hopefully, one, we'll give you some interesting commentary and, two, this will give us a sense of what kinds of technology would actually be worthy of doing, like, dedicated Geek Dice reviews of.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 1: So we'll see.
Speaker 1: I just found all the things I bought on Amazon recently.
Speaker 1: They're remotely relevant.
Speaker 1: So you want to start or should I start?
Speaker 0: So the thing that I bought most recently at Amazon is remotely relevant.
Speaker 0: It's something that everyone needs to have, which is a USB to serial ATA adapter thingy.
Speaker 0: This way... I mean, I had one of these, right, but the one that I had was... The oldest one I had was actually the IDE, right?
Speaker 0: Then I bought a serial ATA one, but I don't know what happened to it, so I bought a new one.
Speaker 1: Did you buy the Cables To Go one, like that one that everyone buys?
Speaker 0: No, so the one that I bought that was that I had that I found in my desk drawer at work was only for two and a half inch drives.
Speaker 0: It was basically USB on one end, serial ATA on the other end.
Speaker 1: Oh, I got one down here somewhere.
Speaker 0: But it didn't work on a three and a half inch drive because it didn't provide enough power to spin up the motor, right?
Speaker 0: So I went on Amazon and I was trying to find one that would be like, you know, because you can never tell like, is this one a good one or is it a bootleg, crappy one, right?
Speaker 0: So I just want to let people know.
Speaker 0: I got this guy.
Speaker 0: If you got a serial ATA drive... No, no, no.
Speaker 0: I just have the little cable.
Speaker 0: I don't have a box.
Speaker 1: Oh, there's a drive in here.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: If you want to connect an internal hard drive to a computer via USB, you should go on Amazon and buy the Ugreen USB 3 to SATA adapter.
Speaker 0: It comes with a little power supply thingy and now you can power up a three and a half inch drive.
Speaker 0: It will totally work.
Speaker 0: And it's USB 3 so it's pretty fast.
Speaker 0: It was good.
Speaker 0: Oh, it's a must have device for anyone with drives and computers.
Speaker 1: This is the SSD I bought back when SSDs were real expensive.
Speaker 1: that eventually died.
Speaker 1: I spent like 400 bucks on this thing.
Speaker 0: OK, something else really small that I bought is, you know, in my HDPC, I have an optical audio output, right?
Speaker 0: But my Nintendo Switch sends audio to the PC via HDMI cable and then the PC, the TV has an optical audio output.
Speaker 0: So you have these two optical audio outputs, but my speaker system only has one optical input.
Speaker 0: So I got a switch and the switch that I had for many years was large.
Speaker 0: It totally worked and it had a little remote control.
Speaker 1: Let me admit, shamefully, I'm still just using the speakers in my TV.
Speaker 0: I mean, whatever.
Speaker 1: They're not great.
Speaker 1: Like, I'm not going to pretend I'm not the kind of person who's going to say they're fine.
Speaker 1: They're not.
Speaker 1: I'm just too lazy to do anything about it.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so I had the opposite of an optical audio switch, but the remote control broke because it was a cheapo model, right?
Speaker 0: So I'm like, man, I should just try to fix this remote control.
Speaker 0: So I tried and I failed and the thing totally worked.
Speaker 0: I just get up to push the buttons on it to switch it.
Speaker 0: And it was large.
Speaker 0: So I went on Amazon just to see how much is a new one.
Speaker 0: You know what?
Speaker 0: A new one is fifteen dollars.
Speaker 0: So I'm like, all right, fuck it.
Speaker 0: I'll just buy the new one because the new one was so tiny compared to the one that I had.
Speaker 0: Now it's completely hidden.
Speaker 0: I freed up all this space in my own theater system because it's just this tiny little box.
Speaker 0: You don't even know it's there.
Speaker 0: And there's like a little.
Speaker 0: the remote control infrared receiver is on little wires.
Speaker 0: You can hide it somewhere and you can put the box hidden in the back and, you know, you don't see it.
Speaker 0: But the thing is the one that I originally ordered.
Speaker 0: I want to let people know the portrait three, the portrait three port three by one digital digital audio optical switch.
Speaker 0: What I actually received when I bought that on Amazon was not a switch, but instead the opposite of a switch has something with many outputs in one input.
Speaker 0: So I returned that and I instead ordered the J tech digital premium quality as p diff tasseling digital optical three by one switch.
Speaker 0: And that indeed was a switch.
Speaker 0: remote control that totally works.
Speaker 0: So if you've got many optical audio sources and one optical audio speaker input on the speaker end by one of these guys, it totally works as cheap.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: I'm actually looking at because Hitman the forum always talks a lot about like he knows soundbars pretty well.
Speaker 1: I'm thinking about just buying one of those soundbars.
Speaker 1: Soundbars ain't bad and just plugging it because unlike you there is only one thing that ever sends audio that I care about to the TV and that's the HD PC and I guess the switch would be a second, but it's just HDMI.
Speaker 1: So it still goes to the TV so I can just go out of the TV into a soundbar and not worry about it.
Speaker 0: I mean, if you're not doing surround, the reason to do the optical audio is for the surround sound, which I just gave up on.
Speaker 1: I let that ship sail.
Speaker 0: Then it doesn't matter.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: Soundbars just fine.
Speaker 1: So I'm thinking about it.
Speaker 1: I also got the Sonos device.
Speaker 1: That's for sure.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So I bought recently a whole bunch of USB cables from Anker.
Speaker 0: Why is that a story?
Speaker 1: So I want to review them.
Speaker 1: because, so the other day like a while ago, I was traveling like about a month ago and my phone started running low on battery because I was using it heavily and I was out a long time before I'd like be anywhere to charge it.
Speaker 1: So I plugged it into my Anker in my pocket and it just didn't charge.
Speaker 1: That was a problem.
Speaker 1: So I threw that USB cable away because clearly the USB cable was faulty.
Speaker 1: And over the next few weeks I had this happen to me like nine times.
Speaker 1: What happened, like I went back and looked, basically almost every USB cable I own I bought them all around the same time a long time ago.
Speaker 1: And they all just wore out in the same way.
Speaker 1: USB cables, well the previous generation of USB cables, not the modern like USB-C stuff, the USB micro with the little springs they wear out.
Speaker 1: They have a limited number of times.
Speaker 1: they can be plugged in before they start to lose their contacts.
Speaker 1: And all the USB cables I bought around the same time started to wear out around the same time.
Speaker 1: So I threw them all away and I just bought like a bunch of packs of Anker like braided cord USB cables.
Speaker 1: They're super cheap.
Speaker 1: And they're great.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so I've learned over the years lightning cables, right, and micro USB cables.
Speaker 0: That's like I was buying Amazon Basics ones.
Speaker 0: I was buying all kinds of different ones Anker ones.
Speaker 0: See which ones would be like the most durable right.
Speaker 0: Anker for greatly to their credit.
Speaker 0: Once I had one of their cables break that was supposed to be the super strong one.
Speaker 0: And they just sent me a new one like they were like oh warranty on that cable sure.
Speaker 0: And they just sent me a new one with no questions asked.
Speaker 0: But what I ended up realizing is that the way to go is the braided ones.
Speaker 0: If it's a rubber cable is no good.
Speaker 0: Metal cable is overkill and ridiculous.
Speaker 0: Braided cables will last the longest if they're seeing heavy use charging phones in your pocket anyway.
Speaker 1: So that's it because it's not something like the ones that are like near my computer like they're fine still.
Speaker 1: But I got rid of them anyway.
Speaker 0: You can also you can look for that MFI certification too.
Speaker 0: That's that's it.
Speaker 1: But I just bought all new USB cables and the Anker braided ones are fine and it was a great improvement over my previous state.
Speaker 1: And because I bought them all at once I bought the appropriate numbers of the appropriate lengths for all my possible use cases.
Speaker 0: It feels real good.
Speaker 0: I had a lot that were too long in different places.
Speaker 1: And I had some that were too short.
Speaker 1: I had a couple that were one foot long.
Speaker 1: That is actually too short.
Speaker 0: I also want to say if you go you can buy these hundred packs of like velcro cable ties.
Speaker 1: Oh yeah.
Speaker 0: Actual velcro brand.
Speaker 0: I'm ordering my second pack and I'm putting one in every single cable I own.
Speaker 0: And it's great because now nothing ever tangles.
Speaker 0: Cables that are in storage are all bundled up nicely and even cables that I'm using have the velcro on there so I can shorten them or tie them up and put them away and untie them.
Speaker 0: It's like.
Speaker 0: so just get those by as many as you need and put these little velcro ties but one literally every fucking cable you own no matter what kind of cable is HDMI cable, lightning cable whatever.
Speaker 0: It'll be super great.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: I did something similar a decade ago with all the Geek Nights audio crap.
Speaker 1: So I did buy something actually new.
Speaker 1: So as you know I still think to this day that the Pebble smartwatch was the best possible UX for a smartwatch.
Speaker 0: Pebble watch is pretty great.
Speaker 0: The only reason I stopped using the Pebble watch is because it died.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: Because it didn't do a bunch of fancy bullshit that you don't need.
Speaker 1: It was always on.
Speaker 1: you got your notifications.
Speaker 0: The battery lasted forever.
Speaker 1: The battery lasted like a week.
Speaker 0: It looked great.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So the only reason.
Speaker 0: It was comfy and small.
Speaker 1: So Scott's kind of stopped working and he got the iWatch.
Speaker 0: It didn't really stop working.
Speaker 0: it just worked a little bit less good.
Speaker 0: And then the support went away.
Speaker 1: So I held out longer but eventually the basic things I use it for.
Speaker 0: I think the reason I was able to bail so easily is because Apple is just like guess what new Apple watches with LTE and I'm like well alright.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: And I do think that both the Apple watch and the Android watches are an inferior overall experience to the Pebble for us.
Speaker 0: Well I think that if you have an iPhone like I do the Apple watch is actually sort of better.
Speaker 1: It does more but it's a trade off.
Speaker 0: The trade off is that it's a little bit bigger but that actually stopped bothering me now.
Speaker 0: It's more expensive.
Speaker 0: that's truly a problem.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: It's not always on.
Speaker 0: And the battery life is much worse.
Speaker 0: But other than that it's better.
Speaker 1: So I can't get an iWatch because I don't have an iPhone.
Speaker 1: so I had to get an Android watch.
Speaker 0: You can get an iPhone.
Speaker 1: Eh.
Speaker 1: I like my, I actually really like my Android smartphone.
Speaker 0: I haven't had an iPhone.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: You know what?
Speaker 0: You haven't had an iPhone.
Speaker 1: You say that I like this phone.
Speaker 1: Completely waterproof for a long time.
Speaker 1: I just like take it in the shower with me and read Fark like it's totally chill.
Speaker 1: Anyway so I needed to buy a smartwatch because the rot of services got to the point that my Pebble was an inferior experience.
Speaker 1: I gave it to our friend Kat because she's gonna ride the Pebble train to the bitter end.
Speaker 0: And yeah.
Speaker 0: I got Pebble watches.
Speaker 0: I have two of the original Pebble watch.
Speaker 0: One is broken.
Speaker 0: And one Pebble Time which is not really broken.
Speaker 0: It's just sitting there unused.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: So I factually said it and gave it to her so she can extend the life.
Speaker 1: I read that.
Speaker 0: I'll put them with my Google Glass in my museum of technology.
Speaker 1: In July.
Speaker 1: You can kind of use Google Glass with generic Android wear actually.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna try that out.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna see if I can just get started using it again.
Speaker 1: Alright.
Speaker 0: Good luck.
Speaker 1: But I had I had to buy a smartwatch and I was looking at Android because I can't do the iWatch thing.
Speaker 1: Most Android smartwatches are either gigantic bullshit monsters just like most Android phones are.
Speaker 1: And a lot of them are way too expensive for what they do.
Speaker 1: And it seems like the best one to get is the LG style.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 1: The reason for the obsessed one I bought.
Speaker 1: The reason I got it is that it's the smallest one.
Speaker 0: That's a good reason.
Speaker 1: The battery seems to last like all day.
Speaker 1: It's fine.
Speaker 1: Like an iWatch.
Speaker 1: Alright.
Speaker 1: It doesn't have.
Speaker 0: But a pebble watch lasts multiple days.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: But I can't compare it to the pebble because I can't buy a new pebble.
Speaker 1: I can't keep using the pebble.
Speaker 1: The LG style smartwatch in my opinion is the best Android smartwatch.
Speaker 0: What Android smartwatches have you tried?
Speaker 1: Just reading specs, reading reviews.
Speaker 1: I bought this one.
Speaker 1: I've been using it.
Speaker 0: The one that I bought is the best one.
Speaker 0: I haven't tried any others.
Speaker 1: So what I'm gonna say is that the other ones are definitely bigger and don't seem to provide any material advantages for me over this small minimalist one.
Speaker 1: I couldn't like every other smartwatch I looked at.
Speaker 1: this Android was way bigger had a bunch of bullshit in.
Speaker 1: it was real ugly but mostly just it was so big.
Speaker 1: This is the smallest one.
Speaker 1: It's actually the same size as a normal watch.
Speaker 1: I got out my old normal watch from high school.
Speaker 1: They're all the people who say this watch is bad.
Speaker 1: their primary complaint is it's too small on my wrist.
Speaker 0: Same people want a giant phone.
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 1: So I have the tiny weird Android phone and the tiny Android smartwatch and while it is an objectively inferior experience to the pebble, it is a perfectly fine experience.
Speaker 1: if pebbles didn't exist and I needed a smartwatch.
Speaker 0: Alright.
Speaker 0: so I had this NAS, the ready NAS NV+ which actually was way older than I thought and at one point I had to replace the power supply in it with a third party power supply and that actually totally worked.
Speaker 1: Yeah that feels wrong though.
Speaker 0: Yeah it does not.
Speaker 0: even though like I thought it was failing but actually it was not properly informing me of the way the drive failed and I did put a new drive in it and it totally did resurrect itself.
Speaker 1: My night gear ready NAS do had similar problems like it would get into a weird state and I have to fuss with it.
Speaker 0: But the main thing is that it was really slow, it was really noisy.
Speaker 0: it had a lot of issues it's like but for some reason it did keep on working like it was a good.
Speaker 0: if you just cared about your data being reliable as long as you replaced the power supply.
Speaker 1: Same boat, this net gear thing like it actually is still working fine.
Speaker 1: it's just annoying to use and kind of dodgy.
Speaker 0: The main problem that really bothered me the most though was the fact that it failed made me worried of its future reliability.
Speaker 0: Yup.
Speaker 0: Also the it only supported, the software never really got updated so it only supported SMB1.
Speaker 0: Windows 10 actually removed support for SMB1 because it's inherently insecure and you have to go to a special menu to add SMB1 support back to Windows because SMB2 is secure and I really was like you know I probably should stop using SMB1 and disable that and use SMB2 only.
Speaker 0: but to do that I need new NAS.
Speaker 0: So I went and I bought the Synology that Rym has.
Speaker 0: only mine is the same as his.
Speaker 0: only mine is four bays, Rym has five bays.
Speaker 0: Yup.
Speaker 0: But it's otherwise identical.
Speaker 0: it's the Synology.
Speaker 0: I have the DS918+ And I have the DS1517+.
Speaker 0: It's the same exact device only mine has one less drive bay in it.
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 0: And let me tell you compared to that ready NAS and it costs a lot of money for this thing.
Speaker 0: Yup.
Speaker 0: It's night and fucking day.
Speaker 0: the Synology is like a masterpiece of engineering.
Speaker 0: it is incredible.
Speaker 1: And we both had this experience.
Speaker 1: our NASes are the same other than this one bay.
Speaker 0: But NASes like this didn't exist when I bought my NV+.
Speaker 1: So the big difference is kinda like how when we went from building those old AMD computers just going Intel I turned this thing on.
Speaker 1: it just works.
Speaker 1: there's a web interface that is super responsive.
Speaker 0: The web interface looks like a desktop operating like you go in your browser and a thing that looks like Windows comes up and you can drag and drop and it has Windows in it.
Speaker 0: It's like a whole GUI OS windowing but it's just to manage your NAS.
Speaker 0: it has apps you can install and it all works perfectly.
Speaker 0: it has any feature.
Speaker 0: it's like you don't need to hack firmwares or anything cause any feature that you can imagine.
Speaker 0: like gee I'd really like my computer to automatically back up things to this NAS.
Speaker 0: Oh there's a thing that does that.
Speaker 0: Gee I'd really like this NAS to automatically back up it's data to the cloud.
Speaker 0: there's a thing that does that.
Speaker 0: Gee I really wish this NAS like I could plug things into its USB slot.
Speaker 0: It does that.
Speaker 0: Anything that you could possibly like you don't need it to be open source cause literally any feature you can possibly imagine that you'd want this NAS to do is an app.
Speaker 1: look Active Directory hit a button.
Speaker 1: it's an AD server now DHCP server.
Speaker 0: it's a web server.
Speaker 0: there's like nothing that I could possibly want it to do.
Speaker 0: that it doesn't do.
Speaker 1: you can run like clouds.
Speaker 1: I can run Java bullshit on it.
Speaker 1: look at this node node.js.
Speaker 0: it's super quiet.
Speaker 0: if you when you plug it in you go to find.synology.com and it finds it.
Speaker 0: you can even fix the SSL cert on it if you want to.
Speaker 0: it's like damn like the people at Synology I can tell are Linux nerds who set the shit up and know how it goes down.
Speaker 0: but also it uses BetterFS for its raid.
Speaker 0: it's like damn son.
Speaker 1: it's very much prosumer edging into professional.
Speaker 1: because the plus model is well yeah so we are specifically reviewing the plus models.
Speaker 1: the non plus model not.
Speaker 1: it's more like the regular old shitty NAS experience.
Speaker 1: it'll still work.
Speaker 1: it is that little plus is worth the extra couple hundred bucks like way worth it.
Speaker 1: the other big difference I think that we both notice is that it is just faster.
Speaker 0: like data access is faster everything is so much faster compared to the other.
Speaker 0: and it could be cause the drives are faster but they're like 5400 RPM drives.
Speaker 1: they're still spinning disks yeah and the only reason I have 5 bays instead of 4 is my NAS is for 2 people.
Speaker 1: so that extra storage actually really mattered a lot cause Emily generates a lot of data and I also generate a lot of data.
Speaker 1: so we're both using it.
Speaker 1: I enabled the Glacier Sync.
Speaker 1: it just synchronizes up to Glacier.
Speaker 1: it has a built in interface for like restoring files.
Speaker 1: if this NAS dies I can download the NAS's configuration from Glacier back onto itself like.
Speaker 1: it's pretty great.
Speaker 1: the only problem I have with this NAS other than that it is substantially more expensive than a typical consumer NAS like hundreds and hundreds of dollars more.
Speaker 0: yes Synology has other models that are much cheaper and from what I can tell those models do have similar features like probably are.
Speaker 0: actually I probably recommend them based on what I know but they are gonna be much slower and they don't have a lot of RAM and power in them so they might not be as a magical experience as the plus fancy models.
Speaker 0: the other thing with the plus model that really sold me on it is I'm thinking man down the road what if this NAS is too small?
Speaker 0: right you know what if I need bigger drives in there?
Speaker 0: what if right you can get expansion things to add more slots.
Speaker 0: I can get this thing and attach it.
Speaker 0: that will add 5 more 4 or 5 more bays to this thing and just put another volume in there.
Speaker 0: yeah and so I could load that up with drives.
Speaker 0: then I could basically get enough parity swap out my old drives put in bigger ones.
Speaker 0: right because the drives I have in there are 4 terabyte drives.
Speaker 1: I want 8 terabyte partly because I got them on sale though I think it might be able to support like 16 8.
Speaker 0: it definitely is 8 terabyte drives so I can at least double my capacity.
Speaker 0: it might support 16 terabyte drives.
Speaker 0: I don't know all I'm saying.
Speaker 1: one day those are gonna be cheap and available if you have serious data needs and are not a company.
Speaker 1: the Synology NAS is with the plus.
Speaker 1: next to them the DS number number number number plus they like.
Speaker 0: that is the solution it's gonna.
Speaker 0: it's gonna really help you out.
Speaker 0: if you have you know computers like comparing these to like some of the QNAP type things I think this can actually even more than someone like me.
Speaker 0: if you're the kind of person who's say doing like photo and video work right oh yeah and you've got like a laptop and you don't really have a desktop.
Speaker 0: just having this in your house right.
Speaker 0: so when you get home you back everything up that it's gonna.
Speaker 0: really it's really huge.
Speaker 1: now I'll give you one further caveat don't go beyond five bays unless you know what you're doing.
Speaker 0: you don't need more than five days beyond five bays.
Speaker 1: there's actually a different kind of drive you probably want to buy or else the resonance of this device on its own will actually increase your drive failure rate?
Speaker 1: yeah we don't even need that.
Speaker 0: so in relation to that I think we both bought the Western Digital.
Speaker 0: what's it called my passport?
Speaker 1: oh yeah I put that in here because I was gonna talk about that right?
Speaker 0: so what this is related to the NAS.
Speaker 0: so what this is?
Speaker 0: it's such.
Speaker 1: it's so good I didn't realize.
Speaker 0: once I realized this existed I paid even though it's kind of also overpriced.
Speaker 1: it's like two hundred bucks for the four terabyte.
Speaker 0: I got the four.
Speaker 0: I got the biggest one because the three terabyte one's like ten dollars cheaper right.
Speaker 0: so anyway what this is?
Speaker 0: it's an external hard drive.
Speaker 0: it's an external USB three hard drive.
Speaker 0: right okay it's a big square.
Speaker 1: it's kind of big yep but it's self powered.
Speaker 0: it's self powered.
Speaker 0: so it is also a battery.
Speaker 0: you can turn it on when it's attached to fucking nothing connect to it with your phone with an app wirelessly and look at your data on there.
Speaker 0: you can back up your phone to it wirelessly.
Speaker 0: you can get stuff from it wirelessly.
Speaker 1: you can plug your phone into it and charge your phone from it if you're really in a pinch.
Speaker 0: it's a battery right it's a battery and a hard drive but wait there's more.
Speaker 0: it has an SD slot.
Speaker 0: you can take your SD card out of your camera or your phone or whatever shove it in there and it will start once you push a button backing up that data from the SD card to itself when it's not even plugged into the wall because again it has a battery in it.
Speaker 0: also that wireless part is wifi.
Speaker 0: you can with it not connect it to anything.
Speaker 0: have it connect to wifi to get it on the internet and it can back up its data to the cloud when it's connected to fucking nothing.
Speaker 1: or because I set up my NAS like this.
Speaker 1: so we're at a con we video like a bunch of panels.
Speaker 0: yeah this is the main workflow here.
Speaker 0: you video stuff you photo stuff.
Speaker 0: you take your SD cards while you're out and about traveling and every night you put your SD cards into this to back them up.
Speaker 0: then when you get home you take this you plug it right into your NAS.
Speaker 0: you plug this external drive this Western Digital My Passport thing into your NAS and push the button on the NAS.
Speaker 0: now that drive starts backing up all the photos and videos from your trip onto the NAS.
Speaker 0: meanwhile you take your SD cards that you didn't erase over to your computer and start editing video while the backing up is happening losing no time whatsoever.
Speaker 0: and now you've got four copies of your stuff.
Speaker 0: you've got it on the Passport you got it on your NAS you got it on your SD cards and now you have it on your desktop where you're working on it and maybe you'll have it in the class.
Speaker 0: so suddenly you got five copies of something with like no effort.
Speaker 0: super backed up super safe it's.
Speaker 0: it really changes everything.
Speaker 1: like the workflow for me and Scott now at a convention is we both generate a bunch of SD cards with shit.
Speaker 1: I put all mine into mine he puts all his into his and then we swap cards we swap SD cards so they're all backed up two times.
Speaker 1: so then when we both get home we can both immediately start making whatever media we're gonna make from our combined set of footage.
Speaker 0: right but even if you're just say like even if you're like just a wedding photographer right okay so you're at a wedding you're taking photos taking photos fill the memory card shove it in here put a new memory card in the camera shoot photo shoot photo shoot photos.
Speaker 0: by the time you filled up that memory card it's gonna be done right.
Speaker 0: it's gonna be so huge.
Speaker 0: I don't know really how.
Speaker 0: if you're someone who collects data on the go right maybe even if you're just like doing work on the go that creates large amounts of data you need one of these bad boys like before.
Speaker 1: this like the UX is the reason to buy this because before this like I could do a similar workflow but what I ended up doing is I'd plug the SD cards into my laptop that had an external hard drive connected to it
Speaker 0: and then you had to manually drag
Speaker 1: them all around.
Speaker 1: do you know how many times I would like forget to drag one like I'd forget one and I get home and I can't edit the panel until Scott comes over like the next week and gives me his SD card.
Speaker 0: yep it's it's real if you go out and take videos or photos or something.
Speaker 0: these are these like must have device here.
Speaker 1: I am super impressed with this device and I can't.
Speaker 1: there aren't really other ones like it.
Speaker 0: yeah do not get the Western Digital NAS because I've heard bad things about those.
Speaker 0: get the Synology one.
Speaker 1: so we both bought.
Speaker 1: we both needed a label maker partly to label our SD cards.
Speaker 1: as part of updating this workflow.
Speaker 0: I didn't update my label my SD cards.
Speaker 1: we both bought the same.
Speaker 1: there's this one label maker on Amazon.
Speaker 1: it's like the cheapest one.
Speaker 1: it's like 30 bucks and it's fine.
Speaker 1: okay I don't know what else I can say about it.
Speaker 1: it's fine I'm using it as my label maker.
Speaker 1: the fact that the mere fact of owning a label maker is convenient enough to be worth this basically trivial cost of entry even if it breaks in a year or two.
Speaker 0: it was so cheap I used it to label batteries.
Speaker 0: so I know because labeling batteries is a great idea.
Speaker 0: you've got say you know something that has like.
Speaker 0: so you got a GoPro and you got five GoPro batteries.
Speaker 0: right you label them one two three four and five always start with one.
Speaker 0: now you know which ones are the ones that are full and empty.
Speaker 0: right without having some sort of system of like flipping them or whatever.
Speaker 1: right yeah those I had.
Speaker 1: all those systems it's.
Speaker 1: this is so much more elegant.
Speaker 0: labeling them all is way better than what I say.
Speaker 1: yep all right.
Speaker 0: so something else I want to talk about here.
Speaker 1: all right what do you want?
Speaker 0: so you know for many many moons since like 2000 before geek nights I always used headphones.
Speaker 0: I had six I which is the white ones that went with iPods.
Speaker 0: then I upgraded to like the hf2 hf3 ones which had the controllers which are for iPhones and I went through a few of those and the main.
Speaker 0: the thing is they were effectively perfect.
Speaker 0: they did everything I wanted.
Speaker 0: they sounded great.
Speaker 0: I didn't sound the best but they sounded great.
Speaker 0: the isolation was incredible.
Speaker 0: you put them on and you could stand next to a subway train with your volume down real low.
Speaker 0: you'd hear your music.
Speaker 0: you wouldn't hear the subway.
Speaker 1: I use the exact same ones for a long time.
Speaker 0: your hearing was protected.
Speaker 0: it was fantastic.
Speaker 0: you know the controls on the wire worked great.
Speaker 0: everything was great except the problem with every single animatic I've ever had no matter what model is that the wires were flimsy as hell.
Speaker 0: and what would eventually happen over months or perhaps a year or two of use is that the wire near the jack would become stressed and you could tell that it broke internally because your music would cut out and you'd wiggle the wire near the jack and if you held it in just the right position you could hear the sound again.
Speaker 0: but if you let go well then it would cut out again because the wire was broken inside the rubber cable.
Speaker 0: they never made ones that had duh replaceable cables.
Speaker 0: all they had to do they had to make one with a completely replaceable cable.
Speaker 0: where the cable goes up to the actual earbud.
Speaker 0: they didn't have to make it to where like maybe the cable ended around your neck and then there was a little you know jack where you could swap it out because the part that always broke was the part that was in your pocket anyway.
Speaker 0: so the etymotic broke again as I thought they would and I may yet still RMA them which is all.
Speaker 0: they've always honored my warranty even when I've been way beyond warranty.
Speaker 0: but I decided to take you know to try out some wireless headphone option instead.
Speaker 0: because well wireless you don't got to worry about any cable damage right?
Speaker 1: I will admit that the non apple wireless headphone experience generally sucks.
Speaker 0: yes so I've had bluetooth headphones before.
Speaker 0: I have some I was going to review and they're always a pain in the ass because the bluetooth pairing really sucks.
Speaker 0: so I looked apple the new apple bluetooth whatever has this thing where the there's certain headphones that use like the wireless apple standard and they quote just work.
Speaker 0: so uh one of our listeners luke suggested he is a big big fan of the beats x wireless inner headphones I mean beats kind of turned me off because like you know it's beats I mean I bought.
Speaker 1: sure in the end that's what I'm using for this.
Speaker 0: but I went.
Speaker 0: I bought them just to see how they were.
Speaker 0: I figured I could return them and here's how they are right.
Speaker 0: so on the first problem I had when I got them is that the wireless part it is once you do have it hooked up to your iPhone it's pretty great because like you turn them on and it's paired turn them off unpaired it.
Speaker 0: once you pair them with your iPhone your apple watch and your iPad both know about it now so you can easily.
Speaker 0: just I went to my iPad.
Speaker 0: I pushed one button and it just switched.
Speaker 0: it moved from the iPhone to the iPad immediately.
Speaker 0: it's super great.
Speaker 0: the pairing works.
Speaker 0: uh the thing is it took me a while to get used to turning them on and off and I had to turn on and I wasn't used to turning my headphones on and off.
Speaker 0: now I am.
Speaker 0: but until you get used to that it was kind of annoying like why is music coming out?
Speaker 0: oh I didn't turn my headphones on right.
Speaker 0: they do have a battery that will run out but it lasts so long.
Speaker 0: I've never had it run out.
Speaker 0: uh you do have to charge it with a lightning cable which okay.
Speaker 0: so I charge my headphones at night.
Speaker 0: it's a thing I have to remember to do but I got used to it it.
Speaker 0: you know it's still not as good as wired.
Speaker 0: um the two problems with it the negatives and I think this might be the only negative.
Speaker 0: oh the sound first of all.
Speaker 0: uh the you can see the drivers on these are like way bigger than the drivers on the etymotic and they sound way more bassy and way more like fun.
Speaker 0: I guess that's what beats are supposed to sound like.
Speaker 1: my surers are pretty much the same way like they have this giant driver.
Speaker 0: yeah it's like you can like.
Speaker 0: they sound more fun.
Speaker 0: I don't know if they sound better for certain kinds of music.
Speaker 0: you know it it's yeah that well I mean that's the kind of moods we don't really get into.
Speaker 1: but there's there's a difference between headphones that sound good for listening to music and headphones that are a pure experience which really only matters if you're doing like editing a podcast.
Speaker 0: so I can't really judge the quality of it so much but it's definitely a different aesthetic to the listening experience.
Speaker 0: yeah um so the negatives is that one they don't.
Speaker 0: they're not like comfortable in my ear.
Speaker 0: and the.
Speaker 0: there's multiple earbud choices like different you know rubber bits you can put on.
Speaker 0: none of them felt great and none of them sealed to isolate my ear at all.
Speaker 0: really.
Speaker 0: and when I was first began using them I was very frustrated with the lack of isolation.
Speaker 0: because it was such stark contrast because I do because the etymotic skin wearing out.
Speaker 1: I went with the Shure out and said I got the Shure like durable ones the SE-215.
Speaker 1: they're invincible.
Speaker 1: I can replace the cables if they break.
Speaker 0: oh yeah the durability is not a concern.
Speaker 1: but also the.
Speaker 1: they have the flange tips.
Speaker 0: there are flange tips.
Speaker 0: they're just not the triple flange they're two flange.
Speaker 1: nah you need the three.
Speaker 0: well they don't have a three flange.
Speaker 1: so I have the three flange.
Speaker 1: but I tried out the Shure just like the foam thing that you roll up and expands in your ear.
Speaker 1: perfect isolation just great.
Speaker 0: I don't think there was a foam thing that rolled up in my ear.
Speaker 0: there were three.
Speaker 0: I think there were three sizes of rubber bits giant giant medium and small.
Speaker 0: this is the style I'm using right now and none of them felt great and none of them isolated.
Speaker 1: great these are like way comfortable.
Speaker 0: maybe I can go get some different ones somewhere but yeah the one again I have some extras they might fit.
Speaker 0: actually I know the ones that came with it were not good.
Speaker 0: they don't isolate and they're not comfy.
Speaker 1: yeah see I got all these different options that came with mine.
Speaker 0: what was the other negative part besides not isolating and not being comfy?
Speaker 0: there was something else that bothered me about them.
Speaker 1: yeah cause I use the Shures.
Speaker 1: they're wired but I don't really care.
Speaker 0: oh I remember so because they're all appley and Bluetooth and what not right?
Speaker 0: I pulled out my Nintendo Switch and then I was like oh there is no way for me to connect these headphones oh see my Shures to this Nintendo Switch.
Speaker 1: they're plugged into my phone and I think oh I'm gonna play my Switch.
Speaker 1: I just plugged them into my Switch.
Speaker 0: the animatics are normal wired headphones with a wired jack.
Speaker 0: I could plug them into a Switch or a DS or whatever.
Speaker 0: it was not so with these wireless headphones with a lightning connector and it's like they connect to your apple watch and your iPhone and your iPad.
Speaker 0: and that's it.
Speaker 0: they don't connect to nothing else.
Speaker 0: I can't plug them into my computer or anything.
Speaker 0: so that was very.
Speaker 0: you know it's like on the one hand.
Speaker 0: well now I don't have to use that little converter on the bottom of my iPhone which doesn't have a headphone jack.
Speaker 0: but hey at least with that converter I could detach the converter and use my headphones on a Nintendo Switch.
Speaker 0: no I can't.
Speaker 0: so yeah if you use your headphones with anything that is not an apple device you might not want to get these.
Speaker 1: so I bought some wireless.
Speaker 0: it's like I'm sticking with them cause I got them but I feel like when they did I'm probably not getting them again.
Speaker 1: yeah I like my Shures.
Speaker 0: I might even just try to get my Etymotic or Playz now but I did buy a wireless headphone.
Speaker 1: I use the Shures for like normal listening but I have a specific use case of mostly in the winter when it's crappy I will run or bike on a treadmill or exercise bike and I want to listen to music or podcast or like watch Netflix on a tablet while I'm doing so.
Speaker 1: and isolation headphones plus exercise equals weird sweaty air.
Speaker 0: okay I guess I don't have this problem cause I never wear a headphone while I'm downstairs running for like an hour and a half.
Speaker 1: I don't want to just have nothing.
Speaker 1: so I bought these like $60 Blue Ant.
Speaker 1: I don't know what that brand is but these over the year Bluetooth wireless headphones it's one of those cheapo brands.
Speaker 1: yeah they're like 60 bucks.
Speaker 0: I had ones like that at work.
Speaker 0: those are the ones that were difficult to pair but otherwise the ones I bought were August brand and I had them at work and they were actually amazing.
Speaker 0: if once I got them paired and working at work and I would charge them they sounded great.
Speaker 0: they were actually the most comfortable headphones over ear headphones I've had.
Speaker 0: it was like a square around my ears so cozy.
Speaker 0: the reason they died is simply cause they were so cheaply manufactured.
Speaker 0: the plastic band that went over my head cracked like the rig.
Speaker 1: the rig was so comfortable and then it just snapped in two and I was like well that was pretty much the same situation.
Speaker 1: so these are made specifically for exercise.
Speaker 0: those look good.
Speaker 1: so the deal is they're kind of waterproof.
Speaker 1: so like they're waterproof in fact I wouldn't bring them in the pool but if I sweat on them I can just wipe the sweat off.
Speaker 0: they don't soak in but I wouldn't take them outside.
Speaker 0: they only get wet.
Speaker 1: they're sweat proof.
Speaker 0: I mean I've never had headphones that aren't sweat proof.
Speaker 1: yeah but if they have like foam then your sweat will kind of seep into the foam.
Speaker 1: there's nothing to seep into two.
Speaker 1: the batteries last a long time.
Speaker 1: they isolate pretty well.
Speaker 1: the pairing was interesting though because one I can just plug a three and a quarter inch jack into it.
Speaker 0: yeah that's the kind that I had.
Speaker 1: yeah so I can plug it into like a device.
Speaker 1: but also the quick way to pair it is as NFC.
Speaker 1: I just hold them up to the back of my phone and then my phone goes.
Speaker 0: we're good to go and it just works.
Speaker 0: mine did not do that.
Speaker 1: now while they're paired sometimes the Bluetooth just works but you know how Bluetooth is finicky and sometimes it doesn't.
Speaker 1: if it ever doesn't seem like it's just gonna work all I have to do is hold it up with the NFC and it just instantly works.
Speaker 1: that was pretty clever and I'm pretty pleased with that aspect of them.
Speaker 1: the sound quality though is not great because they're cheap but it's good enough for a podcast while I'm like lifting weights for an hour.
Speaker 0: yeah the August Bluetooth ones that I had the sound quality was much better when you plugged them in with a wire than when you used the Bluetooth.
Speaker 0: the other reason I want the wire on my Shure isolations is that occasionally and I did make sure I was using the right Bluetooth profile it wasn't that that was the problem.
Speaker 1: I do uh like when I'm rejiggering the Geeknight's audio or I'm mastering like a video that I really care about.
Speaker 1: one thing I will do is I'll play parts of the audio not just with my monitor headphones from the mixer while I'm editing but also from cheap headphones plugged into the mixer and also with my isolation earbuds directly into the mixer to make sure I'm not optimizing to make a poor experience for like a normal person.
Speaker 1: so if I had like iPhone-y app-ly things the only way to test that would be to like play back the audio that I exported from the editor on an iPhone.
Speaker 1: that would be a pain in the ass.
Speaker 1: so the fact that it's wired is actually still a use case for me.
Speaker 0: alright this is long enough and I'm hungry even though there's a lot more things we can talk about.
Speaker 0: yep so I'm gonna skip.
Speaker 0: there's so much stuff I can talk about but you know give us feedback.
Speaker 1: was this interesting useful?
Speaker 1: should we do this again cause.
Speaker 1: this is an easy way to knock out a bunch of Monday episodes.
Speaker 0: thanks a bunch.
Speaker 1: this has been Geeknights with Rim and Scott.
Speaker 1: special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 0: be sure to visit our website at frontrowcrew.com for show notes, discussion news and more.
Speaker 1: remember Geeknights is not one but four different shows SciTech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays, and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 0: Geeknights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 0: Geeknights is recorded live with no studio and no audience but unlike those other late shows it's actually recorded at night
Speaker 1: and the Patreon patrons for this episode of Geeknights are Craig Oliver, Alan Joyce, Rebecca Dunn, Heidi McNichol, A Shimmering Ruby Obelisk Hanging in the Sky, MyStacy.com, Jeremy Minor, Link Ege, Cold Guy, Amanda Duchette, Sean Yeager, Matthew Smith, Nicholas Brando, Mr.
Speaker 1: Strong Strachan, 421 Creations, No I Never Ever Wonder Why We're Here, Semper Fi Bitch,
Speaker 0: Shervin
Speaker 1: Van Horl, Rare Laval, James David White, Rochelle Montanona, Superboy, Rim Says Something Funny Here, Sailor Vista, Don Schleich, Kjartavishan, Joe Shrojo Star, Sam Cordery, Clinton Walton, Ren from New Zealand, Ryan Perrin, Drew Openlander, Finn, Chris Midkiff, Chris Knox, Daniel Redman, Sean Klein, Chris Reimer, and Thomas Hahn.
Speaker 1: Many of you complained about the duck song last time, as Emily predicted.
Speaker 1: All I can say is you know what you're in for when you come into the end of the podcast here, and I regret nothing.
Speaker 1: So now I leave you with...
Speaker 0: you, so go and pardon your cute little pussycat nose.
Speaker 0: Pussycat, pussycat, I love you, yes, I love you and your pussycat nose.
Speaker 0: What's new, pussycat?
Speaker 0: Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
Speaker 0: Whoa,