Speaker 1: It's Monday April 16th 2018 on rim.
Speaker 1: I'm just gonna and this is geek nights tonight.
Speaker 1: We are talking about destroying data.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: So I had a co-worker who was in town from London this week And I got to tell him that he basically got to experience the entirety of New York spring.
Speaker 1: okay, cuz It feels like this has only been happening in the last three years.
Speaker 1: But I feel like every year.
Speaker 1: It's just like winter and then suddenly it's 80 degrees and then it goes like a little bit And then it's just summer.
Speaker 0: everyone talks about climate change, right?
Speaker 0: Oh, it's get the.
Speaker 0: you know, the average temperature of the world is getting warmer, right?
Speaker 0: Well, that's not been my experience.
Speaker 0: My experience is simply that we did.
Speaker 0: the start and end of the seasons has been shifted later, right?
Speaker 1: It's not just that the summer star selves are.
Speaker 0: summer starts later and it goes longer and then winter starts later and goes longer.
Speaker 0: So really just the season moved.
Speaker 0: they got pushed ahead in the year.
Speaker 0: They don't line up with the months in the same way, but it's not that it is not extreme.
Speaker 0: the changes are more extreme on a day-to-day point is is that it's cold and Even though other people say climate change is bad.
Speaker 0: I feel like I want to burn more coal until it's you know 80-degrees every day.
Speaker 1: He's called.
Speaker 1: they want their stand-up routine bad.
Speaker 0: I'm just saying I want it's cold.
Speaker 1: I'm not happy but I can say that because I ski.
Speaker 1: so I thought I'd like the Nuances of weather like yeah, we should burn coal until no one can ski anymore.
Speaker 0: Well actually save lives even though the the the bad weather will kill some people.
Speaker 1: I think the bad weather already kills more people than skiing ever has key.
Speaker 0: people will not be able to ski and will does be saved.
Speaker 1: Plus we can ski indoors.
Speaker 1: They're skiing in Dubai.
Speaker 0: That's safer than Skiing on a mountain?
Speaker 1: probably not because no there's no trees and rocks and indoor skiing Yeah, but indoor skiing is pretty much only people who don't know how to ski which is the primary source of ski injuries.
Speaker 1: People who don't know how to ski skiing.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm, but So it got crazy hot.
Speaker 1: but oh, yes, I was getting my wasn't crazy hot.
Speaker 0: It was slightly chilly relative slightly chilly.
Speaker 0: It was 79 degrees slightly chilly.
Speaker 1: I think you've just turned into an old man.
Speaker 1: I think you're permanently there.
Speaker 1: You're your old man thermal when you're.
Speaker 1: what are you gonna do when you're 90?
Speaker 1: It has to be like a hundred and ten or you're freezing putting on a sweater.
Speaker 0: Well, all the people who are currently in Florida who are no good will be dead because I'm younger than them.
Speaker 0: So now I can move to Florida and perfectly fine.
Speaker 0: But Florida will know all the Florida men will be dead by then.
Speaker 1: if I fly in Florida will suddenly be a good place And I fly out west or go way north.
Speaker 1: I can just ski.
Speaker 1: It doesn't really matter.
Speaker 1: but in terms of like upstate New York, Vermont, New Hampshire skiing The difference of even a couple degrees a month like a month and a half or so in either direction drastically changes everything.
Speaker 1: and I can definitely say that the last three years have been very difficult ski seasons because we're just over that threshold for at least like Upstate New York and edging into parts of New Hampshire in Vermont.
Speaker 0: No, I don't give a shit is good for me For now till New York floods Inflated today.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I was fine.
Speaker 0: I'm on the third floor.
Speaker 1: the funniest thing about that is that I got the alert and of course my phone doesn't make noise because I'm an adult but Pretty much.
Speaker 1: I'm on this floor with like thousand plus other people so all morning Every like five minutes someone's phone would make that D Emergency alert sound and then you get this scattered delay as one by one.
Speaker 1: Everyone's phone makes the noise.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm I think the only person on earth or just keeps their phone always in vibrate mode no matter what when there's a Another when there's a real emergency that actually warrants the use of that system.
Speaker 0: then what's gonna happen?
Speaker 0: It'll vibrate and I'll know cuz I knew anyway I'm it on your floor of a thousand people.
Speaker 0: It'll go D D the same thing and then everyone looks at their phone and then what?
Speaker 1: and then they do whatever.
Speaker 1: Whatever the thing says so far all the things said was parts of Queens.
Speaker 1: They don't care about flooded.
Speaker 1: Stay off the stay off the highways on the edges of Manhattan.
Speaker 0: Yeah, what's it gonna say when I live in Manhattan surrounded by fire?
Speaker 1: I feel like at that point.
Speaker 1: I'm already on my bike with the rabbits in a backpack like making my way out of town.
Speaker 0: You're not You're.
Speaker 0: you're not gonna make it through.
Speaker 1: the firewall depends on how high that firewall is.
Speaker 1: the Staten Island Bridge is pretty high.
Speaker 1: the Arizona Narrows.
Speaker 0: You're on Manhattan and you're inside the fire ring.
Speaker 1: How tall is the fire ring?
Speaker 1: is it over the Queensborough Bridge because if it's not I could walk over the top of the Queensborough Bridge.
Speaker 1: There's a little pad.
Speaker 0: there you get cooked.
Speaker 1: Depends depends on how hot this fire is.
Speaker 0: the bridge is gonna be a nice grill.
Speaker 1: We get some rim egg and cheese or I'll walk through the East River tunnel.
Speaker 1: Fire's not in there and outside.
Speaker 0: That's a good idea.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you'll get I got plans for everything.
Speaker 1: Yeah Scott has a pretty good news.
Speaker 0: What's all my news?
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, so we talked about a lot about Internet of things and how.
Speaker 0: you know, there's a lot of terms going on these days like cloud and Internet of Things.
Speaker 0: Yeah we also have a cloud.
Speaker 0: actually just means someone else's computer.
Speaker 0: if you ever see an article with the use of the word cloud.
Speaker 0: a lot.
Speaker 0: replace every instance of cloud with Someone else's computer and it will make perfect sense.
Speaker 0: That's all.
Speaker 0: cloud is right.
Speaker 0: Internet of Things simply means Thing that doesn't look like a computer.
Speaker 0: That is a computer.
Speaker 0: Yep, for example, if you have one of those refrigerators with a screen on it and whatever guess what that refrigerator is a computer and If it happens to connect to the internet There's a lot of computers that don't connect to the internet right like your car is a computer or
Speaker 1: like the computer in Mission Impossible One
Speaker 0: right is a computer doesn't connect to the internet.
Speaker 0: But if you have a computer in a thing that normally doesn't look like a computer But it connects to the internet now you have Internet of Things.
Speaker 0: right computers hidden in places You didn't know
Speaker 1: usually gets a little more nuanced and that almost now I'd say 99% of the time people specifically mean Something that does a physical thing in the real world like tracks the food in your fridge or lets you turn off a light.
Speaker 0: Right, but you know, it's a smart TV is Internet of Things.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's it's a computer That's that's your TV now has a computer attached to it hidden inside.
Speaker 1: because as a technology professional What Internet of Things means to me is that thing does not get updates, right?
Speaker 0: It's basically a device.
Speaker 0: right and this is the main problem with them is you have basically full-on computers.
Speaker 0: They got CPUs.
Speaker 0: They got RAM.
Speaker 1: They're connected to your Wi-Fi.
Speaker 0: probably really as long as you have a CPU RAM and a network card That's enough.
Speaker 0: Yeah that to do damage and a power source.
Speaker 0: That's enough to do damage.
Speaker 0: Yeah, any CPU with RAM and a network card can now do evil.
Speaker 0: it can send spam emails.
Speaker 0: It can attempt to hack other computers.
Speaker 1: It could turn your light switch on and off again so rapidly that it literally starts a fire in your house.
Speaker 0: It gets.
Speaker 0: try to send SSH, you know Connections.
Speaker 0: it can do anything that a CPU can do which is all the things.
Speaker 0: well.
Speaker 1: So if you do anything that can be accomplished by some combination of adding ones and zeros together, right?
Speaker 0: So like those fancy thermostats people have or what else?
Speaker 1: The secure those malware mail me one Bitcoin or the temperature was up by one degree per hour.
Speaker 1: the garage door openers with Wi-Fi They only one Bitcoin or I break your car right.
Speaker 0: all these sorts of devices that have an internet connection in a CPU and RAM hidden in them are Computers that are not being properly taken care of.
Speaker 0: the people who have them don't recognize them as computers and if you connect them To the Internet somebody can Hijack them connect to them use them in ways.
Speaker 0: They weren't intended to be used.
Speaker 0: You know your garage, you're literally not even a joke.
Speaker 0: your garage door opener could be made to like send spams or Host child porn on its meager storage or who knows what yep mine mine bitcoins.
Speaker 1: So there's a concept that's a little deeper than a firewall because a firewall is just some rules around the network traffic.
Speaker 1: But the computer on the other side is still connected to the network Like it's.
Speaker 1: still two people are connecting to it effectively directly to do stuff Unless you have a fancy like layer 7 firewall.
Speaker 1: But the air gap is an important concept in IT security.
Speaker 1: if something is so important that Like it's serious like capital s serious Usually those are systems that are not connected to the internet at all.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: There is no path There is no IP anywhere that will get between that computer and the internet.
Speaker 0: yep, like in our IT we had this.
Speaker 0: I took a computer security class and You nothing.
Speaker 0: in that lab in that room there's a bunch of racks and a whole bunch of tables with like patches on them and All these desktops in there in that room at all the at all the desks.
Speaker 0: Oh, but there was no internet connection in that room.
Speaker 0: if we wanted to bring software into the room We had to go outside with a USB stick load it up bring it in USB stick son.
Speaker 1: I used a zip disk for that.
Speaker 0: I used USB sticks because it was 2004 or whatever it was.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I was.
Speaker 1: I took that.
Speaker 1: collect the collect the equivalent class in 2000.
Speaker 0: Yeah The point is we had to bring software from the outside, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah It's like the Mission Impossible computer or say the computer that already a lot of times you just bring laptops in Already loaded and put like the computer that launches nukes.
Speaker 1: even if you have the best internet security and firewalls on earth It's probably safer to just not actually have a connection to it.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so I you know, usually practically speaking this usually comes up in casual conversation because I can tell people hey You shouldn't be getting those, you know boxes, you know connected to your TV.
Speaker 0: You should be getting an HD PC that you can update and has real software You should not be getting.
Speaker 0: if you have a smart TV Don't connect it to the internet and don't use any of the smart features get an HD PC, right?
Speaker 0: This is the usual conversation we have because I'm talking about the insecurity of internet of things stuff.
Speaker 0: Right because those you know that you're not getting software updates.
Speaker 0: You don't know what the hell software is on there.
Speaker 0: You've connected it to your network.
Speaker 0: You're putting everything at risk connecting some strange computer to your network.
Speaker 0: But here we go We have a real story.
Speaker 0: This really happened.
Speaker 0: It's not sci-fi.
Speaker 0: It's not some example.
Speaker 0: Well, it is an example.
Speaker 0: It's a real example.
Speaker 0: this thing actually fucking happened.
Speaker 0: some casino Had in the fish tank that was at the front of the casino as a decoration because you know casinos got fancy decorations.
Speaker 0: Yeah, a internet controlled thermometer thermostat thing to control and monitor the temperature in the fish tank.
Speaker 0: But this wasn't just a thermometer like mercury and a stick.
Speaker 0: it was a computer with an internet connection that connected to where the Wi-Fi.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right.
Speaker 0: You just don't think of it as a computer.
Speaker 0: You just you know, you think of it as fucking thermometer.
Speaker 0: So, of course somebody hijacked that and now that's a computer that was on the casinos computer network And they went in through that very insecure thermostat connected to the casinos other computers that had real things.
Speaker 1: I didn't look up the details of this particular Thermostat but generally the reason why these are never things things are so dangerous and even these contacts is that you connect it to your Internal network, but it's not directly accessible from the outside kind of like with Skype back in the day.
Speaker 1: These these Internet of Things devices have to work when idiots are involved.
Speaker 1: So they are good at net busting and getting out to the internet to connect to some server somewhere To do their biz.
Speaker 0: a lot of them are like these, you know, like for example the NAS I have you know Synology, yeah, it's like it connects to like this Synology stuff That's way out on the real internet like to help you if you don't know how to do land stuff in your house.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that shit's all turned off on mine.
Speaker 0: Yeah, exactly It's like you can go to find that Synology calm and then it helps you.
Speaker 0: that thing That's on the real internet helps you find something on your land.
Speaker 0: It's like no no land only We're not having my NAS that's on my local network.
Speaker 0: Talk to anything else outside.
Speaker 0: So people will install these Internet of Things things on an internal secure network like web like someone will set up a webcam Those the worst security webcam and then in order to see what the webcam sees you go to a website.
Speaker 0: That's on the public internet and now everyone can see everything that's it going on.
Speaker 0: Yes, and even you didn't open as opposed to connecting directly to it from you know, wherever you are.
Speaker 1: Yep So if anything on that server that web thing that's letting this webcam do its thing is compromised at all You can get into the webcam and do whatever on the internal network.
Speaker 0: someone used this thermometer.
Speaker 0: They hijacked at that and then now they're on that.
Speaker 0: they had a connection.
Speaker 0: They were able to browse the casinos internal computer network and they found a database that was not so secure and that database had all Info about all the high rollers in the casinos.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Okay, this is fun stuff.
Speaker 1: now this is not the crazier exploits that people in talking about about using To get at completely air gap systems meaning has nothing to do with it now, but that's a similar but more Interesting story.
Speaker 0: there are ways, you know, depending on what's going on You can try to hack into systems that aren't connected to the internet, but it's extremely difficult.
Speaker 0: Yeah point is There are things that are computers.
Speaker 0: You need to be able to recognize what is and what is not a computer and in the future Everything is a computer.
Speaker 0: if something is a computer do not put it on your network unless you have somehow separated it or something and Make sure you you know don't let it connect it if it doesn't have to.
Speaker 0: you can get one of those internet connectable garage door openers and never Connect it to the internet and just open your enclosure garage door without any Wi-Fi.
Speaker 1: yep, or if you're gonna use its internet stuff at least put it on a Segregated Wi-Fi network that doesn't have any access to the rest of your network.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and then it's like, okay.
Speaker 0: Well, here's this thing on its own this smart TV.
Speaker 0: It might start sending spam to the internet and does whatever.
Speaker 0: the worst it can do is use my bandwidth.
Speaker 0: It can't hurt anything any of my other real computers or anything.
Speaker 0: It's all on its own.
Speaker 0: It might as well have its own private internet connection that it shares with nothing else.
Speaker 0: And if it becomes horrible and using my bandwidth then I'll disconnect it and I can take advantage of its features in the meantime.
Speaker 0: So in some other news, but ideally just don't connect it in the first place you want the problem.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: So in some other news, I just saw this story.
Speaker 1: I remember seeing some rumblings about this and it's kind of interesting.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna summarize to.
Speaker 1: the details are pretty technical and they rely on some understanding of the plain old Television set like the plain old television the plain old telephony networks like old phone pots.
Speaker 1: Yeah pots.
Speaker 1: so basically the way phones like phone calls work in the US is actually very well defined and modern internet-based telephony largely fakes a lot of that stuff or Translates between that stuff.
Speaker 1: So like for example in the old days if you picked up a phone and by the old days I mean like the 90s and you called someone on the phone Like you picked up a landline if you've ever seen one of those people and yet rotary dialed something.
Speaker 1: Whoa, I had a read a rotary dial when I was a kid.
Speaker 0: We're talking 90s, all right, you had a Phineas's key modem and you do dialed someone 80.
Speaker 1: Yep right so The ringing sound you hear in the phone actually means like that is a part of the SLA of the phone network that the Destination phone is ringing.
Speaker 0: I thought the destination phone was actually making those noises and sending them over the phone line to you.
Speaker 1: Uh I'm pretty sure that was.
Speaker 0: you call different places.
Speaker 0: You heard different rings based on what phone they had.
Speaker 1: pretty sure that wasn't actually true in the 90s.
Speaker 1: but I'm not actually that familiar with the previous iterations of the phone like
Speaker 0: that like when the person picks up the phone they start talking and You hear and their voice gets sent over the line But before then the phone that has now received a call is and ringing out loud is also sending ringing noise.
Speaker 0: What's crazy line to you.
Speaker 1: is my freshman year wrong, but that's what I thought my freshman year.
Speaker 1: at RIT I actually took a whole class on this stuff and I mostly forgot it all because it's literally irrelevant to the modern world.
Speaker 0: Yeah, unless you're setting up an asterisk server Which you're not.
Speaker 1: but like the sound that a phone makes when you try to call someone in the phone is busy Like that.
Speaker 1: DDD like all those things are very well-defined and there's rules about them and more importantly there's laws about them.
Speaker 1: Yep So this story is fascinating and I'm only gonna skim the details because partly there's a broader story.
Speaker 1: I want to talk about the rough story here.
Speaker 1: Is that t-mobile was caught Faking the ring?
Speaker 1: sounds that come back.
Speaker 0: Why would you want to fake the ring sound?
Speaker 1: because the old phone network the hyper?
Speaker 1: reliable phone network with all those mechanical relays and everything.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: It's really expensive to run and Really really really expensive to run in Shit-ass rural burg like a middle-of-nowhere, Arizona, right?
Speaker 0: But it's still there.
Speaker 0: You could just you connect someone to it.
Speaker 0: What's a big degree?
Speaker 0: But there's a lot of things going on For it, whoever's whoever's in that area pays.
Speaker 1: So part of the reason that worked is there was a limited number of phone companies and the infrastructure is relatively simple And they all sort of followed the same rules, but in the modern world of the Internet there's a lot of ways to connect calls.
Speaker 1: most people are using cell phones exclusively and It might just be that a cell phone trying to make a call Going through all these different networks that are run by all these different private companies Might time out or otherwise not make it to some shit-ass rural phone somewhere that still has some old physical infrastructure.
Speaker 0: So rather than I don't know every time I've called the landline it works.
Speaker 1: Uh I'm trying to think of the last time I call the landline.
Speaker 1: that wasn't like an 800.
Speaker 0: you live in a farm in the sticks and you have a telephone.
Speaker 0: let us know we'll try to call you.
Speaker 0: We will both try to call you first come first serve Like you need to be in the way.
Speaker 0: sticks way.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and you have a landline most in the forum.
Speaker 1: we'll decide if you're sticks enough, yeah, but basically there's a bunch of things going on because a lot of the phone networks in rural areas are selling numbers in those areas to companies that then provide telephony services to other areas because it's way cheaper to connect or The air.
Speaker 1: the infrastructure those phone numbers run on is subsidized by old federal nonsense.
Speaker 1: so that's why you can go to all these services and pay like 20 bucks a month and get as many 888 numbers as you want and just like route calls everywhere All right.
Speaker 1: But what this means is this is a lot of the SLA of the phone network is starting to fail.
Speaker 0: still haven't explained why t-mobile Would fake the ringing noise.
Speaker 0: what is what is t-mobile?
Speaker 1: give a shit because t-mobile tries to connect to some destination.
Speaker 0: All right, so I have t-mobile phone and I'm in New York City with my t-mobile smartphone.
Speaker 0: So I'm a t-mobile iPhone and I call.
Speaker 0: the person who lives in the sticks is listening to this show.
Speaker 0: So why does t-mobile give a shit just connect the call?
Speaker 0: So yeah, why would you fake the ringing noise?
Speaker 1: so they're trying to connect the call but the call the the circuit might not actually be open to that destination for a Significant amount of time because of all these complications in the I want to see mobile characters.
Speaker 0: Let me wait.
Speaker 0: So you call you always I'm used to that where you call and like there's a silent noise and you go, huh?
Speaker 0: Why isn't it ringing and eventually it rings.
Speaker 0: that happens?
Speaker 1: Yeah, so the it might have been too long or they didn't want to worry about it.
Speaker 1: It was much easier to just always start playing a ringtone back at whoever called Well separately.
Speaker 1: you're trying to connect.
Speaker 0: Okay, why would you do that?
Speaker 1: I'm not t-mobile.
Speaker 0: like the person let the person wait one.
Speaker 0: I don't understand the benefit to t-mobile.
Speaker 1: if I try to call anyone and I don't hear a ring like right away I just hang up.
Speaker 1: I just give up.
Speaker 0: and what is t-mobile should like that?
Speaker 0: Yeah, why don't I send the benefit to t-mobile of?
Speaker 1: Mobile, I don't know why they went down.
Speaker 0: Well, that's key to understanding the story because that's the thing they did.
Speaker 0: that was supposedly bad But I don't know why.
Speaker 0: what benefit they get from doing it?
Speaker 1: partly?
Speaker 1: I think it was just to simplify their own infrastructure by not having to track all the way to the end destination if you made it there and when that phone actually started ringing before you come all the way back and play a specific SLA based ringtone on the other
Speaker 0: feel like that's how just the phone system would work by default and you have to do extra Work to me.
Speaker 0: No, it's now again.
Speaker 1: It's that's not how it works anymore.
Speaker 1: It's way more complicated than it used to be and frankly that SLA is probably fundamentally obsolete, but it's still regulated.
Speaker 1: It's still part of the FCC rules.
Speaker 1: The rules about how phones work are very strict
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm,
Speaker 1: and the meta point I want to make is that I think the reason it took so long That for anyone even notice or do anything about this is that most people your cell phones don't give a fuck and rarely if ever Make phone calls.
Speaker 1: Yes, and when they do they're almost always calling someone else who's also on a cell phone.
Speaker 1: So the reason why this issue made it as long as it did is partly that people like us don't call people.
Speaker 1: And if we do call people I use modern technology like the internet and I don't try to call a landline Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: I don't think the sticks.
Speaker 1: I don't think I've tried to call a landline in a decade.
Speaker 0: I've called my mom's phone, which is a landline.
Speaker 0: My mom doesn't have a landline.
Speaker 0: My mom does.
Speaker 1: No relative of mine has a landline.
Speaker 0: Even though it is a landline.
Speaker 0: I think it is provided by the cable company.
Speaker 0: So I think technically it's like a VoIP phone that just has the phone number Of the former landline that was in the house And I think it might even use the landline in the house like it connects to it.
Speaker 0: But I think that I could get a landline, but I think that basically it's like it's like an old.
Speaker 0: It's like an old-school phone with an old-school landline wire.
Speaker 0: But then when you get outside to where the connection is actually it's can that you know that old?
Speaker 0: It's cooking up to some sort of VoIP transceiver.
Speaker 1: Well, yeah, I mean I got an rj11 I could just use and it plugs into my files box.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's something like that, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think that's what it is where it's.
Speaker 0: it's a landline, but it's not really so.
Speaker 1: this is a kind of complicated story And you can read the article if you're really interested in the details.
Speaker 1: But basically t-mobile is getting fined a pittance for this.
Speaker 1: and this is the other meta story the FCC Because American politics is completely fucked right now.
Speaker 0: The FCC is just basically the worst.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but they're even worse now Because they're controlled by the Republican Party, which is the bad party in the US.
Speaker 1: So the Democrats actually wanted to take much more aggressive action to deal with the fundamental problem of Phone companies are ignoring most of America.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm, at least bland wise.
Speaker 1: Yep, and kind of like the post office We need to provide basic connectivity services to everywhere people live regardless of how economically viable.
Speaker 0: I mean FCC are not Democrat or Republican or not.
Speaker 0: Show me a time where a company was actually fined and a major company was fined and punished.
Speaker 0: An actual significant amount like they should be.
Speaker 0: I can only think of like a few handful.
Speaker 0: So these are completely breaking up AT&T.
Speaker 0: Yeah, these Right There's not a lot of them, right?
Speaker 0: There's not a lot of times when companies have actually been punished a proportionate amount, but in this case in particular The Democrats.
Speaker 1: because basically the Minority on this because the Republicans are in power so they get the majority meaning they can literally do whatever they want Ignoring the Democrats.
Speaker 1: so they basically did this like minimum fine and are just sort of ignoring the issue.
Speaker 0: Yeah I don't even understand the point of having the two opposing people there just so they can say what they is as the Democrat.
Speaker 0: It's like.
Speaker 0: it's basically just so you can let everyone know that it's bullshit.
Speaker 0: And I guess occasionally when you agree and you vote it's just symbolic, right?
Speaker 0: It's sort of like.
Speaker 0: well, you can see.
Speaker 0: well, we disagree and all voted.
Speaker 0: Yes, so clearly.
Speaker 0: this is good.
Speaker 1: This is a pretty recent phenomenon and all these committees where previously There would more often than you would expect be some sort of compromise or they'd argue behind closed doors And then they just present like they'd vote unanimously or close.
Speaker 0: I'm pretty sure I remember when they were doing all this stuff during the Obama times.
Speaker 0: It was usually three to all the time.
Speaker 1: Also, it depends It's gotten to the point that it is the rule as opposed to the exception in the last year.
Speaker 1: But basically the Democrat made a good point that this affected billions of telephone calls to rural areas over the last several years and is a quote massively deceptive and harmful violation.
Speaker 1: and The FCC will net will not even look at changing these rules will not even look at updating like basic connectivity services.
Speaker 1: I mean I would argue that broadband connectivity to these rural areas should be a right way more important than plain old telephone nonsense.
Speaker 0: I mean, yeah.
Speaker 0: I mean also if I was in charge of the world anytime anyone got fined for anything the fine would always be Proportional to their means and significance.
Speaker 0: So if like you're a poor person and you know the iron monkey strategy Yeah, if you're a poor person you do some crime like littering I'd be like one dollar fine and they'd be like no God damn it.
Speaker 0: I can't.
Speaker 0: they'd be pissed off.
Speaker 0: There's like a whole.
Speaker 0: it's a big deal, right.
Speaker 0: and if Bill Gates litters Fucking hundred million dollar fine go fuck yourself Bill Gates Same littering but it has to be an amount where he like he'll be like, ah shit, right?
Speaker 0: So 40 million dollars t-mobile doesn't even give a shit, right?
Speaker 0: If you find any company ever it has to be enough to make their stock go down and people sell off.
Speaker 0: That's the only because that's the only way the CEO will be hurt.
Speaker 0: right is that the stock has to go down significantly.
Speaker 0: So what it's like what's t-mobile's like total worth like some billions 25% of your worth.
Speaker 0: here's one minimum.
Speaker 1: This is probably the first time where I'm gonna go beyond you So you're gonna find him even harder.
Speaker 1: So I generally Ideologically disagree with the death penalty for basic for criminal law.
Speaker 1: Yeah I Don't want to get into the details of that argument that discussion mean death penalty for a company?
Speaker 0: sure But I mean don't think you give t-mobile the death penalty if it is.
Speaker 1: Oh, no, but I'm saying if there is a death penalty for humans Irrespective of whether or not.
Speaker 1: that is the right thing to have if it exists and Corporations are ostensibly treated like humans for many purposes.
Speaker 1: Then there should also be a death penalty for corporations.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but this isn't.
Speaker 0: this isn't bad enough to warn the death penalty for t-mobile, but there are many corporations For example, I don't know any company that like poisons a river.
Speaker 0: It's like yeah Yeah I think not only should you give the death penalty but all the executives should go to real jail.
Speaker 1: But the other sort of a more subtle point to think about is that whenever you're building new things?
Speaker 1: It is important that the people who are building the new thing at least someone building the new thing Understands what the old thing they're replacing did and why it did what I what it did I think I do.
Speaker 0: they just don't give a shit.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 0: It's got to also care.
Speaker 1: It is very easy to believe that Having the ringtone just play through a cell phone was just some engineer saying well that makes sense.
Speaker 1: I'm not thinking about this like physical relay connected to some copper in Oklahoma saying is like an open DNS Thing.
Speaker 0: or the people who may go up in DNS don't care how DNS is supposed to work.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and they don't send you an NX for a non-existing domain.
Speaker 0: They send you some other bullshit.
Speaker 1: I wonder if the open DNS people are still mad at us for saying that they are naive.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: open DNS is like a big thing now, but I know We are.
Speaker 1: the ship of Well-formed DNS sailed and we lost that fight a long time ago.
Speaker 0: No, I'm actually.
Speaker 0: everyone else provides well-formed DNS.
Speaker 1: Yeah Well, so the T the TLDs Expansion has started to pollute the core idea of a tree.
Speaker 1: But anyway, I digress but anyway things of the day.
Speaker 1: So the Nintendo switch is very important because this is the first mainstream console I have bought myself to play games on since the 3ds and Before that was the DS and before that was Scott and I shared that gamikube that Scott bought and before that it was the SNES.
Speaker 1: Like I I was very disengaged from consoles for a long time.
Speaker 1: The switch is amazing.
Speaker 1: However, this video is living proof that even a great console Pales in comparison to the same experience on a PC Can mod it and mess with it.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm I mean pub G. the latest and greatest craze is a mod just like counter-strike was yep And you can't mod anything on switch, right?
Speaker 0: Imagine if you could mod Zelda for reals.
Speaker 0: What kind of all these like?
Speaker 0: imagine what games would emerge, right?
Speaker 1: That would be the next pub G which is not only a mod mashup of Breath of the Wild with I think the shot.
Speaker 0: I mean.
Speaker 0: look at the randomize just people make because they can mod, you know The SNES games you can't mod switch games.
Speaker 1: But I think the genre of what is mashed up here is called weird shit rims into a man.
Speaker 0: one day They're gonna have you know Like in the way the decade or so we're gonna have mods of switch Zelda and they're gonna do a randomizer.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, so Breath of the Wild randomizer.
Speaker 1: Oh my god I look.
Speaker 1: I await the day where I can watch a Breath of the Wild where the very important item is just in some random Ass cave.
Speaker 0: It's like oh that Korok seed.
Speaker 0: Actually, that was the key item.
Speaker 0: That was Gannon.
Speaker 1: Yeah, Gannon is just hiding there.
Speaker 0: Oh Triforce.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so yeah, but also it's worth noting that the song on this thing of the day Might be one of my favorite songs.
Speaker 0: Okay Well, let me talk to you about another song on the Wu Tang album return to the 36th chamber sung by the deceased old dirty bastard known as shimmy shimmy.
Speaker 0: ah Here is an excellent perhaps better than the original rendition of this song by one of my favorite people mum, rah the everliving I'm like old dirty bastard is Everliving.
Speaker 0: this is just too and also is also and like old dirty bastard is old dirty And a bastard.
Speaker 1: I uh, I also legit like this Rendition of this song and it gives me a feel.
Speaker 0: I don't think you know the original rendition of this song.
Speaker 1: I don't know Wu Tang.
Speaker 1: that well, okay.
Speaker 0: Can you name more than one Wu Tang member that I already named?
Speaker 1: Nope Okay, just so we put that in terms of rims music in that in that in that that area of music like things I enjoy I knew the Wu Tang clan existed.
Speaker 1: All right, and when as someone has pointed out, that's a Wu Tang song I've usually thought oh, that's a pretty good song.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there's a reason they famous.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's about as far as they got.
Speaker 1: I do want to hear the The album that we don't know we can't hear yet.
Speaker 0: well Have you listened to the eco, why are you so you're so interested in listening to this unobtainable Wu Tang album?
Speaker 0: Do you realize there are Wu Tang albums?
Speaker 0: You could already listen.
Speaker 1: If you look at my sonos history, I was listening to a bunch of Wu Tang clan a couple weeks ago.
Speaker 1: I don't know names of songs off the top of my head.
Speaker 0: You don't know The classic in the meta moment.
Speaker 1: the book club book is the Odyssey by Homer.
Speaker 0: I'm not working next week So I'll probably be going on an Odyssey.
Speaker 0: So I've gone on quite an Odyssey already and also it's shorter than I thought.
Speaker 0: I just stopped reading it.
Speaker 1: So she got to Odysseus, right?
Speaker 1: Are you still a Telemachus?
Speaker 0: I just got to Odysseus.
Speaker 0: Okay, he's on the island.
Speaker 0: He's on the island.
Speaker 0: I think he's building a raft and making his move.
Speaker 1: Okay, so Hermes came was like yo, you got to let this guy go.
Speaker 1: stop Stop having amazing goddess sex with him every single night.
Speaker 0: I don't know why she doesn't have amazing goddess sex with like Hermes.
Speaker 0: who's a god right there.
Speaker 1: my one of my favorite And Hermes wouldn't say no in the Odyssey is when Hermes is like god.
Speaker 1: damn it cuz Zeus is like Hermes.
Speaker 1: go deal with this.
Speaker 1: He's like.
Speaker 1: and then he goes and even he is like, whoa this island Whoa, he literally goes from Olympus to this island.
Speaker 0: I mean Olympus isn't that great.
Speaker 0: That's the thing, right?
Speaker 0: Olympus is not like fuck it in paradise.
Speaker 0: It's the top of a mountain.
Speaker 1: It's fucking cold Yeah, but it's still opulent full of splendor.
Speaker 0: It's better than man meat world or Hades, but it's not.
Speaker 0: it's not as good as fucking.
Speaker 0: you know Whatever the name of that island is.
Speaker 1: But yeah, so we'll.
Speaker 1: uh, this is the book club.
Speaker 1: you should read it.
Speaker 1: it's amazing.
Speaker 1: Emily Wilson did a fantastic job Translating this in a way to where reading it feels like just reading a story and enjoying it for what it is Without having to parse through somewhat archaic language.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: No what they didn't write it, you know a lot of people Intentionally write in old-timey ways and she pointed out like, you know These people make an English translation and they write it with like ye old choppy talk.
Speaker 1: Yeah, ye old choppy talk isn't any closer, right?
Speaker 0: The whole Greek fake old English is only like a couple hundred, you know, even if that's how they spoke Yeah, which they didn't and that would only be like 200 years ago.
Speaker 0: Whereas Homer Odyssey is BC You're not.
Speaker 0: it's like you Predates the Greek it predates the idea of English it predates Greece.
Speaker 1: So this is some like there's.
Speaker 0: no there is no point in using old-fashioned sounding language, right?
Speaker 0: It's not that much closer.
Speaker 1: Yeah, at least Shakespeare is a product of its time.
Speaker 0: Yeah, Shakespeare that's is how Shakespeare, you know wrote plays.
Speaker 0: that might not be how they talked but that's how they wrote plays.
Speaker 0: There's the actual words that Shakespeare wrote.
Speaker 0: Shakespeare was a person most likely we know.
Speaker 1: so if you're listening We know more about Shakespeare.
Speaker 1: They know about Homer because you saw us at PAX East because somehow our morning panel And you're confused that we haven't even mentioned games yet filled the room which it did eventually fill the room.
Speaker 1: They turned people away.
Speaker 0: They feel that's awesome.
Speaker 0: empty seats.
Speaker 0: Yes, I believe in.
Speaker 1: they were smart Yeah, but they're also a ton of people.
Speaker 0: stay like if you listen to the stream not smart.
Speaker 0: They should learn from the people who left.
Speaker 1: But if you wanted that list of games you saw us and now you don't wonder why we're talking about Linux and all this nonsense.
Speaker 1: Well, guess what geek nights is four nights Mondays our technology and Linux and stuff You probably don't care about.
Speaker 1: Tuesdays is where you're want to listen and not not tomorrow.
Speaker 0: Tuesday.
Speaker 0: You're gonna have to wait a whole week and maybe even not even then because I'm not working.
Speaker 0: Who knows if I'll be in the mood to make a podcast?
Speaker 1: Yeah, we're on a minor hiatus But while geek nights is coming in and out while we're sort of getting our shit together because Scott and I have both made Significant life changes recently and there's a lot we got to deal with.
Speaker 1: but We are doubling down on the YouTube content because once we do pre-production Scott and I can go our separate ways and crank it out.
Speaker 0: Yeah, thanks to my new computer.
Speaker 0: I was able to make a video with much greater ease than usual.
Speaker 0: So we have and my video skills increase slightly each time I make a video, you know, what really helped you out?
Speaker 0: I don't need the knob.
Speaker 0: The knob is not necessarily really underestimate the power of this knob.
Speaker 0: I did not at any point feel that I had the need for a knob.
Speaker 1: You never wanted to just move something one frame before you did your thing to it.
Speaker 1: No, I don't even use my keyboard just a mouse and knob and I can do almost everything.
Speaker 1: It's amazing.
Speaker 0: I used I learned the keyboard shortcuts.
Speaker 1: Yeah, my keyboard shortcut.
Speaker 1: This does more than I got a shuttle and I got a. well anyway, I have a mouse wheel.
Speaker 0: I'm a mouse.
Speaker 0: Yeah mouse left and right arrows and not enough if I hold shift and push the left and right as it goes even faster.
Speaker 0: Then I have markers so I can just push up and down and go Turn this shuttle and the speed just varies.
Speaker 1: in an analog fashion.
Speaker 0: I can just push the up and down or to go to exact spot.
Speaker 0: I need to go.
Speaker 1: Uh, your timeline is much simpler.
Speaker 1: You want me to send you what.
Speaker 1: what a geek knives presents.
Speaker 1: your tenant project looks like The like nested sequence upon nested sequence and templates everywhere.
Speaker 0: I think I'm good.
Speaker 1: but anyway So our video judging and reviewing all of the anime that's coming out in the spring.
Speaker 0: So we have not yet watched the spring season.
Speaker 0: that has already begun.
Speaker 1: We already reviewed it all and the video is on YouTube.
Speaker 0: We previewed it.
Speaker 1: Oh, we reviewed it.
Speaker 1: Sure.
Speaker 1: We're rarely wrong Even though we don't.
Speaker 1: it seems like we don't know how all that persona nonsense is linked together.
Speaker 1: now I do but I don't think the persona fans even really understand.
Speaker 0: No, they explained it to me that it's like if they're correct I'm trusting them.
Speaker 0: Yeah that it's sort of like Final Fantasy where it's not linked together.
Speaker 0: They just all have the sort of like some similar themes like all the Final Fantasy of chocobos.
Speaker 0: Final Fantasy 10 is nothing to do with Final Fantasy 6 other than they both have chocobos or Boogles or whatever, right?
Speaker 0: So personas like that, which is actually good news because I was basically avoiding persona completely because I thought it was all connected.
Speaker 0: But now I realize I could just go to any fucking persona thing.
Speaker 0: I don't have to give a shit and maybe that actually makes me more likely to check one out.
Speaker 1: I watched a let's play like partially of persona for like just a little bit of it Like.
Speaker 1: I feel like we could enjoy that.
Speaker 0: I mean, I think it's basically just an RPG that looks like an anime, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, yeah Yeah, so I feel like we should play Yakuza games before we play this.
Speaker 0: share whatever.
Speaker 1: But the other video that's on YouTube is that panel the 40 tabletop games you need to play from PAX East 2018 in Glorious 2k.
Speaker 1: Well, you don't need 4k when it's just us day.
Speaker 0: I only did 1080p is cuz.
Speaker 0: I'm like I'm gonna shit.
Speaker 0: I didn't know why my face in 4k.
Speaker 1: You know why I do 2k.
Speaker 0: I recorded it in.
Speaker 0: 4k is but I put it out into 10.
Speaker 1: I do 2k cuz.
Speaker 1: I did some zooms plus.
Speaker 0: none of the other content other than the image of our face was 4k resolution.
Speaker 0: So it would be kind of silly but
Speaker 1: I did it because When I'm doing the picture in picture like when we're talking the slides down here and when the slides up we're down here It means if someone does have a nice monitor that little area will be like 1080p or at least 720p depending on how big.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah Because your cut that content was 1080p to be exactly.
Speaker 0: none of the images of anime that I had were 1080p.
Speaker 1: Yep So it is on YouTube and you can watch it and maybe you learn a lesson about.
Speaker 1: if you don't go to a geek nights Panel at a con it's probably just gonna be on YouTube later.
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 0: You shouldn't show up and you shouldn't.
Speaker 0: you should basically consume none of our.
Speaker 1: you should tell people Who don't know about our shit to go to the panel?
Speaker 1: so one we don't waste our time talking to people already know who we are and That way you can get them to go there and then they'll see the same panel and you don't have to tell them all the games Or whatever it is.
Speaker 1: We talked about in the panel.
Speaker 0: You just tell them to watch the YouTube video.
Speaker 0: I fast-forward so they can you waste as few time in their life as possible but then they can go play games with that extra time to catch 22.
Speaker 1: because if everyone learns that lesson and No one goes to our panels Then we'll have to do order into these anime panels because we don't go to anime cows anymore and record them in our houses Which is way less fun and doesn't get us free badges to conventions.
Speaker 0: I'll just move forth.
Speaker 1: We're gonna get to I. we're gonna do a point in the future to where No one goes to panels at any convention because they're all on YouTube.
Speaker 1: Good except anime cons because you can't put any of that stuff on YouTube because the content idea immediately takes it down.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so destroying data.
Speaker 1: We talked a lot about backing stuff up.
Speaker 1: I don't think we've talked recently about destroying things.
Speaker 0: Well part of it is that in most cases not all cases, but most cases I find it morally reprehensible to destroy data.
Speaker 1: I keep I have chat logs of every I am conversation I have ever had Since the ICQ days, right?
Speaker 1: I mean if you think every single conversation I've ever had I have the exact conversation when Scott and I talked online for the first time, right?
Speaker 0: So now a lot of people might think like short-term about destroying data, right something like rims chat logs, right?
Speaker 0: And first of all, just cuz you don't destroy the data doesn't mean you have to distribute the data.
Speaker 1: Yeah That's a separate conversation, right?
Speaker 1: But yeah, it's not on the internet.
Speaker 1: I don't even on the cloud.
Speaker 0: I always think about you know, like Library of Alexandria.
Speaker 0: It's like ah, what a shame it was, right?
Speaker 0: So when you delete a file, you know some you started to write something and then it's no good and you delete the file.
Speaker 0: It's like okay That was probably worthless.
Speaker 0: You don't want anyone to see it.
Speaker 1: But one day you'll be dead and just Just Finding my NAS and finding on that NAS the thousands of garbage pictures I took of like New York City and using that as part of their Research into what New York City was like a thousand years ago.
Speaker 0: Even the most worthless data that you have created could be worth something, you know.
Speaker 0: Even something that seems completely like just a text file Could be a work of art or historical artifact or who knows what.
Speaker 0: so I'm usually don't want to delete any data But there are some things it is okay to delete for example child porn.
Speaker 0: delete it all please.
Speaker 0: Faster the better.
Speaker 1: one could make an argument That not deleting.
Speaker 1: it allows AI's expert systems and law enforcement personnel to use the data from it to find.
Speaker 0: Let us not get off topic Let us not get off top.
Speaker 1: just saying there's a project out there where they ask people to take pictures of hotel rooms.
Speaker 1: So Researchers who have the child porn that like the FBI has gotten when they've arrested people They can try to find the kids and rescue them.
Speaker 1: point is just saying Data may have a vet intrinsic value.
Speaker 0: anyway.
Speaker 0: Deleting data is usually bad.
Speaker 0: But sometimes well, there's.
Speaker 0: you do have to delete some data.
Speaker 1: for examples There's two different.
Speaker 1: there's three different levels of deleting data.
Speaker 1: on one There's do you have data that is local that you were trying to destroy so no one ever gets it?
Speaker 1: Versus do you have data that you don't care about preserving necessarily?
Speaker 1: Versus did you publish data and you're trying to unpublish it?
Speaker 0: Well, that's that's not deleting.
Speaker 0: That's unpublishing true true But anyway, okay.
Speaker 0: So the most basic case of deleting data is my phone is running out of room, right?
Speaker 0: So obviously just go to listen to some old episode of one of a hundred episodes of eat nights about backing up Back it up somewhere else and delete it from your phone.
Speaker 0: Now same thing applies on your computer.
Speaker 0: It's like oh, no, my computer's hard drive is full But I need to save this information.
Speaker 0: Put it some buy another hard drive save it somewhere else and then delete it from the place That's full like I keep by pushing the delete key Like I keep.
Speaker 1: every photo I take on my phone goes into Lightroom basically forever.
Speaker 1: They're tiny files.
Speaker 1: They own a Google photo forever.
Speaker 1: because they're tiny files.
Speaker 0: I got it backed up in three clouds.
Speaker 0: Remember cloud means other person's computer and also my NAS and also my computer.
Speaker 0: and what help?
Speaker 1: Cuz I might want that data someday.
Speaker 1: the incremental cost to me of keeping that data Approaches zero on a pearl.
Speaker 0: I like to add them all up together.
Speaker 0: actually it adds up to pennies a month which adds up to dollars which becomes significant.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but the way I preserve that stuff is using mostly free surface anyway anyway.
Speaker 0: So there's that.
Speaker 0: that's normal deleting right?
Speaker 0: You need to.
Speaker 0: you're not actually deleting the data from existence You're just different one.
Speaker 0: you're doing it from one place.
Speaker 0: Okay, so now I've got something I need to actually delete from existence.
Speaker 0: why?
Speaker 0: well I'm selling someone this hard drive, and I've backed everything up.
Speaker 0: I'm not deleting it from existence, but I need to make sure that whoever gets this hard drive can't recover any of that data.
Speaker 1: Yep, and that's mostly what we're talking about right now, right?
Speaker 0: And in that case you need a tool that has existed for a long time.
Speaker 0: that is still probably the best tool Called D band so named after the guy who made it Derek Derek's boot and nuke.
Speaker 0: now it boots and it nukes.
Speaker 1: When I was young I knew this was called D band But I always assumed that stood for something fun.
Speaker 0: when you boot it it says right on the screen Derek's boot and nuke.
Speaker 0: Yep, it's not hiding its name somehow.
Speaker 1: so well the first time.
Speaker 1: I actually had to use it was way back.
Speaker 1: I worked at IBM.
Speaker 0: I didn't know about its RIT, and that's when I used it.
Speaker 1: yeah at RIT I was.
Speaker 1: I was a co-op, and I was working in this department before I got her.
Speaker 1: like a big job there and the thing one of the things I had to do is We had all these servers, and they were like yo Wipe out all these hard drives following these regulations.
Speaker 1: they pointed me at this like government site of like regulations for destroying data and That's your project.
Speaker 1: spend a few months and like get rid of all this data.
Speaker 1: And I was like can I just take the hard drive down to drill pass press?
Speaker 1: and they were like no We're going to reuse the hard drive somewhere mm-hmm, so I did my research and I encountered Derek's boot and nuke and I encountered that it actually did all the things that the regulations said I had to do about Overriding the data with random data a certain number of times to make sure there is no Feasible chance anyone could get that data back
Speaker 0: mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: And I did it.
Speaker 0: a lot of this has to do with the way magnetic hard drives work where even if you like delete files.
Speaker 0: Well all that does is usually if you have to say if you know a normal file system is Delete the pointer to the file in the file system But it's somewhere to actually you know manually control the hard drive and read all the bits.
Speaker 0: all the bits of the file are still There.
Speaker 0: it's just.
Speaker 0: they're not listed in the file system anymore, so they don't show up right.
Speaker 0: so you know It's like even modern file system, but you know also if you do try to delete them or overwrite them a magnetic hard drive It's like well You know it's like this sort of zero.
Speaker 0: you could sort of try to figure out.
Speaker 0: Aha this sector is a zero, but it used to be.
Speaker 1: oh Think of it this way.
Speaker 1: y'all the the analogy I was about to use.
Speaker 0: how does a work?
Speaker 1: I was gonna talk about CRT's, but those are also obsolete yeah, so It's a similar thing though, and that say you have a you know what it's like.
Speaker 1: It's like the aspirin in a couch Sit in the couch for a long time data is just there, and then I get up There's a there's a really minuscule aspirin there so someone with a very high resolution camera could theoretically take a picture of that and
Speaker 0: Figure out who's that.
Speaker 0: figure out they could recreate the ass.
Speaker 1: yep, so think of it like that now.
Speaker 0: in practice This is.
Speaker 0: I've never actually seen a case actually of anyone actually doing that.
Speaker 1: I read a recent paper Showing that it is actually way less feasible Than it used to be because of the density of data on modern magnetic drives.
Speaker 1: Yeah, cuz like back when this was a more feasible attack hard drive had like 500 megabytes on it mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: nowadays I mean I have.
Speaker 1: I have five eight terabyte hard drive sitting up there.
Speaker 1: So also file systems have changed a lot like things have changed so much since the last time I cared about this Mm-hmm that I actually have to do a little bit of research if I actually want to wipe out data on.
Speaker 0: a large D-band still works.
Speaker 0: It's still out there.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's still gonna get the job done.
Speaker 1: I have not used it cuz I haven't actually given anyone.
Speaker 0: Actually heard recently though that D band was like bought by a different company And then yeah There's a fork and then the fork is what you should be using cuz you don't want to pay this company that bought D band.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 1: So I guess they give it this way when you on the high level.
Speaker 1: and the reason I don't go deep again It's just that the details are so specific To circumstance nowadays, and I don't even know what the story is with different kinds of SS.
Speaker 0: The point is this is only good for deleting a whole hard drive.
Speaker 0: usually you booting and nuking right.
Speaker 0: what if say I'm on my computer And I've got you know some files and I committed some crimes?
Speaker 0: But they're good crimes cuz I'm a revolutionary person.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you're Robin Hood, right?
Speaker 0: I'm a good person allow it I'm doing some anti-government work.
Speaker 0: That's actually but my government's evil and they're gonna come and take my computer And I can't have these files on the computer that they're about to that.
Speaker 0: I know they're coming to take so already You're fucked.
Speaker 1: and my argument is modern computers modern file systems.
Speaker 1: there's a lot of collateral change and Circumstantial evidence that appears when you do anything on a computer.
Speaker 1: There's time stamps and there's stuff the file system did all over the place.
Speaker 1: It's pretty likely that no matter what you do to delete something that was previously there Someone could at least figure out that you deleted something.
Speaker 1: Oh, no shit I think that you've although you've already like.
Speaker 1: it's already too late if you're doing that kind of thing All the data that is ever involved in that thing should already be in a separate encrypted store somewhere.
Speaker 0: All right, so I've got a separate encrypted USB stick.
Speaker 1: Yep Okay, deleting the keys to out into decrypt it is the same as deleting the data.
Speaker 1: Yeah, because look at how Modern bit locker style malware works.
Speaker 1: It doesn't delete your files It encrypts them and if it doesn't if it doesn't give you the key to decrypt it the data is gone.
Speaker 1: There's no way to get it back.
Speaker 1: It's.
Speaker 1: it might as well be deleted.
Speaker 1: It's arguably better.
Speaker 0: I mean, it's like this you go to someone's house.
Speaker 0: You put it you replace the lock on their front door You can't get in the house.
Speaker 0: Yeah But you can.
Speaker 0: you're out.
Speaker 0: you can change the lock on their front door or you can actually install another door in front of their Front door that has a lock on it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and that lock is 100% unlockable without the key magic lock.
Speaker 0: It's a perfect magic lock.
Speaker 0: and now you eat the key and you threaten to not poop it out Unless or dissolve it an acid or something unless they give you money.
Speaker 0: So in the modern era like company and now no one can ever get in that house the end You have to smash the house.
Speaker 1: Most companies have some sort of data retention policy and like rules for how they'll delete stuff.
Speaker 1: It seems like a lot of people either don't pay that much attention to what they've documented or They don't worry about it that much.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: And I don't know how much of a concern it really is Because from what I've read the feasibility if you just delete files and Override a hard disk with zeros like do like a DD and just like write zeros over everything on a hard disk I don't know if it's actually feasible for anyone other than a government operator That's well-funded to even attempt to get that data back.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and I don't know like an SSD like what really especially if that drive keeps getting used.
Speaker 0: because thinking if you're doing you know Data retention operations that like a corporation what you're doing is getting rid of old customer data probably, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, you're only keeping it for a certain amount of time and then you're clearing it out, you know, it's like, okay We'll keep your track of your I don't know your all your transactions and all the things you bought Only for a year and then we'll get rid of them right something like that.
Speaker 0: so that if anyone busts into our database and there's a leak which you know We're of course not gonna have a leak because we're not stupid like all that the other people had leaks like eco facts or whatever.
Speaker 0: If there is one, you know, or if they say there's an internal accurate the company who's evil and starts poking around the database They'll only get the last year of data and not your full world history.
Speaker 0: But you know what if you just clear delete those days.
Speaker 0: if you just do like delete everything older than a year Those are the same hard drives in the same server All the new information is gonna just start filling in that space over time.
Speaker 0: You're gonna be okay You can just.
Speaker 1: probably I think what it comes down to is as much as this Feels like it should be a very technology focused episode.
Speaker 1: The reality is that unless you work at a company with a policy and some real reason to care It generally doesn't matter because as a consumer just run something like DBAN and then just give sell the hard drive.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean at that company with a data retention policy, you know a hard drive in the net the sand crashes or something Right or whatever.
Speaker 0: they use their storage array.
Speaker 0: Yeah You take it out you put a new one in and then you make sure that before you put the old one in the garbage You do the DBAN equivalent.
Speaker 1: So most of the companies I have talked to about this over the years Prefer physical destruction of those situations.
Speaker 0: perfectly fine as well.
Speaker 1: drill press to the platters Which theoretically if it's just a drill press through the platters someone could pull the platters out.
Speaker 0: Well, if it's a magnetic with but if you take an SSD and put a drill through it Yeah, unless you miss the persistent storage in there I think you open it up and you find the right spot and just like shoot it with a gun.
Speaker 0: Yeah Take you could actually just rip that one chip off and throw there, you know, but I guess the the.
Speaker 1: it's not a technology question It's a procedures question.
Speaker 1: if you need to delete data you need to do the research and come up with the risk-reward like ratios and procedures you could follow.
Speaker 1: and the most important thing about deleting
Speaker 0: data is
Speaker 1: having an audit history of when and how you did you deleted the data so that if Someone recovers the data in some crazy way in the future You least have proof that you did what you said you did and that you Asserted that it was good enough at the time.
Speaker 0: It's a lot like, you know paper shredding, right?
Speaker 0: It's like yeah, you just buy a paper shredder it, you know, all of us deep over whatever your staples Yeah, or Amazon and put a piece of paper in there.
Speaker 0: a lot of crazy nuts are like, oh my god It.
Speaker 0: those cut the paper in a certain pattern and and the government's know how to put together get a cross shredder.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if it if the piece of paper is like the names of your spies in North Korea Yeah, maybe you should use a cross shredder and then burn it.
Speaker 1: but if it's my bank account statement the regular shredder I got from Amazon for the regular shredders and the raw chicken that it's in the Garbage with is probably sufficient.
Speaker 0: My shredder has its own trash bin.
Speaker 0: It's like its own Thing.
Speaker 0: it doesn't mix with the.
Speaker 1: oh, yeah, but I would just dump it in with the kitchen stuff.
Speaker 1: Okay, why not?
Speaker 0: Stick it up.
Speaker 0: Yeah help take it up help ward people away.
Speaker 1: I don't think anyone's digging through like cat litter.
Speaker 1: No figure out a bank statement for me.
Speaker 0: No So, yeah, but yeah, I like big companies.
Speaker 0: what they do is they usually get the Visiting shredder.
Speaker 0: Yeah big day put all their shredding stuff in these bins with locks on them like padlocks that could easily be busted because it's a plastic bin.
Speaker 0: and then once a week or so the plastic bins go downstairs and there's Tractor trailer with an enormous shredder of industrial nature in it and it dumps out the bins into the shredder There's in such a way that even the shredding guys who are driving the truck can't even see what's in there and it shreds that Shit like oh, baby big time.
Speaker 1: now I get the impression that a lot of the stories of someone got a hard drive and got data off of it are Literally just thought nothing was even done.
Speaker 1: like the hard drive just stopped working and someone threw it away and didn't even try to Even get a shredder to put the hard drives in.
Speaker 0: I'm sure a big real big one.
Speaker 1: I have That kind of shredder before they are terrifying to be around.
Speaker 0: Don't put any human flesh or any flesh period and anywhere near the entrance hole.
Speaker 0: Yeah use a long stick to drop the hard drive Grabbers.
Speaker 1: what this comes down to is if you just do basic due diligence to delete data from hard drives before you give them to people and If you can't do basic due diligence Destroy the hard drive rather than give it to anyone.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm, and that's probably enough.
Speaker 1: And if you can't even do that Then all the data on your hard drive is probably still there and easy for anyone who gets that hard drive to get.
Speaker 0: if they Wanted to yeah, or maybe they'll just install Windows and treat it like a clean hard drive and they won't ever look at it.
Speaker 0: So now we'll talk about not so much deleting but rim wanted to talk about Unpublishing right.
Speaker 0: So the first obviously we talk about unpublishing.
Speaker 0: It's because you can't it's not possible to do this.
Speaker 0: Yep, right as soon as you have some bits.
Speaker 0: if you send those bits out onto the internet somewhere, right?
Speaker 0: Guess what?
Speaker 0: You might as well just broadcast them the whole world.
Speaker 0: deal with it.
Speaker 1: So case in point my crazy archive of like everything.
Speaker 1: it's on my NAS Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: And as a result, it is also mirrored onto Amazon Glacier.
Speaker 1: Okay, but it's not published because it's encrypted up there.
Speaker 0: So yeah, it was encrypted before it was sent there.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and it's sitting there encrypted.
Speaker 0: So yeah, someone could get those encrypted bits, but because the keys are here.
Speaker 0: It's not actually published You don't need to unpublish it because if so, even as Amazon people open up Glacier and get the files out Yep They got a bunch of random nonsense.
Speaker 1: mostly.
Speaker 1: what this comes down to is the thorny question of if you have data on a service and You want to stop using that service?
Speaker 1: How do you know they actually remove your data if they even do you have to trust them?
Speaker 0: Yep, there's no way.
Speaker 0: Cloud is someone else's computer.
Speaker 0: So it's I have my private photos and someone else's computer.
Speaker 0: I asked them to delete them.
Speaker 0: They say they did The end.
Speaker 1: yep, and you might say oh, but what about things like snapchat?
Speaker 1: that the you you have to trust them.
Speaker 1: That's it.
Speaker 1: You still have.
Speaker 0: you're just going on their word.
Speaker 1: You look at the code.
Speaker 1: You know what they're doing unless you got.
Speaker 0: even if you see the code How do you know that's the code that's running on their server, yep They could have just shown you some other code.
Speaker 1: look at Facebook and Cambridge Analytica and all.
Speaker 0: they let you come into their office and look at their server and examine it.
Speaker 0: How do you know that?
Speaker 0: that's the server that's actually being used?
Speaker 0: It's not some phony setup.
Speaker 1: Well, look at geek nights Like.
Speaker 1: we won't even remove Comments in the old forum that is archived forever.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm if you post it in there like tough nuts, you know, if you really had like I guess if someone came to us with like a Serious problem like being stalked by something we might go back into that database and like change the name on an account.
Speaker 0: I mean people would could change their own names and on their accounts.
Speaker 0: So like people had done that where I was like, no, I'm not deleting anything.
Speaker 0: Sorry I want to help you but you know, that's not a way that I can help you.
Speaker 0: They just changed their username to make it so that anyone searching for their old name wouldn't find them And they close their account and stop posting.
Speaker 1: It's like if I delete my Flickr account, let's say Should Flickr be legally obligated to delete all my shit.
Speaker 0: I mean if we're in charge of writing the law Mmm, it depends cuz at the same time running a forum.
Speaker 1: I don't want to delete cool data.
Speaker 0: No Right someone took a cool photo in your Flickr, right?
Speaker 0: It's like.
Speaker 0: well You know, I kind of don't want to delete that photo right the whole world should be able to experience that photo.
Speaker 0: It's so awesome.
Speaker 0: I like person who previously had already shared it with the world now wants to unshare it with the world.
Speaker 1: I like the idea of a new class of copyright.
Speaker 1: I just thought of this now.
Speaker 0: Uh-huh.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: I'm sure it's a great idea You just thought of now.
Speaker 1: So here's my basic idea because this is kind of like something like.
Speaker 1: so I want to.
Speaker 1: when I die and this is in my Will but I want I get updated because it's Mr.
Speaker 1: Willow basically a public domain is mine to all my email account everything.
Speaker 1: Fuck it.
Speaker 1: Here you go.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the world can read every email remember sent.
Speaker 0: Well, I mean I got like, you know instructions like here is how to get into every one of my accounts and get all my Stuffs and you know because someone might need to my emails to manage my stuff when I'm dead.
Speaker 1: I like the idea of there being a class of copyright law Above and beyond.
Speaker 1: public domain may be called like the public trust or something or the public time trial.
Speaker 0: things probably exist.
Speaker 1: No But imagine so I there's would have to be a government run service.
Speaker 1: can't trust some tech startup to do this.
Speaker 0: Send it the Internet archive say archive.
Speaker 0: No.
Speaker 1: No, I want the ability to Basically send data to a government service that is encrypted and unlocks Something like some number of years after your death and there's laws protecting it.
Speaker 1: so you could say Here is data.
Speaker 0: Why don't we start that service and then not actually unlock anything because the dead people can't sue?
Speaker 1: that's not a bad idea.
Speaker 1: That's like saying selling rapture insurance.
Speaker 1: Yes Yeah, but I do like the idea of like services that get users data being obligated to unpublish it At least from the things they control if someone quits their service.
Speaker 1: But I also like the idea that like 50 years after that person's death that data is out again.
Speaker 1: Like get past the point where it's going likely to harm people and have a way To put data into the public trust on a time-delayed fashion.
Speaker 0: Hmm If someone posts a cool YouTube video and it's cool It's worth seeing and then they decide that they want to delete it from the internet.
Speaker 0: Like there's that guy who deleted all this code from the internet.
Speaker 0: You know, I've been a few guys like that.
Speaker 0: Guess what?
Speaker 0: It's out there.
Speaker 0: Everyone's got it.
Speaker 1: It's too late Yeah, but how do you know what we it was worth?
Speaker 1: We've never been able to find that fuck his head thing.
Speaker 0: Remember that?
Speaker 0: why didn't you save it?
Speaker 1: Because it was some flash thing and I didn't save.
Speaker 0: why didn't you save the eight people going gaga?
Speaker 1: I do have that on a hard drive that's dead and I'd have to pay someone.
Speaker 0: Why didn't you back up?
Speaker 1: Uh, because that was a time when I didn't have any money different time.
Speaker 0: You understand.
Speaker 1: That's a bad hard drive Only holds a gigabyte one whole gigabyte gigabyte.
Speaker 0: Whoa.
Speaker 1: And actually almost everything else from that hard drive was backed up except for the most important file.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we don't have Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles.
Speaker 0: You need it.
Speaker 1: I can't find it.
Speaker 1: Good luck I found a similar but different video.
Speaker 1: I'm just saying there are things I remember that are gone.
Speaker 0: There are things that are good to be gone.
Speaker 0: I said, I usually I think it's immoral to delete data, but not all day.
Speaker 1: The other day there's a there's the.
Speaker 1: We're talking this morning - there's the I. how do you delete something from your own brain?
Speaker 1: Because we knew a gentleman.
Speaker 1: well we can end the show on this.
Speaker 1: and RIT who with a hammer who was so vile That we agreed as a group that he would only be referred to ever as huge.
Speaker 1: You'll not be named.
Speaker 1: in the hopes that we would all eventually actually forget this person's name.
Speaker 0: I thought we were just saying he who shall not be named because a it was funny and be used to Remind you how gross the first.
Speaker 1: but I legit wanted to forget his name.
Speaker 0: Oh, I didn't I did.
Speaker 1: Okay, I could not recall his name.
Speaker 0: I'm 90% sure the name I told you is correct.
Speaker 1: I know and I'm.
Speaker 1: I'm almost mad because I may have actually forgotten him.
Speaker 1: I may have deleted to information what he looks like.
Speaker 0: I can spot him on the street.
Speaker 1: I Vaguely remember what he looks like but I've morphed him with another person who I do remember their name a little bit because they had similar physical attributes.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm that person.
Speaker 1: we both know that person's name.
Speaker 1: Okay first and last but the name you said.
Speaker 1: I don't actually know if that's the real name.
Speaker 0: Pretty sure it is.
Speaker 1: we'll have to ask Pete who is the keeper of the name because I remember you remember Pete's name.
Speaker 1: I asked him at the New Year's party if he remembered the name of you shall not be named and he thought about it for A minute and said and I quote yes god damn it.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: I still remember his name.
Speaker 1: He lived with.
Speaker 0: you want to know and I said no he lived with you shall not be named.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 1: Yes, that is true But I had forgotten and I might have unforgotten thanks to you.
Speaker 0: I mean, I basically it's weird right because I had not thought of he who shall not be named for a very very very.
Speaker 1: You just need a pointer to account as soon as you mention it.
Speaker 0: It's like up now.
Speaker 0: I remember this person that I hadn't thought about in years.
Speaker 1: so think of this.
Speaker 1: your brain is a lot like these hard drives where You think something is deleted, but actually you just deleted the pointer to it Mm-hmm, but if anything else in your brain points at it something you haven't thought about in a long time You'll smell a weird smell and suddenly your brains like oh, that's what that guy's name was Because you smelled him one day and your brain remembered that pointer.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm All right.
Speaker 1: I think we're done cuz I'm real fucking hungry now.
Speaker 0: I'm so hungry.
Speaker 1: Stop the show.
Speaker 1: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Speaker 0: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 1: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays and my comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 0: But unlike those other late shows It's actually recorded at night
Speaker 1: and the patreon page runs for this episode of geek nights are Craig Oliver Alan Joyce Rebecca Dunn hiding Nicholas shimmering rubiobolus king in the sky my study comm Jeremy minor link Iji Kelly Snyder cold guy Amanda Duchette Shawn Yeager, Matthew Smith Nicholas brand out.
Speaker 1: Mr Strong-stratchin 4 to 1 creations.
Speaker 1: No, I never ever wonder why we're here.
Speaker 1: semper fi bitch Shervin but horrible James David White Rochelle, Monta Nona a super boy.
Speaker 1: rim says something funny here.
Speaker 1: sailor Vista Don't you like chartovish and joshiro Joe star Clinton Walton to run from New Zealand Ryan Perrin through openlander Finn?
Speaker 1: Chris midkiff Chris Knox Daniel Redmond Sean Klein Chris Reimer and Thomas on.
Speaker 1: if you didn't notice I posted in the patreon that all of you who are patrons of the patreon can see the raw Pre-production footage from the new geek nights presents utenna episode 16, which I am currently working on the post-production for.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so anyway stay tuned for more geek nights as we're back from PAX.
Speaker 1: And now I leave you with something that you're gonna be really mad at me about.
Speaker 1: Oh They cross their souls man They drink a beer and swear.
Speaker 1: they're faithful to the king No matter what you say.
Speaker 1: They're always ready to fight or to sing.
Speaker 0: 1 for 0 and 0 for 1.
Speaker 0: Musket hounds are always ready 1 for 0 and 0 for 1 Helping everybody 1 for 0 and 0 for 1.