Speaker 0: It's Thursday November 22nd.
Speaker 0: I'm rim and I'm Emily and this is the geek night Thanksgiving special where we're gonna talk about London.
Speaker 1: It's about our worldwide journey.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so yeah you as many of you know I spent a lot of time in London over the years for work.
Speaker 1: You spent a lot of time a bunch of places.
Speaker 1: So it's it's kind of nice because I figure a lot of places we're gonna go travel.
Speaker 1: I'll have a built-in tour guide.
Speaker 0: But London was weird because I had like never really had time to sort of tourists there and I was always there for work.
Speaker 0: So I knew London from this perspective of like just living there and going to work and like running in the morning And I never went to like any touristy thing there.
Speaker 0: I never really saw any of the like sites other than just like wandering around town.
Speaker 1: it was actually kind of funny because like once we were there I could recognize some of the places from like Financial industry videos that you had filmed in the past.
Speaker 1: I'd be like, oh we just passed that square We're that fixed flyer video.
Speaker 1: yeah, and I mean like.
Speaker 1: I don't feel like our trip was super touristy.
Speaker 1: like To talk a little bit about our method of travel.
Speaker 1: It's usually like walk all day and just look around When you're hungry go find a place to eat, you know, it's we don't really we plan a little bit But mostly it's just.
Speaker 1: you know, if we're feeling hell and ready to go like hike It's I walk like 20 miles in a day.
Speaker 0: Yeah Well partly do is that's just kind of what I do when I'm traveling because usually in this travel I just have I have like a couple hours of downtime here and there or more interestingly I really only ever had a lot of downtime at night.
Speaker 0: So a lot of these places I've been I'm really like I've only explored them in the middle of the night or in the late evening or the early morning.
Speaker 1: So one of the funny things.
Speaker 1: so we can just start off and talk about like what we did.
Speaker 0: But we got into London, you know in the evening It was already dark, which is my go-to thing like for London in particular, especially from New York.
Speaker 0: Like it's really nice to just kind of leave in the morning and land in the early like to mid evening.
Speaker 0: So you have time to get some dinner and basically just go straight to bed.
Speaker 1: Yeah Well, you said you usually you land you have a Caesar salad at that one French place.
Speaker 0: I wonder happy French place?
Speaker 0: That's kind of by st.
Speaker 0: Paul's.
Speaker 1: It's like right across the street from the hotel.
Speaker 1: But it was funny because I did the thing that happens to me every time I go somewhere new.
Speaker 1: It's like I'm really unreasonably excited about Everything.
Speaker 1: and so the one of the first things we saw when I get outside of Paddington And I took a bunch of pictures of Paddington station and stuff, but I see this pub and I'm like, oh my god It's an English pub.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna take a million pictures.
Speaker 1: So I have all these blurry pictures.
Speaker 0: I mean the first pictures I took once we landed are like you and Paddington you in the on the train.
Speaker 1: My hair was so bad It's a little grease.
Speaker 0: and then you wanted to take a picture in front of one of those weird old-time boots, but yeah Well, that was cool.
Speaker 1: That's one of those things.
Speaker 1: That's very symbolic like, you know, not not stereotypical per se But it's like somebody taking a picture in front of a yellow cab.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but you got a very like quintessential London experience because the first thing we do is walk over to get on the central line, yeah, and it's like weirdly warm.
Speaker 0: we get on the subway and You encountered the kind of culture that exists in London that I don't really.
Speaker 1: my god, it was so charming.
Speaker 1: Everyone was drunk But they were drunk and like the most jovial Friendly sort of way like like New Yorkers.
Speaker 0: drunk on the subway tend to be either.
Speaker 1: certainly Oh, no, if you see New Yorkers drunk at the subway, I'm like, oh my god, please just go away.
Speaker 0: Maybe the New Yorkers don't interact with other drunk New Yorkers.
Speaker 0: They don't know you.
Speaker 1: Maybe it was just cuz I was in a really good mood or something.
Speaker 1: cuz what I encounter a bunch of drunk bros on the Subway in New York.
Speaker 1: I'm like, oh my god fucking shut up right now I am I don't want any part of that but these people like these 20-somethings were so Excited and they were talking to this older lady and I thought they knew each other like they're talking to this auntie and I'm like.
Speaker 1: So they must be friends no total strangers.
Speaker 1: I got off the next stop and it was just like one of those things where they were being like Buddy and having this chat with this total stranger
Speaker 0: On the tube because often I'd be out drinking with co-workers or doing stuff at night And that's just kind of how it is Like.
Speaker 0: maybe I've always run into that just people are kind of drunk and friendly and strangers will start Conversations with other strangers and actually have those conversations.
Speaker 1: and it's like as a New Yorker Usually I would not be in to that but I was into that.
Speaker 1: I was like, this is nice This is a good warm welcome to this city.
Speaker 1: also the tube is super small.
Speaker 0: I know it's a little baby subway like a tiny car.
Speaker 0: It basically can't hold any people.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like I was just imagining that at rush hour in New York and I was like, oh that would be such a nightmare.
Speaker 0: But like I feel like all this never super crowded.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah I mean we didn't really use it much during the rush hour, but even then it's never.
Speaker 0: it's like it gets crowded But it's nothing like New York.
Speaker 0: Yeah, also I think every train on all the lines in London combined is less capacity than like the trains on just the four-five In New York.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they just they don't hold a lot of people.
Speaker 0: They're not that big and as much as you like to complain as I do how loud the New York City subway is because it's old And crappy.
Speaker 0: the London subway is just as loud just in a different way.
Speaker 0: It was funny because I was like, oh it's much quieter too.
Speaker 1: And then we stood by an open window and I hear like You know, just this horrible creaking subway noise that I'm like, no, I think it's just old subways in general.
Speaker 0: Also, it's loud and you have open windows because There's no like HVAC system.
Speaker 0: There's no air conditioning in there.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and in the tube like it is literally a tube There's not very much clearance at all on either side of the train.
Speaker 0: now to be fair.
Speaker 0: The other lines aren't nearly that bad.
Speaker 0: That's the central line which is the oldest subway there is like.
Speaker 0: that thing is ancient and weird.
Speaker 0: It's kind of it's the weird one.
Speaker 0: It'd be like it'd be like looking at the sea train and thinking the New York Subway is like that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean fair.
Speaker 1: But anyway, that was kind of cool.
Speaker 1: and You know one thing that struck me while we were walking through London that night is just you know It felt very familiar but it felt almost like being in at a Campus like one of those old colleges like Brown or Harvard or someone's.
Speaker 0: they're like trying to emulate the style.
Speaker 1: It's so funny because it's like, you know the United States.
Speaker 1: You know, it's comes from an English colonial background.
Speaker 1: So it's like you don't realize how much Anglo influence is in our culture.
Speaker 1: until you go to the place It's like oh that's where that comes from.
Speaker 1: Yeah kind of feeling to it.
Speaker 1: And so like seeing all the architecture it just everything felt super old and stately and You know what?
Speaker 1: They would probably Londoners would probably laugh at me for saying something like that.
Speaker 1: They'd be like, what are you talking about?
Speaker 1: But like trust me as a New Yorker.
Speaker 1: Everything looks like Very like.
Speaker 0: I don't know the Londoners.
Speaker 0: I know they're always like very excited like whenever we go any marble facade.
Speaker 0: They'd always just be like that pub has been there since 1692 and let me tell you about this pub Reminds me of that old Eddie Izzard bit about like Americans in history.
Speaker 1: being like.
Speaker 1: this was made 50 years ago and everybody gasps.
Speaker 0: No one was even alive back then Because our other big trip a while ago was Australia and we were in Toronto a while ago to other like Commonwealth descending.
Speaker 1: Yeah, which are relatively recent, you know, Toronto is actually Canada in terms of its you know national heritage I think is even Younger than the United States.
Speaker 1: So any case we get to the hotel and it's just a business hotel because we end up choosing it because I was like Why don't we stay at someplace cheap?
Speaker 0: membership Membership at Club Quarters, which is like this It's really a chain for people who are like literally business traveling because their shtick is if you have a membership It costs the same no matter when you book.
Speaker 0: so you can just like book hotel and it's a guaranteed price.
Speaker 0: There's a guaranteed room if there's like.
Speaker 0: you don't have to talk to anyone you just swipe your credit card and a key comes Out of a machine, but I guess you can.
Speaker 0: just I never realized you could book them without a membership.
Speaker 0: It just might cost a little more.
Speaker 0: So we stayed like literally the hotel.
Speaker 0: I've stayed at like 12 or 13 times.
Speaker 1: Yeah And the nice thing about that is it was a neighborhood you knew really well and like you basically you knew the drill.
Speaker 1: so staying at Club Quarters meant like We didn't really have to plan that much.
Speaker 1: It was you know, and they had that automatic key thing.
Speaker 1: so you just put in your your credit card and the paperwork was done and And it's kind of a quiet part like basically it was the plate.
Speaker 0: cuz I'd say there's three of those.
Speaker 0: I would stay So cool less.
Speaker 0: I usually stay.
Speaker 0: there's one I'd stay in if the other two were booked But usually I'd stayed either.
Speaker 0: the one in Grace Church, which is a little bit Remember when you walk toward the Barbican in that area?
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's like the Grace Church is a little more that way.
Speaker 1: Yeah to the st.
Speaker 0: Paul's one.
Speaker 1: Didn't we go by Grace Church?
Speaker 0: We went through every neighborhood that I knew anything about.
Speaker 1: We basically walked.
Speaker 1: if you looked at our heat map of where we walked in London It would basically traverse most of the downtown and we even walked over to like Isle of Dogs and stuff.
Speaker 0: Isn't that what was called?
Speaker 0: We went toward Isle of Dogs went to Canary Wharf and then we petered out and got lunch.
Speaker 1: Yeah Canary Wharf which was like it was basically like the fight I and it had a lot of kids were anyway.
Speaker 0: anyone Who is who asks like hey, what did you do in London on tourists?
Speaker 0: Hey, I went to Canary Wharf because I was one of my co.
Speaker 0: I mentioned one of my co-workers from London And he said exactly what I expected.
Speaker 0: All he said was why?
Speaker 1: No, we had a really nice dinner and it was kind of like there was this whole restaurant row of all these new new restaurants like.
Speaker 0: it's a lot like Stone Street and that it's a place for like.
Speaker 0: people don't really live over there and it's quiet at night But all the people get out of work who work there and go drinking and eating like no It really did remind me of downtown Manhattan like financial district Manhattan Except that it was like all new development.
Speaker 1: Whereas fight I has a lot of the old shit in New York.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like like.
Speaker 1: this is our oldest building.
Speaker 1: I don't know if actually the oldest building but I do know the oldest pub in New York.
Speaker 1: Is that one?
Speaker 1: That's like right by Wall Street.
Speaker 1: Like, you know the Anyway the oldest.
Speaker 0: We didn't go into it But we did walk by the Cheshire cheese Which I think is the oldest surviving pub in this actual city.
Speaker 1: I learned a lot about the great fire.
Speaker 1: Most things are like this is from the 1660s because it's like that's after the fire and the English Civil War.
Speaker 1: So that's really when a lot of these surviving wood structures are from.
Speaker 0: Yes So like even when you go to see the crown jewels, it's like these are all after the fire because they got destroyed.
Speaker 1: No, it was because the Civil War.
Speaker 1: Well, and there was the other fire where Cromwell and his shithead Yeah Cromwell was like no more crown jewels melted all down and then they're like after they kicked his butt out and sent the crazy religious people away to.
Speaker 1: What became our country then?
Speaker 0: It where they ruined everything over here.
Speaker 1: It was since we're recording this on Thanksgiving.
Speaker 1: I was just sitting on the couch and I was like, you know what the pilgrims were kind of fuckers like the pilgrims.
Speaker 0: I'd say I'm sick of their shit, but it's a little too little too late.
Speaker 1: Yeah Well, I was just we're talking about.
Speaker 1: I was reading a lot about the English Civil War after the trip on the plane home And I was like, was it King James the second or Kim James the first?
Speaker 0: Who's the one who got chopped?
Speaker 0: I think it was James the second who got chopped.
Speaker 1: I don't remember.
Speaker 1: anyway It was one of the James's and I was like, I don't like him But I think I don't like Cromwell more especially because what he did to Ireland so Him and his pilgrims and all the crazy Religious
Speaker 0: I know he was the way he was the one who succeeded.
Speaker 0: I think it was James the first who got shot.
Speaker 1: Yeah, yeah, James.
Speaker 1: the second was the one who put the end to Cromwell's bullshit.
Speaker 0: This is one area of history I actually don't know that much about like I. just it wasn't really focused on.
Speaker 1: There was a bunch of nonsense and that's why the crown jewels are from the 1600s.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: So we stayed like right at st falls and we just like walked over the Millennium Bridge and walked around at night.
Speaker 0: and the one thing about Is in a lot of neighborhoods not much is open at night.
Speaker 1: you are hella hangry and I felt kind of bad because it was like.
Speaker 1: I Understand why you were so hungry.
Speaker 1: I ate a ton on the plane and so I was like I'm good but like it was 11 o'clock at night and We get into our neighborhood and check into the hotel and then nowhere is open to eat like there was no 24/7 K deli that I could.
Speaker 0: The places we could have gone were kind of far away like there's other hip neighborhoods.
Speaker 0: It was kind of late for that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, also London in general like move like almost every city I've ever visited just kind of shuts down at night in a way that New York really doesn't in most neighborhoods.
Speaker 1: Yeah it's it's kind of wild like Realize it cuz like Tokyo the train stopped running and there's always this rush for all the like the tipsy business Partiers to to get on that last train.
Speaker 1: But yeah, London also kind of gets pretty sedate at night and I think we ended up going to a bodega.
Speaker 1: You got a bunch of beer nuts In the morning, yeah, but yeah, we ate really well.
Speaker 1: when we were there we had one fancy dinner.
Speaker 1: We had one fancy dinner.
Speaker 1: That was the second day, but the the first day was my birthday.
Speaker 0: Yeah, all we did is we walked around Basically the entirety of like the proper city of London yeah, and crossed the Thames back and forth and back and forth like Did we go to?
Speaker 1: was that the day we went to Westminster?
Speaker 0: Yeah, we walked it.
Speaker 0: We basically we walked like over toward Westminster through like Southwark in the south side of the Thames.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we walked up to Westminster.
Speaker 0: We poked around there and we'd all whack around took a break and then we went to the right instead and went over to Tower.
Speaker 1: Yeah Thing about Westminster.
Speaker 1: that was funny going across the bridge.
Speaker 1: cuz they were like shellgate.
Speaker 1: I think you talked about it Like two guys who look kind of the same as the previous group.
Speaker 0: You see like every one of them like has two guys doing the thing and every one of them had a tallish woman Wearing black with heavy eyeliner who is clearly like doing the hustle to get the crowd together Like the same woman at every single show game.
Speaker 1: It's like this is my con man uniform, but yeah, and the only bummer thing was We saw Westminster Abbey like just from far away But we didn't
Speaker 0: go in any of that nonsense
Speaker 1: and was under construction And it was like way too crowded because it was a weekend and tourism was happening.
Speaker 1: So we were like, oh, let's Let's hike back and but we had a good proper Upstairs food at a pub.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I had kedgery cakes cuz it's fun cuz that's a thing in Toronto, too.
Speaker 0: You go to like a pub and then upstairs.
Speaker 0: There's just food and Sydney and Melbourne both have that as well.
Speaker 1: That was more just like that specific pub there.
Speaker 0: It's pretty common though Like that's a that's a thing.
Speaker 1: the like the Queen the Queen and Beaver in Toronto is a good pub And I go there a lot when I'm up in Toronto.
Speaker 0: The first meal we ate was we went into a pub and we wanted food and we could go upstairs or downstairs And upstairs was basically identical to the places we're talking about.
Speaker 0: Yeah like same deal and Downstairs was that except there were all these old men who were clearly like friends who hang out there every day drinking Yeah, day drinking and eating food.
Speaker 0: and it was.
Speaker 0: it was weird and awkward, but it was easier to eat at the upstairs part.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so that was nice.
Speaker 1: We got some food and then We also went to the financial district like the place where the the banks are.
Speaker 0: We kind of walk by like cheap side and all that.
Speaker 0: there's not a lot to see over there.
Speaker 0: You kind of just walk through the neighborhood.
Speaker 0: I can point out like that's a bank ride tried to sell some software and like.
Speaker 0: I've eaten at that pub and I've Gone to this place.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, and we saw Becky Ham Palace from the outside.
Speaker 1: Yeah mostly I really enjoyed walking around in the park because it was like full-on autumn and there were a lot of like Ducks and geese and like.
Speaker 1: they were Canada geese and they were kind of sort of coexisting with the local wildlife.
Speaker 1: But they were also kind of getting mad at people who were feeding them.
Speaker 1: Like give me food.
Speaker 1: I'm a goose and There were squirrels.
Speaker 1: So part-time was nice.
Speaker 0: Yeah We basically respect because it was.
Speaker 0: it was fredder naturally warm and sunny and like beautiful weather Except that there were fast everywhere.
Speaker 1: Well, they're also Antifa and there was.
Speaker 1: there was some sort of protest nonsense as best I can tell.
Speaker 0: It was like a soccer club that's fascist and they were trying to do a thing.
Speaker 0: There are a bunch of counter protesters like soccer hooligans who have gotten political.
Speaker 1: Seemed to be the what I could gather from our cursor.
Speaker 0: We encountered multiple like police like riot police barricades Full shields and stuff.
Speaker 1: So it's like nice walk in the park by Buckingham Palace.
Speaker 1: Oh my gosh There's a bunch of riot police.
Speaker 1: So it it kind of quashed the idea that I was like, oh, you know I'm so nice to be a far away and not have to think about the u.s.
Speaker 0: Well considering Brexit I mean The same problems happening over there, too.
Speaker 1: It's.
Speaker 1: it's not a not a pretty picture anywhere you go, but but that was the only day with nice weather.
Speaker 1: Yeah, oh my god, it was gorgeous.
Speaker 1: It was just like blue sky.
Speaker 1: I was like, hey everybody says London is so great.
Speaker 1: And then the next day it was like Completely my mental picture of what I thought British weather was good Missed it and rained the entire day after that like every day just Drizzling.
Speaker 1: but like it was also it wasn't that cold It was I. I had a bodega umbrella that kept turning inside a lot of pictures But it did its duty like what it was really writing.
Speaker 1: it actually was.
Speaker 0: it could have brought my fancy umbrella.
Speaker 1: We could have bought a fancy umbrella But I didn't and it worked and it was fine.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but Then one of my co-workers has suggested there's a play that apparently made it to the u.s.
Speaker 1: So we went and saw a play that was yeah, that was the next day.
Speaker 1: So the the first day was walking around looking around and the whole day we wandered and you know until dusk we went by the Globe Theatre and I think I hadn't fish and chips at that place by the By the hotel, but the second day it was like our let's plan stuff.
Speaker 1: So we went to.
Speaker 1: We went to Hyde Park, I forget what we were going to do, but we decided it was too much bother.
Speaker 1: Oh the British Museum.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: No, we didn't go to Hyde Park.
Speaker 0: we were gonna go to the British Museum and then we decided not to because there was a Crazy line to get in and it was raining and that line just looked.
Speaker 0: it was full of miserable tourists.
Speaker 1: It's like a line around the block in the pouring rain and we were like, yeah So we went to a different park.
Speaker 0: That wasn't Hyde Park Yeah, actually Regency Park, which I'd never been mark I'd never been up there.
Speaker 0: But Regents Park was just like beautiful and we wanted around in the flower gardens.
Speaker 1: Yeah, all the roses were blooming and like it was all the autumn leaves were falling and there were a lot of good dogs.
Speaker 1: We saw many many good dogs.
Speaker 0: And so that was actually probably even more enjoyable to me than Then the museum we vaguely considered because we saw there was some sort of dog show thing like down.
Speaker 1: Oh, it was the schnauzer festival.
Speaker 1: It was like a walk a walk where all these schnauzer schnauzer parents decided to like walk their dogs together to raise money to rescue schnauzers and Like like dogs who had been in puppy mills and stuff like that.
Speaker 1: I was like, this is a good cause Let's go and see the schnauzers, but it was really far away.
Speaker 1: And I also think it was more of like Schnauzer people.
Speaker 1: I'm sure they would be fine If a couple of random Americans showed up like.
Speaker 1: we'd like to join you on the dog walk But I like.
Speaker 1: after I read a little bit more about it I was like, no, this is more an event for dog people instead of people to look at dogs.
Speaker 0: So we had a fancy dinner and we went and saw the play.
Speaker 0: that goes wrong.
Speaker 1: The play has gone wrong right?
Speaker 0: or the play that goes wrong.
Speaker 1: it was.
Speaker 1: Basically The title is very apt.
Speaker 1: That is exactly what you're giving.
Speaker 0: It was pretty fun.
Speaker 0: The only trouble with it.
Speaker 0: Is that we First it was really step slapstick and the first act was great and really funny and Like it was it was good.
Speaker 0: Well done slapstick.
Speaker 0: The trouble was the second act was just more of the same and at no point was there a twist or an escalation.
Speaker 1: it was.
Speaker 1: This is not so.
Speaker 1: I'm just gonna sound harsher than it actually was but it was a very shallow play.
Speaker 1: Yeah It's basically just.
Speaker 1: the set is breaking and the actors can't remember their lines and the play goes wrong.
Speaker 1: And it's at points hysterically funny, you know like sometimes the little subtle things are the The funniest bits like the doorknob being broken or like, you know there will be points where this guy has to play dead and people just like Sit on him or like bump into him and he like, you know, he's obviously he kind of winces in pain but he's still having to play dead and so like.
Speaker 1: Bits like that are actually really funny physical comedy.
Speaker 1: but I guess I was expecting the second act to kind of often a Play will have a thing happening from one perspective and then like the perspective will change.
Speaker 1: But that didn't really happen.
Speaker 1: It was just more funny slapstick and I enjoyed myself immensely.
Speaker 1: I left very hard at many points during this production But Yeah, so that was really nice and we went to was super good.
Speaker 1: dinner at that place called Frenchie.
Speaker 0: it was like modern French cuisine and And pretty much like the rest of the trip.
Speaker 0: We just like picked a different neighborhood Wandered around it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I was very happy in particular when we found that one the international incident that occurred.
Speaker 1: Two guys whooping this other guy's but it's like general.
Speaker 0: The Austrian butcher was recognized and attacked by Barclay and Perkins Draymond.
Speaker 0: It was on the spot in 1850.
Speaker 1: It was just two regular dudes saw this Basically a war criminal and kicked the shit out of him.
Speaker 1: and it was like good on ya.
Speaker 1: and those guys were publicly recognized as heroes.
Speaker 0: We also encountered a lot of like teenagers Making mischief.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah Yeah, the bike kid mischief in London is like very distinct to London Like I don't encounter this kind of bike kid mischief anywhere else.
Speaker 1: These punk kids who are like we want to take our bikes into the store and the security guard was like, well,
Speaker 0: no I think their thing lately is that they all will be shirtless with like the were their backpacks, but like not wear shirts and Go into shops and then get kicked out of the shop for not wearing shirts because that's funny and the other thing they'll do.
Speaker 1: Many instances they were not able to enter the stop in our not even just this trip.
Speaker 0: I've encountered this other times too or They will Leave their bikes laying in front of the door of the shop blocking it and get really mad when the shopkeeper tries to move the Bikes, so is this just?
Speaker 1: is this literally like a really dumb prank?
Speaker 0: It's just their hobby Just like we're gonna be slight.
Speaker 1: every time I've been to London.
Speaker 0: I've just seen like Like little young teenagers on bikes with backpacks just being pains in the ass to shopkeepers.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well we did observe that while we were walking like in New York.
Speaker 0: You see that like in Midtown sometimes around Central Park or even in Brooklyn But they tend to just be shouting at people and biking around like yelling.
Speaker 0: but in London, they seem to specifically bother shopkeepers.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like I never really I guess at least in my experience in New York I have seen like confrontations between like teenagers and business establishments, but usually it's not intentional.
Speaker 1: Usually the kids are just like being rowdy or something and somebody will try to like go Leave the McDonald's and the kids are like, no, we don't want to leave the McDonald's.
Speaker 1: So that kind of thing will happen.
Speaker 1: But like I've never seen such a coordinated effort to go into the confrontation of the shop security guard.
Speaker 0: So the one thing I had done once before and we did it again But much we went everywhere in it.
Speaker 0: We spent a long time in there is the Tower of London is super cool.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I was way worth going into.
Speaker 1: Scott didn't believe that it was a castle.
Speaker 0: I was like Obsessed with castles and literally doesn't know anything about.
Speaker 0: he's like.
Speaker 1: if I went to Europe I would see a castle I'm like, that's literally what we did and he was like Tower of London.
Speaker 1: Is it a castle?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I wonder.
Speaker 0: he also didn't seem to understand how old that building is.
Speaker 1: Like it's a thousand years old, right?
Speaker 0: It's like from the era of William the Conqueror.
Speaker 0: He started building it before he died.
Speaker 0: Like different towers in the facility were built in like 1290 or whatever.
Speaker 0: like the.
Speaker 1: the white tower is like the oldest structure, right?
Speaker 1: It's like around the time Rome was being kicked out or something.
Speaker 0: No, it was literally.
Speaker 0: well Yeah, so there was a straw Roman wall there that they incorporated into it But it was literally.
Speaker 0: the construction was begun by William the Conqueror who then died like right away and then other people finished it And then they slowly built stuff up around it and it was.
Speaker 0: it was basically in continuous use for that entire period until today and it's still in use and there's literally like people who live in it.
Speaker 0: apparently and Like the crown jewels are still stored in the grounds.
Speaker 1: keepers like they have houses on the premises.
Speaker 1: actually, I think the Raven guy has house there like I. they live in the Facility.
Speaker 0: we got to interact with the Raven.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 1: I was so happy I've decided that I wouldn't want to be a Raven keeper though because they have to feed them dead rabbits.
Speaker 1: Yeah sad, but you know, that's what crows, you know, you have to feed crows good food.
Speaker 1: Like what was it?
Speaker 1: Biscuits soaked in blood.
Speaker 1: And then the one Raven was like came over to us and he was like Well, like I can't patch you cuz there's a sign right there that says you will bite me.
Speaker 0: And he's like, oh you're no fun.
Speaker 0: and then he goes over to this girl and she starts to react like oh my god.
Speaker 0: And he starts fucking with her.
Speaker 1: It's like pulling.
Speaker 1: she had a tote bag right and the Raven likes that's pulling on the bag and go like poo-poo but I'm like trying to Steal her bag.
Speaker 0: and she's like, oh no mom.
Speaker 1: And It was like the Raven made like the happiest pace Like it was like open its mouth like ha ha ha and spread its wings.
Speaker 1: Like it was laughing.
Speaker 1: Really amazing, but yeah, that was them one of the main reasons I wanted to go to Tower of London Not just because it's famous But because I had.
Speaker 1: I followed the waving keeper and they always post pictures of the birds and I love Corvid.
Speaker 1: So I was like, I want to see the team and they're really funny.
Speaker 0: You see I'm just like around like bother people.
Speaker 1: you see videos online of them like stealing people's potato chips and stuff like that but they're good birds and So you notice too.
Speaker 0: but one thing I liked about London in general was that there's all this old Architecture like Tower of London is just like hanging out there Yeah But also the skyline like has a huge variety of buildings because you kept making fun of that one weird one That looks like an air filter.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that what I I'm generally pretty like.
Speaker 1: I'm pretty open-minded when it comes to modern architecture cuz there's like the big tall thing.
Speaker 0: There's the gherkin.
Speaker 1: I even like brutalism in certain context.
Speaker 1: I'm like, you know people make fun of that.
Speaker 1: and I'm like, yeah It can be rust the rustic concrete can be can be beautiful in its own way But that air conditioner building just looks like an air filter just lose it looms.
Speaker 1: and I'm like, I don't like that building.
Speaker 1: It's not aesthetic anti-aesthetic but Anyway with after the tower.
Speaker 1: Oh the cool thing about the Tower of London was all the graffiti like the prisoners that poor sorcerer And like the guy who there was a guy and they arrested him.
Speaker 1: Somebody was like some nobleman was like he put a curse on me and my wife and he was like, no I I did not put a curse on you and your wife and even though I used to practice sorcery.
Speaker 1: I don't do that anymore.
Speaker 1: I've gone clean and and Really what he was doing?
Speaker 1: It looked like he was studying star patterns and doing astrology and astronomy and stuff like that.
Speaker 1: He had like this star chart that he carved into the rock.
Speaker 1: I hope they didn't chop him.
Speaker 1: That would have been too bad.
Speaker 0: I forget if they did or not.
Speaker 0: I feel like they did.
Speaker 1: Maybe let him go.
Speaker 1: we could look it up after yep See what the deal is with that guy and it was interesting to see.
Speaker 1: like it was a military base for a lot of its History and also like all the armor stuff.
Speaker 1: they got wrong like the Victorians.
Speaker 1: Victorians are just full of shit like in terms of what they know about history So they wouldn't make stuff up all the time like.
Speaker 1: this is Richard the Lionheart's armor.
Speaker 1: It was totally had nothing to do with him.
Speaker 1: it was for 200 years after that, you know, so a lot of the Exhibits were kind of like.
Speaker 1: this has been a museum for like Hundreds of years basically and that was kind of cool.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we had to avoid those screaming kids that were slowly catching up to us.
Speaker 1: So, yeah, we were running away from from kids on a field trip.
Speaker 1: Here they come.
Speaker 1: But so after that we walked up.
Speaker 1: that was when we went to the Canary Wharf and then we went to the Barbican and wandered around and the Barbican.
Speaker 0: the Barbican is this like Horrid looking but I like.
Speaker 0: it has a charm to it but it's it's the stereotypical ugly like.
Speaker 0: it reminds me a lot of The reaction and the feeling and like just what it felt like to be around the Rensin in Detroit.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it feels very like sit like mid-century 60s 70s Kind of thing.
Speaker 1: I don't know when it was constructed But that's like both in terms of its color state scheme and general aesthetic.
Speaker 1: That's kind of what it reminds me of and that was when I started getting jet lag really fading fast.
Speaker 1: I don't know what it is.
Speaker 1: But like I don't even get so much tired.
Speaker 1: I mostly get hungry at weird times and then I'm not.
Speaker 1: I don't feel hungry when I actually am Like it will be time to eat and I'll be like my stomach says no But if I make myself eat then it's like it's like a potion has been given to me and I'm like I could see this.
Speaker 1: It's just like you feel.
Speaker 1: this general Malay is just like stuff is bad and you're just like Little beer into you and you were good to go.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we had some ramen.
Speaker 1: It was actually pretty good.
Speaker 1: We only went to one like pub to have a pint Yeah, but it was the one you go to on business all the time.
Speaker 1: So I felt it was like old.
Speaker 0: Dr Butler's head which just happens to be a pub that I would go to a lot.
Speaker 1: I kind of like that.
Speaker 1: It was just the most generic pub because it was like if we had gone to a fancy one.
Speaker 1: It wouldn't have felt like.
Speaker 1: One thing I like about traveling with you is it feels very everyday and that's the kind of experience I like when I'm traveling like going with a friend who lives in that city or going with somebody who's very Familiar with the area.
Speaker 1: It's just.
Speaker 1: it feels so much more like regular Everyday life but in a very positive way, you also got to see the.
Speaker 0: I want to see the laundromats of your country Proper London drinking culture, like everyone's just drinking out in the street.
Speaker 1: Yeah, yeah, it's like opposite of Philly cuz.
Speaker 1: Philly everybody's drunk in agro.
Speaker 1: this one everybody's drunk and like hey come over Have a pint, you know, it's like that old man in in Japan who is like you weren't with us.
Speaker 1: That was when I was with my father, but he's like really good like come on into the izakaya and drink drink here You know, so I I just thought it was very very good and then we walked some more and we went to that That pub that was on the water.
Speaker 0: Yeah To have fancy dessert.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we went and got some dessert like a few miles away And that was kind of a nice bookend because that was where we went in the first place.
Speaker 0: Yep, we waited but there was too late to get food there and even as hungry as I was beer does not count enough as food.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know Have a pint and then go to bed.
Speaker 1: You wake up a little bit of a blurg.
Speaker 0: but It's like we spend a third of our time doing like looking at specific things a third of our time Wandering around parks and a third of our time wandering around neighborhoods.
Speaker 1: But that's like a really it was a really good balance because we did plan some stuff like the play we planned and I mean we said oh, we're gonna get a fancy dinner before the play and You had some things you wanted to show me.
Speaker 1: you're like we should go to Hyde Park at some point and see the buns.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and we didn't see any buns But we saw a lot of good dogs and squirrels and we got a fancy high tea at that random bed-and-breakfast over We that's right right before we got on the train.
Speaker 1: We got.
Speaker 1: We got like went to some random hotel like not super notable or fancy, but they had like regular High tea, so we got like the little tower with the like right by Lancaster Gate.
Speaker 1: And I don't get what the deal is with all the hotels there because there are like a million tiny hotels.
Speaker 0: It's kind of it's like all the tourists like that's where they come in because they fly to London They stop at Paddington and they like stay right they just stay right there.
Speaker 1: They're all like.
Speaker 1: they're not name-brand.
Speaker 1: It's not like airports right.
Speaker 1: where they have like this is the Marriott by the airport or something It's like specifically these off-brand bed-and-breakfast that all have funny quaint names.
Speaker 0: So there's also like very different.
Speaker 1: all those warehouses were like the Days Inn has one of them, but it will be like the Spotted pig and then next to that hotel there will be a Days Inn sign But it's the same kind of building I was like hmm This is like.
Speaker 1: that was one of those things that I was like.
Speaker 1: we don't have that here.
Speaker 1: So Yeah, so that was.
Speaker 1: that was good.
Speaker 1: We wandered around in the park and saw that nice garden and then we wouldn't have.
Speaker 0: that was like the Princess Diana garden and all That stuff.
Speaker 0: I'd never I never been over there.
Speaker 1: We saw three parks.
Speaker 1: all in all we saw three parks and walked most of them when we were in the city.
Speaker 1: and So for you know four days pretty much of doing stuff.
Speaker 0: I think four days is about Like that's about the most time you can spend in London if you don't have a like a specific reason to be in London.
Speaker 1: After that, I figure it would probably just be doing how we do in New York where it's more like.
Speaker 1: You know, I'd actually like be working on stuff again working on stuff meeting up with friends that kind of thing.
Speaker 0: But like like in Sydney where I were just like I've worked every day in Bondi Junction And then we go out at night and do stuff, you know a weekend on foot to explore a city like Seattle, right?
Speaker 1: It's like if I walk around Seattle, I can explore a lot if I just walk all day.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and because we walked all the way to Canary Wharf, yeah Which that's actually my running around.
Speaker 0: I'd usually run away in the mornings.
Speaker 1: I was so good.
Speaker 1: It was just such a good trip all around.
Speaker 1: you are an excellent traveling companion.
Speaker 1: And the funny thing is I remember when you got your passport to go to Costa Rica with you.
Speaker 1: You are the the world traveler who's been Very very many places.
Speaker 1: So I'll just follow you around from now on.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so great trip.
Speaker 1: Oh, and the other thing is the last thing.
Speaker 1: when we were going in Paddington Station, there was a pasty shop Pasties and pasties.
Speaker 1: I like my favorite my favorite foods.
Speaker 0: We had pasties today for lunch.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I decided I'm gonna make some you for pasties cuz that was what I was craving and I found a good crust recipe.
Speaker 1: So I put it on my Twitter.
Speaker 0: So if anybody wants a pasty crust It's just like a chill modern dense city that like.
Speaker 0: as a New Yorker I could live there.
Speaker 1: Like.
Speaker 0: I don't say that about a lot of cities, you know It's.
Speaker 1: I know it's a silly thing to say But like I feel like a lot of big cities.
Speaker 1: if you go to them and you're used to like that big International city.
Speaker 1: it feels like home like it's kind of the opposite of what people often say about like big cities being alienating and like Feeling overwhelmed and stuff.
Speaker 1: I'm like this feels familiar to me.
Speaker 1: This feels kind of comforting and the one thing I loved about London is just there were you know, it was very international.
Speaker 1: It's like every day going about our business.
Speaker 1: We just hear people talking in all different languages and you know feels very much like New York's.
Speaker 0: like one afternoon We just went over London Tower Bridge and then we just like wandered around that kind of hipster neighborhood through some like housing developments.
Speaker 1: Oh, I could have totally lived there like.
Speaker 1: it probably cost an arm and a leg in rent.
Speaker 1: It looked like a fancy neighborhood.
Speaker 0: It looks like most of those places we can.
Speaker 1: So it reminded me of like Astoria like.
Speaker 1: it's not like living in Midtown.
Speaker 0: It's like South work really feels like Queens.
Speaker 1: Yeah, yeah that definitely it felt like going to Astoria.
Speaker 1: I mean like just like with any foreign city.
Speaker 1: It's not like one-to-one and I could be like, oh this is like New York and that is like New York.
Speaker 1: But I think you know, I kind of did that in Australia, too.
Speaker 1: It's like, you know You just find these points of similarity and you'd be like.
Speaker 1: this neighborhood reminds me of Brooklyn and this neighborhood's like.
Speaker 1: so but we don't have a castle.
Speaker 0: but Well, we had Bannerman Castle upstate.
Speaker 1: Well, that's not a real castle.
Speaker 1: That was just that was guy who was basically like a nerd about old castles.
Speaker 1: It's it's like like I was saying we got all our weird English Englishness from the original source,
Speaker 0: yep like the thing that I always love about being in London and going to like some random pub is that Every pub in the US is desperately trying to look and feel like those pubs But always feels a little shabby as a result like everything is almost made to look shabby and old on purpose.
Speaker 0: But then you go to an actually old pub in London and you're like this bar Because it's been there for a hundred years 200 years old and it's full of like the spilled pints of Decades.
Speaker 0: so and we had some like mediocre like satisfying pints because there's not good beer in.
Speaker 1: Most of the beer was kind of weak sauce, but you know in some ways it was kind of.
Speaker 1: I guess it was the kind of beer that's like Kind of like drinking Kirin or something like that where it's light and refreshing and good and not skunky and nasty like Well, I like Corona in its given certain context.
Speaker 0: Yeah but not many though But I do not like.
Speaker 0: the only reason I was able to tolerate Corona was that if you were taking Metro North home That was the best beer they sold for the train.
Speaker 1: I think it's one of those things where my memory is colored by nostalgia where like Corona was usually the beer we'd order if the alternative was bud.
Speaker 1: Yeah so it's like we get this get this bottle of Corona and I remember like listening to your guys show like ten years ago back when we lived at the geek house and I'd be lying on the bed and The windows would be open and I'd be watching you guys record the show.
Speaker 1: And so that's what I associate that particular brand of beer with.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's kind of funny.
Speaker 1: But Anyway, go to London.
Speaker 1: It's lovely and I enjoy it.
Speaker 1: If I had to live there I would be happy.
Speaker 1: That's what I got to say about that.
Speaker 0: So yeah Thanksgivings now, we're gonna actually eat some food.
Speaker 0: scouts off eating food.
Speaker 1: We're having Thanksgiving bibimbap We have Thanksgiving pasties for lunch and we had very many nice people invite us to share their Thanksgiving dinner.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but everybody do far away This year.
Speaker 1: I was just gonna cook and chill.
Speaker 0: we do a different Thanksgiving thing.
Speaker 0: This morning we went and saw an oscar-screener for wreck-it Ralph.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that was fun.
Speaker 0: We had a pasty.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I played some overwatch.
Speaker 0: Maybe I'll play a little more overwatch.
Speaker 1: So anyway, happy Thanksgiving guys.
Speaker 0: Yep This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at front row crew comm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 0: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 0: But unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 0: It's actually recorded at night.