Speaker 0: It's Thursday April 26th 2018.
Speaker 0: I'm rim.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott and this is geek nights.
Speaker 0: tonight We're talking about not just failed conventions, but actual scam conventions But also fail conventions.
Speaker 1: Let's do this minimum.
Speaker 0: so yeah, I uh Every two years or so I got a new cell phone and it's about that time because I noticed that just in the last week My current cell phone which is about two years old So actually a little over two years old.
Speaker 0: I got a pretty good run with this thing.
Speaker 0: It used to have a for 30 to 40 hour battery life.
Speaker 0: Like.
Speaker 0: the whole reason I bought this phone is that it's the one small Android phone like the only one.
Speaker 0: that's good and the battery lasts forever And it's running out of juice now because it doesn't throttle itself and slow down like the iPhone does when it's batteries die.
Speaker 1: You can't just replace the battery.
Speaker 0: No, you can't replace batteries on most phones.
Speaker 0: I mean, I guess I could try to take it to a custom shop, but I could replace a battery on my iPhone At an Apple store or some third-party person doing it either way.
Speaker 0: Yeah, because this phone is actually waterproof Can't just open it.
Speaker 1: It's been said that many phones are Waterproof and simply do not advertise as such because they don't want people to like jump in pools with their.
Speaker 0: I've jumped in pools with This one.
Speaker 0: I've used it in the water at the beach.
Speaker 0: I've showered with it.
Speaker 0: I've read FARC like while I was shot.
Speaker 1: my iPhone 7 has been through many wet.
Speaker 1: It hasn't been dropped in submerged in water.
Speaker 0: I have taken photos underwater with my phone All right, but it has.
Speaker 1: you know, it has been in many rainy and wet and splashy situations.
Speaker 0: yet It is working 100% Well, but anyway, so the batteries finally running out of steam has been about two years gonna buy a new phone I look at.
Speaker 0: sure enough There is a brand new like just coming out the latest iteration of that same kind of phone.
Speaker 0: however Upon looking at it.
Speaker 0: It's bigger.
Speaker 0: It's like a Taller.
Speaker 0: Even the compact version of this phone now is starting to grow.
Speaker 0: Also, it looks really fugly.
Speaker 0: But last year they released an updated version.
Speaker 0: That is basically just a far superior version of the phone I already have and because it's a year-old design It costs hundreds of dollars less.
Speaker 0: so I just bought it and for the first time in my life.
Speaker 0: I am buying a new phone.
Speaker 0: Before my old phone was actually unusable.
Speaker 1: You didn't break it on purpose to feel better about yourself.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean you I really do.
Speaker 0: Well, like you broke your computer so you could upgrade your computer.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you definitely did except that Yeah, then gave that computer to someone who then recognized.
Speaker 1: It was definitely broke.
Speaker 0: Oh, no you broke it and they fixed it.
Speaker 1: How can I break a computer in that specific way?
Speaker 0: Uh Even if I wanted to you set the RAM timing wrong, I assume you were smart enough to set it, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, I always trust auto and every look.
Speaker 0: Uh-huh.
Speaker 0: Yeah, just trust auto the one always just one part of your life.
Speaker 0: You just trust the auto configuration even though you should have known better.
Speaker 1: I trust auto in all parts of my life.
Speaker 1: I default everything.
Speaker 1: that's my policy.
Speaker 0: Yeah, uh-huh.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I didn't know that your motherboards default is some weird overclocking nonsense.
Speaker 1: Yeah, why is the default wrong?
Speaker 1: That's a good question.
Speaker 0: Why didn't you know what the default does?
Speaker 0: I just do why'd you bride you set up your computer to break so you could buy a new one?
Speaker 0: Anyway, I bought a new phone.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna review it on Monday cuz it's coming tomorrow cuz I live in a city.
Speaker 0: if I buy anything on Amazon it arrives either The same day or the next day.
Speaker 0: so it's gonna be.
Speaker 0: it'll be waiting for me when I get home.
Speaker 0: The funny thing is our friend Chris Reimer who many of you know as the last name I say in the patreon call-outs at the end of the show every week.
Speaker 1: I thought what happened to Thomas Hahn?
Speaker 0: well and Thomas Hahn Chris Reimer and Thomas Hahn And if they ever change the order it's gonna really fuck me up.
Speaker 1: They should Thomas Hahn get out.
Speaker 0: the only way to change the orders to change the amount of money They give us.
Speaker 1: no Thomas Hahn could go to zero and then go back to stay at zero cuz that's the smart.
Speaker 0: Then I wouldn't say his name.
Speaker 1: good So everyone go to zero.
Speaker 1: us the wise thing to do.
Speaker 0: hey that money is gonna fund our conventions gonna fund that graphic design thing You're trying to do.
Speaker 1: No, it's gonna fund Church of the beach.
Speaker 0: Nah, so yes to fund the church on the beach We would the picture under have to be a couple.
Speaker 0: order may orders of magnitude above.
Speaker 0: in fact, that is a stretch goal.
Speaker 0: There is an amount of money that is formally in the patreon And if we hit that amount We will quit our jobs and go to the beach and the only thing we'll do is make this Person with more money than you know what to do with.
Speaker 1: It's a lot of money.
Speaker 1: They should get on that everyone else zero.
Speaker 1: Oh Yeah, if there's a well-known out zero rich person the full amount.
Speaker 1: if there is a wealthy benefactor out there who wants to fund us For some reason I don't think rich people like ignites because of how much we smack talk about how evil and bad rich people are there.
Speaker 0: I know a small number of pretty rich people who listen and I don't know a lot about them, but they listen to the show and I know about them.
Speaker 1: All right, I've talked to them.
Speaker 1: All right rich person you have so much money.
Speaker 1: It's just a giant number in a bank account that does not affect your life in any way But you can dramatically change our lives better.
Speaker 1: yet the lives of someone who deserves it more than we do.
Speaker 1: What the fuck are you doing?
Speaker 1: Yeah, I feel like you won't even notice anything Tomorrow.
Speaker 1: just be numbers will be different big fucking wolf.
Speaker 0: I feel like they should skip funding us and go right down to someone who needs it more.
Speaker 1: That's what I'm saying.
Speaker 0: Patreon for Ignite should be zero, but uh, yeah, so red system with there's a lot of news to talk about.
Speaker 0: We're avoiding talking about all the breaking news where we don't have anything new to add to the conversation.
Speaker 0: There is nothing news, but there is some pretty big news that we have a lot to say about.
Speaker 0: Is there it's your news?
Speaker 1: All right Okay, so the news is Ford which is I guess a big car company if you're in America But I guess the rest of the world doesn't necessarily give that much of a shit about.
Speaker 1: I have no idea how Ford sells Internationally, yeah, I've seen Ford's in other countries, but not much.
Speaker 1: I've never owned a Ford Yeah, but anyway, so we had Ford's some tourists and I had.
Speaker 0: I was all Plymouth Pontiac like that was where I went.
Speaker 1: anyway Ford is a big-deal car company because the name comes from Henry Ford who is the first person with a First one with a car factory the Model T the first car Yeah, I mean, I guess technically there may have been other cars before the Model T Maybe but there was the first mass-produced car that everyone could buy who had money, you
Speaker 0: know so fun side story when I when my when I was a kid and moving it in high school my family moved and we bought a house and The person who owned the house that we were buying it from when we were inspecting a Model T. We go into the garage.
Speaker 0: It's just a Model T there and we're like, oh, that's cool.
Speaker 0: And she's like, oh, yeah I want to go for a ride.
Speaker 0: She was using it as her primary car.
Speaker 1: Why not?
Speaker 1: Yeah people do that.
Speaker 1: It works.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's real simple.
Speaker 1: Anyone can fix it.
Speaker 1: You can fix that engine with like pliers screwdriver wrench and easy acknowledge Model T running than some other car cuz it's just so straightforward.
Speaker 1: It's like, you know, if you'd like a part breaks you could just make the replacement part probably anyway.
Speaker 1: So, yeah for the news is that Ford the car company is only gonna be making two cars from now on.
Speaker 1: no more tourists no more.
Speaker 1: the only cars that are sedans know.
Speaker 1: the only car they're making now is the Mustang and There's one Ford Focus model that's kind of sporty and the otherwise they're only making trucks and SUVs.
Speaker 1: fuck all other models now.
Speaker 0: I think there's a lot of reasons why this is big news.
Speaker 0: one Car companies traditional ones tend to move very slowly and tend to make incremental change and very rarely will do a big Part of it is because they're old-fashioned big businesses.
Speaker 1: But also part of it is because you got a big old car factory.
Speaker 1: you got things away in advance.
Speaker 1: You can't just suddenly change the car factory suddenly close one suddenly open one suddenly retool one.
Speaker 1: It's not easy It takes time, but I even if they had decided to do this years ago It would have taken until now to actually make it happen.
Speaker 1: But the
Speaker 0: reason I think this is big news is that a lot of the car industry like commercialization model shall we say has relied forever at least for modern history on taking the identity of a person and Getting them to attach that identity to a car brand and then tying the idea of owning to a car to all these Fundamental aspects of American life like freedom and adulthood.
Speaker 1: Well, I think in other countries cars are marketed differently.
Speaker 1: But oh, yeah about America specific cars are marketed in America.
Speaker 1: Is that?
Speaker 1: it's like this whole marketing cultural thing.
Speaker 1: There's a car culture and an advertising culture.
Speaker 0: cars are most.
Speaker 1: the ads are car.
Speaker 0: Yes I'm pretty sure the majority of all ads in America are car ads and their sole goal is to Drive that brand recognition.
Speaker 0: and it's very interesting that when when I got adblock and never had didn't have TV anymore in high school Within a like five or six years.
Speaker 0: I didn't know what the current like makes and models of cars were anymore.
Speaker 0: I mean, I know the ones that have been around forever Yeah but I didn't know about new ones like I did.
Speaker 0: I just didn't know whereas previously that was basic common knowledge that I just Learned through osmosis from ads.
Speaker 1: but anyway.
Speaker 1: So what's happened over the years is through a combination of marketing but also other factors American people who live in car places have leaned towards driving trucks and Truck-like vehicles like SUVs or crossovers or whatever the hell you want to call
Speaker 0: partly because those are vehicles that actually have very Utilitarian purposes and also partly because those areas tend to ski more conservative and conservative people tend to ski more toward trucks SUVs.
Speaker 1: there's some.
Speaker 1: there's cultural reasons, but there's other reasons right?
Speaker 1: It's like my mom drives like.
Speaker 1: I think it's like a Subaru something.
Speaker 1: It's right, but the main reason that you know, she drives that instead of a car, but she drove like most of her life.
Speaker 1: It's just as higher off the ground.
Speaker 1: it's like more comfortable to be up there.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I can say that it's like, you know, it's those sorts of reasons Like if you're driving a car after driving, you know, like like, you know, like a van or a truck You just feel like your ass is on the ground.
Speaker 1: You see all these other people are driving the cars that are way up above you.
Speaker 1: now It's harder to see around them.
Speaker 1: It creates this whole sort of like arms race almost but it's also a comfort You know.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's you know, it's like, you know, there's all tons and tons of reasons for this.
Speaker 1: but effectively all this marketing and whatnot stuff worked.
Speaker 1: and now most people who drive cars in the United States want a truck or non sedan non car non coupe.
Speaker 0: most of the Industry and press and paid press I've read for the last decade because car sales have been on the decline in America, right?
Speaker 0: They have been making this consistent argument Paid argument like it wasn't journalists writing these things It was paid journalists like those fake stories.
Speaker 0: But they all had the same narrative that car sales are down because Millennials don't have money.
Speaker 0: Not for any other far more intrinsic reason.
Speaker 0: But I've always believed and I'm pretty confident This is still true.
Speaker 0: The reality is that a lot of Millennials want to live in places where they don't need to have a car.
Speaker 0: Have been more willing to not have a car.
Speaker 0: and it's not just that they can't afford them It's that they don't want them.
Speaker 1: I don't want one.
Speaker 1: and further
Speaker 0: even when Millennials and younger people want cars They're much more resistant to advertising than the industry projected and they don't give a shit What kind of car most people I can think of who I've talked to her younger than me who are actually like getting a car.
Speaker 0: I care about cars.
Speaker 0: They want the cheapest car that will let them drive to the thing.
Speaker 0: They need to drive to.
Speaker 1: yes They literally don't person the person who has grown up on the internet.
Speaker 1: Right in terms of culture they buy a car.
Speaker 0: the way they buy a cell.
Speaker 1: they may care about clothes or shoes Or their phone or their computer Office chair than a car.
Speaker 1: right these sorts of things they care about.
Speaker 1: but the car like it's like they don't.
Speaker 1: Car nerdery has gone way way down in you know, the years, right?
Speaker 1: So, you know It's only certain the number of people who are nerdy for cars is very much decreased and thus Pretty much anyone who's my age who buys a car who has to buy a car gets like a Honda Civic and keeps it forever as long as it works.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: So case in point when I was in high school I needed like my own care more about like the fact that their iPhone integrates well with this sound system in the car.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and what kind of engine it has or anything like that?
Speaker 0: My old car.
Speaker 1: a lot of people are in I know are interested in like, you know electric car super efficient car Yeah things of that nature.
Speaker 0: And I am too if I ever buy a car again one It has to be at least a like minimally self-driving and to probably getting something that's electric I'm I'm just holding out until they're.
Speaker 1: you know, I don't have to own the car.
Speaker 1: There's just self-driving cars about And I just call one I don't.
Speaker 1: they just come up to me and I get in them.
Speaker 0: but when I was in RIT and my previous car had literally the engine had exploded and I needed a new car because living in Rochester without a car Sucked ass.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 0: So we need we as a group needed a car.
Speaker 0: I was the one who had the most money and the ability to buy a car.
Speaker 0: so I bought a car and I remember going to car lots and like trying to buy a used car and Hating every second of it because I literally didn't care.
Speaker 0: I just wanted the cheapest car that would work and ended up buying this purple Sunfire.
Speaker 0: and Apparently no one was buying this thing because it was purple.
Speaker 0: Mmm.
Speaker 0: So I got it for like 10 grand and I didn't care even when I bought.
Speaker 0: I bought a Until it literally died.
Speaker 1: right.
Speaker 1: when I when I had to drive a whole bunch living in Beacon in 2006 I bought a brand new Mazda 3 cuz it was nice.
Speaker 1: I had a hatch which is way useful for carrying shit to conventions.
Speaker 1: that we're doing a lot at the time.
Speaker 1: Also putting a bike in the hatch stuff like that tons of groceries in the hatch.
Speaker 1: Yeah Anyway, but it was super nice car.
Speaker 0: We lived out in it when I lived upstate.
Speaker 1: you me and Emily each had our own car But even then it was sort of like they're like.
Speaker 1: what color do you want?
Speaker 1: And I'm like, I don't give a shit.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like it's like which one.
Speaker 1: All right, you're getting this coppery orange color.
Speaker 1: That's like exclusive to like.
Speaker 1: fine.
Speaker 1: Whatever.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there's a cost more.
Speaker 1: No fine.
Speaker 1: Give me that one.
Speaker 0: I remember you were looking at the Volkswagen and that salesperson kept being like listen to the sound.
Speaker 0: the door
Speaker 1: Money had less space in it But it had heated seats and less fuel-efficient and also the Volkswagen dealership had a huge line at the service area
Speaker 0: Yeah, but she kept trying to sell you on like the identity of the car and you were just like I do not give one fuck.
Speaker 0: It was really funny cuz I was in the backseat While she was trying to sell you on this fucking car.
Speaker 1: Well, cuz it's about like the feel right?
Speaker 1: It's sort of like you're just like luxury goods, right?
Speaker 1: They feel a certain way.
Speaker 1: It's like the they must have constructed the doors and such in such a way where like it just gives a really satisfying Closing sound right like it, you know in the joint on the door just feels like really satisfying.
Speaker 1: to close Yeah, and it's like they're trying to sell you on that.
Speaker 1: but it's like sure that you know, it feels interesting and you know You know it like.
Speaker 1: but it's sort of like you're getting a really nice pencil.
Speaker 1: It writes the same even though it just feels nice in your yeah, like ooh, it's like it's not worth thousands of dollars Yeah, and also there's that cost fallacy where if you're buying a big thing then Incremental it increases in that cost.
Speaker 0: most people do not value them accordingly.
Speaker 0: So if you're buying a two hundred thousand dollar house, which I wish there were two hundred thousand dollar houses here It's not great.
Speaker 1: not here not no not right here.
Speaker 1: No.
Speaker 0: Yeah actually in beacon there really aren't $200,000 house.
Speaker 0: there you can.
Speaker 0: I've seen the $200,000 house.
Speaker 1: I looked at in beacon was a meth lab.
Speaker 1: I've seen some things that are like trailers that are not moving.
Speaker 1: Trailers are $200,000 On a plot a tiny plot of land.
Speaker 0: but people who people who are buying a $200,000 house will not think that much of a $10,000 swing in either direction, but if they're buying a $10,000 car they will care a lot about a $10,000 swing in either direction.
Speaker 0: as they're buying a $5 sandwich They'll care a lot about a $1 swing in either direction.
Speaker 0: People just have a terrible time of valuation, but I do that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I do it too.
Speaker 0: It's it's it's human nature.
Speaker 0: It's very difficult to avoid that quandary.
Speaker 1: I'm already spending this much.
Speaker 1: What a $1 more.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like that's a whole bagel extra.
Speaker 1: you're giving them an extra bait.
Speaker 0: I spent $40 more on the new cell phone.
Speaker 0: I just bought because I got the blue one instead of the black one and in retrospect $40 is like two pretty good meals in New York City.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like pretty good with like an appetizer.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think to not turn this into a whole show that this news from Ford Indicates a seismic shift in the car industry in the United States Consequence of a seismic shift that already happened.
Speaker 0: Yes, I agree.
Speaker 0: This is the consequence of a seismic shift.
Speaker 0: SUV ain't new but the seismic shift is that a car company Admitted that this is happening and is trying to get ahead of it.
Speaker 0: All the other car cover all the way behind it are kind of fucked and it's shocking that Ford is the one that was like Wow, this is happening.
Speaker 0: Here we go.
Speaker 1: Well some companies right?
Speaker 1: So like I talk about Honda Civic It's like well Honda's Japanese company There's yeah, they get they're selling those civics everywhere in the world.
Speaker 1: And this is only happening in America.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I like how you still say America to this day because the other cut you see SUVs rolling and you know, Like I don't know Japan.
Speaker 0: I'm just still shocked that I see SUVs rolling here.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like how do you park that thing?
Speaker 0: and the answer seems to be you don't.
Speaker 1: people drop them in New York for some reason.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so I guess it'll be real interesting to see how this shakes down over the next decade.
Speaker 1: No more Ford Taurus a legendary car.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So in some other news, it's just sort of fascinating that this happened.
Speaker 0: So I know a lot about Serial killers.
Speaker 1: All right is great.
Speaker 0: Okay, next topic in this because when I was a kid remember I watched vampire 100 D when I was in fourth grade.
Speaker 1: What is vampire hundred?
Speaker 1: you had to do a serial killer because my mom really wanted me to said I watched sounds of the Lambs, I also at least make sense.
Speaker 0: I watched Silence of the Lambs when I was in elementary school.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean I saw it also hood.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I remember when but I definitely saw when I was you know.
Speaker 0: But my family like my mom was really into like horror fiction and true crime stuff and disease stuff and all these things.
Speaker 0: So I just was very interested in those things as well as a child.
Speaker 0: So I knew a lot about like scary diseases and serial killers and horror nonsense.
Speaker 1: My mom was into horror but more aliens vampires.
Speaker 0: Oh, we were also into that.
Speaker 0: I was reading Lovecraft like Back when my elementary school teacher actually went to my parents and said do you know your son has that book?
Speaker 0: and they were like?
Speaker 0: what?
Speaker 0: lol Of course, he does.
Speaker 0: But anyway, the Golden State Killer was kind of a really extra terrifying serial killer.
Speaker 0: I've never heard of him before.
Speaker 0: Yeah a long time ago What's crazy is they just arrested this guy?
Speaker 0: Now good like 40 years after he was an active serial killer slash rapist good, and the whole story behind this thing is Ridiculous and the kinds of crowd like this is a class of crime like the way it happened.
Speaker 0: That literally could not happen in a modern urban setting or even a modern suburban setting like it couldn't have gone on as long as it did.
Speaker 0: and it's crazy and the whole story about it is crazy and It is very.
Speaker 0: I guess it speaks well to one tiny aspect of American law enforcement that Despite all the other very obvious problems that I could point to in terms of American law enforcement The fact that the the system existed to catch this dude this late is still amazing.
Speaker 1: I mean that's you know for all.
Speaker 0: that's the thing is like like there are good jobs who try to catch people like this.
Speaker 1: Well, no, I mean it's just even the bad cops try to catch people like this.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah
Speaker 0: They just also shoot random innocent black people for no reason
Speaker 1: right is that that's the thing that they do is they'll be like they're Actually doing their job and you know enforcing the laws, you know, yeah
Speaker 0: I guess part of their job is maintaining this racist status quo,
Speaker 1: right.
Speaker 1: and then if you try to say hey Stop doing the bad stuff you do they'll say well look at the stuff that we're doing that we're supposed to do Right, and that's the thing that you know, it's like yeah They do what they're supposed to do and they also do these other bad things at the same time.
Speaker 1: But also just doing a good job today does not excuse doing an evil thing tomorrow.
Speaker 0: But also the nuance I want to point out is that this is the biggest like.
Speaker 0: it is big news.
Speaker 0: It's crazy news.
Speaker 0: It's a crazy story.
Speaker 0: but also if they had just ignored this guy and Maybe shot a few less innocent people it probably would have been a net benefit to society.
Speaker 0: But anyway things of the day.
Speaker 0: What do you got?
Speaker 1: So check this out?
Speaker 1: I don't know if I use this already I forget but I don't think so.
Speaker 0: I don't know anything about this.
Speaker 1: Okay, so check this out.
Speaker 1: It's an NES ROM.
Speaker 1: It's a file.
Speaker 1: It's a series of zeros and ones on your file system and they add the file name ends and dot NES and you can open It up in your NES emulator and run it because it's a valid NES ROM.
Speaker 1: You could put it onto a cartridge and put it in NES and it would run and a game would appear.
Speaker 1: I don't know what the game looks like.
Speaker 1: I haven't tried to run it, but it's an NES file.
Speaker 1: Anyway at the same time if you take those exact same set of zeros and ones and you just rename the file To dot zip it is also a zip file.
Speaker 1: It is a zip file and an NES file the same set of zeros and ones.
Speaker 1: and if you were to unzip That ROM which is also a zip file out would come some source code Like actual source code and if you were to run that source code through a compiler Out would come the set of zeros and ones that is an NES ROM and also a zip file.
Speaker 0: I don't even know what to say about this.
Speaker 1: the end.
Speaker 1: This is like that you could you could compile it and unzip it and then take the stuff that comes out and compile it and unzip And any one of those zips could be run in the emulator.
Speaker 0: I've seen stuff like the recursive script of a dolphin or whatever or like the cell compile But this takes it to a level that is Amazing.
Speaker 0: It's like the speed will Fun like toy code exercises like this become the speed running of computer science.
Speaker 1: yeah, you're gonna need a copy.
Speaker 1: if you want to do actually do this, you're gonna need zip Python 3 and ASM 6. it's the assembly compiler because the source code that comes out is assembly Right, this is amazing.
Speaker 1: If you try to use some other assembler, it might not assemble into the exact set of zeros and ones.
Speaker 0: Yeah, anyway, so there's a song Scott hadn't heard it which I'm kind of surprised by.
Speaker 0: but if you poke around in the red parts of the internet parts of this song or remixes of parts of the song are used in a shockingly wide variety of memes and gifs with sound type things like.
Speaker 0: You'll hear this song a lot if you're in the right parts of the Internet.
Speaker 0: Most people don't seem to know anything about where the song came from what the deal is with it.
Speaker 0: I'll play a snippet at the end of the show and you'll I'm pretty sure something you'll be like.
Speaker 0: Oh that song.
Speaker 1: I hadn't heard the song before but you can tell from the instrumentation That it is a Commodore 64 song because it sounds like it's coming from a SID chip and it is yep.
Speaker 0: but the song is Rob Hubbard's Monty on the run theme from a Commodore 64 game called Monty on the run.
Speaker 1: never heard of this game.
Speaker 0: You don't need to play the game.
Speaker 0: It is not worth playing in the modern era at any point.
Speaker 1: but Commodore 64 games universally almost universally have amazing music because that's what the system had the capability for.
Speaker 1: and among those games the soundtrack to Monty on the run I think until exceptional I think until like the Super Nintendo and Genesis the Commodore 64 still had better audio than like any other Non-computer, but I cannot stress to you how good this song is.
Speaker 0: Well, this soundtrack is and I implore you to listen to this entire thing In the meta moment.
Speaker 0: the geek nights book club book is homas the Odyssey translated by Emily Wilson.
Speaker 1: Not some other translation.
Speaker 1: only the Emily Wilson.
Speaker 0: true only the Emily Wilson one.
Speaker 0: I'm.
Speaker 0: uh, I'm still really into it and you guys should just read it.
Speaker 0: If you've never read the Odyssey just read this translation.
Speaker 1: Don't bother easiest of the Odyssey translations I have seen to read and understand because it is in a modern language and not Pretend old language.
Speaker 0: if you've read the Odyssey before Read this Anyway, I think you'll have a very different perception of some of the aspects of the Odyssey when read through modern language.
Speaker 0: I'm on our educated pop-up book.
Speaker 0: Pop-up book Odyssey is also real good But even the pop-up book Odyssey does not really drive home the degree to which Slavery was a part of pre-greek society.
Speaker 1: There's also a lot more Agamemnon in the pop-up book Odyssey that was not yet appeared in the text.
Speaker 0: Is there any Lega lamb?
Speaker 0: none?
Speaker 1: I hope so.
Speaker 0: I got Otherwise geek nights But me not Scott will be live not this weekend, but next weekend at Zenkai con in Lancaster, Pennsylvania.
Speaker 0: It's gonna be amazing.
Speaker 1: No, it's not.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it is.
Speaker 1: It's gonna be a waste of your week.
Speaker 0: I don't know why you're so down on those con.
Speaker 0: I have a great time every year.
Speaker 1: It's Lancaster, Pennsylvania is not a place you want to go.
Speaker 0: I have more fun and I'm gonna be honest I have had more fun at the average Zenkai con than I did at the average anime Boston even at the peak of our going to anime Boston because all our board game friends go and all I do other than doing our panels is eat awesome like farm-to-table food or Play board games.
Speaker 1: You just break your microphone stand on purpose So you could buy a new one.
Speaker 0: No, I just popped the spring off because it pops off really easily.
Speaker 1: You just broke it.
Speaker 0: No spring just lashes on here It's not it's not.
Speaker 0: an intrinsic property of this literally the cheapest microphone boom on Amazon.
Speaker 0: Okay, so And other meta things we're looking to hire a graphic designer.
Speaker 0: We talked about it a lot in the previous show.
Speaker 0: if you think you could fully rebrand geek nights
Speaker 1: Professionally like
Speaker 0: we're talking like
Speaker 1: press
Speaker 0: kits logos
Speaker 1: like if you're ever like
Speaker 0: ocean graphics
Speaker 1: Right someone who is pro level like you could do it for a legit company that people know the name of level Because you're gonna be paid at probably at least four digits worth of money for this job.
Speaker 1: Yeah, not more.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's a real job.
Speaker 1: You're gonna pay money.
Speaker 1: You got to be real good to do this job, right?
Speaker 1: We're not looking for someone who's does graphic design for like you local eSports team or you local small business because frankly our website Looks like web 2.0 point one, right?
Speaker 1: The idea is to get something done that's so good that it can last for like fucking ever and be timeless.
Speaker 1: You know the way like, you know, like the greatest logo like a McDonald's timeless, right?
Speaker 1: Obviously, we're not gonna get that level like one or two levels under that.
Speaker 0: hungry for apples.
Speaker 1: Yeah So there are many places on the internet Besides this podcast and you should come find us in all those places.
Speaker 1: if you think about places that exist on the internet YouTube Twitter Even Facebook, I guess if you haven't deleted your account.
Speaker 1: We're in those places.
Speaker 1: Come find us there.
Speaker 0: seriously Just type the word geek nights into Google and a lot of different things appear.
Speaker 0: We pretty much only one word.
Speaker 1: there's no space in the middle.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I wonder what happens if I put a space in the middle.
Speaker 1: try it and see Same thing.
Speaker 0: Okay, same list.
Speaker 0: All right geek nights podcast on TV tropes.
Speaker 1: Who made a TV tropes page?
Speaker 1: that's been there for a long time.
Speaker 0: I guess I never noticed.
Speaker 0: Okay interesting anyway, so we're not going to talk about these specifics of Universal fan con.
Speaker 0: it is just the most recent Egregious convention failure.
Speaker 1: It is my opinion and not all these things are conventions.
Speaker 1: There was.
Speaker 1: there was the the the thing that was higher festival.
Speaker 1: Yeah fire festival and dash come.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I guess what the what we want to talk about - can't happen.
Speaker 0: it technically happened.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we didn't happen again.
Speaker 0: No, but go thing.
Speaker 0: there's been a rash of Multiple kinds of convention failures lately.
Speaker 0: We've done shows on major
Speaker 1: major events Yeah festival failures as well Expos,
Speaker 0: but they've broken down into sort of three categories and one of those categories I think is something that we need to talk about because I think this is I feel like the problem We're about to describe is going to get a lot worse before it gets better.
Speaker 1: I've seen it getting worse.
Speaker 1: So it's like I can see.
Speaker 1: the snowball has already rolled halfway down the hill and it ain't stopping.
Speaker 1: Yep, so you got anyone who doesn't see that snowball halfway down the hill better open the eyes.
Speaker 0: so the first thing we're not going to talk about are conventions and events that happen But are just really shitty like - con like - con or lie Chris - con ages into the second category heavily.
Speaker 0: There's a there's a Venn diagram here and at the center is a lot of sad kids who show up in a time.
Speaker 1: For example the first Ohio con we went to right.
Speaker 1: it was a con.
Speaker 1: it happened right they ran it.
Speaker 1: It was just a lot of failures at the actual event.
Speaker 1: Yeah Logistically and otherwise like to the point that we would never go back, you know, there's the sit-a-con we went to.
Speaker 1: yeah It was just like.
Speaker 1: well it actually happened but the turnout was just like.
Speaker 0: it wasn't a scam.
Speaker 0: It just sucked right.
Speaker 1: It's like there's a lot of people.
Speaker 1: they run a convention.
Speaker 1: They make it happen They put on the event like Philly wizard world happened a bunch of times.
Speaker 1: It's either you know, maybe it's just.
Speaker 1: maybe it happens and it's just a bad convention.
Speaker 1: Maybe it happens and no one shows up or maybe that happens in this logistical failures at the thing.
Speaker 1: But they happen, right?
Speaker 0: I gotta get interrupt.
Speaker 0: someone pointed when we're talking about the graphic design Someone just said in the chat.
Speaker 0: What if we dig spelled capital di GG your website's current look Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: That's it.
Speaker 0: That's the appropriate level of burn for our current website.
Speaker 0: But anyway, yeah We're not talking about conventions that just suck or fail in the traditional sense.
Speaker 0: But that is the thing that happens.
Speaker 0: There's another kind of convention that fails Before it happens or fails in a way that prevents the event from continuing Almost always either because it was oversold and the fire marshal shut it down Or the people who ran it were so incompetent that they failed to do things like Put the requisite deposit down for the convention center
Speaker 1: have insurance Yep,
Speaker 0: have enough money to pay for the things you need to pay for during the event,
Speaker 1: right?
Speaker 1: So like the the the fire festival right is everyone showed up to this place But like they didn't have water for people to yeah, like there wasn't an event.
Speaker 1: I don't remember the details But I remember.
Speaker 1: I vaguely remember something like there weren't toilets to go in of course.
Speaker 1: So suddenly you've got a group of people in a place and now it's just.
Speaker 1: it's unfunctionable.
Speaker 1: Right as opposed to say like Ohio con where it's like Oh The tournaments didn't happen or the video game systems weren't.
Speaker 0: like we show up in Baltimore And an anime convention that we pre-registered for net hotel for just isn't happening.
Speaker 0: Like we show up at the convention center The doors are locked and that's it.
Speaker 1: a whole bunch of people go to PAX They're outside the doors and they can't get in that things aren't set up on the inside.
Speaker 0: now It's interesting.
Speaker 0: you mentioned fire festival.
Speaker 1: Someone shows up to their panel.
Speaker 1: There's just no equipment and no enforcer.
Speaker 0: pretty sure some Charges were filed around fire festival because here's the third part and this is where things get interesting.
Speaker 0: I also want to say very clearly right now.
Speaker 0: We're not lawyers.
Speaker 0: We are not making specific Accusations against specific events who may have know enough about any of them to do so.
Speaker 0: But fire festival and Fan con and conventions like it.
Speaker 0: there is a line between it failed because the people who ran it sucked And it failed because it was designed to fail and was actually a scam, right?
Speaker 1: It's hard to tell the difference and sometimes you'll never even know the difference and it doesn't matter It's the same thing either way now.
Speaker 0: I suspect very strongly that there are Actual events that have happened in the last several years that were scams from the beginning.
Speaker 0: Yes And I feel like they're going to be a lot of these because of the more fundamental problem one.
Speaker 0: as we learn from black beauty Ignorance and malice have the exact same effect on it on their victims.
Speaker 0: So it does not matter why a convention fails in this matter.
Speaker 0: It harms people who try to attend it the same way.
Speaker 0: but also there's this extra weird problem that is specifically to certain kinds of conventions and events where there are a lot of people both on the on the privileged side who know things about these events and have worldly experience and on the underprivileged side who literally don't have Experience with these things like people have never been to a concert never been to a convention.
Speaker 0: in both groups There's a huge percentage of people who are willing to give other people Large amounts of money To attend events that they assume will exist because there's a website that says that event exists.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean this people willing to give people money just because the website has a thing on it for not just conventions But anything.
Speaker 1: yeah, it's like.
Speaker 1: I don't really.
Speaker 1: I think a lot of this actually comes down to not necessarily conventions.
Speaker 1: conventions like a special most egregious case of a larger problem of simply Pre-crowdfunding anything right.
Speaker 1: someone puts up a fake board game.
Speaker 1: everyone pays money because they want the board game.
Speaker 1: the board game never ships.
Speaker 1: Yep, right It's the same thing.
Speaker 1: the difference is that when it's a convention or an event of large scale right or moderate scale People not only you know pay like oh, I pay $40 or a board game that I never get.
Speaker 1: I'm out 40 bucks, which could be a big deal for the convention.
Speaker 0: Okay, like a first night at the hotel.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you're not only you're also.
Speaker 1: probably you can cancel your hotel rooms up to 24 hours in advance depends.
Speaker 0: So there's but flights.
Speaker 1: know you're boned.
Speaker 0: There is an icing trend.
Speaker 1: actually he's already putting your vacation days at work.
Speaker 0: You or who knows maybe you're vending at it and you shipped things to the convention.
Speaker 1: Maybe yeah, you started printing and manufacturing merchandise.
Speaker 1: You started, you know marketing.
Speaker 0: I don't have one out Scott.
Speaker 0: There's been a trend increasingly with a lot of conventions where the hotel blocks have policies of a week or a month in advance.
Speaker 1: Never seen that before.
Speaker 0: I have seen it many times in the last three or four years.
Speaker 1: I've never seen a hotel reservation.
Speaker 1: That was the longest I've seen is 48 hours.
Speaker 1: I have seen No, I don't deny it.
Speaker 1: But I'm just saying I've never personally never seen more than 40 seen one month for multiple events recently.
Speaker 0: And I have seen events that I did not go to Where the policy was you cannot cancel a hotel if you book it through the conventions block.
Speaker 0: And this is happening because the idea of hotel blocks is becoming obsolete because literally any major event will sell out every hotel in every City anyway, so no one has an incentive like no hotel.
Speaker 0: Well has any reason to provide discounted rooms anymore?
Speaker 1: No, not discounted But the incentive is for the events to partner with the hotels to make sure that those Rooms are set aside for its attendees and not for people doing anything else in town.
Speaker 1: Otherwise the convention won't get enough people coming to it because they can't get rooms and it'll hurt the convention itself.
Speaker 1: So the hotels can actually if your event is selling out.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you can charge the events say hey give us money It's a lot set these room asides for you.
Speaker 0: But the hotels increasingly can back away from the traditional SLA of canceling hotels.
Speaker 0: But anyway, that's a sort of side problem.
Speaker 1: But yeah The point is is that when it's a convention that people are crowdfunding and paying for in advance People are putting in a lot more investment and they get way way way more boned when it fails.
Speaker 1: Maybe they've even like you've gone to the place and then found that it failed.
Speaker 1: now They really have been super boned, right?
Speaker 1: You actually flew to a place stayed in the hotel went to a town and there's nothing there.
Speaker 0: So that latter part is what extra terrifies because it's one thing if someone gets scanned by a website and buys a board game That doesn't exist.
Speaker 0: but if someone Does enough research to know say like, you know The examples from packs where there are people who have never been to a packs before who know that a particular YouTube streamer is Performing at this packs in a particular room not performing appearing.
Speaker 0: Yeah appearing not music.
Speaker 0: So this person knows that this event exists and that a person they want to see is going to be in a room at this convention
Speaker 1: But do
Speaker 0: not know what
Speaker 1: day
Speaker 0: of the event that person is in the room and make arrangements to travel to the event Anyway, and then make a terrible mistake because the event was on Saturday instead of Friday Mm-hmm, though the number of people then I have a lot of experience
Speaker 1: Specifically doesn't post the schedule until very close to the actual convention.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and you have to buy your tickets way way way in advance.
Speaker 1: And if you really if you're going there to see, you know, your markiplier, are you buying all four days?
Speaker 0: Ah, but this is the thing.
Speaker 0: people who attend conventions and having worked on a lot of conventions over the years Not just attended them I can say that a huge percentage of the people who go to nerd cons literally do Zero research about the event before they attend.
Speaker 1: somehow they get there.
Speaker 0: Yeah But like they don't know that hotels charge sales tax and can't pay for their room like.
Speaker 1: so How can how can the person that ignorant and clueless possibly be able to tell a real convention from a scam convention?
Speaker 0: So I think what I want to talk about right now is how to tell the difference between a convention that's likely to occur Versus a contention that is likely to not occur or fail in some disastrous way.
Speaker 0: Rule number one if it is a first-year convention.
Speaker 0: There's already like a 20% chance of failure, right?
Speaker 1: So a first-year convention, even if it's trying to honestly happen is so difficult Especially if the people doing it don't have a lot of experience doing it So many ways it can fail in so many different categories That it's like the odds of failure are very very high even if everything that they're trying hard and they're honest.
Speaker 1: So if it's a first-year convention now, here's the thing.
Speaker 1: if I just say don't go to first-year conventions That's bad because especially because we want to do a convention Well, no, but you're basically saying not just that but yeah You're basically saying look the conventions we have are the only ones we can ever have.
Speaker 1: We should never have competition We should never have new ideas or anything.
Speaker 1: No, we need to have new conventions.
Speaker 1: the more the merrier Right, but how do we make sure that people aren't taking risks and going to first-year conventions that are too risky?
Speaker 1: And here's my advice.
Speaker 0: It's real simple All right I'm curious what your advice is.
Speaker 1: now my only go to a first-year convention if it's a Near you and that it's not a really big deal and B Don't pre-register or pre-order a first-year convention should not and will not sell out because it's brand new.
Speaker 1: buy tickets at the door.
Speaker 0: Here's the problem.
Speaker 0: Most first-year conventions either do a Kickstarter or Need a certain amount of pre-regis to even happen.
Speaker 1: I would not kickstart a Either so cheap or very close to me so I don't have to risk the hotel.
Speaker 1: I would only be risking the price of the badge and such.
Speaker 0: Yep So I think a more nuanced approach is if a first-year convention Targets and attendance of more than a few hundred people Avoid like the plague.
Speaker 0: Yes Because it is unless that first-year convention is being run by a corporation like the new anime convention, New York City.
Speaker 0: It's run by a real company that has real employees who have experience running big conventions in the Jacob Javits Center Right, for example, I'm confident that convention have like Disney.
Speaker 1: I think is gonna do some.
Speaker 1: you know They've always had the Star Wars con.
Speaker 1: There's gonna be Disney Con.
Speaker 1: You know, it's legit.
Speaker 0: It has bro runs of My Little Pony con.
Speaker 0: I'm pretty sure it'll happen right, but if Someone on Kickstarter is kick-starting their My Little Pony Steven Universe con and they're gonna have an artist alley and they're gonna have 10,000 people attend that convention is almost guaranteed either going to fail or is actually a scam.
Speaker 1: If you see like a small first-year convention, right?
Speaker 1: Usually if you're like you're trying to suss out how legit it is, right?
Speaker 1: Check that guest list, right and Try to meet.
Speaker 1: if those guests one of them is gonna be someone you want to see.
Speaker 1: otherwise, why you going?
Speaker 1: yeah Contact them.
Speaker 1: Ah, so y'all cuz if there's a first-year con the guest isn't gonna be so big you can't contact them Right.
Speaker 0: Well if they are if there's a first-year con and their guests are like Barack Obama and carrot top Something's up.
Speaker 1: Yeah I don't know why carrot top is always the first-year con and the guests are Riven Scott.
Speaker 1: Contact Riven Scott to see.
Speaker 1: are they actually going to this thing, you know, can it be trusted?
Speaker 1: Yeah, get try to contact and communicate with other people who are going or of Kimmy or know the people running it.
Speaker 1: You know, you gotta do some sort of you know networking whatever to figure out how legit is this con?
Speaker 1: Maybe you'll call us back.
Speaker 1: Hey, I see you guys are guests of this first-year con.
Speaker 0: We might be like what?
Speaker 1: Yeah, we might be like what.
Speaker 1: I don't know what that is.
Speaker 0: or and you might laugh that happens a lot.
Speaker 0: You know many of these fake fucking conventions.
Speaker 0: just say they have a guest attending And that guest was never invited to the convention.
Speaker 1: They don't even know what the hell it is.
Speaker 0: Yeah, or they're like they're selling autographs for someone who hasn't hasn't actually signed a contract to come yet.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but maybe you contact us and we say oh, yeah that cons being run by our friend.
Speaker 1: I think you should definitely come.
Speaker 1: I know it's legit.
Speaker 1: It's it's real.
Speaker 1: You'll hear us talk about it in the meta moment.
Speaker 1: Yeah, then, you know, you can go.
Speaker 1: if you trust us you got to trust somebody right?
Speaker 1: The point is you get to find someone you can trust in this chain here.
Speaker 1: If you don't know the people running the con Right, then you got to find someone else who knows them that you can trust.
Speaker 0: if there's no one you trust then You got to stay away wait for the second year If a first-year con is in a large convention center and not run by a big company I'm pretty much a hundred percent.
Speaker 0: It's gonna fail.
Speaker 1: No, it's got to be in a small place like a hotel ballroom at the biggest Yep.
Speaker 0: If a first-year comms website has a lot of like Squarespace looking graphic design and looks really slick But there's no actual content Like there's no community stuff.
Speaker 0: There's no like.
Speaker 0: there's nothing there below the surface and there's a lot of promises about like an artist alley But there's no form to sign up for an artist alley.
Speaker 0: Avoid it because it's probably just a scam at that point.
Speaker 1: If you try to talk to the other people who are thinking about going to this con right and see how Communicative are the people running it with this, you know, you form this community of attendees.
Speaker 1: How communicative are the people running the con with the attendee group, right?
Speaker 1: And what are they giving you specifics or are they leading you on?
Speaker 1: Yeah, if they can't say oh, yes It's on this day in this place and here's our you know Like they're not showing that they're doing all the things like.
Speaker 1: here's our policies on this and here's a weapons thing And here's you know, we're gonna have his.
Speaker 1: we're working on the schedule.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right also cut tape.
Speaker 1: they're just sort of like.
Speaker 1: yeah guys sign up.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's gonna be great.
Speaker 1: It's like uh-huh.
Speaker 0: Oh even more than that.
Speaker 0: This is like a specific one I've.
Speaker 1: they don't say anything.
Speaker 0: if take if they have like, you know, there's policies on their website.
Speaker 0: Let's say about stuff.
Speaker 0: takes a few sets of text from their website Type and copy paste it into Google and see if that appears in Generic websites.
Speaker 1: also look if you can get the names of the people running the con.
Speaker 0: and well If you can't get the names of the people running the con Probably a fail.
Speaker 1: right but Google them and see what's up.
Speaker 1: One of the ones that recently failed the person who ran it ran a previous.
Speaker 1: This is the second time they did this and they got away with the both time.
Speaker 0: Yep, right This is the segue.
Speaker 1: only after the second fail did people point out.
Speaker 1: Hey that same person did both of these fails.
Speaker 1: Why would somebody who did a failing con if they tried to if they were gonna try again Wouldn't they run the exact same like be like, okay, I failed.
Speaker 1: Honestly, I'm gonna try to do the exact same con again.
Speaker 1: No, they tried to do a different con the second time.
Speaker 0: Well, you know what this is.
Speaker 0: this is getting into the final point like the thing I'm worried about.
Speaker 0: that I think is gonna happen a lot.
Speaker 0: I Think there's gonna be a lot of fan conventions over the next few years that are basically the producers.
Speaker 0: Yes, and I think the roadmap for this seems pretty clear.
Speaker 1: If you know anyone doesn't know what that means.
Speaker 1: go to your video source.
Speaker 0: Just type the word the producers into Google right.
Speaker 1: make sure you watch the Mel Brooks movie.
Speaker 1: If you can't go to like a theater and see it performed.
Speaker 0: I should watch that movie again.
Speaker 0: It's been a while Why not?
Speaker 0: That movie is so good.
Speaker 1: Why not watch it every day.
Speaker 0: That movie is so great.
Speaker 1: But yeah, make sure you watch the Mel Brooks Gene Wilder producers.
Speaker 1: Oh my god, and not any other producers.
Speaker 0: Here's the roadmap that I see.
Speaker 0: First you have a you and a small number of people are gonna run the convention scam Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: But if you just scam people like you kick start a con and just don't do anything and steal all the money You can get sued in trouble.
Speaker 0: You've got your scam fraud.
Speaker 0: You need to Proudfund the convention.
Speaker 0: put the token effort in to show that you did some minimum level of due diligence.
Speaker 0: But here's what you do.
Speaker 0: you target the convention at either underprivileged people Unworldly people narrow fandoms that are underserved like go straight line for like ladybug Whatever or Steven Universe, whatever like.
Speaker 1: I mean, there are some cons like that.
Speaker 1: I think there's like a gargoyles con I've heard about right now like a Jim and the Holograms con somewhere.
Speaker 1: Yeah, these super narrow cons that do happen are pretty good for the people.
Speaker 1: or in those fandoms and I write so it's like if I Were to run saying what's something really narrow?
Speaker 0: Thundercats Thundercon.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's a little bigger than those.
Speaker 1: But yeah, that's still pretty niche right the Thundercats con I'd be like lionos coming everybody.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I might actually want if it was close I would go to if it was clay if it was in New York City, I would go to.
Speaker 0: it is I could.
Speaker 0: But But What you do then and this is what I've seen happen a lot of these cons that fail.
Speaker 0: they.
Speaker 0: they fail in a way Like they're designed to fail in a way that could in court Plausibly be put off on the staff having made mistakes and fucked up.
Speaker 0: Negligence as opposed to gross negligence negligence as opposed to actual fraud.
Speaker 0: So I think what they do is you find people who go to a lot of conventions or maybe we're Low-level staff at a bunch of conventions like someone who's like well, for example this person who I've heard.
Speaker 1: I don't I'm not saying the person's name because I just saw this in some tweets.
Speaker 0: I write about it, too.
Speaker 0: I'm not a name because I don't want to get involved, right?
Speaker 1: but the person who tried to run this recent con and the other one that failed both and it was the same person twice that Was a person who had previously been a high-level staff person at Anime Expo or at least as credited as such And thus bring some believability, right?
Speaker 1: If you're like, oh I used to be Almost the car the con chair or almost the con chair at other successful convention and now I'm doing this one on my own You sort of want to trust that right.
Speaker 1: but apparently is a case where a person was in that kind of position or claims to Have been.
Speaker 1: I think they were and then did two scam cons as far as we can tell.
Speaker 0: so Here's the.
Speaker 0: here's the rub.
Speaker 0: Like here's the matter not the rub.
Speaker 0: Here's the magic part of this.
Speaker 0: you find those kinds of people who might be earnest.
Speaker 0: You need to have a staff Who believe in the convention and you guide them into making their own mistakes and being responsible and culpable for those mistakes.
Speaker 0: So you get people who have been low-level staff at a bunch of conventions and feel you know You know the people we meet at conventions who feel like it's easy to run a convention because they don't know better.
Speaker 0: They've never done the finance of a convention.
Speaker 0: They've never done logistics of a convention.
Speaker 0: Then the person like checking badges at the door or scheduling panels.
Speaker 1: Well, this is something that not just conventions but I think the world as a whole, you know in all sorts of organizations even just like your families and Companies and all every organization right is.
Speaker 1: there are certain things that people at the executive level do.
Speaker 1: Right, if you're in a family only your parents know about like how much money they got in taxes, right?
Speaker 1: It's usually money related things but not always You know in a company right when business deals happen between the executives and closed meetings The employees don't know what the fuck goes on in there.
Speaker 1: Right and cut.
Speaker 1: at a convention only the people on the board deal with things like insurance and who knows what right?
Speaker 1: Yep, and thus people who are not in that top tier of an organization on the executive level Not only don't know about these things that go on right.
Speaker 1: They don't know the details of them.
Speaker 1: They don't even know that they don't know like you don't even know that a convention has to buy insurance.
Speaker 0: so you need someone like the director of operations for a convention and You set them up to not get insurance because they're not gonna.
Speaker 1: but there's also no way for them to learn unless somebody Specifically brings them in.
Speaker 1: and this is why we sort of have like these, you know Like this big gap in our whole society of like people who know the things and how to make them do People who don't because they haven't had someone who knows how the world works Teach them and bring them up and show them all these things that have been hidden from their whole life.
Speaker 1: I
Speaker 0: think these scam conventions are getting a very earnest staff who are given all the rope They need to hang themselves and they will make promises based on assumptions that are false and really try to make the event happen and That provides the cover for the event actually just failing right?
Speaker 1: I think we need as a whole right, you know In general we need to somehow open up the whole world.
Speaker 1: Right, you know to not necessarily the specific details of any one organization, right?
Speaker 1: That's the stuff you want to keep secret.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but the generalities of like this is how things work on, you know executive levels of things people who aren't You know through the wall, of course, and at least learn how these things go.
Speaker 0: course counterpoint That's what people who run big Companies and events go to college for and learn like.
Speaker 1: I learned some of those things some of them But you don't really learn.
Speaker 0: well, I learned the thing cuz I'm.
Speaker 0: I do that kind of work for certain certain areas I've done.
Speaker 0: I've done a lot of executive work and you know what I Learned about it and know about it because it's my profession.
Speaker 0: It's a one thing to expect a professional to learn those things.
Speaker 0: It is another thing to expect like some rando to learn these things a lot of times.
Speaker 1: you can't learn those until you know It's got to become you.
Speaker 1: It's like you can't get the job to do it until you've learned it already.
Speaker 1: What's that?
Speaker 1: beeping noise?
Speaker 0: That's the Marantz running out of battery.
Speaker 1: Good job Better turn the show up because our backup is gone.
Speaker 0: I think we should turn the show off because I'm actually really hungry.
Speaker 1: I'm also really hungry.
Speaker 0: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Speaker 1: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 0: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 1: But unlike those other late shows It's actually recorded at night
Speaker 0: and the patreon patrons for this episode of geek nights are Craig Oliver Alan Joyce Rebecca Dunn, Heidi McNicholas, Sherman Rubiobolus, Hanging in the sky, mystady.com, Jeremy Meyer, Link Iggi, Kelly Snyder, Cold Guy, Amanda Duschad, Sean Yeager, Matthew Smith, Nicholas, Brando, Mr.
Speaker 0: Strong, Strachan, 421 creations.
Speaker 0: No, I never ever wonder why we're here, Semper Fi, bitch Shervin Van Horl, R.I.M.
Speaker 0: rare is pronounced.
Speaker 0: Rory Sorry James David White, Rochelle Montanona, Superboy, R.I.M.
Speaker 0: says something funny here, Sailor, Vista, Don, Schleich, Jartavish, Jojo, Joestar, Clinton, Walton, Ren from New Zealand, Ryan Perrin, Drew Openlander, Finn, Chris Midkiff, Chris Knox, Daniel Redman, Sean Klein, Chris Reimer, and Thomas Hahn.