Speaker 1: It's Monday October 29th 2018.
Speaker 1: I'm rim.
Speaker 1: I'm Scott and this is a spooky October geek night.
Speaker 1: It's tonight.
Speaker 1: We're talking about live streaming technology.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we didn't do shows for like two weeks because Scott and I had independent travel plans that did not overlap And in fact, we're such that we just couldn't do shows for two weeks.
Speaker 0: I mean we could have squeezed one in.
Speaker 1: yeah Not gonna.
Speaker 0: Why would he bother?
Speaker 0: What's the point?
Speaker 0: We're not getting paid for this shit.
Speaker 1: Actually, we are from the patreon.
Speaker 0: We don't have enough ideas.
Speaker 1: The thing is at this point.
Speaker 1: We actually have a plethora of Tuesday and Wednesday shows.
Speaker 1: Cuz we're actually watching.
Speaker 0: animators have always been the easy show.
Speaker 1: yep well And we have the plan to fix Thursdays and potentially Mondays with that new format.
Speaker 1: but I still have to do some work to set that up and I did not do that work because I was busy working on Some other stuff and actually I had to make a lot of slides for pecs unplugged.
Speaker 0: anyway I can tell you tropical island means you can go to the beach in October.
Speaker 0: Warm and it's great and the water is salt water and it's wavy But it's not.
Speaker 0: it's way less wavy.
Speaker 1: I have not been to a tropical beach since I was in Costa Rica.
Speaker 0: It's also clear and blue and not dirty like New Jersey Yeah, and there's no.
Speaker 0: there's no crabby's bite into the sand is just nice and smooth.
Speaker 0: There's not a bunch of seaweed and other garbage down there.
Speaker 0: It's pretty much just great, but the only thing is tropical islands at least the one I went to Greatly lack in nerdery there is unless you want to go to a casino Well, what do you expect?
Speaker 1: what or what tropical beach town is gonna have anything nerdy for you to do at night?
Speaker 0: Well, I'm I think we you know, I want to make some sort of resort.
Speaker 0: That is like permanent joco cruise.
Speaker 0: Let's be big.
Speaker 0: it could be like, you know 100 rooms even smaller like 50 rooms, right just a little like motel sized Right, just something somewheres that a nerd at any time can go and a tropical nerdy vacation.
Speaker 0: So, you know there was and if all the nerds in the world You should be able to keep the resort relatively full at all times.
Speaker 1: Disney tried to do that with a nerdy like separate resort.
Speaker 0: I thought that was a Disney Cruise.
Speaker 1: I know not cruises not cruises.
Speaker 0: I'm sure Disney Resort.
Speaker 1: No, these were not at Disney Uh-huh.
Speaker 1: You'd you don't remember the do.
Speaker 1: Oh god.
Speaker 1: What was it called Disney something?
Speaker 0: Disney I'm talking like during the day you go to the beach and then once the Sun Goes Down at this board games in the hotel You could probably make one of those.
Speaker 0: that's what I'm saying.
Speaker 0: Don't be big.
Speaker 1: you probably make about as much money as like all those nerdy cat.
Speaker 0: Basically just make as much money as any other is.
Speaker 1: just make a nerd Gaming store arcade II type place with tables and stuff and happen to put it at the beach Like those people who tried to make that land gaming plays in Wildwood that called no noobs that it just immediately went out of business.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: This is like no people would fly and physically make reservations at your resort.
Speaker 0: Unlike the land party place Nerd foot traffic cuz I would I'd rather if you were going on a tropical vacation where you just you're gonna go to a resort and just land a beach for a week and You discovered that somewhere on a tropical island near you.
Speaker 0: There was a resort that had So one.
Speaker 0: there are no tropical islands near me relatively near.
Speaker 0: Within five hours of flying and two.
Speaker 1: I wouldn't go to a tropical place to land a beach for a week.
Speaker 1: I'd go there for like two or three days and I'd go off somewhere else in the tropical area like into the rainforest or by The volcano.
Speaker 0: there was no rainforest or volcano.
Speaker 1: I should have gone to Costa Rica.
Speaker 0: There were some rock formations, but I figured those are not worth visiting.
Speaker 1: How do you know?
Speaker 1: watch that was like the most awesome thing one shaped like Sonic the Hedgehog or something?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I saw a picture.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I guess the trouble is that Resorts that are frequented by I don't say basic people but just like old people Normal people there were old people there during the day like beach like put me on any beach on earth.
Speaker 1: I know there's not toxic and I'm good to go.
Speaker 0: I noticed at night Walking around in most of the rooms people were sitting and watching television.
Speaker 1: Oh, that's so sad.
Speaker 0: They were at least I remember silly one night.
Speaker 0: We're just like like well, we can't go to the beach anymore Just sitting next to the pool, which is also closed and then we walk back to the room.
Speaker 1: Why does the pool close?
Speaker 1: when I was a kid and we went to like eight when we went to tropical play The beat the Is 24/7.
Speaker 0: there was no lifeguard either at any time every beach resort like that.
Speaker 0: I've ever gone to no lifeguard on the beach or pool, but they closed the pool at 8.
Speaker 1: Wow The pool was open till like 2 in the morning and granted They were like drunken teenagers in the pool.
Speaker 0: by close the pool I mean that around 830 to sometime between 830 and 9 some dude walks over it with a You know a sandwich board and puts it near the pool and it says sorry pool closed.
Speaker 1: But Like putting any beach on earth like what we used to in wildwood during the day.
Speaker 1: just be on the beach all day.
Speaker 1: It's great.
Speaker 1: Like that's that's the life I want.
Speaker 1: But what did I do at night?
Speaker 1: I played board games with all my friends.
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 0: We need to do the same exact thing.
Speaker 0: only bring more friends and more games.
Speaker 1: I has sadly feel like the demographic overlap between Go to tropical island beach and want to stay inside playing board games.
Speaker 1: I feel like it's the opposite of a Venn diagram.
Speaker 1: I is Joe go cruise full then One because it's not that big it sells out instantly.
Speaker 0: It is fill the whole boat.
Speaker 1: I've heard it is way harder to get Joe go cruise than it is to get to packs.
Speaker 0: Well, I heard that they fill the whole boat now.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's big I'm.
Speaker 1: uh, I want to go.
Speaker 1: actually I want to go on it at least once like I'm so once.
Speaker 1: yeah It's way hard to get on that thing.
Speaker 1: It is it's it sells out faster than like SDCC's.
Speaker 0: got on it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you got to got to know someone you got to go in like.
Speaker 1: it's tough to do.
Speaker 1: We could try to do it.
Speaker 0: I'm sure we can get on.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So meanwhile I for the first time in my life I went to the op the literal opposite of a tropical island.
Speaker 1: I went to Britain Albion.
Speaker 1: Yeah But it was weird.
Speaker 1: I've never.
Speaker 1: I've been to London like 14 or so times Maybe more like it's to the point where I don't know how many times I've been there.
Speaker 1: I'd have to go like count and I'd never been there where I didn't have work to do.
Speaker 1: Like I never just went to London with nothing to do and it was pretty novel to just wake up in London and be like What do you want to do?
Speaker 1: Fucking whatever?
Speaker 1: Let's just go crown jewels.
Speaker 1: So the only know Well, you can just go see him.
Speaker 1: We were with you.
Speaker 0: Why didn't you get him for me?
Speaker 1: Because there are heavily armed gentlemen who would have taken issue with that as your LuPone skills.
Speaker 1: I ain't LuPone Why not?
Speaker 1: So yeah, if you ever you've never been there, right?
Speaker 1: You've never seen the crown jewels.
Speaker 0: No I've never even been to Europe.
Speaker 1: Okay, so here's the deal.
Speaker 1: when you go into the Tower of London Which is a legit fucking castle from like thousand years ago, but it's not a castle like the stereotypical Lego castle Yeah, it is.
Speaker 0: No, it doesn't look like that.
Speaker 0: Yeah It looks more like a.
Speaker 1: you know, it's got crenellated walls for archers.
Speaker 1: It's a thousand years old.
Speaker 1: What do you know about the Tower of London?
Speaker 0: Pictures.
Speaker 0: it doesn't look like a stereotypical castle.
Speaker 1: Okay, what now?
Speaker 0: I'm curious what you think a stereotypical castle looks like because like all the domes and shit Towers domes on the top of the towers got.
Speaker 1: domes are either way earlier or way Later than the area you're thinking about Typically not in castles but in palaces.
Speaker 1: and while some castles are also palaces most were not anyway.
Speaker 1: So in the Tower of London the crown jewels are just there and you can just like go see him and they're just on this floor and there's this whole long build up where you walk by like pictures of them explaining which ones which and how most of them are from after the English Civil War because They all got destroyed in the English Civil War and they had to make new ones.
Speaker 1: and then when you finally get to them there's just a sideways like Airport walking path like one of those like moving sidewalks to make sure you can't stand next to them too long and It just slowly takes you past them and you look at them as long as you can and then they force you to get the fuck Out of that room and that's the end
Speaker 0: of it.
Speaker 0: Why don't you just make a little video so that you can then rewind the video and stop and look at them?
Speaker 1: You're not allowed to take pictures in there.
Speaker 1: Uh-huh at all.
Speaker 1: Now the rationale is not for security or anything dumb like that.
Speaker 1: The rationale is simply the government of that country has plenty of great pictures at ultra high resolution.
Speaker 1: You can get.
Speaker 1: Oh and they don't want some shit ass tourists taking some shit ass picture and that being the picture that someone sees.
Speaker 0: Well, then if you want to see them why go there when I just look at the picture?
Speaker 1: because you can see him in person And it's actually like honestly, it's a jewel.
Speaker 1: It's yeah, I thought you know The first time I went to see him when I was by myself years ago I just kind of went in like okay, whatever.
Speaker 1: and then when I was actually in front of that big fucking diamond It was for a moment.
Speaker 1: It was like whoa, that's actually bigger than I expected.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so the Museum of Natural History in New York, which is not a disappointment and you should totally go there.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, every museum in New York is great But that one's my favorite.
Speaker 0: but they had I don't know if it's still there cuz I haven't been there a long time But then the geology section they had the world's largest diamond Period yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's also bigger than you expect And I saw it and it was a. it was big.
Speaker 0: it was also a big disappointment cuz it was just a fucking rock.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well this one.
Speaker 0: I'm not interested in seeing jewels in person So these are cut.
Speaker 0: show me show me your jewel next to a banana in a photo for scale.
Speaker 0: If you got bigger than the banana, then I'll come see.
Speaker 1: But the other thing is I'd never ever like gone over to like see Westminster like any of the like touristy stuff and the one Thing that stands out from all of London that I don't know what to do about because it was like it was so unexpected.
Speaker 1: Like, you know, there's like con games all over like go to Times Square.
Speaker 1: There's the guys give me rap CDs or whatever.
Speaker 1: Yeah in London by Westminster.
Speaker 1: It's three card money.
Speaker 1: It's the shell game.
Speaker 1: Yeah There is literally.
Speaker 1: if you walk on the bridge that approaches Westminster every 15 feet There is a shell game with like the exact same four people to the point that it was like a glitch in the matrix.
Speaker 0: Why don't you?
Speaker 1: Set up a shell game because I feel like all these other people running these clearly all run by the same illegal criminal organization.
Speaker 1: Shell game would have done something to me if I don't know.
Speaker 0: go like go like three blocks past the final shell game.
Speaker 0: Ah, right and set up your shell game there and an area with slightly less traffic cuz clearly no one's no cops are stopping Anyone running a show?
Speaker 0: Yeah and set up your completely fair American shell game.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so the funniest thing.
Speaker 1: I watched a recent video.
Speaker 1: It's not my thing of the day, but I'll just talk about it.
Speaker 1: I saw a good video of someone Demonstrating the shell game.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's laid a hand.
Speaker 1: No, no, no, but they did it for people.
Speaker 1: It was like close-up magic.
Speaker 1: They used clear shells and the people still got fooled.
Speaker 0: How could you get fooled with a clear shell?
Speaker 1: It was very well done.
Speaker 0: You can see the ball right under there.
Speaker 1: You think that but then you are watching what happens.
Speaker 0: if you use clear shells, I would basically like close my eyes.
Speaker 0: No Wait till the end and you'd say which one and I would look at the three clear ones.
Speaker 0: See which one had a fucking pee under yep.
Speaker 1: And as soon as that one and as soon as the shell that has that clearly has the pee under it is lifted It's not there.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'm the one who should be lifting it.
Speaker 0: Not you get away from there cheatin, man.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well, how do you think it'll go?
Speaker 1: if I tell this like Russian looking mobster who's running this shell game?
Speaker 1: Hey, I'm gonna pick up the shell.
Speaker 1: I don't think that's gonna go over very well.
Speaker 0: I should devise a shell game where you the person does all the touching and I still win.
Speaker 1: Thing is I feel like you would make money just running the shell game.
Speaker 0: legit because people are really bad The one out of three.
Speaker 0: I feel like people would just mess up real fast so that they would get confused and not be able to track it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, pretty much.
Speaker 0: I can't use any sleight of hand.
Speaker 0: Just move the shells real fast like whoo-hoo-hoo-hoo-hoo.
Speaker 1: I feel like you'd still win.
Speaker 1: So anyway, it's Monday when people do get it.
Speaker 0: I mean you go to a baseball game and on the jumbotron they always do the shell game with three baseball hats.
Speaker 0: Yep, and it's always legit like they're not cheating because there's no prize at stake.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's just to keep you entertained in between innings and people do get it wrong.
Speaker 1: So it's Monday, we're back.
Speaker 1: It's geek nights.
Speaker 1: I don't know if any of you are new and stumbled upon this but because I saw a bunch of people like Recently subscribed to my youtube like a whole bunch.
Speaker 1: I don't have someone linked to us, but this is geek nights.
Speaker 1: We're here and we're starting the show again like normal and it's Monday.
Speaker 1: So on Wednesday We're gonna talk about the dragon prince because it's the animation day.
Speaker 1: So, uh, yeah, we got some news.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's too much tech news going down big.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so I picked a right.
Speaker 0: I don't know how much even though they're big news is.
Speaker 0: I don't know how much there is to say about these big news.
Speaker 1: There's a few that while I would have a lot to say about it.
Speaker 1: Most of what I have to say isn't really technology.
Speaker 1: It's more like business related or like all there.
Speaker 1: It's related to things other than the technology itself and to I don't care a lot about a lot of these news Like the IBM the big one.
Speaker 0: IBM fucking bought redhead with cash totally makes sense because they have the same customers.
Speaker 1: Yeah It does.
Speaker 0: they're basically the same company.
Speaker 1: It also makes extra sense because remember IBM has been Ending their Unix line.
Speaker 1: So if IBM stuff like if you want to use IBM stuff, it's all Linux now.
Speaker 1: So there isn't like IBM Unix like everyone's getting off all that now.
Speaker 0: It's not like you buy what it's not like you buy.
Speaker 0: You know a big blue from IBM Who buys those now are anyway, someone must be buying them.
Speaker 0: But if you are the I got a lot of those but they're all legacy if you're a weird-ass company that buys one of those.
Speaker 1: Do you know how many of those I've dealt with in my career?
Speaker 0: More than you worked at IBM.
Speaker 1: I did work at IBM, but you know what.
Speaker 1: when I worked at IBM The mainframes I dealt with are old to the point that IPL meant something to me That was different from a reboot.
Speaker 0: the point is if you if you're the kind of weird-ass company that buys an IBM server It's like I've been Windows.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but IBM is buying redhead for 34 billion dollars.
Speaker 0: I said that the number makes no sense to me.
Speaker 1: So that is a significant premium because right out was worth 20 billion dollars.
Speaker 0: that number still makes no sense.
Speaker 1: Well, I so that I realized this after we were talking before the show.
Speaker 1: What do you think redhead does?
Speaker 0: they just provide support and they manage a distro.
Speaker 1: they provide a lot more services than that and a lot more tools than that and Not just support but also professional services.
Speaker 1: They got all these cloud solutions.
Speaker 1: redhead actually has a lot of stuff and they generate like three billion dollars in revenue a year.
Speaker 0: That's insane because as I was telling remember for the show like the New York Rangers are worth about a billion.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I was like who if I win that big lottery I could just buy the team.
Speaker 0: Yeah be set.
Speaker 1: So you get rid of the.
Speaker 0: she could fix the only thing wrong get so IBM Instead of buying the redhead could have bought almost every NHL team.
Speaker 1: No.
Speaker 0: Oh almost.
Speaker 0: Oh god Just buy every NHL team.
Speaker 1: billion for you billion for you billion for you.
Speaker 0: That'd be a better idea.
Speaker 1: Probably not.
Speaker 1: so I don't want to like go too deep in like business.
Speaker 0: Almost all the NHL teams then own IBM and redhead, I mean the crazy things about this are like.
Speaker 1: apparently this is the biggest deal.
Speaker 0: Maybe that's stupid because if I apparently you said what red hat brings in how much a year three billion.
Speaker 0: so I could just buy Red hat and every year buy three teams.
Speaker 1: now, I don't know how much profit they make.
Speaker 1: I didn't look that up.
Speaker 1: That's just revenue.
Speaker 0: Oh But it can't cost too much to run.
Speaker 0: So I imagine most people are just paying you for support and you're giving them almost no services Like a gym, this is the biggest thing and not coming IBM has ever done And it might looks like it.
Speaker 1: according to this article at least it is the third for inflation as well.
Speaker 0: Yeah, okay.
Speaker 1: This is the third biggest deal in the history of US technology.
Speaker 1: I can't believe it's so big.
Speaker 1: the only ones that are bigger.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna quote this article from CNBC excluding the AOL Time Warner merger.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Well, that's a merger.
Speaker 1: The only larger deals ever were these 67 billion dollar merger between Dell and EMC.
Speaker 1: Okay, hold that thought.
Speaker 0: I never heard EMC.
Speaker 1: hold that thought because that gets back to a point I was gonna make earlier about you.
Speaker 1: Okay, and JDS is uniphase or JDS Uniphase is four point one billion dollar acquisition of some optical component supplier Right before the dot-com bubble burst.
Speaker 1: Neither do I because that was 2000.
Speaker 0: people like optical parts where they like put laying all the dark fiber in the.
Speaker 0: probably Basically, that makes sense that they would go out as best.
Speaker 1: I can tell.
Speaker 1: that deal was literally like the deal happened and then seconds Later the dot-com bubble burst and everyone got fucked.
Speaker 1: It makes it so part of the reason why I think the majority of the technology world is on the internet is really surprised by this.
Speaker 1: and then a small number of us aren't.
Speaker 1: and Is that your question of what is EMC and your questions about what a red hat does?
Speaker 1: really shows the very very stark divide between the far majority of technology use cases and The enterprise use cases like the scale of enterprise technology.
Speaker 0: I think enterprise as usual is just spending way too much money on a whole lot of nothing which But it's the scale of that money is bad.
Speaker 1: So some of that is true.
Speaker 1: I mean wait, I'm not gonna get into my whole like rant about why enterprise technology usually sucks ass But I've talked about that a lot on early gig nights because basically my entire career with one exception has been working with enterprise.
Speaker 0: Instead of paying red hat their portion of their three billion dollars of revenue You can hire like two nerds and just use free software.
Speaker 1: it to a point.
Speaker 0: There's a certain what can red hat give you that I can't give you?
Speaker 1: if you hire me I don't think you could provide the level of scaling technology that I need.
Speaker 0: I just I would you just give me the power to hire more me's.
Speaker 1: It doesn't really scale well or that leads to weird like spaghetti Report to lines and poorly documented solutions across a lot of disparate hardware over time anyway, this also it sort of makes sense based on what IBM does and what red hat does.
Speaker 1: and The best way I can describe this for like people who aren't in enterprise world is that it probably means IBM is gonna really try to push into like private and semi-private Cloud solutions for companies that aren't gonna just trust Amazon with their data.
Speaker 0: yeah, I guess you know you'll have another choice right instead of Google or Amazon or Microsoft like.
Speaker 1: here's the difference.
Speaker 0: IBM slash red hat will now become an actual choice.
Speaker 1: Small medium-sized and even the lower end of large companies can still like just put their stuff on but cloud technologies Solutions and just go with it.
Speaker 1: But there's a scale above that where either because of the data because of laws because the scale There's a lot of reasons why some of these extremely big companies or companies that do extremely proprietary things basically need to run their own cloud and provide it as a Software solution or hardware solution to the rest of their own company.
Speaker 0: I mean you don't need to.
Speaker 0: there are ridiculously big companies that run on Google Microsoft Amazon true.
Speaker 0: But I'm sure those companies even though they do that and even though it may work some of them may be Unhappy giving their competitor a giant pile of money every month.
Speaker 0: Yep, or running it themselves They would save a ton of money or
Speaker 1: there might be issues like Amazon's got a lot of great solutions But for certain kinds of connectivity or certain kinds of things you might want to solve There SLA is actually like unusable Like you can't really do real-time stock trading from AWS.
Speaker 0: No, probably not like.
Speaker 1: there's a lot of things you need to do differently.
Speaker 1: so I guess the meta point of all this is that this deal does make sense if you Have a broad view of the technology sector, but it does not make sense to the vast majority of technologists.
Speaker 1: so in some other news Twitter let's talk about the Apple stuffers.
Speaker 1: That's more fun.
Speaker 0: Absolutely Apple is so.
Speaker 0: usually Apple Announcements are not surprises because they're like.
Speaker 0: people are always like, oh my god Apple.
Speaker 0: It's like are you not paying attention?
Speaker 0: They release that.
Speaker 0: they make the same announcements at the same time every year on a clock like calendar, right?
Speaker 0: September is always back-to-school iPods which became back-to-school iPhones every year for the past many many years.
Speaker 0: But they're going off schedule in October, which is like real November like real soon.
Speaker 0: They're going.
Speaker 0: I think it's this week maybe right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's coming out.
Speaker 0: It's in Brooklyn.
Speaker 0: I don't know why the fucking right.
Speaker 1: the Brooklyn Academy of Music on October 26 of those few days ago.
Speaker 0: It must be music related.
Speaker 1: Oh, they put the signs up.
Speaker 1: They put all this Apple stuff there.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it definitely must be related to iTunes music Apple music.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if they're going there, right?
Speaker 0: They're definitely telling you something.
Speaker 0: Well, it's tomorrow.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: There's gonna be announcements Relating to iPads.
Speaker 0: mostly people are hoping maybe some beats action music.
Speaker 0: Right, maybe some.
Speaker 1: the rumor is specifically new round of iPads.
Speaker 0: I heard all using USB C Apple TV, maybe all those sorts of things.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I feel because it can't be phone stuff.
Speaker 1: They already did phone.
Speaker 0: So phones are in September.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I've never seen an Apple thing in October November, but there's no way.
Speaker 1: It's like desktop II stuff.
Speaker 0: No that stuff is always done if they do it.
Speaker 0: They used to go to CES But now they tend to.
Speaker 0: I think they like make an announcement sort of close to CES or maybe in March And then they have their WWDC which is where they announce all their software updates because that's for developers.
Speaker 1: So apparently the theme of the event is the word making so it's probably around using.
Speaker 0: They're probably gonna also be announcing like, you know, if I get an I work updates again and probably like Creative software that works well on iPads ways to integrate iPad Pros getting updated, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's what that's what the making is.
Speaker 1: I wonder if they're gonna try to provide software and like I don't know whatever cables you need to integrate iPad pros into like Actual media production pipeline.
Speaker 1: I mean they already do that Yeah, but they're not like.
Speaker 1: that's not really like.
Speaker 1: most production pipelines don't involve an iPad.
Speaker 0: I see a lot of people use iPads for a lot of things.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but not not the kind of stuff I'm talking about.
Speaker 1: iPad Pro will be the most significant in the products history apparently.
Speaker 0: Hmm.
Speaker 0: So yeah, we'll see my iPad Pro is still just fine.
Speaker 0: I'm not gonna replace it cuz it's so expensive.
Speaker 1: though.
Speaker 1: If it's true that they're moving until it's really dead if it's true that they're moving to USB C then that leaves the iPhone as the sole device on earth that uses lightning.
Speaker 0: I guess Yeah, well, I mean they.
Speaker 0: they made everyone go like lightning headphones and shit, yeah I don't think.
Speaker 0: I think what it is is I don't think they're actually replacing the lightning part.
Speaker 0: I think it's still gonna be lightning on one end and it's USB C on the other end.
Speaker 0: Right because right now it's like you.
Speaker 0: you know It's regular use.
Speaker 1: that doesn't really make a lot of sense though Cuz.
Speaker 1: then what are you gonna plug that into to charge?
Speaker 0: You're gonna need a regular Mac which has only USB C's on the side of it.
Speaker 1: What if you only have an iPad Pro?
Speaker 1: I Have your charging brick.
Speaker 0: this it comes with a thing.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah Let's see faster processors.
Speaker 1: Oh LED screen on the.
Speaker 0: Didn't make iPad Pro with an LED screen that will cut and it's as big as this one 13 inch.
Speaker 0: that will cost like $2,000.
Speaker 1: Yeah, this is the rumors.
Speaker 1: This is the rumors that I found on this website.
Speaker 1: Maybe even 2500 smaller bezels USB C.
Speaker 0: Oh LED screens are the best screens if you don't know that at least available to consumers right now.
Speaker 0: the problem with the LED screens is that when they try to make them a lot of them just don't fucking work and like they'll Have a dead pixel in them or something and they basically it's like they try to make ten screens like one of them is any Good and that's why they cost an arm and a leg.
Speaker 1: Oh Face ID will enable animojis.
Speaker 1: Yep, probably Screens, nope, the screens will be less expensive.
Speaker 1: LCD panels.
Speaker 1: No LED.
Speaker 1: Okay Rumor, I mean, it's usually the rumors are on but yeah, let's see a complete redesign of the look more squared off sides faster processor Custom Apple graphics chip.
Speaker 1: apparently Apple every iPad has a custom and an updated Apple pencil.
Speaker 1: Okay All right.
Speaker 1: I can't say that I care that much.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna continue to use my 2009 Lenovo laptop.
Speaker 0: You did my use my first gen iPad Pro until it is Unusable.
Speaker 0: Yep, and then so my problem is oh, I'm gonna survive at least Hopefully one hopefully more than one more generation of iPad Pro.
Speaker 0: So I guess if they're gonna start doing these in October, I may be October 2020 Maybe yeah, so everyone's freaking out cuz Twitter said they're gonna remove the like button.
Speaker 0: They're not actually gonna remove.
Speaker 0: Well, they just suggested they might.
Speaker 1: so they said they might but it looks like in a clarifying statement They probably will.
Speaker 0: just first of all everyone is so mad when they changed it from the the save to be like button.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and now they're mad that they're gonna remove the like button.
Speaker 0: It's like you got mad about its old.
Speaker 1: So the problem was like whatever that was.
Speaker 1: it served a purpose.
Speaker 1: But then they turned it into like a light version of retweet.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm, which was a just a terrible UX decision.
Speaker 1: and The real story here is just that Twitter Continues to be beholden to its shareholders to make money yet There is literally no way to monetize this platform in a way that will satisfy them.
Speaker 1: and they're gonna play this game Until eventually Twitter collapses and there's like there is no chance this company will ever make a good UX decision again Until their stock collapses to the point that all the shareholders give up and maybe someone more intelligent takes over.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I looked into Some of the you know non-major.
Speaker 1: So they're all awful.
Speaker 1: half of them are free speech extremists like gab which is literally just Nazis.
Speaker 0: Well, no, not that one.
Speaker 1: All the free speech ones are just Nazis and child porn all the way down.
Speaker 0: So all the the some of the ones that seem to be good like in terms of good people are really bad software.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and there was one that had a really nice design.
Speaker 0: It reminded me of like a sort of like an or cut that was made in the modern times of mastodon.
Speaker 0: No You know, but it seemed okay, but then note the free speech extremist.
Speaker 0: I didn't actually see too many Nazis on it.
Speaker 0: But I basically, you know the I was like, oh there's no one to follow on this thing, obviously Yeah I followed the founders of it to see what kind of people they were and like the first post that he made was like Yeah, I made.
Speaker 0: we made this so that we could you know for all the people who got kicked off of other platform No, I'm like no delete delete account cuz the further rally is all those other platforms are really hesitant to kick anyone off.
Speaker 1: So the people who are actually kicked off are the worst human beings on earth.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm I mean look at the people who are on gab Terrorists and now gab is shut down because they got to monetize and be platformed again, thankfully.
Speaker 1: So I suspect Twitter is gonna do something really stupid with the like button and what's really crazy Is that the rationale that they give is that they want to?
Speaker 1: Increase the quality of debate by forcing people to engage Which is the literal opposite of what any human wants from this platform.
Speaker 0: I want to debate.
Speaker 0: I want to share pictures Of cute dogs, I wanted to just be a platform.
Speaker 0: tweet out when there's a new geek nights episode.
Speaker 0: Yep, all the tweets when there's a new Nvidia driver.
Speaker 1: Literally, the only good thing that the Twitter has ever provided is a chat room that me and all my friends are in.
Speaker 1: but I can Also follow strangers if I want to but I don't have to.
Speaker 0: I can get a notification when like this pack tickets for sale.
Speaker 1: Yep, I tried to use mastodon, but there's no one really on there.
Speaker 0: Also, it sucks.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it sucks But also there's no one on there.
Speaker 1: So I just like I'd look at it.
Speaker 1: No one posted anything that I care about and I have to cross post.
Speaker 1: I'm not willing to do that.
Speaker 0: I came up with an idea of how to get people to.
Speaker 0: it's like anything you start is gonna start small.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there's no way to start it big.
Speaker 0: How do you get people to use a thing when it's small?
Speaker 1: You got to get a single community to jump ship.
Speaker 0: No, I had an idea.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 1: I'm curious.
Speaker 0: I'm not telling you the idea.
Speaker 1: Oh Okay, you can just do the idea maybe or you just got Other ideas.
Speaker 0: Because I got a lot of ideas I got.
Speaker 0: you have any ideas?
Speaker 0: I got The hopper Scott Hopper.
Speaker 0: Jerry Scott smacks top of his brain.
Speaker 0: Oh, I got.
Speaker 0: I can fit so many ideas in this.
Speaker 0: It's going in the hopper Jerry.
Speaker 0: You know my ideas.
Speaker 0: I can fit in this skull.
Speaker 0: Oh Baby.
Speaker 1: so last and least There's an article here on motherboard.
Speaker 1: I just want to kind of point you people add because Bitcoin is shitty and serves no purpose in modern society.
Speaker 0: all coins bullshit.
Speaker 1: but it is also a Direct contributor to global warming due to the sheer amount of energy it wastes on a hourly basis.
Speaker 0: We are well aware.
Speaker 1: So if you need more evidence old news This is at least a year old to tell your idiot friends who think that bitcoins are in any way a benefit to society.
Speaker 1: here is yet another article you can throw at them and now it's time for things of the day.
Speaker 1: so a long time ago like 2006 I talked about this on gig nights because I learned about it and I did it and it worked and it was awesome But kind of forgot about it till recently.
Speaker 1: But if you work if you live in an apartment building Like in a city or you work in a company where there are doors that have keys Usually you'll have a key that opens your door and someone else in the company will have a key that opens many doors And there's usually someone who has a key that will open any door.
Speaker 0: Well, usually at least at least what I've seen in New York is there isn't usually a key that opens.
Speaker 1: I think I can open your apartment building and get in like with a key.
Speaker 0: I can buy an Amazon stuff probably Yeah But there is usually a janitor or super or someone who just has a fuck ton of keys one for every buck.
Speaker 0: That's actually to remember which one goes with it.
Speaker 1: That's actually pretty rare because the the master key or like delegated key systems are really really common.
Speaker 1: You can buy a system where you can literally like.
Speaker 1: there's multiple keys.
Speaker 1: Like though you can have a key that only works on this floor and a key that only works on this door on this floor And I can't.
Speaker 0: that's modern.
Speaker 1: I'll talk about these new buildings That's modern from like the late 1800s.
Speaker 1: Like that's not.
Speaker 1: that's not that new.
Speaker 0: Well, then why do you buy it?
Speaker 0: even when I was a kid people's blood is laying keys.
Speaker 1: uh so the problem with almost every implementation of this system old or new is that from any one key You can derive the master key and you don't even need to use any other Doors in the building to test this.
Speaker 1: you can use your own door like in your own office with your own key That's only keyed for your door and with a little bit of filing and fucking around You can derive the actual master key to the entire building.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm And I did it once in a building and it worked.
Speaker 1: this was in like 2006.
Speaker 1: Here's a video that explains in like really easy digest detail Exactly how to do it with animations about why it works.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: So I'm not saying I encourage you to try this but it will totally work.
Speaker 0: But yeah if you live Somewhere that you know like an apartment building where the super has a key to your apartment Try to add like a second lock that has a key from a locksmith that only you have.
Speaker 0: Yeah, actually the Additional lock that is not part of any sort of key system.
Speaker 1: Our super can open our door because once I like myself out so it's nice to be able to get like Get back in.
Speaker 0: but also if say you rent office space Don't just use the locks to come with it.
Speaker 0: add your own, you know, get some like RFID lock extra thing on there.
Speaker 1: Yep Oh as a bonus control as a bonus decide it usually doesn't matter because you can usually just slip the latch You don't even need to do the key thing.
Speaker 0: Well, yeah, also make sure your latch can't be.
Speaker 1: Do you know how to tell if you keep your latch can be on D last year usually people put those like big metal plates Over them.
Speaker 1: those don't stop anyone.
Speaker 0: Obviously, you can pry off the metal Piece of metal wire.
Speaker 1: you're good You can slip in locks is so easy.
Speaker 1: It's so, you know, this is a total aside, you know when you close the door There's like the latch and then there's that little piece of metal sticking out behind the latch.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know that that moves independently.
Speaker 1: Yeah, do you know what that little piece of metal does?
Speaker 0: No, I feel like I could figure it out if I just stood next.
Speaker 1: it prevents latch slipping But only if the plate that the latch goes into is shaped the right way.
Speaker 1: And most doors it is not shaped the right way because even people who install doors Don't know what that little piece of metal.
Speaker 0: Usually you hopefully you have like a bolt Bolts.
Speaker 1: the latch bolts are just as easily slipped.
Speaker 0: I mean look hinges.
Speaker 0: you could just bust the door down.
Speaker 1: Oh, no actually, there are a Hinges where even if they're on the outside, there's literally no way to open the door.
Speaker 1: Even if you just remove the pins He's knocked the door.
Speaker 0: You could destroy the door.
Speaker 1: Yes, you could battery ram the door down.
Speaker 1: that will always work.
Speaker 1: Yes, except on the crown jewels because that door is like 12 inches thick get a bigger ram.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so you're talking about the shell game, right?
Speaker 0: So in the in if you go to some arcades these days They're mostly full of crane games and other bullshit like that And one of the things I've seen in arcades for maybe 10 years or so.
Speaker 0: ish is the the What's it called dealer no-deal game?
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's basically just a ticket game You know, it's luck-based.
Speaker 0: you choose suitcases trying to open the ones that have the money in them or whatever.
Speaker 0: I don't know exactly how it works, right?
Speaker 0: But it's you know, it's based on the dealer no-deal game show you see on TV.
Speaker 0: Yeah And some enterprising kids the arcade have figured out a way to completely scam this game to get the maximum prize every single time.
Speaker 0: Now at first I thought whoa they hacked that game Wow, but then no I realized They're just using stupid kid logic and the people who made the game were even stupider.
Speaker 0: The way the game works is it shows you all these suitcases and opens all of them Yeah, and shows you how much money is each one and there's a lot of them not three Yep, and it shuffles them up like a shell game.
Speaker 0: Right, but it shuffles them up on a digital screen and there's no way you could possibly follow them because they're like 100% you know, what's funny is I would assume that that would just be an animation.
Speaker 1: It was the same no matter what right.
Speaker 0: and then so what these kids did?
Speaker 0: using their phones They record a video of the shuffling and then they play it back in slow-mo and skip around and you know Shuffle back and forth and figure out which suitcases move to which position.
Speaker 0: now The question is why does the animation of the suitcases match?
Speaker 0: Like what the values that are in them?
Speaker 1: If I wrote the soft I would have easily played a video.
Speaker 0: that's the same literally every time I wrote the software for that game.
Speaker 0: I would just have a video of suitcases shuffling and then use a random number generator to fill this to populate the splats and Then you wouldn't be able to follow which one had all the value.
Speaker 0: but no these kids totally worked.
Speaker 0: the animation Matches the values in the suitcases and these kids.
Speaker 0: it's awesome.
Speaker 1: So when I was a kid, we did something similar.
Speaker 0: It's at all its tickets and they got the best prizes.
Speaker 1: We basically figured out a way to hack this one game and get it to spit out every ticket it had With a quarter.
Speaker 0: the one we did is the one where the you put the quarter in the slot.
Speaker 0: Oh, it rolls down on that conveyor belt.
Speaker 0: It rolls on a conveyor belt.
Speaker 1: That was the
Speaker 0: one and what we would do is we would just put Tokens in until we got the highest score
Speaker 1: and then we still need to stick gum or tape in the side
Speaker 0: Electrical tape or something to lock that Into that position because they didn't have any sort of randomness or you know Anything like say that the coin pusher or the the ball rolling it was so it was just the same thing.
Speaker 0: It was so uniform and I you know, you don't see that in arcades a lot these days.
Speaker 1: Yep So yeah, the problem was like my friends all did it and I was like, oh that's clever.
Speaker 1: But then I did a little bit of math based on the prizes available.
Speaker 1: Even winning the maximum prize on every quarter You could get that TV by spending like three hundred dollars and that TV that you could win The met grand prize was worth like eighty dollars.
Speaker 1: Also cold guy points out here, you know why they did it?
Speaker 1: the way they did it?
Speaker 1: Because it has to technically be a game of skill per gambling laws.
Speaker 1: It might be one of those things where it may be one jurisdiction they sold the game.
Speaker 1: Also because I'll bet the maximum payouts translate into profit for the arcade regardless, I'm sure they do.
Speaker 1: That's the real answer.
Speaker 0: But I'm sure these kids saw some prize that they wanted to get with those tickets and they those kids have a bunch of arcade Tokens and they have a bunch of fun time messing with this machine.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and they don't have enough money to just go buy that thing.
Speaker 1: It only works if you have a scan to get free arcade tokens.
Speaker 1: That's how you launder arcade tokens into shitty TVs and game gears.
Speaker 1: When I was a kid the major magics, there's a game gear you could get for 10,000 tickets.
Speaker 0: You can just buy a game gear for less than the cost of 10,000.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we I ended up.
Speaker 1: we bought a game gear.
Speaker 0: It was so quick math because when I was a kid It was 25 cents a token.
Speaker 0: you could end up and if you won the game, it was 25 cents for 200 tickets, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, so you said 10,000 tickets for the game 10,000 gigs for the game gear if I recall correctly divided by 200, that'd be you need to play 50 tokens.
Speaker 0: That's 50 times dot.
Speaker 0: 25 cents 1250 for a game gear.
Speaker 0: No, that can't be your.
Speaker 0: your arcade must had lower pay else than mine.
Speaker 0: The major magics didn't have the conveyor belt game I mean But you probably had nothing.
Speaker 0: that was paying out 200 on the single token.
Speaker 1: the conveyor belt game was at the arcade in the mall.
Speaker 1: The Oh God what the poor was that place called the reason it was notable because that arcade had a water slide in it.
Speaker 1: There was a water slide in the mall.
Speaker 1: Okay, that went through the arcade.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: I was a kid.
Speaker 1: All right I was wanted to ride it.
Speaker 1: when I was a little kid I kind of assumed the water slide drowned everyone and it was a trap because I never saw anyone ever get out of it.
Speaker 1: But that's cuz.
Speaker 1: getting out of it was like this hidden area.
Speaker 1: Anyway, the tubes like went around the mall and then ended in the arcade like in the.
Speaker 0: bring a bathing suit to the mall.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it wasn't just a slide slide.
Speaker 0: It was a one-side ball.
Speaker 1: There's a water fucking slide in lakeside mall.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna bring your bathing suit to the mall to go in there Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna try to find a picture of it.
Speaker 1: There it is the fucking water slide in lakeside mall And then it ended in the arcade anyway, okay Wow, that picture actually brings a ridiculous amount of nostalgia into my life.
Speaker 0: okay, so in the meta moment the book club book is a 2001 a Space Odyssey, which I didn't read but I read instead many fans.
Speaker 0: I Could have read 2001 several times over in the time.
Speaker 0: It took me to read those fantasy novels on the beach.
Speaker 0: I also didn't read it by a nerd.
Speaker 1: I am I just played slay the spire for like two weeks.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah All right.
Speaker 1: Otherwise, we are going to be live at PAX unplugged kind of soon.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's in Shitty, Pennsylvania, but it's a pack.
Speaker 1: So real packs.
Speaker 1: We're doing the 40 tabletop games Break even but we're gonna be a little more.
Speaker 1: we're gonna assume the audience knows tabletops.
Speaker 1: We're gonna go a little deeper there and we're doing a learn and win brand-new Puerto Rico for two hours on Saturday.
Speaker 0: Are you ready?
Speaker 0: over/under on five Gritties at PAX unplugged.
Speaker 1: Ooh I Think I'm gonna say under but I think there's gonna be like three or four.
Speaker 0: He's easy.
Speaker 0: three or four.
Speaker 0: Yeah And I think it's gonna be five.
Speaker 0: That's why I put it.
Speaker 1: if I'm saying under cuz I think there's Gonna be I think there's gonna be three or four.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna push but I think two of them will be anti-foss specifically.
Speaker 1: We should bet money on this.
Speaker 1: we should take a.
Speaker 0: no, I'm the bookie.
Speaker 0: that's why I set the odd.
Speaker 1: Say we're gonna be there's gonna be awesome.
Speaker 0: He always pushes.
Speaker 0: otherwise There's that in.
Speaker 0: the odds are huh?
Speaker 1: And also if you are having trouble with Twitter and want somewhere else to go just point out the geek nights forum is a Nazi free social network.
Speaker 1: That's pretty like there's a lot of people in there talking about cool stuff.
Speaker 0: It's also a great place like, you know, a lot of people have sort of set up blog in there.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they just make a thread and make it their blog.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like look chaos Chaos of 99 just posted two reviews and anime in here.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like good to go like that.
Speaker 1: Seriously, like our only rule is you can't be a Nazi in here and we enforce it.
Speaker 1: You also can't be shitty.
Speaker 1: it's the only other rule.
Speaker 1: We enforce that one and it works out pretty well.
Speaker 1: So seriously, forget Twitter.
Speaker 1: join the geek nights forum.
Speaker 1: it like.
Speaker 1: I personally vouch for it.
Speaker 0: I hang out and I personally vouch for my own forum that I'm in charge of.
Speaker 1: Yeah, cuz you know what all I did Yeah, and all I did was kick out the Nazis and the shitty people.
Speaker 0: Nazis can't even get in because they got to apply.
Speaker 0: Oh, that's one thing.
Speaker 0: if you when you apply it makes you type in a reason you are applying and you have to type in Plain-english something that makes me believe that you are not a bot and not a Nazi and that you're like a listener of the show.
Speaker 0: Some people have typed some really good stuff in there Some people have tied good stuff and I instantly approved and some people typed like, you know Want to discuss and that is not enough.
Speaker 1: No that is not getting you in and frankly that those might have been real people.
Speaker 1: But something that's been bothering me lately and I think about this a lot is the people I encounter online who Fail the Turing test if I administer it.
Speaker 1: yet I know they are real people.
Speaker 1: So I decided and Scott agrees in the forum at least if you fail the reverse Turing test You don't get in even if you're a human.
Speaker 0: All you have to do is type something in the box that I a human being I'm going to read with my own eyeballs.
Speaker 0: That will convince me to push the approve button.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: That's all you got to do.
Speaker 1: If you say something about Grady, you're pretty much guaranteed.
Speaker 0: If you say like hi, I'm not pushing approve.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if you say I am a geek nights listener and you told me to listen to the yeah I'm gonna click approve.
Speaker 1: if you say jet fuel can melt steel beams.
Speaker 1: I agree that you're a human, but you're not getting into the forum.
Speaker 0: That one could be paired might be joking like in the right way.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if you could be that the problem is you can't always tell.
Speaker 0: I think I think you know.
Speaker 0: It would be a close call.
Speaker 1: You know what this is a special for the next 48 hours.
Speaker 1: if you type jet fuel can't melt steel beams You're definitely getting in because it means you listen to this episode For
Speaker 0: sure,
Speaker 1: and if you did
Speaker 0: odds of someone typing that in who had not listened
Speaker 1: I'll put it this way if someone types that in in the next 48 hours and didn't listen to this episode It's gonna be funny either way.
Speaker 1: Sure All right, that was like 45 minutes.
Speaker 1: Let's talk about live streaming.
Speaker 0: So we did a show on live streaming already.
Speaker 0: We did in 2013 where it was literally a completely different world and we had Didn't.
Speaker 0: I think we tried to live stream it and fail to do so.
Speaker 1: quote tonight on geek nights We talked about live streaming video while streaming said video live and discovering after the fact that the video ended up stuttery as fuck.
Speaker 1: Sorry about that.
Speaker 1: And then we talked about phone numbers, which is funny.
Speaker 1: Okay, and Scott reviews the iPad the iPad mini Yep, 2013 ladies and gentlemen.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 1: So here we are in 2018.
Speaker 1: We're Live-streaming is completely different.
Speaker 1: Like the technology is way better.
Speaker 1: There's a lot more tools.
Speaker 1: It's just working.
Speaker 1: We like.
Speaker 0: I don't think.
Speaker 0: I think the main difference is that it's just easier and it works But technologically it isn't very much different other than our computers are better and YouTube and Twitter better.
Speaker 1: Here's what I'll say processors got a lot faster.
Speaker 1: That's actually a big important thing.
Speaker 1: like GPUs can help Yep, but seriously the processors in particular.
Speaker 1: 2 gigahertz is about the line below 2 gigahertz.
Speaker 1: You really couldn't do modern streaming.
Speaker 0: Yeah, cuz the first thing about streaming right is that you got a camera and the camera sends video to a computer of some Kind.
Speaker 0: Yep, that is connect to the internet or over USB 2 or your camera has a computer in it That is connected to the internet.
Speaker 0: But either way, you know, that's what your phone's doing when you live stream, right?
Speaker 0: It must take that video it is capturing with its camera and turn it into Like a video file with encoding and that is a CPU intensive process.
Speaker 0: You could even get the GPU in on it to help you if you want.
Speaker 1: now like it wasn't that long ago This was hard to do non real time.
Speaker 0: Yeah back in the day We're using
Speaker 1: like fraps to try to record a game
Speaker 0: or like just using something like, you know You take a DVD you rip it and you'd want to turn that DVD File into a different video file
Speaker 1: that took longer than the running length of the DVD.
Speaker 0: took a computer a in those days My Pentium 3 or whatever a long time to do that, dude It used to take me like two hours to rip a CD.
Speaker 0: if you want a live stream Not only do you need to transcode video you need to do it in real time.
Speaker 0: so if you are streaming at 30 FPS video your computer needs to be able to take a frame of video and turn it into Video data and then upload it to the internet 30 times a second without fucking up.
Speaker 0: Otherwise your video is gonna go up for a frame.
Speaker 0: Yeah every time you fuck up.
Speaker 1: So we needed hardware to catch up which it did like hardware today just had I mean that's 2013 computer could do it barely Mmm, it was.
Speaker 1: I believe we couldn't do it.
Speaker 0: It was.
Speaker 0: it wasn't our computer's fault.
Speaker 1: I'm pretty sure it was our computer in those days.
Speaker 1: It was the fault of Because remember even the Elgato we're on unless I unless I overclock to above 2 gigahertz They actually couldn't keep up any early days.
Speaker 0: Anyway, the next problem you need is You got to get some software that actually does this.
Speaker 1: so in 2013 the like point 0.3 alpha version of OBS existed meaning it didn't really exist.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like there weren't great.
Speaker 0: You know the software available for this sort of thing, you know has as over time, you know There was expensive stuff that did it.
Speaker 0: there was stuff meant for actual TV stations to you like remember Adobe on location.
Speaker 1: Of course you don't right this.
Speaker 0: I remember it.
Speaker 1: I used to try to use it all sorts of different solutions.
Speaker 0: Most of them were like ultra professional expensive things.
Speaker 1: now ashen coder.
Speaker 0: right now There's OBS and if you want to pay some money you can get X split.
Speaker 0: and is this?
Speaker 0: you know This OBS is what you're gonna use probably honestly.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, it's not perfect But it works also.
Speaker 1: OBS just in the last two years Has gotten good to the point that it is suitable for professional usage.
Speaker 0: I mean, yeah it because it works, right?
Speaker 0: It's not user interface wise.
Speaker 0: it is still very poofy.
Speaker 1: Ah, I would argue that it's better than current X split.
Speaker 0: I mean X split isn't the greatest.
Speaker 1: It's like kind of the shitty interface.
Speaker 0: They're both.
Speaker 0: they're both poofy.
Speaker 1: No, I would argue that.
Speaker 1: have you have you used the current version of OBS?
Speaker 0: Yes, cuz my expert license It's better not renewing it.
Speaker 1: The oh at the UX of OBS is in my opinion really really good.
Speaker 0: because I would not say it's really really good.
Speaker 1: I'd say it's really really good because no people who don't know anything about this technology Can just turn it on and it just works.
Speaker 1: because it got over a line that most open-source software.
Speaker 1: It never gets over.
Speaker 1: the line of the intelligent defaults just work and you only need to click in all these menus if you're doing Something weird.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but it's still not.
Speaker 0: it's not exactly an Apple product, right?
Speaker 0: It is still janky.
Speaker 0: It's just got some like rectangle buttons that someone threw together.
Speaker 0: So there no no design.
Speaker 1: There is no Apple like Apple like product that just works for Complex streaming use cases.
Speaker 0: Is this just the crazy expensive professional one?
Speaker 1: Like what name one?
Speaker 0: What's that fucking thing called?
Speaker 1: Yeah, I do wire cast.
Speaker 1: Have you used it?
Speaker 0: No, this isn't.
Speaker 0: there's like a you know, I forget what it's called Adobe has a professional one.
Speaker 1: That is the successor to on location.
Speaker 1: that things a piece of shit.
Speaker 1: You don't use that.
Speaker 0: No, no, no, there's like a thing that they actually use it like Like TV stations and shit.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know what?
Speaker 1: But what one?
Speaker 1: there's hardware solutions that have like proprietor there.
Speaker 1: those things are so hard to use That you remember the old TriCaster.
Speaker 1: they feel like that.
Speaker 0: the point is you're gonna use OBS, right?
Speaker 0: And now OBS you you if you are intelligent enough to listen to gig nights You're intelligent enough to figure it out, even though it's poopy.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and it works and it's free.
Speaker 1: So the other thing that caught up is computers.
Speaker 1: It's not just.
Speaker 1: they were fast enough to encode all the video stream and send it live.
Speaker 1: They got fast enough to.
Speaker 1: it's like I'm sending three video streams to OBS and like four audio streams and Muxing and mixing them all together and those are two different things and sending a composite stream.
Speaker 1: Computers were definitely not fucking fast enough to do that in 2013.
Speaker 0: Well, the main other thing is that you're right you could when you're streaming You could try to stream directly to the people watching which is what a lot of people tried to do back in the day.
Speaker 0: They would get their own server and stream to it and then people would connect to their server.
Speaker 0: Yeah, then I remember What was it the hurricane in New Orleans?
Speaker 0: Yeah, there was like a live stream of Someplace flooding and I was watching it.
Speaker 0: But it's like there was like a hundred people watching this guy's webcam in his flooded store and it's like he was running that off his own hosted computer and That computer couldn't really handle because it had to upload data to how many people they didn't have the bandwidth to upload to.
Speaker 0: Yep, right so many people cuz like.
Speaker 0: okay all the CPU part has already been done But these JPEGs need is in 30 JPEGs a second every time.
Speaker 0: Alright, so you're sending out 30 JPEGs a second and you get a second person watching now.
Speaker 0: You're sending out 60 JPEGs right now right now in the life.
Speaker 0: You get a third person watching now You're sitting on 90 JPEGs a second.
Speaker 1: They're a linear scaling and not only that but quality wise like quality is going up.
Speaker 1: So the the default the bitrate you want to use in the modern era is about six megabits per second.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like sending more than that is a special use case already and you're sending out, you know It's 1080p video.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so six megabits per second Those 30 frames are 1080p each.
Speaker 1: six megabits per second times the 13 people watching this stream live right now is Already not cheap.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so thankfully nowadays because of YouTube and Twitch And other you know companies that are providing streaming services You just stream your one stream to them and now they with their massive massive computers will a transcode it again into many different formats of someone watching on their phone watching on a TV or someone watching on a 4k screen or someone watching on a tablet or someone watching on a shitty low-res computer or all kinds of different screens are gonna get any.
Speaker 0: or someone watching with really little bandwidth are gonna get an appropriate video for them because it's been transcoded so many times and also They're the ones handling the scaling part.
Speaker 0: You only have to handle the 130 JPEGs a second.
Speaker 0: Then if you get a hundred viewers or a thousand viewers or ten thousand viewers, that's on them And for some reason they're providing that for free.
Speaker 0: I'll take it Sure, provide me that bandwidth for free.
Speaker 0: Thank you.
Speaker 1: So I think what really made that like what made that difference is gaming streaming in particular took off big.
Speaker 1: They must be making money But it made a consumer market which meant that now like tools like do you know how many like?
Speaker 1: Supplemental pieces of software exist to make live streaming easier.
Speaker 1: how much hardware like Consumers and prosumers can buy?
Speaker 1: that'll just make this stuff work.
Speaker 1: None of that existed in 2013.
Speaker 1: Remember the Elgato and what a piece of shit that thing was.
Speaker 1: we've come a long way.
Speaker 0: I mean the Elgato actually was good and worked until it just suddenly stopped working.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well the trouble with mine was that my laptop was not powerful enough to encode because they didn't do the encoding.
Speaker 1: It was basically just a glorified video capture device.
Speaker 0: I mean the Aver thing I have now also is just a glorified video capture device Except it just works instead of the Aver which didn't work.
Speaker 0: I mean the Elgato.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the Aver one I have works.
Speaker 0: the Elgato one just broke eventually, but effectively they're like the same functionality Yep.
Speaker 1: But also the fact that streaming got built into a lot of games and a lot of software Like consoles will just live stream like.
Speaker 1: there's all this live streaming culture Which made a market for technology to make live streaming easier for non-professionals and Professionals are just reaping the benefits of having access to all these free or cheap tools Like there's so much more available than there was in 2013 that it's staggering
Speaker 0: right now.
Speaker 0: There's certain things you might want to do if you're doing some advanced streaming and some of those things Are very difficult to do still and some of them have gotten easier.
Speaker 0: So for example, one thing I like to do is I stream one time, but I want to stream to YouTube and Twitch at the same time.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so right now with my computer I could stream to YouTube and Twitch and record a different resolution like a high Quality version to my hard drive and it would even put a dent in my computer, right?
Speaker 0: But the thing is you would it would still.
Speaker 0: if I did that from my computer I would have to use double bandwidth double bandwidth.
Speaker 0: So there's a website Restream.io that provides the service for free.
Speaker 0: I stream to restream.io using RTMP and then with RTMP is basically like the HTTP of streaming yep, and then they stream to YouTube and Twitch and But it's already very telling.
Speaker 1: when I was first doing live streaming and attempting to do it I had to actually know a lot about RTMP worked and like set stuff up
Speaker 0: If you don't want to use some sort of service like restream in order to do this You have to set up like your own server somewhere and that will do this Restreaming for you and you stream to it and then it streams to the right and like.
Speaker 0: if you want to say combine your Stream and your friends stream together like your friends at home.
Speaker 0: You're at home and you want to combine your streams together into one video frame you need to like set up a server and your friends streams to it and then your Your friend at you add your friends stream as a source to your stream and things get complicated real quick.
Speaker 1: Yep, so The fact that like OBS just has a button that's like I am connecting to YouTube.
Speaker 1: I'm connecting to the other service.
Speaker 1: like you can set up manual streams new clever stuff, but you don't have to yep.
Speaker 0: So a twitch con which just happened.
Speaker 0: they announced that they're gonna add slowly I think towards the end of the year.
Speaker 0: this year, they're gonna add it for select streamers But then hopefully next year for everybody.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's quad stream and the way shit We're gonna use this because there's a thing we wanted to do that would be a pain to do without this.
Speaker 0: The way it works is.
Speaker 0: I streamed my twitch rim streams to his twitch channel.
Speaker 0: We got two channels going but we're both playing counter-strike.
Speaker 0: Let's say right, but then I go on twitch and I say yo twitch Rim, he and my squad and then rim does the same thing.
Speaker 0: I guess I don't know.
Speaker 0: and then when you watch my channel, you'll see under the big video box Which has me in it a little video box, which is rim in it and you can click on that to switch Between us and you'll basically be able to swap channels really quickly between both of us.
Speaker 0: and whichever channel you're on You're gonna see the other channel in a small box And if we've got a whole team of say 10 people playing a game There'll be nine little boxes and the one big one that you're watching currently.
Speaker 0: So now you can sort of see all the perspectives on a single event.
Speaker 0: if you know Ten channels are all streaming sort of together.
Speaker 0: Yep And that saves you a lot of the trouble of doing say those RTMP tricks I just talked about.
Speaker 0: so setting up servers and all that nonsense.
Speaker 1: the two problems that remain Really like in terms of live-streaming today seem to be that Most people who want to do it don't know how to make their audio sound good.
Speaker 0: Yep, but that's that's also partly the fault of the tools like OBS and X split not helping you out too much.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, they do.
Speaker 1: There's a whole compressor chain built into OBS now that just works.
Speaker 0: Yes, but it is not some.
Speaker 0: it is not an intelligent default, right?
Speaker 1: Actually it is.
Speaker 1: Did you try to recently?
Speaker 1: they really up their game?
Speaker 0: You have to.
Speaker 0: you have to click something to turn it on.
Speaker 0: it's not just automatic.
Speaker 0: it happens you don't.
Speaker 0: If you start playing a game and your game is too loud It doesn't intelligently adjust to match your game.
Speaker 1: And so the right.
Speaker 1: the problem there is a little more fundamental though.
Speaker 0: It needs something that automatically looks to see how loud your game is.
Speaker 0: how loud you're talking is Adjust both automatically without you having to sit there and fiddle with.
Speaker 1: that doesn't even exist in like professional settings And it probably won't anytime in the foreseeable future.
Speaker 0: Oh, whoa, because
Speaker 1: honestly and
Speaker 0: that's why no matter how good they make it unless they make it that good people continue to fuck it up,
Speaker 1: but that what it means is that Live-streaming unlocks like all this stuff for people who know the basics of video and audio production None of this stuff helps you with like three-point lighting know or how to use a microphone.
Speaker 1: No, and the other problem is that?
Speaker 1: No solution that any of you will have access to will Synchronize the audio and video across all the multiple sources.
Speaker 1: You're trying to mux together.
Speaker 1: There's a reason why my mouth and Scott's mouth don't 100% match.
Speaker 1: what's on that?
Speaker 1: because this is a webcam.
Speaker 1: That is a different webcam.
Speaker 1: This is going through a firewire mixer right a hardware.
Speaker 0: Let's say I'm looking at a webcam and the webcam has a microphone built in right.
Speaker 0: So if I just use the webcam only and the microphone built into the web perfect sync It will be perfectly synchronized because that webcam is synchronizing the video and the audio that it captures.
Speaker 0: So when it we stream from the webcam, everything's gonna be great.
Speaker 0: But if I turn off the microphone in the webcam and use a different microphone How can I sync or synchronize this microphone with the webcam video?
Speaker 0: The answer is you fucking can't.
Speaker 0: it's almost impossible.
Speaker 1: Yep now with most of the ways you would do this you could try to set an offset like look at it and figure out like Oh, it's about two milliseconds off.
Speaker 1: So put a delay in one of the lines, but the problem is usually that latency is non-deterministic.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and then you got say you drop a frame here and there and all the weird stuff happens.
Speaker 0: It's like, you know that you get your computer involved in this, you know You could try to synchronize it outside of the computer using some sort of device and that would.
Speaker 0: that would get you right where you Need to be.
Speaker 0: but if you try to synchronize it in the computer Things are gonna get off.
Speaker 1: So this is why like you're gonna drift.
Speaker 1: if like part of the reason why I got that fancy camcorder with the XLR inputs Is that say we're gonna do a live stream of like a board game thing.
Speaker 1: I would actually take the main audio Into the camera directly via the two XLR cables.
Speaker 1: So there's at least one set of two channels of audio that are guaranteed in sync at the time of encoding With at least one of my video channels.
Speaker 0: And a pro tip is most of the time all that matters is that your mouth is Synchronized.
Speaker 0: people don't really care if the other audio is like half a millisecond off that they won't notice, right?
Speaker 0: We're playing a board game and that the the table is like a few milliseconds drifted and no one will notice.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the only notice of our mouths are drifted.
Speaker 0: So that's sub millisecond to synchronize the camera and the audio and video with our the mouth camera.
Speaker 0: Yep, that shows our face.
Speaker 1: and I guess the only other problem that remains it really is You know the rest of the production cycle like lighting and like color and like all that stuff.
Speaker 1: There really aren't prosumers allusions to that.
Speaker 1: in terms of the streaming technology That's just make a recording studio make a soundstage.
Speaker 1: Guess what?
Speaker 1: It's huge and it sucks.
Speaker 0: That's most people even professional streamers get away with.
Speaker 0: you know, put a light in front of you of some kind.
Speaker 0: It's bright enough use a camera or a webcam that's good.
Speaker 0: That's expensive.
Speaker 0: That's fancy.
Speaker 0: Yeah I just 1080p or 4k.
Speaker 0: and then some people the one thing they do that's actually not very difficult and is made actually very easy Is to do some chroma key to erase the background.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and what you do is you buy a green screen, which is just a big green sheet.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you put it behind you and in fact, there are some webcam solutions that can sort of green screen without a green screen.
Speaker 0: They sort of figure it out and sort of draw the line around you really shittily, but they work.
Speaker 0: And that way you could say appear in the corner of your video.
Speaker 0: there you are of your game There you are, but there's nothing around you.
Speaker 0: You're just sort of super imposed on front of the game like a ghost.
Speaker 0: Yeah Or you sort of erase your room So no one can see what's in your house and you put something else behind you.
Speaker 0: But
Speaker 1: the reality is even now short of a
Speaker 0: city or a
Speaker 1: fire short of like pop culture mainstream stuff like most streaming Content is what matters more than anything as long as your quality is above the line kind of like the early days of podcasting Yeah, so production values mean nothing unless your content is good.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and like.
Speaker 1: for us audio is the main content, which is why my audio pipeline costs a lot more than my video pipeline.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the one other thing is if you are doing game streaming specifically You're gonna want to add like especially I'm like a twitch situation.
Speaker 0: You got to add like these graphics like someone just subscribed and you know.
Speaker 1: But again, software just exists to make all this happen.
Speaker 0: The stuff that GDQ has, right?
Speaker 0: You know that like where it's like they're showing the donations on there and stuff And it's like.
Speaker 0: how do you do that?
Speaker 0: Basically, they make like a web page that shows all that stuff.
Speaker 0: Or they make some sort of program that just displays all those graphics And then has green in it in the spots they want to erase.
Speaker 1: You can either buy like packages and plugins that do this stuff Or like even OBS has plug-in points like point it at a URL point it at a rest service Like it'll just kind of work.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you can just make an exe run it and then add it as like, you know.
Speaker 0: So it's like you're streaming two games and one of the games on top of the other game and one of them is see-through Right stuff like that.
Speaker 0: So it's actually it's.
Speaker 0: it's like.
Speaker 0: you're like, whoa, how do they do that?
Speaker 0: It's actually really easy once you see someone do it.
Speaker 0: It's like, oh, that's how you done it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's really janky and simple But they're actually it's really hard to search online for how to do that.
Speaker 0: It's like not well documented.
Speaker 0: So you sort of need someone to show you and then it becomes obvious.
Speaker 1: and on that note, I'm hungry.
Speaker 1: So This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at front row crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 1: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 0: But unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night And the patreon patrons for this episode of geek nights cannot be easily read to you because patreon is currently down.
Speaker 1: So rather than just I might just play the one from the last episode we did and Leave it at that because I don't know when it'll come back up.
Speaker 1: But anyway, we're back with normal geek nights from this point forward.
Speaker 1: So stay tuned for all our nonsense including our panels of packs and a bunch of videos, etc.
Speaker 1: But now I leave you with Craig Oliver, Ellen Joyce, Heidi McNicholas, shimming rubiobolus, hanging in the sky chartovician mystady.com, linky, gjbanz, scootalonely, Roberto Kingsley, Sean Yeager Matthew Smith, Nicholas Brandau, Mr.
Speaker 1: Strong, Strachan, 421 creations, Chris Reimer and Thomas Hahn Shervin Von Harl, Rory Rochelle Montanona, Superboy, Tripwire, SailorVista, Don Schleich, Joe Shiro, Joe Star, Clinton Walton, Wren from New Zealand, Ryan Perrin, Drew Copenlander, Finn, Chris Midkiff, Daniel Redman, Sean Klein, Chris Reimer and Thomas Hahn.