Speaker 0: It's Monday April 30th 2018.
Speaker 0: I'm rim.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott and this is geek nights tonight.
Speaker 0: What's next for smartphones?
Speaker 0: Let's do this so as you all know I Very much don't like large cell phones like if I could get a phone that was the size of my old palm free But had the capabilities of a modern smartphone.
Speaker 0: I'd be very much for it.
Speaker 1: It just doesn't make any sense right is?
Speaker 1: in the earliest days They came with the iPod and then they're like smaller smaller smaller.
Speaker 1: Let's make this as small as we can.
Speaker 1: and then we got that iPad And everyone was and everyone was like common sense.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: I would like to carry around more things in less space iPod Nano iPod shuffle, let's go as small as we can go.
Speaker 1: We don't want to carry around a big heavy fucking thing.
Speaker 1: and then the iPhone came out and then they're like iPhone 3g Smaller iPhone 4 smaller iPhone 5 smaller and all these other companies were like we make them bigger.
Speaker 1: And why did they make them bigger?
Speaker 1: It wasn't because bigger is actually better.
Speaker 1: It's because they did not have the miniaturization.
Speaker 1: It's hard to make something small.
Speaker 1: Yeah They did not have the advanced hardware miniaturization technology that Apple had.
Speaker 1: so but they did have was marketing Technology and they just convinced people that bigger they like bigger screen guys.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we can't make our battery any smaller.
Speaker 1: So, uh-huh, but we're not gonna tell you that just you know bigger is better.
Speaker 1: So people believe bigger is better because they're stupid American.
Speaker 0: but I have also found that in general most of the Preference I see for large phones stems from a combination of untreated vision problems People who don't have a computer.
Speaker 0: Their smartphone is the only computing device they own and they literally use it for everything.
Speaker 1: Uh Those are primarily the two People who say they have big hands, but actually don't.
Speaker 1: if you actually measure their hand Yeah, I think they have a big.
Speaker 0: well, never mind There's that UX study that showed across the board phones above a certain size, which that size by the way is Not much bigger than my tiny phone right now.
Speaker 0: our objectively slower for even expert users to interact with Because the thumb can't get all the way across.
Speaker 0: Yep So, uh, I guess the other reason I've seen is a lot of the people we know our friends who were like Oh, I like a big phone and these are people who should know better.
Speaker 1: I mean, obviously there's some personal preference like I guess if you're not carrying your phone if you're using it as a tablet.
Speaker 1: If you're just putting it in a car, it doesn't go in.
Speaker 0: Ah, but that's it.
Speaker 1: I'll go in a pocket.
Speaker 0: almost everyone.
Speaker 0: I know who has a giant ass phone Does is not walking long distances mobile every single day?
Speaker 1: Like we let their phone in a bag instead of in their pocket Like we all get.
Speaker 1: so at work We had a really don't carry their phone with them at all possible times.
Speaker 1: Like it is an appendage of their body.
Speaker 1: I know where's your phone?
Speaker 1: Oh somewhere else.
Speaker 1: It's like maybe if it wasn't a big fucking ass thing You would have all the time.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like you should.
Speaker 0: so anyway, I the problem with this is that I want a small phone and We hit this point where most Android phones got really really big like starting with the Nexus 5 and onward.
Speaker 0: They're just gigantic, but you've heard me say this before I did find the perfect phone.
Speaker 0: a few years ago I got these Sony Xperia Z 5 compact because I don't enjoy the Apple experience and I'm already too deep into the Android ecosystem.
Speaker 0: so iPhone is is an option that I continue to exclude and A lot of my friends have iPhones except for Scott seemed to periodically run into weird complaints that I do not have Random stuff like the other day.
Speaker 0: I so in Android.
Speaker 0: my Android Google keyboard has a really easy way to automatically insert gifs into anything.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I have g-board for it's an app you get in the App Store.
Speaker 1: It gives you the Google keyboard.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so Multiple people we know who have iPhones don't know they can install the Google keyboard things like that because they're stupid.
Speaker 0: Well, they don't know better.
Speaker 1: I just it's an app called G board.
Speaker 1: I use the Google keyboard the only time it doesn't show.
Speaker 1: in fact The iPhone is so smart that the G board actually communicates with Google.
Speaker 1: right networking wise.
Speaker 1: So Apple does not allow custom keyboards to appear whenever you're in a password prompt Forces it to be the local only no network communication Apple iPhone and then it switches back to the Google keyboard for any other inputs.
Speaker 1: So that way nobody.
Speaker 1: if you were to say install an evil custom keyboard app It couldn't spy on you because in the OS it will not allow a custom keyboard on a password prompt.
Speaker 1: So it's so smart.
Speaker 0: The z5 compact was pretty much the best Physically like put together Android phone for a long time now.
Speaker 0: the problem with it is that it's a Sony.
Speaker 0: So it's boutique and it was a little expensive.
Speaker 0: But the benefit was it was straight-up waterproof, which I tested.
Speaker 1: I used it in water Just dunked it in a bucket.
Speaker 0: I like.
Speaker 0: I brought it with me in the shower.
Speaker 1: I brought it up dump it in a bucket of water.
Speaker 1: It's a fully submerged and see what happens.
Speaker 0: I Swam with it in a pool and took pictures underwater.
Speaker 1: All right, can I can I take it and dump it in a bucket after the show?
Speaker 0: my old phone?
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's fine.
Speaker 0: I'll put it in a glass of water right now.
Speaker 0: It's totally fine.
Speaker 0: All right The battery also lasted like two full days.
Speaker 1: post a photo of it playing like a YouTube video while it's in the cup of water.
Speaker 0: I mean, this isn't that unknown.
Speaker 0: There was a waterproof phone.
Speaker 1: We'll see.
Speaker 0: What do you mean?
Speaker 0: We'll see we'll see.
Speaker 1: Okay Anyway, so wait you said your old phone?
Speaker 1: Well, you're not gonna put your new phone in a cup of water.
Speaker 0: So my new so that old phone was the most waterproofist phone that anyone's really ever made and most of them have walked in back walked it back to Water-resistant, I think IP 68.
Speaker 0: This is to IP whatever ratings that they've got.
Speaker 0: So my new phone should survive submersion But it's not recommended to submerge.
Speaker 0: as opposed to the previous phone, which they were like fucking.
Speaker 0: take pictures with it underwater.
Speaker 0: It's fine.
Speaker 0: It is water proof.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: And while they got sued over that I looked into the details.
Speaker 0: It was only not waterproof.
Speaker 0: if you have futzed with it Or if you like open this little door on the side of it that was sealed that held the SIM card Which would not open unless you really picked at it.
Speaker 1: Anyway, this phone sometimes they're like waterproof But like then if you push a button Pressing the button sort of breaks the seals.
Speaker 0: the pebble had that problem for a second.
Speaker 0: The pebble was waterproof unless you pushed a button and then it was no longer waterproof.
Speaker 0: Yeah But this phone was brilliant and the problem was it's put it's well over two years old.
Speaker 0: The battery started running out and unlike the iPhones which were just throttling your speed So the battery would still last all day without telling you.
Speaker 0: This is an Android phone.
Speaker 0: So the battery just ran out faster and faster.
Speaker 1: Which one of these things is preferable, but I can configure it.
Speaker 0: I could tell it to throttle itself.
Speaker 0: It was configurable.
Speaker 0: That's the difference.
Speaker 0: the Android ecosystem.
Speaker 0: people complain.
Speaker 1: They added a switch for that in the iPhone.
Speaker 1: I did not touch it.
Speaker 1: I left it the way it was.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but the phone's starting to wear out because it's two and a half years old and I can go to the Apple Store Just get a new battery.
Speaker 0: Well, yeah dollars Zero dollars.
Speaker 0: how long after you bought the phone?
Speaker 0: or do you have Apple care full-on or whatever?
Speaker 0: I get Apple care.
Speaker 0: Yeah What do you pay for that?
Speaker 0: It's not zero dollars.
Speaker 0: That's that Apple care cost.
Speaker 1: It's included because I got the iPhone upgrade program.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah But how much does that cost compared to just buying an iPhone?
Speaker 0: Zero extra zero extra.
Speaker 1: if you were to buy the iPhone outright and then buy Apple care that would cost you extra money.
Speaker 1: If you get the upgrade plan, you're basically financing the phone at zero percent interest over two years.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and then you get free Apple care and you're only paying the price of the phone just on monthly install But you lose the resale value of the previous phone.
Speaker 1: I assume so Don't think I've ever sold a previous phone.
Speaker 0: Well, normal people do they usually just if they don't break their phone They sell it.
Speaker 1: I don't do that.
Speaker 1: I just give it to someone I know.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Well, that's cuz we got money.
Speaker 1: So also the thing is the resale.
Speaker 1: if you use the upgrade plan and you actually I was gonna do the upgrade but then They didn't release a better enough iPhone.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so that's the only problem with the upgrade plan.
Speaker 1: But the you turn in the old phone which begets automatically fully repaired by Apple care before you turn it in.
Speaker 1: So it gets you go and you go use the Apple care You're like.
Speaker 1: can I have a brand new screen in a band your battery please to make sure the resale value of my phone is?
Speaker 1: Perfect.
Speaker 1: Thank you All right.
Speaker 1: Now I'm giving you the phone back and you're using the value of that phone towards the app.
Speaker 1: the next iPhone that I'm upgrading.
Speaker 1: So the next iPhone you upgrade to now cost you less because you turned in the old one to Apple.
Speaker 0: So I did my research to see if in the third two and a half years since I last bought a phone Anything had changed.
Speaker 0: the answer was no.
Speaker 0: Only Sony makes small Android phones that are good and only Sony has good hardware design for small phones.
Speaker 0: so the Xperia XZ2 Compact is the newest one that came out.
Speaker 0: It just came out and it's an ugly looking piece of shit and it's big.
Speaker 0: The compact is a more than a centimeter taller than the previous Compact and taller is the problem because taller means it will fit in my tiny pocket.
Speaker 1: Is it waterproof?
Speaker 1: Can you put it in the ocean?
Speaker 0: No phones are waterproof anymore.
Speaker 0: Okay, it's water resistant Like it would survive dunking in water the ocean, uh, probably for a short amount of time.
Speaker 0: But and I don't want to get into the details of what those different IP whatever certifications Can I put it inside a walrus and take it out?
Speaker 0: Why walrus?
Speaker 1: I was thinking hippo, but I said the wrong thing.
Speaker 0: Anyway, the XZ2 compact is big ugly Not materially better than the previous year's iteration the XZ1 compact.
Speaker 0: Also, it's way expensive.
Speaker 0: the previous year's XZ1 compact is in my estimation as of today April 30th 2018 the best Android phone hardware on the market.
Speaker 0: it is just markedly better in every way than the Z5 compact that I had before.
Speaker 0: it's super fast.
Speaker 0: It's got the newest version of Android.
Speaker 1: Is that just because it has a battery that's not dying?
Speaker 0: It's not just that.
Speaker 0: it is faster.
Speaker 1: It has a much faster process if you just buy two for insurance and then use the second one when the first one dies.
Speaker 0: So what I did instead is this is the first time in my life I bought a new phone while my old one was still technically usable.
Speaker 0: It's not like every other time where the old one stopped working And I have to buy something Like when you broke your computer and then you can upgrade your computer so you can render faster.
Speaker 0: Yes, so this time the USB ports a little jank, but otherwise the phone works fine.
Speaker 0: It's just slow because the battery is shitty.
Speaker 0: So I just bought the new phone because I did my research.
Speaker 0: It's about the cycle time.
Speaker 0: it's the best one and all I have to say about this phone having used it is that I have Zero complaints.
Speaker 0: This phone is amazing.
Speaker 0: if you want an Android phone That's the problem with it.
Speaker 0: This is the one and it's only like 400 bucks because it's last year's model and the newer model is like 700 bucks and worse.
Speaker 1: See what I'm hoping for.
Speaker 0: Also this phone appears to have One of the best if not the best camera of any Android phone.
Speaker 0: It's a crazy good camera.
Speaker 1: What's likely to happen this year is that you're gonna get first of all, they're gonna upgrade Supposedly within like a month or two, maybe the the iPhone SE, you know, the one that still looks like an iPhone 5.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so then that will be a very good choice for a tiny phone and I might go that route.
Speaker 1: but also they may.
Speaker 1: They're supposedly, you know iPhone 9 or whatever It's gonna be is gonna.
Speaker 1: basically they realize no one bought an iPhone X for a fucking thousand dollars.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they're gonna take the iPhone X technology The only part of which that anyone really wants.
Speaker 1: no one cares about fucking like face recognition garbage, right or whatever that is.
Speaker 1: But the only technology in the iPhone X that I want is the fancy OLED screen of oh, it's as fancy as screen.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah The best LEDs the best screen on any phone there is.
Speaker 1: and supposedly you take that screen and you put it on a cheaper phone And then I go.
Speaker 1: Oh, that is the best screen on a phone.
Speaker 1: I buy that.
Speaker 1: Yeah But yeah, I'm real pleased with this.
Speaker 0: so if you need an Android phone in the in the immediate future, I Think this is literally the only one worth buying even despite its Sony because it's not stock Android.
Speaker 0: You can really only get good stock Android if you read your phone or you buy like a Google device But all like a Nexus whatever is whatever those turned into.
Speaker 0: but all those phones are gigantic monsters so it's not worth it.
Speaker 0: and the Sony like branded Android is 99% of Android like none of the Sony.
Speaker 0: shit gets in my way.
Speaker 0: you can disable the few things that actually does And it's pretty much as normal Android and it gets updates constantly.
Speaker 1: Hmm So just because it's Tech Monday, I can make this aside about technology.
Speaker 1: So OLEDs if people don't know.
Speaker 1: so in normal screens for any kind of screen whether it's a phone or a TV or whatever Right most screens these days are LED screens.
Speaker 1: This is a sheet of You know Like, you know LCD liquid crystals that change colors Yeah, and then in order to see the image that's being generated on the screen basically, there's a light bulb behind there that shines through and Basically that light bulb is if the TV is on or the phone is on the light bulb is on.
Speaker 1: And the better screens these days don't use light bulbs.
Speaker 1: They use LEDs to light them up.
Speaker 1: That's what someone means.
Speaker 0: They say an LED TV, but it's really these that are on all the time.
Speaker 1: It's still just an LCD screen.
Speaker 1: It's the same screen as a right as an old screen.
Speaker 1: It's just has LEDs a different light bulb a better light bulb, right?
Speaker 1: So it's a better image.
Speaker 1: an OLED screen is an organic LED, right?
Speaker 1: So basically what those do is In the screen itself in the LCD part the pixels each have their own light.
Speaker 1: they light up Individually, which means that the pixels that are dark are dark, you know When you look at a TV and you see the even in the black area It's sort of gray because you got this light shining through Right, and that's what makes the image and the contrast ratio kind of crappy and hazy and not as awesome as a movie theater.
Speaker 1: Right, but an OLED screen is like only the pixels that are lit up are lit up and the other ones are pitch fucking Black and it looks incredible.
Speaker 1: It's the best image like screen you can get since like plasma screens ain't cheap.
Speaker 1: They ain't cheap because the factories that make them have very very low yields.
Speaker 1: like they try to make an OLED screen in the factory and like the vast majority of them like More than I say 75% of them when they come off the fad into the factory line there.
Speaker 1: They got there busted like they're no good.
Speaker 1: It's like oh, this one's no good.
Speaker 1: This one's no good.
Speaker 0: Typical of a new technology of any kind.
Speaker 0: once you hit mass manufacturing, right?
Speaker 1: So you can actually you know, so think that the the TVs are ultra expensive because at the factory they're making the big screens.
Speaker 1: You're getting even worse yields, right?
Speaker 1: Cuz you make this giant screen and like a few pixels are bad You make more pixels better odds of some of them being busted, right?
Speaker 0: Let's we're past the point where I'm.
Speaker 0: well I mean remember when LCDs were first around the idea of Returning one because it had five or six busted pixels wasn't a thing like.
Speaker 0: you couldn't return an LCD for that.
Speaker 0: That was expected.
Speaker 1: Yeah, then Samsung figured that out.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but but now but now.
Speaker 1: so you'll see OLEDs these days on like watches and Phones because you make it a smaller screen.
Speaker 1: More of the screens you make will turn out to be good because they're smaller.
Speaker 1: You have a better shot of not fucking up any parts of it when you're making something smaller.
Speaker 0: But well as fewer pixels smaller not miniaturized smaller, right?
Speaker 1: Right, right.
Speaker 1: But yeah, so but the The giant TVs are like ultra expensive.
Speaker 1: So if you win a lottery or you save up your money and you I guess Use your TV more than anything else cuz your cash potato you should invest in an OLED TV because they are besto And that's why I want to OLED phone.
Speaker 1: But otherwise if you don't have a fortune of money or TV is not the most important thing in your life Just get a normal screen the way cheaper like orders of magnitude cheaper for and the only thing you're getting is You know a little gray in the black area a big deal.
Speaker 1: You won't notice.
Speaker 0: So I'm sure you all saw the news that Microsoft sent a computer recycler to jail and didn't really read the details of what happened.
Speaker 1: Alright, so here's this story.
Speaker 1: I think we actually may have reported this story a long time ago when the case started.
Speaker 1: but here's here's the deal.
Speaker 1: Right as a guy and he runs a business a nonprofit act sort of thing, right?
Speaker 1: I don't know the exact details, but it's one of those places that takes old computers Collects them all together takes out the good parts Recycles the bad parts and puts together working computers out of old parts and then you know gives them the people or places that need Computers and don't need a lot of horsepower.
Speaker 1: right and you're you're saving so much in an environment.
Speaker 1: You're saving people who can't afford computers.
Speaker 1: It's such a great thing to do.
Speaker 1: the people come there and learn how to build computers.
Speaker 1: It's just like this multifaceted really great thing to do.
Speaker 1: So this dude I did a thing where he needed.
Speaker 1: he wasn't pirating software necessarily, right?
Speaker 1: Cuz you know, he wasn't making license keys Windows license keys.
Speaker 1: But when you're you know setting up these old computers They have these Windows stickers on them with the keys because it's some old case.
Speaker 1: you Dell case you found from 19, you know 2000 whatever.
Speaker 0: Yep, and I think the OEM license you actually have to put it on some part of the computer, right?
Speaker 1: So he's got this old Dell case.
Speaker 1: They put a new motherboard and stuff in there.
Speaker 1: It's still the same computer with new parts and they got that Windows license on there.
Speaker 1: That's legally belongs to that computer or whatever computer ends up in that box and they want to install Windows.
Speaker 1: You need a Windows disk, you know, cuz those are old computers.
Speaker 1: It's spinning optical drives.
Speaker 1: You need a Windows disk to install Windows on there.
Speaker 1: So, you know, those aren't you know, the easiest to come by.
Speaker 1: I saved all mine.
Speaker 1: I got like Windows 95 B.
Speaker 0: Well, so like my my old laptop I got Windows 2000 my my current laptop.
Speaker 0: actually the OEM license keys Would not work with Windows 10 upgrade.
Speaker 0: There's a bunch of issues.
Speaker 0: We're just wouldn't?
Speaker 1: I started out my whole deal and got everything to work super great.
Speaker 0: yeah, well part of us is.
Speaker 0: I'd also replaced the hard drive which had died and There was a spinning disk risk.
Speaker 0: Well, there was a because it was dead.
Speaker 0: There's nothing I could do about it.
Speaker 0: I meant you fucked up your license key, man There was a spinning disk recovery that could not deploy to the new drive Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: So I ended up just buying a Windows 10 license and just installing on it.
Speaker 0: cuz I didn't want to deal with it.
Speaker 1: I bought a Windows.
Speaker 1: I think I had a Windows Vista ultimate license and then I got it upgrade to Windows 7 Pro and then I took that license and I upgraded it to Windows 10 with the free upgrade.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: And then now it's in such a state that when I set up the new computer the one I just bought I Went to Amazon where I bought the keys from.
Speaker 1: Legally, right.
Speaker 1: and you when you log into Amazon You can see there's a screen you can find in your account where all your keys for all the software you've ever bought are Still there for yep.
Speaker 1: And I took that last a very last key that upgrade key that I used to upgrade from 7 to 10 And that was the only key I needed plus my Microsoft account and it totally just installed legal windows on.
Speaker 1: that can nuke brand new Computer that had nothing to do with the computer that died.
Speaker 1: So it totally works now.
Speaker 0: Well, not too shabby.
Speaker 0: Anyway, I don't know computers.
Speaker 0: that often doesn't matter anymore.
Speaker 1: I needed for this to work.
Speaker 1: He needed the Windows CDs with the old versions of Windows.
Speaker 1: So, you know, he Microsoft he mass manufactured these disks to get you know to give to people who need.
Speaker 1: we're making old computers.
Speaker 1: and Then Microsoft took him to court was like counterfeiting piracy.
Speaker 1: We're gonna sue you into oblivion you bad.
Speaker 1: and then now he lost and he going to jail for a 15 months or something.
Speaker 0: Well, it seems like the disks he was getting it.
Speaker 0: It's this is where it gets sort of complicated long time.
Speaker 0: He's going to jail cuz he was getting.
Speaker 1: you know, it's 15 years or 15 months.
Speaker 0: He was getting.
Speaker 0: I don't know what it says in here.
Speaker 1: Anyway, he wants right here.
Speaker 1: So he lost the court case.
Speaker 1: He's going to jail and everyone is when you hear that story that I just told you're gonna get mad, right?
Speaker 1: That's some bullshit right there.
Speaker 1: The guy was copying Windows disks.
Speaker 1: He wasn't generating keys It wasn't pirating Windows.
Speaker 1: every one of those disks still needed a key to go with it, etc.
Speaker 1: Here's the story.
Speaker 1: Microsoft actually put out a good press release that gave out information That changes your thoughts on this story a little bit.
Speaker 1: and there's the two things that change your thoughts in the story.
Speaker 1: one He was not given out these discs for free.
Speaker 1: He was charging a tiny amount of money for them.
Speaker 1: But also there's like emails.
Speaker 1: they showed that you know They were in court as evidence of him like expecting to profit from selling these discs and even so like I think if a he Hadn't been selling the discs.
Speaker 1: He just given away for zero.
Speaker 1: I don't think Microsoft would have done a goddamn thing about it, right?
Speaker 1: It's because he was charging money for them even though he was you know, not Selling the keys only the copies of the software, right?
Speaker 1: So that's problem number one.
Speaker 1: and problem number two is He wasn't just going to make it a bunch of CD ours and scrolling windows on them with a sharpie, right?
Speaker 1: He had a place in China like mass manufacturing discs and he went through great effort to make them look exactly like Official legit windows discs with holograms on them and all that biz which is sort of like.
Speaker 1: why are you doing that now?
Speaker 1: It looks like they were.
Speaker 1: if you're really just trying to help people right, you know?
Speaker 1: get computers working Wouldn't you just take the one good disk you have and just get?
Speaker 1: you know Just make crappy CD ours and scroll windows on him with a sharpie and give them out to everybody Right.
Speaker 1: So that's the reason.
Speaker 1: Microsoft went after him, but he still wasn't copying keys.
Speaker 1: So the end, you know, he wasn't making well he was copying.
Speaker 0: Manufacturers like OEMs restore this right?
Speaker 1: So it's like he wasn't still copying.
Speaker 1: discs are still useless without giving Microsoft money Right, so it's now.
Speaker 1: it's not necessarily this clear-cut thing where Microsoft is bad.
Speaker 1: It's sort of like a half-and-half situation.
Speaker 1: We're like, yeah, he wasn't.
Speaker 1: actually the discs are still useless without giving Microsoft money.
Speaker 1: He wasn't necessarily pirating the software But also he was sort of.
Speaker 1: why was he counterfeiting the discs so heavily and also not charging zero dollars for them?
Speaker 0: Yep, and it looks like I mean, I haven't read too deeply but it looks like there's even more He might have been selling those discs to other PC recyclers.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's what he was doing.
Speaker 0: Yeah, as opposed to just using them to recycle pcs himself.
Speaker 1: No, no, right He was said he was selling them to other people who were in this.
Speaker 0: I don't know if he was also recycling pcs or he was just recycling them, but also selling the.
Speaker 0: yeah I guess the more.
Speaker 1: really each recycling place only needs like one disc per like employee.
Speaker 1: Okay, cuz right you build a computer you install Windows.
Speaker 1: Well, you just don't want to have to share the same.
Speaker 0: you can using the same disc in every computer And in fact if you want to really protect yourself use the disk to restore the computer.
Speaker 0: But you give the person the URL of how to download the manufacturers there.
Speaker 0: So the person can redownload restore media themselves directly from the manufacturer without touching you.
Speaker 1: Microsoft doesn't and other manufacturers don't always provide the downloads of those Discs like ship with the computer and that's the only way you can get the disc separately.
Speaker 0: I think there should be a law.
Speaker 0: there should be a certain amount of time like a decade after any Manufacturers sells a PC where they're obligated to provide restore media.
Speaker 0: Well, I think you know if they bundled the OS they should be responsible For it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean a lot of how can PC hardware manufacturers do a good job of this you go to someone's website.
Speaker 1: They got the drivers for fucking everything there.
Speaker 1: Yeah, he's his website.
Speaker 1: There must be so many drivers available there for every fucking motherboard.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right, you know doesn't do a job about this any scanner in the world.
Speaker 1: like every time Windows updates If you get a cannon or a brother those websites have all the.
Speaker 0: yeah They have drivers for like Windows 7 that don't work in Windows 10.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, they don't update that.
Speaker 1: They're not supporting and providing drivers for newer OS.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's true Yeah, but I guess the real moral here is when you see a story like this making the rounds and There's a very outrage worthy headline.
Speaker 0: Do at least a cursory read of the article because I'm almost everyone I've talked about this issue with.
Speaker 1: well Cuz.
Speaker 1: the thing is a lot of the articles that came out were only telling that first half of the story and it was only After.
Speaker 1: like we told this story way back when it was new and it was only that first half.
Speaker 1: We didn't hear the other side And only now the dude was sentenced.
Speaker 1: and then people told that same first half of the story again.
Speaker 1: and those are first round of articles.
Speaker 1: and then Microsoft made a statement and then we got a second round of articles with that second half of the story only now.
Speaker 1: So it's like you didn't hear the whole story right away.
Speaker 1: So you got to wait for you know, it's like you got to wait till you know everything that was go all those details Cuz you know even people who saw that story didn't bother to go read the court filings and look at the evidence or anything.
Speaker 0: So some other news.
Speaker 0: If you haven't noticed there's been a lot of talk about how Cable TV and just TV services in general are completely tanking.
Speaker 1: Of course because I talked about this That's not new.
Speaker 0: So what's new is that Comcast in particular?
Speaker 0: This is this partly.
Speaker 0: it's not just illustrate what Comcast is doing because Comcast has always been a pretty terrible company.
Speaker 0: the worst one It's the worst one, but it's more to show what the stakes are and like why?
Speaker 0: Why the industry is structured the way it is and why everything that's happening around this question is happening.
Speaker 0: Basically Comcast is increasing the speed of their internet in a bunch of places.
Speaker 0: So anyone who is nice of them So anyone who has 60 megabits down is gonna get up to 150 for free.
Speaker 0: Okay, anyone with 150 is getting 250 and with the 250 is good.
Speaker 1: It's upgrading all their tiers Yeah, everyone to 50s.
Speaker 0: So the 400 people are getting a gig.
Speaker 1: damn son.
Speaker 1: Yeah gig doesn't say if it's symmetric cost a lot of money a month of you already getting 400.
Speaker 1: What are you paying?
Speaker 1: Yeah, right.
Speaker 1: I can get I can get like a ton from spectrum.
Speaker 0: I gotta pay a hundred bucks a month, but They are only giving this free upgrade to people who also pay for TV.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean that's a totally I guess legal business thing.
Speaker 1: But on the other hand they have this regional monopoly and also Comcast is part of NBC, which is a TV company.
Speaker 1: So it's totally shady as fuck and could be antitrust.
Speaker 1: Maybe we should do some antitrust thing in there instead of letting them merge in the first place all those years ago.
Speaker 1: Oops
Speaker 0: Yeah, but yeah the stakes here for these cable companies is basically that They if they don't they need to boost the numbers of humans They can say have TV or else the entire thing breaks
Speaker 1: good Fuck them meaning
Speaker 0: that they will very often Like they will do anything to get you even if you don't pay for it to have the TV service.
Speaker 0: and It'll be real interesting to see this all collapse in the near term.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean, you know advertising has always been this sort of you know fraud Situation where people like lie about numbers or use numbers that are technically true, you know It's like because you're trying to sell ads you're trying to make someone else buy ads, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah ad seller you have inventory.
Speaker 1: You're like buy an ad on my website.
Speaker 1: we have X uniques we have X views you have X impressions.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you're always trying to inflate me.
Speaker 1: Our newsletter has this many subscribers.
Speaker 1: How many of those are fake?
Speaker 1: I'm just saying somebody subscribers are you know, and you're not technically lying.
Speaker 1: So you can't be sued for fraud even though it totally is a fraud because the meanings of those numbers are totally right.
Speaker 1: You're not telling the person here is how much money how much you'll actually get in return for the ad that you are buying.
Speaker 1: No one ever tells you that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you would never buy the ad the price they're selling it for.
Speaker 1: So, you know ratings on TV are simply the same exact thing.
Speaker 1: this many people watch our TV show.
Speaker 1: actually This guy on Twitch has like 7,000 people watching them all day long every day.
Speaker 1: How many people actually watch that baseball game?
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's why eSports is so terrifying to a lot of industries because it's not a million.
Speaker 0: You can see exactly how many people are watching and it turns out it's a lot of people.
Speaker 1: in some cases turns out It's a lot of people.
Speaker 1: but also it turns out that that number nowhere near Approaches the numbers that like Nielsen ratings say they're getting.
Speaker 1: but the Nielsen rating numbers are actually super.
Speaker 1: they're that inflated.
Speaker 1: They're actually like less right?
Speaker 1: It's like we see how many people are watching League of Legends Championship.
Speaker 1: We know that that's bigger than like, you know some baseball playoff game.
Speaker 1: Yet the baseball playoff game is claiming to have these millions and millions of viewers.
Speaker 1: But it's probably just because the way they're counting is fraudulent.
Speaker 1: Yeah and if they accounted the same way the League of Legends people counted you would see that they're smaller and then the whole can of worms collapse.
Speaker 1: There goes we see the man behind the curtain and then show But anyway things of the day what he got.
Speaker 1: Was this all right cells?
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so this is so.
Speaker 1: I didn't think I don't know how the hell they image this Which is really the amazing part of this, right?
Speaker 1: But they took a zebra fish and they went to the zebra fish's inner ear Okay, and they somehow Captured imagery of the cells in the zebra fish's inner ear.
Speaker 1: So we got like super microscope action.
Speaker 1: You're seeing individual cells moving around right and it's also moving.
Speaker 1: it's not like some dead cells on a plate with some electron microscope.
Speaker 1: is this video of Living cells moving the fuck around?
Speaker 1: and they're immune cells.
Speaker 1: So you're seeing immune cells in the inner ear of zebra fish moving around Immunifying.
Speaker 1: I guess I don't know what the hell's going on But holy shit, look at that.
Speaker 1: It's moving cells on a video.
Speaker 1: Have you ever fucking seen that in your life?
Speaker 1: No, and that makes it thing of the day.
Speaker 0: That's pretty cool.
Speaker 0: So this was making the rounds Periodically, and I guess I just never bumped into it until now, but it's a little over sensationalized.
Speaker 0: But the gist of it is it's an accessory for the Gameboy Ostensibly the original Gameboy called pedicidates and Alright like the Gameboy Gameboy Gameboy with Tetris.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: Okay, but integrated with a contraption that will Administer nitrous oxide and knock you out while you're playing a game.
Speaker 1: I Mean I did have an orthodontist who had plenty of Gameboys.
Speaker 1: I played many Metroid twos and links awakenings in that orthodontist office.
Speaker 1: So the argument here was that it was just Gameboy did not have any accessory.
Speaker 0: It's an integration of.
Speaker 0: you take a gaming system like the Gameboy that a kid would be used to and you couple it with What is basically just glorified headphones and a gas mask?
Speaker 1: So why did I don't understand why it needed to be an accessory?
Speaker 1: What did it accomplish by connecting to the Gameboy?
Speaker 1: You could have just given a kid a Gameboy and then also administered the nitrous oxide while they're distracted by the Gameboy.
Speaker 1: Yeah, what do you need to attach the delivery mechanism to the Gameboy for so the kid the kids controlling the release with the game?
Speaker 0: No It does is the only the only point of integration.
Speaker 0: as far as I can tell looking at this thing is it's just headphones with a guest thing.
Speaker 0: It has nothing to do with the Gameboy except it was designed for the Gameboy and I suspect the only reason it was actually designed and pride and socialized this way was to probably get some grant money around using gay like.
Speaker 0: there's probably some reason why They framed this as a Gameboy accessory, but really it's just gas headphones.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 0: So because I bought a new smartphone or just talking about smartphones and we got no other.
Speaker 1: Monday show ideas.
Speaker 1: send your Monday show ideas - yeah nights at front row.
Speaker 1: crew calm and you skip the meta moment.
Speaker 0: Alright the meta moment the booklet book is still Emily Wilson's translation.
Speaker 1: Oh, I said I would read more of it during when I was not working last week and I did not.
Speaker 0: So you're still hanging out with.
Speaker 0: uh, I guess you just got your dishes.
Speaker 1: I read zero more pages.
Speaker 0: So you had just gotten to Odysseus making his raft.
Speaker 1: I think I read yeah, pretty much He didn't get out.
Speaker 0: Did he get off the eye that he meet an Ashka yet?
Speaker 1: No, okay Yeah, yeah, I also did not know.
Speaker 1: before I can I want to tell you this I did not know.
Speaker 1: I knew now she could was Only a Miyazaki character to me.
Speaker 1: Ah Did not know that that name came from anywhere.
Speaker 0: It really seems like most people who started the Odyssey in high school only read Specific excerpts from it because so many people have said to me that they didn't know.
Speaker 0: it started with Telemachus.
Speaker 1: I knew that and because I had to pop.
Speaker 0: they don't know about characters like Nausicaa because I didn't know about.
Speaker 0: now Everyone seems to start with like the Cyclops stuff and like a couple of spits of odds of.
Speaker 1: Actually, you know that taught me the most about the Odyssey when I was young was not any class in school or anything like that.
Speaker 1: It was a multi-part DuckTales episode Yeah in which they dealt with the I don't know if the Cyclops was in it, but there was the the the whirlpool the They.
Speaker 1: they sailed in between You know like a colossus and then they got to Cersei who was just magic at the spell and uh in a place And I think they're also sirens.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I should find that and rewatch it.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, that's good stuff otherwise, so that did obviously did not include Telemachus or a wife or suitors or Nausicaa or hundreds and hundreds of slaves or a hot Calypso keeping Scrooge McDuck hostage on a island.
Speaker 1: Not included in the DuckTales Just the adventuring part.
Speaker 0: So this weekend I without Scott will be live for gig nights at Zenkai Con.
Speaker 0: on Saturday I'm doing my anime openers panel one last time.
Speaker 1: before I retire it forever I'll be biking in beautiful weather.
Speaker 1: the only
Speaker 0: reason I'm retiring it is because it's a pain to Update it and I don't want to can and also most of the videos I want to get for it are Increasingly taken down from YouTube and it's not worth the effort to find like weird openers to anime around the world.
Speaker 0: So I'm retiring this one the last time I'm ever gonna run it and I'm doing a brand new anime panel And I'm also redoing one of our PAX panels.
Speaker 0: but if you're gonna be a Zenkai Con on Saturday or Sunday, you can see me there and Otherwise, I'm just gonna be playing board games Maybe in tabletop at the con or possibly just like in a hotel room.
Speaker 0: and good luck finding me.
Speaker 1: It sounds like a safer idea.
Speaker 0: So yeah smartphone sales independent oh kind of like it's tied to all this stuff we talked about the beginning are dropping pretty Rapidly, it's cuz no new phones come out that are compellingly better than the phones we got.
Speaker 0: Yep So I just pointed out a newer iteration of a phone that I like is actually in almost every material way worse Than the phone it's replacing.
Speaker 0: and simultaneously You notice that smart watches after their big splash.
Speaker 0: Those aren't selling well because it turns out a lot of people didn't really understand why they wanted a smart watch and Smart watches by and large have a pretty bad UX.
Speaker 0: Like nothing's really been better than the pebble.
Speaker 0: You can't buy the pebble anymore.
Speaker 0: So I guess I'm wondering Partly cuz we need to come over the Monday show that wouldn't take too long.
Speaker 0: I would have something to say about what would water real material things That could change that would make like you or me for example, what would make you excited to buy a phone?
Speaker 0: I mean they're like what would make you be willing to.
Speaker 1: the problem is is that back in the day phones are so shitty that You could easily imagine ways to improve them right.
Speaker 1: the cameras are so bad The data was so slow the battery ran out.
Speaker 0: So let them plug into my computer with USB and not a proprietary cable screen was so shitty.
Speaker 1: The there were.
Speaker 1: you know, there's so many things that were just obviously bad about the phone that could easily be improved.
Speaker 0: Let me access the internet.
Speaker 1: Yeah, let me have apps.
Speaker 1: iPhone one.
Speaker 1: They added the absolute later iOS update when the iPhone 3G came out which is when I bought it like a smart person.
Speaker 1: Anyway, you know, so there's so many obvious problems.
Speaker 1: But now it's like what can you really offer me in the next phone?
Speaker 1: We already talked about the OLED screen, but that alone is not Super.
Speaker 1: it's nice, you know, but it's not super compelling like oh man.
Speaker 1: I gotta had that phone right away, right?
Speaker 1: You can make the camera better.
Speaker 1: You can make the CPU faster.
Speaker 1: You make the battery last longer.
Speaker 1: You can even make the data faster.
Speaker 1: That's one thing that you sort of almost forces you to upgrade.
Speaker 1: if they come out with like 5g 6g New radios you sort of had to buy a new phone.
Speaker 0: Oh, but even then unless the until the infrastructure upgrades like yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but I'm saying then I'm saying at that point You're gonna have to do something.
Speaker 0: Yeah Well like the difference between 3g and 4g is night and day.
Speaker 1: the difference in 4g and 5g though is supposedly not much because we're Not even using all the bandwidth possible on 4g.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah I thought I stopped holding on to my unlimited grandfathered Plan because I'd never use more than a few gigs a month ever.
Speaker 1: And the other problem is that not only are the new phones coming out these days only marginally better than the previous phones But the previous phones are still working just fine.
Speaker 1: It's not like they died.
Speaker 0: Yeah, look I just bought a new phone But I still have my old phone for the first time also the new ones.
Speaker 1: the price has gotten exorbitant.
Speaker 1: There's been sort of this decreasing returns where to make the phone a little bit better costs a fortune more money.
Speaker 1: That's not worth it.
Speaker 1: if it was like yeah for that nicer screen I'd give you 50 more bucks or a hundred more bucks or something like that, but not for a $1,000 iPhone X. but no, it's not worth for just that for a little screen and also this feature I don't care about where it looks at my face.
Speaker 1: I don't even want that.
Speaker 1: I'd probably disable it.
Speaker 1: Yeah No, I don't want that.
Speaker 0: So what could?
Speaker 0: what could phones materially do?
Speaker 0: because it seems like they're mostly focused on more pixels.
Speaker 0: Higher quality pixels are good pixel density.
Speaker 1: Those are good things.
Speaker 1: But yeah, but they don't not making that big a difference.
Speaker 0: But they also considering that people want these giant phones the ultra high res does not buy much for the average phone user.
Speaker 1: No, I mean the things that I want, you know, for example are you know?
Speaker 1: If that iPhone the one thing you can always complain about the iPhone is that there's no SD card slot.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I have it an SD card slot in a phone.
Speaker 1: Now that I've been used to have an SD card lightning reader which works but actually is kind of way slow If you have a ton of photos on there.
Speaker 1: I usually use it for putting photos from my camera into the iPad or iPhone.
Speaker 1: It works like you.
Speaker 1: plug the thing in the lightning hole and you put the SD card in it and then Importer shows up and it works nicely.
Speaker 1: But it's kind of slow you to wait for all the photos to appear.
Speaker 1: if it took a ton of raw photos It's you gotta wait.
Speaker 1: So, I think the first material thing I can think of It would be nice if it was just like put an SD card right in the in the iPad or the iPhone and boop Like.
Speaker 0: I think the next real phone revolution like something that would actually change the market would be if there were a battery that lasted More than a day or two.
Speaker 0: Mmm, like that would be the killer app for most people.
Speaker 1: There are a lot of people who want that but I mean that's personally never been a problem for me.
Speaker 1: It's only been like a minor inconvenience because the only times my battery comes close to even going down are Days where I'm out and about the whole day which yep, which is for me rare.
Speaker 1: Usually I'm at a desk all day and my phone is plugged in whenever I'm near a thing to plug it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and usually when I when I wear my phone out or when I need battery when I'm using it all day It's cuz I'm doing an activity like hiking all day like if I biking all day with Strava.
Speaker 1: if I bike all day I have a little cylinder right of battery.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I fully charge it.
Speaker 1: the night before I leave my phone plugged into it I have that same cylinder and when I get home My phone is still at a hundred percent and the cylinder is not a hundred percent empty.
Speaker 1: that cylinder holds so much energy And it's still that cylinder is a minor Inconvenience, right?
Speaker 1: So being able to get rid of it because the battery and the phone was just so fucking awesome would be nice.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but it's not worth paying more than you know, 50 to 100 dollars.
Speaker 0: Well, I guess it would be material different.
Speaker 0: I'm talking like the difference between the pebble smartwatch and any other smartwatch.
Speaker 0: It's not the difference of oh it lasts 50% longer.
Speaker 0: I'm talking like what if it lasted more than a week?
Speaker 1: Yeah, but I mean like.
Speaker 1: I can still like plug my any week.
Speaker 1: I can plug my phone and what benefit do I actually get from the battery lasting a week?
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I noticed once I switched from my pebble to this it's it's such a minor and trivial Inconvenience.
Speaker 0: just to make sure I'm charging my like every night put my watch on the charger before I go to bed.
Speaker 1: But I had.
Speaker 1: the thing is that's not like an inconvenience for me.
Speaker 1: It's a habit.
Speaker 1: It's not even like a problem true, but I had carrying the cylinder is a minor problem.
Speaker 0: But I had lived for a while in a world where I would travel without even bringing a charger for my smartwatch Mm-hmm, and because the pebble just lasted a week plus Mm-hmm, uh, I don't feel like screens will really get better in a material way.
Speaker 0: that would matter and if you make them bigger They're just laptops or tablets again That's not.
Speaker 1: I mean you could.
Speaker 1: you know people have always tried to make that thing where you put the phone in something, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah So if you made a phone that was truly somehow so powerful like it's got a 1080 and an i7 in it That powerful that it could be your computer Then yes That would be compelling because then I could throw away all my computers and when I'm home I could just plug the phone in and then he would have monitors and keyboards on my desk.
Speaker 1: But actually I'll just have this phone and I wouldn't have to have any desktops or HDP C's or any other computers.
Speaker 1: I could just have this one tiny thing that has this Incredible horsepower of a 1080 and I do literally everything on it and that would be terrific.
Speaker 1: and I would only need one computer instead of one two Five or six computers that I have You know, so that would be compelling.
Speaker 1: but that ain't coming till I'm an old man, yeah when I'm old man That's how strong a phone will be.
Speaker 0: I still really want and I feel like this will happen at some maybe
Speaker 1: not even then
Speaker 0: the like periphery cloud of Interface devices and the phone and I'm making quote fingers here It's basically just everything that my phone does except the screen and it's literally just the batteries and communications And horsepower to connect to all my cloud shit and to do local processing.
Speaker 0: but then I carry around like I have a bunch of screens and I use whichever one I want or I have a smartwatch and Some glasses.
Speaker 1: that's way better than the same things people always imagined, right?
Speaker 1: But I mean really what we got to do is get to the point where you know You don't have to carry around a CPU in a video card or anything.
Speaker 1: You just have literally just glasses that are non dorky or not.
Speaker 0: Even any glasses like it's like dorky Dorky is fine.
Speaker 0: No, why?
Speaker 0: why do you care about aesthetics?
Speaker 1: Because it gets in the way.
Speaker 1: Oh, how do you like unlike you my eyes work?
Speaker 1: So I don't need to put any garbage on my face except to block the horrible rays of the Sun.
Speaker 0: I already wore glasses.
Speaker 0: So glasses that do something is just great.
Speaker 1: Yeah for me, it's I don't want to hang and I don't want to have to put anything on.
Speaker 1: I want to get to the point where it's like a sticker.
Speaker 1: I just put a sticker on the side of my head like One right.
Speaker 1: I get a little tiny sparkly spec and actually it projects everything in front of my face like it's cyberpunk land I am curious about.
Speaker 0: I think another a big No one else will be the because the the second screen peripherals tended to not go that well.
Speaker 0: I feel like these screen peripherals that are some sort of contact lens that can give an AR overlay like that sort of Technology, I don't have to poke my eyeball but the caveat to that is that again?
Speaker 0: That's the kind of technology that I want But I don't know what a consumer like kids might be into it.
Speaker 1: But I don't know what.
Speaker 1: the only reason I want that sort of thing is to carry around less shit.
Speaker 1: It's the same as me.
Speaker 1: It's really just making the phone smaller and it's just another way to make the phone even more ridiculously small To make it invisible.
Speaker 0: But I guess I do want heads-up display like I want to be able to see information from my phone without having to get my Phone out.
Speaker 1: Yeah smartwatch Same thing is.
Speaker 1: making the phone smaller.
Speaker 1: Yeah, make it so small that you can wear it next to your eye or in your eye.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah It is your eye or it's in your ears in your brain and someone like it goes to the shell style is gonna be.
Speaker 1: It's the same thing as making it smaller, right?
Speaker 1: It accomplishes the same goal.
Speaker 1: It's just when you reach a ridiculous level of smallness suddenly new things become possible like Having it in front of your eyeball.
Speaker 0: So what about people who aren't super techie or don't care that much about this stuff?
Speaker 0: Is there anything we could do to make smartphones better for them?
Speaker 0: like anything that would compel them to upgrade?
Speaker 1: I Mean you make marketing compel them to buy them.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah marketing problem not a technology problem because technology doesn't convince those people that you know.
Speaker 1: If you're not a person who cares about technology, then you're not gonna care about technology.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right.
Speaker 1: You did.
Speaker 1: you just buy what you know marketing would makes you buy.
Speaker 1: you're convinced to buy something?
Speaker 0: Yeah because nerds always seem to go that like I see every now and then I see that perennial story of some nerd is like.
Speaker 0: The real answer is we need modular smartphone so I can build my own.
Speaker 0: It's like son.
Speaker 0: You can't even build your own laptop There.
Speaker 0: no one's gonna let you build a phone.
Speaker 0: There's a reason why they're manufactured the way they are.
Speaker 0: No one wants a modular phone where you could like swap out the processor except you.
Speaker 0: I don't even want that.
Speaker 1: I Mean, I guess you could have a magical phone that like, you know is small and then can get big and then get small again.
Speaker 0: Oh someone in the chat actually points out a phone that could actually play real games.
Speaker 1: I mean iPhone.
Speaker 1: iPad can play real games to a degree.
Speaker 1: I mean the pie phone can't play.
Speaker 0: what's it about battle tech?
Speaker 1: Why couldn't it?
Speaker 0: Well, it can't right now because it won't run on iOS I assume.
Speaker 1: well, I mean it hasn't been written for it, but you can get the same exact xcom that is on.
Speaker 1: You can get for iPad.
Speaker 1: I had I got said iPhone.
Speaker 1: I got sib6 on my iPad.
Speaker 0: I pad not iPhone.
Speaker 1: You can get it for iPhone.
Speaker 1: I'm sure are you sure?
Speaker 1: reason you couldn't?
Speaker 1: Yeah, but actually you just the graphics be cut down.
Speaker 1: But there's no there's no technological reason you could not make such a game for the iPhone.
Speaker 1: You know other than you just have to cut the graphics down because the GPU is not as powerful.
Speaker 0: But you see you keep saying could could.
Speaker 0: is it actually a game that is playable today on an iPhone?
Speaker 1: No one has made the software doesn't mean that has nothing to do with the hardware.
Speaker 1: Right?
Speaker 1: It's like.
Speaker 1: what if by that logic?
Speaker 1: That's like if I got it if I got a logic.
Speaker 0: Apple computers are fine for gaming because you could run any of these games On them.
Speaker 1: I'm just saying but there's nothing that Apple can.
Speaker 1: what if I have a PC with a 1080 and he's just like oh Well, nobody they release a game from Mac.
Speaker 1: That's ridiculous.
Speaker 0: It's no one makes a good game for Mac Also on PC saying it's like oh it's not out on that platform.
Speaker 1: Therefore that you know, it's like well, there's nothing the platform can do to make someone who writes software write it for that platform.
Speaker 1: That's stupid.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, but if the put but if it doesn't exist It's already the plat.
Speaker 1: the hardware is already capable of running the software right and Making that software for it is not the job of the person who makes the phones.
Speaker 1: It's not a part of this conversation.
Speaker 1: You can have real games on a smartphone these days.
Speaker 0: Well that to a degree the only mean what about your you keep?
Speaker 0: seems like real game.
Speaker 0: What do you mean by real game?
Speaker 0: Because Fortnight is the only game that like normal people care.
Speaker 1: It's on phones.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I know it's on iPhone, right?
Speaker 0: That's on phone and that's.
Speaker 0: that's a real game to most of G's on phones, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, so those are the top games.
Speaker 0: there are phones the end and that doesn't seem to be driving smartphone sales.
Speaker 1: No, it's just driving.
Speaker 1: people have phones to give more money to Fortnight and pub G.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I Just I don't know if there's any Material advancement to a smartphone that would change the situation for the average PCs had the same thing.
Speaker 1: they got better and better and better and better.
Speaker 1: and now what if what is change?
Speaker 1: what has made a PC better in the past X years Besides just being faster and better for normal people?
Speaker 0: nothing They don't use only real just use phones and tablets.
Speaker 1: only real thing that has come to PCs and that as Recently, that is not just faster and better is high DPI screens.
Speaker 1: Yeah, other than that.
Speaker 1: It's like, okay They're just faster and stronger with more memories and more chippies.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but PCs are already coming.
Speaker 1: phones have reached the same thing.
Speaker 1: It's like well, we've made him as good as we can.
Speaker 1: What else can we do?
Speaker 1: I guess what I find interesting is that last time someone made cars better It's like the engines got way way better.
Speaker 0: And now oh the edges actually have continued to get much more efficient.
Speaker 1: Yeah, just like CPUs.
Speaker 1: They keep getting slightly better, but cars, you know four wheels and they go.
Speaker 0: No, but there have been a lot of material changes that made like make a new car today Objectively superior to a car you could have bought a few years ago.
Speaker 1: with our crazy rate of improvement You know tapers off at a certain point.
Speaker 1: the dramatic change of the say between a 50s car and an 80s car versus the difference between a 2000s car and a 2010s car.
Speaker 0: a lot of people say wireless charging.
Speaker 0: wireless charging has come and gone a million times in phones.
Speaker 0: It's never more convenient than just plugging it in.
Speaker 1: why?
Speaker 1: right wireless charging is cool.
Speaker 0: We have it in certain phones Starbucks is used to have like pads Phone on if it was to.
Speaker 1: the two problems is why and it works.
Speaker 1: the problems of the wireless charging is one It's not really more convenient because you still have to put your phone in a certain like spot.
Speaker 1: It's what's the difference between putting it on a pad and putting it in a neck in a near a wire?
Speaker 1: The wire is actually more convenient because you can pick up the phone and move it around.
Speaker 1: you're gonna leave it on this spot.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right Wireless charging would be great if like it was just wireless charging being beamed everywhere.
Speaker 1: So as you walk down the street, you're this thing's shooting at your phone charging it up.
Speaker 1: That's wireless charging.
Speaker 0: something like that might exist someday But for right now pretty sure most get rid of.
Speaker 1: you know, we've made everything made all the all these technologies We've been able to remove the wires, right?
Speaker 1: It's like.
Speaker 1: well if you want to remove wires for power You need to remove the power grid like.
Speaker 1: you don't have to plug in your TV.
Speaker 1: There's just power in the air.
Speaker 1: I don't have to plug in your microwave.
Speaker 1: There's just power in the air, right?
Speaker 1: You don't have to plug in your phone to charge everywhere.
Speaker 1: Electronic devices that are in this area are just all being powered with electricity shooting through the sky if that's even physically possible.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right, but yeah, no more outlets in your walls in your house.
Speaker 1: No more power lines outside Right just power everywhere.
Speaker 0: I guess what's interesting though is that and your guts getting fried?
Speaker 0: I guess he sees partly like that market got gutted by the Introduction of smartphones and tablets that were good enough for the things that an average person They did all the things that a person does with the computer only smaller and more convenient and easier.
Speaker 0: but smartphones There isn't anything that really is teed up to replace them.
Speaker 0: So they replaced PCs for a lot of people But they're already good enough to do everything that most people would have done with a PC and now do with their phone.
Speaker 1: Actually, you know if you if you could imagine, you know, here's a real material Imagine the thing that would replace smartphones and be the next thing that ramps up and then tapers off.
Speaker 1: You would be yeah not have to work.
Speaker 0: I think a material change would be a phone that was actually pretty invincible.
Speaker 1: I Mean, that's a help because it makes me want to buy.
Speaker 0: I think a full third of all the phones I see in the wild have cracked screens.
Speaker 1: They have invincible phones Relatively, but they're sort of a you know, are more or they're boutique like so full Elegant.
Speaker 0: I am NOT going to test my new contacts, but the previous one the one that I replaced.
Speaker 0: I Have beaten the ever-living shit out of this phone.
Speaker 0: I dropped it at work.
Speaker 1: I haven't put an iPhone in a case since the iPhone 3g.
Speaker 0: I've never put a phone in a case.
Speaker 1: the only time one broke was the iPhone 5.
Speaker 1: I was riding my bike and it was in my bag and I fell over and I guess just the whatever hit the ground just Happened to spike into the phone.
Speaker 0: So despite having gone swimming with this phone Used it in the shower.
Speaker 1: I think my iPhone 6 I had in my pocket and I was waiting into some water and then I think it got half in the water.
Speaker 1: I went oops and I put it.
Speaker 1: I went back out and Then it was totally fine.
Speaker 0: But I dropped this in a stairwell and it bounced down two full stories on concrete and There was a couple of tiny dents in the case The screen was uncracked and the phone was undamaged in any material way.
Speaker 0: This phone is actually invincible.
Speaker 0: And but again because it still works I'm not going to push that or test it and I'm definitely not gonna test it with the new phone.
Speaker 0: But arguably the new phone with its metal case or as miss metal top bits is actually probably more resilient.
Speaker 0: I Feel like if you if you made a phone and you marketed it as not needing a case it is that strong.
Speaker 0: I feel like that iPhone doesn't need a case.
Speaker 1: It is that strong.
Speaker 1: Don't just don't be.
Speaker 0: why do I see so many cracked iPhone?
Speaker 1: because people are fucking clumsy.
Speaker 1: Well, how come?
Speaker 0: mine isn't except for the one time I fell yeah, but I'm saying make a phone where even if you're clumsy It doesn't break.
Speaker 1: Don't be a clumsy oaf.
Speaker 0: But like dynamite I Mean I'm not.
Speaker 0: I don't break phones.
Speaker 1: I mean take care of your shit.
Speaker 1: be careful Don't like grease up your hands and use your phone with one hand while you're biking and not even looking at the road and you know doing stupid shit.
Speaker 1: Just Hold on to it tight.
Speaker 0: My Nexus 4 broke.
Speaker 0: I remember literally I was.
Speaker 0: it was in my pocket and I was just sitting at a desk and I hung my jacket on the Door and it was in my pocket of a jacket.
Speaker 0: I was typing on the computer doing something and I just heard this sound like glass shattering like what.
Speaker 0: what was that?
Speaker 0: Whatever?
Speaker 0: and I ignored it and then I went to go to bed.
Speaker 0: I went to get my phone to charge it and the screen had just shattered on its own.
Speaker 0: Uh-huh Well, the ray I I'm pretty sure there's just a defect and it had been.
Speaker 1: it had to knock back the rim breaking things on purpose.
Speaker 0: Why would I that Nexus 4?
Speaker 0: I loved I didn't.
Speaker 0: in fact when that phone broke was a terrible time to upgrade I ended up buying a really suboptimal Nexus 5 in London because I was really in a hurry to have a working phone again Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: I think I gave that Nexus 5 away though.
Speaker 0: That one still kind of works.
Speaker 0: Yeah, smartphones are an interesting space and I'm hungry.
Speaker 0: It's coming shopping.
Speaker 0: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott.
Speaker 0: special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening.
Speaker 0: music can't leave for web design and brand.
Speaker 1: Ok for the logos be sure to visit our website at front row.
Speaker 1: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 0: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 1: But unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night.
Speaker 0: I'm watching some Bruins Tampa Bay hockey while I record this.
Speaker 0: but anyway the patreon patrons for this observe.
Speaker 0: geek nights are Craig Oliver Alan Joyce Rebecca done.
Speaker 0: Hi, give me nickel.
Speaker 0: Shimmering group yobble is hanging in this time.
Speaker 0: my stated calm Jeremy minor link Iji Kelly Snyder cold guy Amanda Duchette Shawn Yeager Matthew Smith Nicholas Brandau, mr.
Speaker 0: Strong Strachan for two in creations.
Speaker 0: No, I never ever wonder why we're here.
Speaker 0: Semper Fi bitch Shervin von Horrell rare.
Speaker 0: James Rory.
Speaker 0: Sorry James David White Rochelle, Montanona Superboy capybara pickle come quat Sailor Vista Don's like chartovish and Joe Joe.
Speaker 0: Joe starts Clinton Walton Renford, New Zealand Ryan parent drove and later Finn Chris mink.
Speaker 0: if Chris Knox Daniel Redmond Sean Klein Chris Reimer and Thomas Han You know, this is the first time in my entire life That I do not have a an NHL team that I care about in the Stanley Cup playoffs.
Speaker 0: It's just.
Speaker 0: it's never happened to me before Always had the Red Wings and as the Red Wings are in their decline at the Rangers So, I don't know.
Speaker 0: I just want to see the world burn.
Speaker 0: So I'm rooting for the Bruins only because they're against Tampa right now and one of our friends who's newly into hockey is really into Them.
Speaker 0: and I'm rooting for Vegas because I just want to see the world burn.
Speaker 0: So yeah, Vegas Golden Knights, they're winning the Stanley Cup.
Speaker 0: you heard it here first and now I leave you with Hello out there.
Speaker 2: We're on the air.
Speaker 2: It's hockey night tonight.
Speaker 2: Tension goes the whistle blows and the puck goes down the ice.
Speaker 2: The goalie jumps and the players bump on.
Speaker 2: the fans all go insane.
Speaker 2: Someone roars Bobby scores and the good old hockey game.
Speaker 2: The best game you can name is the good old hockey game.
Speaker 2: Second period Where players - with skates of flash the home team trails behind But they grab the puck and go bursting up and they're down across the line.
Speaker 2: They storm the crease like bumblebees.
Speaker 2: They travel like a burning flame.
Speaker 2: We see them slide the puck inside.
Speaker 2: It's a 1-1 hockey game You can name and the best game you can name is the good old hockey game.
Speaker 2: Third period.
Speaker 2: last game in the playoffs - oh take me where the hockey players face off down the ring.