Speaker 0: It's Tuesday, June 5th, 2018.
Speaker 0: I'm rim.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott and this is geek nights tonight.
Speaker 0: We just got shapes and beats.
Speaker 0: It's just shapes and beats.
Speaker 0: Let's do this Just that time of year.
Speaker 0: I'm biking to work again.
Speaker 1: I'm biking everywhere.
Speaker 0: Yep, but uh, so cuz I change jobs.
Speaker 0: I bike to midtown like I have a really sure.
Speaker 0: it's like a 12 to 14 minute bike ride to work.
Speaker 0: It's not that far.
Speaker 0: I think I spend equal amounts of time on the Queensborough Bridge and not on the Queensborough Bridge But I'd never really biked around in midtown like during the day before.
Speaker 0: like it's like Midtown only existed for me to get across to Central Park or across the way would you exactly?
Speaker 0: so I have to bike through like into the heart of midtown to get to my office and I encountered something that I've never really encountered before biking.
Speaker 0: I encountered old people Yelling at me to slow down.
Speaker 0: All right, I have encountered in the like four times I've ridden my bike to work in midtown Four different old people who yelled at me to slow down.
Speaker 0: I was biking in the bike lane and today there were two of them.
Speaker 0: two of them were today.
Speaker 0: So in the second one when this old man yells at me to slow down.
Speaker 0: I actually stopped turn.
Speaker 0: why would you do that?
Speaker 0: Cuz I was curious and I was like, what do you mean slow down?
Speaker 0: and I had a Conversation with this person now, I decided would you do this?
Speaker 0: I was really curious, but if he's a crazy old man He was a crazy old man.
Speaker 0: I know but specifically he said he seems to be Terrified of the idea that a bike will hit him.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: So don't go in the bike lane.
Speaker 0: yet simultaneously, he thinks the bike lanes are Sidewalks that are for slow biking only and that if a bike is going fast It should be in the street with the cars instead of in the dedicated fast bike lane.
Speaker 0: And he was really fucking mad that I was on a bike and that I was talking to him and I could have I could Have killed his wife and then I left.
Speaker 0: cuz he was obviously crazy.
Speaker 1: And why did you just make him go crazy?
Speaker 1: if I keep talking to him till he just dies I think he would have hit me.
Speaker 1: Oh, well, then you can call the police and crazy old man go where he belongs.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but I see while you there was a time you called the police on the crazy hobo and you felt bad like well Cuz that crazy hobo was crazy in a way where he just needed help.
Speaker 1: exactly if the police came and bludgeon this old man Over the head.
Speaker 1: I wouldn't feel bad at all.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I really have no sympathy for old.
Speaker 0: I have no sympathy for the specific class of old people who are anti bike lane Or anyone is pretty much well, you know really knitted and uppity.
Speaker 0: really anyone who's anti bike lane.
Speaker 0: I got no tolerance for anyone who's anti anything.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I'm anti a lot of things.
Speaker 0: Yeah about bike lanes only because there's no good reason to be against bike lanes.
Speaker 0: There's only bad reasons to be against bike lane.
Speaker 1: There shouldn't be a bike lane.
Speaker 1: There should be a car lane and that would be none of them in Manhattan.
Speaker 0: Well, there shouldn't be cars in Manhattan.
Speaker 0: The only there should be.
Speaker 0: there should only be Professionally driven cars and eventually robot cars to drive around people who have disabilities there and for deliveries.
Speaker 0: There should be no other vehicles that are powered anywhere in Manhattan.
Speaker 1: Deliveries only at night.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: Also emergency vehicles.
Speaker 0: The end.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: That's it.
Speaker 1: And then it should spread slowly to the entire rest of the earth.
Speaker 0: Yep, and we just shut down every town.
Speaker 0: That's too far away from things and if you live too far away from a place Well government's gonna buy your house and you get to move into an apartment or just you know.
Speaker 0: Yeah So yeah that aside there we got some news today.
Speaker 1: Yeah, okay.
Speaker 1: So e3 is coming soon, which means, you know, first of all e3 is still bad.
Speaker 1: I'm surprised because years ago I remember talking about e3 was gonna die But somehow it avoided death.
Speaker 0: Okay, it's interesting cuz e3 was like for nerds who didn't know better because the Internet didn't really tell us what things were like.
Speaker 0: back Then people thought that e3 was like this mecca of gaming.
Speaker 1: e3 is like just the bad parts of packs without without any other parts Yep.
Speaker 0: But it took the modern internet and them letting non Developers in for everyone to realize this and I'm shocked that there's anyone who still cares about e3.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean basically e3 is all the video game companies still I don't know why go and have their major yearly press conferences there to show off their new shit.
Speaker 1: I don't know why they don't do it somewhere else.
Speaker 1: or just one year Nintendo just did it on their own and was like fuck E3 and I know why they didn't stick with it.
Speaker 1: They're they're going back to e3 again.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so What's the thing?
Speaker 1: that's happening soon which means gonna produce a lot of good Tuesday news for us.
Speaker 1: It's not happening now but luckily Some companies have got a little preemptive action a little teaser a little this and that to give us something to talk about.
Speaker 1: So the most notable one is the trailer for fallout 76. now is tough for me already because a to fall out of one I didn't.
Speaker 1: I never actually beat fallout one.
Speaker 1: I never beat any fallout fallout - I booted up and I went for like a few screens in and that was it.
Speaker 1: Yeah Fallout 3 I beat.
Speaker 1: I beat fallout 3.
Speaker 1: Ooh, I didn't.
Speaker 1: The thing is that was a $50 fallout 3 year edition with DLC fallout 3 new vegas.
Speaker 1: I played I got Oh Middling bit in.
Speaker 1: I didn't even make it to Vegas.
Speaker 1: I think I was like about to get to actual Vegas.
Speaker 0: I just didn't care about.
Speaker 1: him starts like in the desert.
Speaker 0: I just didn't care.
Speaker 0: and really what happened to me was that the you are outside.
Speaker 0: Fallouts were completely ruined by the mean every fallout.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Well you are outside and it's an FPS or at least a first-person game.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so then I didn't play fallout 4 cuz I'm waiting for to be el cheapo and it's not el cheapo yet.
Speaker 1: Yeah But the thing is you got this fault 76 and this trailer for fallout 76 Right.
Speaker 1: really appeals to me because the thing I like is it reveals no gameplay.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: The thing I like about fallout is the inside the vault aesthetic.
Speaker 1: it reminds me of paranoia and wool and Logan's run and all of those.
Speaker 1: it's the Apocalypses outside and you're safe inside.
Speaker 1: things of yes fallout is one of.
Speaker 0: well, there's two.
Speaker 0: there's two genres there There's your safe inside and your safe inside.
Speaker 1: Yeah, anyway, and that's the thing that I like about fallout.
Speaker 1: Is that you know, the vault boy cartoon?
Speaker 1: Yeah, a little society having a birthday party inside, you know, right?
Speaker 1: I love that action and Once you're outside, it's like this lame, you know post apocalypse mad mag situation.
Speaker 1: But it doesn't have any of the fists of the North Star parts to make it any guy.
Speaker 0: but even worse the more recent Fallouts the open-world like when I got outside in the modern fallouts, it felt really great and looked like this massive world.
Speaker 0: But as soon as it started poking around there wasn't really anything anywhere except the plot flags, right?
Speaker 1: Well, if you had the DLCs, it fills in a lot of this stuff.
Speaker 1: so for example, I played oblivion, which is the one that came which is the Yeah, I got time for that's the old scroll one, which is basically all these Bethesda games of the same game, right?
Speaker 1: but yeah oblivion was the old scroll and it came before fallout 3 and That one when I got it was super cheap like $5 or something and was full of DLCs.
Speaker 1: I didn't even realize DLCs when I encountered them because the way the DLCs are made is they basically what used to be empty land now has a thing In it, right?
Speaker 1: So for example when I played oblivion there was a DLC that was like this quest to get the holy armor and I was like That's my alley.
Speaker 1: That's that's that's Scott right there.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the holy armor be the great Crusader or whatever, right?
Speaker 1: So I discovered this like I didn't even realize it was a DLC.
Speaker 1: I found this holy temple In the middle of nowhere and I went on these quests and I got the holy armor and basically that became my home base.
Speaker 1: I'd always teleport there leave my shit in the treasure chest there right always hang out there always use the holy armor Always be the holy warrior, right?
Speaker 1: And I didn't realize there's a DLC until later and it really, you know fills in the empty spaces in that big map Which is why you got to wait for those game of the year editions.
Speaker 1: But anyway The thing about fall 76 that makes me slightly Excited whereas otherwise I'd be meh.
Speaker 1: is that a?
Speaker 1: the aesthetic of this trailer is the part that I like.
Speaker 0: It's just got aesthetic and B.
Speaker 1: Supposedly, this is not going to be a Bethesda RPG game.
Speaker 1: quote.
Speaker 1: the word on the street is that it's going to be some sort of multiplayer survival game something kind of like a daisy or rust something like that and I'm down.
Speaker 1: I haven't you know, I'll go.
Speaker 1: I can go for one of those in the Fallout L world multiplayer fallout for real, okay, I am cautiously intrigued and that's all you're gonna get out of me for the time being.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but it's like can't write that off You know, yeah There you go.
Speaker 0: Cautiously intrigued is the best anyone.
Speaker 1: I was just hoping for another Bethesda RPG.
Speaker 1: Oh, well, yeah You got enough of them.
Speaker 1: I mean, I actually played Skyrim a whole bunch but eventually I got to this quest where I had to go up a mountain and there was like a Abominable snowman and I couldn't beat the abominable snowman.
Speaker 1: so I quit.
Speaker 1: I might try.
Speaker 1: I actually had the slight urge to try again.
Speaker 1: So I might.
Speaker 1: I might do that someday.
Speaker 0: So in some other news Mario tennis.
Speaker 0: Mario Danny is coming back.
Speaker 1: we've been waiting for this but I was worried because the Mario tennis that was for the the Wii U was just a redo of Previous Mario tennis and the Mario tennis on the DS or the 3ds was el pupa was garbage.
Speaker 0: It was basically just a glorified Simon game in 64 and GameCube a Mario tennis.
Speaker 0: All the GameCube one is still so good.
Speaker 1: Those are the real Mario 10.
Speaker 0: I love that Mario tennis.
Speaker 1: So now there's Mario tennis aces for the switch which is an all-new Mario tennis and they had a demo over the weekend Friday Saturday and Sunday and The demo.
Speaker 1: the way it worked is you could play solo against the PC to train PC Switch to train your friend calm your friend calm Or you could play online and the way the online play worked is very clever.
Speaker 1: I want to know why games like Hearthstone don't do.
Speaker 1: this is a bracketed tournament and you get You play and you don't see the whole bracket.
Speaker 1: all you see is it just matches you up with someone who also has zero wins in a row and Then if you win it matches you up with someone who has one win.
Speaker 1: and if you win it matches you up against someone who?
Speaker 1: Has two wins and it creates the bracket post-hoc.
Speaker 1: and then you.
Speaker 1: I made it to the finals once and then I got I lost And I made it to the semi-finals.
Speaker 1: every other time the semi-finals are tough.
Speaker 1: I got lucky.
Speaker 1: what that time I made to the finals.
Speaker 1: I was lucky.
Speaker 1: My semi-final opponent was Algarve.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, I was only able to get two or three games in with humans because everyone had such terrible pain.
Speaker 1: I basically played for a whole bunch of hours Like on Friday and I didn't play it all Saturday or Sunday.
Speaker 1: cuz I'm not.
Speaker 0: The people playing this game had such horrible latency that it was an unplayable like Pointless game.
Speaker 1: Yeah at first I was streaming and I thought oh my streaming is causing the connection to be bad.
Speaker 1: Then I stopped streaming.
Speaker 0: No, my connection was fine.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I stopped streaming and I got a little bit better connection But not much.
Speaker 1: luckily it let you deny a match.
Speaker 1: like you see your opponent has one bar.
Speaker 1: Well, I'm not playing them.
Speaker 1: Okay, we'll find you another opponent with the same number of wins.
Speaker 1: Okay, and if you keep trying long enough, sometimes you get a good player right away.
Speaker 1: Sometimes not.
Speaker 1: I didn't even mind losing.
Speaker 1: I just minded playing in some with horrendous lag.
Speaker 0: the few times I found someone I could play with who didn't have terrible lag They were terrible at Mario Tennis.
Speaker 1: Yeah, luckily When this game comes out it's gonna have everything that the other Mario Tennis has had.
Speaker 1: Yep, and then we can ignore the online part.
Speaker 1: It's like I paid 50 bucks for GameCube Mario Tennis.
Speaker 1: Why wouldn't I pay 50 bucks?
Speaker 1: and that had no online?
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: So why wouldn't I pay 50 bucks for this even if the online didn't exist?
Speaker 1: Well, the trouble is Nintendo and they could fix it too.
Speaker 0: Nintendo's charging money for their online play for all their games.
Speaker 0: Yeah
Speaker 1: I'm not paying any amount of money to play online and
Speaker 0: based on the experience with this demo because the whole point of this was that it was an online event
Speaker 1: the
Speaker 0: fact that 90 plus percent of all the people I played with we're talking like Multiple second delays between me hitting a button.
Speaker 1: It could have been the netcode too, right?
Speaker 0: You know, I do not trust Nintendo to get it right though.
Speaker 1: No, I'm not paying any extra money for the online play.
Speaker 1: But I probably am gonna pay money for Mario Tennis.
Speaker 0: I'll play this in part.
Speaker 0: The problem is what I worry is that based on my experiences with other games like on the 3ds that the local multiplayer won't work either Because the pac-man verse local multiplayer works for shit Like it breaks all the time at home.
Speaker 0: So my worry is we won't ever actually be able to play this game with other people ever Unless we put it on a TV and plug two pro controllers in.
Speaker 1: that seems fine.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I can live with that but It's I'm getting really worried about the ability to play multiplayer games on the switch because so far it doesn't seem to actually work.
Speaker 0: But in terms of the Mario Tennis game, at least it's not quite as full-on as GameCube and At the end 64 version in that it still has largely removed timing from the game.
Speaker 0: You can't hit the ball sooner.
Speaker 0: It does matter because the one way well timing matters in terms of how hard and how well you hit it.
Speaker 1: Well, also if your timing is bad is see people didn't realize like there's a lot of subtleties that they didn't teach you in the tutorial.
Speaker 1: Yeah basically in the new in this Mario Tennis if your timing is bad if you swing when the ball is too far away from you that's What causes your opponent to get the star around the ball coming on their side?
Speaker 1: Gotta get a well-timed hit so that your hit goes to the other side Just normally and doesn't give your opponent the chance to get some sort of power shot or the zone shot or any of those fancy Shots with the star.
Speaker 1: Yep Right, but there's actually quite a lot going on here a lot more than going on than in the DS one That's for sure.
Speaker 1: You got the zone shots.
Speaker 1: You've got this slow-motion thing.
Speaker 0: You got the trick shots for trick shots are interesting because every character is a different trick shot and they're not just an automatic Save no, they're a pain in the ass.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they're really hard.
Speaker 1: I kept hitting the arse.
Speaker 1: I don't like the control set up because I kept hitting the our stick by accident disabled it.
Speaker 0: you can just turn it off.
Speaker 1: Oh, you can.
Speaker 0: did you go to the options?
Speaker 1: That's like.
Speaker 0: the first option is disable our stick.
Speaker 1: Oh, I gotta do that Anyway, but then I got a prat.
Speaker 1: thing is I was also using the our stick to do the trick shot.
Speaker 1: So I'm gonna have to practice doing the trick shot the other way.
Speaker 1: Yep, but it was nice.
Speaker 1: There were two ways to do almost everything except basic shots.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so like even though the instructions were like oh to do the lob use X and something.
Speaker 1: I was able to do the lob with my old AB and BA and the timing is exactly the same.
Speaker 0: Oh that worked.
Speaker 0: I didn't even try that.
Speaker 1: even try to all the old controls just work.
Speaker 1: Ah Maybe for the lob BA for the drop shot.
Speaker 1: They like it.
Speaker 0: I kept consciously thinking X to do the law no X to do the drop shot.
Speaker 1: There's also lots of like.
Speaker 1: for example There's other real subtle things going on.
Speaker 1: if you're in the star your drop shot drops way harsher Lobs way harsher.
Speaker 0: I found.
Speaker 1: also if you do like if you use a to do the the the I don't know Which one is the slice which is his left hook or his right hook.
Speaker 0: B is the slice?
Speaker 1: I don't know which one's hook and which one slice.
Speaker 1: the point is if you do hook then your opponent want and it's like a Power hook then it's gonna knock back the opponent a whole bunch which will allow you to get a much easier drop shot.
Speaker 1: I'm on the volley.
Speaker 1: I also find that if they counter it with the right shot Then they'll get knocked back less.
Speaker 1: But if they do that Then you're know which shot they're coming back with and you'll be in position to return it.
Speaker 1: So do they get less knock back and do the shot?
Speaker 1: They want to do to avoid the drop shot But then you know what it is and they're predictable.
Speaker 0: the fact that we can have this Conversation means this is probably gonna be a good Mario tennis.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there's a lot going on subtly in this Mario tennis.
Speaker 1: It's it's a worth of playing.
Speaker 0: Yep, but unfortunately, you can't play it.
Speaker 1: The demos gone now Demos gone now and why the fuck was there?
Speaker 1: no boo in the demo?
Speaker 1: Fuck apparently, I think Rosalina though was was very boo like she bug and when she hooks.
Speaker 1: Oh, baby Yeah It hooks bit and chain chomp was apparently the cheap bullshit character because his reach is just like enormous.
Speaker 1: He can hit the ball with barely moving.
Speaker 1: It's like yeah, I can reach that.
Speaker 1: I'm a chain chomp.
Speaker 1: No No, it's like.
Speaker 1: shouldn't the chain chomp have limited range?
Speaker 1: is he tied down?
Speaker 0: yeah, I feel like I'm just gonna buy it when it comes out, but I Would caution you that if you are if you were interested You're not the kind of person like me who will play through all the single-player Mario tennis and who will try to play it.
Speaker 1: You probably don't need to buy it unless you're in a situation We have many people and you will be partying in which case one person should buy it.
Speaker 1: if you're not gonna play it in Person on a TV wait until after it comes out so we can tell you From the e-shop wait until the exact moment You are actually at a party with a bunch of people who want to play it before you buy it.
Speaker 1: cuz we're gonna have Unless you're there like me and you're gonna play single-player in practice and get good.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but as soon as it comes out We will on geek nights tell you if online play works at all, right and they could always patch it because it's now internet E right.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so if they you know, and also I'm not paying any money.
Speaker 1: So as soon as they charge money for online play, I'm not paying no matter what.
Speaker 0: Yep, so in some other more minor news packs unplugged badges are on sale.
Speaker 0: It's November 30th to December 2nd.
Speaker 1: We will be there the week after Thanksgiving.
Speaker 0: Yep, you should be there.
Speaker 0: packs unplugged is a full-on packs, but it's tabletop only.
Speaker 0: Yep It's got a main theater.
Speaker 0: It's got panel rooms.
Speaker 0: It's got tabletop specific panel rooms that have tabletop specific Content.
Speaker 0: that is not add other boxes.
Speaker 0: It's a great time and Bay you can totally just buy badges.
Speaker 0: hotels are easy to get.
Speaker 0: if you live anywhere in the Northeast It's just an Amtrak away.
Speaker 0: Like takes you right downtown And if you want to go to PAX West, it's too late.
Speaker 1: badges sold out within like an hour though But if you want to go if you live in the area near PAX West near Seattle You can get to Seattle easily without like a plane or a hotel.
Speaker 0: Monday badges are available.
Speaker 1: Labor Day 2018 badges are real easy to get.
Speaker 1: you can just buy them.
Speaker 1: It's 50 bucks and You can see the omega-thon finale.
Speaker 1: It'll be a shorter day than the other days but you can see the omega-thon finale and the expo hall will be less.
Speaker 1: the hall will be exactly the same only way less crowded and You can go to tabletop.
Speaker 1: You can do everything you can do at PAX.
Speaker 0: You just can't see you just sir.
Speaker 1: You just yeah, you can't see a concert and it'll be shorter But it totally worth it if you're in the area.
Speaker 0: Yep I feel like it took longer for the badges to sell out this year because I feel like it's like less time.
Speaker 0: I think it took 37 minutes for Saturday and Sunday to both be sold out But I think that does not account for the fact that the queue was probably already full beyond those days.
Speaker 1: I think their computer system was just you know, well oiled.
Speaker 0: Well, I think also and this is just a suspicion This is not based on any inside knowledge we have but I suspect highly based on guts.
Speaker 0: Yeah that due to the technically distributed nature of PAX West because PAX West is in the WSCC the Washington what at State Convention Center, but it's also in a bunch of hotels in the area like It's in.
Speaker 1: there's a lot of location an ex-place.
Speaker 0: I suspect they sell Way more badges that can fit in the WSCC at any one time.
Speaker 1: I think yes They're definitely selling badges way over the numbers of like.
Speaker 1: they're probably combining the capacities of all those places and then adding even more Onto it and just dare in the fire marshal to shut down Because who can catch him right?
Speaker 0: Well, if all those people try to go to the WCC at the same time Yes, then they'll just be like, sorry.
Speaker 0: There's a way to get into the expo hall.
Speaker 0: That'll be fine.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I just suspect that's what's going on with pax's in terms of the badge Situation.
Speaker 0: and once again if you are bitter or butter or salty about the fact you didn't get badges There's literally no way to solve that problem.
Speaker 0: So stop.
Speaker 0: There's nothing you can do.
Speaker 0: Just give up.
Speaker 1: Oh, no, there are a hundred things that a thousand people want and I was one of the 900 people that did not get Yeah hundred things where either change it.
Speaker 1: So I'm one of the hundred people and someone else can be one of the 900.
Speaker 0: be sure we'll make the badges cost $500 each and guess what?
Speaker 0: It'll probably still sell out.
Speaker 1: Well, I'm rich.
Speaker 1: I'm okay with that.
Speaker 1: Yeah Man, and then the poor people have something that actually legitimately complain is I don't got fucking $500 a day.
Speaker 1: What the fuck is it?
Speaker 0: but I'll just warn you all cuz the other con that's gonna come up not too long after that.
Speaker 0: Well, actually it's after not too long artifacts unplugged.
Speaker 0: It's mag fast.
Speaker 0: I think mag fest will be selling out just like pax's.
Speaker 1: I think they will sell out the hotel Problem.
Speaker 1: I did not and what much sooner they.
Speaker 0: so mag vest hotel problem is already a fucking disaster.
Speaker 1: Yes, they because the capacity of mag fest is greater than the number of beds they have within walking distance of mag And the.
Speaker 0: the fact that we have a way around that that has nothing to do with mag fest will remain that way.
Speaker 0: I'm never gonna help you guys.
Speaker 0: Sorry you're on your own But I think the mag fest badge situation is gonna get bad to me eventually.
Speaker 0: I that's my suspicion but anyway things Of the day.
Speaker 0: so this made the rounds like wildfire probably thanks to the share zone.
Speaker 0: the share zone has done a done its part to make sure that Everyone in the world is aware of bofa.
Speaker 0: so Horses as you know have really really stupid names in horse racing.
Speaker 1: So I watched the first episode of Uma Musume.
Speaker 1: the characters also have horse names.
Speaker 1: Just like these horses Do they have to?
Speaker 0: yes, that's how it goes You know like Cumber Bunch and toilet paper.
Speaker 0: and there's a famous horse that was just called our Horse we saw in Australia.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah Far Lap Far Lap.
Speaker 1: No, isn't Far Lap the game?
Speaker 0: Far Lap was the giant goddamn horse.
Speaker 1: What's the get?
Speaker 1: a long shot is the game?
Speaker 0: Yeah Far Lap.
Speaker 0: Here's this Wikipedia page the biggest goddamn horse ever.
Speaker 1: This horse is like an elephant.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they have him stuffed.
Speaker 1: We saw it.
Speaker 0: He saw the taxidermy body and all I have to say is that you might think with our own eyeballs You are surely exaggerating.
Speaker 1: the size Next to a horse and it's big and Far Lap was up on a pedestal, but no Far Lap is enormous.
Speaker 0: It is shocking how big that horse was.
Speaker 1: It's obvious why the other horses were not as fast as Far Lap.
Speaker 0: But the other great thing about horse racing is that there's the horse racing announcer, which is a professional Yep and coming around the bend is both of these nuts.
Speaker 0: and the thing about horse racing announcers is that they have to with aplomb be able to say the names of these horses and not laugh at them and The to this gentleman's.
Speaker 1: try to do that job.
Speaker 1: I could do it To this gentleman.
Speaker 1: that job pays enough.
Speaker 0: I don't think so but he is capable of Announcing the fact that both of these nuts won the race Without at any point cracking up, which I don't think I would have been able to do.
Speaker 1: I think that, you know, that person has probably been announcing many horse races with equally Probably not even in the top ten funniest names.
Speaker 0: He's dealt with over the years.
Speaker 0: Yeah But this video really made the rounds.
Speaker 0: In fact, right before the show Scott was like, here's my thing of the day.
Speaker 0: and I was like, that's already my thing of the day.
Speaker 1: So I found another thing in the day, yeah so we've done things of the day of videos similar to this before.
Speaker 1: I guess this sort of like this genre of You know because like the speedrunning community they just love to promote themselves and they're like they love to like talk.
Speaker 1: You know, it's like they got this whole thing going on.
Speaker 1: So there's plenty of videos on YouTube where people explain how to do a speedrun how these glitches work.
Speaker 1: You know, there's like this whole genre of like super In-depth explanation of video game thing.
Speaker 0: I love this shit.
Speaker 0: Subscribe to like.
Speaker 1: all these are way more detail than you ever needed to know.
Speaker 1: and there's a channel Called summoning salt and it's a somewhat recently made channel and this channel explains the history of Particular speedrun.
Speaker 1: So he's like Megaman - he's like well the first recorded speedrun We have a Megaman - is this guy with this time?
Speaker 1: and then this person to figured out this trick and got Faster.
Speaker 1: and then this person got faster just by working real hard.
Speaker 1: And then this person figured out this trick and got faster and so on and so on.
Speaker 1: and you know They describe the drama of the people involved the tricks that they figured out.
Speaker 1: You know the all this kind of stuff and some of these Are not too exciting.
Speaker 1: the Super Metroid one would you think would be the super exciting ones is like the number one speedrun game?
Speaker 1: It was not that exciting.
Speaker 1: It was just pretty much like well It was this person and then this person practiced harder and this person practiced harder and then these two people went back and forth But practicing more and then this person practiced more and it's like yeah All right, and this person got lucky.
Speaker 1: there wasn't any like development, right?
Speaker 1: But the video.
Speaker 1: there's some really good ones on here.
Speaker 1: This is one about Choco Mountain Mario Kart 64.
Speaker 1: This one goes deep and it is crazy.
Speaker 1: And why did this one person waste their lives with tens of thousands of attempts on to get this trick three times?
Speaker 0: Well, basically, I feel like that trick like what he did was basically going for the full web in player of games.
Speaker 1: Yeah He got the full web And it was amazing that I was able to watch you and gain all the joy of that full web in like 15 20 minutes Whereas you probably spent like years of your life getting for that full web.
Speaker 1: But if you want to get all that enjoyment in the fame 15 minutes is some videos on this channel.
Speaker 1: I haven't even watched them all yet, but there's some good ones and there's some mad ones, but I subscribe to this channel.
Speaker 1: It's good.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: I've been following it for a while.
Speaker 0: This is the same channel that did that the history of Super Mario Brothers world 4 - 2 and why that is such a crazy world.
Speaker 0: It's just a real good channel.
Speaker 0: in the moment Book the book is homas the Odyssey translated by Emily Wilson, which Scott has not read even a single additional word of.
Speaker 0: I assume.
Speaker 1: No, I was on the.
Speaker 1: there was a day when it was raining and I took the choo-choo to work.
Speaker 1: So I read it when I was standing on the choo-choo.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the problem is I didn't.
Speaker 0: I kept watching more water koi on my phone my phone.
Speaker 1: Oh, you're into that, huh?
Speaker 0: I'm gonna finish.
Speaker 0: it's not that long.
Speaker 1: I'll watch it but the What's it called?
Speaker 1: So yeah, you know, there was some Odyssey action happening.
Speaker 0: All right, I'll catch up reading it so we can finish it.
Speaker 0: do the show.
Speaker 0: Seriously if you've never read Homer's Odyssey.
Speaker 0: Read this translation and you will get it and understand it and more importantly enjoy it.
Speaker 1: I saw my boy Agamemnon.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, Agamemnon is my boy.
Speaker 1: Good, dude Poseidon but also my boy.
Speaker 0: Yeah only because you don't want him to kill you.
Speaker 1: No, he's also my boy.
Speaker 0: Also, uh, you might have noticed I'm uploading more and more videos but gig nice presents board games.
Speaker 0: I'm literally taking every tabletop game review.
Speaker 0: we've done over the last like 14 years of geek nights And I'm cutting out just the reviews putting them on YouTube and they get a lot of views.
Speaker 0: so if you're interested in seeing our game reviews without having to listen to like a half hour of me talking about biking to work or Like when it whatever we talked about ten years ago on geek nights Some ridiculous news that doesn't matter anymore how excited we are that Team Fortress 2 is coming out.
Speaker 0: Then this is for you this playlist.
Speaker 0: I have done 51 of them so far.
Speaker 0: And also if you're a fan of our anime stuff the playlist that has our geek nice presents.
Speaker 0: utenna show is also there.
Speaker 0: We put up a new episode recently.
Speaker 0: There's 16 of those plus an AMV that I made and two bonus episodes and we're gonna finish the show Hopefully before the end of the year.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we're gonna judge anime in a few weeks again.
Speaker 0: Yeah, our other series judge anime by its cover.
Speaker 0: We're going to review all the upcoming anime before it comes out because we're pretty good at that.
Speaker 1: apparently this season I actually like I said I actually watched a couple episodes of a Few of the more.
Speaker 1: I've watched more of the shows that we judged last time than in previous times.
Speaker 1: So we got stuff to say.
Speaker 0: I think the two best shows that I actually watched some episodes of From our judge animes so far.
Speaker 0: We're pop team epic.
Speaker 0: Mmm.
Speaker 0: I really like.
Speaker 0: I keep watching it.
Speaker 0: It's good.
Speaker 0: Okay, no, I will admit I don't always watch the second half even though I appreciate what the second half is that and What was the other?
Speaker 0: I forget what other one I was actually intrigued by anyway.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well made in abyss is the show I actually like the most recently.
Speaker 0: I don't remember if we talked about that one or not.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: you might have anyway go see what we judged.
Speaker 0: We've been waiting for fucking shapes and beats to come out as far as I can remember Forever so many many packs ago.
Speaker 1: I don't know how many packs.
Speaker 1: I feel like my entire life.
Speaker 0: I've gone to a packs.
Speaker 0: I've seen shapes and beads.
Speaker 0: I asked him what it's gonna come out and I said There's a guy standing there.
Speaker 1: He's got this game.
Speaker 1: The game is pumping fucking awesome music.
Speaker 0: It already looks great.
Speaker 0: I'm willing.
Speaker 1: He's got four controllers and on the screen are these little shapes and the shapes are dodging things and it's pretty much bullet hell.
Speaker 1: We all you do is dodge but you don't shoot with a really bumping like style and out and all the obstacles that you don't want to bump into are moving and appearing to the rhythm of the awesome bump in music and There's pretty much all.
Speaker 1: you can just see the game in two seconds and know everything there is to know about it.
Speaker 1: The only other thing you need to know is that what if you press a button you do a very short teleport and that short Teleport lets you a move fast to get out of the way and be teleport through an otherwise impenetrable obstacle without dying.
Speaker 1: if you You know position yourself correctly and don't teleport into the obstacle as I often do which you will do very very often.
Speaker 1: So we waited years.
Speaker 1: we'd go to packs.
Speaker 1: We'd see the game.
Speaker 1: We go to another packs and see the game again.
Speaker 1: The game was it following us around to every packs and every time we went to packs The game would change a little bit and it got to the point.
Speaker 0: I feel like video ball appeared got released and then died but in the span of us waiting for shapes and beads.
Speaker 1: That is correct.
Speaker 1: The only game I've seen in more packs is is spy party, which has been in every pack.
Speaker 1: Come out.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but anyway, so Shapes and beats improved a little bit the first few times I saw it and then I said, you know what?
Speaker 1: I don't need to keep monitoring this game for every little improvement I'll just wait for it to be out and done every year.
Speaker 0: I just went up to the booth and I was like when's it coming out?
Speaker 1: At the beginning of this year I walked past the booth and it was quieter because the pack south.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the guy is the same guy.
Speaker 1: is there the developer guy and I said hey this game actually fucking coming out.
Speaker 1: I've seen you like 20 times.
Speaker 1: He's like.
Speaker 1: He's like you should look for something soon.
Speaker 1: He's like, you know He actually gave some firm stuff and sure enough the game came out for switch and steam like last week.
Speaker 0: It's so good.
Speaker 1: It's so good.
Speaker 1: So it's everything we expected all that time we were waiting.
Speaker 1: they were polishing and polishing and polishing and polishing and That's what makes a good game.
Speaker 1: is hella polish and this is pretty much exactly what it was the first day We saw it.
Speaker 1: it is you're a little shape.
Speaker 1: don't touch the obstacles this bump in music.
Speaker 1: The obstacles move according to the music so you can predict them and you can also visually predict them too.
Speaker 1: if in case you can't hear yeah, and The end it's fucking awesome.
Speaker 1: it's polished like crazy.
Speaker 1: so it's so perfect.
Speaker 0: So what it reminds me of very heavily even though obviously there's a lot of differences because super hexagon was a very simple game.
Speaker 1: Super hexagon is dodge the things.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and it's bumping music bumping.
Speaker 1: It's changes and it's just shapes on the screen very, you know, geometrical solid colors.
Speaker 1: But super hexagon the differences is a not as much variation of shapes and beats No, not as much music as shapes and beats much smaller simpler game.
Speaker 0: But it's scratched the same itch that shapes you don't move don't move freely.
Speaker 1: in super hexagon You just sort of rotate left or right as you're sort of, you know Your way out of the middle and super hexagon isn't always the same pattern.
Speaker 1: every time it's like depends on what mode you're in Right, but there's like.
Speaker 0: I played a lot of super hexagon.
Speaker 1: There's like a few different patterns and they come at you in different, you know.
Speaker 1: So it's like pattern one pattern two pattern one And the next time you play it be like pattern four pattern four pattern four pattern one, right?
Speaker 1: You know, you know see memorize the individual patterns and learn to recognize them quickly.
Speaker 1: Whereas in shapes and beats you just memorize the level as a whole and then it doesn't change it even one pixel but shapes and beats like I.
Speaker 0: just it's interesting to me how Equally my brain puts these two games in terms of if there's a if I want a certain kind of feeling in my life They both provide that feeling a hundred percent, right?
Speaker 1: So shapes and beats.
Speaker 1: in its final form a has plenty of fucking songs.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there's no shortage of songs in it and I'm sure there'll be more in the future.
Speaker 1: They're all they'd manage to get that fucking Mortal Kombat song in there.
Speaker 1: They got the license, you know, cuz he saw.
Speaker 1: we saw.
Speaker 0: that was like a demo at PAX was the Mortal Kombat song You know, and they already said there will be DLC So that I am confident we're gonna be able to get.
Speaker 1: and we knew they were trying to get it in there But I thought it might not get in there.
Speaker 1: do the licensing.
Speaker 0: They got it in there.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah That's where it's worth buying it alone just for that one level.
Speaker 0: So some other interesting things about it Is that in terms of gameplay - it is way more varied than you might expect.
Speaker 0: It's what it's like.
Speaker 1: That's what the polish is.
Speaker 1: they polished it so much that it's like so creative.
Speaker 1: It's like you think.
Speaker 1: how many different ways can you make crazy?
Speaker 1: Rhythmic obstacles with shapes that are bullet like every level is completely different from every other level.
Speaker 0: Remember that Atari game design panel we did a few times where we talk about Surround on the Atari and how that game live wasn't called sir.
Speaker 0: It literally try.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it was Ron basically, but how that Atari game fully explores every possible mode.
Speaker 0: You could have for that very simple set of rules Shaves and beats.
Speaker 0: does that for this concept and the levels are all so shockingly varied that you will really be impressed playing it.
Speaker 0: Sometimes it's bullet hell.
Speaker 1: Sometimes it's just like these giant rhythmic heaven like stay in the right spot and the best is like there isn't I'm sure there Isn't seem to be like a best approach to any one part or no.
Speaker 1: There's never any like one way like ah the way to get through this to do this.
Speaker 1: Sometimes you can get through something by teleporting a whole bunch.
Speaker 1: Sometimes you can get through something by staying really quite still and moving very slightly just to stay just away.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, but then sometimes you're just moving around like crazy like that Right.
Speaker 1: It's like sometimes you can just hide in the corner and not even move and you know, it's like that strategy work.
Speaker 1: Sometimes it's like you can always approach something in a different way and it can work or not work.
Speaker 1: Who knows, you know Like.
Speaker 1: sometimes where it seems like okay, there is only one way to do this.
Speaker 1: Sometimes the execution really matters like okay, I have to teleport it.
Speaker 1: There's a big disc rolling towards me with a hole in the middle.
Speaker 1: I got a teleport into the disc and then teleport out the other side of the disc.
Speaker 1: There's no other way to do this.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but you got to do it just right because in the middle of the disc is a solid ball.
Speaker 1: You got it's like and I would knew exactly what I had to do, but the execution had to be tight on that part.
Speaker 0: it's also a really good balance of Elements coming out of the screen and telegraphing what they're going to do in some way Coupled with bullet hell.
Speaker 0: nonsense, that's just coming at you.
Speaker 0: I just deal with bullet hell.
Speaker 1: But it's not so hellish.
Speaker 1: to the point where you're like fuck this game cuz I'm really bad at right.
Speaker 1: It's right on that border.
Speaker 1: Like it's like one step easier than super meat boy in terms of annoyingness of hellishness.
Speaker 1: Yep It's like you can do it.
Speaker 1: I made it to the final boss and the only reason they haven't beaten the final boss is because I just haven't sat down and Like done it enough until I beat it.
Speaker 0: cuz story mode also has two really good things going for it.
Speaker 0: It has a pretty good checkpointing system, right?
Speaker 1: So that yeah This you're not really gonna have.
Speaker 1: the only time that you're gonna have problems with checkpoints is when you're actually fighting a boss and there Are no checkpoints.
Speaker 1: You know heat the whole boss at once which is also why I haven't beaten the final boss.
Speaker 0: But the other cool thing is that they have just a casual mode you can turn on.
Speaker 0: that gives you double life.
Speaker 1: Yeah, casual mode is like way easy.
Speaker 1: I'm playing a normal mode Yeah, and I'm at the final final boss and I don't plan to turn on the casual mode.
Speaker 0: I don't need it, but I'm glad they have the casual mode.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's because remember a tumble seed how There was no casual mode.
Speaker 1: It was just balls.
Speaker 0: It was like Mega Man 2 style normal and difficult Yeah, so the other really cool thing is that it has a pretty because this game is so pulsing thumping flashing in your face.
Speaker 1: the intro does a little bit bet.
Speaker 1: the intro part of the game does a little bit better at the timing of the thumping.
Speaker 1: and then You know the levels still have it.
Speaker 1: but the outside the levels it gets a little bit less.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know.
Speaker 1: But it also that intro is just so high.
Speaker 1: the first has levels are so high.
Speaker 0: It has an accessible mode so that you can tone down the flashing.
Speaker 0: So if your photo says the first thing that happens you turn on.
Speaker 1: the game is is oh my god If you have seizures don't play this fucking game.
Speaker 0: I'm like, yeah, but it has a mode that'll minimize that.
Speaker 0: So some people who might be on the edge Might still be able to play this game and the fact that they went to that level even for a game like this.
Speaker 1: I think it was obvious if you make this game.
Speaker 1: It's obvious that it is strobe light the game There.
Speaker 0: it's also got Online multiplayer and local multiplayer.
Speaker 0: Yeah competitive and co-op basically like semi-competitive.
Speaker 1: Yep And basically it's you and a bunch of other people on the screen at the same time all dodging stuff together.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think you can bring each other back to life and it's just really really fun.
Speaker 1: It also has yeah, it's like why would I want to bring something back to life and competing against them?
Speaker 1: Well, you get it ahead if you bring them back to life and then they even though they get a chance to score some.
Speaker 0: But also the game with the multiplayer.
Speaker 0: It's really set up with multiplayer casual mode combined.
Speaker 0: to basically put it in this party mode Where this is the kind of game when you're out of house party You put it on one of the TVs with four controllers.
Speaker 1: party mode Basically, just keep.
Speaker 1: there's a party mode specifically and what it does is keeps playing music over and over.
Speaker 1: It'll stop.
Speaker 1: you can just pick up controllers.
Speaker 1: put them down doesn't keep score.
Speaker 1: It just keeps playing shapes and beats keeps changing songs over and over.
Speaker 1: I am confident.
Speaker 0: at the next go Joe Laura party.
Speaker 0: This is what's gonna be in that TV.
Speaker 0: instead of star wall Yeah, why not?
Speaker 0: cuz I'm gonna go put it on the TV before people show up to the party.
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 1: The only things negative I can say about this game is that there are like a few Little wiggly niggles that you know, it's like they polished it so much but you can never be perfect, right?
Speaker 1: So one thing that bothered me is as a level one level in particular.
Speaker 1: But there's other places where it happens and where these spikes are falling from the ceiling and landing in the water in quotes And making a splash.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that was real hard.
Speaker 1: And well, yeah, but when the splash comes out There's a bunch of balls of splashing water in quotes, which is just pink balls of death.
Speaker 1: The pink balls of death were actually see a lot of the game.
Speaker 1: There are places where for example, there'll be a solid horizontal bar on the screen.
Speaker 1: That's that sort of faded pink and then it becomes solid pink and when they become solid it's when it kills you.
Speaker 1: Yeah, faded one is the warning like don't stand here get the hell out of the way Yeah, and that's great.
Speaker 0: That's perfect design and you think oh doesn't that make it too easy?
Speaker 1: The pink in this area where the splashing there are pink balls of water splashing.
Speaker 1: those pink balls were not solid pink They were the faded pink.
Speaker 1: Oh And they did not and they did not ever become solid.
Speaker 1: They just stayed faded and landed in the ground landed back in the.
Speaker 1: those shouldn't kill you.
Speaker 1: They don't kill you.
Speaker 1: Oh, okay, but Because they weren't like faded and then becoming solid it felt like they were gonna kill me.
Speaker 1: So I was like avoiding them subconsciously and it took a while to realize.
Speaker 1: Oh, those aren't deadly at any time.
Speaker 1: Why are they even on the screen if they're not deadly ever, right?
Speaker 1: I mean, I would be like imagine if a horizontal faded bar appeared and you stayed there.
Speaker 0: That'd be brilliant.
Speaker 0: You got so afraid of it.
Speaker 1: You got out of the way and it never became solid.
Speaker 0: I'd be so afraid of.
Speaker 0: that thing is just hanging out there a whole level.
Speaker 1: Yes, but I'm just great.
Speaker 1: I'm just saying is that that's kind of like, you know, there were parts of the game that were like that.
Speaker 1: They're a little air.
Speaker 1: also the teleport, you know if you have to sort of judge its distance and get used to it I teleport.
Speaker 1: like Rick you said I teleported into things a lot.
Speaker 1: Yeah, also if you teleport and you're not currently holding a stick in a direction.
Speaker 0: Yeah, good.
Speaker 0: Good.
Speaker 1: God help you It always goes right on the screen East.
Speaker 1: so there'll be times I'm like go left left left left left and then I press teleport.
Speaker 1: and Because I let go of the stick like a fraction of a second too soon I teleported to the right instead of the left, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, I feel like if you press teleport and you're not holding it in any direction at all You should teleport completely still.
Speaker 0: so the last thing about this game that's worth talking about is that it is available both on steam And not in the Nintendo switch.
Speaker 1: and which one do you buy it for?
Speaker 0: I actually bought it on the switch.
Speaker 0: I bought it on the steam because I'm gonna play it when I'm just going around.
Speaker 1: I wanted to play it when I was going around because that's how I play super hexagon.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but the thing is I bought it on the steam because it was $3 cheaper.
Speaker 1: Yeah I thought there was a DLC but I was wrong.
Speaker 0: Yeah, Scott Scott was like, oh I told Scott I got about the switch version.
Speaker 0: He's like, oh, well, can you get the DLC?
Speaker 0: I was frantically googling like what fucking DLC is he talking about?
Speaker 0: Why can't I get it?
Speaker 0: Why is no one talking about this DLC?
Speaker 1: So on this on the steam page there's no DLC.
Speaker 1: there's a DLC.
Speaker 1: it's a soundtrack of mp3s, it's not DLC.
Speaker 0: That's just a soundtrack.
Speaker 1: I know but it looks like a DLC.
Speaker 1: So I paid three dollars for some mp3s.
Speaker 1: So I paid a dollar more than the switch version.
Speaker 1: I paid three dollars less.
Speaker 1: So steam is cheaper.
Speaker 1: Steam won't go away when the switch is no longer a console people play.
Speaker 1: true It is probably.
Speaker 1: you know, there might be a situation where I was afraid Oh the switch won't get updated But you know what tumbleseed get.
Speaker 1: all the updates of the steam got in very good time because I have tumbleseed.
Speaker 1: I'm confident when there's real DLC.
Speaker 0: It'll be available.
Speaker 1: I have tumbleseed on switch instead of on Steam because I wanted to play tumbleseed in bed with two sticks.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but I can play you know Shapes and be just fine with anything with one stick.
Speaker 1: I didn't need this.
Speaker 0: part of the reason why I got on the switch is that I can still play it with four people on My TV.
Speaker 1: that way we can play it with four people on my TV.
Speaker 0: Well, my htpc Scott is from late 2008.
Speaker 0: No, it's got a GTX for video.
Speaker 1: mine has an integrated Intel because I took the video card out.
Speaker 1: I got a core i5 and it had 50 and had a 1070 but I took it out and put it in my desktop for Starwall has frame rate issues.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm gonna get one of those.
Speaker 1: their Nvidia is coming out with these 1050s that are three gigs of video ram.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm gonna get one of those from htpc because it doesn't require any extra power cables.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna try to do a lot of party games on the switch for a while and then hold out one.
Speaker 0: I think you can go wrong picking either console.
Speaker 1: Really?
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's just like the dip, you know, it's just pick whatever.
Speaker 1: I was going to say well get on steam and if I really played a whole bunch I'll get it on switch also cuz worth it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but the single player is the kind where I beat it once and then I'm done.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so I don't really need to do that.
Speaker 1: There are a bunch of challenges and nonsense if you're a masochist and I'm saying oh one other thing Is this an overworld in this game?
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah The single player has an overworld like Mario 3 style or Lolo 3 style Where you go from level to level right even though the actual game plays in the levels.
Speaker 1: But the overworld actually has some gameplay even though you can't die or anything.
Speaker 1: And it's the overworld is way cute and the pirate ship is the best.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there's a helicopter.
Speaker 1: The helicopter is cute, but the pirate ship is best.
Speaker 1: and the overworld is like really it's.
Speaker 1: it's like a really really good overworld that has rhythm and it has cute graphics and it has a story and It's way good.
Speaker 1: So I guess all you really say is one of the best one of the best Overworlds.
Speaker 1: that isn't like, you know a Zelda overworld.
Speaker 1: right stuff actually happens.
Speaker 0: So if you're a game developer The advice to take from shapes and beats is some advice that has really been making the rounds in the industry for a decade now And it's always right.
Speaker 0: You should spend more time polishing your game than you spent making your game.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean, I've you know, we talked about this and also spy party being so many years in development.
Speaker 1: But it's like.
Speaker 1: that's why I have confidence.
Speaker 1: spy party will actually be fucking good.
Speaker 1: Yeah, although I read about what spy party is and even though it is I admit very very good It's just not a game that for me.
Speaker 0: Well, it's good Fighter problem.
Speaker 1: Yes The other thing I got to say is that you know The first time I learned this lesson people don't know half-life 1. most people listening this may not Remember when half-life 1 came out.
Speaker 1: the story is real simple gave in and friends who worked at Microsoft had a bunch of fucking Money, they said well, let's make games instead.
Speaker 1: So they made half-life 1 the dream game and They it was delayed and it was hyped and delayed and hyped and delayed and hyped and delayed.
Speaker 1: and they just said we don't now.
Speaker 1: So no release date.
Speaker 1: It'll be ready when it's ready.
Speaker 1: Fuck you and Sure enough because they spent so much time and let it be ready when it's ready and spent ages on it and delayed it forever.
Speaker 1: When it came out in 1990, whatever the fuck late 90s It was God the game of God because they had polished that turd until it was no longer a turd.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: So this game Proves that out yet again.
Speaker 0: that polish kind of matters more than the core game As long as the core game is above a certain level of quality Yep, and the other thing to say if you're a game player This is a must play
Speaker 1: game Yeah, and the thing I like most about this game is I feel like you know I can spend the 20 bucks play it.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna beat the single player as soon as I sit down to actually do it Yeah, and then I won't need to play single player anymore.
Speaker 1: I'll be done, but I'll still have this great multiplayer game for any time.
Speaker 1: a local party action Yeah, right and I tested it out on some people who you know, you think this is a kind of a hard game, right?
Speaker 1: It's one of bullet hell.
Speaker 1: I tested it out on people who do not have bullet hell skills.
Speaker 1: They're not very good at games and they totally had fun Enjoyed the music right and had a good time and didn't die nearly as often as you would think.
Speaker 1: you would just die constantly like dead.
Speaker 1: Yeah, did not be fun.
Speaker 1: It's like no they cuz it gives you lives.
Speaker 1: It's like you just say you take damage before you die.
Speaker 1: It's not a one-shot kill even on hard mode.
Speaker 1: So everyone can have total like bald tons of fun with this even if you don't normally like a bullet hell Situation.
Speaker 0: this has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Speaker 1: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 0: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows It's actually recorded at night
Speaker 0: and the patreon patrons for this episode of geek nights are Craig Oliver Alan Joyce Rebecca Dunn Heidi McNicholas shimmering grooby obelisk hanging in the sky my state e.com.
Speaker 0: Jeremy minor link eg.
Speaker 0: Roberto Kingsley Kelly Snyder cold guy Amanda Duchette Shawn Yeager Matthew Smith Nicholas Brando, mr.
Speaker 0: Strong stretching for to one creations.
Speaker 0: No, I never ever wonder why we're here.
Speaker 0: Semper Fi bitch Shervin von Horo Rory James David White Rochelle, Monta Nona Superboy copybar pickle kumquat sailor Vista Don Schleich jar television Jojo Joestar Clinton Walton Ren from New Zealand Ryan Perrin Drew open Lander Finn Chris mid Kim Daniel Redman Sean Klein Chris Reimer and Thomas, huh?
Speaker 0: This has happened before.
Speaker 0: so in case you think I should be saying your name And you're not make sure you didn't check the box.
Speaker 0: that says I don't want a reward.
Speaker 0: Because if you say that you show up below the line and some people chose that because while they donate money to the patreon They do not want me to say their names on the show for whatever reason But if you want me to say your name You've got to uncheck that box and say you actually want the quote-unquote reward Also along those lines.
Speaker 0: I'm actually spending the patreon money.
Speaker 0: I'm spending a percentage of it.
Speaker 0: we are hiring a pro graphic designer and she looks pretty great and we're gonna finally Remake all our branding all our logos everything.
Speaker 0: We're no longer going to be a podcast that has the logo of a stick figure with a microphone.
Speaker 0: Having a microphone and a podcast logo was the style of the times if the times were 2006 and I think we're past that point.
Speaker 0: So stay tuned for some pretty fancy stuff.
Speaker 0: We're working on and Now I leave you with.
Speaker 0: I don't want to die.
Speaker 0: You got the wrong guy.
Speaker 0: I Was double-crossed by a dirty rat.
Speaker 0: actually this rat was a dog, but his car ran me down.
Speaker 0: I just blew out of jail.
Speaker 0: I just got back to town.
Speaker 0: Hey, this is hard to explain.
Speaker 0: May I speak to your superior?
Speaker 0: You got the wrong guy.
Speaker 0: Hey listen, my time's not up yet.
Speaker 1: Oh it is.
Speaker 1: There's no mistake about that.
Speaker 1: We know everything.
Speaker 0: Murdered in the prime of my life That car face.
Speaker 0: I'll kill him.
Speaker 0: Hey, this must be the watch department, huh?
Speaker 0: Me am?
Speaker 0: I call it that.
Speaker 0: see this watches your life and it stopped.