Speaker 0: It's Thursday July 19th 2018.
Speaker 0: I'm rim I'm Scott and this is geek nights.
Speaker 0: tonight in the geek nights book club We're talking about Emily Wilson's translation of Homer's the Odyssey.
Speaker 1: Not uh, this is the Let's do this.
Speaker 0: So yeah, no news cuz it's the geek nights book club.
Speaker 0: I guess what I should point out is that if you're new to geek nights We have a book club and we've been doing this for a long time.
Speaker 1: So even though it takes a long-ass time for us to read a book If it doesn't you take a long time to read the book.
Speaker 1: It just we don't spend enough time reading.
Speaker 0: Yep, partly cuz we had a lot going on.
Speaker 1: We probably only took me like maybe less than 10 hours to read this book in total.
Speaker 1: Yep But it just those 10 hours just spread out over many many months at least Three at least six maybe.
Speaker 0: but anyway the deal we're gonna get right into it.
Speaker 0: We're gonna have things today, but we're gonna get right into this book club.
Speaker 0: Is that we're not?
Speaker 0: we're assuming you read the book Meaning we're not going to explain the plot to you and we're gonna casually spoil everything.
Speaker 1: Granted I feel like I don't feel like you can spoil the Odyssey.
Speaker 0: Yeah, guess what?
Speaker 0: He makes it home.
Speaker 1: I mean if you don't know the story of the Odyssey, even if you never read the Odyssey I feel like I knew the story of it the general story Before even reading the pop-up book.
Speaker 1: Yeah Partly because the word I learned I learned the story of the Odyssey from other things That I watched in my child or read my childhood and then I didn't read the Odyssey.
Speaker 1: There was a multi-part DuckTales Episode I had in VHS.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that was the Odyssey.
Speaker 1: There was.
Speaker 1: what else was the Odyssey?
Speaker 1: That's the one I remember the most.
Speaker 1: but there was I think I read.
Speaker 1: you know, there's like a children's Video one of those like story books that you see at the library.
Speaker 1: that hardly moves.
Speaker 0: You've got that awesome pop-up book that you got a mocha a long time ago the Odyssey.
Speaker 0: Well, that's you know.
Speaker 0: I mean that was more recent.
Speaker 0: I didn't actually read the Odyssey like for real until ninth grade because in my high school Ninth grade was the year you did Greek literature.
Speaker 0: So you did the Odyssey and all that like all the tragedies and all that stuff.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm and We didn't actually read all of the Odyssey and I wasn't really realized that till I read the Odyssey again later There was only mythology in our school.
Speaker 1: if you elected mythology in high school And I think then they made you read a whole bunch of mythology.
Speaker 1: I did not elect that.
Speaker 1: I elected science fiction and also hippie anti-war book.
Speaker 0: Mythology was its own thing, but the Odyssey in Greek literature was not opt-outable.
Speaker 0: That was core like even even the dumb side of the school like the regular basic class English It was still Greek stuff the snooty.
Speaker 1: basically there were three literature electives for snooty smart kids and I chose none of them which is Shakespeare Mythology and Mark Twain type action.
Speaker 1: I just none of those three.
Speaker 1: I chose all the other ones.
Speaker 0: at RIT I just tested out of everything except the one class I couldn't test out of.
Speaker 0: yeah where I had to read that tear all those terrible books.
Speaker 0: tree of red stars.
Speaker 0: Yep, we will never do a book club book on the tree of red stars I promise.
Speaker 0: why would we guess we should warn people against it?
Speaker 0: anyway three stars run away.
Speaker 1: So the point is that you know we know the Odyssey, but this is a new translation of the Odyssey And you know I've never read any other translation of the Odyssey.
Speaker 1: that wasn't some simplified children's or pop-up book.
Speaker 1: I've never read and you know I've read some other.
Speaker 0: I've read I've mostly read in high school one translation I don't know which one it was in our textbook, and I fully read a different translation I'm pretty sure was a penguin book, but I don't know anything about it.
Speaker 1: We're not a lot of them.
Speaker 1: It's like there's like four different ones than Amazon And you don't know which one's good, but I'd never read a modern or modernized translation until this mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: But again really like we're going to assume you read the book.
Speaker 0: you can continue to listen to this episode If you didn't read the Odyssey.
Speaker 0: But that's like when you're at a convention or at a party and you're hanging out on the outside of the circle of people talking About something and you have no idea what they're talking about and you're just standing there kind of nodding along.
Speaker 0: You really don't want to be that guy.
Speaker 1: Rim is that guy?
Speaker 1: no I usually know what's going on right.
Speaker 1: the other thing is to talk about this book Right is kind of hard because I feel like the introduction and also the notes at the end Sort of say everything there is that I could possibly say and I don't have any special knowledge about.
Speaker 1: you know Greek history literature Homer or anything.
Speaker 1: so it's like.
Speaker 1: what can I say other than reiterate?
Speaker 1: What was already in there?
Speaker 1: Right it's like there's already these people who study this for a fucking living.
Speaker 1: What do I have to contribute?
Speaker 0: well?
Speaker 0: That's why rather than talk about the forward which if you read this book and didn't read the forward the forward What the forward is the what you're paying for the forward taught me a lot about the Odyssey?
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, and it also reinforces something that a lot of people don't seem to realize that when people say Greek They always think like Athens and Sparta.
Speaker 0: that is way way late Greece.
Speaker 0: There's a lot of Greek and quote-unquote Greek history before that.
Speaker 1: yeah, Homer comes way before say Euclid.
Speaker 0: yeah, right Homer comes way before Athens and Sparta as you would know them.
Speaker 1: yeah I mean they still the you know like Sparta.
Speaker 1: they mentioned Sparta in the book.
Speaker 1: right it exists.
Speaker 0: yeah But the Sparta of 300 was far far away and arguably they might not even be the same thing.
Speaker 0: yep They could just have the same name because you know there was the Dorian invasion Which may or may not have been an actual.
Speaker 1: and being Homer they're talking about mice And I like.
Speaker 1: it's a present thing mice And I is like the ancient Greek civilization that was lost and we don't know enough about yep.
Speaker 1: You want to have a good honor, but that was present to Homer's writings.
Speaker 0: You want to go down a rabbit hole.
Speaker 1: go read about the Greek Dark Age cuz I realize Like what BC number are we talking about here with you know when Homer was supposedly possibly writing the Odyssey?
Speaker 0: Like we're talking like literal way if the Trojan War happened like that.
Speaker 0: So imagine raw on a super rough scale cuz I'm not I don't know that much about currency current.
Speaker 0: the Greece that you think of like Sparta Athens Marathon like and after that is Alexander like on a really broad stroke a great one.
Speaker 0: so before The Athens Sparta stuff not not not Wayne.
Speaker 0: the great one Is the Greek dark.
Speaker 0: effectively the Greek dark a like archaic Greece the Dark Age and then before that is the Homer era.
Speaker 0: But yeah, we're not gonna try to get in Greek chronology.
Speaker 1: the sack of Troy was dated to 1184 BC.
Speaker 0: that's a long time before the Battle of Marathon.
Speaker 1: That's that's like Less than half the distance between us and Jesus who didn't exist.
Speaker 1: The Battle of Marathon the one on the other side the Battle of Marathon Which is what most peep.
Speaker 0: that era is what most people think of when they think of ancient Greece.
Speaker 0: They're actually I think most people think of like classical Greece like Roman Greece But anyway, or like all those like way later eras was 490 BC Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: so the stuff you think about it from 490 BC is not the same years so it's as old.
Speaker 1: it's basically the distance between us and the medieval times.
Speaker 1: is the distance between Homer and The Greece years they normally think.
Speaker 0: but before we get into that we do have Things of the day.
Speaker 1: you just forgot to do things of the day now And you started book clubbing.
Speaker 0: no I was doing a pre moment about the book club because we haven't done one in a while.
Speaker 0: And I want to remind people that we have a book club And you should just go look at the old episodes and if a book looks good read it and then listen to our show about It.
Speaker 0: you should read books.
Speaker 1: if you want to be an intelligent person.
Speaker 1: if you come up to me and say I am a person who?
Speaker 1: Does not read books that consist only of words doesn't matter.
Speaker 1: if they're e or paper audiobooks don't count for me at least.
Speaker 1: But if you're a person who does not read books my respect for you is diminished.
Speaker 1: you are below other humans on the respect Ometer compared to humans who do read.
Speaker 0: so my thing of the day is this video.
Speaker 0: SV nation is pretty good.
Speaker 0: videos about like sports History and sports faz fun stuff and this one is about Tom Dempsey if you don't know Held the record for the longest field goal in his in football history for 43 years and so people knew how to kick.
Speaker 0: Well, it wasn't just until people know how to kick stuff changed and technology change.
Speaker 0: There's a lot of things that changed also steroids more of a thing like.
Speaker 0: there's lots of things.
Speaker 1: I don't think kickers.
Speaker 0: They're on steroids Wouldn't be surprised.
Speaker 1: They don't use it.
Speaker 1: the kicker is usually the tiniest tiniest people with one big like trogdor looking leg.
Speaker 0: yeah But Anyway the deal with Tom Dempsey was that he was so good That they made a rule to basically prevent anyone else from ever kicking like him.
Speaker 0: and the reason he kicked the way he did is Because he was literally missing half of his foot and his foot was basically a club That he used to great effect with terrifying power.
Speaker 0: and the NFL literally made a rule that Specifically prevented anyone from ever doing what he did ever again, and it's just a pretty interesting story.
Speaker 0: hmm So what do you got?
Speaker 1: so as it would have been a Monday thing of the day?
Speaker 1: But whatever I don't even know if this is real cuz I didn't try it for myself.
Speaker 1: This could be like a scam website.
Speaker 1: That's like fooling you into thinking.
Speaker 1: This is real.
Speaker 0: That'd be really funny if it is but yeah.
Speaker 1: So one thing people in the way who work in the web always talk about is links.
Speaker 1: Ella why?
Speaker 1: and X?
Speaker 0: there's also another one Li and clearly in the context of you made a modern website.
Speaker 0: But will it work on links right?
Speaker 0: so look at how long my neckbeard is.
Speaker 1: Links is a web browser that runs in the terminal and is like only text.
Speaker 1: so it's sort of like if you make your website Good and accessible enough and and adaptable enough someone should be able to use your website Fully from links in the terminal with text only and it's sort of like a litmus test But sort of a bullshit one.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'd say it was a legitimate litmus test until about 2002.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it had its day, but it's like no one does no one using links.
Speaker 1: Maybe there's one guy.
Speaker 1: The point is it's a way to browse the web from the terminal and it works.
Speaker 1: even today it works yeah, but in some web pages it works better than others.
Speaker 1: and What someone here did is they made a thing?
Speaker 1: What's it called?
Speaker 0: It is called browshe browshe.
Speaker 1: For I guess it stands for browser shell or shell browser And it's basically a web browser that runs in the terminal.
Speaker 1: But it takes advantage of all the features of modern terminals and modern computers not which are things like color Right links and links.
Speaker 1: the you know both spellings are two different texts.
Speaker 1: right they can run on like a VT 100 in the work.
Speaker 1: Right that's one of those old term like hardware terminals.
Speaker 1: They just got a green screen right.
Speaker 1: but browshe can run in say gnome terminal or x-term or rx-vt Or the I term on your Mac, and you know all the modern terminal emulators that you're running on your real computer.
Speaker 1: That's made in the 2000s Like a VT hundred that has colors and sounds and you have a mouse and all these sorts of assumptions and scroll wheel.
Speaker 1: So it basically uses all those modern features of your browser to render a web page Just like a real web page.
Speaker 1: the thing is the resolution is just really low.
Speaker 0: it is the resolution the pixels on anything that is Not text because it's all icons.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's all icons in a pixel grid.
Speaker 0: the well in a grid Not a pixel grid the pixels and the images are each Exactly the size of a tile that would have a character in it like a letter.
Speaker 1: yep, so but yeah It's.
Speaker 1: you can even watch video in it look at images click on links read tags.
Speaker 1: It's like it's a full-on web browser.
Speaker 0: What's really?
Speaker 0: what's really?
Speaker 1: Anyone who knows how to use a web browser could use this.
Speaker 1: it would just look really pixely.
Speaker 0: What's really weirding me out is just scroll like looking at these images.
Speaker 0: They look so much like the resolution you got in old PC games like police quests.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that is giving me a weird nostalgia for games like police quest.
Speaker 1: it would be like if you ran.
Speaker 1: it feels almost like you ran actual chrome But on DOS and the resolution of the screen was still 320 by whatever the fuck.
Speaker 1: it was an old DOS Yeah, but your CPU is strong enough, and it actually just kind of worked.
Speaker 1: But you didn't have any advanced GPU and your resolution was still 320 by whatever with 256 colors.
Speaker 0: got in the DOS era I had a monitor that was 12 inches and it its max resolution Was 800 by 600.
Speaker 0: I think we had a 15 each.
Speaker 0: No, I didn't have that.
Speaker 0: but then I had that giant 19-inch super CRT that I brought to RIT.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I brought it to RIT a 17-inch.
Speaker 1: yep that 19-inch.
Speaker 0: That was one of the the only thing I've had to move in my life That was harder than moving.
Speaker 1: that monitor was the fucker that couch And then the people who took away that fucker just took it away.
Speaker 1: one two three whoop.
Speaker 0: I was really saddened by that.
Speaker 0: they had no problem movement, so yeah in the meta moment whatever We're gonna be at PAX West the real PAX.
Speaker 0: We're doing a panel.
Speaker 0: It's not only going to be live at PAX on Monday But it's going to be live streamed on the official PAX twitch.
Speaker 1: So if you don't go to PAX I don't know which one of them they think there might be two or three official.
Speaker 0: It will be probably packs two or packs three.
Speaker 0: as soon as we know we will let you know.
Speaker 1: We'll probably tweet when it's starting - yeah I will probably schedule all those tweets well in advance if I follow geek nights on Twitter and Facebook and Instagram and all the different social places because we have accounts there.
Speaker 0: also if you're listening to this podcast You could actually watch us record it live on YouTube.
Speaker 0: There are currently five people watching.
Speaker 1: I mean I would already discourage you from listening to this podcast saying you could not worth your time to listen to this podcast.
Speaker 1: It's even less worth your time to watch the podcast being recorded live.
Speaker 0: I'm just saying you could.
Speaker 0: I didn't say you should.
Speaker 0: And also we just did another judge anime by its cover.
Speaker 0: that video is up And it's on Scott's YouTube and a lot of you only follow my YouTube.
Speaker 0: You should also follow Scott's YouTube.
Speaker 1: Start some project of great evil possibly on my YouTube soon.
Speaker 0: Oh is this one I know about or is this a new evil.
Speaker 1: I told it to you recently.
Speaker 0: okay I think I know what you're talking anyway a lot.
Speaker 0: if you do that evil.
Speaker 0: It'll be great.
Speaker 0: so We're not gonna try to analyze the Odyssey.
Speaker 0: I think you're gonna mention that there's nothing we can say.
Speaker 0: well anything I could say would either be me Basically poorly reiterating things I learned in high school.
Speaker 1: I feel like if you write a book about physics and then tried to say things about physics.
Speaker 1: It's like but more importantly like qualified.
Speaker 1: We're consumers.
Speaker 1: We're not.
Speaker 0: you know it depends on what the book is like The ear the eye the arm.
Speaker 0: there aren't a lot of book clubs that talked about it.
Speaker 0: So we tried to analyze its themes and do like some serious Likrit.
Speaker 0: but I don't really want to bother with that with the Odyssey because The Odyssey is one of the most studied stories in human history.
Speaker 0: You can read way smarter people than us, so I want to approach this talking about This translation and like it how it worked
Speaker 1: for us
Speaker 0: And more importantly I also want to talk about The story at face value as we read it like as though We just read this book and it had no history.
Speaker 0: But I'm not gonna try to read into it.
Speaker 0: you can go read the debate over whether or not Odysseus was justified in killing all the slaves.
Speaker 0: right.
Speaker 1: so Having not read completely other translations, I've read you know small portions.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's why I'm really curious.
Speaker 0: from your impression What kind of person do you think Odysseus is?
Speaker 0: is what I really want to ask you.
Speaker 1: well That's the thing right is like.
Speaker 1: so on the one hand you sort of feel like well this story is so old and not Advanced right.
Speaker 1: it doesn't have modern sensibilities.
Speaker 1: It has the most ancient of sensibility possible yep Almost the most ancient human sensibility possible.
Speaker 1: so you assume that it's sort of really Straightforward and not complex.
Speaker 1: right Odysseus is a is a straightforward Hero good guy, dude.
Speaker 1: right he goes to a war, but it can't get home because the gods are tormenting him.
Speaker 1: But he's a smart good awesome, dude Which is why Athena likes him.
Speaker 1: I love.
Speaker 0: he's so smart and good that the the opening to the book is basically just Athena being Like hey Zeus remember Odysseus.
Speaker 0: We should do something about him.
Speaker 0: and Zeus is even like oh, yeah He's like the one smart one.
Speaker 1: all right all right his special skills are lying and fighting.
Speaker 0: That's pretty much all he lying fighting and then crying about the aftermath of fighting.
Speaker 1: There's three things you know, but he's a good person.
Speaker 1: He cares about his family right now.
Speaker 1: You know he cares about his crew people right even though.
Speaker 1: He's banging a hot goddess He still wants his regular life and frankly his crew people not the sharpest tools in the shed You know.
Speaker 1: and then you know he gets home And you know he takes care of things.
Speaker 1: and if in a way that you know it's a modern sensibility seems evil and cruel First he lies and then he fights yeah exactly those are his two things.
Speaker 1: Say I guess he's okay at voting.
Speaker 0: I guess what I enjoyed the most.
Speaker 0: that didn't come out because when I read the old when I read this originally I read the Odyssey in high school fall friend.
Speaker 0: and was that it?
Speaker 0: I Didn't really get him be like.
Speaker 0: it said like oh, yeah He's a good liar.
Speaker 0: But I didn't really like.
Speaker 0: think about like.
Speaker 0: I had to have that analysis sort of spoon-fed to me And it didn't really come out from the text that he was a good liar other than the text telling me over and over again He's good at lying.
Speaker 0: reading this he is good at lying.
Speaker 1: He lies all the time comes up with Incredibly complex people are like oh, who are you?
Speaker 1: and he comes up with this complete character?
Speaker 1: I'm from this town in this place, and I met this person our vandal a right.
Speaker 1: He's got like a whole story just out of his ass with every minute detail.
Speaker 1: Person's life, that's mostly believable, so I know it was his own dad.
Speaker 0: I noticed something I did.
Speaker 0: the only one the only person he does not fool is this dog.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm I love how his dog is like doesn't the dog just die about?
Speaker 0: the dog sees him and it's like well You're back.
Speaker 0: I see you now.
Speaker 0: I'm dead.
Speaker 0: I was only waiting to see you.
Speaker 1: yep So I think the thing about his lying though right is that?
Speaker 1: is that the structure of the book?
Speaker 1: Actually sort of like the chronology of it was totally messed up.
Speaker 1: This is the thing that I noticed the most right and most people don't seem to notice this.
Speaker 1: oh Yeah, so normally you think of the story of the Odyssey right and it's like well.
Speaker 1: What order do the things happen?
Speaker 1: This is the order.
Speaker 1: the things happen.
Speaker 1: right.
Speaker 1: he's at the war.
Speaker 1: he runs away from the war.
Speaker 0: Well, he would they win the war and he leaves right.
Speaker 1: he leaves the war.
Speaker 1: then all those adventure things happen with the Cyclops And the men and yeah right.
Speaker 1: then he gets trapped on the island with the goddess yeah, then he escapes that island to get to the island with Nausicaa and Then from the island with Nausicaa they actually help him get home.
Speaker 0: Then when he's home he deals with all this shit And then he just that's the actual chronological order and all the shit that home like telemic is not.
Speaker 0: that is happening in parallel.
Speaker 1: But what order if you actually read this book are these things told to you in the book?
Speaker 1: He starts on the island with the goddess yeah, and then he goes to the island with Nausicaa and then he tells them the story of the things that happened between the war and Being on the island with the goddess.
Speaker 1: they don't actually say show you those things happening.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's Odysseus telling that King Nausicaa's dad about those things happening and the thing that's.
Speaker 1: and when he's telling him Those things is he lying.
Speaker 0: I am so sure he's lying.
Speaker 1: so Once I realize this.
Speaker 1: but all those things about the sirens all the famous parts the sirens the world cool That that that's only Odysseus telling a king.
Speaker 1: those things happened right?
Speaker 1: are they actually true?
Speaker 1: is the stuff that happened at the war Even true?
Speaker 1: well first of all the same time that happened at the war is corroborated by other people like Menelaus.
Speaker 0: Yeah, okay, telemic is we see him actually going around and talking to people right and they like they all agree on the history.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the second thing is that even though once I realized that and I was like oh Maybe all the fantasy famous adventure shit.
Speaker 1: That's in one chapter of this book by the way yeah, all that's in one chapter where he lie tells the king.
Speaker 1: that is that part a lie because everything every story Odysseus tells everyone Else is a lie, but some things he knows later on like in the even towards the end of the book There's a part where Odysseus is thinking to himself, and he's like.
Speaker 1: he's like oh, man This isn't as bad as he's like.
Speaker 1: am I gonna fight all these suitors, and he's like well I killed that fucking Cyclops.
Speaker 1: And it's like he wasn't lying about the Cyclops.
Speaker 1: because why would he unless he lied to so much that he convinced himself It was about to make a point that that is?
Speaker 0: the only Potential disruption to your read of that is that people who are very good at lying and tell certain lies consistently Tend to accidentally start to believe those lies and internalize them.
Speaker 1: There's also other truths for example.
Speaker 1: so we everything that happened at the war was confirmed by other people who are also at the Trojan War And he did leave on a boat with a bunch of dudes and those dudes are gone.
Speaker 1: What the hell happened to them?
Speaker 1: if his story is a lie?
Speaker 1: Right, so I'm pretty confident that the story We know what happened to them according to him They'll say I'm fairly confident that all the things that he said happened between the war and being on Calypso's Island were mostly true.
Speaker 0: Yeah
Speaker 1: But and then when he's because it's you know it's a it's primitive writing from the ancient times when he's telling stories to other people and the book the story makes it obvious to the reader that he's lying because he's usually starts those stories by saying he's someone other than Yeah,
Speaker 0: but at the same time when he tells
Speaker 1: the king he's Odysseus He's not lying,
Speaker 0: but he also like reading those passages where he tells the story.
Speaker 0: the thing I noticed being a pretty good liar myself Is that he (Laughter) He you in the telling of the story he does the things that Someone who's good at lying would do.
Speaker 0: when they're lying like Lampshading the fact that he lies he half his stories are.
Speaker 0: so I lied to this other motherfucker And I'm telling you about it.
Speaker 0: That is like.
Speaker 0: that is one of the best ways to convince someone you're lying to that you're not lying to them.
Speaker 0: Bring them into the trust of yeah, so I lied to that other guy about this thing.
Speaker 0: hmm And he also like he starts to include very specific details sometimes in the manner that someone who's lying might Do that about exactly how far away the rock was thrown.
Speaker 1: But here's the thing is that other people when they're telling stories and not lying Also include all those details.
Speaker 1: remember this is yeah these ancient times are before books TV cell phones distractions Whatever all right.
Speaker 1: so people mostly spent their time Entertainment with storytelling.
Speaker 1: so people were good at telling stories or remembered lots and lots of details.
Speaker 1: But so I feel like if you showed up at say a king's house Asking for piston the night, and they asked you about your life They would expect you to have all those details because that's how everyone has can tell stories like that true
Speaker 0: But at the same time it sort of implied that being a really excellent liar is a core fundamental Aspect of great Greek men.
Speaker 0: well and one might notice that all the people telling these stories are great men and Are probably maybe they're all lying to each other great Great in quotes.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'm making quote marks and Telemachus is too young to know how to lie effectively.
Speaker 0: So he's just earnest and I did Look at it that maybe other people are lying to him.
Speaker 1: So so so Telemachus right people tell me is basically glossed over and not paid attention to and people Adapt or homage to the Odyssey.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right.
Speaker 1: so the thing about Telemachus.
Speaker 1: That's interesting is one.
Speaker 0: He's 20 Yeah, but the book it treats him like he's seven mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: the book is like He is to die like he is too young to know anything about anything like even walks outside like you.
Speaker 0: They're worried.
Speaker 0: He's gonna die.
Speaker 0: well.
Speaker 1: I mean you look at Odysseus.
Speaker 1: He's got the time of the scar.
Speaker 1: He's got the.
Speaker 1: so people know it's him for sure yeah, but the story of how he got it.
Speaker 1: It's like he was doing Adventury shit from a young age.
Speaker 1: Telemachus I think was sheltered in this wealthy house and yep even though he's 20 He wasn't doing adventury shit like Odysseus was.
Speaker 0: arguably his first adventure is because Odysseus isn't there And he goes out to try to deal with that.
Speaker 1: yeah, and you know and the thing is he's not.
Speaker 1: He's not like herp-de-derp.
Speaker 1: It's like you know.
Speaker 1: usually he learns.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Usually when you have that sort of character like the weak young Kid who never went on an adventure is like they suck, but Telemachus actually doesn't suck.
Speaker 1: He's just inexperienced, and he you know shows that he clearly he's the son of Odysseus.
Speaker 1: yep You're not actually gonna suck if you practice.
Speaker 0: look at his baby's first deceit of like.
Speaker 0: well don't tell my mom I'm leaving yeah, and I. but then you compare that to Odysseus and his like.
Speaker 1: so here's what we're gonna Do to trick the Cyclops right and even though he doesn't like you know he can't physically do anything about the suitors Right he totally just smack talks them all the time.
Speaker 1: Yeah, he has no problem smack You know talking back to them, but he just can't.
Speaker 0: actually that's something that didn't come out either when I read the Odyssey originally.
Speaker 1: He isn't just like oh poor suitors.
Speaker 1: No.
Speaker 1: I'll do what you want.
Speaker 1: He's like you fucking assholes.
Speaker 1: Why don't you get the hell out of here, but I really like you can't make us.
Speaker 1: He's like you're right I can't but you guys suck.
Speaker 0: I really read Telemachus as this kind of wishy-washy Like milk toast piece of crap kinda like that.
Speaker 0: he wasn't aggressive that he was weak But reading this translation really brought out out.
Speaker 0: He's doing what he can yeah, and I think it's partly just that.
Speaker 0: the Capabilities.
Speaker 1: yeah, if he was a badass you probably would have just murdered them all in day one, but he wasn't so.
Speaker 0: But he's got this kernel of it like.
Speaker 0: he's got the kernel of violence and the kernel of lying like ready mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: So let's see.
Speaker 0: But I just the way Odysseus tells that story because though another way to look at this like you said is he lands on this island after the war Alone tells this elaborate story, and then the kings of the all the people on this island give him Enough treasure to basically account for everything you would have had if he'd gone to the war
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm,
Speaker 0: and then he just goes home with all
Speaker 1: that mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: I do like this kind of sad as an aside though that that island gets completely fucked over for helping him.
Speaker 0: Yep, like that is not really talked about much like yeah, Zeus or Poseidon just punished them forever, and they're gone.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean I think you know Odysseus doesn't really care about anyone other than himself.
Speaker 1: He doesn't care about like side Consequences, you know it's like the whole Trojan War is like a huge Like basically natural disaster, and he doesn't give it.
Speaker 1: He doesn't get a crap.
Speaker 0: Yeah, of course It's hard to say cuz I don't care about his man who died.
Speaker 1: You know even though he makes at the very end he makes peace all of those families, but he doesn't care.
Speaker 0: Well notice so he when they're leaving Cersei's house There's what's-his-name props to my man F. Whatever his name was I can't remember who got drunk and just fucking fell to his death from the ceiling because he was dumb and drunk And Odysseus was like.
Speaker 0: well we got to go.
Speaker 0: so they just didn't like.
Speaker 0: they just left him laying there and The only reason he goes back and buries the guy and does all that stuff is because he meets the guys Literal ghost and makes a promise to that ghost and then he has to follow through on the promise or I'll get in trouble.
Speaker 1: Yep, I feel like if he does what you know and the other thing is that people you know Oh, this is so smart and so powerful and so awesome 90% of the time Athena just says Odysseus do this and he does that and then Athena makes him strong.
Speaker 1: Athena puts a disguise on him.
Speaker 1: Athena You know tells him what exactly where to go and what to say and what to do.
Speaker 0: It's a little.
Speaker 1: are you really that awesome?
Speaker 1: if Athena is just there some goddess is just you know helping you out and giving you Specific.
Speaker 0: and now because if you look at the story Athena didn't help him with Polyphemus.
Speaker 1: No, they're you know, there are definitely things Athena didn't help.
Speaker 0: Athena didn't help it with Cersei.
Speaker 0: He dealt with Cersei on his own mostly Hermes gave him some advice there.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but it's it's still.
Speaker 1: it's like there's a lot of God Interference going on right?
Speaker 0: It's like there is a lot of non God interference.
Speaker 0: But I do like.
Speaker 0: I read Athena very differently too in this translation.
Speaker 0: She's very like oh my god is bell dandy magical girl like.
Speaker 0: there's a lot more stuff going on with her.
Speaker 0: that comes out in this text because she's actually Kind of chill and a little bit snarky and a little bit like I'm gonna help you out like do this.
Speaker 0: Let's go.
Speaker 0: and She's also really good at lying.
Speaker 1: Well, she's also like sort of eager to do certain things.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and Zeus is sort of like whatever right?
Speaker 1: So she's a lot of times.
Speaker 0: She's like, I really want to help this Odysseus guy.
Speaker 1: She's like she's like Zeus.
Speaker 1: I want to do this.
Speaker 1: It'd be so fucking awesome.
Speaker 1: It's just like Alright, and then she's like, yes, she goes down.
Speaker 1: She's like, yeah, let's fuck.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and she's on Odysseus aside.
Speaker 1: So other people get fucked.
Speaker 0: as opposed to Poseidon you get the impression that he's just looking around like someone in Philadelphia Just waiting for anyone to cross him, right?
Speaker 0: He just comes down.
Speaker 1: He's like who's burning lots of things and sacrifice to me.
Speaker 1: those people good those people good.
Speaker 1: Mmm I don't see a lot of smoke coming from over there.
Speaker 1: Yeah, who's that smoke for?
Speaker 1: not for me?
Speaker 1: Mmm, there's any water near these people.
Speaker 1: Let me see.
Speaker 0: they got any boats And it also reminds you that boat.
Speaker 1: move of it back.
Speaker 0: how powerful Poseidon is that even Zeus is like?
Speaker 0: yeah Odysseus really got the short end of the stick, but I can't really do anything about what Poseidon wants.
Speaker 0: Even Zeus can't really tell Poseidon what to do.
Speaker 1: So I like how Zeus is like.
Speaker 1: he's the god of strangers, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's I about that.
Speaker 1: and like most of the book like this is one more.
Speaker 1: I mean there's a lot of morals but the number one moral of the book seems to be if someone comes to visit you properly, yep, you gotta be just nice to them and Don't treat them like shit.
Speaker 1: and if you visit someone you can totally expect them to feed you and give you treasure and It's sort of like hey everyone if people are traveling around even if you don't know who the hell they are you should be nice to them and Treat them nicely and that's a lesson.
Speaker 1: I think that is good for the modern world.
Speaker 0: But also based on the context of the forward and a bunch of reading I did about the old Greece is That there seemed to be this idea that people who shared food and did this stranger thing.
Speaker 0: they would then basically be allies and not make war against each other or cause trouble for each other and That was a way to sort of prevent in like local warfare So that to the rest of the world the Greeks are these roving like murderous barbarians that just come to your shores and fucking kill Everything and eat everything.
Speaker 1: I mean in I guess in newer times than this.
Speaker 1: right you know lots of nomadic peoples have the same kind of thing.
Speaker 1: Hospitality right where it's like.
Speaker 1: you know you come into my tent.
Speaker 1: You know kind of thing.
Speaker 0: yeah well We've shared water now.
Speaker 0: We can't ever go to war.
Speaker 0: yep, but we did neither one.
Speaker 0: We know there's.
Speaker 0: let us be friends, but we know there's people on that other island.
Speaker 0: Did you ever have water with them?
Speaker 0: No, let's just go steal all their shit.
Speaker 1: It's like yeah They were jerks and he visited them.
Speaker 1: And it's sort of like.
Speaker 1: well nice people who treat foreigners nicely are treated nicely But even the people who treat each other nicely if you're a shithead won't treat you nicely.
Speaker 1: It's sort of like it's okay to kill jerks.
Speaker 0: Yep, because I noticed when they put when he's telling the story of all the different places They land like all these short vignettes.
Speaker 0: They land on the one island and everybody tries to eat them and they land on Polyphemus Island and he just eats them and then he goes by skillet and crib doesn't skill.
Speaker 0: I just eat six of them.
Speaker 0: a lot of people get eaten.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean, it's a good.
Speaker 1: it is also a good lesson for the modern world, right?
Speaker 0: Don't get eaten.
Speaker 1: be nice to everyone except jerks.
Speaker 1: Jerks, you can treat like shit cuz they're jerks.
Speaker 0: I do enjoy.
Speaker 0: you know you talked about like you don't have to tolerate intolerance how the gods do a lot.
Speaker 0: but if you notice as most situations where a god or goddess helps Odysseus They're only helping them with the part with him with the part that he can't do anything about.
Speaker 0: Because there's one point where Hermes is like and I think Athena says a similar thing to him at one point You can't.
Speaker 0: Cersei definitely says this you're a human.
Speaker 0: You can't do shit about what the gods want.
Speaker 0: If a god tells you to do something you do it.
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 0: Ghostbusters taught us that lesson, but not but.
Speaker 1: but Someone asked you if you're a god you say this is in the lucky position where the gods want good happen to want him to do Any unlucky position whether them do.
Speaker 0: he's in the unlucky position where the gods are interested in him.
Speaker 0: It's this double-edged sword if the gods notice you it's generally more bad than good even if they want to help you.
Speaker 0: But because the gods noticed him and are fucking with him at least he has other gods who like him enough to help him.
Speaker 1: If you want to know about God's noticing you you should watch Clash of the Titans.
Speaker 0: Yeah Or possibly read the Prince of Nothing series depending on how that goes Because that is definitely do not let the gods notice you.
Speaker 1: what do you see?
Speaker 1: The Lord of the Rings you don't want the Eye of Sauron upon you do not want it to see you.
Speaker 0: But oh I had.
Speaker 0: it was nothing I was thinking of along the lines of polyphemus and all these people eating people right.
Speaker 0: so the gods Like they make all these points about how you can't do anything about the gods.
Speaker 0: You can only do things about people and the gods really only help Odysseus with the god stuff And he really just deals with the people stuff on his own.
Speaker 0: He's pretty good at it, but at the same time With the people stuff he very often makes mistakes like he doesn't tell his crew the full truth And then as a result they do something stupid, and then he gets fucked over by it.
Speaker 1: that happens with the cow eating situation.
Speaker 0: Yeah, he's just like yeah, don't do this thing but he doesn't really tell him why.
Speaker 0: or like don't open this bag, but doesn't really tell him why and then they do something stupid and That ruins him, but should he?
Speaker 0: I feel like he could have lied to his guys Or he could have told him the truth.
Speaker 0: They both would have worked, but instead he just omits the truth.
Speaker 0: it seems like omitting is worse than both lying and not lying And that seems to come up multiple times.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm Yeah, you know it's like Yeah, he was sort of following the instructions.
Speaker 1: He was given right.
Speaker 1: He was like don't eat the right But he can't make anyone else follow the instructions right.
Speaker 1: if I if I see a lot of times where he sees Athena and no One else sees her right stuff like that.
Speaker 1: And it's like how if I saw God and it told me stuff and then what am I gonna tell you?
Speaker 1: hey rim?
Speaker 1: I saw Athena, and she said do this you put me in the crazy house The same time at one point.
Speaker 0: tell tell tell Emma kiss is like Athena told me to do this and everyone's like oh Then you should do it mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: if Athena tells you to do something just do it like.
Speaker 0: Everyone agrees that gods are literally real.
Speaker 1: and even that time where it's like Oh Zeus send me a sighs like Thunder.
Speaker 0: It's like oh all right Immediate thunder, but there's one thing in Emily Wilson's translation that I noticed specifically.
Speaker 0: I remember when they win the siren bit which is so short.
Speaker 0: It's like such in passing.
Speaker 1: It is weird that that's like the number one most Adapted.
Speaker 1: you know thing in other media other you know tales yet.
Speaker 1: It's like a page.
Speaker 1: It's less than a page, but how?
Speaker 1: I wonder how you know that became like that portion of the story became the.
Speaker 1: You know as it were the story was adapted over the years how that part was magnified and the other modified.
Speaker 0: Sexy bird ladies because it's fun.
Speaker 0: Yeah There I think actually the forward talks a little bit about that Especially because it points out that the thing the siren seduce Odysseus with is not any of the things.
Speaker 1: Oh, I love that a lot.
Speaker 0: that yeah They literally try to seduce him with.
Speaker 0: we'll tell you about what happened in the war that you fought because you clearly have PTSD.
Speaker 1: Yep, imagine rim if there was like.
Speaker 1: you know you're going past some sirens right and it's like you know.
Speaker 1: people tend to think you know With the sirens they were just singing such sweet music.
Speaker 1: It was so wonderful to hear you wanted to go over and listen to it forever because it was like.
Speaker 1: you know I'm mystifying.
Speaker 1: It's like.
Speaker 1: no the sirens were like hey Odysseus.
Speaker 1: We know everything.
Speaker 1: he's like uh-huh all right, so he's like Rim.
Speaker 1: I know everything uh-huh.
Speaker 1: I'll tell you what dark matter is.
Speaker 0: oh, no.
Speaker 0: I'd swim over there.
Speaker 1: It's like I'll let you play this video game.
Speaker 1: I'll let you play quest for glory.
Speaker 0: But when Cersei warns him about the sirens she basically says I'll tell you what happens in half-life 3.
Speaker 0: She says like like plug your ears if you want to hear it like if you're curious Get your men to tell you up like if.
Speaker 0: but when Odysseus tells his men about the sirens He says she told me I have to listen.
Speaker 0: I Thought that was really really funny That that divide between those two lines I mean that stood out in my head.
Speaker 0: cuz I got to.
Speaker 1: you're a smart.
Speaker 1: cuz if you're a smart person at least You're a curious person, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, Odysseus.
Speaker 1: We're told is the smart person smarter than the other people and there's some evidence of that?
Speaker 1: Yeah, so you know he's curious as hell.
Speaker 0: And also it's smart because if he was like yeah guys I really want to listen to this shit cuz apparently it's awesome.
Speaker 0: But none of you can You know what happened?
Speaker 0: one of his 88 people would have pulled the earplugs out.
Speaker 1: You can't tie everyone to the back to the mask because Who's gonna row the boat?
Speaker 0: and he learned his lesson because all the other times his crew fucked up.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so it was both smart that he did that and really funny that that's how he did it.
Speaker 0: That stood out to me really strongly even though I read that part a long time ago cuz we announced this book club in like March.
Speaker 0: okay so I mean uh Really really like this translation And I really like the story.
Speaker 1: the main thing that you know that I like about it.
Speaker 1: Is that it's just way Easy to read because usually when you have translations of things They're they're all written in a way that makes them difficult to read or you have to read them slowly and carefully.
Speaker 0: I'm just easy to read but more like I Intrinsically got the parts that were funny or the parts that were supposed to be scared.
Speaker 1: I can both breeze through it and not have to read slowly and carefully and also gain a complete understanding of what's happening.
Speaker 1: A lot of the ones are written in sort of fake oldie English.
Speaker 1: You know they're written the way that Shakespeare actually wrote, but fakely right now put in like so these mr..
Speaker 0: Thou mr.
Speaker 1: Thou yeah thousand these and whatever to sound old even though the the Shakespeare was thousands of years after.
Speaker 1: But the difference between current English You know the English that we speak on this podcast and the English of Shakespeare is a spec compared to the difference between Shakespeare's English and Greek Homer.
Speaker 1: so what's the point if you're even if you use fancy old words that they're not any old They're not really as old as Greek, so what's the point right?
Speaker 0: What is the difference between as long as I'll make it so someone can fucking read it like reading a paragraph or a stanza?
Speaker 0: Whatever, and then there's the note.
Speaker 0: That's like Telemachus is being snarky here versus just reading.
Speaker 0: be like a Telemachus Yeah, yeah.
Speaker 0: And like the ghosts were not scary at all in high school like when I read that bit with like ghosts It was just like.
Speaker 0: so what these people just like walk over and talk to him this part.
Speaker 0: It actually was like creepy.
Speaker 1: Yes, like yeah in order to in order to proceed he had to go into hell and back Yeah, and it's like oh shit.
Speaker 1: Where's he going?
Speaker 0: I like that bit a lot cuz he's like Scared, but then he starts to do it, and then he's like really individually see like his graph.
Speaker 1: forget all the details.
Speaker 0: like he sees He sees captain what's-his-name?
Speaker 0: who fell to his death.
Speaker 1: yeah, right like that guy's just like oh, yeah He sees Agamemnon, but Agamemnon runs there later to see the suitors.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, that was funny Agamemnon.
Speaker 1: at the almost at the very end of the book all the suitors are dead and Agamemnon and Achilles are there and isn't someone else there?
Speaker 0: I forget so yet.
Speaker 1: But basically those are the two important ones that are there, and they're like oh all the awesome dudes from Ithaca Why the hell are you dead?
Speaker 1: and they're like we were trying to get with Odysseus' wife because he disappeared.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and they're like they knew Odysseus in life, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah And like half the ghosts are like motherfucking Odysseus.
Speaker 1: Oh my god.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and then they're like you know because they didn't think the suitors are bad Because they weren't paying attention to what was happening in the real world.
Speaker 1: right and then they're like.
Speaker 1: But then Odysseus actually came back and his wife didn't.
Speaker 1: you know like was actually loyal to him and wouldn't get with any of us.
Speaker 1: And Agamemnon's like man, what an awesome wife not like my bitch wife who killed me.
Speaker 0: Yep, Agamemnon is really like.
Speaker 0: his advice to Odysseus is pretty shitty and sexist because he's like yeah Don't let your like don't tell your wife too much Because she might do something to you.
Speaker 0: You know and then but then at the same time.
Speaker 0: He's like the Penelope is pretty smart.
Speaker 0: Yeah My favorite bit of the ghost and we talked about this before the show was that Hercules comes out and he's just like all the other ghosts are like sad and mournful and wistful and Like they're they're very weird.
Speaker 0: and then and like yeah, we're dead and where there's no substance to us anymore And it sucks down here and then Hercules just comes out with a bow and arrow like Like you see Odysseus and all the other ghosts are afraid of his sword, and he's just like.
Speaker 0: I'll fight you Like he comes right out just being badass like yeah, all these other people are dead, but I'm a badass I'm Heracles.
Speaker 0: What do you want?
Speaker 0: Let's go What up?
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know.
Speaker 1: it's also cool that even in whatever BC thousand-something BC sex and violence are still really awesome And people today still really like sex and violence.
Speaker 1: so not much has changed humans.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: But the story does like Many parts of it feel very natural to a modern sensibility if you just translate it with natural modern language Like the like the lying and all the things Odysseus does like.
Speaker 0: a lot of it fits very well with the way we talk act And think today.
Speaker 0: humans back then weren't that different from humans today?
Speaker 1: I mean you can see most basic adventure stories you read today really aren't?
Speaker 1: you know have a lot in common with this, right?
Speaker 1: You know it's like oh, I'm in a tight spot.
Speaker 1: I go on a little journey I get into another tight spot a little journey.
Speaker 1: I have a goal in mind of place I want to get to at the end.
Speaker 1: You know the big bad guys.
Speaker 1: they get there they get their comeuppance everyone's happy.
Speaker 0: the end yep And this is in the forward.
Speaker 0: so I don't really want to go deep into it because you can read the forward if you didn't.
Speaker 0: But I really like how specifically this calls out the slaves everywhere Because that's just that.
Speaker 0: pre like proto-greek society like the Mycenae, you know all the civilizations that disappeared around the see people time Probably built the most entirely on slavery.
Speaker 1: Yeah I mean you know most people they think.
Speaker 1: if you.
Speaker 1: if I say to you ancient Greece most people in their mind immediately Have a picture of like you know Athens with white pillars and buildings everywhere.
Speaker 0: Those pillars were painted the most gaudy paint you can imagine.
Speaker 1: also You know parthenon's right and then lots of dudes and togas walking around right?
Speaker 1: It's like.
Speaker 1: That's what you think immediately.
Speaker 1: But it's like.
Speaker 0: no it was way ancient human times before even feudalism Sparta invaded its neighbors and enslaved them to similarly to how the United States enslaved Africans.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you had a rich dude And then you had a chattel slavery not not all those other forms of slavery from like later greek or roman times.
Speaker 1: You had rich people who mattered in society at least and then a whole bunch of slaves and servants and other subs.
Speaker 0: You know servile peoples below them and even like Circe has nymphs as slaves like.
Speaker 0: they're just slaves Everywhere.
Speaker 0: and you see all these times so dizzy has had so few people with him that even on the trip he's always like.
Speaker 0: so I'll send you three and Take a slave like he'd send slaves along because he didn't have that many people to do stuff for him Mm-hmm, but they're never mentioned in it.
Speaker 0: like the people Until he assigns a slave to like one of his scouting parties.
Speaker 0: at no point is anyone with him described Like until it matters and like oh yeah and some slaves like you wouldn't even know he had slaves with him.
Speaker 1: at the end though They do make they they make like this special note, right?
Speaker 1: It's like okay.
Speaker 1: Well, there's the swine herd who's like the best slave and he's a good person who lets people in his home and treats them Well still a slave.
Speaker 1: He's still a slave but because he's good Odysseus treats him good.
Speaker 1: There's the cow herd also who's good.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean I stayed loyal to Odysseus So he was treated well, and then there's the goat herd who is probably the worst motherfucker.
Speaker 1: The goat herd is worse than the fucking suitors.
Speaker 1: He's just an evil asshole who betrayed Odysseus and tried to help the suitors even though he was Odysseus's slave.
Speaker 1: And it's like all the other like the suitors.
Speaker 1: They just get speared in the head or whatever.
Speaker 1: This is the goat herd man.
Speaker 1: He gets like chopped up into pieces.
Speaker 1: They like chop his nuts off.
Speaker 1: I think it's like He gets it bad and they sort of.
Speaker 1: you know, it's like he deserves it.
Speaker 1: bad because You know, I guess he did a worse thing than what the suitors are doing.
Speaker 0: Yep But those are the bits That are very different compared to a modern sensibility of a story.
Speaker 0: all the stuff around the slaves all the stuff around the Retribution against like the women after and this after the suitors were killed all that stuff Definitely reeks of this very old and messed up age.
Speaker 1: I like how he tells the grandmother the nanny slave grandma.
Speaker 1: He's like, I don't need you to tell me, you know, which women are good and which ones aren't good.
Speaker 1: I'll figure that out myself.
Speaker 1: And then when it actually comes time, he's like, hey granny, which of the ladies should Which ones are gonna get hung outside and which ones are stayed loyal.
Speaker 1: I guess
Speaker 0: it definitely comes out very clearly that Odysseus's primary attribute might not even necessarily be that he's good at lying Or good good at lying and fighting but it's that he spends almost all his effort Controlling what other people think about him and making sure that the story people tell about him is exactly the one he wants them to Tell.
Speaker 0: I mean he gets a bunch of his like.
Speaker 0: he gets his men killed leaving Polyphemus's cave because as soon as he's out of range like as soon as he's on the boat, he turns around.
Speaker 0: He's like yo, guess what?
Speaker 0: My name's Odysseus.
Speaker 0: fucker Like he risks everyone's lives just to make sure someone will remember his story.
Speaker 1: Also, even when he's lying and saying he's not Odysseus.
Speaker 1: He includes Odysseus in his story.
Speaker 1: He's like, yeah, I met this.
Speaker 1: He's like, yeah, my name is so-and-so I you know, and what?
Speaker 1: what's my story?
Speaker 1: I was traveling around that I met this totally awesome dude named Odysseus And he was doing this and then we parted ways and then I ended up here
Speaker 0: You know, and
Speaker 1: now that person who believes that lie may know of Odysseus because he's so famous but also now believes Awesomeness about Odysseus.
Speaker 0: I would actually believe a Specific party lied a lot in is the part where he's recounting all the dead people he met.
Speaker 0: Let's assume that he did go to Hades and some of that is true, which does make sense.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I guess there's no that he could be lying about going to Hades But he's like he.
Speaker 0: I think he learned of what happened to him Agamemnon there in a way that he might not have been able to other like.
Speaker 0: It's possible to argue that he learned things from them that he couldn't have learned otherwise.
Speaker 0: But I would read that even if he literally did the Hades thing and literally met some of those people that he lied about most of them because it goes from like My mom like specific people who he learned something important.
Speaker 0: and then it's just like he name-drops fucking Everyone in all of Greek history, it's like oh, yeah and Hercules was there and Agamemnon was there.
Speaker 1: the thing is it's like I'm the one.
Speaker 1: usually what happens in a lot of stories a common trope is There'll be fantastical elements.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right and those fantastical elements It's like oh that was actually that none of that literally happened.
Speaker 1: that was just shown.
Speaker 1: You know, you thought it was literally happening, but actually it was in a dream or an imagination.
Speaker 0: Example of that Kill Bill the Crazy 88 at the end of Kill Bill like there's this crazy fight scene.
Speaker 0: It's like the climax of the movie the second movie.
Speaker 0: when the crazy 88 comes up and someone tells the story They make it very clear.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there weren't actually 88 of them.
Speaker 1: Well, there weren't 88 of them in the movie But you know there was a crazy fight.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the crazy 88 but that line if there weren't 88 of them in the way It's.
Speaker 1: they just thought it was cool to call them.
Speaker 1: But anyway, but now but the way that is more like, you know Utena where there's like there's an explanation for the supernatural parts that they do not real.
Speaker 1: Yeah, even though you see you think the whole time you're reading the story is supernatural parts are real and then they're not actually real.
Speaker 1: Right, they were just made.
Speaker 1: you believe they were real but actually no in the Odyssey The supernatural parts are within the world of the Odyssey real.
Speaker 1: bringing Zeus is making Thunder.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like.
Speaker 1: so there's no reason to question the Hades part or The Cersei turning people into pigs part or the goddess and the island of
Speaker 0: Question that based
Speaker 1: on this based on their supernatural
Speaker 0: oh, yeah, but based on the the Shorter they caught the giant name-dropping that happens after the important ones Really feels like you just throw it in right bunch of more stuff to keep the cuz.
Speaker 0: he's got the.
Speaker 1: he's basically got all The important people on this island listening to his story, but you what I'm saying is that you could easily Modify the Odyssey so slightly To where you could be like.
Speaker 1: well all the soup most of the supernatural stuff happens on that the one chapter of adventure After the war right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's most of the supernatural stuff is there.
Speaker 1: You could retell the Odyssey in such a way to where nothing supernatural at all happens outside of that one part.
Speaker 1: and Yes, Odysseus actually is lying about all the supernatural thing.
Speaker 1: else, you know, and that would be kind of a cool You know way to think about it.
Speaker 1: That's not what happens in this.
Speaker 1: Nope, you know the real one.
Speaker 0: But I think you could even tell the story and I never considered this possibility until I read this translation.
Speaker 0: You even tell the story of he might not have even made it to the fucking Trojan War.
Speaker 0: He might have gone to this war bailed Had trouble ended up on this island and then just tells this giant story gets these people to give him much elude and then goes Home and fucks up the suitors.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm Like you could you could think that you could argue that the entire middle was a lie.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm But I really enjoyed it and I want to read pretty much anything that Emily Wilson translates at this point.
Speaker 1: What is she gonna translate that?
Speaker 1: so there's the the Iliad which comes before the Odyssey?
Speaker 1: Which is the actual story of the Trojan War.
Speaker 1: there's the law there's a Kelly's and Agamemnon and everybody.
Speaker 0: There's supposedly some sequel at the.
Speaker 0: tell us something that is it's the sequel to the Odyssey.
Speaker 0: That was written way later than the Odyssey but way Ancient still like still really a really old story, but supposedly it's lost Uh-huh.
Speaker 1: It is cool that like even in this ancient ancient times a thousand years before, you know actual Greece there was like You know like sequels, right?
Speaker 1: It's like, you know, it's like they keep bringing up Achilles and all this stuff and it's like Yeah, that was from a different book.
Speaker 1: It's like it's like they're expecting you and they tell it when you're reading the Odyssey.
Speaker 1: It's sort of assumed, you know, what happened in the Iliad, right?
Speaker 1: It's like oh there's Agamemnon and there's Menelaus and Helen and everything.
Speaker 1: and it's like, you know, you're supposed to know Yeah, it doesn't tell you who Achilles is.
Speaker 0: it assumes, you know, yeah I mean it was just like yeah, no kill I saw Achilles and it was like yeah Achilles.
Speaker 0: Oh man Fist bump.
Speaker 0: It's like you're supposed to know I just can't get over Heracles coming out of Hades Just like wit armed and ready to fight and just like yeah, I was in hell no big deal All right, so I guess we're done here, okay What's?
Speaker 0: uh, have you thought about what the next book will be?
Speaker 1: cuz I got I got some ideas All right.
Speaker 0: I won't hold you to it now.
Speaker 0: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Speaker 1: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 0: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 0: But unlike those other late shows It's actually recorded at night and the patreon patrons for this episode of geek nights are in an order that is relative to the amount of money they pledge to us on a monthly basis.
Speaker 0: and Stay tuned because we're gonna do some Q&A's and all that fancy Patreon specific stuff that we were doing before we got too busy with some obligations that we are now mostly free of.
Speaker 0: Ah The list is as I continue to stall for time while I open the tab Craig Oliver, Alan Joyce, Rebecca Dunn, Heidi McNicholas, Shimmering Ruby Obelisk, Hanging in the Sky, Kjartavishan, MyStady.com, Jeremy Minor, Link Kije, Scootalonely, Roberto Kingsley, Kelly Snyder, Cold Guy Amanda Duchat, Sean Yeager, Matthew Smith, Nicholas Brando, Mr.
Speaker 0: Strong Strachan, 421 Creations, Chris Reimer and Thomas Hahn, Sherman Von Harl, Rory and James David White Rochelle Montanona, Superboy, Trip Wire, Sailor Vista, Don Jelik, Jojo Joestar, Clinton Walton, Ren from New Zealand, Ryan Perrin, Drew Openlander, Finn, Chris Midgiff, Daniel Redmond, Sean Klein, Chris Reimer And Thomas Hahn.
Speaker 0: And now I leave you with something that might haunt your dreams.
Speaker 1: I sail to Troy with the Navy.
Speaker 1: I taste great with spuds and gravy.
Speaker 1: I command all of the archives.
Speaker 1: Roast me up at gas mark five.
Speaker 1: All Achaeans, bow to me.
Speaker 1: I am great with rosemary.
Speaker 1: I command bad killer Achilles.
Speaker 0: Why not have me with some peas?
Speaker 1: I spill entrails of our Trojan foe.
Speaker 1: I'm nice with garlic, don't you know?
Speaker 1: I command bad killer Achilles.
Speaker 1: Why not have me with some peas?
Speaker 1: I'm nice with garlic, don't you know?
Speaker 1: I command bad killer Achilles.
Speaker 1: Why not have me with some peas?