Speaker 1: I need something that's risk-free.
Speaker 0: It's Tuesday, January 30th, 2018.
Speaker 0: I'm Rym.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott.
Speaker 0: And this is Geek Nights Tonight.
Speaker 0: We're talking about the adorable Ratineer.
Speaker 1: Yar.
Speaker 0: Yar.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: It's been a while since we've done a Tuesday show, because we've been out of town and busy.
Speaker 1: It's been a while since we did any show.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but Tuesdays are the easiest shows to do, because we actually do play a lot of games.
Speaker 0: Almost every convention we go to is a gaming con.
Speaker 1: Well, because you only do two shows a month of gaming, assuming we don't bail.
Speaker 1: And when you go to one convention, you're playing like ten board games.
Speaker 1: So that's getting you five months, which definitely carries you to the next convention.
Speaker 1: And that's just board games, not any other games.
Speaker 0: All the non-Geek Nights stuff we do, it's like 80% gaming right now.
Speaker 1: It's also really easy to find gaming news.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that is true.
Speaker 0: And it's also really easy to make gaming news by just reviewing something briefly.
Speaker 0: Anyway, we're back.
Speaker 0: It's a Tuesday show.
Speaker 0: If you saw us at MAGFest or PAX Unplugged, and you wondered why we were talking about anime or neckbeards or whatever, tonight's your night.
Speaker 0: We're actually talking about games.
Speaker 0: It's every other Tuesday we do this.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So right off the bat, we got some news.
Speaker 0: If you might know, in fact, one of our more popular YouTube videos is us teaching a bunch of people how to play Tigris.
Speaker 1: Hey, you're stealing my news.
Speaker 0: And Euphrates, I'm introducing your news, like the MC.
Speaker 1: Okay, yeah.
Speaker 0: Tigris and Euphrates is literally our favorite board game.
Speaker 0: And I don't say that lightly.
Speaker 1: At Panguicon 2.0, in ancient times, there were many legendary things that occurred there.
Speaker 0: We met Steve Jackson.
Speaker 1: One of the legendary things that happened was we went into a room of board games, which we discovered too late into the convention, and there were some employees from then-thriving Mayfair games, and they had this game, T&E, which I had vaguely heard of.
Speaker 0: That they had just published in the U.S No, it had just published.
Speaker 0: Remember, the tiles we were playing with were mixed in German and U.S.
Speaker 0: tiles because they didn't have enough pieces.
Speaker 1: The game had been in the U.S.
Speaker 1: for a while.
Speaker 0: But they had just done a printing of it, and it was a different-sized tile.
Speaker 0: The
Speaker 1: point was that I
Speaker 0: had heard of this
Speaker 1: game, and they taught us how to play, and we played, and we were like,
Speaker 1: "Whoa."
Speaker 1: And then we bought it, and then we proceeded to play it many, many, many, many times, and to this day, there are games that we play at a PAX, and before the PAX is over, we're done with it.
Speaker 1: T&E, a game that we have played perhaps as long as most games that we played, tabletop-wise, and still play it, and we are not done with it.
Speaker 0: Even three-player Puerto Rico ran out of plays, but T&E did not.
Speaker 0: So, what's your news, Scott?
Speaker 0: Why am I talking about Tigris and Euphrates?
Speaker 0: Well, Dr.
Speaker 1: K, Rainer Canizia, the creator of, not Puerto Rico, T&E.
Speaker 0: I've never heard anyone call him Dr.
Speaker 0: K before.
Speaker 1: I've been calling him Dr.
Speaker 1: K all the time.
Speaker 0: I've never heard you do that, but I'm gonna also start doing that, 'cause I like that.
Speaker 1: I decided to do it on my own.
Speaker 1: I never heard anyone else do it, and I just kept doing it.
Speaker 1: I don't know if that'll make him mad, but if it does, oh, well.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna be your first follow.
Speaker 1: Yeah, okay.
Speaker 1: But anyway, so Rainer Canizia, also known as Dr.
Speaker 1: K, and not the one who helps you kill yourself.
Speaker 1: Not that Dr.
Speaker 1: K.
Speaker 0: Not Dr.
Speaker 0: Dre.
Speaker 1: No, he is a man who has prolifically made a bunch of amazing board games, including T&E, and he has announced and put out the pictures and press release and the rule book for a as-yet unpublished game called Yellow and Yangtze.
Speaker 0: You might recognize those as being the names of rivers.
Speaker 1: In a different part of the world than the Tigris and the Afraidys, and basically this game is T&E with hexes instead of squares.
Speaker 0: Oh, my God.
Speaker 1: And also rules modifications to accommodate the hexes instead of squares.
Speaker 0: I cannot stress to you how much the news that this is T&E with hexes matters to people like me, Scott, and our friend Pete, and our friend Alex.
Speaker 1: Like, the fact that this would come out so many years after T&E, that would be like if Nintendo put out like, you know, well, I guess Nintendo does do that, the F-Zero, and then wait 20 years and then another F-Zero.
Speaker 1: -Yeah.
Speaker 1: -That's what this is.
Speaker 0: But that doesn't happen with the things we care about usually.
Speaker 1: No, but, yeah, well, we care about F-Zeros.
Speaker 1: -Eh.
Speaker 1: -Anyway, so, yeah, this is gonna get, like, insta-bought and played a zillion times.
Speaker 0: So, what we're thinking about doing is T&E is a game that we, you know, we love it, we know it inside out, we're kind of obsessed with it.
Speaker 0: I'm really curious what it'll be like with hexes, because if you've played any game, it doesn't matter what kind of game it is, doesn't matter what the rules are in almost any capacity, changing between hexes, triangle grids, which you don't really use anymore, or squares, has profound impacts in ways that you might not realize.
Speaker 0: I'm really curious what the game of T&E is like with hexes.
Speaker 0: And I imagine that it is okay at minimum, because otherwise Dr.
Speaker 0: K would not have done this to us.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: I wonder if it would work with triangles.
Speaker 1: -You and your stupid triangles.
Speaker 0: -I like the triangle grid.
Speaker 1: For anyone who's not nerdy enough to realize, the hex map, it's like, why doesn't everyone use a square map?
Speaker 1: Well, the reason the hex map is the best map for all gaming is because each space is equally distant from any other space.
Speaker 1: You move to any adjacent space, and you are moving the same distance, right?
Speaker 1: On a square map, if you move to say, you can only move four directions.
Speaker 1: If you try to move diagonally, you're actually moving a different distance because of the Pythagorean theorem, right?
Speaker 1: If you have a triangle map also, moving one space is not always the same unit of distance.
Speaker 1: On a hex map, moving one adjacent space always moves you the same distance in space, and so all movements are equal.
Speaker 1: On a hex map, a hex map is the perfect and best map for all games, which require movement of dudes around on the map.
Speaker 0: However, hex maps have some-- Well, one, there's no movement in T&E.
Speaker 1: That's what I didn't say, but just saying, for games that require movement, say Battletech--.
Speaker 0: Also, you, by saying that it is the best way to deal with movement, you are really discounting the triangle grid.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I am discounting your stupid triangle grid.
Speaker 0: Triangle grids have a time and a place.
Speaker 1: No, they don't.
Speaker 1: You're just obsessed with triangle grids lately because you've realized that orthogonal and diagonal are part of them.
Speaker 1: And that's how you do, is you get obsessed with a thing, and then that's a thing for you, regardless of merit.
Speaker 0: The problem with hexes is that the definition of diagonal is crazy, but more importantly, hexes mean that there are six things directly adjacent to any other thing, as opposed to squares, where if you're doing orthogonal adjacency, there's only four things.
Speaker 0: That is a big deal for many things.
Speaker 0: That is a big deal for Tiggers and Euphrates.
Speaker 1: You know what we should do?
Speaker 0: That changes everything.
Speaker 1: You know what we should do, Rym?
Speaker 0: What should we do?
Speaker 1: We should just make hex carcass sound.
Speaker 0: I don't think it would be good.
Speaker 1: I want to play.
Speaker 0: I don't think hex carcass sound would be good.
Speaker 1: Surround that fucking, what's it called?
Speaker 1: It's going to be way easier.
Speaker 0: The cathedral?
Speaker 1: Yeah, the whatever.
Speaker 1: No, not the cathedral, the other one.
Speaker 0: What other one?
Speaker 1: The one where when it surrounds you take your guy off.
Speaker 0: Anything?
Speaker 1: No, the, you know.
Speaker 0: The cloister?
Speaker 1: Yeah, that one.
Speaker 0: We just did a panel where we taught people this game.
Speaker 0: The thing where you surround the thing.
Speaker 0: Remember though, factory fun squares was great and hexes is apparently awful.
Speaker 1: That's true.
Speaker 0: Everyone said, I haven't played it, but everyone I know who has played the new factory fun with hexes has said that it is not fun.
Speaker 1: I agree.
Speaker 0: So I think what we might do is, this is an idea I had and people seem into it.
Speaker 0: I feel like we should try to do a, we just did our judge anime by its cover again.
Speaker 0: I kind of want to try to read the rules to this T and E version too.
Speaker 1: They're up there.
Speaker 1: Read them.
Speaker 1: Their PDF is right there.
Speaker 0: And then do a show where we try to review it before we play it and then review it after we play it and see how right we were.
Speaker 0: I really want to see if we are able to figure out how the game really is based on the rules alone and our deep knowledge of T and E.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but that's not an objective thing because in your preview where you just read the rules, you could cement judgments in your mind and then hold firm in those beliefs regardless of what actually occurs during the game.
Speaker 0: Is that one not an argument we could make for our judge anime by its cover?
Speaker 1: I mean it happens to scientists doing real legit research too, so it's unavoidable.
Speaker 0: But two, other people may play the game and then listen to both of our reviews and both notice the differences and be able to have an opinion on which of the reviews is more accurate to their experience.
Speaker 1: Whatever.
Speaker 0: We're the test subjects.
Speaker 0: We're not the test doors.
Speaker 1: The point is this game becoming is a big deal for us.
Speaker 1: I don't know if it's a big deal for you, but I mean you're listening to Geek Nights.
Speaker 0: I feel like the first comment in the board game Geek Thread you linked me to is, "I really wonder how the T and E diehards will feel about this
Speaker 0: one.".
Speaker 1: Is that a Geek Nights listener?
Speaker 0: I assume so.
Speaker 0: It's Dr.
Speaker 0: J over here.
Speaker 1: One before Dr.
Speaker 1: K. You got one up on him.
Speaker 0: So in the other news...
Speaker 1: He knows how to slam dunk Dr.
Speaker 1: J.
Speaker 0: I got a brief Geek Bite for you because I did finally just... The only reason I didn't own any VR up until now is that I didn't have time.
Speaker 1: The only reason I didn't own any VR up until now is because it's a ginormous thing.
Speaker 1: you got to slap to your head.
Speaker 0: See, I don't know why it's not that enormous.
Speaker 0: It actually works great.
Speaker 1: I'm not down with the VR until it's like cool sunglasses or a jacket that goes into my neck or something like that.
Speaker 0: I don't think you'll ever experience VR in your life then.
Speaker 1: I think we're good.
Speaker 1: I think we will definitely make it.
Speaker 0: We'll see.
Speaker 0: Material science is a limitation.
Speaker 0: But anyway, I would say having an Oculus and having fucked around with it a bunch now that I finally have time...
Speaker 1: Material science is a limitation.
Speaker 1: Let me show you telephones from earlier in my life compared to telephones now.
Speaker 0: Yeah, telephones are still a physical thing I got to carry around.
Speaker 1: They're way small.
Speaker 0: They're not just in me.
Speaker 0: Also, they're getting bigger.
Speaker 1: They're not that small anymore.
Speaker 0: They could be smaller.
Speaker 1: They're getting worse.
Speaker 1: We have the power to make them small.
Speaker 0: But we choose not to.
Speaker 1: They're still way smaller than a VR headset.
Speaker 0: So I would say if you do not have a modern hot shit gaming PC, it is not worth it to get one just to get VR.
Speaker 0: But if you already have a gaming PC that is capable...
Speaker 1: And a bunch of extra money to burn and nothing better to do...
Speaker 0: Then the extra money it takes to have full motion tracking VR, pretty minuscule compared to what you paid for that PC.
Speaker 0: The whole Oculus thing costs less than a third of what a 1080 will cost you today thanks to the coin miners.
Speaker 0: But what I want to geek by here is a game... Because a lot of people talk about what the must play games are if you get VR.
Speaker 1: There's not too many of them, at least not yet.
Speaker 0: There's probably 10 or fewer must play VR games right now.
Speaker 0: The bomb defusing one.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: The job simulating one.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the Rick and Morty one is actually like...
Speaker 1: I've heard good things about that one.
Speaker 0: The Rick and Morty one is fantastic.
Speaker 0: It might be the second best VR game there is.
Speaker 1: The robot shooty one.
Speaker 0: Robo Recall startled me to the point that I ran into the wall.
Speaker 0: But I would say that the top of those is Superhot VR.
Speaker 1: The bad guys only move when you move.
Speaker 0: So Superhot is an FPS.
Speaker 0: where the shtick is, nothing moves except when you're moving.
Speaker 1: So if you stop moving, the game is paused.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: So if you play this game, basically you just take your mouse, hands off the keyboard and mouse and you look around and you think, all right, I got to kill that guy next.
Speaker 1: How am I going to move?
Speaker 1: And you move real carefully and then headshot him.
Speaker 1: But meanwhile, as you're doing that, all the other bad guys are coming or perhaps even shooting.
Speaker 1: And he's like, well, I see a bullet coming at me.
Speaker 1: I got to move this way.
Speaker 1: And it's almost like a real time, a turn based game.
Speaker 1: But you sort of control the clock, but it only goes forward.
Speaker 1: And it's a really, really good concept.
Speaker 0: It's a really good concept and it's really fun.
Speaker 0: But Superhot VR is not just.
Speaker 0: we made a VR version of Superhot because the reality is very few games can just be turned into a VR version of the game.
Speaker 0: And games that try, people who try to do this tend to make really bad experiences.
Speaker 1: Well, any FPS is much easier to do because it's FP because pretty much VR has to be FP.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you'd think that.
Speaker 0: But there's a lot of surprising problems that make that not feasible.
Speaker 1: I'm saying you want to make games in VR first person.
Speaker 1: We really would have a third person view.
Speaker 0: Actually, some of the must play games are these third person games.
Speaker 0: They work great.
Speaker 1: What, like Mario?
Speaker 0: Like Lucky's Tale or whatever.
Speaker 0: How does that work?
Speaker 0: Just third person.
Speaker 0: You just got to see it, like play it.
Speaker 0: And you're like, oh, I get it.
Speaker 0: And it's hard to explain the experience.
Speaker 1: But anyway, are you poking Lucky in the ass to make a move?
Speaker 1: You're actually not lucky.
Speaker 0: Poking him in the ass is probably a yet another game.
Speaker 0: Because one thing I will say, poking around the indie VR experiences.
Speaker 1: Lots of porn?
Speaker 0: Not really.
Speaker 0: They're not porn.
Speaker 1: Porn adjacent?
Speaker 0: They are porn adjacent.
Speaker 0: They are porn for certain people and not porn for other people.
Speaker 0: They are like a wife who comes and like stands next to you the game.
Speaker 0: But Super Odd VR is its own experience.
Speaker 0: And to geek bite it, having played it, it is a peak gaming experience.
Speaker 0: Everything everyone has said about it is 100% accurate.
Speaker 0: This game, it's really short.
Speaker 0: It's a very curated experience.
Speaker 0: You can beat the whole thing in under an hour.
Speaker 0: It is the best experience I have had in VR.
Speaker 0: hands down, bar none, no exceptions.
Speaker 0: And it is an amazing game.
Speaker 0: I'm not saying that if you don't want VR, that you should buy VR to play this game.
Speaker 0: But if you have a VR headset, you're doing yourself a grave disservice not playing this game.
Speaker 0: It is intense.
Speaker 0: And the deal is, it's just like the concept we talked about.
Speaker 0: Everything is frozen and as you move, the game moves.
Speaker 0: Turning your head counts as movement.
Speaker 0: So you're basically Neo in the Matrix like you shoot a guy in the face with a shotgun.
Speaker 0: You drop it and you slowly raise your hand up and catch the gun that he dropped out of the air and turn around in bullet time dodging bullets and shoot another guy in the face.
Speaker 0: It's also a very high concept because it starts you in a room and in the game you put on a VR helmet and play super hot and then you take the VR helmet off and do other stuff.
Speaker 0: It's just abstract and beautiful and crazy and it is the example of what to strive for in making a VR game.
Speaker 0: I cannot stress enough how fantastic this game is.
Speaker 0: My only warning to you is that it is quite intense and the scariest thing that will ever happen is just someone knocking on a door.
Speaker 0: So what do you got?
Speaker 0: You got anything else?
Speaker 0: Other than the fact that we were at PAX.
Speaker 1: I had my news which is that there's a new game coming out.
Speaker 1: And MagFest.
Speaker 1: You didn't even have a news.
Speaker 0: That was my news, the Geek Bite.
Speaker 1: I thought you said there's so much gaming news.
Speaker 0: There is and I didn't want to waste all our time talking about all this gaming news.
Speaker 0: We could talk about how the Overwatch League has had already two separate instances of high profile sexism.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's got problems.
Speaker 0: And also the fact that I watch the games and I enjoy them.
Speaker 1: I only watch New York vs.
Speaker 1: Philly and it's like even as someone who's never played Overwatch, it's like, "Oh, alright, it's
Speaker 1: okay.".
Speaker 0: But I literally do not care who wins any game.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like I wanted to root for New York but it's like there's no connection between that team and New York whatsoever.
Speaker 0: The New York team has so little tie to New York that if you change the names of all the teams, so they were officially from different cities, I don't think anyone would notice.
Speaker 1: They don't play in New York.
Speaker 0: They don't play in New York.
Speaker 0: They're not from New York.
Speaker 1: I mean, their name is Excelsior which is New York-ish because of the New York State motto.
Speaker 0: There's only two kinds of people who recognize that word.
Speaker 0: People who care a lot about New York State and comics fans.
Speaker 1: People who like Stan Lee.
Speaker 0: Yeah, no one else even thinks about that word and that word means nothing to them.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like, "Uh,
Speaker 1: alright.".
Speaker 1: The logo doesn't even look good.
Speaker 1: It doesn't make me want to buy their merch.
Speaker 0: The token effort of having like a physical place somewhere in New York doesn't even have to be a good place.
Speaker 1: I'm pretty sure all these games are played at the Blizzard Arena in LA.
Speaker 0: They need a place in New York where they sell tickets for people to physically sit and watch the game on a screen.
Speaker 1: They do at the LA.
Speaker 0: Yeah, yeah.
Speaker 1: At the Blizzard Arena.
Speaker 0: The teams are just so interchangeable that I can't care about them.
Speaker 0: Despite being a crazy fan of both Overwatch competitively and playing Overwatch.
Speaker 1: They came so close.
Speaker 1: And the other thing is that Overwatch is such a fast game to watch.
Speaker 1: And they keep the camera work.
Speaker 1: They keep switching between characters.
Speaker 0: They don't do it well.
Speaker 1: Constantly.
Speaker 1: It's not the greatest spectator experience.
Speaker 1: I feel like they should just use a zoom.
Speaker 1: They should never use the first person view ever.
Speaker 1: You don't have a first person view when you're watching NFL.
Speaker 1: Just give me the all 22 the whole time.
Speaker 0: You know what I would do actually?
Speaker 1: I guess in this case the all 10.
Speaker 0: If I were the production manager for esports like Overwatch.
Speaker 0: I would always make sure that there are two different feeds for every game.
Speaker 0: that's our real game.
Speaker 0: There'd be the normal spectator view that has a certain kind of commentary.
Speaker 0: And it's that high level never first person zoomed out curated view.
Speaker 0: And then I'd have a separate stream.
Speaker 0: that is are you a serious Overwatch player?
Speaker 0: Here's your crazy bullshit.
Speaker 0: Here's the zoomed in view that you want.
Speaker 1: I don't know why we don't have more like a user control of the cameras during esports.
Speaker 1: Because if you look at say Hearthstone.
Speaker 1: When you watch Hearthstone on Twitch everyone's using these plugins now.
Speaker 1: All the streamers.
Speaker 1: And the plugins allow you to like move your mouse over the deck to see how many cards are left.
Speaker 1: Or hover your mouse over a card to see what the text is.
Speaker 0: Dude old FPS tournaments in the old as days before modern esports.
Speaker 0: The spectator mode was you join a game like a tournament.
Speaker 0: They still have that.
Speaker 0: Yeah but you join it as a spectator and that was the primary way you'd watch.
Speaker 0: You just move around and watch whatever you wanted to watch.
Speaker 0: So there's actually.
Speaker 1: this is gonna be my other news.
Speaker 1: But I guess we got.
Speaker 1: we got to it right.
Speaker 1: So this crazy thing happened.
Speaker 1: Where the I forget is it Dota I think.
Speaker 1: Or was it Dota or was it LoL?
Speaker 1: I forget but basically.
Speaker 0: Doesn't matter.
Speaker 1: I think it's.
Speaker 1: I think it's Dota.
Speaker 1: And the oh right I know what it is.
Speaker 1: Okay so ESL the European esports right group right.
Speaker 1: They made an exclusive agreement to stream on facebook.
Speaker 1: only right.
Speaker 1: So the official ESL dota championship was streamed on facebook.
Speaker 1: And if you were to restream that on twitch they would shut you down for copyright infringement.
Speaker 1: Because you're like restreaming this you know broadcast that you don't have expressed written consent.
Speaker 0: You had only implied oral consent.
Speaker 1: You had no consent whatsoever.
Speaker 1: Right well you know what some people did.
Speaker 1: What some people did is they used dota TV which is sort of like half-life TV.
Speaker 1: They basically spectated the pros in dota on their computer.
Speaker 1: And broadcasted that on twitch with their own commentary and their own camera.
Speaker 1: work right.
Speaker 1: Basically it'd be like if I was at the NFL game with my own camera making my own TV channel.
Speaker 1: According to valve.
Speaker 1: that is a-okay you can totally do that.
Speaker 1: And that doesn't violate.
Speaker 1: you know the only one who can stop you from doing.
Speaker 1: that is valve.
Speaker 1: But ESL was trying to shut people down on twitch for doing that.
Speaker 1: They weren't rebroadcasting ESL stuff.
Speaker 1: And valve and ESL are now butting the heads and this is really awesome.
Speaker 0: Now my opinion and fascinating.
Speaker 0: ESL independent of any like what the actual legal arguments will be.
Speaker 0: Is making a big goddamn mistake by trying to do this kind of nonsense.
Speaker 0: That is not the way to monetize your esports.
Speaker 0: Because you cannot treat that aspect of it like traditional sports.
Speaker 0: Because there is no culture in watching baseball of recreating the baseball games and then streaming that.
Speaker 1: I think another thing is that you know you look at TV sports right.
Speaker 1: If you sign an exclusive TV agreement for a sport.
Speaker 1: So now your favorite team is on this channel instead of that channel.
Speaker 1: right.
Speaker 1: The only real difference is the announcers.
Speaker 1: And it's like oh you lost the announcer you liked and now you got a shitty one.
Speaker 1: Or maybe you get a better one.
Speaker 1: That's the only real difference right.
Speaker 1: You don't care if your football game is on CBS or Fox that much.
Speaker 1: Because they're all shitty announcers.
Speaker 0: Except for like two right.
Speaker 0: There is not a culture in those sports of doing streaming.
Speaker 0: Esports right.
Speaker 1: No but what I said but here in esports right.
Speaker 1: Facebook watching on Facebook is very different than watching on YouTube.
Speaker 1: They're very different than watching on Twitch.
Speaker 1: The actual channel it's on matters a lot.
Speaker 1: So when Facebook wants to get some gaming content on their streaming site.
Speaker 1: So they make these deals and they pay ESL to bring the games exclusively to Facebook right.
Speaker 1: That's basically like well this games on a shitty channel that's worthless to watch on.
Speaker 1: And now people are gonna watch these other people instead.
Speaker 1: Who are broadcasting their own broadcast competing with the official one.
Speaker 0: I just I wonder who makes these kinds of decisions like do they not.
Speaker 1: Facebook paid ESL a bunch of money and ESL said wow we could really use that bunch of money.
Speaker 1: Okay sure we don't give a fuck.
Speaker 0: But no one involved on either side thought for a minute of wait.
Speaker 0: is this gonna work?
Speaker 1: I mean ESL I think probably realized but I mean like.
Speaker 1: well it'll stream.
Speaker 1: who cares.
Speaker 1: And Facebook I guess you know has so much money and they're stupid.
Speaker 0: Yeah I feel like companies like Facebook are going to vastly mishandle this.
Speaker 0: In a way that.
Speaker 1: They already mishandled.
Speaker 0: Yeah I feel like they're gonna continue to mishandle it.
Speaker 1: But yeah this is a fascinating story here and there's more to come in this arena.
Speaker 1: I'm watching it closely.
Speaker 0: But anyway things of the day.
Speaker 0: What do you got?
Speaker 1: What did I have?
Speaker 1: I forget.
Speaker 0: Getting Over It?
Speaker 1: Yeah so this is a game called Getting Over It.
Speaker 0: Which I literally had never heard of.
Speaker 1: Raymond never heard of this even though it's a big deal and everyone's raving about it lately.
Speaker 1: Anyway so.
Speaker 0: I just never encountered it.
Speaker 1: You may have if you haven't if you don't know exactly what I'm talking about already.
Speaker 1: You may have seen a game where there is a man or some sort of human inside of a cauldron with their torso sticking out.
Speaker 1: And they have a sledgehammer and they wield this sledgehammer to climb.
Speaker 1: And they basically poke the sledgehammer down to push themselves up.
Speaker 1: Swing it around to grab onto things.
Speaker 0: It's quap crossed with mount your friends.
Speaker 1: That's basically what it is.
Speaker 1: It's climbing quap.
Speaker 1: It has real as the controls are as awful as you think they are by looking at it right.
Speaker 1: And you can get used to it though if you played a bunch.
Speaker 1: And this game has been all the rage lately.
Speaker 1: There have been a lot of videos of it.
Speaker 1: The game has a few jump scares.
Speaker 1: So there was some great video going around of people getting freaked out by the jump scares.
Speaker 1: And then falling all the way down.
Speaker 1: So yeah it's a pretty good game.
Speaker 1: I'm not playing it because I feel like watching the video.
Speaker 1: I got all I need to get out of it.
Speaker 1: And it's not worth my time.
Speaker 1: But I still applaud this game.
Speaker 1: Good job.
Speaker 1: Nice design.
Speaker 1: Nice.
Speaker 1: You know very clever.
Speaker 1: Very funny.
Speaker 1: You know.
Speaker 1: Good job you.
Speaker 1: Anyway here is my thing of the day which is somebody getting the world record time for beating this game.
Speaker 1: Which is basically like a few minutes.
Speaker 1: And you can see the whole game really really quick.
Speaker 1: This person is like a master.
Speaker 1: They practiced so much.
Speaker 1: Oh my God.
Speaker 1: And then they uninstalled the game right after they got this world record.
Speaker 1: And I'm pretty sure it is still the world record for beating this game.
Speaker 1: Good job.
Speaker 1: I clap for you.
Speaker 0: That is amazing.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So yeah if you somehow are like rim and have been living under a rock and haven't seen the game called Getting Over It.
Speaker 1: Here you go.
Speaker 0: I don't know how I missed this.
Speaker 0: It's just my social media feed.
Speaker 1: I imagine most of you have seen it.
Speaker 0: And somehow in my social media feed literally no one has mentioned this game.
Speaker 1: It's been around for a while.
Speaker 0: Oh yeah.
Speaker 0: It just never came up in my social media.
Speaker 0: Alright.
Speaker 0: So when I was a kid at Cedar Point.
Speaker 0: There was a roller coaster that I rode.
Speaker 0: And it was called Avalanche Run.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 0: Didn't have rails.
Speaker 0: It was like a toboggan run.
Speaker 1: Like half pipes.
Speaker 0: No.
Speaker 1: So like a bobsled but instead of ice just wood?
Speaker 0: Basically yeah it was a roller coaster bobsled.
Speaker 1: How did the friction?
Speaker 1: not like just start a fire or something?
Speaker 0: I mean it worked fine.
Speaker 1: Was it like a fiberglass tube or something?
Speaker 0: Yeah this video will actually get into detail on all that.
Speaker 1: I imagine the friction would like wear away the thing you're sitting in right?
Speaker 1: Like one of the two surfaces.
Speaker 1: either the track or the thing you're in the vehicle are gonna like erode right?
Speaker 0: That would end up being fine.
Speaker 1: Scratching against each other?
Speaker 0: But anyway.
Speaker 0: The ride was not popular because it actually just wasn't that good.
Speaker 1: I imagine that would not be a smooth ride.
Speaker 0: No it was smooth.
Speaker 0: It just wasn't that scary or fun.
Speaker 0: Like it was a pretty sweet milk toast roller coaster.
Speaker 1: Maybe that's why the friction didn't start fires.
Speaker 0: So.
Speaker 0: They.
Speaker 0: This coincided.
Speaker 0: When they decided this roller coaster wasn't actually that popular or doing that well.
Speaker 0: With Star Tours.
Speaker 1: In Disney.
Speaker 1: Oh the one where.
Speaker 1: I've done Star Tours.
Speaker 1: Star Tours is a Star Wars ride.
Speaker 1: It used to be the only Star Wars ride in Disney.
Speaker 1: But now they're building a Star Wars land around it I guess.
Speaker 0: I'm pretty sure Star Tours is gone.
Speaker 1: Is it?
Speaker 0: I'm pretty sure it was gone a long time ago.
Speaker 1: Oh I've ridden it many times.
Speaker 1: Oh yeah as a kid.
Speaker 0: I probably rode it like eight times in a row.
Speaker 1: You go and you sit in what appears to be a Star Wars vehicle.
Speaker 1: They close the door and there's a screen in the front.
Speaker 1: Yes Scott it closed eight years ago.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: I've ridden it many times thankfully.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: And you get a video of C3P and R2D2 doing something and the thing moves around but it doesn't move forward or back.
Speaker 1: it just sort of moves in place and makes you feel like you're moving.
Speaker 1: and they have improved on that not moving ride technology much since the time of Star Tours.
Speaker 0: Oh the newest Harry Potter equivalent of that is pretty fucking crazy.
Speaker 1: Even the Spiderman one I went on in the late 90s early 2000s or whatever that one was is way way way beyond Star Tours.
Speaker 1: Star Tours and it's like back to the future ride level of you know action.
Speaker 0: This video is basically a really deep dive into what Cedar Point did with that roller coaster?
Speaker 0: because what they did I mentioned this on Geeknet a long time ago they built a building around the roller coaster and they made it a themed Star Tours like experience.
Speaker 1: With no Star Wars.
Speaker 0: With a Disney style lot.
Speaker 0: yeah no Star Wars.
Speaker 1: Did they use Snoopy?
Speaker 1: because it's a Snoopy park.
Speaker 0: It wasn't Snoopy park.
Speaker 0: then it became Snoopy park relatively recently.
Speaker 1: I thought it is.
Speaker 1: I thought it's no longer Snoopy Park.
Speaker 0: Well but before that it wasn't anything.
Speaker 0: They had a Berenstain Bearsland like in the middle for kids but there was no licensed.
Speaker 0: there was no license to anything at Cedar Point.
Speaker 0: So this video is a pretty well researched deep dive into the whole story of why Cedar Point did this what this ride was like and it sort of has this implied story of.
Speaker 0: there's not a lot of footage or photographs of this or a lot of similar things from this era.
Speaker 0: It is amazing how much information from the late 70s through the early 90s is just fucking gone.
Speaker 0: And this video like does the best it can to get all the information that's possible to describe.
Speaker 1: you think information for that era is gone.
Speaker 1: if you go back in time it's even more is gone.
Speaker 1: As you go back in time more information is gone.
Speaker 1: Until recently where we've had ridiculous recording and storage technologies.
Speaker 1: Even now think about how much is gone.
Speaker 1: We can't even keep fucking websites from Geocities around.
Speaker 0: But like the only reason we actually know like what it like.
Speaker 0: we can see today what it looks like inside this ride is because some rando carried a camcorder in there once and we got a hold of that footage.
Speaker 0: So this video is just really interesting about the history of this one roller coaster in detail and like why it was made the way it was and how Cedar Point decided to try to copy Disneyland and have an experience as opposed to a thrill ride.
Speaker 0: and then they realized fuck that and they never did that again and now they make just crazy thrill rides.
Speaker 0: It's also interesting because you might have seen me complaining on Twitter about this.
Speaker 0: The only complaint I have is this is another one of those videos that is really good except the person who does the narration is a fragile child who has modulated their voice because they don't like what their voice sounds like when they hear it.
Speaker 0: And that bothers me to the point that is very hard to watch videos that have that.
Speaker 1: You know just my initial guess though is that you know Cedar Point.
Speaker 1: the employees who make the rides are engineers largely and thus they would fail to make an experience whereas Disney Imagineers actually extremely creative people.
Speaker 0: So actually the engineers the experience they made was actually really high production values.
Speaker 1: Well just that doesn't mean it's creatively good.
Speaker 1: You could give me a ton of money to make a movie and it will say this video answered a question that was burning in my mind for decades.
Speaker 0: because when you got when I got off this ride because when Cedar Point got a new roller coaster it was a big deal as a kid.
Speaker 0: So when you got off this ride this attendant would be there and they'd be like welcome to Alaska and I didn't know what the fuck they meant.
Speaker 0: And now someone validated that that wasn't just something I made up that that did happen and why it happened.
Speaker 0: They had two different stories around this roller coaster and they never actually linked them up.
Speaker 0: So it's just interesting this whole thing.
Speaker 0: In the moment the book club book which will I'll be updating the website will be reading soon is Emily Wilson's translation new translation of the Odyssey by Homer.
Speaker 1: Yeah not dancing home.
Speaker 1: I'm at home.
Speaker 1: Just regular home.
Speaker 1: Stabbing Homer.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Well he does stab that Cyclops in the eye.
Speaker 1: so Homer isn't the one who stabs.
Speaker 0: Well if Homer wrote it then I ostensibly if you take the Princess Tutu look Homer did stab that Cyclops in the eye by way of a character that he created.
Speaker 0: But I digress.
Speaker 0: We were at Pac South.
Speaker 0: We were at Mag Fest.
Speaker 0: We have video from both those conventions on a YouTube channel and much more to come.
Speaker 0: We also Scott just uploaded like today.
Speaker 1: It's a little bit late because it's like there's already like three or four episodes in the current anime season but we didn't see any of them at the time of this recording.
Speaker 1: So we still judged the winter 2018 anime season by its cover.
Speaker 1: And I mean all this if you know.
Speaker 1: I think it's in time right.
Speaker 1: The spring one will be more on time.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: And more you need to subscribe to Scott's YouTube channel because this video is good and we're doing this as a series but they're on Scott's channel because he makes the videos and I mean I can't upload them to your channel.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: It's your channel.
Speaker 1: I can't log into it.
Speaker 1: I need your Google account.
Speaker 0: And we are way too far down the road of having our own channels to make like a new branded channel that will have no subscribers.
Speaker 1: There is a Geek Nights channel and we sort of I think I can still log into it but it's it's problematic because we made it in an ancient era of YouTube and Google.
Speaker 1: I mean the real goal is to like if we're ever making enough video to where it matters.
Speaker 1: we would just like you know like YouTube would talk to us right.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Make us an accommodation.
Speaker 1: And if it's not at that point then who gives a shit really.
Speaker 0: But anyway if you if you feel like you're missing out on some Geek Nights talks and videos.
Speaker 1: You can always go to front row crew dot com where all of our content is forever.
Speaker 0: Except this one.
Speaker 0: because we go to front row crew dot com it's still the balancing game design.
Speaker 1: No I put they put the thing on.
Speaker 0: I think you set the date behind the date of balance and game design.
Speaker 1: Did I?
Speaker 0: Balance and game design shows up in the front page.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: Go check it right now.
Speaker 0: No.
Speaker 0: So yeah otherwise we got no conventions until PAX East.
Speaker 1: Good.
Speaker 0: We can finally relax and actually do Geek Nights again.
Speaker 0: So follow us and all our stuff and stay tuned.
Speaker 0: the next video I'm going to upload is the top 40 tabletop games you need to play for magfest which was actually a pretty good panel.
Speaker 0: So we played a game that Chris and Anthony brought and it's another one of these like indie Japanese tabletop games.
Speaker 1: We played at magfest and PAX out.
Speaker 1: And it was made by the same person who made what the Yokohama and which we didn't like and what other games.
Speaker 1: It's Sashi Hayashi.
Speaker 0: Let's see.
Speaker 1: Yeah Yokohama.
Speaker 1: We played a few games by this person.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: Yokohama is the one that I remember.
Speaker 1: There was also some emperor one or something that I sucked at.
Speaker 0: No no no here we go.
Speaker 0: Emperor's Choice.
Speaker 1: That one.
Speaker 1: I sucked at that.
Speaker 0: I liked Emperor's Choice.
Speaker 0: It has some problems but I enjoyed it.
Speaker 1: Was Emperor's Choice the one I was good at?
Speaker 1: I forget.
Speaker 1: Well the one where the scoring cards flipped over.
Speaker 1: is that it?
Speaker 0: Or is it the one?
Speaker 0: That is Emperor's Choice.
Speaker 1: Okay that's the one I sucked at.
Speaker 1: The one where you place your worker and you could occupy two spots.
Speaker 0: That is the game you'll never forget.
Speaker 0: Your year with the dragon.
Speaker 1: Is that made by the same person also?
Speaker 1: No.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: Anyway.
Speaker 0: This is the Emperor's Choice person.
Speaker 1: Anyway so yeah this game is called Ratineer and when we saw the game at least I was immediately attracted to it because as the name implies it is a combination of rats, squeak squeak, eating pizza, and also buccaneers, yarr.
Speaker 1: we are pirates, let us be cute pirate rats, pirates who are cute.
Speaker 1: I don't know why they didn't translate it to pirat but Ratineer is okay.
Speaker 1: Yeah it's a game where you are pirate rats trying to out pirate the other pirate rats.
Speaker 0: So it's not a great game?
Speaker 0: It's not in the class of like Tiggers and Euphrates.
Speaker 1: I mean the theme though.
Speaker 1: The theme.
Speaker 0: The theme's good.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: And the game is relatively unique in that there are few games that use a mechanic like this.
Speaker 1: I cannot, there are not many games that you can compare this game to mechanically.
Speaker 1: no.
Speaker 0: The game, but the game has a lot of the elements, like.
Speaker 0: I feel like a game that was meteor.
Speaker 0: that did some of the things this game does would be very much up my alley.
Speaker 0: But this game is good.
Speaker 0: It's a good game to bust out at a convention because it generates a lot of moments where everyone goes oh shit really and something crazy happens.
Speaker 1: So first of all the game is really cute.
Speaker 1: I was immediately attracted to these pieces in the game.
Speaker 1: One of which had a tiny cute rat and a little red and white floaty rat.
Speaker 0: There are only two images of this game on BoardGameGeek.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Which is the cutest little rat I've ever seen?
Speaker 1: and then I was told that that is the rat king of the sea.
Speaker 0: The rat king of the land is pretty good though.
Speaker 1: The rat king of the land is also cute but not as cute as the rat king of the sea with the red and white floaty.
Speaker 0: The floaty is what does it.
Speaker 1: Yeah I'm all about the rat king of the sea.
Speaker 1: I almost thought about making that a Twitter avatar.
Speaker 0: So the theme is your rat pirates.
Speaker 0: whatever but the gist of the game.
Speaker 1: The main mechanic.
Speaker 0: that matters.
Speaker 0: You do a blind bid for where you're gonna go on this chain of islands.
Speaker 1: Everyone's got two pirates and you never get more and you could get some deckhands but whatever.
Speaker 1: You basically secretly allocate to, there's a chain of islands from the land out to the treasure island in a straight line and you allocate secretly where you're gonna send your pirates and your deckhands.
Speaker 0: You'd be like I'll send a pirate to island one and island three.
Speaker 1: Yeah I'll send a pirate to the magical treasure island and a pirate to this middle island and a deckhand on the land and so forth.
Speaker 0: And the islands all have goods that you're gonna do some stuff with.
Speaker 1: All the islands do stuff.
Speaker 0: Well the islands all have goods on them.
Speaker 0: The treasure island has crazy bullshit on it.
Speaker 1: Everyone reveals and then simultaneously sends out their pirates and deckhands to the thing but starting at the land where I guess the tavern is right where the money is.
Speaker 0: You do the thing on the first place then the second place then the third place.
Speaker 1: And as soon as you reach a spot in the chain, it's just a straight line where there nobody sent anybody.
Speaker 1: No one sent a pirate.
Speaker 1: No one sent a deckhand.
Speaker 1: No one sent anything to that spot.
Speaker 1: All of the islands further out in the chain.
Speaker 1: Everyone just gets swept away to the beach and doesn't get to do that stuff.
Speaker 1: So it's really hard to do the treasure island because to do the treasure island you need to have something on every single other spot.
Speaker 1: Something to keep that chain alive so that I guess you can get home safely with a treasure.
Speaker 0: Now also this leads to those situations where every round especially later in the game people are thinking did anyone go on space one?
Speaker 0: Please I hope someone went on space one.
Speaker 1: There are a lot of times where no one goes on space one and everyone gets washed away to the beach.
Speaker 0: Yup.
Speaker 1: The end.
Speaker 0: Now the rest of the game is pretty simple mechanically like it's not even that exciting.
Speaker 1: Each of the different islands does something.
Speaker 1: The first space just gives you money.
Speaker 1: The second space lets you buy helping cards and more deckhands.
Speaker 1: All the other normal spaces are all the same and they have cards that line up next to them that have goods and the goods become victory points and then at the very end of the treasure island.
Speaker 1: And I think there's another one that lets you flip victory points and then the beach.
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 1: Whatever.
Speaker 0: The game is only of sort of moderate actual depth in terms of strategy.
Speaker 1: The main mechanic that's fun and interesting and that you care about is the one I just described where you want to send your guys deep but if you do they might just get washed away to the beach and sort of risk and also looking at what other players are going to do.
Speaker 1: And if you fill in stuff.
Speaker 1: But try to guess what they're going to do and then you know.
Speaker 0: If you fill in stuff to go deep you're giving other people potentially a stepping stone to go deeper.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: And if you look at some spaces in the middle and it's like well that's a really good spot to go.
Speaker 1: but if I go there, Rim also goes there, he's going to, I'm going to get less stuff.
Speaker 1: but wait if I don't go there, Rim's going to go there alone and take all the stuff.
Speaker 0: So here's where this has another level of that same sort of like guessing what the other people are going to do and anticipating and risk taking is that all the islands where you get stuff, if you're there by yourself you get all the stuff.
Speaker 0: If you're there with other people you take turns based on some rules and who gets stuff.
Speaker 1: You're basically looting cargo ships.
Speaker 0: But if one of those islands has fights on it, you gotta win the fight.
Speaker 1: Otherwise everyone dies and goes to the beach.
Speaker 0: And when you win the fight, if you win the fight, the dudes you use to fight the fight generally die.
Speaker 0: So ideally.
Speaker 1: Unless you have cards.
Speaker 0: But all the people on that island share the fight and the results together.
Speaker 1: So if you get someone else to fight, you can get treasures by joining in.
Speaker 1: So there's multiple levels of- But if you go there and then no one else goes to fight there, you could just die.
Speaker 0: Multiple levels of anticipating what other people might do and planning on that and risk taking based on that.
Speaker 0: Now in terms of strategy, the trouble with the game is that really the only thing, like the strategy is pretty simple.
Speaker 0: You play conservatively when you're ahead in the sense that you play easy plays early in the board and you don't ever give people opportunities to go deeper.
Speaker 0: Because why would you?
Speaker 0: If you're already ahead and there's a turn where no one gets to do anything, you stay ahead.
Speaker 0: And if you're losing, you take increasingly desperate risky strategies to try to go deeper, to try to get a big payoff because you're hoping that nobody went on the place with three fights and you get all the goods.
Speaker 0: And that's really the only strategy involved.
Speaker 1: I mean, but that's the interesting part, right?
Speaker 1: What other game does that?
Speaker 1: Most of the risk reward games are games of like pushing, like, you know, no thanks where it gets deeper and deeper and deeper and you take it.
Speaker 1: or infiltration where you go deeper and deeper and deeper than turn back or deep sea adventure where you go deeper and turn back.
Speaker 1: In this game, every single turn, it's like, how deep is it safe to go?
Speaker 1: Every single turn, you're making a brand new judgment and you're getting severely punished for going too deep.
Speaker 0: Is the splendor of that kind of game.
Speaker 0: But then you can try again.
Speaker 0: Actually, Antdecker has that to a big degree.
Speaker 1: A little bit.
Speaker 0: Antdecker, when you're exploring, that's the how much are you going to risk?
Speaker 0: What's the risk reward ratio?
Speaker 0: But most of these games, the risk taking is independent of anticipating what other players will do.
Speaker 0: Like in infiltration, it's obvious what other players will do because the game's actually infiltration.
Speaker 1: I don't have as much freedom.
Speaker 0: I have an increasingly dour opinion of because the game always plays out the same way and you have very little agency.
Speaker 0: It takes too long for what you get out of it.
Speaker 1: That's true.
Speaker 0: And there is.
Speaker 0: it is almost never viable to go even halfway into that stupid place.
Speaker 1: You need some luck to get deep.
Speaker 0: You need a lot of luck to go deep.
Speaker 1: Unlike Deep Sea Adventure, where you can get the big treasures reliably.
Speaker 0: Retinaire is a pretty good balance of these mechanics and you get to have that go deeper not anticipate other players over and over and over again.
Speaker 0: My only complaint and I'm not going to complain that the game's a little random with the cards because it is, but that's not bad.
Speaker 0: That's fine for this level of game.
Speaker 0: My only complaint is the game takes about 10 to 15 minutes longer than it feels like it should.
Speaker 1: My complaint with the luck actually in this game is that you have the land seat rat king and the water rat king, right?
Speaker 1: The cutest pieces and they rotate around the board fairly.
Speaker 1: So everyone gets a roughly even number of times as both.
Speaker 1: And basically what those do is they allow you to either have priority on the land spaces or priority on the water space, which gives you more context to decide what other players are going to do.
Speaker 0: So when
Speaker 1: you are the sea rat king, you want to play your guys out in the water and you will get first dibs even if someone goes to the same space you go to, but everyone
Speaker 0: knows you're going to do
Speaker 1: that obviously, but I mean you just do it anyway because you still get first dibs.
Speaker 1: What they can do about it, right?
Speaker 1: And then if you go land, you're the land rat king.
Speaker 1: You also get first dibs, you can get more money or more cards or whatever before other people.
Speaker 1: And so they rotate evenly and it's kind of fair.
Speaker 1: But the thing is there's a lot of situations where, for example, I was the sea rat king once and no one went on the one space, just coincidence that time.
Speaker 1: And I had a good play and I just, Oh, I got, I got burned.
Speaker 1: And that's, you're only going to get to be the sea rat king, like two or three times GG.
Speaker 1: I basically lost right there.
Speaker 0: Why'd you take that risk?
Speaker 1: I didn't, you know, how was I, why would I go on the land space when I'm the sea rat king?
Speaker 0: You put one deck hand there as insurance.
Speaker 0: I just, but I'm just saying it's like, you know, you know, this risk reward, this game, you literally can spend actions, which are the primary economy in the games.
Speaker 0: You don't get many.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: To buy insurance.
Speaker 1: By putting a deck hand somewhere to ensure, you know, it's just the thing that can happen, It could be not even getting a big, not as that's, that's an example of really big, bad luck.
Speaker 1: I'm talking about a little bad luck.
Speaker 1: Like, Oh, I was the sea rat king and there really weren't any good islands to go to.
Speaker 1: Like there weren't a lot of cards out there to pick up on when I happened to be the sea rat king because of the way the turns went.
Speaker 1: And then I, so I, you know, I did what the best I could and whatever.
Speaker 1: And then I passed the sea rat king to the left and suddenly all these amazing diamonds get dealt out.
Speaker 1: And now the person to the left of me is the sea rat king and they get all these victory points by going to this awesome island.
Speaker 1: And because I was just the sea rat king, I have more, I have like no priority on water.
Speaker 1: I've heard on land.
Speaker 1: I can't get those victory points just because luck.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: I mean, that's why I said, I'm not saying this is bad.
Speaker 1: Board games have luck.
Speaker 1: That's the thing.
Speaker 0: But that's why I'm saying the game needs to be like 15 minutes shorter.
Speaker 1: It doesn't ruin the game.
Speaker 1: It's just, it's a thing.
Speaker 0: If the game were shorter, that would be less of a concern because you just play it again.
Speaker 0: Uh, the other funny thing as Demoisell just pointed out in the chat, it's not localized so well.
Speaker 1: Well, yeah.
Speaker 1: There's some really funny things like, so this money art is in.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: There's a cut.
Speaker 1: There's, there's cards for the special rats that you can buy on the land at the tavern.
Speaker 0: A few of them are basically like translated wrong.
Speaker 0: So like the surgeon is the thief.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: They wrote the wrong words on them.
Speaker 1: But the, the, uh, the best one, the bogus money artisan, the counterfeiter who gives you like a money every turn, basically, uh, something like that.
Speaker 1: But instead of saying counterfeiter, it says bogus money artisan, which is amazing.
Speaker 0: I will at any point in my life where there is an opportunity to say the word counterfeit, I'm going to say bogus something, say bogus money and say bogus money artisan.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: But it could be bogus.
Speaker 0: I mean, we're gonna do a geek nice episode in the future.
Speaker 0: Are you a bogus MP3 artisan?
Speaker 1: Is that what you are?
Speaker 0: But I would say that if you are the kind of person who whips out games for people like you're the kind of person who brings a game to your group and says, Hey, let's play this game.
Speaker 0: It's cool.
Speaker 0: This is a game to have.
Speaker 0: This is a game that a lot of people you bring games for have not played before.
Speaker 1: Also it's, people haven't played this.
Speaker 1: It has cute rats that can bring people in as a cute pirate theme that you can get into.
Speaker 1: It's pretty cool.
Speaker 1: Even though it has some problems, you can still get enjoyment out of it multiple times.
Speaker 1: It's easy to learn.
Speaker 1: It's quick to learn, even though it's too long for what it is, it's still not long to play overall.
Speaker 0: Yup.
Speaker 1: Uh, and it's unique.
Speaker 1: It's not like other games.
Speaker 1: You have this unique mechanic that make it worth playing.
Speaker 1: There isn't like some replacement game that's like, Oh, you shouldn't play right near play this instead.
Speaker 1: It's like, there isn't really a game that I've seen that has that chain connection mechanic.
Speaker 1: That's really interesting.
Speaker 1: Uh, I almost sort of feel like it's a furry and it's obviously nothing like for you of Dracula, except free of free of Dracula has the Dracula's hidden movement mechanic.
Speaker 1: that is amazing.
Speaker 1: That is unlike any other game.
Speaker 1: And the rest of the game is may rat near has the chain simultaneous placement mechanic, which is unique and unlike any other game.
Speaker 1: And the rest of the game is a game.
Speaker 0: If we could make the, make the combat and fury of Dracula act somehow like this blind bed system in right near.
Speaker 1: So basically take two unique systems and combine them.
Speaker 1: And that's the whole game.
Speaker 1: Two really interesting, unique systems together.
Speaker 0: I feel like that could work.
Speaker 1: Go for it.
Speaker 0: That goes against most of the advice we give people for designing games.
Speaker 1: But yeah, it's a, you know, definitely, I think, you know, there was so much attention on the Euro games.
Speaker 1: I'm glad we have some friends who pay attention to the, uh, Japanese produced board games out there.
Speaker 0: I haven't been, I do not have time to pay attention to that right now.
Speaker 1: And I'm sure there are other countries besides Japan and European union that are produced and United States that are producing quite excellent tabletop games.
Speaker 1: And I would like to see some of those, please translate them and deliver them to us for the win.
Speaker 0: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website@frontrowcrew.com for show notes, discussion news, and more.
Speaker 0: remember geek nights is not one, but four different shows, sci-tech Mondays, gaming Tuesdays, anime comic Wednesdays, and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a creative comments attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 0: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night and the Patriot on Patriots for this episode of geek nights are including someone who got robbed from their, uh, name reading due to a checkbox in Patriot.
Speaker 0: Um, Craig Oliver, Alan Joyce, Rebecca Dunn, Heidi McNichol, a shimmering group, the obelisk hanging in the sky.
Speaker 0: My state of the.com Jeremy minor, a genuine bonafide, like five, six car monorail, cold guy, Amanda, you shot Sean Yeager, Matthew Smith, Nicholas Brando, captain Chinguac.
Speaker 0: Cause he, four to one creations.
Speaker 0: No, I never ever wonder why we're here.
Speaker 0: Semper fi bitch.
Speaker 0: Shervin, not horrible.
Speaker 0: Real of Val.
Speaker 0: James David White, Rochelle, Monta, super boy room says something funny here.
Speaker 0: Sailor Vista.
Speaker 0: Don's like chart option.
Speaker 0: Joe Shiro, Joe star, Sam Cordery, Clinton, Walton, Ren from New Zealand, Ryan parent for open ladder, Finn, Chris Midkiff, Chris Knox, Daniel Redmond, Sean Klein, Chris Reimer and Thomas Hahn.
Speaker 0: I've been talking about Cedar point a lot lately cause I'm going there this summer.
Speaker 0: And once I decide when I'm going, I will tell all of you when I'm going to be there in case you happen to be there.
Speaker 0: But anyway, now I leave you with something that has nothing to do with Cedar point.
Speaker 1: you don't belong to them.
Speaker 0: They left me in a world of darkness without your sexy hands.
Speaker 1: And I miss you.
Speaker 1: night, man.
Speaker 0: We have defeated the evil that was here naturally.
Speaker 0: For I am the day, man, the night man, the master of karate and friendship for everyone.
Speaker 0: Hey man.