Speaker 0: It's Wednesday October 3rd 2018.
Speaker 0: I'm rim.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott, and this is geek nights.
Speaker 0: tonight We're talking about middle manager, Tony gawa.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: So I don't know if you got this email.
Speaker 0: Which one I actually?
Speaker 0: I got a couple of emails I was thinking about talking about on the show the one from city bike.
Speaker 0: Oh, no, I got an email from G kids.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: No so Like about a week ago I Got an email from city bike - okay I noticed like hey where the fuck did all the city bikes go?
Speaker 1: the docks are empty and then someone else posted on the internet Like hey, are there any city bikes, and I'm like no Astoria is barren.
Speaker 1: There's like no bikes here.
Speaker 1: What the?
Speaker 1: oh, that's no.
Speaker 0: cuz the email I got was like yo We saw that you canceled your city bike a while ago.
Speaker 0: You want to start it up again.
Speaker 1: No no okay I get it free from work.
Speaker 1: so Then Right after we're discussing in that thread like yeah, there's no fucking city bikes anywhere.
Speaker 1: They've been gone for like two days.
Speaker 1: I get an email from city bike.
Speaker 1: all right And I think it was coincidence that people started discussing it on the internet right before the email came, but the email was like yeah There was some issue with like the handlebars or something on a lot of the bikes.
Speaker 1: So we took them out of service.
Speaker 0: Oh the thing where they'll like droop.
Speaker 1: I don't know what it is, but they it wasn't very Explicit it was very vague and what the what the problem was.
Speaker 0: it must have been at least a little bit dangerous.
Speaker 0: That's the only reason.
Speaker 0: they would recall the city by.
Speaker 1: yes, but basically they're apologizing that there's no bikes and even now.
Speaker 0: I biked here on my bike just now because I knew there weren't any outside because the app actually now that I think about it If there's not a lot of city bikes that really fucks up the commute of a lot of people I work with.
Speaker 0: Lot of people were way late the last few days.
Speaker 1: It fucks up a lot.
Speaker 1: so that so on my way here on my bike because I knew there were any city bikes outside I passed by one maybe five city bike docks And I saw one city bike.
Speaker 1: all the all the docks are empty.
Speaker 1: also the last time we did a podcast on Monday yeah, and I was leaving here I go over to grab one to go home And I go over to the bridge where the dock is and it's empty and someone comes down the bridge of the city bike And jams it in there, and I'm like oh, yes I'm grabbing that and it's one of the.
Speaker 0: it was one of the e ones I have not yet tried one of those.
Speaker 1: it was one of the pedal assist ones which I also have not yet tried.
Speaker 1: So I was it.
Speaker 1: I wanted to go try it and I go over there and that motherfucker pushed the red repair light And I was like you motherfucker You just rode this down the bridge.
Speaker 1: safely if the bike works do not push the button Especially at an empty dock where there's none in service.
Speaker 1: you only push the red button if the bike is unrideable.
Speaker 0: He was already gone I didn't?
Speaker 1: you know.
Speaker 1: you only push the repair button which takes the bike out of service if The bike is literally unsafe to ride or impossible to ride.
Speaker 1: If like the brakes were a little weak or squeaky or if the gear shifter is a little messed up But it's still.
Speaker 1: you know you can still pedal and go Even if you stuck in one gear right.
Speaker 1: if it has a flat tire you push the button.
Speaker 1: yeah If the brakes don't work you push the button right.
Speaker 1: otherwise if I give that battery was dead.
Speaker 1: Don't push the buy.
Speaker 1: What's wrong with people?
Speaker 1: Especially when there's not bikes in service?
Speaker 0: You know I imagine the average person doesn't think about like they the the idea of considering How many bikes are at the dock they're dropping on when there's plenty of bikes?
Speaker 1: That's the policy for pushing the button.
Speaker 0: now if there's plenty of bikes if there's anything wrong with the bike I hit that button.
Speaker 1: I don't hit it otherwise.
Speaker 0: They'll never fix the bike.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I hit it when it's actually like Beyond.
Speaker 0: you know if it's even a little annoying I'll hit the button.
Speaker 1: then you hit the button on every single city bike.
Speaker 1: just go down the whole dock City bike.
Speaker 0: that worked fine and in fact the brakes actually Stopped the city bike like reliably which I have not experienced before.
Speaker 1: usually those brakes are just The brakes usually work Usually the shifter.
Speaker 1: that's an issue.
Speaker 0: thing is I don't really need city bike still because I can park my bike inside my building in A really nice bike parking.
Speaker 1: I know I use it for things like I'm gonna go ride the subway But I can go to the subway.
Speaker 0: yeah, well, that's it because I live next to the subway.
Speaker 1: I use it for things like oh, I can just go over to.
Speaker 1: You know like you could use it for example to go down to LIC and eat it.
Speaker 1: take casa Enrique.
Speaker 0: I just biked there with my regular bike.
Speaker 0: No one's stealing a bike in Queens I'm just saying.
Speaker 0: you know though actually what I would use it for is to bike to other nearby subways like the E.
Speaker 1: That's also good.
Speaker 1: You know that's the kind of thing you use it for yeah at work But I want to eat lunch somewhere slightly far away from work.
Speaker 1: It could be done.
Speaker 0: So in some other will will meta will probably not even matter will probably skip next Thursday's show.
Speaker 0: cuz I'm just kind of Emily And I were randomly going to London to dick around.
Speaker 1: so oh Speaking of which I'm going to tropical island tropical island October The week of October 20 Through the week that has mo all 20s in it in October sitting by the.
Speaker 1: so there won't be any podcast.
Speaker 1: There won't be any podcast on what is this?
Speaker 1: the?
Speaker 0: There'll be some days with no podcast coming up because we're both traveling at different times.
Speaker 1: I'm not sure which days it is.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't I barely remember.
Speaker 1: It's a. it's a. It's a Tuesday Thursday week the 23rd to 25th.
Speaker 1: I won't be here.
Speaker 0: one thing I can say that's funny.
Speaker 0: Is that the more I travel like as I traveled more and more and more in my life Not only do I plan travel later and worry about it less But I roll into the airport like right before my flight, but I basically plan nothing.
Speaker 1: my plan is Go to the.
Speaker 1: I got a plane.
Speaker 1: I got a hotel.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna go to the tropical island.
Speaker 1: No, I'm gonna lay on the beach.
Speaker 1: I don't need any plans.
Speaker 1: I assume there'll be food there that I can find once I'm there.
Speaker 1: yep I don't need my phone even to work Like.
Speaker 0: I know my way around like central London better than I know my way around Brooklyn, so I don't need what do I need?
Speaker 1: You know I don't need anything there.
Speaker 1: the hotel will provide a beach.
Speaker 1: It has a beach on it.
Speaker 1: It has food.
Speaker 1: it has a bed.
Speaker 1: Yeah No, my planning was basically bring a book with me.
Speaker 0: She just goes somewhere that weekend, and I just went on kayak, and I was like Paris.
Speaker 0: and then I looked.
Speaker 0: and it is way more Expensive to fly to Paris right now than I'm used to.
Speaker 0: I don't know why like way more I fell out is cheap.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but for whatever reason.
Speaker 0: It's way cheap to fly to London right now, so hey Mom went to London now.
Speaker 0: Oh What's she doing?
Speaker 0: They're just hanging out hanging out?
Speaker 0: Yeah, is she like central London?
Speaker 0: like?
Speaker 0: where is she?
Speaker 0: you don't know?
Speaker 1: What do I know about London?
Speaker 1: This is a big band, and there's a castle.
Speaker 0: I know about diamonds is you know?
Speaker 1: Fancy taxis that are black.
Speaker 1: they call the subway the underground yep.
Speaker 0: their subway is very they talk funny.
Speaker 0: London and Paris the only cities.
Speaker 0: I've been to where the subway is like the New York subway.
Speaker 0: Paris way more so than London.
Speaker 0: It's not 24/7 Paris's is parts of it.
Speaker 0: at least Paris is the closest to New York.
Speaker 0: London is real close, but yeah It doesn't run at night and the central line is a bunch of weird construction.
Speaker 0: like the last time I went the station I normally use to like get from Paddington to where I'm going was just closed and because I don't live there It's not like I get their equivalent of the MTA Notifications, it's not like I'm getting the thing that says yo the station's closed on this day actually
Speaker 1: really notify You can get I guess but I can have the notify NYC app.
Speaker 1: That's like yo Helicopters coming.
Speaker 1: yeah, there's a flood.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's you know well I use the MTA three what we are 311 app.
Speaker 0: but 99% of what I do with it is get people's cars towed for parking in the bike lane.
Speaker 1: you get the notify NYC.
Speaker 0: yeah, yeah, I think I got that too.
Speaker 0: I got the notification today.
Speaker 0: The funny thing is when we get the flood warnings like everyone's phone goes off at once with this thing it like rolled across the Office for about 20 minutes like back and forth
Speaker 1: mm-hmm
Speaker 0: and almost no one knew It was happening like no one knew what it was except
Speaker 1: not read news.
Speaker 0: I guess not the only people who knew it was coming were the people who pay attention to politics and the young people.
Speaker 0: All the non young people who don't pay attention to politics had no idea.
Speaker 0: and the funniest thing was Everyone coming out of like the elevator like I was leaving.
Speaker 0: I was like everyone who came out of buildings later.
Speaker 0: It just went off like I guess their phone wasn't getting signal until they came to the ground floor.
Speaker 0: Hmm, so yeah, it's a Wednesday so in the news it looks like there's a. This is perhaps the epitome of too little too late the well I don't know what the deal is here.
Speaker 1: So they're gonna make a movie somehow based on dance dance revolution.
Speaker 1: Konami's money is behind it.
Speaker 1: who fucking?
Speaker 1: But it's the 20th anniversary of DDR so that has something to do with it.
Speaker 1: They're actually.
Speaker 1: they did some cool stuff.
Speaker 1: It's like the new DDR machines have a mode in them apparently that they added for the anniversary.
Speaker 1: That lets you load up the the menus and stuff and stuff, so it looks like the old mixes.
Speaker 0: That actually gets me really excited.
Speaker 0: So as much as I make fun and even though DDR is kind of dead I just really want to play DDR right now.
Speaker 1: Yeah, why not?
Speaker 1: but the point is they're making some movie.
Speaker 1: That seems really really dumb.
Speaker 1: Somehow be I've seen DDR appear in movies.
Speaker 0: Well, we saw it appear in wasabi.
Speaker 1: I've seen it appear on TV shows and comics and all sorts of other mediums, but I've never seen something that was about DDR.
Speaker 1: that seems really dumb.
Speaker 0: Yep, I mean the best case scenario the best possible case Like initial D.
Speaker 1: The only way to make a movie about DDR that would be good would be to make a documentary about DDR champions.
Speaker 0: I'll bet you could make a movie.
Speaker 0: That was the aesthetic and style of initial D. But just about DDR like that could work.
Speaker 1: You could do it about all rhythm games, but not just DDR.
Speaker 0: It's not enough to work.
Speaker 1: It's not enough to work with.
Speaker 0: you got Takumi the kid who just sits at the arcade The kid who's really good at DDR, but doesn't like DDR doesn't even like no one knows He only he's dead.
Speaker 0: He works at the bowling alley and he plays DDR at night when he's doing maintenance.
Speaker 1: There's the kid who's actually like, you know, the head boss.
Speaker 1: He's legendary at DDR, but you never see him.
Speaker 1: do any move.
Speaker 0: Oh, that's Ken's game.
Speaker 1: Right and then what you got?
Speaker 1: the guy who?
Speaker 1: Best DDR shoes.
Speaker 1: There's no other guy.
Speaker 0: The guy who does the matrix is only so many character machine and like cuts his arm the guy who's all style and and Tape the dude's arms to the bar.
Speaker 1: Come on.
Speaker 0: I feel like that you'd have to go crazy with it for it to be good.
Speaker 0: I feel like this is gonna be a gem in the holograms the movie situation.
Speaker 0: I Just I. DDR is kind of dead like even at the cons like at mag fast There really aren't.
Speaker 1: it has a minor resurgence right now, but not it's not a resurgence among the people It's a resurgence and that the people who are into it Have it more than they used to because they're actually putting some machines over here in places and updating them.
Speaker 1: But meanwhile step you go to certain places in the US.
Speaker 1: now there are new machines that are updated and hooked up to the score system and that's how I think we talked about this before.
Speaker 1: how The world champion of DDR is from America like last year the year before I forget.
Speaker 0: But meanwhile step mania has kind of gotten worse like there's not more people into it, but the people were into it.
Speaker 1: It's like it's get.
Speaker 1: they're getting a little bit more support than these two.
Speaker 0: But in all the cons where they're quote-unquote DDR machines like mag fast used to have like a bunch of legit DDR machines all different Mixes.
Speaker 0: it's all these kind of shitty laggy bootleggy machines now And I'm really curious like what?
Speaker 1: like how come there are no DDR machines older than extreme did like all of them Just like did all the third fourth fifth mixes in the world just like get updated to you know They can't get updated all the way.
Speaker 0: third fourth fifth I'm not gonna get into it, but I'm saying I think there are several generations of machines.
Speaker 1: Right, but I'm saying like it seems like all the machines of a certain generation were updated like are there any fourth mix plus machines in the world anywhere on earth?
Speaker 0: There was one of the machines at mag fest this past year was a was clearly a fourth mix plus machine But it had some bootleg bullshit inside of it like it was not the DDR.
Speaker 1: I'm saying is there a fourth mix plus machine?
Speaker 1: That's actually running fourth mix plus in its original form.
Speaker 0: I have to imagine it on earth anywhere.
Speaker 1: if there's one anywhere have all of those because there were many.
Speaker 1: there were thousands Hundreds of me.
Speaker 0: I feel like they got bought by people who then took them home and modded them And that's where they live now.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: there might be one in Japan.
Speaker 0: if there's one anywhere it might be still at the putt-putt.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: that was a regular fourth mix not a plus.
Speaker 0: I know I know.
Speaker 0: So in some other news anime fest and New York comic-con are this weekend and thank Satan That I'm not going.
Speaker 0: I think I've skipped once the last seven years of this nonsense.
Speaker 1: I went the first year I didn't go to it.
Speaker 1: I walked past it to see what the deal was and there was a big mega line And it was.
Speaker 0: it was a shit shows a failure.
Speaker 1: the second year I went to it just one night to go in and see one person and say hi I just look around and then I left.
Speaker 0: well We got free badges every year until we just stop picking up the free badge.
Speaker 1: went to it like.
Speaker 1: We went to it for like one day when the anime fest was there, and we had a panel.
Speaker 1: No when we went to it also the next morning to see a Makoto shinkai's movie that wasn't good yep.
Speaker 0: And then none of the.
Speaker 0: I remember.
Speaker 0: there was the I don't remember the name of the movie And then there was the interview with him and we were just gonna see the panel.
Speaker 0: We were in the room and literally no media were there, so I just filmed the whole thing myself.
Speaker 0: My video is the only video of it.
Speaker 1: and then I don't remember But we all went to a bunch of.
Speaker 1: I haven't been to it in many many years.
Speaker 0: I went to more of them and did panels without you and I used to get me and Emily used to get Professional badges every year, but there was increasingly just no reason.
Speaker 0: even when I did go to it I usually went to it for a day like honestly, New York comic-con is now in the class of Conventions that are the anti pattern for how to run a fun enjoyable engaging convention.
Speaker 1: for people like us It's basically San Diego comic-con, but worse, but it's in the United States, but it's in New York.
Speaker 1: The other one San Diego is also in the United States.
Speaker 0: So we've talked about how they added the anime fest back to it But like five asterisks next to what I just said It's in a different location not accessible by any form of transportation.
Speaker 0: That's weird and far away and cause extra.
Speaker 0: There is no way the anime fest thing is gonna succeed.
Speaker 0: Like I am confident.
Speaker 0: No one's gonna go to this thing I don't know.
Speaker 1: I don't know but there are actually a lot of Events happening around it that are yeah That email that I got from not only like.
Speaker 1: there's some like this individual specific things that I've seen people excited for.
Speaker 1: For example, there is a panel.
Speaker 1: There's a Someone's.
Speaker 1: they're making an official babymetal graphic novel that will supposedly reveal the very, you know secretive lore to some extent and the person who the person who made this graphic novel has doing a panel and People are like, oh shit.
Speaker 1: We got to send any questions.
Speaker 1: We got to do a livestream like they're organized around this one panel.
Speaker 1: There's also gonna be like some sort of a whole bunch of like anime Idol j-pop kind of concert situation going on.
Speaker 1: Yep You know, there's certain like individual events that on their own are like, whoa, that's pretty great But as a whole the event seems like not so good.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that was that G kids email.
Speaker 0: There's basically there's some sort of like G-kids Party at some venue like over on 38th Street the night before and I got an invite to it for some reason.
Speaker 1: Go have fun.
Speaker 0: Yeah, no, I'm not going to Review con.
Speaker 0: Okay So yeah, but the news is not that we've talked about all this before.
Speaker 0: like there's a we don't go to this kind of con Cuz they're not.
Speaker 0: it's not for us.
Speaker 0: It's not fun.
Speaker 0: But What we used to say is that We could take the seven train from our houses to this con and we still don't bother going.
Speaker 1: Well the time that we that's how long ago was we went to it.
Speaker 0: There was no seven trains.
Speaker 1: The seven train did not go there.
Speaker 1: when the last time I went to the New York Comic Con I had to walk there from like 34th Street.
Speaker 1: But now the seven train goes to the Javits and I don't go there anymore.
Speaker 1: But Yeah, the seven train this weekend is not running.
Speaker 1: it's being replaced by a shuttle bus.
Speaker 0: Yep, so there's no way to get to New York Comic Con except a bus.
Speaker 1: Well, it's just like it was in the old days.
Speaker 0: Even worse a lot of the people who come to New York Comic Con come from outside of the city for like one day Like half a day like take a
Speaker 1: metro
Speaker 0: north
Speaker 1: drive in and park
Speaker 0: kind of like how I said I mean the
Speaker 1: parking near the Javits though,
Speaker 0: like yeah, not that much.
Speaker 0: But also a lot of people take the train in and Remember how I said earlier that I got kind of fucked in London that like Lancaster Gate Station was closed And I didn't get a notification because I don't live in London.
Speaker 0: a lot of people think they're gonna go from Grand Central on the seven train to this con and they're gonna get told to go Ride a weird bus that's gonna be stuck in travel.
Speaker 1: They're gonna go in down into the station.
Speaker 1: There's gonna be MTA people there.
Speaker 1: There's gonna.
Speaker 1: the stairs are gonna be roped off.
Speaker 1: They won't be able to go down there.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and someone's gonna say go upstairs Shut up reach out of us and that free shuttle bus is gonna arrive at Grand Central from Queens already full And you're not gonna be able to get on it.
Speaker 1: This is MTA.
Speaker 1: So New York City transit.
Speaker 1: Yeah, please go upstairs.
Speaker 1: The seventh train is not running it.
Speaker 1: Please go outside to the corner of whatever Street.
Speaker 0: So there won't be a subway that goes to a New York Comic Con and there won't be any fucking city bikes to get there.
Speaker 0: And I caught riding your city bike and gun cosplay Unless you're biking as I was about to say unless you're cosplaying a biking in cosplay as your pedal.
Speaker 0: So yeah, I just think that's really funny.
Speaker 0: But anyway things of the day.
Speaker 0: so I was watching a bunch of YouTube videos and It's funny to say that someone stepped up their game when their game is already so high.
Speaker 0: But I was always a fan of Captain Disillusion, but he's like a.
Speaker 1: you know, he's a video.
Speaker 1: if you don't know this guy He's like a video master.
Speaker 1: So like he's basically so meta on YouTube because he makes YouTube videos But he is a video master and his videos he makes are about videos on YouTube.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right He'll be like.
Speaker 1: basically finds videos that have you know weird stuff happening and then he sort of debunks them and he's like.
Speaker 1: He's like yeah, you think that this person's turning invisible how they do that.
Speaker 1: I'll show you exactly how they did it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you do.
Speaker 0: look so you can tell.
Speaker 0: use a tripod here and look at this and look at that.
Speaker 0: Here's the pixels.
Speaker 0: There's his mask.
Speaker 0: So He has stepped up his game from its already amazing game in a big way Like I but I was just clicking through.
Speaker 0: like I clicked on one of his random videos.
Speaker 0: I was just clicking around in it Like like what's the deal with this one?
Speaker 0: because it looked like a pretty cool thing and I was curious Like how he debunks this and what the deal was cuz I've never heard of it.
Speaker 0: But then I noticed something when I clicked on a random frame in this video that I hadn't actually watched the thing.
Speaker 1: What thing?
Speaker 0: the sentinel from RIT?
Speaker 0: Okay, so I was like wait wait wait wait what the what what what?
Speaker 0: so I had to back.
Speaker 1: realize for us This is so the set if you don't know at RIT the college we went to while we were there They built the thing they built.
Speaker 1: they spent a bunch of money that didn't come from student money.
Speaker 1: It came from some in some donation.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so we couldn't add.
Speaker 0: we complained about it, but we couldn't really complain.
Speaker 1: I mean whoever donated the money.
Speaker 1: Why'd you donate it for a statue instead of for a fucking?
Speaker 0: no I do like the statue Making fun of the statue as well.
Speaker 1: They built this giant statue that's sort of vaguely in the shape of a knight with a lance.
Speaker 1: that not really though But it's and all the pieces of it look like rusty metal weird purpose.
Speaker 1: It's somewhat abstract.
Speaker 1: You know, it's it's an acquired taste this statue, but it was a big deal.
Speaker 1: well, cuz we were there and they put it in.
Speaker 1: but Realized though that like for students now, it's just there.
Speaker 1: It's just.
Speaker 1: it's an accepted like thing.
Speaker 1: They don't realize that like they don't have that experience as a science situation.
Speaker 1: It's like for us.
Speaker 1: It's like the quad there was like the infinite spinning infinity thing.
Speaker 1: We just accepted it that it was there.
Speaker 1: It wasn't like some new thing to complain about.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: So I just saw the thing.
Speaker 1: It's enormous.
Speaker 1: You don't realize how big this thing is.
Speaker 0: It's Look for scale.
Speaker 0: There's a person standing next to it.
Speaker 1: I think it's like four or five stories tall.
Speaker 1: Maybe it is huge.
Speaker 1: It's really.
Speaker 1: it's as big as like an apartment building.
Speaker 1: It's tall.
Speaker 0: So I watched this video and the videos like.
Speaker 0: so.
Speaker 0: apparently there's a viral video I just never noticed about this Asherian stairwell that did it Like.
Speaker 0: it looked like an MCS your thing if you walked in it and apparently it was in building 7 and I was like what?
Speaker 0: I don't remember this fucking thing.
Speaker 0: There's nothing like that in building 7 and of course it was a hoax perpetrated by RIT students at RIT.
Speaker 1: So here you go, so dr.
Speaker 1: Disillusion was dismissed.
Speaker 1: he's debunking some RIT students who thought they were too clever.
Speaker 0: Yep, and it's good because this now intersects RIT and Captain Disillusion.
Speaker 0: So you're unfamiliar with either of those two things.
Speaker 0: My thing of the day is for you.
Speaker 0: I don't understand why 2,000 people dislike this video RIT students.
Speaker 0: Because I was like building 7. there is nothing like that in building 7 because I broke into building 7 and explored the entire thing In the middle of the night multiple times.
Speaker 1: I worked in building 7.
Speaker 0: Yeah Building 7 was the building that was open at night and you could bust into and wander around.
Speaker 0: there were art.
Speaker 1: students had to do Art.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and there were.
Speaker 0: there were weird that like building 7 had the most weird areas.
Speaker 1: It was like two combined buildings.
Speaker 0: Yep, it had like all these balconies that weren't accessible to students that you could kind of get out on to and anyway What do you got?
Speaker 1: Oh, so it's just a tweet.
Speaker 1: but in the tweet is a video and The tweet has a joke in it, but the joke is you know for machine learning people.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the point is the video is awesome whether you understand the joke or not.
Speaker 1: if you understand the joke, that's great.
Speaker 1: If not, the video is this door on I think what it looks like a barn or some sort of like a garage Something like that.
Speaker 0: There's a car in there.
Speaker 1: It is an awesome fucking door.
Speaker 1: If we get the house to put a DDR machine in we should have only doors like this.
Speaker 0: So the only problem with this door and the reason I think about it is because remember the marble machine.
Speaker 0: Oh, the guy's making the new machine, which by the way, it's getting close to completion.
Speaker 0: So I'm gonna get ready to buy tickets to the New York.
Speaker 0: The guy's awesome.
Speaker 0: Okay with the winter gotten guy is like super cute and super funny Like it's very good videos to watch and I saw one of my engineers watching one of his videos while he was coding today.
Speaker 0: That's why I was thinking about him But he made a point.
Speaker 0: cuz he's making the machine he has this stuff and he starts talking about how someone on the internet pointed Out that a part of the machine he had designed Would very easily if he wasn't paying attention literally crush his entire foot flat.
Speaker 0: So I'm looking at this door.
Speaker 0: This door is guaranteed to crush someone's finger completely.
Speaker 1: I think the main problem with the door is that it is not ADA compliant.
Speaker 0: Yeah, ADA compliant It will crush you.
Speaker 0: that will destroy your finger.
Speaker 1: I think it's.
Speaker 1: you can only open the door if you have like an arm and you can stand and move to the side.
Speaker 1: I think that's the problem with the door.
Speaker 0: There's also no ramp here.
Speaker 1: There's multiple Good part about the door.
Speaker 1: Is that once you open it?
Speaker 1: You don't have to like you never have to hold the door open.
Speaker 1: You don't need a door.
Speaker 1: stop You don't need anything like that, right?
Speaker 1: You can.
Speaker 1: you open the door.
Speaker 1: It's open.
Speaker 1: That's just a portal.
Speaker 1: You can open the door a little bit and close it.
Speaker 0: It's closed Yeah, but it does.
Speaker 1: and it's cool.
Speaker 1: and it is cool like opening the door.
Speaker 1: It will provide you joy Whenever you enter or leave the space in the meta moment the yingas book.
Speaker 0: a book is apparently still Homer's Odyssey Still not updated.
Speaker 1: That's the one thing that I plan to do today.
Speaker 1: that I didn't do because I was busy editing.
Speaker 1: Judge Anime by its cover winter 2018 which is now rendering and I'll upload it when I get home.
Speaker 1: So yes, I'm uploading it.
Speaker 1: I will update the website of frontworkrew.com to say that the current book club book is not Homer's Odyssey But is instead R. Z. Clarke's Space Odyssey 2001.
Speaker 0: So Judge Anime by its cover.
Speaker 0: I'll link to the playlist.
Speaker 0: We've done this a bunch of times.
Speaker 0: The new one is just about to go out.
Speaker 0: we review every coming season of anime before it comes out based solely on the information On Anna charts and we're pretty accurate about the quality of these shows and whether or not they're worth watching.
Speaker 1: other meta We already talked about what shows we are and aren't doing in the near future because the trips to London and tropical islands.
Speaker 1: We are gonna go to PAX unplugged, which is soon.
Speaker 1: the schedule just went up today.
Speaker 1: I'd even look at it.
Speaker 0: We are doing learn and win Puerto Rico and we're doing the 40 tabletop games you must play.
Speaker 1: We are not going to New York Comic Con this weekend But we are going to our friend Matt's house who we're gonna play a shit ton of board games and live stream them.
Speaker 1: So pay attention to twitch YouTube channels that belong to us.
Speaker 1: Who knows which one we're gonna use?
Speaker 1: Yeah, you should know them all.
Speaker 1: anyway, look at our.
Speaker 1: if you just follow our Twitter's will all tweet.
Speaker 1: You know not only links to the streams, but also who wins and loses and other things.
Speaker 0: It's the second review con.
Speaker 1: This is we're gonna play board tabletop games literally all fucking weekend long.
Speaker 0: But the point of review con is that we play these games with experts all of us Like we're all experts at tabletop and then we load up on Games for us to review on two shows going into the future and we're gonna up that game.
Speaker 0: We're going to get commentary from the other people.
Speaker 0: So it's not just gonna be room and scout do a normal gig nights episode.
Speaker 0: We're actually gonna get the commentary from the other experts.
Speaker 0: We're gonna play some weird games and we'll have a lot to talk about right also Are we gonna go to anime NYC or not?
Speaker 1: Nah, man I just didn't go to it for one day.
Speaker 0: we could go to her for one day But we're not gonna do a panel at it.
Speaker 0: Not because why didn't submit anything because I realized They have a policy around like they had this really big thing in their panel thing around.
Speaker 0: now You can't show like do the?
Speaker 0: do you have permission like written permission for clips and stuff like that?
Speaker 0: You want to include in your panel.
Speaker 0: all our good anime content involves showing stuff and I didn't want to go through that hassle.
Speaker 0: Okay, cuz the only other anime content we have is that doesn't involve.
Speaker 0: that is really good But it's really stale.
Speaker 0: Like we haven't written a new anime panel like that because we still go to anime Boston.
Speaker 1: Yeah in five plus years how much the tickets cost for one day man.
Speaker 0: No idea.
Speaker 1: I want to take a look at it.
Speaker 1: What is it?
Speaker 0: I have no idea.
Speaker 0: We have so many paxes to deal with plus magfest that and zenk icon at least for me that I just don't have time.
Speaker 0: Like I'm running out of room to deal with cons.
Speaker 1: Anime NYC which is not the thing that's happening in conjunction legit with with the New York Comic Con this weekend is a different anime con though.
Speaker 1: It's also in the Javits is November 16th through 18th.
Speaker 1: Order by October 15th to get your tickets mail.
Speaker 0: Oh, we can still order them get a mail.
Speaker 1: Yeah, how much are they?
Speaker 0: Let's see who even knows?
Speaker 0: Anyway, I don't know what conventions cost anymore a mega ticket.
Speaker 1: nod some bullshit right there.
Speaker 1: All right Sunday ticket 40 bucks Mmm, maybe we'll see.
Speaker 0: so we watch an anime and we're gonna review it.
Speaker 0: and Before we get into that we need to point out that Akagi and Kaiji are not the same thing Right.
Speaker 1: So who's the creator of this?
Speaker 1: What's the guy's name?
Speaker 0: Oh god Wikipedia brand.
Speaker 1: so this is a person who made these manga and this anime based on two of these mangas And or three.
Speaker 1: it may be three anyway three.
Speaker 1: So first they made one.
Speaker 1: I forget what it's called Because no one's ever talks about it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but there was a spin-off of this manga they created It was.
Speaker 1: it was a manga about mahjong.
Speaker 1: There was a spin-off called Akagi which is also about mahjong and that Akagi became an anime.
Speaker 1: and that's when I first heard of Because I saw this Akagi mahjong anime.
Speaker 1: then there was a brand new thing unrelated to the first things Called Kaiji, which I confused with Akagi But I knew that it was related because I had the same exact art style.
Speaker 1: It was clearly by the same creator.
Speaker 1: the animes and the manga's look the same.
Speaker 1: I thought it was also about mahjong.
Speaker 1: It's not.
Speaker 0: Kaiji is about gambling in general and not just about mahjong Yep, and because I vaguely knew that like Akagi was a spin-off or something.
Speaker 1: and Okay, we got these things confused until just now.
Speaker 0: Yep, apparently most of the internet also confuses and conflates them for what I can tell right?
Speaker 1: Anyway, there was a spin-off of Kaiji that we judged Last season on judging a by its cover called tonagawa middle manager, whatever.
Speaker 0: Yeah There's a lot of different English titles for the chronicles of middle manager to konagawa middle management blues.
Speaker 1: So here's the deal in Kaiji from.
Speaker 1: I've never watched Kaiji But in middle manager, they give you basically summaries of what happened in Kaiji So you can sort of figure out what the deal is.
Speaker 1: It seems like what happened in Kaiji is an evil company, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, and the boss of this evil company was the most evil head boss person and he's bored and he's bored.
Speaker 1: so he got his employees to create this ridiculous gambling game of death and Kaiji the main character of Kaiji got involved in this horrible gambling game of death and That game existed to entertain the big evil guy in charge of the company
Speaker 0: Yep And like the second boss like the sub boss of the show was this tonagawa guy who was like a second.
Speaker 1: It was the second in command was this guy named tonagawa who did most of the work setting up this evil game of death.
Speaker 1: So What is tonagawa's middle manager?
Speaker 1: It's a completely separate anime that shows you how Tonagawa the middle manager second-in-command of the evil company whose boss is the head boss.
Speaker 1: He's basically the vice president.
Speaker 1: Tonagawa is the vice president.
Speaker 1: It shows you how this the main character is the second-in-command guy.
Speaker 1: It shows you the story of how he created the game of death Which I presume is the main plot of Kaiji itself.
Speaker 0: and it's literally like He's thinking about going to golf and he's like a middle manager like doing HR paperwork or whatever.
Speaker 0: And then the big boss is like, yeah, I need you to make a game of death for me.
Speaker 0: So it ruins his weekend and his job like he gets a team together and it's literally just like board meetings and HR shit and like how do I put this together?
Speaker 1: and office jokes like Dilbert?
Speaker 1: Yep, but at the same time like even though he's also a bad guy.
Speaker 1: He's also terrified of his insane boss But he's also trying to keep his.
Speaker 1: you know, the the people below him under control.
Speaker 0: But he's also trying to be like.
Speaker 0: he's trying to be like good manager, right?
Speaker 1: He's trying.
Speaker 1: he's like, you know, his boss is a crazy bad evil dude who everyone's scared of right?
Speaker 1: But he isn't like trying to learn the names of all his subordinates so that he can gain their loyalties.
Speaker 1: That was actually really funny and they all have names that like are too similar to each other and he's going crazy.
Speaker 1: But he's also trying hard to actually remember them and gain their trust.
Speaker 1: But you know, it's like they hate him.
Speaker 1: They like him.
Speaker 1: He's trying to make you know, he takes them to a barbecue to try to make them like him So that they'll come up with good ideas.
Speaker 1: He accepts all their ideas, but then when the boss comes in he has to you know, berate them all.
Speaker 0: now It's pretty funny and I watched a bunch of it.
Speaker 0: We're not gonna finish.
Speaker 1: only watched like three episodes.
Speaker 0: I watched like seven but basically It's pretty funny.
Speaker 0: Like it's worth watching a few episodes, especially like the first couple when he's trying to learn Everyone's names is actually really funny.
Speaker 1: That's the funniest part.
Speaker 0: But as the as it goes on, I guess the problem is you don't actually have need to seen Akagi Akagi kaiji at all, right?
Speaker 1: It gives you these flashbacks and summaries of what happened in Kaiji in like excruciating Like.
Speaker 1: literally the beginning of the first episode is like this very long summary of what happened in Kaiji.
Speaker 1: At least I assume.
Speaker 1: I don't know if the other things happened in Kaiji that they're not summarizing cuz I didn't watch Kaiji.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but I feel like I don't need to watch Kaiji now because I got a cliff notes of it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, cuz it does.
Speaker 0: it spoils stuff like it tells you what happens to him in the end, but on the other hand I don't even though it's summarized the events of Kaiji.
Speaker 1: I don't care about Kaiji or the events of Kaiji.
Speaker 1: So so many of the jokes are referencing or basically tied to the story of Kaiji That it's like oh, here's how they came up with that particular game of death that happened in Kaiji.
Speaker 1: It's like I don't care about Kaiji because I maybe if I had seen Kaiji it would be funny.
Speaker 0: Oh my god.
Speaker 0: the scene when they're.
Speaker 0: that's the other really good scene in the early episodes where they're.
Speaker 0: they're workshopping like High-level ideas for games of death and one of the guys is like what do you say something like what if we make him?
Speaker 0: Play poker, but they're betting their own blood and that was actually a really good idea.
Speaker 1: Anyway, the point is if think if you've seen Kaiji and like Kaiji a lot of the jokes in this show will hit harder.
Speaker 1: I you don't have to have seen Kaiji to watch this show But I think you will because you care less it will be less funny And yeah, there'll be less tying you to it.
Speaker 0: now in one way the concept is really solid.
Speaker 0: take a not really a deconstruction But take any of those anime that have an evil organization with lots and lots of faceless goons.
Speaker 0: that's like always ever present and hyper organized and and Look at it from the back and explore How would you organize like these thousands of goons to be the bad guys in the anime?
Speaker 1: right.
Speaker 1: It's like usually when you watch a typical, you know Show right.
Speaker 1: that's an action show where there's good guys and bad guys.
Speaker 1: You see the mostly focusing on the good guys and a few scenes of the bad guys that you know What they're up to but like the thousands of just faceless dudes and sunglasses who get shot in noir Thundercats, but they show.
Speaker 1: but it was mostly what are the mutants up to and the Thundercats are just dicking around and yeah No, there's not a fight going on.
Speaker 0: That's one thing he man did.
Speaker 0: Well, he meant spent equal time on Skeletor.
Speaker 1: Oh, right But imagine if the show was just like, you know Skeletar and on all what all the days when they're not fighting with he-man.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and he's like preparing to fight, you know Like Starscream.
Speaker 1: just you know, chillin with some energy on cubes or whatever.
Speaker 0: and I really like that concept and the show pulls it off.
Speaker 0: Okay But there's a fundamental problem that makes like.
Speaker 0: there's a poor aspect of the execution in that it'll make really good jokes but then it'll go way out of its way to explain the joke to make sure you've got the joke to double Reinforce what the joke is referencing and it like it.
Speaker 0: almost the jokes are funny But it spent it over.
Speaker 0: it really brings them out too much and just drags everything out too far.
Speaker 1: Right that funny joke about the the getting trying to memorize the names of all the employees It's like that goes on for like minutes.
Speaker 1: It's like it was funny.
Speaker 1: and now why you still?
Speaker 1: it's like someone just keeps telling the joke like hey Why the chicken cross the road to get the other side to get the other side get it And I guess the chicken cross the road to get the other side you get it.
Speaker 1: And on one hand why didn't cross it for like two minutes?
Speaker 1: Someone just keeps going on.
Speaker 1: It's like it was funny the first time but why are you still telling the joke again?
Speaker 0: No on one hand It's clearly parodying the style of Kaiji Like it'll cut to someone who's thinking like well if I do this then he'll do that.
Speaker 1: So therefore lots of internal monologue, which is good.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: I like that a bit of you know, it's just the timing of it.
Speaker 1: Things are stretched out too long Right and there is zero comedic time.
Speaker 1: the timing of the comedy is just wrong.
Speaker 1: It's like a joke is perfectly good and it's just.
Speaker 1: there's no timing whatsoever.
Speaker 0: Yep It's like the literal opposite of Nijijou where the jokes are very simple or absurdist or often completely nonsensical.
Speaker 0: but the comedic timing of Nijijou is so perfect and This completely fails to execute at any point on the timing and cadence of a joke.
Speaker 0: only the content of the joke is conveyed And that's the fundamental flaw of this and I feel like it's a common problem in Almost all of these parody anime that I've seen.
Speaker 1: I feel like what this like the fist of the North Star parody.
Speaker 1: It showed him way better if it was a short show like Devilman Parody, like a Damago Dobutsu Yeah, and they were forced to squish it because they're trying to fill this full episode length.
Speaker 1: I think that's the reason that I think it feels like they didn't have enough material to work with.
Speaker 1: they had to stretch it out Yeah, or they could have just crammed two episodes into one and told more stuff.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that could have worked also but they could have or you know.
Speaker 0: what they could have done too is if they'd aimed it at The audience of people who have already seen Kaiji and our fans.
Speaker 1: I think they did but they.
Speaker 1: it's like they aimed it at them, but they tried to make it so that anyone could watch it.
Speaker 1: It's like they should have given up on the people who haven't seen Kaiji Cuz at least like.
Speaker 0: remember that like mini that Devilman Parody thing that we watched a long time ago Like all those other weird parody anime They tend to do the opposite and they don't explain shit.
Speaker 1: Yeah There was I think it's a fist of the North Star like working in a grocery store one where they're all chibi or something and they Didn't explain nothing which was fine.
Speaker 1: But even then as someone who's seen all fists of the North Star I couldn't even watch it.
Speaker 1: Also, it wasn't funny.
Speaker 0: Yeah Well, that's the thing that that show the content wasn't funny and the execution wasn't good.
Speaker 0: this show The content is great and the jokes are great.
Speaker 0: It's just the comedic.
Speaker 0: timing falls so flat that it really kills the momentum and it's hard to keep watching.
Speaker 1: You know, it is funny.
Speaker 1: What's that?
Speaker 1: The chibi lotus wars?
Speaker 0: Oh The lotus island.
Speaker 1: lotus island also mini Potto, but there's not a lot of mini about.
Speaker 0: yeah mini Potto really relies on having seen Pat Laboire.
Speaker 1: that yeah, it does like.
Speaker 0: if you haven't seen Pat Laboire, you're just like.
Speaker 1: what if you haven't seen Pat Laboire Why why would you even think about watching middleman?
Speaker 1: When you can go watch Pat Laboire which is itself has a lot of comedy in it Even though it is not a comedy, but I guess what I would say.
Speaker 0: I'd recommend watching one episode of this partly because then you'll see what the deal is and You'll see like kind of what the deal is with Kaiji and it'll tell you if you like either or both.
Speaker 1: I would recommend watching Kaiji.
Speaker 1: See if you see.
Speaker 1: if it's a thing you like.
Speaker 1: watch one or two episodes of it is good.
Speaker 1: If not, then don't watch anything ever.
Speaker 1: don't watch any of it ever again.
Speaker 1: But if you do like Kaiji, well, you can finish watching Kaiji.
Speaker 1: And then if you need some humor that will probably you know be not be as lost on you.
Speaker 1: You can then watch the middle manager and maybe even watch Akagi or who knows what.
Speaker 1: anything else created by what's the person's name?
Speaker 0: Oh, I didn't even pull it up.
Speaker 0: You didn't pull it up.
Speaker 1: Nah, I'll look it up.
Speaker 1: It's because we should you know, give credit to be the person.
Speaker 0: Paul Chapman wrote the article.
Speaker 0: I got up here.
Speaker 1: Nobuyuki Fukumoto That's the person who wrote Wow lots of stuff But it seems a lot of it is a Gambling apocalypse.
Speaker 1: Kaiji gambling magnific chronicle.
Speaker 1: Kaiji gambling advent chronicle.
Speaker 1: Kaiji chronicle.
Speaker 1: Kaiji Kazuya art.
Speaker 1: Yeah, okay a very prolific gambling manga writer.
Speaker 0: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brand-ok for the logos.
Speaker 1: be sure to visit our website at front row crew dot-com for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 0: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 1: But unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 0: It's actually recorded at night And the patreon patrons for this episode of geek nights are Craig Oliver Allen Joyce hide to me Nicholas shimmering ruby obelisk hanging in the sky kashar tovish.
Speaker 0: in my state.
Speaker 0: I come like a GJ bad scooter lonely Roberto Kingsley Shawn Yeager Matthew Smith Nicholas brand on mr.
Speaker 0: Strong stretch in 4 to 1 creations.
Speaker 0: Chris Reimer and Thomas
Speaker 1: Hahn
Speaker 0: Jordan van Horl Rory Joe Rochelle, Montana Superboy trip wire sailor Vista Don Schleig Joe Shiro Joe star Clinton Walton Ren from New Zealand Ryan parent rope and lender Finn Chris mid gift Daniel Redmond Shawn Klein Chris Reimer Thomas on and
Speaker 1: No record of a hurricane ever hitting Springfield.