Speaker 1: It's Wednesday, September 19th 2018.
Speaker 0: I'm Brim.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott.
Speaker 1: And this is Geek Nights.
Speaker 1: Tonight, we review the fantastic Night is Short Walk on Girl.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: So I've been actually training myself to do faster half marathons.
Speaker 1: Like I've realized that I can't run short distances as fast as I used to because 35 and 25.
Speaker 1: And that kind of training is kind of hard on me.
Speaker 1: And like my 5k times are never going to get better.
Speaker 1: But old people consistently run very good marathons and half marathons and all those like like 10k and up length races.
Speaker 1: So I've actually been training to do long runs for the last summer as opposed to what I used to do up to that point.
Speaker 1: And it's starting to pay off.
Speaker 1: So I can now reliably do a half marathon under two hours, even if it's hot out, even if I'm tired, even if I don't bring food, like I'm always under two hours.
Speaker 1: So now I'm shooting for an hour 50.
Speaker 1: But more importantly, I found a pretty good route because they fix a couple of, there's a couple of spots, like all the ways I can run 15 or 14 or whatever.
Speaker 1: miles basically either require me to do a bunch of like fiddly navigation around like traffic lights or I have to go way out of my way from a bike path.
Speaker 1: Like if I run north on the east side, the bike path or the running path is broken in a couple of places for construction.
Speaker 1: And if I run around into Queens, I got to deal with traffic.
Speaker 1: And like if I go another way, I got to ride the subway home because I'm not going to run five miles home after I run 15 miles.
Speaker 1: But I found a route that goes a loop into Manhattan and back up through Brooklyn into Queens.
Speaker 1: That's almost exactly a half marathon if I make one tweak to it.
Speaker 0: Why don't you just run to a park and then run in a circle and then run home?
Speaker 1: Because that sucks.
Speaker 1: I like to cover new novel ground.
Speaker 1: Otherwise, running's boring as shit.
Speaker 1: See, also biking.
Speaker 1: You want to just you want to just bike to Central Park and go around it all day and nothing else.
Speaker 0: Are you enjoying the biking or are you enjoying the seeing stuff?
Speaker 0: Both.
Speaker 0: If you're enjoying the seeing stuff, you could just ride a car.
Speaker 1: No, it's both.
Speaker 1: It's traversing distances with different scenery over time.
Speaker 0: Get a Google Maps VR biking hookup where you just bike in place and then you see new stuff on your VR.
Speaker 1: No, that's not nearly as fun because you're just on rollers.
Speaker 1: You're not really biking.
Speaker 0: Put a fan in front of you so you don't even know.
Speaker 1: No, you're still just on rollers.
Speaker 1: I mean, yes, if biking in New York or in the world constituted a perfectly flat level, unchanging distance.
Speaker 0: No, they have one, the trainers that like get harder, that match up with the video and they get harder and easier as the video has hills or downhills in it.
Speaker 1: That's still not, that's still just not, like.
Speaker 1: it's not a terrain.
Speaker 1: It's just flat.
Speaker 1: It's still perfectly flat.
Speaker 1: There's no bumps.
Speaker 0: I guess, I guess it can't bump you.
Speaker 1: I would like it to bump me.
Speaker 0: You want to get bumped?
Speaker 1: Actually, what I'm really going to try now is that a mountain biking course up in sprain.
Speaker 1: Now that I figured out where it is.
Speaker 0: So maybe there's one in Queens.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's not good.
Speaker 1: I looked into it.
Speaker 1: The good one near New York is near the sprain brook highway and like up in the Bronx.
Speaker 1: That's the place to go.
Speaker 0: It's being a biking, uh, because of tariffs bikes in the U S are about to get expensive.
Speaker 0: So if you want, and it's already the right time to buy a bike cause it's fall, which was when new bike models come out and last year's bikes are cheap.
Speaker 0: So if you want to buy a bike, you got about a month to buy a bike.
Speaker 0: And after that, it's not going to be a great time to buy a bike unless you buy like a used one, which then it won't matter.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but it's only going to be like a 20% price increase significant.
Speaker 0: It turns your $500 bike into a $600 bike or your $5,000 bike into a $1,200 bike.
Speaker 0: That is a lot of money.
Speaker 0: Well, unless you're buying $100 bike, then it becomes $120 bike, which is not a big deal.
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 1: The other thing would be if you're like, I'm going to buy some parts that I'm going to need in the near future sooner rather than later.
Speaker 1: The other, the problem is even buying them now, I think the price increases are going to come well ahead of the tariffs actually affecting the supply line by like today.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: This week, the moral is if you voted for Trump, you fucked up and now bikes are more expensive.
Speaker 1: Unless you hate bikes and then you're still a bad person.
Speaker 0: Either way, you think people who voted for Trump like bikes?
Speaker 0: You ever seen a cyclist or the red hat?
Speaker 1: They're in fact the literal opposite of the kind of person who would like a bike.
Speaker 0: I feel like anyone who rides bikes is guaranteed not to be right-wing.
Speaker 0: You ever seen a right-wing bike person?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I imagine if I found a right-wing bike person, they either have one of those cheating things that lets it look like you're on a real bike, but it's actually an electric motor or they just stole the bike.
Speaker 1: So anyway, we got a ton of geek bites because we've been watching a bunch of stuff and we've not been watching the same stuff.
Speaker 1: In fact, I think almost nothing.
Speaker 1: we're watching overlaps except Tonegawa's middle management whatever and Walk on Girl.
Speaker 1: the Night is Short.
Speaker 0: I think I'm done watching Tonegawa.
Speaker 1: I watched two more episodes and I like it, but I feel like I got to watch Akagi before.
Speaker 1: I could truly appreciate it.
Speaker 1: And also as much as I like it, it's not as good as a lot of the other things I'm watching.
Speaker 1: So what do you have to say about Hanabado?
Speaker 0: Oh, so...
Speaker 1: Because we talked about this in Judge Anime, right?
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: So when we judged anime, there was a badminton show and I feel like what we said was like, "Oh, it's a sports anime.
Speaker 0: It'll probably be just like all the other sports animes like Yo-Yo Peddle and Haikyuu, but only badminton this
Speaker 0: time.".
Speaker 0: So I watched one episode of the badminton show and the badminton show is not good.
Speaker 1: Like, what's bad about it?
Speaker 1: I'm just curious.
Speaker 0: So the first of all, it doesn't have any of the comedy or excitement that other sports anime have.
Speaker 0: It is super serious.
Speaker 1: Which could be good.
Speaker 1: I was like, they're super serious, like touch.
Speaker 0: Sure.
Speaker 0: But it has a little bit of the things that Yuri on Ice has, which is at the very start, it shows two people and one of them loses to the other person at badminton.
Speaker 0: And then for some reason, they're both at the same school.
Speaker 0: One of them is in the badminton club, the one who lost, and is all angry at the world and, you know, is mean to all the other badminton club people.
Speaker 0: So the club is going to fall apart.
Speaker 0: And the other person, the person who won and scored all the points and destroyed the angry person, isn't even playing badminton.
Speaker 0: They're playing tennis and they're like a genius.
Speaker 0: They're just like, you know, but they don't even want to, right?
Speaker 1: Well, to be fair, tennis is way more fun than badminton.
Speaker 0: They're the reluctant, you know, prodigy person.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 0: They're all shy and don't want to say anything and don't even want to play badminton.
Speaker 0: Like it's almost like Shinji, right?
Speaker 0: But basically none of these characters have any character or likable in any way.
Speaker 0: It's like there's no character you give a shit about.
Speaker 0: And everyone's taking everything way too serious.
Speaker 0: Like they're crying about badminton club within episode one.
Speaker 0: And then the only character that has any life to them whatsoever is the mysterious person who's clearly some sort of coach who reminds me a lot of the bad perverted coach from the horse show.
Speaker 1: Oh, that's not good news.
Speaker 0: Only there was only one scene of perversion so far.
Speaker 0: And then it's like, we've introduced here, this person's going to help the badminton.
Speaker 0: It's not, no, unless it's not good.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 1: I will refrain from watching it.
Speaker 1: I forget.
Speaker 0: I like, but nope, there's no character in here.
Speaker 1: What's funny is I already forget what we said about this show.
Speaker 1: So I don't actually know if we said pretty sure.
Speaker 0: I thought it was going to be just like all the other sports anime, only badminton, but no, it's worse than all the other sports anime, only badminton.
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 1: So I watched the first episode of the dragon prince, which is actually really, really good.
Speaker 1: So it's on Netflix.
Speaker 1: It's a high fantasy drama.
Speaker 1: The vague gist of it is so it's like slayers.
Speaker 1: So it's kind of, but serious, like a hundred percent serious.
Speaker 1: It's written by this or at least partially written by the same head writer as avatar, the last airbender, which you also haven't seen.
Speaker 1: And which is also fantastic.
Speaker 1: Like if I had to rate it on our old anime scale, avatar is an a anime, a minus at worse.
Speaker 1: Like it's up there with the a shows that we talk about.
Speaker 1: This is basically avatar to not set in that world, like nothing to do with avatar, except that it has a lot of the, a lot of similar tropes, similar writing, similar characters, but it's a high fantasy world where basically elves and humans, like all these different kinds of elves and humans and dragons all live in this fantasy world.
Speaker 0: No dwarves.
Speaker 1: That's fine though.
Speaker 1: Cause there's multiple kinds of elves and there's super hot dragons.
Speaker 1: So at some point there's still like, there's six kinds of magic in the world and there's this whole fantasy thing.
Speaker 1: But then the humans discover the seventh kind of magic, which is basically evil bullshit.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: And they use it and they're like, yeah, we got evil bullshit.
Speaker 1: And the elves are like, ah, fuck, no, get the fuck off our Island.
Speaker 0: Check out my evil bullshit.
Speaker 0: All the elves dead.
Speaker 0: So the
Speaker 1: elves and the dragons just for, well, the elves at least force all the humans to the other side of the continent, put a big wall between the two of them and the king of the dragons, who's just this giant bad-ass fucking dragon
Speaker 0: president of the United States.
Speaker 1: The dragon basically just says, I'll guard the wall between you two sides.
Speaker 1: You never fight again.
Speaker 1: And the humans use the dark sides.
Speaker 0: King of dragons.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So the humans go use the dark magic to kill the king of the dragons.
Speaker 1: And now war is about to begin.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: And the show is, it's a kid's show like Avatar, but Avatar is super good.
Speaker 1: And this is also super good.
Speaker 0: I wanted to see the evil magic be all like evil and like bloodbath.
Speaker 1: Avatar is a bloodbath.
Speaker 1: Do you know how many people die in Avatar?
Speaker 0: No, no, no.
Speaker 0: Like, like, like, you know, violence, like, you know, like berserk or it's like, uh, we'll see how far, how close it goes to that.
Speaker 1: Cause it's on Netflix.
Speaker 0: Like the Netflix Castlevania anime.
Speaker 1: Well, there is more of that coming, which I'm really looking forward to.
Speaker 1: The only problem with it, like the character designs are great.
Speaker 1: The voice acting is fantastic.
Speaker 1: The story is pretty good so far.
Speaker 1: The writing is good.
Speaker 1: The only complaint, and Emily pointed this out because I couldn't articulate it that well, is a lot of people were saying the frame rate is bad on the animation.
Speaker 1: Remember like walk through.
Speaker 0: Wouldn't it be 30 FPS being?
Speaker 1: it's not that the show is 30 FPS.
Speaker 1: It's that the characters look kind of jittery.
Speaker 0: Like when they move like stuttery, it almost looks like, is it animated on like the fours or the sixes or who knows?
Speaker 1: It almost looks like if you took a 24 frame a second cinematic and just put it on a modern television, but only the characters, not like the backgrounds or anything else.
Speaker 0: It's not that just the way they rendered it.
Speaker 1: And the, it's the way that what Emily said, cause she knows way more about this than we do is what appears to be happening is they wanted it to look hand drawn instead of a CG cause it's CG and it looks pretty kind of like walk through.
Speaker 1: It looked great when it was still, but it looked a little weird when it moved.
Speaker 1: So in this case, she said that the characters don't ease.
Speaker 1: They never ease.
Speaker 1: And I didn't, I, now I realize what that means.
Speaker 1: You know, when someone like strikes a pose and then they settle like a little bit, like after they struck the pose, that's easing and this show does not have that animation.
Speaker 1: characters strike a pose and then they're static, but it stops being distracting after one episode and the show is so good that I'm just going to watch anything else.
Speaker 0: So I watched an episode of yellow guy, yeah.
Speaker 0: Assassination classroom, which is an anime I'd heard of many times.
Speaker 0: I don't know how old it is.
Speaker 0: It has a lot more episodes than I thought.
Speaker 1: I've never watched it.
Speaker 1: And all I know about it.
Speaker 1: All I know is that it's the yellow guy, the yellow guy.
Speaker 1: And it's one of those anime premise.
Speaker 1: There are rules shows.
Speaker 1: It's in the genre of.
Speaker 1: there are rules.
Speaker 0: Are you ready for the premise?
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: This is not spoilers because it's all in episode one, which is the only episode I've seen.
Speaker 0: You ready?
Speaker 0: Here's the premise of assassination classroom.
Speaker 0: Everyone on earth looked up at the moon and holy shit, like the moon exploded.
Speaker 0: It's now permanently a crescent moon because a giant hole was blown and it explode because everyone looked up at it at the same time.
Speaker 0: No, you couldn't notice the moon not exploded.
Speaker 0: It was a giant explosion.
Speaker 1: The way you phrase that everyone looked up and the moon exploded.
Speaker 1: So the moon exploded and everyone looked up.
Speaker 0: Anyway, the moon exploded, right?
Speaker 0: The government found out this explosion on the moon that destroyed it was caused by yellow guy.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Yellow guy is ridiculously powerful.
Speaker 0: You don't really know his origins.
Speaker 0: He can travel at mach 20.
Speaker 1: So like cuba or what's his name from the show where all the kids die.
Speaker 1: He's yellow.
Speaker 0: He has tentacles.
Speaker 0: He can change color.
Speaker 0: Who knows what other powers he has.
Speaker 0: He's from the earth.
Speaker 0: He says he's not an alien.
Speaker 0: Uh, and he speaks English, even though his mouth doesn't move when he speaks English, but he has a mouth.
Speaker 1: It just smiles all the time.
Speaker 0: And he basically has threatened the earth that he will destroy the earth after I think a year or some amount of time.
Speaker 0: I think something like a year.
Speaker 0: And the only way that he will not do to the earth, what he did to the moon is if someone, someone kills him.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: He has to be killed.
Speaker 0: He has demanded that he be allowed to teach this class of students how to kill him.
Speaker 0: Uh, and so he's teaching this class of students, which is like, and it's, it's like the delinquent class, like class E.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 0: And they're in this school that is like, you know, an abandoned school.
Speaker 0: So no one else is there really.
Speaker 0: So these students perfectly normal, but low grade students, have to go to this class in the school that's in the woods and he's their teacher and the yellow guy is their teacher.
Speaker 0: He teaches them perfectly normally.
Speaker 0: Uh, he doesn't, you know, he's perfectly good, excellent teacher.
Speaker 0: And, but they're trying to kill him.
Speaker 0: If they kill anyone who successfully kills him, will not only save the earth, but will be paid like a zillion, bajillion dollars by the government.
Speaker 0: And the government has provided them with all manner of deadly weapons that are deadly only to yellow guy and not to them.
Speaker 0: So like they have guns that shoot these little balls and they try to shoot him and they like, he's, he's taking attendance and they're all blasting at him nonstop with assault rifles and Uzi's.
Speaker 0: and like for the whole time he's taking attendance, he's moving around to mock 20, dodging everything.
Speaker 0: And then they're like, you know, oh, we don't believe that, you know, someone questions whether the bullets even actually work.
Speaker 0: So the yellow guy shoots his own arm with one and his arm explodes.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And he's like, no, they totally work.
Speaker 0: You guys just couldn't hit me.
Speaker 0: I was gonna mock 20.
Speaker 0: He goes, he, he flies at mock 20 to get Mavo tofu for lunch from China.
Speaker 1: Ooh, I would do that if I could do that.
Speaker 0: I'm just saying.
Speaker 0: Uh, so it has this comedic aspect, but also this scenario aspect.
Speaker 0: And the thing is on the one hand, it's like, I could watch all of this, right?
Speaker 0: And like, you know, I guess you would learn the characters of the different students and other thing.
Speaker 0: And I, I assume there's this sort of conflict between.
Speaker 0: he's a good teacher.
Speaker 0: What's his deal?
Speaker 0: But we have to kill him to save the earth.
Speaker 0: Who knows what's going on?
Speaker 0: because you see moments where he's evil too.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Uh, but I feel like there's the kind of show where I just want to go right to the end and skip all the middle part.
Speaker 0: And I just want to know what the deal is.
Speaker 1: Read a spoiler.
Speaker 0: I will.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 0: That's what I'm going to do because I don't want to watch 47 episodes or whatever it is.
Speaker 1: That's how I dealt with my desire to know what happens in the attack on Titan while having zero interest in watching any more attack on Titan.
Speaker 0: I feel like it could be fun, but I feel like it's just, it's like, it's just a little bit too shallow and transparent to actually be worth my time.
Speaker 0: So I should just go right to the end and be done with it.
Speaker 0: I feel like I would watch this, but watching it's not bad.
Speaker 1: I, you know, I feel like I would watch this if I didn't have so many other great shows to watch right now.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: It's like, I feel like it's just below the line of something.
Speaker 0: It's like, you could watch it and he'd be cool with that, but it's just below the line where I need to watch it.
Speaker 0: I can just, you know, go see what the answer is.
Speaker 0: So I also kill him.
Speaker 0: Do they not kill him?
Speaker 0: Does he destroy the earth?
Speaker 1: So I know, I think I've mentioned this a couple of times, but because it's Wednesday, I can sort of formally do it.
Speaker 1: Adventure time's done.
Speaker 1: Of course.
Speaker 0: The ending is now done.
Speaker 0: We can know what, instead of us saying, Oh, it's ending soon.
Speaker 0: It is over.
Speaker 0: Like there will never be another tele official television episode of adventure time on Cartoon Network.
Speaker 1: You cannot know more about the Canon of this cartoon than me because I have seen is going to literally every second of.
Speaker 1: it is going to be a movie that does not impact the Canon in any way.
Speaker 0: And there are comic books, which I own many of.
Speaker 1: They're fantastic.
Speaker 1: The comic books.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: Kind of like the pony comic books.
Speaker 1: Those are just like a plus comics.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: But I own all those too.
Speaker 0: I own all the adventure done comics.
Speaker 0: I own a lot of them.
Speaker 1: My gig bite of adventure time.
Speaker 1: Now that I know the fullness of it is that it is one of the greatest cartoons ever made.
Speaker 1: I think it will, that was already true, but it'll stand the test of time.
Speaker 1: Uh, and it ended literally perfectly.
Speaker 1: That ending is so utterly perfect.
Speaker 0: Is my man choose goose in the final episode?
Speaker 1: The voice actor of choose goose.
Speaker 1: I'm pretty sure is in the dragon Prince.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 1: There's a character who comes out.
Speaker 0: I told her in this earlier, I learned today, today I learned this, that the voice actor of choose goose the best character, but also the voice actor of a zillion other things, including candle Jack from freak is what, you know, I'm going to need more rope.
Speaker 0: If you don't have a candle Jack is I'm going to need more rope.
Speaker 1: If you don't know what freak is all it is almost say is that it was weirdly ahead of its time.
Speaker 0: You can put that out today and people would think it was made today.
Speaker 0: If it was an HD, do yourself a favor.
Speaker 1: If you're not caught up on adventure time, don't just go watch the end because it literally sort of needs you to have seen every single episode of the show.
Speaker 0: All the, all the episodes that matter.
Speaker 0: There's no episodes.
Speaker 1: I would say you need to have seen every episode of the show for it's a really, even the Masaki was a weird food chain episode.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: Actually specifically.
Speaker 1: I ain't even shitting you bro.
Speaker 0: It is even the, or even like that early episode where, um, where, uh, what's his name?
Speaker 0: was the voice for the heart guy.
Speaker 1: Oh, Ricardo.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Uh, I think you would need to see that because it does set up some things about why bubblegum does what she does.
Speaker 1: It's.
Speaker 0: you'll see even the episode with the horse on the ball.
Speaker 1: All I'm going to say is that remember that the Lynch said that he is the last scholar of golf.
Speaker 1: The show ends perfectly.
Speaker 1: And I cry every time I watch.
Speaker 0: the ending ends with golf.
Speaker 1: Uh, there's a golf.
Speaker 0: golf is involved related to glob.
Speaker 1: Possibly.
Speaker 0: Possibly.
Speaker 1: It's very secretive spacey.
Speaker 1: Like the, like it's, it, it kind of frames everything nicely.
Speaker 1: That's my favorite part.
Speaker 1: Give me that Prisma boy, but it frames everything nicely and wraps things up appropriately for both the literal reality of the show and all of the themes that have recurred in the show over its run.
Speaker 0: Give me that Prisma and that cosmic owl.
Speaker 1: There's a, the last time you see Prisma is an excellent moment.
Speaker 1: I would say that every character, the last frame that they're on screen is a masterpiece by itself.
Speaker 1: So yeah.
Speaker 1: Uh, the other thing that I'm watching right now is a BoJack season five.
Speaker 1: It's continuing to be excellent.
Speaker 1: It's still some of the best like animation for adults that's out there.
Speaker 1: And season five is already better than a lot of the previous seasons.
Speaker 1: And it hasn't even gotten to quote unquote the good part yet.
Speaker 1: And of course, DuckTales, which I also watched all of and is fantastic and you should watch it.
Speaker 1: And I'm actually really looking forward to season two, which apparently starts in March.
Speaker 1: No, it was renewed in March this year.
Speaker 1: And the second season will premiere in God, late 2018.
Speaker 1: I got to wait a while.
Speaker 0: We've got time for this.
Speaker 1: There's only 23 episodes.
Speaker 1: I found that once I watched one, I just had to watch them all because the show just every episode is better than the previous episode and the episode where it makes a crossover with the gummy bears is pretty good, but not quite as good as the episode that crosses over kind of with My Little Pony.
Speaker 0: Here's the news.
Speaker 0: Care Bears is coming back.
Speaker 1: Oh, God.
Speaker 0: It looks pretty cute.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'm not watching it.
Speaker 0: I'm conflicted on that because what I was saying is I'm not telling you to watch the new Care Bears because I don't even know when it's coming out or I don't care.
Speaker 0: But do look.
Speaker 0: There's like one promotional image floating around.
Speaker 0: Look at that image to see what the Care Bears look like.
Speaker 0: They look pretty good.
Speaker 1: Well, we're in this weird golden age of like bringing this stuff back.
Speaker 0: Yeah, because no one's got any new ideas.
Speaker 1: Not people have plenty of new ideas.
Speaker 1: BoJack's new.
Speaker 1: I guess unless you saw Californication.
Speaker 1: So there is some actual news that isn't just us talking about shows we've watched recently.
Speaker 1: Space Jam 2 is coming with LeBron.
Speaker 0: Oh, baby.
Speaker 1: I'm weirdly excited for this.
Speaker 0: Let's go theater.
Speaker 1: I look forward to the slam and I want to come to the jam.
Speaker 1: See, the thing is, I suspect that the original movie does not hold up at all, but I have not.
Speaker 1: I get this feeling it's not going to hold up.
Speaker 0: Oh, you don't think so.
Speaker 1: I don't.
Speaker 1: We should watch it.
Speaker 1: We've never reviewed it on Geek Nights.
Speaker 0: See, I think the thing with Space Jam is that it was it was merely okay to good to begin with, but I think it is still holds up as okay to good.
Speaker 0: I don't think it is decreased.
Speaker 1: I could see that.
Speaker 1: I remember being okay to good.
Speaker 0: Thing is, is that it loses its novelty to Space Jam's coming back.
Speaker 0: They need to bring back the Quad City DJs, a.k.a.
Speaker 0: 95 South with the Miami booty for the theme song.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Otherwise, it's no go.
Speaker 0: Streets of Rage is coming back.
Speaker 0: They're remaking that.
Speaker 0: If they don't have music by the same person who made the music, I forget his name, we saw him at MAGFest.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we did.
Speaker 0: Who made the music for Streets of Rage?
Speaker 0: one and two and three, then there's no point.
Speaker 0: No matter how good the game is, it's like, no, the music is what made it happen.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: It'd be like if you made a Miyazaki movie and you didn't have some Joe Hisaishi music.
Speaker 0: It's like, just get out of my face with that.
Speaker 1: Like if you made more utenna and didn't put that J like Shazar music in it.
Speaker 0: It's like Initial D without Eurobeat.
Speaker 0: It's worthless.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Literally worthless.
Speaker 1: Initial D.
Speaker 0: If this Space Jam movie has some Miami booty, we're good to go.
Speaker 1: Then we know exactly.
Speaker 1: I'm weirdly excited about this.
Speaker 1: I don't know what to do.
Speaker 0: What could the plot possibly be?
Speaker 0: Monsters come again.
Speaker 0: And they're like, Michael Jordan's old.
Speaker 0: We can beat you now.
Speaker 0: It's like, no, we made a LeBron.
Speaker 1: That is literally the plot I would have pitched like that.
Speaker 1: Exactly.
Speaker 1: With a cameo and everything.
Speaker 1: That is the exact plot I would put in.
Speaker 0: The only other problem is that I think that kids these days did not grow up with Looney Tunes as much as we did.
Speaker 0: I'm sure they still know those characters, but not as much as we do.
Speaker 0: I think what you should do is make it with other characters, perhaps Cartoon Network characters.
Speaker 1: You know what actually would work?
Speaker 0: Or anime characters.
Speaker 1: If you could somehow pull together Roger Rabbit style characters from a bunch of different things because there were those new like Mickey Mouse cartoons that are really good.
Speaker 0: Here's the problem, though, is that original Space Jam worked because the Looney Tunes characters are clearly not athletic.
Speaker 0: Other than Bugs Bunny, who has natural skill at everything.
Speaker 1: Like what's Elmer Fudd gonna do?
Speaker 0: Exactly right.
Speaker 0: But the characters that kids are into these days, it's like, but fucking Jake the dog.
Speaker 0: Jake the dog doesn't need the bronze help as long as he learns to play basketball.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: You're good to go.
Speaker 0: You know, it's like, well, you know, Naruto, Naruto can jam.
Speaker 0: Don't need no LeBron.
Speaker 0: Largo can probably beat LeBron.
Speaker 0: LeBron is going to be on the bench.
Speaker 1: If you got Naruto on your team, it's just going to be a bunch of Fortnite's and that's it like Fortnite's and LeBron.
Speaker 0: I don't know if Fortnite's is stronger or weaker than LeBron.
Speaker 1: Gumball could work because those characters are not athletic.
Speaker 1: The point is, right.
Speaker 0: LeBron can't out basketball Captain America.
Speaker 1: I feel like this could be used instead.
Speaker 1: Here's a counterpoint to catapult and bring back a big Looney Tunes era.
Speaker 0: Go for it.
Speaker 1: Because Looney Tunes could work in the modern era.
Speaker 1: Those new Mickey Mouse cartoons, like all that stuff were really good.
Speaker 0: I think we need to.
Speaker 0: you know, the thing is, if I was writing it right, the way I write this shit is I'd be like, yo, you know, we still don't need the LeBron if I let Cody just bomb the other teams and himself.
Speaker 1: But anyway, things of the day.
Speaker 1: So I have a thing of the day that's really good and interesting, but depressing.
Speaker 1: So I figured I'd save it.
Speaker 1: So instead, this is just a dog feeding carrots to three rabbits and a pig.
Speaker 0: I don't.
Speaker 1: it is literally that this is not a Mustang hits bike bicyclist.
Speaker 0: Did you see that it was a gift going around with his three dogs and they try to give a treat to the dog in the middle and he pushes the treat to the dog on the left.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: And then another treat comes in and he pushes the treat to the dog in the right and helps his friend does because he's a good dog.
Speaker 1: I also saw the one where the guy gives the treat to the first dog and then he gives the treat to the second dog.
Speaker 1: But the first dog grabs and runs away and the second dog just looks up like, what the fuck is also a good one going around.
Speaker 0: I think I see multiples that follow this formula where they were first.
Speaker 0: There were videos people did where they would play like the, you know, the treat in the three cup shell game.
Speaker 0: And the pet would get right.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Oh, the one where the pet got it wrong.
Speaker 0: No, they do it where they have three cups.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: They put the treat under one of the cups.
Speaker 0: They play the shell game.
Speaker 0: The pet takes the shell with the or the cup or the bowl with the treat in it.
Speaker 0: It's one treat.
Speaker 0: And then the owner opens up another bowl that was previously had just been I think I saw there's a little white dog that looks like one.
Speaker 0: And there was a ton of treats in that.
Speaker 0: And then.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And that's that's a funny a lot of these.
Speaker 1: They always there's this one song that was used in Rick and Morty and they cut to that song.
Speaker 1: usually when they make these memes.
Speaker 0: Like imagine if I play the shell game with rim, but instead, you know, you don't start with all the shells open.
Speaker 0: You only open the one shell.
Speaker 0: And then you reveal the one I didn't pick is like I put like a dollar under it.
Speaker 0: I shuffle them all around.
Speaker 0: And then the other one had a gold bar.
Speaker 1: Now the other one's got like an unreleased Advance Wars.
Speaker 0: So it's code to advance.
Speaker 1: So what do you have for me?
Speaker 0: So I don't know if I feel like I've done this thing of the day before, but for almost 20 years, we have loved the radical.
Speaker 0: The fact that we never got a canonical published conclusion, I think, wasn't in the book that we didn't get couldn't get.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but we didn't.
Speaker 1: we didn't get to see it animated speculation.
Speaker 0: So the creator of Radisco is a guy named Joe Sparks, who has an Elvis Presley style haircut and still does.
Speaker 0: And Joe Sparks, after finishing Radisco and going to get jobs at places.
Speaker 0: And I guess those jobs prevented him from making more Radisco in some way.
Speaker 1: There's a whole complicated story.
Speaker 1: There's a situation why he couldn't make more Radisco.
Speaker 0: Anyway, the point is, is that he disappeared to go work as an adult for years and years and years.
Speaker 0: And only recently, maybe less than two years ago, returned to YouTube and has been producing content of various sorts.
Speaker 1: In fact, he has a note on this video.
Speaker 1: you link to a quote.
Speaker 1: I am searching for those millions of Radisco and Devil Devil doll fans from 2001.
Speaker 1: That is, if you know one, please let them know about my YouTube channel.
Speaker 0: I'm here.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Joe, we got your back.
Speaker 1: We're like the O.G.
Speaker 1: fans of Radisco.
Speaker 0: We are.
Speaker 0: But anyway, the point is, is I think I've talked about his return to YouTube before.
Speaker 0: It may have been a previous thing.
Speaker 1: He's still only got like a thousand subscribers.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: This may have been a previous thing of the day, you know, his channel or some video on his channel, but he just put out a new video on his channel.
Speaker 0: And in this video, what's going on is he was at one time an employee at LeapFrog, who I believe made children's fake computers.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, that sounds right.
Speaker 0: And I believe he was some sort of game developer software maker there making games for children's tiny computers for maybe at some portion of his life in between making Radisco and now.
Speaker 0: And while he was there, that company had a talent show and he was in the talent show performing Radisco songs live.
Speaker 0: It seems like he just told the entire story of all episodes of Radisco.
Speaker 0: And this is a video that was of that performance at that talent show that was rescued.
Speaker 0: And he put it on YouTube and is well worth watching because I have never seen a live performance of Radisco before.
Speaker 0: And also, wow, he just makes the Radisco and Deviled all voices.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that he can do that way more naturally.
Speaker 0: They required no audio production.
Speaker 0: He is just a good voice actor.
Speaker 1: I feel like the pro movie for Netflix to pick up and reboot Radisco and Deviled.
Speaker 0: Also, he changes kill to kiss because I think he's talking to children.
Speaker 0: He's performing in front of many children.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well, I think it was bring your kid to work day.
Speaker 0: Well, because one company where they make children's toys.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well, also there's a so Adventure Time has a lot of moments where Finn or Jake or someone will say the words, I'll kill you.
Speaker 1: And in the UK, at least, I don't think this has changed.
Speaker 1: They won't let that be in a kid's shows.
Speaker 1: They usually remove it, kind of like how you can't spit on anyone.
Speaker 1: That's why they cut out all the scenes in Adventure Time where someone spits on someone.
Speaker 0: Well, that's why in the Ninja Turtles live action movie, which is excellent and holds up.
Speaker 0: The Foot Clan is like teenagers and bad people in the Teenage Ninja Turtles cartoon that ran on TV for many years.
Speaker 0: All of the foot soldiers are robots that explode the same as they are on the Teenage Ninja Turtles arcade machine.
Speaker 0: Yeah, et cetera.
Speaker 1: There's there's a. there is a joke about that in Rick and Morty that you would not appreciate.
Speaker 1: So I'll just skip it because you haven't seen that show.
Speaker 1: But it's relevant to your turtles analogy.
Speaker 0: They fight a bunch of guys that robots and then fight a real guy and he believes that.
Speaker 1: So they're fighting.
Speaker 1: So they're fighting a bunch of guys and the kids like, I don't want to hurt anyone.
Speaker 1: And he's like, shoot him.
Speaker 1: They're just robots.
Speaker 1: Kill him.
Speaker 1: They're not shooting them.
Speaker 0: They're not.
Speaker 1: They're clearly not robots.
Speaker 1: And he's like, they're not robots.
Speaker 1: Oh, my God.
Speaker 1: And then Rick is just like, yeah, but I mean, they're like robots.
Speaker 1: I just I don't respect them.
Speaker 0: Before we start the show, I just want to say it's hockey time.
Speaker 1: Oh, it is.
Speaker 1: I even watched the fake hockey preseason.
Speaker 1: No, it was a pretty good game because it went into OT.
Speaker 0: I'm sure he was, but no.
Speaker 1: And the OT was pretty good.
Speaker 1: But very briefly, in the meta moment, if you are here because you saw us at PAX, if you go to our website, there is video of the panel we gave not from PAX West, but when we did it at PAX East, because guess what?
Speaker 1: We did the same panel twice and the entire list is available in that YouTube video.
Speaker 1: Also, the Book Club book is still Homer's Odyssey, apparently, because Scott has an update at the 2001 Space Odyssey.
Speaker 0: We're just going to do all Odysseys called the Odyssey Club.
Speaker 1: And you may know that over a year ago, I started a Civilization V multiplayer game with the Patreon.
Speaker 1: patrons of Geek Knights, like people who are in the Patreon had the chance to join this game.
Speaker 1: It was all humans.
Speaker 1: We played this giant civilization five game.
Speaker 1: The game actually just finished like the game is done.
Speaker 1: We've been playing Civ V by mail for a long goddamn time.
Speaker 1: The game is over, and I am now uploading the series of videos showing the progression of the game in the world over time.
Speaker 1: So you can watch all that on YouTube.
Speaker 1: I just uploaded a video where I titled it "The Raising of Susa" because if you couldn't guess, I burned fucking Susa to the ground.
Speaker 1: I'm sorry, Craig Oliver.
Speaker 1: Rule one of multiplayer Civ.
Speaker 1: Building the great library sends a message to everyone around you.
Speaker 1: And that message is I have built this instead of building an army.
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 0: I built this for you.
Speaker 0: Please accept my gift of one great library.
Speaker 1: Do you have spear men and catapults?
Speaker 1: Well, there is a party here and you're all invited.
Speaker 1: So we've actually talked about a bunch of Masaki Yuasa movies in recent memory because Masaki Yuasa is really productive lately.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and really good.
Speaker 1: And if I had to describe Masaki Yuasa in terms of like the kinds of works I expect.
Speaker 1: Off the wall, kind of weird, little spacey, like that's kind of the way where I'd put it.
Speaker 1: And night is short, walk on girl does not disappoint.
Speaker 0: So, yeah, so hold on.
Speaker 0: I'm trying to bring something up, which is an interesting thing that I learned only at the end of this movie, when after the credits, Masaki Yuasa comes out to speak.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, yeah.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: So this is what I learned, right?
Speaker 0: So there is a person whose name is Tomohiko Morimi.
Speaker 0: Tomohiko Morimi is an author, right?
Speaker 0: And they are the author of Eccentric Family.
Speaker 0: Eccentric Family, Tatami Galaxy, Night is Short, Walk on Girl, something called Penguin Highway that's probably amazing, Adventures of a Saintly Slacker, which sounds amazing.
Speaker 0: And 2016, something called Night Train, which sounds amazing.
Speaker 0: Basically, everything they've written sounds amazing.
Speaker 0: And the things, my only experience of their work, their novels are the anime adaptations, right?
Speaker 0: So Eccentric Family was not animated by Masaki Yuasa, but Tatami Galaxy and Night is Short, Walk on Girl were both written by the same author, the original novels and animated by the same people.
Speaker 1: And there seems to be a trend that at least these things are linked in subtle ways in the anime adaptations.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 0: So, Rim, see, after seeing that thing after the credits, I said, "Well, I feel like I'm not going to be able to do a show on this.
Speaker 0: Night is Short, Walk on Girl, unless I've seen at least some Tatami
Speaker 0: Galaxy.".
Speaker 0: So I went home.
Speaker 0: I've seen now two episodes of Tatami Galaxy.
Speaker 1: And I do plan to watch it all.
Speaker 0: In Tatami Galaxy, within the first minute, I see that Tengu Chin guy.
Speaker 0: Literally, that character is just right there at the start, right?
Speaker 0: The main two characters of Night is Short, Walk on Girl are Crook, slightly so, but are also the main two characters of Tatami Galaxy.
Speaker 0: The minor character in Night is Short, Walk on Girl, the demon in the book.
Speaker 1: The used book, God.
Speaker 0: Yes, a crook, a little bit more than slightly version of that character, is a very main character of Tatami Galaxy.
Speaker 0: The art style is basically identical.
Speaker 0: The mood is very similar.
Speaker 0: The plot is not so similar.
Speaker 0: They're not redundant.
Speaker 0: Just, you know, you think, "Oh, that was only the same character, just the same
Speaker 0: thing.".
Speaker 0: No, it's not the same thing at all.
Speaker 0: They're two separate works.
Speaker 0: They're originally two separate novels, right?
Speaker 0: It's just that because the same animation team was adapting two works from the same author that have some similarities, they kept some character designs and some moods and some things.
Speaker 0: But from two episodes, I can already tell that Tatami Galaxy is fantastic, but we're not renewing Tatami Galaxy.
Speaker 0: I'm just letting you know that I feel like it's hard to fully review one of these things without knowing about the other because there's so much togetherness going on here.
Speaker 1: But at the same time, I cannot stress enough, The Night is Short, Walk on Girl is 100% watchable in a vacuum.
Speaker 0: Yes, either one of these things stands alone.
Speaker 0: If you were to watch them independently, but to fully grok either one, I think you need to experience both.
Speaker 1: So I would actually recommend just go see this movie.
Speaker 0: I don't think it matters which one you see first.
Speaker 1: No, I mean, just like stop listening to gig nights right now and just go see this movie.
Speaker 0: That would.
Speaker 1: this movie is one of the better anime movies I've seen in a long time.
Speaker 1: I went into it knowing literally nothing about it except who directed it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think it's even better than the other Yuasa one we saw with the vampire dog, but that might be because the vampire one, Lou Over the Wall.
Speaker 0: I think it's better than Lou Over the Wall.
Speaker 0: Maybe that's just because Lou Over the Wall is more of a children's movie and I'm an adult.
Speaker 0: If this is not a children's movie, it begins with people getting blasted.
Speaker 0: Yup.
Speaker 1: It's hard to describe what this movie is about without either really spoiling it or getting really, really sort of philosophical because it is very philosophical.
Speaker 1: The plot is expansive in scope and covers probably 500% more ground than you expect it to.
Speaker 0: Basically, the way to summarize it best is that this is girl and it's one night in her life that we're experiencing.
Speaker 0: Yup.
Speaker 1: She's on the cusp of becoming an adult or friends getting married.
Speaker 0: The night begins at this wedding that she's attending and she goes on after the wedding.
Speaker 0: She goes out to drink and starts partying and the night becomes this big adventure, right?
Speaker 1: But in that like time-dilated way that nights like that when you're young feel like they last a lifetime.
Speaker 0: Right, so in this night there are four seasons, right?
Speaker 0: And I think he said the book was divided into four seasons and they sort of compressed the four seasons into one night in the movie.
Speaker 0: I haven't read the book.
Speaker 0: Obviously, it's Japanese.
Speaker 0: I don't think it's translated.
Speaker 0: I think it might be be getting translated though.
Speaker 0: I think I did read something somewhere that they're working on publishing these novels in English.
Speaker 0: I would read them.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I would read them, but the four seasons, right?
Speaker 0: It sort of starts and I think it's starting.
Speaker 0: It starts in spring because it ends in winter, right?
Speaker 0: So that's the, you know, that wedding part and that the parties soon after that are the spring.
Speaker 0: Then there's this summer part and thank you.
Speaker 0: Everything gets hot, right?
Speaker 0: There's an ice kotatsu because they're all melting, right?
Speaker 0: They go to the night book fair like, you know, the cicadas.
Speaker 0: It's really right.
Speaker 0: The hot times then there's then this fall and there starts to be stuff happening at the school and people are getting cold, but I guess and then at the end it's winter and everyone's sick, right?
Speaker 0: And that's sort of the flow of this this one epic long adventurous night that goes through these four seasons and crazy stuff happens.
Speaker 1: And if I really had to try to explain what it's about on a high level like it's it's that feeling when you're young and you haven't really decided what you want to do yet in your life and you're sort of you're just entering the adult world and you're starting to do the things that adults do and everything feels very important.
Speaker 1: Very minor things feel like they're the most important things in the world and it follows someone through like experiencing a night like that like those nights we used to have when we were young like at RIT wandering around at night fighting with sticks and whatever.
Speaker 1: But it also, but it simultaneously has this long-running theme about how the exact same night is very different even for the people who had the exact same experience based on their state of mind and how they feel about the situation.
Speaker 1: Like multiple people have the same experience and they all see it completely differently because of the state of their own heart and mind.
Speaker 1: And you see this illustrated in so many different ways.
Speaker 1: it'd be hard to catalog them like the clocks literally are moving faster for the old people than for the young people.
Speaker 1: Things like that like the school festival which I can only describe as Kill La Kill like that festival like bunker where they're running it.
Speaker 1: it evokes how it felt to be running the RIT anime club back when I was in college compared to now as an adult the reality of what running the RIT anime club was really like.
Speaker 0: Right so not you know.
Speaker 0: the main character is the the girl right who has like.
Speaker 0: we keep saying the girl like she has no name it's just the girl it's literally the girl.
Speaker 1: there's the girl the guy there the characters the other characters.
Speaker 0: some of them have names right.
Speaker 1: so she's just walking on she's just going from moment to moment the world's sort of passing her by and she's interacting with things for the hell of it.
Speaker 1: these
Speaker 0: other characters though all have threads right and it's like everyone's thread gets resolved at some point usually tied up with some other character
Speaker 1: and she's sort of almost a catalyst like as she's passing through the world everyone else's stories keep merging with hers and then splitting off again and then merging with each other.
Speaker 0: yeah it's like this there's a character who's like in the beginning right and like the very opening scene the the guy who doesn't change his underwear and then katsu and then he goes away.
Speaker 0: you don't see him for a while and then later on he comes back and he's real important.
Speaker 0: yeah right uh the only other character besides girl who is sort of there the whole time is guy who is sort of in love with her from afar and keeps chasing her and keeps getting caught in the wake of her adventures but not really catching up to her and it you know coincidentally he
Speaker 1: feels a little bit like a scojo person like in terms of the way scojo
Speaker 0: that doesn't mean anything to anyone who's listening
Speaker 1: a friend of ours.
Speaker 1: i guess a lot of the characters in this evoke not the details of the lives of our own friends but the feeling about those people when they were similarly young and having these experiences like being young and running the anime club and being young and pining after a girl that you know like it's.
Speaker 1: it's all those feelings and encapsulates what it felt like to be 19 and full of vim and vinegar and gin.
Speaker 1: right also there is a lot of flowing this entire hemming away and the girl's superpower is that she can drink an infinite amount of alcohol.
Speaker 0: there's a very important drinking contest and she just keeps going.
Speaker 0: yep uh there's a lot of eating and a lot of food.
Speaker 0: there's a scene where oh the hot nabe which is literally like lava nabe.
Speaker 0: uh you know this and you know at the same time that you've got sort of this.
Speaker 0: you know serious philosophical thing and these character threads.
Speaker 0: it is wacky and kuku bananas right in terms of like the you know in a masaki yuasa way and it just keeps going.
Speaker 1: it just keeps moving like it never pauses the only like the masaki yuasa episodes of uh adventure time adventure time or what was the space dandy?
Speaker 0: yeah it's it's wacky like those.
Speaker 1: very often they're like there's.
Speaker 1: so we could if we did a final thoughts episode where we talked about the details of this movie.
Speaker 1: it could go on for hours.
Speaker 1: but what?
Speaker 1: the other thing does that reminds me there's an america there's a movie a live action movie called punch drunk love.
Speaker 1: that actually does the same thing at least for a portion of its run.
Speaker 1: it never pauses like.
Speaker 1: it never gives you a break.
Speaker 1: it never like pauses to reset or like to establish.
Speaker 1: it just keeps going and going and going and going and going as fast as possible covering so much more ground than you possibly expect and then it ends.
Speaker 0: yeah the pace of this is really really fast and i at the start of the wasn't really cat.
Speaker 0: i felt like i was missing something right.
Speaker 0: but no i wasn't missing anything.
Speaker 0: it's just it was going fast and only giving me the minimum of what i needed to know.
Speaker 0: and then later on you know things filled in.
Speaker 0: things came around a second time a third time and i realized no i didn't miss anything they're just you they're just pushed it to the limit in terms of information.
Speaker 0: they can give you right so that you can catch it all and comprehend everything but they can cram it all into the time they have in this movie before it's over.
Speaker 1: i think my favorite moments without spoiling are like number one is actually early on when all the different drinking parties sort of converge with each other.
Speaker 0: well i mean just when he they learn the dance from the all the sofas and then the old people fucking sofas.
Speaker 1: they go.
Speaker 0: they end up at the sofas club where these kids are doing this weird.
Speaker 0: they seem to be in a cult and they do the sofas dance.
Speaker 0: then they go to some old people and they do the dance and the old people are like oh it's the sofas dance.
Speaker 0: we used to be in the sofas club.
Speaker 0: we started the sofas.
Speaker 1: it's exactly that situation that really happens like when scott and i and a bunch of us ran into the current generation of like the rit anime club and they're like yeah we run the rit anime club we're like son.
Speaker 1: let's talk about the rit anime club.
Speaker 1: we ran that shit.
Speaker 0: hi everybody.
Speaker 1: now we're old.
Speaker 1: it's.
Speaker 1: this movie is phenomenal and i i i am hesitant to use that word about movies usually but i would call this movie utterly phenomenal.
Speaker 1: it is a must-see anime movie like if you haven't yet watched other shows that we've said are good that you should watch or other movies that you should watch just watch this one first before you watch anything else i want to watch.
Speaker 1: i would watch it again right now if i wasn't so hungry.
Speaker 1: this has been geek nights with rim and scott.
Speaker 1: special thanks to dj pretzel for the opening music cat lee for web design and brand ok for the logos.
Speaker 0: be sure to visit our website at front row crew.com for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 1: remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech mondays gaming tuesdays anime comic wednesdays and indiscriminate thursdays.
Speaker 0: geek nights is distributed under a creative commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 0: geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience but unlike those other late shows it's actually recorded at night.
Speaker 1: and the patreon for this episode of geek nights?
Speaker 1: ah craig oliver allen joyce rebecca dunn heidi magnicola shimmering ruby obelisk hanging in the sky kajar tovish in my city dot com.
Speaker 1: jeremy minor link eg j band scooter lonely roberto kingsley kelly snyder amanda duchette sean yager matthew smith nicholas brandau mr strong stretch and 421 creations chris rhymer and thomas han sherman von harl rory james david white rachel monta super boy trip wire sailor vista don schleig joe jiro joe star clinton walton ren from new zealand ryan parent drew openlander finn chris midkiff daniel redman sean klein chris rimer and thomas han.
Speaker 1: what's going on?
Speaker 1: i'm gonna need some finger protection.
Speaker 1: thanks i am choose goose.
Speaker 1: come back for some juice shoes goose.
Speaker 1: i need more armor.
Speaker 1: i've got something for you a metal shoe don't you know?
Speaker 1: you might stub your toe.