Speaker 0: It's Wednesday January 24th 2018.
Speaker 0: I'm rim and this is geek nights tonight Mary and the witch's flower Let's do this.
Speaker 0: So I did something I've been planning on doing for a long time But I just even if I had done it I just never would have had time to use it.
Speaker 0: so I actually have some free time now that we're back from the Month of conventions and travel.
Speaker 0: so I actually got some VR.
Speaker 0: I got an oculus in this house.
Speaker 1: you have nothing else to spend your money on.
Speaker 0: wasn't that expensive actually?
Speaker 1: Okay, so it's rich person.
Speaker 0: I uh it's not like I need to buy a new video card.
Speaker 0: Uh-huh, I already have a video card.
Speaker 0: in fact the cost difference between what I paid for my video card And what that video card would cost right now in light of all the people mining stupid coins Pretty much a breakeven as though.
Speaker 0: I bought the video card now.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's a good time.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: you're weirdly down on everything.
Speaker 0: That's good in the world.
Speaker 0: So I'll assume that you'll never try it and you'll never see cocoa and cetera, but so yeah, it's pretty cool.
Speaker 0: I'll talk about it on Tuesday in depth But I must say if you get a VR thing whatever it is the only thing I got to tell you is that The game you need to play is super hot VR.
Speaker 0: It is definitely super hot mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: Alright, what do you already got?
Speaker 0: What's your opening vid?
Speaker 0: What's going on in your life?
Speaker 1: Going to work trying to not go to work, but have to go to work.
Speaker 0: It's real easy to not go to work anymore Don't go.
Speaker 1: I want to be able to eat and also keep my apartment.
Speaker 0: You can also not get your apartment for a some amount of time if you stop going to work.
Speaker 1: How about as long as I live all right?
Speaker 0: Well then you got to go to work.
Speaker 1: I don't want to go work though.
Speaker 0: you Thought I think do you want a snack?
Speaker 0: Do you want a nap?
Speaker 0: I don't think there's any way out of your situation short of like Full-on communism, and then I feel like you're just gonna be going to work.
Speaker 1: This is this is the problem.
Speaker 1: you see.
Speaker 1: Now come to the same conclusion that I have Go to work despite not wanting to go to work.
Speaker 0: see I must say The fact that I have a new job.
Speaker 0: I actually like going to work, and it's a weird experience.
Speaker 1: We'll see how long that lasts.
Speaker 0: It's lasted longer than it's ever lasted at any job.
Speaker 0: I've ever had.
Speaker 0: That's saying something mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: So yeah, it's anime day.
Speaker 0: so once again if you found this show because we were at mag fast or packs unplugged or pack south And you ought to know what the deal was This is it.
Speaker 0: and also This is the Wednesday geek nights which means we're gonna talk about anime and since we don't really you probably We're only going to gaming conventions these days.
Speaker 1: Yep, so you're probably found us because of some gaming content, and you're like.
Speaker 1: Maybe you are a nerd and also like anime Which you should because that's the whole point of geek nights is that you shouldn't be a nerd who only likes one thing like Silver Rage spider-man guy, but maybe you don't like anime in which case just avoid us on Wednesday.
Speaker 1: or Welcome to the world of anime.
Speaker 1: It's good.
Speaker 0: Yeah, now if you want us to appear at your anime convention hate to say it But we kind of just don't really do anime cons anymore.
Speaker 1: I mean we could but he had to make it worth it right?
Speaker 1: It's like you know I only have so many vacation days to get away from the awful work I just mentioned and for me to use it on a convention like anime convention the problem.
Speaker 0: You know it's got to take something Yep and that's something it has to be more than just paying for our travel and accommodations because Actually a lot of cons offer that to us, and we just don't have time anymore.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I need you got a cut.
Speaker 1: you got to make it so that it's worth using the vacation days necessary to go there Yep, or make your kind of one-day con in New York.
Speaker 1: then on a weekend Yeah, we're very likely to come as long as it's not in the same weekend as fucking Pax unplug next year.
Speaker 0: I'm plug pack south pecs east.
Speaker 1: I guess I'm going to and man why see?
Speaker 0: yeah anime NYC.
Speaker 0: We were locked in 100% gonna go until fax unplugged announced their dates for the same weekend.
Speaker 0: Yep, so yeah We'll probably see you at a New York ad.
Speaker 0: I feel like if that New York thing They're already selling badges for next year.
Speaker 0: yep, but we just don't know the dates of unplugged for next year.
Speaker 0: nope I'll try to find that out.
Speaker 1: mm-hmm Say anyway got any anime news animation news, so this isn't really a news that affects anyone listening to this show.
Speaker 1: Right, but there's more.
Speaker 1: I want to say about this right.
Speaker 1: so your petal is a show that I watch.
Speaker 1: It's not a good show.
Speaker 1: It's an okay generic sports anime Just has to be about biking.
Speaker 0: so I probably better than initial D as much as I like it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's definitely better than initial D and also some of the characters are cool.
Speaker 1: even some of them aren't.
Speaker 0: yeah.
Speaker 1: Anyway, there's only one really cool New season started and to give you an idea of the pace of this sports and may versus others Basically the story is that they're in high school and every year There's a big race.
Speaker 1: so the it took two seasons To basically build up to the start of this race and then the second season they finished the race and then quite a Quite an expanded timeline there and in season season two is basically just just the race.
Speaker 1: season three They build up to the first ray the second race because they're in the second year of high school and the race begins.
Speaker 1: and now We're watching season four which is Started basically in the middle of the first day of the second year's race on the first day and I assume That the most of the right the inter high Yes, it's the inner high.
Speaker 1: I assume the most inner high, right?
Speaker 1: I assume most of the rest of this season will be Finishing this second year race and that in the fort the fifth season the third year of high school will start anyway.
Speaker 1: Your pedal is having its 12.
Speaker 1: That's right 12. live stage play in Japan.
Speaker 0: Wow, right.
Speaker 1: so People don't think anime fans don't think about these a lot cuz like theater is a very local You know thing like you had to live near the theater and you have to go to it specific time.
Speaker 0: the theater.
Speaker 0: anime adaptations that people in anime fandom mostly know about are the utenna ones and it's mostly because It's not like there's been any more utenna.
Speaker 0: So anything more in that universe is something that the fans of that anime will latch out to no matter what it is, right?
Speaker 1: But it's like people don't necessarily realize you think about.
Speaker 1: too often at least people fans outside Japan Like there are actually a lot of live-action stage plays even musicals depending on the whatever of Anime adaptation.
Speaker 1: right we think about adaptations from manga to anime from TV to movies Yeah from to video games to novels to all these different mediums, you know You know crossing and christening go taking the same story and readapting it to live-action TV, right?
Speaker 1: But this the medium of theater people don't think about that adaptation very often Especially if you don't live near theater or think about theater Right, but there are tons and tons and tons of animes and nerdy things that have been adapted to stage plays Especially in Japan and no one thinks about them ever Outside Japan.
Speaker 1: the few times I've delved into like reading about we've seen we've seen Sailor Moon ones We've seen utenna ones in the past right back.
Speaker 0: I don't want to generalize cuz I definitely have not seen enough to have an opinion but all the ones I've seen Were pretty bad.
Speaker 0: I didn't say they're good like Pretty bad, and I'm just gonna leave it at that.
Speaker 1: The point is that they exist right and I think The fact that they still exist I think there's actually probably money to be made by going and digging up Recordings of all the ones ever and starting to subtitle them and put them online.
Speaker 0: I go one step further.
Speaker 0: I think there's money to be made in the US taking other fandoms and just doing this shit.
Speaker 0: I mean look how many people.
Speaker 1: well no see the prop the thing is right.
Speaker 1: They tried this.
Speaker 1: they're not stupid.
Speaker 1: They tried to do spider-man on Broadway and it no worky.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they lose all the money Wasn't that?
Speaker 0: just because they made it bad I mean.
Speaker 1: on the other hand like Disney on Broadway works really well, but those are musicals.
Speaker 0: to begin I guess the spider-man one.
Speaker 0: the problem was that they were like really over produced this technical aspect of it and spectacle aspect.
Speaker 0: But these anime ones tend to be pretty low-budget.
Speaker 0: I Mean, but you guys crank them out.
Speaker 1: You're gonna crank it off Broadway.
Speaker 1: only people in New York can see it.
Speaker 0: Hey Only people in New York can see it as a viable demographic.
Speaker 1: I mean how many times you gonna put it on stage three like there's off-broadway shows about really really obscure shit And they sell for it.
Speaker 0: The previous stage play shin inter high hand heat up ran from only in Tokyo from October 19th To October 23rd.
Speaker 0: These things do not run long.
Speaker 1: It's like it was worth it for these people to make this thing happen for like a week for a week.
Speaker 1: Oh, it's like really you put that much effort into it Or maybe it sucked and they didn't actually put that much ever to do it into the bare minimum.
Speaker 0: to make it happen You should have run spider-man like just for a week off-broadway with like piderman level production value.
Speaker 1: I just I think this is untapped market of in general adapting nerdy things to the medium that things don't get adapted to.
Speaker 0: well the way you make money off of that is you.
Speaker 0: I mean Look at like in gaming cons Tabletop because nerds do love musicals and theater.
Speaker 1: Look at the few times and I can think of there was that What's it called the thing with the guy with the hammer on his chest?
Speaker 1: nerds love that shit, right?
Speaker 0: Well, really?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I guess you never saw any of that Dr.
Speaker 0: Horrible sing-along vlog, right?
Speaker 1: That's the one I was in the room while someone else was watching.
Speaker 0: What do you said?
Speaker 0: the dude with the hammer for a second?
Speaker 0: I thought you were gonna be referring to Gallagher.
Speaker 1: No, not that guy.
Speaker 1: He's not he's a comedian Or possibly Gallagher.
Speaker 0: to.
Speaker 1: the point is that I'm saying nerds do like this shit.
Speaker 1: But that but and also think about is not being targeted enough.
Speaker 0: I mean look at like the world of just doing your D&D game on a stage.
Speaker 0: Yep, the penny arcade ones are literally like the best there is and they're crazy popular.
Speaker 0: even one step down not great.
Speaker 1: Imagine if someone did a. oh my god Someone should make a tabletop RPG, but it's musicals and this karaoke involved and that's specifically made for doing on Twitch.
Speaker 1: Yeah and then we'll get people who can actually sing to do it.
Speaker 0: basically what you're up against your primary competition if you go down this Road is whatever garbage is already at like the cosplay skit review at your anime con Mm-hmm, if you can get above that bar, you can probably make a meager living if you don't live in a big city Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: Yeah people in the theater club are usually nerds.
Speaker 1: Yep, right?
Speaker 0: So in some other news every year we go to the New York International Children's Film Festival Because the New York International Children's Film Festival has a ton of great animation and anime Yep, and we always see this.
Speaker 1: No one else knows what that is like.
Speaker 1: if I showed it to you on YouTube you'd be like what the hell is this.
Speaker 1: But like it's after going to the theater so many times when I see it It's like I rarely go to the theater.
Speaker 1: most of the time I do go to the theater.
Speaker 1: It's to a screening that begins with that fucking thing.
Speaker 0: It's like seeing the toy logo come up.
Speaker 1: You're like, ah, yeah most Most people don't know what that is.
Speaker 1: But I Most of the time I go to the theater.
Speaker 1: I'm seeing the toe.
Speaker 0: So at that time look at right now there's a ton of good stuff to see.
Speaker 0: as always I think what I'm gonna go see is My Twitter, you know, we talk about it when we do it.
Speaker 1: Isn't there at Maru hosted a movie or the next year?
Speaker 0: So there's a Lou over the wall.
Speaker 1: What's that?
Speaker 0: You've seen a bunch of images from it because Anna Twitter tweets about this kind of often Mm-hmm, but it's about a sort of Mermaid girl with the soul of a pop star and Shapeshifting like magic nonsense and it looks really cute.
Speaker 1: Sounds good.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: So Lou over the wall.
Speaker 0: I want to see The show in white Fang.
Speaker 1: What's that?
Speaker 0: What?
Speaker 0: What do you mean?
Speaker 0: what do you mean?
Speaker 0: What's that?
Speaker 1: I don't know what that is.
Speaker 0: You don't know.
Speaker 0: Okay, I'm not gonna dignify that with a response I'm just scrolling down it.
Speaker 0: a shark big fish and begonia.
Speaker 0: this Chinese animated movie actually looks pretty good Hilda.
Speaker 1: actually I've seen pictures of that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and they're showing Horace Prince of the Sun.
Speaker 1: The real Horace Prince of the Sun looks like it in subs.
Speaker 0: I assume so.
Speaker 1: I haven't seen that since a VHS at RIT.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I've also not seen this since a VHS at RIT.
Speaker 1: Horace Prince of the Sun is the kind of thing that only Scott likes.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's slow and old and weird just like night on the Galactic Railroad.
Speaker 1: It's a little bit less slow than night on the Galactic Railroad But it's the same feels that that is notable.
Speaker 0: you're watching it alone at night in the dark quiet kind of feel for having a Scene where the cat guy very slowly walks over to.
Speaker 0: it looks like a not old Horace Prince of the Sun Let's see celebrates the golden anniversary of a mythical tale from fame.
Speaker 0: studio Ghibli founders Blah blah blah film spark in this East meets West.
Speaker 0: take on sword in the stone.
Speaker 0: Did you have it?
Speaker 0: I. Maybe it's just.
Speaker 1: I don't think it's the original.
Speaker 1: I can't tell that doesn't look like it down here.
Speaker 0: It doesn't look like it.
Speaker 1: That is not the horse.
Speaker 1: Oh, maybe that's it.
Speaker 1: Maybe it is.
Speaker 0: You know what it is.
Speaker 0: You've never seen it except in the like Fourth generation VHS fansub bootleg.
Speaker 1: that is the form that I have seen it in.
Speaker 0: Yes, because I got to say I've seen a few like even watching the remastered utenna.
Speaker 0: It's like night and day Compared to what I remembered especially start seeing like cell.
Speaker 1: Maybe someone did a good job preserving the cells for Horace Prince of Sun.
Speaker 0: But if you're a fan of animation at all the New York International Children's Film Festival is a must-go-to event every year.
Speaker 0: we're there every year and you should also be there and Buy your tickets soon because shit sells out.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the big screenings usually sell it immediately but anyway things of the day.
Speaker 0: So, I don't know if any of you know who Adam Neely is, but I've been a fan of him for a while.
Speaker 0: I know Brad Neely is so he's got Washington.
Speaker 0: So The question asked in this video and you might have seen this kind of made the rounds in social media So you might have seen a link to it.
Speaker 0: What is the slowest music that is humanly possible?
Speaker 1: couldn't wouldn't it just be one note like do forever?
Speaker 0: So arguably that would that be music or is that just a static event?
Speaker 1: Don't give me your semantic arguments.
Speaker 0: It's got.
Speaker 0: we're all about the semantic argument.
Speaker 0: No, I'm not.
Speaker 1: I'm specifically thinking semantic arguments are pointless.
Speaker 1: I don't care.
Speaker 0: Song only has one notes.
Speaker 1: It has another note.
Speaker 1: It's just so slow.
Speaker 1: You're not gonna live to hear the second note.
Speaker 0: That's very different.
Speaker 0: There's just one.
Speaker 1: no infinity from now.
Speaker 0: So this gets into that infinity.
Speaker 0: from now We will play the next note, you know There actually is a musical piece that's gonna be going for hundreds of years That is in progress and in 2020 the next it's gonna shift to the next note.
Speaker 1: There's also like this silence forever.
Speaker 1: Is that a music?
Speaker 1: When people have released musical tracks that are just quiet?
Speaker 0: Ah, so one argument you made in this video is that if there's just one note Then there's no possible frame of reference or state change for another note.
Speaker 0: So you can't say that it's a long song.
Speaker 0: there isn't.
Speaker 1: it's just so long that you have.
Speaker 1: it was just quiet forever.
Speaker 0: I I'm gonna say that that's just not music.
Speaker 0: Uh-huh.
Speaker 0: Yeah, however What if I told you that the slowest possible human music is 33 beats per minute?
Speaker 1: I'll just make a song this 34 beats per minute.
Speaker 1: I mean your brain two beats per minute.
Speaker 0: You say that your brain that there's sort of a human limit where kind of like.
Speaker 0: how if you look if you listen Well, I won't.
Speaker 1: you won't hear the next beat.
Speaker 0: if it's if it's at that Will not associate the two events together as music or as a rhythm or even as a pattern Unless you in your brain maintain a separate Faster rate of counting and you count the time off.
Speaker 0: But things that are just a little bit faster than 33 beats per minute Your brain will naturally beat and be able to keep track of.
Speaker 1: well That's still a semantic argument because what if I was a goldfish?
Speaker 1: then me Human human?
Speaker 0: I said human.
Speaker 0: the question as human is very specifically about human.
Speaker 1: What if I'm a dog?
Speaker 1: so maybe we should make different music for dogs?
Speaker 0: Yeah, we probably could and I feel like the dog music could be all about just a voice screaming you want to go for a walk doo doo doo doo.
Speaker 1: Hey, that could make money.
Speaker 1: Yeah Get a CE at mp3 people click on on Spotify and suddenly all the dogs are happy.
Speaker 1: people would be clicking on that shit.
Speaker 0: Actually, the better prank would have a normal.
Speaker 1: you click on these songs on Spotify if you want to make your dog sad happy Normal YouTube video and in the middle of it in the person like a side show different albums are different pets.
Speaker 1: Oh, you want to make your bunny hop around play this?
Speaker 0: No You make it a prank.
Speaker 0: instead in the middle of like a normal video like a SciShow The person doing it just turns the camera and says hey Hey, you want to go for a walk you want a treat and that's gonna cause problems for anyone who owns a dog.
Speaker 0: Okay, so you got a thing of the day.
Speaker 1: I do have a thing a day.
Speaker 1: So lately the the show that's getting the most talk in the anime land is the devil man.
Speaker 0: Yeah, which is funny because I still feel like some people are hype about it because they've seen a lot of buzz about it.
Speaker 0: I'm not saying it's bad.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna watch it.
Speaker 0: I have high Is good show.
Speaker 1: people are hype about it as a girl.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but the point is but I think a lot of people Who don't know?
Speaker 1: What it is when you mean they're watching it?
Speaker 1: That's why they're high.
Speaker 0: I've seen a lot of people who seem to be hype about the media around but I haven't actually watched it yet anyway.
Speaker 1: So the point is that I think the only thing is people who are seeing devil man now and seeing how good it is.
Speaker 1: They actually don't know much about going a guy or old devil man.
Speaker 1: Yeah It's actually a point in the show where a kid using a computer goes to YouTube and plays the old devil man theme song and opener and like people in the show are like devil man, isn't that that old show?
Speaker 1: and Anyway, so, you know gonna guys resurgence here.
Speaker 1: Thanks to the Masaaki washes adaptation of devil man.
Speaker 1: So I found this related thing of the day.
Speaker 1: also going a guy is the video that shows you all of Mazinger Z's special attacks every single one after the other and you can see how awesome Mazinger Z is.
Speaker 1: and Basically this, you know, the three main works of going a guy at least as you know.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right is you got Mazinger Z the robot you got you know, cutie, honey Right the sexy hero and then you combine them to make double man The sexy hero.
Speaker 1: that doesn't know if it's it's it's demon or God or whatever.
Speaker 0: Oh actually so kind of related that first movie I talked about for the film festival.
Speaker 0: Lou over the wall That's a Masaaki Yuasa.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 0: There you go In the meta moment.
Speaker 0: if you saws at a convention We're bit by bit posting videos of many of the things we did at those conventions.
Speaker 1: So I I coded up That's different.
Speaker 1: No, that's not something we did at a convention.
Speaker 0: Nope.
Speaker 0: It is not it's not.
Speaker 1: but yeah, we recorded the winter.
Speaker 1: Whatever.
Speaker 0: judge anime by its cover.
Speaker 1: judging of anime.
Speaker 1: judge Scott and rim judged all the animes and the anime chart.
Speaker 0: as you see.
Speaker 0: That's how we're because we're not going to anime cows.
Speaker 0: We're doing our anime con content on YouTube.
Speaker 1: I made I encoded the proxies and now I can start editing it like today tomorrow.
Speaker 0: You know what the best thing about having a modern computer is.
Speaker 0: I just don't bother with proxies anymore.
Speaker 1: Oh, whatever.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna put it all I did a multi cam with heavy color correction and multiple 4k video streams.
Speaker 0: I can just play it at double speed in real time.
Speaker 1: I'm just gonna go, you know, probably that by this weekend.
Speaker 1: I should have it done and put together and whatnot?
Speaker 1: bad.
Speaker 0: So we have actually I have a lot of videos queued up to publish.
Speaker 0: So yeah, I just uploaded a carcass own learn and win from packs unplugged.
Speaker 0: I also upload balance in game design from packs out which is extra important because our goal is for you out there to post that balance in game design Video in every stupid forum thread where someone's complaining about how something is unbalanced.
Speaker 1: If anyone says Sutton's Opie or Sutton's unfair they want something nerve right then you should post a link to that YouTube video.
Speaker 1: But yeah, check us out.
Speaker 1: I mean if you are already listening to eat knives You must have already checked us out and all the places on the internet.
Speaker 0: This could be the first time they've ever checked us out But I feel like the podcast is not most people's first introduction to us.
Speaker 1: No I think what you got to do now is you've got to find some other nerd and tell them Don't listen to you guys.
Speaker 1: It's a waste of your time.
Speaker 0: Good, but If you tell enough people to listen to geek night do not do this.
Speaker 1: there is a Very low hate you when they say why did you recommend this awful shit to me?
Speaker 0: There is a very low but non-zero chance that it would someday allow Scott to not have to work Except on this and then he would be marginally happier.
Speaker 1: Do not send us your money.
Speaker 1: unless you send me enough money to pay rent in New York City in which case send me all Your money.
Speaker 0: they have sent us some money on the patreon.
Speaker 1: Do not send that money to rim.
Speaker 0: that's gonna fund our convention.
Speaker 1: that is not a place to send your money.
Speaker 0: Otherwise the book club book is Emily Wilson's translation of the Odyssey, which I'm gonna start reading Probably this weekend.
Speaker 0: It's time.
Speaker 1: I'll read it soon.
Speaker 0: I'll read it.
Speaker 0: I'm here.
Speaker 1: I bought it on Kindle right away, but it was on sale.
Speaker 0: That's why I did night's we very pretty much whenever there's an anime movie that makes it into the u.s We pretty much say if it's not like Pokemon 50 or like Digimon 12, like if it's a standalone anime movie.
Speaker 0: Might as well.
Speaker 1: just watch it's night.
Speaker 1: It's gonna be 90 minutes to probably two and a half hours at most of your time And it's probably gonna be worth it.
Speaker 1: It was an anime good enough to get picked up put into theaters in the u.s.
Speaker 1: Probably worth seeing.
Speaker 1: so this is anime called Mary and the witch's flower.
Speaker 1: It's an animated movie full-length animated feature Yep, and it was made by a new studio called studio Pana which I think is a check word.
Speaker 0: They said yeah A lot about them.
Speaker 0: I already knew about them, but baby learn more based on the interview We saw after the movie.
Speaker 1: right but studio Pana what happened was Miyazaki retired for the hundredth time and people thought that was gonna be It for reals cuz he seemed a little more serious than the last time.
Speaker 1: yep.
Speaker 1: So people at his studio at Ghibli were like well, we want to make some fucking anime movies.
Speaker 1: What are we gonna do without this guy isn't?
Speaker 1: we're not making any movies here.
Speaker 1: Let's go make our own okay, so they went and they made studio Pana and then Miyazaki came back and said goddamn it I keep smoking, but I'm not dead yet The die making an anime and he's making another anime And he came back.
Speaker 1: so but meanwhile these people already had left and made their own deal.
Speaker 1: So the first movie the studio Pana produced was Mary and the witch's flower Which is picked up by G kids which is the you know the company that distributes most of the anime movies of big name All the Ghibli's and such in the US and other places.
Speaker 0: which means if you live in New York You can just go see it in the theater.
Speaker 1: You can see in the theater a lot of still in the theater.
Speaker 1: It's a limited run, but you can see it in a lot of theaters in major places in the US and other countries I'm sure.
Speaker 0: so it actually grossed quite a bit in the u.s.. Yeah people I mean relative to an anime movie 1.5 mil alright.
Speaker 1: So it's Mary and the witch's flower.
Speaker 1: the first thing.
Speaker 1: by these you know Ghibli runaways the people with Ghibli skills who were employees at Animators there, but they left to go work on this instead.
Speaker 1: So how did they do?
Speaker 1: we went to see it?
Speaker 1: Okay, right, so we didn't know beforehand that when we bought tickets months in advance But the seven o'clock showing was dubbed and the eight o'clock showing was subway bought the seven o'clock And then we found out it was dubbed later however.
Speaker 1: So we saw the dub, but we don't know anything about the sub, but I will say the dub was competent.
Speaker 0: it seemed fine.
Speaker 1: It was good that the voice acting was good job.
Speaker 1: on the voice actors they done good.
Speaker 1: It didn't sound like an anime dub like you here on TV Yep.
Speaker 1: So that was good and it also.
Speaker 0: it does not feel like The dub took any significant liberties or anything like.
Speaker 0: I don't think if we watched it subbed We would get a have a different impression of the movie.
Speaker 1: It's hard to tell.
Speaker 1: I mean it's probably not that different.
Speaker 1: I don't think the movie was edited.
Speaker 1: The movie was not edited in any way But I don't know.
Speaker 0: I can't compare the dub script to the Japanese cuz I don't speak Japanese But I will say this based on the kinds of like there were the parts of the dub that didn't work.
Speaker 0: Really feel like those were structural problems with the movie and not anything with the dub taking a liberty, right?
Speaker 1: So this is based on a novel as many Ghibli movies are the little broomstick by Mary Stewart, right?
Speaker 1: Which is I guess a popular children's novel that I never read.
Speaker 0: I had never heard of it or read it.
Speaker 0: It's some British thing.
Speaker 1: I think I kind of maybe heard of it in the distance.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I definitely never read a page of it.
Speaker 1: I wouldn't be able to find it in the bookstore.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so the story is let's go marry and for some reason her parents are busy and she has to go live.
Speaker 1: They're all gonna live with Graham or aunt or great-aunt great aunt and instead of living where they lived before.
Speaker 1: but she goes ahead and starts living with the great aunt while she's bored and the parents are still living somewhere else for the Time being.
Speaker 1: and she's bored at this Ghibli esque Ghibli house in the woods and you know what I hate to say.
Speaker 0: this TV doesn't work.
Speaker 0: You're gonna see why she's bored cuz I like like.
Speaker 0: the movie was good like, okay, like I enjoyed it, but they spend a long time With her being bored hanging out in Ghibli land, right?
Speaker 1: So then she goes into the woods and oh my god adventure.
Speaker 0: So we're not gonna really stereotypical plot we're not gonna really spoil because again It's not gonna spoil it but It's only okay.
Speaker 0: It feels like half of its problem is that it feels like a knockoff Ghibli movie.
Speaker 1: But isn't that what it is?
Speaker 0: Yeah but the thing is when there's a studio breakup like when someone like breaks away to make a studio like this the ways it could Go are it's just a knockoff and it's bad or it's just a knockoff like doing the same kind of thing.
Speaker 0: But it's great like more of the same like.
Speaker 0: if it was just another great Ghibli movie That would have been fine.
Speaker 0: And the third way they can go is they say they go in a vastly different direction.
Speaker 0: This felt like it was cleaving very closely to how Ghibli movies go But it just wasn't that well Written.
Speaker 0: it wasn't that well put together.
Speaker 0: It was paced oddly.
Speaker 0: It was kind of lazy and It kind of doesn't make sense.
Speaker 0: And the worst part about it is that if you try to read into it you can you can make an argument.
Speaker 0: I see where they were going with this.
Speaker 1: But even that illusion was ruined for us because I think if you make a movie You can't just see where you're going.
Speaker 1: You have to get to where you're going.
Speaker 1: Yeah before the movies done They didn't rooms.
Speaker 1: rooms is where you get right?
Speaker 1: So first of all, there's some characters in the movie that are like don't do much and it's like why are they even there?
Speaker 0: Like broom guy who's funny, but he's literally guy is a deus ex machina like three times.
Speaker 1: All he is is broom guy.
Speaker 1: He has never doesn't do anything else except really really get excited about broom.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna give you the example here this dude.
Speaker 0: Literally the first magic thing you see like the magic creature you see is this like animal person who shows up and is like Ah, you've got a broom and you're not taking care of it.
Speaker 0: You gotta take care of your broom.
Speaker 0: And then he proceeds to like tell Mary how to take care of her broom.
Speaker 0: And then he takes her to enroll in witch school.
Speaker 0: Don't worry about why we're at witch school now.
Speaker 0: And then he takes her to this sign and the sign clearly shows like four numbered rules.
Speaker 0: and then he's like.
Speaker 0: there's four rules about this place and The first rule is if you fuck up you get trained.
Speaker 1: if you're a trespasser you get trans.
Speaker 0: Yeah If you're a trespasser you so an animal person shows her the first rule.
Speaker 0: and the first rule is if you trespass you get transformed.
Speaker 0: Doesn't even mention the other three rules that are clearly written on this side and then runs away.
Speaker 1: And then as soon as the like headmaster's the school appear he runs and everything else the guy ever does in the whole movie is Talk about brooms and show up.
Speaker 1: when this broom trouble you might be thinking all he says is why don't you take care of your broom?
Speaker 0: ah, ah You might be thinking.
Speaker 0: Oh, I assume that he was trespassing and was transformed and there's a story there now.
Speaker 0: No, no, there's nothing like that.
Speaker 0: No, he shows up at that moment.
Speaker 0: He shows up later to be like, ah, you're not taking care of your broom.
Speaker 0: Here's how to take care of your broom.
Speaker 0: he shows up again to be the deus ex machina and That's literally it.
Speaker 1: yeah, and a lot there's other characters that appear and do almost nothing like.
Speaker 1: there's the the boy character who is.
Speaker 1: It's like she likes him and they there's like this tiny amount of interaction in the big setup part But not much.
Speaker 1: and but suddenly she cares about him a whole bunch.
Speaker 0: Well, yeah, and she's I guess it said because you can read a lot in it.
Speaker 1: She being married the main care.
Speaker 0: yeah, you could make a lot of inferences and ideas about what this movie is really about but after the movie.
Speaker 0: there was an interview with the creators at studio and They pretty much said that the movie is exactly the face value that it looked like.
Speaker 1: Yeah I think the thing is when you see a Ghibli movie Right is not only do you get this story that is approachable to children that is straightforward and such But you also get this sort of.
Speaker 1: you know, subtler, you know thing going on right where there's another message, right?
Speaker 1: Like, you know thing about the first one lava - right where it's like, oh, okay.
Speaker 1: So, you know rescue the girl from the bad guys.
Speaker 0: But no really lava - is the environmental storytelling of the world itself, right?
Speaker 1: This does not have that.
Speaker 1: It's literally just a children's movie.
Speaker 1: Just like all the other Gennaro children's movies of your childhood that you saw.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like the Thumbelinas or the whatever like this movie is a series of Chekhov's guns Just laying all over the place and the main characters just kind of walk by him And then at the end you see him in the credits, but at no point do they fire?
Speaker 0: It's just.
Speaker 0: it's really long and kind of badly paced and it wasn't nothing was that long.
Speaker 1: It was normal movie like.
Speaker 0: I guess it felt long because it kind of didn't really know.
Speaker 1: Jedi felt long.
Speaker 1: It was long literally.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but last Jedi felt longer than Lawrence of Arabia, which is the longest.
Speaker 1: That's not.
Speaker 1: I don't know if it's literally the longest but it's among the longest.
Speaker 0: Yep, but it also sort of has this problem where Mary in particular but some other characters, too they react strongly to things that it doesn't make sense for them to react that strongly because there was no context for that kind of Reaction.
Speaker 0: or they don't react very strongly to something that feels like it should be a bigger deal.
Speaker 0: and that happens repeatedly and I guess every theme that you that seems to be woven into the plot Just sort of Peters out by the end and the story ends up being very simplistic.
Speaker 1: The the animation is like pretty good animation, you know, it's a. it's a movie.
Speaker 1: you got a lot of money's put into it, but it's not.
Speaker 1: it's obviously not as good as Like the the top tier animations.
Speaker 1: It's not as good as shinkai animations.
Speaker 1: It's not as good as the host of the animation.
Speaker 0: It's more like
Speaker 1: like even not being someone who's knowledgeable art You can just tell looking at it right like character
Speaker 0: designs in particular the environment designs felt kind of lazy Like you've got Ghibli world and then the rest of it everything that isn't Ghibli world is Kind of a really chaotic mishmash of things that have no like.
Speaker 0: there's no thematic way to link them together.
Speaker 1: I think that the a lot of it is just the design of the characters and other things is not really That good overall, you know, it's like you think.
Speaker 1: look at like Princess Mononoke and there's like, you know The part where the boar is covered in the slime monster.
Speaker 1: It's oh my god, you look at it and it's just like fascinating to look at it, right?
Speaker 1: It's like holy shit.
Speaker 1: Look at that fucking thing, right?
Speaker 1: Someone came up with that and animated it and it still looks incredible today.
Speaker 1: yep, right, but in here this is like a slime ish monster at one point in this movie and You know, it's like it goes through Stage.
Speaker 1: look at looking at it doesn't really give you any kind of feeling the way that the the Mononoke board.
Speaker 0: Well at one point it looks like a Dragon Quest slime which really doesn't fit at all with what's going on in that scene.
Speaker 0: No, and then it looks like a weird toddler with hair and it just the plot does.
Speaker 0: the Motivations of the villains in this movie do not make sense.
Speaker 0: No from any standpoint And I like a good example of this.
Speaker 0: and again, I'm just not gonna spoil stuff, but to give you some context There's a point where basically Mary ends up at this witch's school and the head mistress and like the head chief professor come out and they're like, oh you're the new student and they just bring her in and You feel like it's setting up a situation where you see all these students.
Speaker 0: there's like this giant Harry Potter ask magical University with tons and tons of students and As you go through you sort of get this sinister vibe because as you get to the more and more advanced students It seems like there's something wrong Like the students at the high level are all wearing sort of Yiga clan masks and it almost seems like it's fake.
Speaker 0: Like maybe it's all a trick and you're trying to figure out what's going on And then all those students just kind of disappear and never met never appear again in the rest of the movie.
Speaker 0: Nope, like all the things that you find everything that I thought was interesting disappears before the end.
Speaker 1: Yeah, why did you introduce these students if they're not in the rest of the movie?
Speaker 0: that creepy-ass room with all the students who are invisible and like doing their weird magic and their masks and all.
Speaker 0: they're all Depersonalized.
Speaker 0: and then she casts a spell to make herself disappear.
Speaker 0: and it felt like that scene felt like it was going somewhere.
Speaker 0: It goes nowhere and never comes back.
Speaker 0: And I just felt like that happened almost everything I was interested in.
Speaker 1: and it's the other thing.
Speaker 1: it does something in the plot That actually bothers me and a lot of other.
Speaker 1: It's this thing that happens in a whole.
Speaker 1: it feels like it happens in a lot of other especially anime movies Where you go to the magical world, right?
Speaker 1: You go back home for the magical world and then you go right back to the magical world, right?
Speaker 0: It's sort of like this this short trip back and forth thing Right that happens and it's I think it's even worse though cuz the at the end It's like, you know, like Bilbo was by his journey.
Speaker 1: They make like getting to the magical world and back home like a plot point like it's difficult to do or something And then it just sort of happens for you know, right.
Speaker 1: so way too quickly without a lot of effort It's like oh no, how will I get back to the magic world?
Speaker 1: Oh, look I did it.
Speaker 1: Yep It's like shouldn't it have been?
Speaker 0: also Mary comes back and she's changed and that she's no longer ashamed of her red hair.
Speaker 0: But at the same time part of the story around that is that all the witch people tell her that red hair is special and Also, she is totally fine.
Speaker 0: Which is resuming her normal life and never seeing magic again.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm course It kind of makes sense because the moral of the movie seems to be that brooms are really important to this one guy.
Speaker 0: magic sucks Like magic just sucks and magic schools suck and stay away from magic.
Speaker 1: It's they can.
Speaker 1: they mix magic.
Speaker 1: Basically love magic and science technology together.
Speaker 1: because you know, right science that becomes sufficiently advanced But they don't do anything interesting with that.
Speaker 1: and then you know, well, they show you like Oh grandma's house or whatever.
Speaker 0: Even the TV doesn't work.
Speaker 1: There's no technology or science or magic there whatsoever Right compared to the other place.
Speaker 0: and that is that could be an interesting contrast.
Speaker 1: They're trying to draw but they don't draw it as well as you know.
Speaker 0: now she could cause it Because you could almost read the moral of this movie as yeah technology sucks.
Speaker 0: Fuck that live in this ghibli boring paradise It's.
Speaker 0: it's hard to says this movie was just a hodgepodge of stuff all thrown together And it won.
Speaker 1: you have a real.
Speaker 1: I wonder how the original book is right because we know that some you know We like Earthsea we know is just a bad adaptation.
Speaker 1: Right because the book is incredible.
Speaker 0: well Earthsea had a lot of the same problems actually in that it had a bunch of Disconnected elements thrown together without a consistent story consistent theme consistent style, but it was animated beautifully.
Speaker 1: But I wonder if the the book of Mary the witch's flower was actually good.
Speaker 1: Adaptation was bad or it might be a really good adaptation of a bad book.
Speaker 0: So we also saw the same thing with how's moving castle which kind of didn't make a lot of sense.
Speaker 1: No, it's a nice at least house moving castle.
Speaker 1: I was like awesome character.
Speaker 0: I was not bored at any point.
Speaker 1: during hell's moving on some calcifer action.
Speaker 0: I was confused but not bored as many redeeming qualities Although the plot is often like what's going on, but like I would watch hell's moving castle again.
Speaker 0: Yeah, sure Why not?
Speaker 0: I would watch Earthsea again with the sound.
Speaker 0: Oh with the sound off and no subtitles.
Speaker 0: No, but I don't know if I ever need to see Mary in the witch's flower again.
Speaker 1: I don't need to see it again.
Speaker 0: I think it would.
Speaker 0: it would be a good movie especially the dub though For to like watch with a younger kid if you actually got kids.
Speaker 1: you're looking for a movie to go see my and for some Reason this movie was rated fresh on Rotten Tomatoes.
Speaker 0: Everyone seems really into it.
Speaker 0: It's weird.
Speaker 1: I know it's like we're sort of saying like it's bad but it's like it's not.
Speaker 1: it's like it doesn't seem like it has Negative qualities.
Speaker 1: He's lacking Extremely positive qualities.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I would rank it in terms of my.
Speaker 0: it's not like.
Speaker 0: it was like.
Speaker 1: if a movie's bad I can be like, oh it was boring.
Speaker 1: It was slow.
Speaker 1: It was right.
Speaker 1: It's like.
Speaker 1: what can I say bad about this?
Speaker 1: It was like it was me.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it didn't have good exciting bits and that's you know, it's like I can talk about the positive things.
Speaker 1: It's lacking but it's like there wasn't really any major Mistakes or badnesses done in it.
Speaker 1: It's not like there was like anime, you know, ugly animations, right?
Speaker 1: It's a movie.
Speaker 0: credible animations from good from like okay to good with just some basic editing like.
Speaker 0: there are a bunch of Medial like side points and side plots that appeared and seemed solely to add ten minutes to the runtime and then disappear like Oh, she's got another berry.
Speaker 0: Oh, she lost the berry.
Speaker 0: Oh, she got that berry back.
Speaker 0: Oh, she didn't need it.
Speaker 0: Anyway, like all this stuff happens that could have been cut out because it was literally immaterial to anything in the movie.
Speaker 1: Oh, you didn't see the magic tablet.
Speaker 1: Did you know?
Speaker 1: I did not magic tab like London or something as the anime movie about self-driving cars and It also had some problems like especially with pacing and other things.
Speaker 1: but I think magic tablet is definitely better than this movie.
Speaker 1: It's better than the witch's flower.
Speaker 0: Yeah but I the one thing I can say is as much for saying it was a. we spent a long time breaking the movie down and I don't want to say making fun of it, but there are a lot of Things that were not intended to be funny in the movie.
Speaker 1: But in looking at the movie having seen it are funny in retrospect You almost want to see it just so you can laugh at broom guy jokes.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like it is in a stupid Scottish accent brooms like that guy It's just all but like the villain, right?
Speaker 1: The is it worth 90 minutes to whatever is two hours of your life to get the broom.
Speaker 0: joke Like the vague overall plot is that the people running the school sort of have this trans humanist Evangelion like experiment they want to run to like bring their school to the next level of like human evolution.
Speaker 0: but What actually happens in the movie is?
Speaker 0: Scientists does experiment.
Speaker 0: it goes horribly wrong in the past.
Speaker 0: now in the current movie Scientists does the exact same experiment under the exact same circumstances.
Speaker 1: Oh, no the same thing happened.
Speaker 0: How could this be?
Speaker 0: Just things like that are funny, but not funny in the context of the movie itself.
Speaker 0: So I still think you should watch it.
Speaker 0: it's not bad.
Speaker 1: I mean, it's still an anime movie that you know, you can see.
Speaker 1: there's not a lot of them.
Speaker 1: It's a written original work at least out of its adapted, but it just wasn't very well like my expectations for this.
Speaker 0: Yeah, don't go higher.
Speaker 1: Yeah, don't go in expecting a jubilee level movie.
Speaker 1: But you know, it's still probably worth watching.
Speaker 1: if you're an anime fan It's orchid.
Speaker 0: it's better than Earthsea.
Speaker 1: in an absolute sense That's right, but I don't think it's always so is the poop that came?
Speaker 0: but I don't think it is better than any other Ghibli movie any other Ghibli movie even the I Can't think of one that I would rank this better than because it has so many just structural flaws.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: It's funny though how we still say she watch it.
Speaker 0: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Speaker 1: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 0: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows It's actually recorded at night.
Speaker 0: and the patreon patrons for this episode of geek nights.
Speaker 0: Ah Craig Oliver Alan Joyce Rebecca Dunn Heidi McNichol a shimmering Ruby obelisk hanging in the sky my stady calm Jeremy minor genuine but if I'd like to fix car mother L Cold guy Amanda Duchette Shawn Yeager Matthew Smith Nicholas Brando captain jinga waka.
Speaker 0: see 421 creations.
Speaker 0: No I never ever wonder why we're here.
Speaker 0: semper fi bitch Sure Not horrible rare.
Speaker 0: Laval James David White Rochelle, Montanona Superboy rims have something funny here.
Speaker 0: sailor vista Don Schleich Czar tavish and Joshua Joe star Sam Cordray Clinton Walton Ren from New Zealand Ryan Perrin drew open Lander Finn Chris midkiff Chris Knox Daniel Redmond Sean Klein Chris Reimer and Thomas Han.
Speaker 0: I'm real tired and lazy.
Speaker 0: So I'm just leaving you with.