Speaker 0: It's Monday July 8th 2019.
Speaker 0: I'm rim Scott and this is geek nights tonight the dark web.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: So over the weekend we went back to Racha to visit some friends.
Speaker 0: City of Rochester that birthed us into this world as a functioning semi.
Speaker 1: adults spab some 4th of July festivities Especially since you know we couldn't.
Speaker 1: the fireworks in the city have moved to where we can't see them.
Speaker 1: Story of fireworks yeah, but we already saw those on Thursday, so what reason is there to stay in town?
Speaker 1: not much.
Speaker 1: So to get to Racha cha there's three options to get there.
Speaker 1: reasonably reason way.
Speaker 1: number one Drive a car for six hours now fucking sucks.
Speaker 1: It sucks Six hours each way by the way.
Speaker 0: I've done that.
Speaker 0: drive many many many.
Speaker 1: It is unpleasant.
Speaker 0: take route 17 well.
Speaker 0: I guess now I 86. yeah anyway.
Speaker 1: So I wanted to avoid that.
Speaker 1: so option two is take Amtrak and then have someone pick you up.
Speaker 1: the train station is in a Shitty place the train is unreliable, and it still takes for fucking ever.
Speaker 1: you're better off in the car.
Speaker 0: however I would say you're not better off in the car because You can take a sleeper car which costs basically nothing on a fucking ever.
Speaker 0: yeah, but you know what?
Speaker 0: You basically just hang out in a private comfortable room anyway with good with pretty good food and internet the whole time.
Speaker 1: option three is pay Some money, but actually quite a reasonable amount of money yeah, and fly there.
Speaker 1: you spend some time waiting at the airport.
Speaker 1: But even with the airport time which is what like an hour Maybe right on each end waiting for the plane You know you gotta get there a little early.
Speaker 1: get their security right.
Speaker 1: the plane is literally like up snacks land.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like 45 minute like you know And the flying time is like 40 minutes or less.
Speaker 0: like the rest of the time is the taxi way.
Speaker 1: like the plane takes off You get in the air they turn the seatbelt sign off you take out your switch You start playing Mario maker, and yeah, it's like all right.
Speaker 1: We are now landing.
Speaker 0: It's like I didn't even finish one episode of Voyager cuz.
Speaker 0: I'd one episode I hadn't watched so I started.
Speaker 1: They bring you the cheese.
Speaker 1: It's you open them you eat them you throw them out your land.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's great It's totally worth the money if you can afford it.
Speaker 1: I mean, it's actually compared to like you know if you think of the total cost of car ownership You know in the gas and stuff.
Speaker 1: I guess you have a lot of people in the car.
Speaker 1: you're saving a lot of money driving yeah But less people.
Speaker 1: it's like if you're only one person driving.
Speaker 1: It's like the plane is actually pretty comparable price wise and it's the plane is the Amtrak Which is the worst of the three is no cheaper than the money by any means.
Speaker 1: so I do like long Amtrak rides But the problem is that costs time yep, and while I wore that amount of money You get a lot more time hanging with your friends.
Speaker 1: You don't see a lot in Rochester Yeah, and I'll even better comfort and a lot easier weekend.
Speaker 0: So what's funny is that?
Speaker 0: The real like the reason we're talking about this before we do the rest of the show is that for a long time like I?
Speaker 0: Don't like jet blue anymore.
Speaker 0: like they're really like they're late a lot and Usually Delta is actually cheaper depending on when I'm going like I fly Delta like 80% of the time when I fly these days.
Speaker 0: yeah I usually and many times I fly Delta.
Speaker 0: a friend of mine flies jet blue.
Speaker 0: I arrive on time.
Speaker 0: They're three hours late.
Speaker 0: that happens a lot.
Speaker 1: usually I fly jet blue But these days since jet blue has gone downhill.
Speaker 1: it used to be I flew jet blue when it was more egalitarian.
Speaker 1: now They've still get now.
Speaker 1: They've got first class and stuff.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we used to have no classes.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it used to just be all the seats are the same.
Speaker 1: It was great anyway.
Speaker 1: You know back in those days You know I flew jet blue all the time.
Speaker 1: But now I basically just go on Google flights or other comparison sites and get the cheapest flight that is the most convenient time.
Speaker 1: That's well.
Speaker 0: That's direct and is not Spirit Airways or an equivalent.
Speaker 1: right exactly never From a real legit airline.
Speaker 1: that's not garbage like not flying United.
Speaker 0: But normally I would not fly jet blue because they're not that great anymore, but they do happen to fly to Rochester.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they happen to fly at a good time, and I used to fly jet blue a lot.
Speaker 0: I had so many jet blue points that I just used them to buy.
Speaker 1: these guys didn't think about my points.
Speaker 1: I probably could have also gotten because I never used a jet blue point.
Speaker 0: I want to get use the points and then just never fly jet blue again, but anyway.
Speaker 1: So I flew Delta because the instead of jet blue because it was the price difference was minuscule like 10 bucks or something each Way.
Speaker 1: the Delta was slightly cheaper, but the times of the Delta flights are much more convenient.
Speaker 1: We're gonna leave right relatively early on Thursday on the 4th of July.
Speaker 1: yeah get to Rochester early party party party And then leave Rochester early on Sunday get back home in New York in time for lunch and have a great old Sunday in New York.
Speaker 1: So getting to Rochester everything was a-okay.
Speaker 1: going home.
Speaker 1: Well, I woke up to get you know thinking all right Let me get my stuff together.
Speaker 1: head over 10 minutes to the airport right you know?
Speaker 1: I look at my phone And it says flight delayed a few hours.
Speaker 1: I'm like all right.
Speaker 1: Well.
Speaker 1: That's fine.
Speaker 1: I'll just you know not get up.
Speaker 0: Yeah, hang out more.
Speaker 1: I'll hang out some more.
Speaker 1: eat a little food hang it.
Speaker 1: You know it's like three hours or whatever.
Speaker 1: I'm like all right hanging out for three hours three hours.
Speaker 1: Go bye Check my phone, it's the delay time has not changed whatsoever, so I'm like all right.
Speaker 1: I guess I'm going to the airport.
Speaker 1: I'm glad I didn't have to sit at the airport for three hours.
Speaker 1: Go to the airport and we get there and when we get there It still says you know the time.
Speaker 1: it said on the on the phone, and I'm like all right.
Speaker 1: It's cool.
Speaker 1: We're gonna sit here for like 30 minutes, and then get on plane right and then the time changes.
Speaker 1: They push it ahead like a couple hours, and I'm like well, that's Not the worst food in the world here meanwhile.
Speaker 0: I took because I did jet blue.
Speaker 0: I flew.
Speaker 0: I was flying home at like six o'clock p.m.. On Sunday.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I decided partly because I want to show the family home.
Speaker 1: our plane was leaving Rochester at 11.
Speaker 0: I would have been home and New York at like noon And I had planned a day of doing stuff with a family like in the Rochester area on Sunday And then getting home having dinner, and then just going to bed.
Speaker 1: right the flight was delayed until like three.
Speaker 1: So I'm hanging out at the airport like to something and then suddenly It's like oh by the way four five Okay, well we're just gonna hang out here, and he gets to the point.
Speaker 0: There's no reason to leave and come back at this point right I head to the airport For my like 6 p.m.. Flight and lo and behold there's Scott There.
Speaker 1: it's like they.
Speaker 1: you know it was delayed that perfect amount of time.
Speaker 1: where if it was delayed a one hour longer than that I would have left.
Speaker 1: I would have called my friends and left and come back all right But it was just that right amount of time where it's like.
Speaker 1: oh not really worth it to leave and come back.
Speaker 0: You know I wish airlines if they're gonna be that delay do not be optimistic just be like yo.
Speaker 1: this flight is not coming Yep, so basically what had happened was there was at the original delay was because of troubles at JFK Which also delayed rims fly.
Speaker 0: my flight was delayed an hour to six from five.
Speaker 0: they warned me way in advance So we just left for the airport way later.
Speaker 1: Yep, but then aren't my specific plane Right had some kind of mechanical problem, and they were.
Speaker 1: they delayed it more and more Right.
Speaker 1: and then there were flights.
Speaker 1: there were two other Delta flights to New York that left basically on time Before our flight left.
Speaker 1: yeah, they were scheduled.
Speaker 1: their skiff lights were scheduled for like 6 p.m.
Speaker 1: To LaGuardia.
Speaker 1: that plane left before my 11 a.m.. Flight to JFK.
Speaker 1: They brought you that like sad Little Caesars bought a whole bunch of pizza for everybody to give me 5,000 miles I don't know how much if that's a lot or not.
Speaker 0: That's That's an okay amount of miles.
Speaker 1: actually whatever the point is they kept changing the delay, but like an hour at a time Making us stay at the airport when we probably could have left and came back You know two or three hours later.
Speaker 0: the last time I had a flight delayed that long as when I was trying to fly to Chicago for a conference.
Speaker 0: it was like a one-day conference.
Speaker 0: I was like gonna fly in the morning.
Speaker 0: do a conference fly home like the next morning Yeah, so the flight was delayed for hours.
Speaker 0: I was just like fuck it And I just canceled the whole trip and went home.
Speaker 1: what actually ended up happening is that plane that was supposed to fly us was Clearly just broken.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they took a plane from some other flight delayed that flight Yeah, used it for 90 minutes to fly to Rochester and back.
Speaker 1: So what's funny is from right and then gave that and then those other people who had to get on that flight That we were borrowing their plane for night there.
Speaker 1: So they were delayed 90 minutes or two hours while that plane was being used to bring people to Rochester eight hours late.
Speaker 1: I actually feel worse for the people who are going to Rochester eight hours late than us going to New York.
Speaker 1: After eight hours you're in New York, but also, you know if you're in Rochester, it's like you could you know Despite it being an eight-hour delay.
Speaker 1: I was only at the airport three four hours because we showed up way late.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if you're if you if I would I is it going to JFK?
Speaker 1: I would have had to go to JFK on time.
Speaker 1: You can't go out and come back in with that kind of security line.
Speaker 1: It's not like Rochester where the security takes two minutes, right?
Speaker 0: JFK security takes zero amount of time because I appreciate you have been extorted.
Speaker 0: you allowed yourself Because my company bought it for me.
Speaker 1: your company paid an extortion fee.
Speaker 0: You pay the big to get the services and the goods.
Speaker 1: the point is hey the big good.
Speaker 1: But if you leaving JFK got to admit to the cruel realities of an evil world and pay the big no If you leave JFK, even if you do Right, you're gonna take an hour air train ride.
Speaker 1: then you take that all the way to Manhattan to take the train ride back.
Speaker 1: There you go that you didn't get to do anything because it took right.
Speaker 1: you can leave LaGuardia.
Speaker 0: You can walk out and like walk to places where the LaGuardia Community College.
Speaker 1: Where are you gonna go?
Speaker 0: There's a few restaurants and stuff over there.
Speaker 0: Yeah, whatever Hang out in that park.
Speaker 0: at least the one time I remember I was flying to Istanbul and The person who booked the flight for me, which was literally the last time I ever let anyone booked my flights instead of doing it Myself, they booked me through London and I missed the connection.
Speaker 0: There weren't any flights to Istanbul for 12 hours.
Speaker 0: So I had 12 hours to hang out in Heathrow which has horrific lines often to get into it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but anyway.
Speaker 1: So I spent quite a few hours in the in the airport got home to New York way late Lost my afternoon in New York that I was expecting to have.
Speaker 0: Oh and also you got home and as soon as soon as you landed you were able to open up Chat and see that I had left you a friendly message warning you that the air train is fine But the e-train is F.
Speaker 1: I just paid a bunch of money and took a cab.
Speaker 0: We were gonna take a cab, but then we didn't.
Speaker 1: there were no lines for cabs.
Speaker 1: actually There was no line for what was happening the.
Speaker 1: actually when we landed we were a terminal for you were probably terminal 5, right?
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: Yeah a terminal for when we landed was a complete shit show.
Speaker 1: We were like the only Arrival and I didn't have checked bags.
Speaker 1: So I just got in the cab.
Speaker 1: There was no line.
Speaker 0: Oh, you wanna know what's going on?
Speaker 0: There were a lot of other flight delays.
Speaker 1: There was like a mega mega shit show going on taxiing right because there's only one runway for departures.
Speaker 1: So planes were having a hard time leaving JFK.
Speaker 1: So we actually had to wait on the on.
Speaker 1: you know The taxi around the JFK waiting for a gate to open to let us off the plane.
Speaker 1: So we spent like 10 minutes just waiting to get off the plane Even though we it was such a tiny flight.
Speaker 0: It's funny that happens a lot because JFK is currently under construction.
Speaker 0: So well, there's several like there's runways that cannot be used if the wind gets too high.
Speaker 1: and then when we got into terminal 4 And we had we were basically they let us in the gate.
Speaker 1: That was at this far.
Speaker 1: far I know that of the terminal we had to walk all the way.
Speaker 1: That's like a 20 minute walk on all four different people movers to get back to them the shopping mall zone.
Speaker 0: Of course, that's also the terminal that has the weird the secret way out.
Speaker 0: if you don't have a check bag It just takes you right out of the term.
Speaker 1: I did that too but the point is we As you're walking.
Speaker 1: it was a complete madhouse on both sides of the people mover Every single flight we passed.
Speaker 1: we were looking to see if they were delayed and whatnot.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there were huge lines like to board planes, but the people weren't boarding they were just crowding around waiting to board.
Speaker 1: They were all international flights Copenhagen Prague and all these European flights Amsterdam Madrid.
Speaker 0: Another thing was going.
Speaker 1: all of those planes were waiting to depart.
Speaker 1: They couldn't leave because they had the single runway for departures.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so the whole terminal all the way down right?
Speaker 1: Well, I walked the full lane.
Speaker 1: It was just just a complete shit show.
Speaker 1: And it's like well glad I'm not going to you know, like London at 9 o'clock at night.
Speaker 0: Yep, which I Okay, I often would fly.
Speaker 0: Well, usually I fly back from London like a Sunday.
Speaker 1: So anyway Airport yesterday was bad Yep, lost half a day in my life.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: Oh, well, I Spent my day having fun and my flight was only too late an hour and everything worked out.
Speaker 0: So the moral is always fly Delta except that one time.
Speaker 1: Don't be unlucky.
Speaker 0: Yeah, don't be unlucky.
Speaker 0: JFK needs a lot more money to get fixed up.
Speaker 0: Anyway, that's the real moral.
Speaker 0: So there's a lot of tech news.
Speaker 0: Yep Let's start with this Quote unquote instructional video thing.
Speaker 1: So someone had their YouTube video taken down and the reason given for the video being taken down was that they were teaching people how To hack and break into system.
Speaker 0: now already what I ask is one What is the line?
Speaker 0: Yeah, what is the dev like?
Speaker 0: does lock picking count?
Speaker 1: Yeah, this is the thing It's like.
Speaker 1: I've seen a lot of security related YouTube videos showing you how to break security or like Def Con.
Speaker 0: You know Panels, how do you know so much about elevator hacking?
Speaker 1: right there is tons of this content on YouTube and tons of it is educational.
Speaker 1: The YouTube claims to have an educational exemption, but isn't all of it educational?
Speaker 1: yeah, like wouldn't literally any video showing you how to get through or Circumvent a security measure be an educational video.
Speaker 1: Yeah, please by definition.
Speaker 1: There is not.
Speaker 1: it's like okay We're gonna have a ban on sports videos.
Speaker 1: Exception.
Speaker 1: anyone getting sweaty makes the video.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: Well, that means all sports videos are okay.
Speaker 1: What sports video has no one getting sweaty?
Speaker 0: Potentially golf late season.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right.
Speaker 1: It's like.
Speaker 1: it's like.
Speaker 1: alright We're gonna ban videos that show hacking but allow educational ones.
Speaker 0: So what they say is there are no videos if the primary purpose is educational documentary Scientific or artistic.
Speaker 1: so all of them?
Speaker 1: Yeah Like it really all of them.
Speaker 0: you ever watch a lot Excepting every single one.
Speaker 1: every single video is an exception to the rule that bans the video.
Speaker 0: dude Yeah, you're a fan of like SGDQ.
Speaker 0: I've seen the equivalent for lock picking lock peeking.
Speaker 0: races are really fun to watch.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they're in the same category as like Rubik's Cube races.
Speaker 0: Let's see.
Speaker 0: So what do they say?
Speaker 0: I thought here's the actual YouTube thing.
Speaker 0: So don't post.
Speaker 0: concept of YouTube.
Speaker 0: Here are the actual like words they wrote.
Speaker 0: extremely dangerous challenges.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so apparently I guess we can't do our Mushroom challenge.
Speaker 0: Yeah Dangerous or threatening prank.
Speaker 1: Let's just make it not a challenge.
Speaker 1: Just make it mushroom.
Speaker 0: Yeah, just like.
Speaker 1: hey not a challenge is mushroom.
Speaker 0: We're gonna eat this mushroom.
Speaker 0: Don't you eat this mushroom?
Speaker 0: What is this mushroom?
Speaker 0: We're about to find out in the woods.
Speaker 0: Instructions to kill.
Speaker 1: I Guess do you need instructions?
Speaker 1: take gun point the right end at the other person pull trigger at the end or harm Which is take knife pointed at rim move, but like or move it closer to rim until he says out.
Speaker 0: But here it's just like like providing instructions on how to build a bomb meant to injure or kill people.
Speaker 1: So if I may take a lot of gunpowder put it in a small space light it on fire, but if I'm making Fireworks, that's probably fine.
Speaker 1: I'm Too many of them bundled them together.
Speaker 1: light them on fire.
Speaker 0: I just found a video how to make fireworks great.
Speaker 0: Also, you know what's on YouTube?
Speaker 0: a whole bunch of World War two in Vietnam War era Military instructional videos on how to make and use munitions in war.
Speaker 0: I watched a video a few weeks ago on like how to use claymores How to make 17th century artillery.
Speaker 0: Yeah Claymores is in the modern weapons not claymores as in the big swords.
Speaker 0: But I did also watch a video on how to use the old claymores how to use not how to make More.
Speaker 1: I watch one and use an old-fashioned.
Speaker 0: I watched one instructional video on how to make improvised weapons.
Speaker 0: Okay, and it was a US government video.
Speaker 1: So I saw a guy talking about like making a weapon out of like a newspaper, uh hard drug use or creation.
Speaker 0: So I've been following this channel.
Speaker 0: That is literally this dude takes every drug and talks about it at length.
Speaker 1: So YouTube is not enforcing any of these rules.
Speaker 0: eating disorders complaining about.
Speaker 1: YouTube not enforcing its hate speech rules.
Speaker 1: But what basically is happening is YouTube isn't enforcing any of its hate speech is not listed in any of these categories.
Speaker 1: that I'm looking right, but also YouTube did I guess arbitrarily enforce its no hacking rule on this one video from this one guy and created a big uproar.
Speaker 1: and Then when the guy complained, I think they took down his whole channel, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah it was like.
Speaker 1: so this random not good enforcement hit someone who made a big stink and now everyone's focusing on it
Speaker 0: and All they would had to do is frame it as here is a documentary of this zero-day exploit
Speaker 1: Yep,
Speaker 0: and then it would probably well, I don't even know
Speaker 1: play some artistic music.
Speaker 0: Yeah, let me teach you how the zero-day exploit was discovered Yep, so in some other news there was actually a pretty big deal breach in Japan.
Speaker 1: So speaking of reaches now to steal money, let's make a YouTube video.
Speaker 1: Yeah steal money from 7-eleven.
Speaker 0: In my professional experience and I will not go into details on this but In my entire professional experience going back like 15 or so years.
Speaker 0: The one thing that has been pretty consistent is that Japanese firms tend to have poor IT security.
Speaker 1: That's not surprising from a country that is like still uses a lot of cash, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah Like that has been a theme in my entire adult professional life and I will leave it at that.
Speaker 0: So the other thing you need to know is that if you I'm about to talk about 7-eleven and if you live in the United States 7-eleven is a place to be avoided at all costs.
Speaker 1: indeed 7-eleven like unless you are desperate for a sad-ass hot dog.
Speaker 1: There's nothing else like 7-eleven is a quickie.
Speaker 1: my things there that come in a package that are okay.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like you go to a 7-eleven when you really need a Red Bull at like 11 o'clock at night.
Speaker 1: Yeah, or if you're at a convention, it's the only thing nearby Yeah, and you need band-aids, but like the food in a 7-eleven It's below the line.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, like the floor in a 7-eleven is perpetually sticky and grimy I think even if you're poor you're going to the bodega to get a quarter water.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know where 7-elevens thrive in the u.s.
Speaker 0: Where they're the area is too poor to even have a proper bodega.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they only have chains.
Speaker 0: They're like outside of.
Speaker 1: If you're not in a major city, you're not gonna have a bodega You're only gonna have a 7-eleven.
Speaker 0: in Japan.
Speaker 0: 7-elevens are the fucking shit.
Speaker 1: They are fucking awesome.
Speaker 0: Oh, they're amazing in other places too.
Speaker 0: Like in Hong Kong.
Speaker 0: I had lunch in 7-eleven like three times.
Speaker 0: Yeah, why not?
Speaker 0: It was great.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's a really good dumplings actually your ramen fucking right there.
Speaker 1: But in Japan, that's only the beginning.
Speaker 0: that's like, you know, not only is 7-eleven great But 7-eleven is also a lot of people's Bank Mmm, like banking happens at 7-eleven.
Speaker 0: like you buy train tickets at the 7-eleven It's.
Speaker 0: they're like there was a time when 7-eleven was like the only place a foreign ATE Like the only place you could use a foreign debit card to get cash.
Speaker 1: now some of this it's like in America.
Speaker 1: There is a lot of this stuff happening.
Speaker 1: We're like a store that does everything.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like we could buy.
Speaker 0: I remember when I was a kid we would pay the electric bill at like this gas station Dude, we would go to the Meijer which was a grocery store gas station appliance store like home improvement store.
Speaker 1: I think you might actually be surprised like at the number of services that places near you are offering that you are not aware of Or using.
Speaker 1: but it seems like in other countries like Japan for instance People are aware of the incredible wide variety of services that places like 7-eleven offer and use them.
Speaker 0: There is a class based and societal based nuance to that in the u.s.
Speaker 0: Most of the places like those kinds of services that are not at banks are used by poor people are Not only not just used by poor people.
Speaker 0: They're usually exploitative and Target poor people.
Speaker 0: there's there's a nuance there.
Speaker 0: But that nuance is important.
Speaker 0: like if you're doing your banking at the 7-eleven in the US or the Western Union in the US It's because you are marginalized.
Speaker 0: Yes most of the time.
Speaker 0: So anyway 7-eleven has a mobile payment system that they launched so people can have a phone app that'll spit out a barcode.
Speaker 1: So like Apple pay?
Speaker 0: yeah like Apple pay.
Speaker 1: Okay, so you guys you give them your money to 7-eleven and deposit it in 7-eleven.
Speaker 1: They open an app on your phone and it shows a code.
Speaker 1: You scan it at a register and that register takes from your 7-eleven account the amount of money that you're required to pay for Whatever you're buying basically and then your account go decreases at 7-eleven and you can like tie different debit cards to it.
Speaker 0: Like I can't read Japanese.
Speaker 0: I don't know all the details of how it all worked But pretty simple thing.
Speaker 1: something along those lines close if not exactly.
Speaker 0: it was launched on July 1st.
Speaker 1: That wasn't very long ago.
Speaker 1: That was seven.
Speaker 1: That was one week ago.
Speaker 0: It was immediately hacked to the tune of half a million dollars.
Speaker 0: They shut it down immediately and now it's fucked.
Speaker 1: All right, so and this is why it's amazing million dollars isn't a lot of money for such a big company A lot of money for people to have it stolen from them and it's also a lot of money I guess.
Speaker 1: does Japan have like an FDIC equivalent?
Speaker 1: I'm assuming there was no insurance.
Speaker 0: funnily enough at work yesterday or last week I was actually reading a lot about because there's a.
Speaker 1: there's I see.
Speaker 0: So I know a lot about like US financial regulatory agencies and bodies and I know a lot about European regulatory bodies like in the US there's a ATS is like an ATS is like so an alternative trading system.
Speaker 0: Okay, so sometimes you trade on like an exchange.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but then you might trade on something that isn't actually an exchange.
Speaker 0: All right, but is regulated similarly to an exchange but is right but is also regulated differently.
Speaker 1: So like I make something that lets you trade stocks I could just make something you can and I let the SEC know about it.
Speaker 1: and they say okay You're following all these rules.
Speaker 0: and I say yeah, basically and it's not actually the FTC in this case.
Speaker 0: But I digress let's not get into that in Europe.
Speaker 0: There's a similar thing.
Speaker 0: There's a similar thing, but it's not an ATS.
Speaker 0: It's called an MTF a multilateral trading Forget whatever.
Speaker 0: Anyway, I was trying to figure out what the fuck those are and how they're regulated anywhere on earth other than the US and the EU and that is actually really hard to find out.
Speaker 0: and I was able to figure out that Japan has regulations around it But I cannot find equivalent relevant regulations in like China or Singapore or other countries in in East Asia.
Speaker 0: Anyway, that was that was me today.
Speaker 0: I was reading Wikipedia at work to figure something out.
Speaker 0: All right, so I don't know what Japan's like it like.
Speaker 0: regulatory models are around this but the fact that they were hacked Not that interesting.
Speaker 0: the egregious security failing like it is so egregious.
Speaker 1: Yeah, this is like didn't even try.
Speaker 0: They basically do hack this.
Speaker 0: all you had to do was know someone's email address and Reset their account.
Speaker 0: Okay, and then now it's yours.
Speaker 1: How did you get the?
Speaker 1: they're like you didn't have to like actually get an email with a link in it.
Speaker 0: So here's what you need.
Speaker 0: You need to know the user's date of birth.
Speaker 0: Okay, the email address and their phone number and you just lets you reset.
Speaker 1: right in the app Send any confirmation to the email or the phone number.
Speaker 0: it asks you what email address you'd like the password to be sent to.
Speaker 0: great Even better you didn't actually even need to know their birthday Because they don't require you to put in a birthday You can.
Speaker 0: if you don't put one in it defaults it to January 1st 2019.
Speaker 0: It just works.
Speaker 0: So basically matter what part that you put in hackers immediately Just attack this Just with scatter attacks and it immediately made as many charges as they could.
Speaker 0: All right, like that is egregious to the point of malfeasance.
Speaker 1: It's not even hacking really, you know based on your it's just like.
Speaker 1: It's just like okay.
Speaker 1: If everyone's password is a I just log in with everyone's account like it.
Speaker 0: what's like?
Speaker 0: on one hand I don't want to blame the victim but the victim here like as you know, the victim here is not 7-eleven 7-eleven customer.
Speaker 1: the customers who had their accounts emptied like The.
Speaker 0: everyone involved in building the system should be charged with crimes Like this is this is pathetic that is crime worthy and it's a negligence.
Speaker 1: I mean at the very least there should be a class-action lawsuit by the people who had accounts.
Speaker 0: and there's even a thing in Japan I don't know.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: Equivalent, I guess like not in the u.s.
Speaker 1: That's what would happen.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I Or forced arbitration.
Speaker 1: just this kind of this is why you shouldn't agree to forced arbitration.
Speaker 0: Yep ever In some other news you probably saw this.
Speaker 0: it's hard to find unbiased reporting about this.
Speaker 1: I just want to say about this story.
Speaker 1: This is a thing that happens a lot these days where something outrageous or seemingly outrageous happens to a single or a very small number of customers or users of a certain thing and That thing becomes a big story and the journalists find like a couple other examples of it happening and then they make a headline Like so-and-so does this to all their customers all their users?
Speaker 1: They're evil my god because of small or even a single Person has an anecdote that is seems outrageous or bad And Some it goes both ways right.
Speaker 1: sometimes it is and sometimes it isn't.
Speaker 0: but in this case all I'm gonna say is I'm gonna report on this as best I can.
Speaker 0: but I found a lot of websites talking about this, but they all had very similar articles written and I'm making quote marks by different people and they all seem to be focused on the single issue of Restaurants don't want to have to deal with grubhub.
Speaker 0: So I feel like there is an industry entity trying to push against grubhub on behalf of Restaurants which we have pro.
Speaker 1: grubhub rim over here may or may not be justified You still owning grubhub stock over there?
Speaker 0: So full disclosure, I did own a significant amount of grubhub stock and also full disclosure.
Speaker 0: I sold it all some time ago for a substantial profit.
Speaker 0: I currently own zero grubhub stock, so I got.
Speaker 0: no I got no horse in this race And I also disclosure.
Speaker 1: we both use grubhub a lot.
Speaker 0: I use grubhub a lot because I'm not calling you on the phone or a pizza.
Speaker 1: I use it like maybe three four times a month.
Speaker 0: I use it.
Speaker 0: Maybe one one to one point five times a week got average.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, I think you say month and but no he's a way more than me.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we order by order in at least once a week.
Speaker 1: Okay, I do maybe once a week, you know.
Speaker 0: But in some week zero, I think part of the difference is there's two of us.
Speaker 0: So it's more bang for our buck if we order in.
Speaker 0: It's like maybe ordering Indian food for one is two nights worth of Indian.
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 0: ordering Indian food for two is either two nights of Indian food or one night of Indian food.
Speaker 0: like it works out Mmm, so the story that you saw was grubhub created fake webs restaurant websites to screw restaurants over.
Speaker 1: Okay The speaking of which if you don't realize grubhub does sort of screw restaurants over Away.
Speaker 1: if you're a restaurant It's like alright.
Speaker 1: Nobody who's buying food to get delivery online is gonna find you if you're not on grubhub.
Speaker 1: So it's like you need to be on there.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I know restaurants on grubhub.
Speaker 1: I don't search elsewhere and then see if you try to make your own Website or be listed on some other thing.
Speaker 1: if you're not grubhub or seamless.
Speaker 1: It's like people aren't really gonna find your restaurant.
Speaker 1: They're gonna order from your competitor.
Speaker 1: You're not gonna get a lot of deliveries unless people know your restaurant and even then if they know your restaurant.
Speaker 1: They'll probably search for on grubhub and not on Google and it's like it's you know.
Speaker 1: But the problem is is how do they screw you over?
Speaker 1: They screw you over because they know they're the only game in town and they charge like a 30% ridiculous fee.
Speaker 1: So it's like you pay the restaurant $30 groves taking like $10.
Speaker 1: Yep, right the restaurants do not make a lot of money when you buy and grow up up.
Speaker 1: You should tip them.
Speaker 0: Well, you know what I do my policy because just the way things are in New York in particular I tip grubhub delivery people at the rate.
Speaker 0: I would tip at a restaurant.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I do too cuz yeah, so a waiter a waiter just came in like delivered basically what I do.
Speaker 1: This dude was on a motor like on an electric bike going the wrong way Reloaded percentage buttons, I push the one farthest to the right.
Speaker 0: I do 20 ish percent because I figure if you're on a bicycle Yeah, this to the right.
Speaker 1: if you're on the bicycle in the rain delivering me pizza and like you're in the rain I put I go beyond if it's raining or snowing or something.
Speaker 1: You deserve a real tip and I try also try not to order in those situations to begin with only if I really have to Yeah, and if I really have to I'd leave a big tip.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but basically here's the deal as best I can tell.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna link to two things because on one hand the second article link to is how to avoid grubhub, but Honestly replace grubhub with Amazon.
Speaker 0: It's the exact same conversation.
Speaker 0: Amazon is problematic for everyone except Amazon and the consumer.
Speaker 0: Grubhub is the same way.
Speaker 0: ordering before grubhub Ordering from restaurants sucked.
Speaker 0: Yep, and outside of New York City ordering from restaurants sucks.
Speaker 0: But basically what grubhub was doing is if you make an account with grubhub They would not only like set up the thing to let you order food, but they would make websites.
Speaker 0: That I have basically like.
Speaker 0: it's a website for your restaurant that is integrated with grubhub.
Speaker 1: So if someone finds that website Someone were to Google for you know rims chicken shack.
Speaker 1: They would find a standalone website for rims chicken shack.
Speaker 1: but is actually a grubhub powered website that would allow them to browse your menu and Order from rims chicken shack directly from rims chicken shack comm yep without having in case they googled instead of going to grubhub first.
Speaker 1: And on the one hand that's good because you didn't maybe didn't have a website right and now people are Finding your website if they finding your restaurant if they happen to search Google Instead of grubhub and they're placing an order with you, so that's helpful.
Speaker 1: It's not helpful because what if you do have a website?
Speaker 1: This is actually a you already have your own rims chicken shack website that allows non grubhub Ordering.
Speaker 1: that doesn't have this big cut taken out.
Speaker 1: if anyone happens to order there someone googles for rims chicken shack and in Above rims chicken shack in the search results is this website made by grubhub.
Speaker 1: Someone clicks on that thinking instead of the second one and basically because they click that link instead of the other one rims losing like $10
Speaker 0: yep, but at the same time if someone clicks on the real website Then they're gonna have to order direct from the restaurant which in my experience Usually doesn't work because most restaurant owners have a garbage website that no one maintains.
Speaker 0: that doesn't work.
Speaker 1: that is true.
Speaker 0: I have literally ordered from restaurants before where no food came And I called them and they were like what?
Speaker 0: like they didn't know you could order online from their website.
Speaker 1: I've had that happen to me, but for example Burger Club over here in Astoria right they have their own website.
Speaker 1: It's powered by some kind of software.
Speaker 1: They've installed.
Speaker 1: It's I guess like a WordPress equivalent for restaurants.
Speaker 1: I forget what it's called.
Speaker 1: It's some kind of thing.
Speaker 1: so if you order directly from Burger Club's website It does not go through grubhub Yep, and the price is slightly cheaper and the restaurant gets a lot more money.
Speaker 1: so and if you order from grubhub It's like it's the same exact menu.
Speaker 1: the prices are a little bit more expensive and the restaurant gets way less money.
Speaker 0: So what's sad is personally I have there are some restaurants around here that have their own website to order from and it's the same Deal is slightly cheaper.
Speaker 0: Kind of like how I'm unwilling to launch any Application other than steam to buy games not really willing to go to a website and log in with a separate credential to order food Even if it's cheaper.
Speaker 1: I only it's.
Speaker 1: the only reason is because then it had to make credential.
Speaker 1: It lets me log in with Google.
Speaker 0: Oh, it's not bad.
Speaker 0: That's actually pretty good Yeah, but so one thing that might be happening here, too Is that grubhub's website the one they make for the restaurant is?
Speaker 0: Probably better and more linked to than the actual restaurants website because who links to a restaurant's website.
Speaker 0: There's gonna be no SEO like there's good Google.
Speaker 0: There's gonna be no Google juice for the website restaurant unless you're searching Google Maps.
Speaker 0: That's just how it is.
Speaker 0: Yeah, no one's linking to your crappy restaurants website on a regular basis.
Speaker 0: So
Speaker 1: unless you're happen to be that one restaurant is really good at internet which may be this one that started this story is I
Speaker 0: don't think so because Basically, I'm reading into this but I'm not gonna explain the details of the lawsuit because that is way too much to talk
Speaker 1: about.
Speaker 1: It's actually a lawsuit.
Speaker 1: I didn't know that there's a lawsuit.
Speaker 0: Okay Alleging that the company bills restaurants for commission fees when calls are made through the number because grubhub those websites also provide phone numbers.
Speaker 0: You can call where a human will take the order through.
Speaker 0: for grubhub.
Speaker 0: The lawsuit is claiming you've been just like.
Speaker 1: go to grubhub and type in the info.
Speaker 0: why not?
Speaker 0: That's what I would do.
Speaker 1: call someone on the phone.
Speaker 1: They go to grubhub.com and type in your order for you.
Speaker 0: That's some bullshit, but they're claiming that grubhub was taking commission fees.
Speaker 0: Even if those calls did not result in an order That would be some bullshit.
Speaker 1: How could you have a commission on a zero dollar?
Speaker 0: That's what I don't understand the lawsuit seems to be about other things and not the thing everyone's talking about.
Speaker 0: Interesting.
Speaker 0: So the thing everyone's talking about?
Speaker 0: From what I can tell one grubhub in 2018 stopped offering the service of making these microsites.
Speaker 0: Okay, maybe because this lawsuit, uh No, because no one used them.
Speaker 0: apparently Yeah And - I've never seen one grubhub said in response to this like they've been responding to those articles.
Speaker 0: site owners can request that these sites be taken down at any time with no cost or and the ownership of the domains would be Transferred to the restaurant free of charge.
Speaker 0: So if you are a restaurant you could say hey give me the domain Grubhub just gives it to you.
Speaker 1: grubhub just registered a domain for you.
Speaker 0: point it point this domain that has a shit ton of Google juice at your real website.
Speaker 0: You just win.
Speaker 0: I Think what's happening here?
Speaker 0: And this is just me guessing based on my interactions with people in this industry.
Speaker 0: Is that the restaurants who are complaining about this the most don't?
Speaker 0: Understand how to use a domain that they are given like?
Speaker 0: they don't know how to point this domain at Their website because their website was either made by their cousin's younger brother Or was made by a fly-by-night consulting company and they don't know how to update it.
Speaker 0: That is how most restaurant websites are.
Speaker 0: There's a lot.
Speaker 0: you can read all these details.
Speaker 0: But all I'm saying is when you see these stories of grubhub creating fake websites for restaurants There's always a lot more to the story.
Speaker 0: and if you see a lot of articles talking about the same thing that use very very similar copy Look into it a little bit deeper.
Speaker 0: There's probably something else going on.
Speaker 0: The real issue is that No one wants to go to more than one website to buy things.
Speaker 0: news 11 So in some last really light news before we get into the main bit There is I saw a ton of people talking about this the discord virus.
Speaker 0: Uh-huh Yeah, there's no discord virus, okay, here's what's going on.
Speaker 0: Some people are sending malicious links to other people via discord chats.
Speaker 1: You open discord you go to some server you have a link that goes to some meet malware site.
Speaker 1: Yeah, send the link to someone and they stupidly click on.
Speaker 1: they stupidly click on it And then yes people are more likely to click on a links.
Speaker 1: if you send someone a link via email the spam filter gets it And no one clicks on it.
Speaker 1: You send someone a link a shady link on discord.
Speaker 0: Well, they click it but even then you go to this website It's shady and then you type in all your credentials again and give it access to your discord And then you're aft and your discord is ruined forever and hackers steal it and spam your friends.
Speaker 0: and it's a thing That's been happening a lot apparently One all I'm gonna say I'm not gonna dwell on this not even talk about the details not even a link directly to any article.
Speaker 1: Not a virus.
Speaker 0: It's not a virus.
Speaker 0: If you fall for this, you're dumb.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but more importantly This is happening a lot and it worries me because basically people are morons.
Speaker 0: People older than us fall for fishing a lot.
Speaker 0: people our age fall for it less for reasons that I don't want to get into now But I'm seeing people younger than us like they get the Russian bot thing Like they can recognize when like there's a Russian bot posting on their Facebook wall or tweeting at them like they get it But they don't understand fishing.
Speaker 0: like they're falling for this ridiculous fishing stuff again And it's happening a lot.
Speaker 1: Let's go Teach a man to fish.
Speaker 0: Yeah, should we just make a fishing site that deletes your account?
Speaker 1: Just quit my job become fisherman.
Speaker 0: So Yeah, if you fall for this like I don't know my condolences Learn how to spot babies first fishing.
Speaker 0: These are not even sophisticated attacks.
Speaker 0: These are literally like I looked.
Speaker 0: I clicked on one of these links to see the deal.
Speaker 0: This is literally the equivalent of those aim fishing attacks from like the 90s.
Speaker 0: So what's old is new?
Speaker 0: But anyway things of the day what he got.
Speaker 1: so it's for the July weekend.
Speaker 1: for July weekend in America America You tend to have a barbecue which is not bar You know, usually not barbecue of the you know, the kind you get at a barbecue.
Speaker 1: right when Americans say barbecue We mean we mean grilling some hot dogs and hamburgers.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know, we also say barbecue when we mean ribs.
Speaker 1: But we also say barbecue and we mean grill some hot dogs and hamburgers.
Speaker 0: Don't judge.
Speaker 0: That's just how the English language is in the US.
Speaker 1: Yes, that's how American English is whatever.
Speaker 1: But yeah, the hot dog and hamburger style of barbecue Grilling also involves often nice deserty or you know, sort of side dish.
Speaker 1: You cut up a big old watermelon.
Speaker 1: tastes great It's watermelon season.
Speaker 1: That's how it works.
Speaker 1: Right?
Speaker 1: So here you go.
Speaker 1: This is guy.
Speaker 1: I just discovered his YouTube channel.
Speaker 1: I'm sure other people have been following it for quite a while cuz it's got five fucking million plus views on this video.
Speaker 1: I was like trending something on YouTube, but in case you haven't seen it turtle loves watermelon.
Speaker 1: This is guy called the fish whisperer and he's got a little pond or whatever he hangs out at and he's got some turtle friends and the fish friends and They love him and he keeps going to feed him and take care of him and he does other videos on here.
Speaker 1: He made special popsicles for the turtles.
Speaker 1: He's just like these turtles are getting like You know really sweet life.
Speaker 1: Thanks to this guy who comes over and takes care of them all the time and gives them sweet shit And everyone loves cute turtles.
Speaker 1: So here you go.
Speaker 0: It's good stuff.
Speaker 0: So in another cute and possibly antifa video so Cockatoos are terrifyingly smart like parrots are in general.
Speaker 1: That's the white bird that's like fans out all its feathers like yeah And I'm a fan of cockatoos like the ones on its head, too like.
Speaker 0: but this is pretty amazing because cockatoos are real smart and there are many kinds of cockatoos, but some cockatoos are Thriving in a world where they coexist with humans like they coexist with humans and they figure our shit out.
Speaker 0: And that's a problem because unlike say squirrels trying to steal my food Cockatoos can be as smart as a like two to two and a half year old human.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: That is trouble.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean I was spent the weekend in the presence of a not even two year old human who could you know Open a door.
Speaker 1: Yeah or point at things grab stuff, right?
Speaker 1: You know, it's like oh shit.
Speaker 1: That's somewhat more intelligent than I thought that a child that old would be.
Speaker 0: So a thing that people do in places like Australia is they will put anti bird spikes on Surfaces to keep birds away.
Speaker 1: It's not just people doing Australia's and people do everywhere.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but Australia It's a pretty good.
Speaker 1: So it's very common because hostile architecture for against humans and animals in New York You see for pigeons all the time like.
Speaker 1: it's funny because you see a place like pigeon is pigeon shit everywhere.
Speaker 1: There's clearly a whole ton of pigeons hanging out here shitting all over and you see spikes all over the fucking everything and there's still Pigeon shit everywhere.
Speaker 0: So this video is a cockatoo.
Speaker 0: very methodically with purpose and malice of forethought is Dismantling and Discarding the bird the anti bird spikes and you watch it and you're like, okay the bird is removing these spikes But then the video zooms down and you see that the bird has been at it all day.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they is.
Speaker 1: remove the spikes from like the vast majority of the fence.
Speaker 1: They are all on the ground.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like you just working down the line this birds taking one for the team.
Speaker 0: This bird is a bird hero.
Speaker 0: Yep In the moment the geekiness book club book is still pages of Getting I was on my to-do list.
Speaker 1: I forget.
Speaker 1: the book club book is the first novel ever written in recorded human history.
Speaker 1: the tale of Genji Beginning then next we're gonna read the second novel in Is not as older.
Speaker 0: I think That's more an oral storytelling.
Speaker 1: I think it is not a novel.
Speaker 0: yeah It's not.
Speaker 0: I don't think it counts as a novel.
Speaker 1: like Homer Homer's Odyssey is much older than the tale of Genji.
Speaker 1: It is.
Speaker 1: it is a epic poem.
Speaker 0: It is not a novel Yep, but the tale of Genji.
Speaker 0: I've never actually read it.
Speaker 0: I've only read excerpts from it.
Speaker 1: Make sure you get the unabridged penguin deluxe version.
Speaker 1: If you get the abridged one that is not what we are gonna read cuz we don't read abridged shit we are pros.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you play hard mode.
Speaker 0: only we're playing Scrabble unabridged OED.
Speaker 1: No We're no baby mode where?
Speaker 0: Scott famously beat me in Scrabble once because he misspelled laser because he wasn't paying attention But it turned out that that misspelling is a word in the OED.
Speaker 1: That's right.
Speaker 0: I was I was I was I was salty shall we say on that day?
Speaker 1: That's why Scrabble is not a good game.
Speaker 1: All right, it's a game of memorization.
Speaker 0: Let's talk about oh, yeah And we got no cons till PAX.
Speaker 0: and then PAX West is actually in two weeks, which two months I was about to say I have not finished writing panels.
Speaker 1: two months PAX West in Seattle, Seattle Liberty weekend.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: We hopefully will see you there.
Speaker 0: All right, so let's talk about the dark web, right?
Speaker 1: Well, I mean back in the day high level.
Speaker 0: We're not going too deep in this right yet.
Speaker 1: back in the day in the earlier internet days The late 90s early 2000s, right, you know, you had this internet connection and at least, you know My experience in the 90s was open up AOL Connect and once you're connected you can now run any internet app.
Speaker 1: What shut up Siri?
Speaker 1: you suck.
Speaker 0: How was Scott?
Speaker 1: What are you doing?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I wasn't even touching my watch.
Speaker 1: I don't have Siri.
Speaker 1: I had Siri disabled.
Speaker 0: Well, Siri's always listening.
Speaker 1: I have to do some more disabling.
Speaker 0: Yeah, basically you had access.
Speaker 1: you had an internet connection and then you could run any network application and it would connect.
Speaker 1: So for example, you could run IRC.
Speaker 1: No, you could run Gopher.
Speaker 1: you could run Netscape navigator.
Speaker 0: All you needed to know Ron aim All you needed to know is a DNS name or an IP address and a port number and a protocol.
Speaker 1: you could run a video game.
Speaker 1: That needed some an internet network play.
Speaker 1: you could run a file sharing program like Napster.
Speaker 1: you can write, you know.
Speaker 0: In the days before that you could if you knew the phone number of the BBS you could get in Right deal.
Speaker 1: then there were some that were even more advanced like for example hotline.
Speaker 1: You would run hotline and then you'd have to know the IP address of a hotline server to connect to Right, and then you'd be like, ooh, or you could run a hotline server, you know.
Speaker 1: So it was like.
Speaker 1: there was a
Speaker 0: whole world
Speaker 1: of networking apps Right that used the internet and it was none of it was necessarily dark But it was sort of like, you know, they call it on Wikipedia At least the hidden web or the invisible web where it's like, you know, it's like.
Speaker 1: yeah It's just.
Speaker 1: there's a thing on the internet.
Speaker 1: There are services that servers are providing on the internet Network ports that are open waiting to provide you with data.
Speaker 0: I care to buy apples.
Speaker 1: you must know about them or hear about them from somewhere security through obscure and be intelligent enough or In the know enough to run the software get the software Configure it and connect and to do the thing.
Speaker 0: now in the old day before the internet Like when you were doing this with phones, you could kind of war dial and find thing.
Speaker 1: You know the phone number of the thing.
Speaker 0: But if you didn't know the phone number, you could war dial your neighborhood and find the phone number.
Speaker 0: Yeah But then and when we were in high school That was an era of the internet where there weren't really search engines that worked yet.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: So like there were websites unless someone told you how to get there there was no way to know it existed.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: So like for one thing I knew of the IP address of a particular server That rather had quick to like.
Speaker 0: I could type in this IP address and there was a quick to server there with only good people.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm on that same IP address.
Speaker 0: if you in the web browser typed a colon So that IP address colon and a particular port number There was a website there and that website had shall we say things to download?
Speaker 0: Where's?
Speaker 0: There were where's there you don't say but cops aren't gonna be able to find that.
Speaker 0: No Unless someone's stupid enough to tell a cop the IP address and the port the cops could never find the place that I downloaded expensive software from in the 90s, right.
Speaker 1: So, you know, this is the way things were.
Speaker 1: but over time people sort of you know Stopped using all these other softwares for the most part and because people just kept making more and more advanced websites and web browsers.
Speaker 1: So it's like oh instead of having your separate Thunderbird email app You now just go to gmail.com in your browser.
Speaker 1: instead of having your separate IRC app You have slack and discord which run in the browser.
Speaker 1: And if you do have these separate standalone slack and discord apps, guess what?
Speaker 1: Those are just web browsers in disguise.
Speaker 1: They're literally just Chrome without a location bar at the top and some other slight mods to them.
Speaker 0: and there are apps like Discord.
Speaker 1: and why did you say like that discord app is literally just another copy of Chrome?
Speaker 1: It is not really its own app that is any different.
Speaker 0: but more importantly all these things because of entities like Google.
Speaker 0: they are Google.
Speaker 1: you search and you can find them.
Speaker 1: anything that's web-based.
Speaker 0: Yep worldwide web, you know the WWW that you don't type in anymore, right?
Speaker 1: But there are still some things that are on the hidden slash invisible web, right?
Speaker 1: These are things where you search on Google.
Speaker 1: You won't find them.
Speaker 1: You have their website You have to know about right now.
Speaker 0: an IRC server You have to know about but website you have to know about means it probably doesn't have a DNS entry May or may not.
Speaker 0: if it has a DNS entry someone is cataloged that it could still be, you know?
Speaker 1: Oh, there's a DNS entry but you got to go to slash slash slash something something something a hidden poor You know.
Speaker 0: crawlers have an economy of scale to find those things.
Speaker 1: Ostensibly it can even be something that worried like yeah, it is indexed by Google But no matter what you search for if it even shows up as a result, it'll be like the 10,000th result.
Speaker 1: No, no one will ever see that link.
Speaker 0: There are a lot of parts of the internet that are hard to find but that is not what we were talking about today.
Speaker 1: The dark web is the next level of hidden web.
Speaker 0: The dark web is something that has like.
Speaker 1: it is relative read about it in the news a lot and you're like What the hell is that?
Speaker 1: It's it's not super new, but it's you know, it's.
Speaker 0: it's new enough like the closest equivalent to the modern dark web are private dark networks that ran proprietary software that were rarely if ever used like Fear like a group of people using waste together could theoretically be like the dark web, right?
Speaker 1: So imagine for a second.
Speaker 0: waste was something nullsoft made.
Speaker 0: we've talked about it.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so imagine it for a second like in my house I make a land a bunch of computers wired together and I run a bunch of services.
Speaker 1: Maybe a web server may not game server.
Speaker 1: Maybe a file server, right all kinds of stuff, right?
Speaker 1: And then it's not connected to the internet.
Speaker 1: There's no way that anyone can access any of these services unless they come to my house Right.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: So now I Connect it to the internet, but due to fancy networking and several routers and VPNs and all that sort of stuff There's no way for anyone to just connect to it from the internet directly.
Speaker 1: They type in the IP address of like, you know, and they're not gonna hit anything.
Speaker 1: It's gonna hit like this outside router and they're not gonna see jack shit.
Speaker 1: none of these services are gonna be accessible to them.
Speaker 0: because basically the way the internet works and we've done old episodes about this is In the end whatever you're trying to get to has an IP address.
Speaker 0: Yeah And there are ranges of IP addresses that are routable meaning if I type in this IP from anything connected to the internet I will be able to get to it from anywhere else on the internet.
Speaker 0: Yep, every router thanks to routing protocols Which we talked about recently because that big cloud flare outage The rise in outages not the cloud flare outage, but like the internet says oh you want to get to that IP?
Speaker 0: I know the next stop.
Speaker 0: go there and ask that guy.
Speaker 0: Yeah Like everything works that way but there are ranges of IPs where every router on the internet will say you can't get there.
Speaker 0: Yep, because they're reserved for things like private networks.
Speaker 0: Like, you know, your house is 192.168 dot something.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: That's because everyone's house is 192.168 Unless you're cool, and then it's 10 out something 172.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you got the idea.
Speaker 1: The point is if you can set up.
Speaker 1: it's possible and actually quite frequently used things like VPNs Tor onion routing you may have heard of some of this stuff Such that someone who is in the know and has the right software and has the right credentials and has the right Configurations and is in the know could run a bunch of things on their computer and then actually connect to those Services that are otherwise completely inaccessible.
Speaker 1: network wise no amount of searching on the internet or scanning or sending packets will ever find these services because there are layers of encryption and routing and other shenanigans that make them inaccessible except for someone who is in the know and Goes right in there.
Speaker 0: well like waste was an example of that.
Speaker 0: where what it did is if I run this software and Scott runs the software and all the People we personally know and trust run this software We can go to an IP address and send data to each other in a way that no one can trace.
Speaker 0: Yeah, no one else has access to.
Speaker 1: yeah, we can chat we can share files We can do all sorts of stuff and it's a hundred percent encrypted and a hundred percent Deniable and no one will ever know that any of it happened and no one who hasn't been given a key by us Will ever be able to find it or access it even though it's just out on the internet.
Speaker 1: This is even more than that.
Speaker 1: This is like cuz.
Speaker 1: even with a waste someone might be able to scan and say oh, there's a waste there that I can never access.
Speaker 1: Yep, this is you'll never find.
Speaker 1: you won't even know.
Speaker 1: this web server is there ever?
Speaker 1: no matter even if you search every IP address On the whole internet and every port you will never see this web server, right?
Speaker 1: You will only maybe see like some sort of VPN gateway that you can't get into and there is completely mysterious shit behind it.
Speaker 0: Yep, like this is the kind of crap where you will like take a range of IP addresses that belong to another company like Microsoft and if you're running the right software and Connected to the right VPN with the right tunnel the right time of day when the moon is full when you type that IP address Instead of going to Microsoft it goes somewhere else.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but when the cops type that IP address it goes to Microsoft.
Speaker 0: Yep, and Shady shit happens in there.
Speaker 1: Yeah, this is where people are buying and selling bitcoins Using bitcoins to buy and sell drugs and weapons and child porn and all sorts of bad shit.
Speaker 1: Yep, and cuz they like.
Speaker 1: let's be honest There is not a lot of reason to go through all this hassle to do legitimate things.
Speaker 0: now I don't think of is activism and oppressive states.
Speaker 1: Yes, that is.
Speaker 1: there are some good reasons to use it and I'm not saying anyone who uses it is bad.
Speaker 1: clearly not right.
Speaker 1: It's like oh, why do you have tinted windows?
Speaker 1: What are you trying to hide?
Speaker 1: if you got nothing to hide you shouldn't be tinting your windows, right?
Speaker 1: We all know that arguments bullshit.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right, but the point is just the truth of it is the vast majority of dark web shit is shenanigans.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the smaller dark or people thinking they're cool going to where the bad kids hang out.
Speaker 0: but like for example, a lot of the things that like legitimate uses of dark nets are things like Like we said we're fighting against an oppressive state.
Speaker 0: Yep in those cases You don't really impressive state.
Speaker 1: we just turn the internet off though, then you're not getting to the dark web or the lightweight.
Speaker 0: That's where you need like distributed peer-to-peer nonsense.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but that's more like waste.
Speaker 0: That's like small scale peer-to-peer friend networks.
Speaker 0: dark web is where you need people you don't know To be able to thanks to knowledge get into the system to interact with you in a way that you can burn that bridge.
Speaker 1: if you Need to write you want to make stuff available on the web.
Speaker 1: You don't want just anyone stumbling across it randomly.
Speaker 1: Yeah You want people in the know around the world to be able to get together and share information in a in a place now securely and privately as possible like a like a Speakeasy.
Speaker 1: and but when the cops come they go into the phone booth in the restaurant.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they dial the exact right number in a kind of pet shop is open at 3 a.m And it doesn't open.
Speaker 1: but then someone in the know comes and they go right into the speakeasy.
Speaker 0: Yep, so what's funny is we don't need this for software piracy.
Speaker 0: Software piracy just happens without the dark web, right?
Speaker 1: You only need the dark web for much more heinous and much more.
Speaker 1: do you need the dark web to get like?
Speaker 0: The bot the key to the botnet you paid for with bitcoins that you got that you're trying to use to launder the cocaine money Like.
Speaker 0: that is what you use the dark net for the dark.
Speaker 1: or you use the dark web to feel cool because you're hanging out With people who you believe these fantastical tales of bitcoins and drugs about.
Speaker 1: yeah You hear those kinds of stories.
Speaker 1: you go Oh, I want to get in on that.
Speaker 1: and then you go do some dark web and it's kind of boring.
Speaker 1: and it's just some Websites, they're just websites.
Speaker 1: You couldn't see unless you did a bunch of shenanigans with Tor and onion routing Yep, and now there's websites there.
Speaker 1: So based on really cool cuz you're seeing websites other people can't see.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: So based on Wikipedia cuz I'm poking around on some stats that are posted here.
Speaker 0: Yep Onion services like.
Speaker 0: I don't want to get into all the different ways this works.
Speaker 0: What I will say is if you're young and you're going into college Study the technology of how dark networks and overlay networks Technology at least some of it especially the routing technology is useful for network engineering and legitimate purposes.
Speaker 0: Yeah Like if you think about it that I have not studied closely because it was not much of a thing when I was in college.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if you think about like a lot of corporate internets and kind of stuff is not too far away from dark web.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you want it.
Speaker 0: you want to do like fancy Balancing is dark web adjacent tech.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so based on Wikipedia It seems like the dark web is used almost entirely to buy and sell drugs.
Speaker 1: Yes That is the number one use.
Speaker 0: for sure.
Speaker 0: that seems number two Let's see is selling other things like it other illegal goods that are not drugs.
Speaker 1: Yep and fraud I think it's drugs are the most I think because they are ones that you can't sell.
Speaker 1: It's something you can't sell easily on the open web.
Speaker 0: I mean if the geek nice website just started selling cocaine can't sell crack on Amazon.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so it the end.
Speaker 1: but you can.
Speaker 1: usually you can.
Speaker 1: it's actually pretty easy to ship cocaine like just by UPS or whatever.
Speaker 1: It actually gets through a surprising amount of time.
Speaker 0: I did because you keep saying it's actually really easy to be clear.
Speaker 0: We do not ship cocaine.
Speaker 1: I never I'm the person doesn't drink alcohol.
Speaker 1: You think I've ever bought or sold or you touched any cocaine ever, right?
Speaker 0: It's like no, but for whatever.
Speaker 0: like a lot like actually like people ship illegal things all the time.
Speaker 0: It's just like postal service, but it's a
Speaker 1: lot harder to ship say a gun
Speaker 0: Yeah, right
Speaker 1: in an illegal manner because it's like that's a big metal thing that would be detected Whereas some white powder in a tiny bag usually ends up in an envelope and someone's mailbox and then they call the police
Speaker 0: Yep, it's not like it got there right now.
Speaker 0: Where do you put your storefront that says I'm selling cocaine?
Speaker 1: Yeah, you can't.
Speaker 1: you got to put it somewhere where cops can't see it.
Speaker 0: You put it on the dark web with an address for like bitcoins Yep, and if someone deposits bitcoins, then you just mail a package.
Speaker 1: I'm sure the dark web is also full of tricks to catch naive people who have Googled on how to get to the dark web.
Speaker 1: guys at the dark web look for the drugstore Yeah, and then got fooled and then got all their bitcoins robbed Which is funny because before the dark way don't hang out in the shady part of town kids.
Speaker 0: Actually, there is one dark web.
Speaker 0: You know what?
Speaker 0: one of the big one of the dark webs that we actually used a lot.
Speaker 0: That isn't really a thing anymore Internet - was kind of a dark web sort of in the sense that the RIAA An entire separate network the RIAA and the MPAA and the cops Couldn't really get access to internet - well, I don't know who's doing these.
Speaker 0: It's not a thing anymore at all.
Speaker 0: Not really now Okay But basically because we were at a university that had access to this.
Speaker 0: we had access to a separate network.
Speaker 0: So like between you of our and our IT there was this direct connect server that we all had access to.
Speaker 0: that no one else had access to so No one could see what we were pirating.
Speaker 0: That was just the thing.
Speaker 0: We had this private piracy network that no one else could access.
Speaker 0: so it's kind of like that Internet - seems to still exist but it's not the kind of thing it was when we were.
Speaker 0: it's not the same thing anymore.
Speaker 1: It still seems to be the same as it was.
Speaker 1: I don't think it's advanced very much.
Speaker 0: There are like that direct connect is gone.
Speaker 1: Oh, I mean, yeah, sure But I'm saying the net internet to itself is.
Speaker 0: it does not have the advantages that it had back in the day.
Speaker 1: It is 500 members including 251 institutions of higher education.
Speaker 1: Yep so if you're at one of those 500 places you can you're on internet - basically internet - if you don't know is 500 places on earth that have their own separate internet connections like physically and They can all share data with each other much much faster than people are internet normal.
Speaker 0: Yep, but it's like it's.
Speaker 0: it's.
Speaker 0: All I'll say is that it is policed in a way that it was not capable of being policed when we were in college.
Speaker 0: I was leaving at that.
Speaker 0: so What do we do with dark like?
Speaker 0: what would we do about dark nets?
Speaker 0: There's no way to make them go away.
Speaker 1: I mean It's the fundamental structure of the internet and the networking technologies that have been developed Will always mean that yeah, it's possible to do things like this.
Speaker 0: There's always holes and cracks in systems like say these darkness all get taken down.
Speaker 0: people would know that if you're
Speaker 1: on the
Speaker 0: World of Warcraft server at a particular time of day at a particular time of place when the moon is full you go talk to the weird-looking elf and He will give you a word and you give it to someone else and then you have a private chat with someone and then You follow the trail of breadcrumbs and eventually you buy your internet cocaine with a Bitcoin.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: It's just mathematically impossible to You know not have this technology unless you make an internet that works differently and I think it's too late for that.
Speaker 1: Yep So, I mean they're just there are what they are.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's out there.
Speaker 0: They're the modern.
Speaker 1: Oh, right.
Speaker 1: Don't go trying to do stupid shit and losing all your money.
Speaker 1: Don't fuck around with evil bitcoins and stuff.
Speaker 1: Oh, maybe use this stuff, you know, if you have a legitimate reason or you just want to you know Learn about networking.
Speaker 0: so what I was getting on to about with before I got sidetracked on internet, too Is that in those early 2000s era because in the 90s like pirated software was just always great.
Speaker 0: but in the 2000s If you went to the wrong place to get wares You would get your pirated software and it was full of malware.
Speaker 0: Yep, but if you knew the right people you'd go to very similar looking sites that had the legit stuff You just had to know.
Speaker 0: Yep, and The dark web is the same way.
Speaker 0: I guess you just have to know right.
Speaker 1: for example today I was reading a story about how people pirate video from like Netflix and stuff.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and apparently they go to Netflix.
Speaker 1: They watch a video right.
Speaker 1: it takes about like eight minutes or whatever because how long is the Netflix video take to download, right?
Speaker 1: They capture all the the chunks of video, but it's all encrypted.
Speaker 1: in the end If you try to watch it in VLC, those be black screen.
Speaker 1: But they capture all the packets right and then they there's tools to decrypt those things and make actual watchable mp4s.
Speaker 1: Those tools are very highly guarded by the people that made them.
Speaker 1: if you try to go on the dark web and search for them You'll find like old fake ones or you're like you'll find someone selling the software for like a Bitcoin or two and actually hahaha They give you software that doesn't work.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right, but they do.
Speaker 0: they give you software that seals the rest of your Bitcoin, right?
Speaker 1: There's a small number of people that have developed and share and use this software that it can actually you know Has the decryption.
Speaker 1: probably people who?
Speaker 1: You know anonymous people who probably work to make the encryption in Netflix are probably also getting the decryption out there.
Speaker 1: It's probably I imagine it's an inside job And you know, it's highly guarded.
Speaker 1: So it's not something you can google for.
Speaker 1: you have to know the right dark web place to go get it.
Speaker 0: Dark webs are basically now they're kind of like those shady bazaars in cyberpunk fantasy.
Speaker 0: Yep, like kind of legit.
Speaker 1: That's what they are Yep, and like I said like you go in planescape and you go to the back of the bar Yeah, and you go through the portal in the door You're gone.
Speaker 1: You're in some other place and when the cops come in they look in the back room and it's a back room.
Speaker 0: so my advice to you the listener is that one if you are not super confident in your personal ability to know how to deal with bad people and You do not have like deep confidence in your own like OPSEC do not interact with the dark web.
Speaker 0: Yep, you are going to get effed.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like that is not something you should be messing around with.
Speaker 1: Nope.
Speaker 0: Number two if you are going to school or want to learn about networking if you learn how dark nets and overlay networks and onion networks and all this stuff work you will be highly sought after because this stuff is Very complicated and very teat.
Speaker 0: like it is difficult to understand the nuances of how these things are actually set up Mmm, and if you learn how to make that like how this stuff works You can get a job in corporate IT or you can get a job working for those same shady people.
Speaker 1: If you are very confident in your abilities Yeah You also can you know learn enough that you could say go and browse the dark web and just not engage in any shady Activities as long as you don't do any bitcoins or drugs or guns.
Speaker 1: if you just you know around and see what You'll see some interesting stuff and have some fun.
Speaker 0: You'll probably see a lot of child porn though - don't look at that either.
Speaker 0: But that seems to be a big part of what is on the dark way.
Speaker 1: I imagine it is Don't do don't look at that.
Speaker 1: just go to you.
Speaker 1: But you could you know do some onion routing and have you know fun Just doing the technology part of it itself.
Speaker 1: the same way you would have fun setting up like a raid in your house And then not using it.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: All right, but I cannot much data.
Speaker 0: I cannot stress enough and I say this as someone who is very Interested in hacking and cracking and freaking back when that was still a thing Don't like.
Speaker 0: this is actually kind of dangerous to fuck around with if you are not careful.
Speaker 1: Yeah Cuz like you go to a drug selling website and then oh it's one the FBI set up on the.
Speaker 1: if you can figure out How to get on the darkwebs right the one that you can.
Speaker 1: even more importantly your place that you can find is the place the FBI can find also and They set up a fake drugstore and you buy a drug from it or
Speaker 0: more importantly you you fuck with the wrong person and buy something from them and then they blackmail you right
Speaker 1: because
Speaker 0: they are not great people.
Speaker 0: and this is Do not let people in places like that figure out who you are.
Speaker 1: It's like oh, yeah Bitcoin is anonymous and then Oh, it's not and then you don't do it right.
Speaker 1: and now you know who you are.
Speaker 0: If you have all say this if you think Bitcoin is anonymous never ever use the dark web.
Speaker 0: Bitcoin is so the opposite of anonymous that half of what happens on the dark web is you need to pay people in Bitcoin to anonymize the other bitcoins you use to buy your cocaine or to sell your cocaine and
Speaker 1: not steal them
Speaker 0: and then The only way to get that money out of the system is to launder it literally money laundering.
Speaker 0: You have to commit federal crimes to get money back out of the dark web.
Speaker 0: Yeah, even if you didn't do anything illegal in the dark web.
Speaker 1: Yep So, uh, yeah, don't do anything involving coins and you'll be more okay.
Speaker 0: Don't do anything involving coins.
Speaker 0: Don't buy anything on the top.
Speaker 1: type your personal information into anything ever Yep If you are not confident that you are not as the dark web using a computer that is not have access to your other computers Or the personal information on them.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: Yeah, maybe use like a virtual machine or some shit.
Speaker 0: Yep, don't necessarily trust that VPN you're paying for to protect you.
Speaker 1: Yeah, no, no, no.
Speaker 0: Basically stay away from this stuff unless you are one of the few edge cases we talked about but you know if you're.
Speaker 1: I think the best way to fool around with it would be actually because I just mentioned a Virtual machine.
Speaker 1: Yep, make a little dark web in your house with a bunch of virtual machines or a better.
Speaker 1: Oh make your own little dark web with like a bunch of like, you know cloud service like machines like on Oz or line.
Speaker 0: Oh, there's no more Pro move.
Speaker 0: Nah, this is if I were younger and still in college.
Speaker 1: This is the kind of thing I would and then get all your friends and teach them how to access your own dark web.
Speaker 1: That doesn't have drugs or child porn or bitcoins.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like I would do this if I was younger or if things were more dire, but make a dark net Yep for you and your friends to have fun.
Speaker 0: Yep, that would be cool.
Speaker 0: And if you do this and you do it Right, then if an oppressive state appears in a place you live where it wasn't previously You still have any kind of internet connection.
Speaker 1: You'll be alright.
Speaker 0: Yep This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Speaker 1: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 0: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 1: But unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 0: It's actually recorded at night And the patreon patrons on this episode of geek nods are Waiting for this to load because they keep changing the interface on this part.
Speaker 0: Okay view all current patrons.
Speaker 0: Here we go Greg Oliver Ellen Joe's like me nickel just like a dude guy.
Speaker 0: charge option link a G Jennifer Hitchcock Chris midkiff my CD J Ben Scooter lonely Shawn Yeager Nicholas Brando, mr Strong structure for two migrations.
Speaker 0: and there would be other secret names.
Speaker 0: You don't even know Sherman on horrible Rory Superboy Clinton Walton run from zealand Ryan parent or open liner fin.
Speaker 0: dread a little temporary Sean Klein Chris Reimer and Thomas.
Speaker 0: on if you saw if you are a patreon patreon a while ago I posted the preview like episode zero of the new Disney theatrical animation show that Emily and I are doing.
Speaker 0: It is now public.
Speaker 0: I'm going to link to it So you can see it for you can listen to the show for free and we're gonna be recording a bunch more episodes Hopefully at least once every week or so at minimum Starting this week and stay tuned for more there.
Speaker 0: patrons will get early access to all these episodes and Patrons will get supplemental material as we get this show together and workshop it.
Speaker 0: so stay tuned for more there.
Speaker 0: It will not be in the geek night's feed.
Speaker 0: You'll have to be on the patreon, but it won't be behind a paywall.
Speaker 0: But now I leave you Partly because I'm very hungry.
Speaker 0: I Don't know.