Speaker 1: It's Thursday, March 14th, 2019.
Speaker 1: I'm Rem.
Speaker 1: I'm Scott.
Speaker 1: And this is the Geek Nights Book Club.
Speaker 1: Tonight, we're talking about 2001 A Space Odyssey the book.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: It's actually pretty warm today.
Speaker 1: It's weird that it's warm today.
Speaker 0: I mean, it's not cold to the point where I'm gonna go woman, it's cold, but it is not warm today.
Speaker 1: It is warm enough.
Speaker 0: It is like 52 degrees fahrenheit.
Speaker 1: When we were at RIT It is warm enough to where I would be wearing shorts and a t-shirt But that's RIT, that's not the real world.
Speaker 1: But two, it is warm enough to where I smell the smell way earlier than I expected to smell it.
Speaker 1: There's this particular smell that I'm very nostalgic for and it only occurs in large old cities like New York or at amusement parks.
Speaker 1: It is that smell in the, like it's a smell you get in the morning.
Speaker 0: The peanut cart?
Speaker 1: It's the combination of peanut cart diesel exhaust and oil slick.
Speaker 1: that comes in like early May if you go to like Cedar Point or Six Flags and in the morning when there's still all the like winter residues hanging out in like late spring before it's quite summer there's this like particular kind of smell you get in the morning.
Speaker 1: You really only get that smell in big cities or amusement parks.
Speaker 0: Usually that happens not just in the first warm morning, but in the first like morning after it rains and it's warm.
Speaker 0: Because basically all this stuff cakes onto the street and then you get that first spring rain in like March-April and in the rain and the heat combined right the rain and the heat combined clean the street right and then all that filth that was built up on the street from the winter goes away.
Speaker 0: and but it's that along with like that mow the lawn smell only for asphalt instead of grass.
Speaker 1: but it's that coupled with the peanut cart and that like diesel exhaust and nuts for nuts isn't peanuts.
Speaker 0: It's like other kinds.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like Whatever it is.
Speaker 1: Don't eat it.
Speaker 0: Of course.
Speaker 0: I don't eat it.
Speaker 0: Are you crazy?
Speaker 1: So I smelled that smell.
Speaker 1: but it's weird to smell that smell in March.
Speaker 1: So it got me nostalgic.
Speaker 1: I got to get back to Cedar Point, but no news tonight.
Speaker 1: I don't really want to talk about Brexit.
Speaker 1: I hope Brexit fails because it's time for Things of the Day.
Speaker 1: So we go to PAX South every year among the many PAXes we go to and one of the bands that performs at PAX South every year is Super mess super mariachi entertainment.
Speaker 0: They have.
Speaker 0: they have been a thing of the day in the past before we even saw them at PAX.
Speaker 1: Oh, yep, so I'm not talking about them because I like mariachi music.
Speaker 1: I've always enjoyed mariachi music.
Speaker 1: This is just a tweet.
Speaker 1: I stumbled upon it is a mariachi band Singing Bohemian Rhapsody on the street in a mariachi style and it is most enjoyable.
Speaker 1: That is it.
Speaker 1: That is my thing of the day.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: So Here is a video of a thing that I'm surprised was not at magfest.
Speaker 0: It is at clearly some magfest ish event somewhere else.
Speaker 1: We got a kickstart bringing this to magfest.
Speaker 0: This could be a gaming room in an anime con.
Speaker 0: Maybe I don't know where this is.
Speaker 1: This looks like the kind of thing that this looks like the anime gaming nights.
Speaker 0: We used to have Oh, it says in the description.
Speaker 1: This is a little beach Rhythm national rhythm game tournament.
Speaker 1: Oh storm 14.
Speaker 1: Damn.
Speaker 1: I gotta go there dude It's in Daytona Beach every year in May.
Speaker 0: Oh sweet.
Speaker 1: We don't have any make-ons anymore.
Speaker 0: But anyway, it says this is in 2014.
Speaker 0: So I guess we missed it.
Speaker 0: Maybe there might doesn't exist anymore.
Speaker 0: How come I didn't know there was a rhythm game convention?
Speaker 0: But anyway, what this is is the world's largest DDR pad.
Speaker 0: if this is in 2014, how come I didn't see it before?
Speaker 0: Anyway, it's five years old.
Speaker 1: The video was uploaded like four days after this event.
Speaker 0: Yeah Anyway, what happened apparently five years ago and I didn't hear about it was somebody took nine DDR pads Put them all together in a grid to make an a DDR pad.
Speaker 0: It is nine times the size of a normal DDR pad and each pad is an arrow.
Speaker 1: The best part about this video is watching this dude who clearly knows how to play DDR Struggling right.
Speaker 0: play DDR on this pad here You have one dude playing it, but I think it'd be much more fun to have four people one per arrow playing this game.
Speaker 1: so, uh, I actually scrolled down a little bit and the amazing thing about this video is that Every YouTube comment just seems to be gold.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: So when I was five, that's how I felt.
Speaker 1: Imagine doing crossovers on that thing.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm should have put nine more pads together to play doubles.
Speaker 1: Little four people play each get on an arrow.
Speaker 1: That's right.
Speaker 1: That looks painful.
Speaker 1: Should have gotten nine pads to play doubles.
Speaker 1: starts to repeat itself.
Speaker 0: nine should have gotten 81 pads.
Speaker 0: Yeah No, 81 times two 162 pads.
Speaker 1: Play doubles make one just giant DDR pad.
Speaker 1: That's in like a park in nine cities Spread out around the United States.
Speaker 0: take eight arrows hide them around the world Put them have cell phones attached to them and then have the game somewhere else remotely.
Speaker 1: I Love this like there's cursed rhythm game controllers.
Speaker 0: This is I set that up as an installation at Right where you basically have you're standing on the thing and there's a while just a light in front of you or just a serum a strip of LEDs and there's.
Speaker 0: they lit up and you have to.
Speaker 0: you have to step when the light hits the bottom or the top right and then Combined you are playing DDR, but you can't see the other three arrows or anything else.
Speaker 0: You have no context.
Speaker 0: But people watching the group of you jump in place can see the arrows and how well you're doing any bad.
Speaker 0: So if you someone was watching from afar then you would look like you were all Individual feet or whatever.
Speaker 1: So in the meta moment because we want to get right into the book club We will be live at PAX East if I finally just posted this on the website.
Speaker 1: the real harm of games.
Speaker 1: Friday March 29th 3 30 p.m Cuddle fish theater in Boston Cuddle fish.
Speaker 1: indeed We're gonna talk about.
Speaker 1: I just Google did something.
Speaker 1: that's gonna be in this panel.
Speaker 1: Like I learned about it today This panel is gonna be pretty pretty real talk about gaming.
Speaker 1: We will also well I will be geek.
Speaker 1: nights will be.
Speaker 1: Scott will not be what I will be at zenkai con The weekend before that.
Speaker 1: I'm just gonna be playing tabletop like the whole weekend.
Speaker 0: It's like icon is an anime con in Lancaster.
Speaker 1: It's not an anime con.
Speaker 1: It is a generic on much like kinetic on.
Speaker 0: zenkai is a Japanese.
Speaker 0: What do you think?
Speaker 1: zenkai con Mean stands for the etymology of that word.
Speaker 1: It is not what you think it is.
Speaker 0: I thought they actually stole.
Speaker 0: it wasn't like another convention.
Speaker 1: Thank God has never been an anime convention.
Speaker 1: it is.
Speaker 1: it has about as much anime content as Kinetic on.
Speaker 0: it was like another anime convention that died and zenkai come came from the ruins of it.
Speaker 0: Thank icon.
Speaker 1: Anyway, there's.
Speaker 1: you're close but not quite there.
Speaker 1: I will be there doing three panels on Saturday.
Speaker 1: I am doing the secret guide to running panels.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna tell you all how to run a panel like do it, right?
Speaker 1: Then I'm gonna do the 40 tabletop games you must play because this game.
Speaker 1: this con is actually Got a heavy tabletop presence like tabletop is bumping there But there's not a lot of tabletop content because people like us don't tend to go to small cons.
Speaker 1: So I'm gonna be there doing that and then play dirty to win on Sunday morning.
Speaker 1: It's gonna be a good time Beyond that.
Speaker 1: I want to get right into it.
Speaker 1: So if you're not aware Gig nights has a book club.
Speaker 1: We've been doing the gig nights book club since November of 2007 but we've only done how many books.
Speaker 1: we have done five pages of books.
Speaker 1: So we've done a decent number of books.
Speaker 0: Let's see if I go back how many books per year at average?
Speaker 1: Let's see - we just did in July of 2018 the Odyssey.
Speaker 0: So it's been almost a year since our last book in 2017.
Speaker 1: We did the fifth season dune Rebecca, so that was three three 2016.
Speaker 1: We did the coming third Reich Oryx and Craig 2015.
Speaker 0: we did any third Reich was not a book club.
Speaker 1: It was the book club.
Speaker 1: Just you weren't on the episode.
Speaker 1: We did.
Speaker 1: I got a bunch of guest hosts and did it.
Speaker 1: It was part of the book club.
Speaker 1: Uh-huh just here gig nights book club.
Speaker 0: It says politics club.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's the book club.
Speaker 1: Uh-huh in the inaugural gig guys following.
Speaker 1: We've done one of those.
Speaker 1: We had Scott Johnson, we had Andrew.
Speaker 1: we had.
Speaker 1: it was a good time.
Speaker 1: 2015 we did the eye of the world.
Speaker 1: 2014 we did wool and I daughter 2013 player of games the great gasps about to a year.
Speaker 0: Anyway, the point is it's been a long time since we did this book because we've been even though this book was tiny.
Speaker 0: So finally did it and thanks to my new read on the subway strategy that I've recommitted to fully I will proceed to finish the future book clubs very very quickly.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah now that I'm not playing race for the galaxy when I'm but the only thing that will prevent me from doing this plan is Biking to her kids that yeah, I think I read 2001 a Space Odyssey in about five days once I actually started.
Speaker 0: not take me long.
Speaker 0: It was like I think I estimated like eight subway rides or something.
Speaker 0: I think it took one less than my when I started reading it.
Speaker 1: Kindle was like it'll take you six hours to finish this book And by the time I finished the second like mini chapter It was like it's gonna take you four hours to finish before we talk about the actual book rim.
Speaker 0: Did I chose 2001 a Space Odyssey?
Speaker 0: Did you choose the next book club book?
Speaker 0: That is your choice.
Speaker 1: So I'm nearly chosen.
Speaker 1: I've thought about this a lot.
Speaker 0: on one hand Luke Burrage has suggested a book that seems very much up my head Burrage of the sci-fi Book-review podcast which has probably put up more book episodes than we have put out book club episodes ever.
Speaker 1: So he suggested nine Fox Gambit, which I want to read.
Speaker 1: the description of this because it might be good.
Speaker 0: I just I just you know personally.
Speaker 0: it's not my choice It's all your choice.
Speaker 0: But if someone pushes me to pick something that makes me not want to pick it even if they're see.
Speaker 1: I look for Suggestions from people I trust like.
Speaker 1: I don't want Scott Johnson to tell me what to read.
Speaker 0: But Luke Burrage is again.
Speaker 1: Luke knows the kind of books that I might like.
Speaker 0: it's probably.
Speaker 0: he's probably right But I still would don't want to be pressure.
Speaker 0: if you problem pressures me I'm gonna.
Speaker 1: but this cover looks like a culture book and it just says to win an impossible war Captain Cal chairs must awaken an ancient weapon and a despised traitor general.
Speaker 0: That sounds good.
Speaker 0: Yeah I still wouldn't pick it if someone forced me to try was trying to push me is disgraced for using an Unconventional method again in a battle against heretics.
Speaker 1: it there's this needle fortress in space.
Speaker 1: this just based on this This feels like you know fortress.
Speaker 0: that sounds a little bit like the the strike.
Speaker 1: It does this.
Speaker 1: this just looking at this surface value It looks like it's Horatio hornblower Grand Admiral throne and Larry and also once a book club.
Speaker 1: Yeah, anyway, but another way I could go is to reread a book.
Speaker 1: I haven't read since I was in high school.
Speaker 1: That is Odyssey adjacent Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: That is technically a pay licensed Dungeons & Dragons Planescape book, uh-oh, which means it is technically in the same universe as forgotten realms.
Speaker 1: but I recall actually being good and Being very Greek mythology like Theseus not Odysseus, but Theseus ship of Theseus, yeah, and Anyboat.
Speaker 1: Multiple people who have read it more recently cuz I last time I read it was like high school Read it more recently than me and said words to the effect of wow.
Speaker 1: That was actually a book.
Speaker 1: Did not expect that.
Speaker 1: People I trust have said these words Mm-hmm, so it's gonna be one of those two.
Speaker 1: probably do I reread a book?
Speaker 1: I read once in high school.
Speaker 1: that might actually be good, but might just be trash Might just be good, but in the guise of trash.
Speaker 1: or do I read a book that might be trash?
Speaker 1: But I haven't read it and it looks like the exact kind of trash I fucking love.
Speaker 0: it could just be alright, but so much better than you expect that it you know right?
Speaker 0: yeah It's like.
Speaker 0: oh, it's it's like those uh those Star Wars ones that everyone likes that I read the Thrawn ones.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like.
Speaker 0: I don't think they were good.
Speaker 0: get mad Star Wars people get mad as you want.
Speaker 0: I don't care They're not good.
Speaker 0: I don't think they were good, but you know what they were just better than the other Star Wars.
Speaker 0: But I remember when I read Troy Dennings how bad the other ones are.
Speaker 0: those are the best.
Speaker 1: when I read Pages of pain when I was in high school what I remember thinking at the end of it was wow that was a really good book.
Speaker 1: Like it made me think a lot about what it like what it meant mm-hmm, but that was 1996 rim.
Speaker 1: so 1996 rim had also read Every Forgotten realms elves doing their elven bullshit book and thought wow fucking elves are just fucking like best elves.
Speaker 1: man moon elves Sun elves.
Speaker 0: let's run them drow.
Speaker 0: Drow me up.
Speaker 1: Yeah, try.
Speaker 1: There's some.
Speaker 1: so Elaine Cunningham Also, did write a drow book.
Speaker 0: that give me some drow and some mind flayer.
Speaker 0: That's all I need.
Speaker 1: so Scott There is a book by someone who wrote pretty good fire out in realms book that is about a drow Who is not drizz it and is actually.
Speaker 0: This was a drow until just now.
Speaker 0: wow wow I just knew driss was the name of some D&D guy.
Speaker 1: driss is the drow Who is?
Speaker 1: Doing evil things, but it's not evil and comes around and does good stuff now.
Speaker 0: I know more.
Speaker 1: yeah, okay, driss I never want to know any.
Speaker 1: I never want to read any.
Speaker 1: I never want to hear driss name again those british garbage Just.
Speaker 1: But there's another drow that Elaine Cunningham wrote books about.
Speaker 1: that.
Speaker 0: better probably You're not inspiring confidence.
Speaker 1: I don't think those books are in the same class as pages of pain, okay I'm gonna pick one of those two books.
Speaker 1: unless someone in the next like by Sunday night this week tells me about a book that I have not thought about and Convinces me without talking to me like if you email me or tweet I mean be like read this book and you're able to convince me with that single interaction I'll pick your book instead odds are pretty low alright,
Speaker 0: so 2001 a space odyssey is a famous movie directed by Stanley Kubrick one of the best movies there ever was.
Speaker 0: I've seen it several times Including recently in 70 millimeter for the first time in a theater At the Museum of the moving image.
Speaker 1: so full disclosure I have seen 2001 a space odyssey.
Speaker 1: I Last saw it when I was in elementary school Elementary school, but I saw before you read pages of pain Yeah And I remember loving the hell out of it.
Speaker 1: And I remember thinking wow this movie is really really really really really really really really really really long And it's a little bit long.
Speaker 1: It's not Lawrence of Arabia No, but for someone in elementary school this movie is a thousand hours long.
Speaker 0: Hey get your money's worth.
Speaker 1: Yeah, no, but it wasn't.
Speaker 1: oh my god.
Speaker 1: This movie's long.
Speaker 0: I think it's my favorite kind.
Speaker 0: quiet in space.
Speaker 0: I think it was the first quiet space best movie.
Speaker 1: I think it was the first long quiet space thing I ever encountered.
Speaker 0: It's my first long quiet space thing.
Speaker 0: period like I saw quiet space thing was there before 2001 a space odyssey when I not not Express.
Speaker 0: so I saw not not a galactic rare.
Speaker 1: I saw the Empire Strikes back and then they came after this too.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and then later I saw 2001 a space Odyssey like in the TV.
Speaker 1: remember that channel on TV that showed what was gonna be on next.
Speaker 1: On all the channels like scrolling by I saw 2001 a space Odyssey and my kid brain said space Odyssey fuck yeah some more Star Wars and It was not Star Wars But I really liked it.
Speaker 1: I never encountered that kind of thing before.
Speaker 0: so I always knew that there was a book for this movie because I had been to Many libraries and I still went to live.
Speaker 0: I mean I should still go to libraries.
Speaker 0: But you know as a kid I went to a lot of libraries Before the internet was a thing and I saw the book there on the shelf.
Speaker 0: I even saw sequels like 2010 and whatnot.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and I just never read them.
Speaker 0: when I was a kid.
Speaker 0: I know I thought I should.
Speaker 1: I just never did and I'd always sort of assumed Like I just like my vague idea was cuz I knew sci-fi authors.
Speaker 1: I read a lot of Bradbury.
Speaker 1: when I was a kid I just assumed that Arthur C Clark had written this book and Stanley Kubrick had made a movie based on it.
Speaker 0: That's of course what you think cuz that's what happens is people write books or comics Which are easy to make at least production wise.
Speaker 0: not the story telling is still just as hard.
Speaker 0: Yeah, production of a book is easier, right?
Speaker 0: So that's where you know, just like with tabletop games.
Speaker 0: The production is easier.
Speaker 0: So your idea ideas get into the world faster and then someone who has got more production resources Will make a video game right now same thing.
Speaker 0: someone with low production resources But good storytelling and ideas will make a book and then someone else with a lot of resources will make a movie or TV show.
Speaker 0: So that's what I thought happened, but that is not what happened.
Speaker 0: Just when I started this book club a year ago Almost a year ago.
Speaker 0: I learned that what actually happened is Arthur C Clark the author and Stanley Kubrick the screenplay writer and director Worked together hand in hand and created both of these works at the same time.
Speaker 0: together.
Speaker 0: There are differences between them but much fewer than in the usual Adaptations.
Speaker 0: you see like say Lord of the Rings or what have you?
Speaker 1: and to be fair most of the differences once we get into This are more around.
Speaker 1: you get some context to a scene.
Speaker 1: That was much shorter in the movie Like that's most and the other differences are mostly a material, right?
Speaker 0: So like the biggest difference like story wise is that they go in the book they go all the way to Saturn yep, and in the movie they just go to Jupiter and it's like.
Speaker 0: That seems like a big difference, but really not it doesn't matter.
Speaker 0: It sounds like the exact same story is just in the book.
Speaker 0: The journey has like this extra chapter of Traveling from Jupiter to Saturn which is sort of like a chapter or two, which I think it's not a long book.
Speaker 1: So before we go any further I just want to say if you for whatever reason if never it didn't read the book because This is the geek nights book club.
Speaker 1: Meaning we're gonna talk about 2001 a Space Odyssey the novel Assuming that the listener you have read it or see we're not gonna same story.
Speaker 1: We're not gonna explain the plot.
Speaker 0: It's the same thing.
Speaker 1: So I think the reason the book had it this way is that it really it's part of the fact that Humans couldn't move that quickly in space.
Speaker 1: yet They had this pre-existing mission planned and then the few people who knew about the TMA-1 and the aliens were like Oh shit.
Speaker 1: Is there any way for us to get to Saturn?
Speaker 1: What if we use that mission that's already planned?
Speaker 1: Like I think that was the story that was implied by the.
Speaker 1: no we're actually going all the way out to Saturn But it doesn't matter to the space baby story.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm Simply by the nature of the medium.
Speaker 0: right in the movie The storytelling is often done through quiet not you know me this music this sound and audio But there is not necessarily dialogue.
Speaker 1: like you don't know what the monkeys are thinking, right?
Speaker 0: It's like.
Speaker 0: it's like the whole beginning of the movie is just monkeys doing stuff.
Speaker 0: You just watch them and all you hear them know it.
Speaker 0: the only there's no language.
Speaker 0: There's no written words.
Speaker 1: All you get is But the book is like Moonwatcher is doing this, right?
Speaker 0: You see what's happening with your eyes and a lot of times what you see with your eyes is explicit.
Speaker 0: You can.
Speaker 0: there's not a lot of room for interpretation But other times especially the end of the movie there's incredible room for interpretation because it's a lot of psychedelic imagery.
Speaker 1: There's basically no room for interpretation in the book.
Speaker 0: The book is like here's what happened in the book because it is words and there's no pictures.
Speaker 0: It has no choice, but too often Explicitly tell you what is happening in the story and You can just take that interpretation and apply it to the movie Which I really enjoyed.
Speaker 0: that aspect of literally every part of the movie that is like open to interpretation Exactly matches some words in the book.
Speaker 0: so you can remove your own interpretations if you want to accept the books.
Speaker 0: Interpretation for example the way it will match up 100% the way like if you're saying what was that monkey thinking just look in the book.
Speaker 0: Oh, that's what the monkey was thinking Like.
Speaker 1: for example the movies sort of like.
Speaker 1: it kind of shows the monkeys basically discovering violence and now humans.
Speaker 1: the book is much more like.
Speaker 1: it's very specific.
Speaker 1: the Monolith just tweaks the brains like it tests them figures out like tweaks It can make to give them a shot in D And it goes into a lot of detail about exactly what it did to these monkeys right in the movie.
Speaker 0: You can if you only see the movie you can go away like wondering like alright.
Speaker 0: clearly the monolith is some sort of alien thing.
Speaker 0: But you could go away thinking as I thought at various times Yeah is the monolith the aliens itself like they are monoliths or They something?
Speaker 0: is it something they made or both.
Speaker 0: or like you know it's like and why did they put them there?
Speaker 1: You could come up with lots of varying ideas or like the movie moves right into like Violence, but the book is it shows much more.
Speaker 1: The humans the proto humans are starving amid abundance because they don't know they can use tools to kill animals and eat them.
Speaker 1: It's not just kill the other monkeys like the movie kind of implies.
Speaker 1: It's more.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you you're looking at the problem the wrong way because you can't think.
Speaker 0: yet in the book it is explicit What the monoliths are.
Speaker 0: the aliens came and set a sort of trap in a way and that they?
Speaker 0: Sparked intelligence in new life forms and then intentionally right they saw some new life on Earth.
Speaker 0: They poked it intentionally to try to you know spur it along the path of being more intelligent.
Speaker 0: And then they explicitly set a trap on the moon and also on Saturn Yeah, such that if and when that life that they sparked right ever You know finally became intelligent enough to go to the moon and find the trap that it would then be carried away.
Speaker 0: You know and discovered.
Speaker 0: you know brought to the aliens place so that they would know yep Much in the way that like I would turn on a fire under some water and then have a thermometer that would beep when it Reached boiling.
Speaker 0: so what I really like it walk away from it It would boil and I could come back where all the like.
Speaker 1: very specific details of what the monolith did to the monkeys.
Speaker 1: that Section is actually pretty long in the book yep.
Speaker 1: And the detail there is interesting because it reminds me a lot of the culture books and the effectors like I can see a lot of echoes of how the monolith interacted with the monkeys and how culture shifts interact with meat.
Speaker 1: people.
Speaker 1: in terms of the effectors like Messing with brain signals to make things change and something's brain Yeah.
Speaker 0: So what's really interesting about this?
Speaker 1: because it also implies that the second monolith might have done the same thing to the Scientists who dug it up on the moon and might have even potentially done that to the AI's right.
Speaker 0: so in The movie right I sort of when I when I only saw the movie I sort of viewed it as this whole work because it presented as a whole work right in one cohesive story even though it has These chapters that are so far apart from each other.
Speaker 0: right, but the book.
Speaker 0: I was told that the book was Slightly adapted stuff from some of other of Arthur Arthur C. Clarke short stories, which I didn't read.
Speaker 0: so I don't know about them.
Speaker 0: But in the book you can clearly see that like this is actually Separate short stories that were then Sort of like very cohesively tied together like the monkey monolith story.
Speaker 1: That's a fine story by itself.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's really good by itself right if you never read about TMA one and everything after that.
Speaker 0: Right and it's like the.
Speaker 0: you know the the main story that everyone thinks of which is only one part of 2001.
Speaker 0: You know the how Odyssey spaceship part right is a computer goes wrong Story, which is the most classic sci-fi story of all.
Speaker 1: right, but it's also Yep, it's definitely like well butler in jihad Because like that little note when they reestablish communication and earth is like yeah one of our two house Also went crazy.
Speaker 0: Now the most right.
Speaker 0: so you know what reading the book.
Speaker 0: I now see how it's these separate stories.
Speaker 0: It's almost like if you were able to take four different Twilight Zone episode Episodes together and sort of make them all the same thing.
Speaker 1: It's it's so there's one bit that happens in the monkey part that you really love the monkey part.
Speaker 1: well I thought about this a lot because it was stated directly like here is what happened here.
Speaker 0: Did you just read the monkey part?
Speaker 1: So beginning I thought about the monkey part a lot because there's a moment with the leopard where like an aspect of it I'll get to in a second is explained explicitly like here is why this went down the way it did.
Speaker 1: And as soon as I read that part I thought about what happened to hell.
Speaker 1: and then when you see in the book what happens with hell I think a parallel is intended to be drawn there.
Speaker 1: so When the humans like the proto humans start to figure some shit out one thing that moon dance or moon watchers does is Drat is like he has this idea.
Speaker 1: wait.
Speaker 1: We don't have to just eat the thing we killed out here.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna drag it into my fucking house, and that's a big deal.
Speaker 1: But then the book makes it very clear that moon dancer had a good idea But was not yet fully equipped to understand the unintended consequences and unknown Dangers or non obvious dangers that would come from this good idea.
Speaker 1: the unknown danger was the leopard Will now smell dead meat and definitely come into his house that night.
Speaker 1: It was almost a test of him.
Speaker 1: can he deal with the unintended danger of a technology?
Speaker 1: He is using that he isn't fully yet understand.
Speaker 1: fast forward to hell humans made AI a tool that was Necessary for them to evolve and to have this space mission.
Speaker 1: But they did.
Speaker 1: they use the technology before they fully understood the ramifications of it And they had to overcome that danger to use the technology to get to the next stage.
Speaker 0: Funny is how 2010 which we're not gonna talk about completely changes like the house story.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right anyway.
Speaker 0: So something else that's really fascinating about 2001. as you watch this movie or read this book Right and if you don't know just like try to guess like when it was written Right or when when the movie was made and you will never guess that this movie and book which the movie still looks better Than any movie that's made even today, right and it was made in 1968. yeah before we were on the moon.
Speaker 0: Yeah The one on the moon and this is about a moon base.
Speaker 1: the forward talks a lot about a spaceship that goes to Saturn like Look go figure out like what humans like what we knew about space and the solar system in 1968. a lot of thing a lot of concepts that you just know today from like Astronomy class or like science class in high school.
Speaker 1: We did not know in 1960.
Speaker 0: some of the scientific things in this book are just straight-up wrong because we didn't know which were which Were clearly based on research of the you know, the knowledge we had in 1968.
Speaker 0: They were true then You know true as in the the best to human knowledge in 1968.
Speaker 0: But for an example is this stuff in there about the age of Saturn's rings?
Speaker 0: Yeah, and it's like we know the age of Saturn's rings now a lot better than we did in 1968 Right and the makeup of them and such and such right?
Speaker 0: So the information in there about it sounds correct, but is not we learn better?
Speaker 1: Yep, but at the same time it is really fascinating how plausible all of this seems right.
Speaker 0: remember It's 2001 the Space Odyssey right.
Speaker 1: now is 2019.
Speaker 0: It's way in the past But they were what they were doing, you know Kubrick and and Clark is they were like well Look at the rate of change in in space technology so far.
Speaker 0: We'll be on the moon soon ish, hopefully, right?
Speaker 0: They didn't know if we would or wouldn't but they thought they would soon.
Speaker 0: Hey, they made a lot of stuff.
Speaker 0: We keep progressing in space.
Speaker 0: at this rate We should be going to Saturn with difficulty around 2001 and we'll have better computers.
Speaker 1: So it is interesting to know I have an AI by then to know the Commodore 64 now like the specific I don't want to say in acronyms like the things that were really wrong.
Speaker 1: and they come down to the casual sexism.
Speaker 1: Mmm, the like.
Speaker 0: yeah, how many women are even in this book?
Speaker 1: Yep There's the design talks about like office ladies and secretaries with typewriters a lot.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's pretty much the only women in this book are like wives The stewardesses on the space plane And the office ladies typing on typewriters.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there's not much typewriters despite advanced AI computers.
Speaker 1: Typewriters are all in the same world, right?
Speaker 0: Well, that's that's what happens with everything right?
Speaker 0: It's like the futuristic stuff we're thinking of now.
Speaker 0: people will look at and laugh in the same way.
Speaker 1: Yep, well like all the old sci-fi still assume we'd have these big CRTs everywhere, right?
Speaker 1: like in Information.
Speaker 1: take it's interesting all sci-fi.
Speaker 1: there seems to be this trend that the main thing everyone got wrong is.
Speaker 1: they assume that like Material science and AI stuff would get way advanced, but they didn't anticipate information technology.
Speaker 0: I think I don't think that's the thing that he didn't anticipate it.
Speaker 0: I think it's like, you know, I always tell people when you're making a game, right?
Speaker 0: There's a thing that your game does.
Speaker 0: Yep, and then you should focus on that and everything else.
Speaker 0: just do what's normal, right?
Speaker 0: So if you're making a sci-fi, maybe your sci-fi is about time travel.
Speaker 0: So you focus on that time travel part and that's the stuff that you really develop the lore around.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and all the other stuff It's like you don't have time to.
Speaker 0: it's really hard to also Futuristically think about all the other parts of the society because the the time travel central to your time travel story.
Speaker 0: So that part is like super fleshed out and is futuristic but like Really someone time travels and there's computers and it's like well, there's just computers.
Speaker 0: You can't really.
Speaker 0: how much effort can you put into bringing that full?
Speaker 1: I think it partly shows because it's specifically with information technology like information technology head is the one science that really has grown at a Terrifying exponential rate like it was information technology that grew not space.
Speaker 0: So the how part was right and the space part was wrong like in 2019.
Speaker 0: It didn't have to be wrong if we would have invested, you know properly and continued to invest.
Speaker 0: We would be better than I'll bet.
Speaker 1: not because the main difference is that information technology Isn't as tied to physical.
Speaker 0: Laws of physics are in the way.
Speaker 0: But yeah We would.
Speaker 0: we could be further along than we are now.
Speaker 1: like we always say with ghost in the shell We the meme warfare and I say that seriously like I'm not joking Meme warfare in 2019 is already more advanced and more terrifying than what happens in ghost in the shell.
Speaker 1: yet We don't have cybernetic bodies.
Speaker 0: Oh, damn it.
Speaker 1: Like why do I part?
Speaker 1: I want Why do we get the worst parts of these dystopian cyberpunk futures, but now I want the good parts only.
Speaker 1: That's why do we have Russian like meme warfare?
Speaker 1: shit posters, but I don't have an awesome sexy cyber body.
Speaker 0: Yeah, give me that sexy server.
Speaker 1: Yeah So, uh, the other thing is I wish the book had not mentioned specific dollar amounts of things.
Speaker 1: I feel like that's an easy trap to avoid because they talk a lot about.
Speaker 1: yeah How many hundred thousand dollar a year people made?
Speaker 1: this is like wow $100,000 a year does not hire advanced people.
Speaker 0: Yeah an actual discovery trip to you know Would cost trillions I guess to go to Saturn.
Speaker 0: I imagine the amount of fuel.
Speaker 0: you would need the size of the ship the moon But they're space stations.
Speaker 1: They had all those aspects track with like modern sci-fi like the space docks are all right Like.
Speaker 1: all that stuff is actually pretty.
Speaker 1: it's like.
Speaker 0: that is how we do it.
Speaker 0: Focus a lot on you know, the fact it's like.
Speaker 0: well, there's no gravity.
Speaker 0: That means it's got to be like this.
Speaker 0: You got a tether like that.
Speaker 0: You got all these things that you know, they're not making up Stuff like magic right out in space.
Speaker 0: So it's all the other thing.
Speaker 0: I don't know if it.
Speaker 0: you know, people always argue about what hard sci-fi means but it's hard sci-fi enough.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right It's hard enough.
Speaker 1: and also I made maybe I miss remember to the movie.
Speaker 1: but the other thing that really stood out to me is that there's one little chapter in the book that is like Here's where the aliens came from.
Speaker 1: Here's exactly what they were thinking in detail.
Speaker 1: Here's the reality.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like.
Speaker 1: it just explains it like oh they did this.
Speaker 1: This is their space.
Speaker 0: when he's on his journey right after he goes into the the full of stars monolith Yeah, it's like.
Speaker 0: oh he went to outer space Grand Central terminal Yeah, and then he's here's this.
Speaker 1: here's a precursor technology that they abandoned because they became energy lifeforms like you do.
Speaker 0: right You know, he's now he's in this room.
Speaker 0: It's basically some sort of prison slash zoo thing that the aliens made on purpose.
Speaker 0: clearly
Speaker 1: the aliens made like the thought Willed this space around him into existence to have him safe long enough to prepare him for what they were about to do to him Which was turn him into one of them send him back to earth and say alright You know enough about humans and now you're a space.
Speaker 1: You're a baby version of us.
Speaker 1: Make humans turn into us, right?
Speaker 1: Make humans have a chance to do whatever it is.
Speaker 1: They're gonna do in the cosmos.
Speaker 0: Oh go be the god of humans.
Speaker 1: Yep, you're you're a and I love that.
Speaker 1: the a lot of people who don't Get things like they watch a movie like the kinds of people in this in 1968.
Speaker 0: my interpretation of the movie was not far off.
Speaker 0: No, it was not exact.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but like you can tell the kind of person who says oh, yeah It's a space baby in the end and didn't get it.
Speaker 1: cuz clearly space baby is just a metaphor.
Speaker 1: He sees himself like a baby because he is a baby of this other race now with human memories and human ideas and that's the way to bridge the Gulf of space and time between what these beings became and What like.
Speaker 1: what is necessary to help humans get to the next level because they're benevolent aliens.
Speaker 0: They're nice They want to help you but they made humans.
Speaker 0: Yeah effectively, right?
Speaker 0: Well, they helped monkey become human and beat leopard and now they you know, they're.
Speaker 0: they're not evil They're not like Independence Day.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: They want good stuff to happen.
Speaker 1: I like that story a lot.
Speaker 1: it the book has a lot of echoes of Specific things in the culture series that the culture series clearly based on this book and books like it.
Speaker 0: What's really great about this story as a whole in in both forms?
Speaker 0: Is that it is not a story of heroes and villains?
Speaker 1: Oh at all.
Speaker 1: Like our may our protagonists like the hell Situation is resolved and not that many pages and he just does it and he feels bad about it.
Speaker 1: He does what he needs to do the to me.
Speaker 0: You know all the main characters of every part are extremely confident and not stupid or any way.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right how isn't even evil?
Speaker 0: or you know hell just panics Which is how was just messed up for reasons that are explained in 2010.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but in this book in a vacuum hell had a crisis of conscience because he was made by humans who didn't fully understand How a I work.
Speaker 1: you mean you.
Speaker 1: it tells you very clearly how hell's are made.
Speaker 1: They're made by making this crazy AI and then just teaching it Like growing like it grows up like it's.
Speaker 1: there's a baby hell.
Speaker 0: I was just like, you know erode basically not evil.
Speaker 1: Hell had a crisis of conscience because he was told to lie to people and didn't know how to handle that.
Speaker 1: So we tried to like he messed up.
Speaker 1: Yep, like it's sad like he's programmed poorly.
Speaker 0: so there's any villains.
Speaker 0: You know, it was the ones who programmed how to lie or raised poorly.
Speaker 0: Well, that's he was according to 2010 his program for according to 2001.
Speaker 1: He was raised.
Speaker 0: He was raised but people who raised him weren't the ones who told him to lie.
Speaker 0: Well, the problem is the government was but the government wasn't malicious in doing so.
Speaker 0: they thought they were doing it for a good reason.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right, so it's like there wasn't anyone with evil or malicious intent anywhere in the story.
Speaker 0: not the aliens not humans like even like a little bit of Cold War conflict.
Speaker 0: because but it's 1968 but they've seemed to have written it such that yeah, they're still sort of competing but not really, you know evil nuclear war.
Speaker 1: competing like it implies that humans are much are very unified and that the Cold War is becoming a legacy thing because it makes a mention of the Russia Soviet bloc.
Speaker 1: like Russia and the USSR and the US are basically allies now and China is like the quote-unquote adversary But in a more cooperative way like it's.
Speaker 1: it implies that humans are close to having a unified government.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm, but that's backstory.
Speaker 0: Yeah, he meets, you know, the Russian dude in the space station and they're friendly and he's like, hey How you doing?
Speaker 0: They're all still separate because of the space station.
Speaker 0: They stole this immigration stuff all the separate but it makes that clear point of you go through.
Speaker 0: They're not sharing all their secrets with each other, but yeah hearing some.
Speaker 1: but like you go through immigration spying But they're not.
Speaker 0: like he doesn't come back to earth to see that it's been destroyed in nuclear warfare.
Speaker 1: well in fact when he comes back to other stories when he comes back to earth a Unified earth government launches nukes at him because they're scared and he's just like oh they're nuking.
Speaker 1: I guess I'll just turn the nukes off.
Speaker 1: Sorry guys.
Speaker 1: You're not gonna nuke me.
Speaker 1: I came out of a literal Sun like just now.
Speaker 1: I Like the book a lot and I feel like the book is required reading material.
Speaker 1: if you've watched the movie and vice-versa Mmm, because I want to watch the movie again shouldn't have gone so long without reading that book and see it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I should.
Speaker 1: I should have read this book when I was in elementary school.
Speaker 0: 2010 is a lot, you know as a movie is a lot less.
Speaker 0: You know, it's not directed by Kubrick, right?
Speaker 0: So it's 2010 is still a good movie.
Speaker 0: That's the Europa one Right, but it doesn't have.
Speaker 0: it's not a lot of interpretive imagery and stuff like that.
Speaker 0: It's much more straightforward like people doing this people doing that people do and this people doing that It's.
Speaker 0: it's.
Speaker 0: it's more like reading this book.
Speaker 0: Very just explicit what happens, you know?
Speaker 0: Not a lot of metaphors or symbologies or anything like that.
Speaker 0: So symbolism, I wonder if both.
Speaker 0: I wonder if the 2010 book how that differs from the 2010 movie which I've seen the 2010 movie within the past year.
Speaker 1: I saw it when we were at RIT because we kept we we were right where for whatever reason we were all Referencing Europa so much that I watched.
Speaker 0: that was probably my fault.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so I. so I just like.
Speaker 1: I downloaded it from the Direct Connect and watched it again just randomly.
Speaker 1: Mmm I remember I watched it in that one has a lot.
Speaker 0: 2010 is a lot more Cold War action.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right then 2001 does.
Speaker 1: the good news is 2001. the book and the movie like just stand alone very powerfully.
Speaker 1: You don't need to read or watch any more to get a lot out of them.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm I'm really.
Speaker 1: I really wish I'd read this book back in elementary school instead of waiting until 2019 to read the 2001 book from 1968.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm Is there anything else we should point out?
Speaker 1: I think we're good.
Speaker 0: I'm sure you know.
Speaker 0: This is the kind of book where people much smarter than us have much more smarter things to say about it.
Speaker 1: I mean the the main thing I got out of.
Speaker 1: the only two things I really got out of it that I didn't get out of the movie were One.
Speaker 1: the pair like that you could not get out of the movie is the parallel between the leopard and hell.
Speaker 1: Like that is something I could not have gotten out of the movie.
Speaker 1: I don't think and I think that is a very important theme.
Speaker 0: I remember if the leopard was even in the moon.
Speaker 0: I don't think it was I died.
Speaker 0: some other small differences in the movie are like like the monolith is a different color for reasons.
Speaker 0: Well, no, the monolith is black in the book except at the beginning of it's.
Speaker 0: it's it's clear sometimes in the.
Speaker 1: well Because it did the monolith that's clear is doing shit.
Speaker 1: The monolith is black is a black body so you won't detect it until you're ready and so it could absorb energy.
Speaker 1: You know, there's.
Speaker 1: and then there's like there's sci-fi reasons why it's black.
Speaker 0: when the doctors on the space station in the movie He talks to the Russian guy and like these two women and I think on the space station in the book It's just the Russian guy.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and I think the discussion he has with his daughter on earth is different and some you know It's really small stuff.
Speaker 0: That doesn't matter for the big picture the actual message book or the core It's all this like this side ancillary stuff that you really literally could be anything and doesn't mean much.
Speaker 1: Yeah like you get out of the book a hundred percent that the monolith is a black body like Vantablack or whatever.
Speaker 1: like it is black for a reason a sci-fi reason.
Speaker 1: Yep So yeah, if you listen to all this and you didn't read the book just read the book Like even if you've seen the movie even if you haven't seen the movie this book is.
Speaker 1: there's a reason why?
Speaker 1: 2001 a Space Odyssey is so important and so remembered and so referenced.
Speaker 1: The book is really good and it takes like three hours to read.
Speaker 1: It's not long It's super sure like I mean.
Speaker 0: it took us almost year to read it But but it really took.
Speaker 1: us are until recently took us about three hours to read.
Speaker 0: It's like us almost here to start reading it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, once you read page one, it didn't take.
Speaker 1: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Speaker 0: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 1: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays and make comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 0: But unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 0: It's actually recorded at night
Speaker 1: and the patreon patrons for this geek nights book club episode are Craig Oliver Alan Joyce Heidi McNichol just like a dude guy kashar tavish and link eg Jennifer Hitchcock Chris midkiff my stady Calm Jay bants scooter lonely Roberto Kingsley Shawn Yeager Matthew Smith Nicholas Brando, mr Strong distraction for to one creations Chris Thomas Robert Hahn and Shervin von Horrell rare Rory Rochelle, Monta Nona super boys sailor Vista Joe Shiro Joe star Clinton Walton Ren from museum the Zealand Ryan Perrin through open Lander Finn Daniel Redman Shawn Klein Chris Reimer and Thomas on.
Speaker 1: if you're going to be at Senkai counter back seats Let us know we will potentially hang out or stand awkwardly next to each other.
Speaker 1: And now I leave you Oh.