Speaker 0: It's Monday April 29th 2019.
Speaker 0: I'm rim.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott, and this is geek nights tonight fishing with a pH Not the band.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: So I was randomly looking at my youtube channel because I was uploading a bunch more of the videos that are just the reviews of Board games.
Speaker 0: we do without like the rest of the episode around the zoom and watch that yeah They all get hundreds of views and I get a lot of like likes within board game geek because that's where I post them all.
Speaker 0: Okay, it's it.
Speaker 0: I think it's good because sometimes we have like a 10-minute review of a game That's at the end of a 50-minute episode of geek not it's mmm.
Speaker 0: So it actually is working out pretty well, and it does not take a lot of work.
Speaker 0: But when I was looking at my youtube channel I don't look at the analytics that often like once a month I check in on it And I notice I look at it.
Speaker 1: never I noticed that I had no idea if I had like a million subscribers.
Speaker 0: I'd only find out when like the silver thing showed up, but so I noticed that I had six thousand nine hundred and ninety-nine subscribers And I was like oh I should get a screenshot cuz that'll be funny, and then I got distracted.
Speaker 0: I finished something I went shot.
Speaker 0: it went up.
Speaker 0: It's like 7020. now it's already passed and don't?
Speaker 0: I guess I could Photoshop it without.
Speaker 1: You could just use the ins the web inspector to change the number and then yeah.
Speaker 0: Or I could block enough people from my channel to get it back down to six thousand nine hundred ninety-nine.
Speaker 1: I could just take screenshots with the web inspector to act like I had a bajillion views And then try to get someone to give me money.
Speaker 1: no him become a. you know fake it till I make it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like people who buy followers or whatever.
Speaker 0: the analytics on the channel are actually pretty interesting If you actually look at them because you do get a lot of dudes watching.
Speaker 0: yeah But you also the thing you get.
Speaker 0: that's real interesting.
Speaker 0: It's the like.
Speaker 0: you can find out what videos people are watching where they're like what fuck this and they unsubscribe As.
Speaker 0: and also you can find out like what video someone watching and they're like People.
Speaker 0: seemed we had a more people unsubscribe from a real harm.
Speaker 1: We need to figure out what videos are watched most by non white non straight non dudes.
Speaker 1: More videos like those we could.
Speaker 0: we could try stuff.
Speaker 0: we could do it.
Speaker 1: We could treat ourselves like we're the gin the the machine learning thing.
Speaker 1: Right and just.
Speaker 1: we just choose right rather than most people who are like going towards following the money or following, right?
Speaker 1: We follow a different metric for for success.
Speaker 0: One thing I can say is that I'll see if it changed right now.
Speaker 0: But if we look at traffic sources most people watch our channel Because they're browsing YouTube and they just see one of our videos recommended and they click on it.
Speaker 0: That is like 90% of our views.
Speaker 0: And then the rest are YouTube searches and the YouTube searches are almost entirely for in order.
Speaker 0: Boardgame design tires and Euphrates board game rare game mechanics game theory game design game mechanics Puerto Rico board game Carcassonne strategy board game.
Speaker 1: in his big these days rim to cost her.
Speaker 0: Okay, making board game diplomacy board game board games board game game balance.
Speaker 0: how to make a board game.
Speaker 1: Are all these like one search each now?
Speaker 0: No, they're all hundreds and hundreds.
Speaker 0: Okay, it's really funny But rim to cost her is like they're in the top ten.
Speaker 1: Say yeah, okay, whatever.
Speaker 0: So what you got?
Speaker 0: news?
Speaker 0: wise it's Monday.
Speaker 1: Ah, so I do have some news to check it out.
Speaker 1: This is relevant.
Speaker 1: This is how we thought of our main bit.
Speaker 1: by the way Someone has found a new and interesting way to fish People using mobile browsers.
Speaker 1: they developed the proof of concept Which is all they only made.
Speaker 1: did the work to make prove it for Chrome on Iowa like what iOS or only what?
Speaker 1: But you could just take there.
Speaker 1: you could easily take what they did and replicate it.
Speaker 0: So it's a really clever escalation of like fishing technique, right?
Speaker 1: So here's the deal, right?
Speaker 1: Let's say you're gonna go on your phone right when you open the web browser.
Speaker 1: You know how you scroll down and you really want to save screen space.
Speaker 0: So not that many P, right?
Speaker 1: So what they do on your phone when you scroll down on a web page is they make the location bar go away.
Speaker 0: Right, which makes sense.
Speaker 1: So it makes sense.
Speaker 1: So what he did this guy is he says, all right I programmed my website such that when you scroll down a bunch and the location bar goes away So the first time you load the page the real location bar is there with the real URL in it.
Speaker 0: Yeah with the HTTPS and it's like yep, you're at your website.
Speaker 1: You scroll down far enough a Different the locate the real location bar goes away.
Speaker 1: He takes an image of a fake location bar and makes it appear and it says like chase.com Or hsbc.com or bank of america.com.
Speaker 1: in right?
Speaker 1: He basically just took a screenshot of the bank location bar on the bank's website, right and just put it at the top.
Speaker 1: So now it looks like you're officially green light green lock on This the bank's website, but you're on this other person's website.
Speaker 1: If the website also looked like the bank's website then they could fool you into now Presumably with like a link in an email.
Speaker 1: you click the link in the email you land on this website.
Speaker 1: It looks real.
Speaker 1: you scroll down the location bar changes.
Speaker 1: If you don't notice the location bar was fake and had the wrong URL in it at the start.
Speaker 1: Maybe it was a really close URL using like some Unico shenanigans, right?
Speaker 1: Then it's gonna look like you're really on your bank's website for real like totally trustworthy.
Speaker 1: And then you type and use the in password and then you lose all your money.
Speaker 0: Yep All right.
Speaker 0: So it's one of those things we're like Phones.
Speaker 0: just the way they're used are very limited and there's a lot of differences compared to a real computer.
Speaker 0: So like you can't hover over a URL just like really quickly.
Speaker 0: See where does it really go?
Speaker 0: Yeah, like things like this disappears the you never have the top bar disappear in a real web browser on a real device.
Speaker 1: Right, you know the real You know.
Speaker 1: the way to take this even further would be to make not just use a screenshot of the location bar But to program a fake location bar that can be used to programmatically detect What browser the person is using to show them a location bar that matches their browser?
Speaker 1: Right, like is that using Chrome on iOS?
Speaker 1: Okay, we got to show this fake, you know location bar style, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, you'd have to go pretty far to make it really convincing but you know, it goes even where it's actually worse than I thought.
Speaker 0: It says that normally when you scroll up, you know, you get the real bar.
Speaker 1: But now you can never get the real bar back unless you reload.
Speaker 0: Yep, because they put you in a scroll jail.
Speaker 0: Yep, scroll jail with an element that just prevents it.
Speaker 0: Let's see overflow colon scroll.
Speaker 0: the user thinks they're scrolling up the page But in fact, they're only scrolling up in the scroll jail.
Speaker 0: I can see how you can pull that off.
Speaker 0: Yep this is pretty big because a Lot of people only have a phone or a tablet as their computing device like they don't have a computer.
Speaker 1: now It's less of a big deal because you know if I'm using my phone I would never do anything.
Speaker 1: Secure login in the browser on my phone.
Speaker 1: I was never the app right.
Speaker 1: and if you're using iOS at least you can trust the app that came from the App Store For the real App Store if you hear right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, if you downloaded the wrong app, you're already hosed, right?
Speaker 1: But iOS Apple won't let.
Speaker 1: they're not the real app in the App Store.
Speaker 1: Yeah, whereas Android might Google Play you can't trust it, but Apple you can more trust it mostly, right?
Speaker 1: So if I get the chase app I can trust it's as secure as the chase website on a secure brand-new good computer.
Speaker 1: It was scary.
Speaker 0: I guess the moral is on a phone Trust apps like you would a TLS certificate and just use your web browser for things that don't matter, right?
Speaker 1: Anything secure you do on your phone?
Speaker 1: You should be using an app.
Speaker 1: Don't trust the browser on the phone not just because of this but just in general.
Speaker 1: Why are you using the browser when an app is available on your phone?
Speaker 0: I mean, I tried to think of what do I actually go to on a browser on my phone?
Speaker 0: And it literally is the gig nights forum.
Speaker 0: Yep, Fark Google News There's like nothing else in my hand.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't use it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but you're still like that.
Speaker 1: You could they could log into your Gmail with that Now if they tricked me into clicking on.
Speaker 1: there used to be more things that I use the browser for on the phone Because there weren't apps for everything, but I've been so long.
Speaker 1: It's been like 12 years since I had iPhones.
Speaker 0: I don't go to Google News that often because I also pay for Waypo.
Speaker 0: So usually I just open the Waypo app.
Speaker 1: Anyway, but yeah, it's like.
Speaker 1: You know, it's been like 12 something years since I had iPhones.
Speaker 1: so Apps exist now right Google Calendar used to not have an app.
Speaker 1: I'd have to like go to Google Calendar on the web.
Speaker 1: now is a really good Google Calendar app, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, so everything's pretty good.
Speaker 0: So in some other app related news there's a lot of apps especially in the iPhone store that are designed to either help you curb your addiction to your own phone or Control how much time your kids spend messing with the phone.
Speaker 1: right now Apple in iOS includes lots of functionality Including in the newest version.
Speaker 1: They've added a lot of functionality for the helping curbing your addiction.
Speaker 1: I keep getting notifications like your screen times up your screen times down.
Speaker 1: you spent this much screen.
Speaker 1: I can look and see exactly how much time I spent in each app.
Speaker 1: It's all built into iOS and Apple's always had parental controls.
Speaker 1: ever since like the first iPhone they've only gotten more advanced.
Speaker 1: but for some people those controls might not be enough and Apple has always allowed and always supported people making other parental control apps or other screen time management apps and putting them in the App Store as Long as they follow all the App Store rules, you know, we can't.
Speaker 1: we're not gonna talk about the general App Store rules.
Speaker 1: You know deal again.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right We're only talking about this specific thing.
Speaker 1: and what happened is that some of the apps right?
Speaker 1: We're given notices like hey, your app is not in compliance with these rules.
Speaker 1: If you don't fix your app in 30 days We're gonna kick you out of the App Store.
Speaker 1: and some apps fix their shit.
Speaker 1: and some apps did not fix their shit And they got kicked out.
Speaker 1: and now they're complaining.
Speaker 0: yep, and it seems like the crux of it is the apps that are targeted specifically at children and controlling children's access to things probably because Children being online is heavily regulated both in the US and in Europe, right?
Speaker 1: But I think the the main technological thing here that Apple is upset about is the use of MDM which stands for mobile device management.
Speaker 1: Right, so basically it much in the way that like when you install an antivirus software on your computer Right the antivirus software in order to clean out viruses and prevent viruses and other Malwares the antivirus software needs a lot of permissions and it needs to do lots of things to detect viruses that are otherwise Not acceptable for other software to do.
Speaker 1: because yeah, it's much in the way to fight a cheater.
Speaker 1: You need to be a cheater.
Speaker 1: How can I find a rootkit if I can't be even lower levels have lower level CPU access than the rootkit, right?
Speaker 1: How can I clean out the virus from these OS files if I don't have permission to read on write all your OS files?
Speaker 0: Yeah, right.
Speaker 1: so much in the same way to Implement a lot of the parental control features right like seeing spying on what websites are going to spying and how much time different apps Are open, you know seeing what's on the screen, you know, I'm your parent.
Speaker 1: I want to see what you're doing right now to see if it's porn without coming up and looking behind you.
Speaker 1: So, you know, I'm looking right.
Speaker 1: make your phone turn off and you can't turn it back on.
Speaker 1: lock your phone.
Speaker 1: Make sure you can't unlock it.
Speaker 1: See where the phone is.
Speaker 1: all these sorts, you know.
Speaker 1: See what the camera on the phone sees remotely.
Speaker 1: These are all major things that would normally be major.
Speaker 1: security flaws cannot allow major permissions problems.
Speaker 1: Yeah in order for these parental controls to work you sort of have to allow these things and apples like no That's unsecure as hell really bad.
Speaker 1: We're not.
Speaker 1: we can't allow apps to be doing this.
Speaker 0: I would not try.
Speaker 0: I don't trust apps like that in general.
Speaker 0: Yeah, because that's the kind of app that I would make if I was gonna try to compromise your phone.
Speaker 1: I notice you don't put any virus stuff on our computer either.
Speaker 0: Yep, because antivirus software It doesn't work and/or is a scam in most cases.
Speaker 0: just use the windows one is fine or don't use anything.
Speaker 0: The windows one is fine.
Speaker 1: Whatever the point is The Apple parental controls aren't those enough for you, really?
Speaker 1: The article I picked a random article about the Apple feature they just added for managing your screen time.
Speaker 1: That's really not enough for you.
Speaker 0: So I picked a random article about this and it seems like the people who are mad are mostly parents who don't understand how to use the Apple one and want Extremely fine-grain control of how their children is.
Speaker 1: you're extremely fine-grain control.
Speaker 0: Don't give your kid a phone unsupervised done or give your kid a phone and Be a good parent.
Speaker 1: Yep Why did you?
Speaker 1: why do you have a kid that wants to go look at?
Speaker 1: you know, murder porn?
Speaker 1: well ultra porn.
Speaker 0: Well, what about the kid?
Speaker 0: Well, what about the kids who are just being recruited by white supremacists because they went to the wrong YouTube?
Speaker 1: Why did you raise a kid who wants to go look at white supremacists?
Speaker 1: Why did you raise your kid not to be able to recognize Nazis?
Speaker 0: well one thing I could recognize Nazis now as a kid, I guess one thing I can say that's different between when we were kids and Today is that when we were kids Most kids did not have access to the internet at all.
Speaker 0: true and the people who did tended to be pretty technologically savvy Or they couldn't make it work also true and we tended to have unsupervised access But most of the stuff on the internet was made by other people like us also true.
Speaker 0: now There's Nazis like actively trying to sneak in and trick people also true.
Speaker 0: So it is a different world Like I don't want.
Speaker 0: I don't want us to fall to survivor bias of.
Speaker 0: I had unrestricted access to the internet.
Speaker 0: I'm fine because when I got it when I got a different internet, it was a different internet in 1997 or 98, dude It is hard to express to some of you like younger listeners how different the internet was in 1997 but my Nazi detecting skills.
Speaker 1: Yes, possibly because I was raised among Jewish people.
Speaker 1: Maybe everyone should be raised among Jewish people, but I would solve a lot of problems.
Speaker 0: I will say I get the impression that most of the apps that were shut down.
Speaker 0: This is probably fine and The people who are mad about this are a vocal minority who want very specific niche things.
Speaker 1: They're vocal minority who made the apps that got shut down.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they probably found some parents who to comply who are mad that the app got shut down and got them They pretended to be their own customers.
Speaker 0: Yeah So in some other news that you probably should be paying attention to like it or not The measles epidemic in the United States is can is actually growing rapidly and is a big fucking problem.
Speaker 1: If you got measles stay the hell away from me and anyone I know.
Speaker 0: yeah, cuz I got vaccinated.
Speaker 1: But in fact if you got the measles and it whether it was because you were bad Or maybe it's because you were good and it just happened because other people were bad You should go find bad people and hang out near them.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you don't make the most of it.
Speaker 0: There are so there are confirmed at least say over 700 cases across 22 states.
Speaker 0: now This is getting to the point to where it is a way.
Speaker 1: Is there no class-action lawsuit amongst the people who got measles who were Vaccinated and or some or couldn't be vaccinated against peep anti-vax people to sue them in in the ground?
Speaker 0: Well, most of the people are getting measles are themselves not vaccinated because their families are anti-vax All right.
Speaker 1: Well, they don't have to sue themselves because they'll just be horribly.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they got measles.
Speaker 1: They already got the consequences.
Speaker 0: So the biggest outbreak In New York City, yep in Brooklyn in one particular community we talked about this Yep, and the city has actually we talked about.
Speaker 0: like the city was doing they're escalating it.
Speaker 0: There are like straight-up mandatory vaccination orders in New York City now Which I think is absolutely justified and they should be us pursuing this much more aggressively than they have been up to this point.
Speaker 1: I think it's.
Speaker 1: I would have no moral problem with just physically detaining people and injecting them.
Speaker 0: I'd be okay with having making sure a doctor's sort of like.
Speaker 0: if maybe the kids allergic to the vaccine Obviously a doctor would be doing the injecting.
Speaker 0: I'm just saying not like cops.
Speaker 1: if you they probably inject it in your eye.
Speaker 0: Child died injected with the measles vaccine 70 times in the back, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I've said they found a measles on.
Speaker 1: the cops can just do.
Speaker 1: No, the cops aren't gonna do the holding part.
Speaker 1: Firemen do.
Speaker 1: the whole time we found measles in his pocket.
Speaker 0: It was self-defense.
Speaker 1: the firemen will do the holding and the doctor will do the inject.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if there's any advice I can give you in terms of I guess EMTs can do it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's not that hard in order the people you should trust with your life.
Speaker 0: Why in terms of like first responders.
Speaker 0: number one firemen.
Speaker 0: number two EMTs?
Speaker 0: About the same numbers three through 99 various other bystanders.
Speaker 0: number 100 the police dog.
Speaker 1: Someone's assaulting me.
Speaker 1: It's like a dog catcher dog.
Speaker 1: No, no cops go away.
Speaker 0: But seriously if you're not sure if you were vaccinated against measles because sometimes medical records get lost like it's actually Terrifying how hard it is to get all my detailed medical records from my entire life because computers weren't really a thing.
Speaker 1: Yes, I saw some people posting I don't know how true it is that like if you got me the measles a vaccine a long time ago Which I did cuz I'm old.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the thing we got is not like a hundred percent that we should get another one.
Speaker 0: I'm looking into that.
Speaker 0: Actually, I'm gonna talk to my doctor when I guess I guess I'll just make a doctor appointment.
Speaker 0: Anyway, yep, but it's like really I'm going to ask my doctor if I should get a like measles booster.
Speaker 1: I don't know if I can find the fucking records of when I had the fucking 1980 something.
Speaker 1: it's probably I'm like a piece of paper somewhere.
Speaker 1: You know, my mom has that shit.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: It's probably buried in some drawer.
Speaker 1: That's just like a pile of paper that I'm surprised has this spontaneously combusted.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if it's anywhere.
Speaker 1: So yeah, I think my pediatrician is like saws my records from 1980. something probably went to like one of those, you know stone mountain archiving One thing you should probably do though is if you know anyone who you know is anti vaccine Do you friend them?
Speaker 1: never speak to them other than to tell them get a vaccine or stay the fuck away from me?
Speaker 1: You should
Speaker 0: end any contact with them and tell them why and then block them
Speaker 1: or Put on protective equipment hold them and physically drag them to someplace to be vaccinated Like find a doctor friend or a nurse friend, you know to like smuggle the vaccine out of work Right, and then there's like invite them over a pizza party hold them down.
Speaker 1: Good to go.
Speaker 0: it is still crazy that it there's a lot like.
Speaker 0: it really does appear that it's Russian bots and things like that that are really spreading the anti-vax mess or just give it to them in their sleep.
Speaker 1: They won't even know through.
Speaker 1: they'll continue being anti-vax though.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I like the idea of And then they'll be like I'm it.
Speaker 1: I never had the vaccine and I think actually we get.
Speaker 1: maybe that's what you should do.
Speaker 1: Anyone who's like anyone who says who's like, you know, who's like I never had the vaccine and I didn't say just be like actually Yeah, even whether it's true or not.
Speaker 1: Tell them.
Speaker 1: Yeah, actually we held you down and gave it to you.
Speaker 0: I like the idea of telling them that actually the vaccine is safe.
Speaker 0: The problem is the mercury in the vaccine.
Speaker 0: So if you take a raw piece of potato Within four hours of getting the kid getting vaccinated and hold it on the wound for an hour It'll suck the mercury out.
Speaker 1: but the vaccination pretty sure it doesn't have mercury anymore.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we're talking to idiots.
Speaker 0: So we make some stuff up.
Speaker 0: Okay, it does not have mercury lie to cure a lie.
Speaker 1: Yep, such homeopathic remedies.
Speaker 0: I mean, how do you fight a forest fire but with another fire?
Speaker 1: Homeopathic water, I'll use one drop to put it a giant forest fire.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'll use a match to put a giant forest here about the guy who died of a homeopathic overdose.
Speaker 0: He forgot to take his medicine.
Speaker 0: But anyway, it's time for things of the day.
Speaker 0: you may have seen people post this in our forum.
Speaker 0: I saw it all over Twitter.
Speaker 1: There's this picture of this like Porco Rosso tailspin looking Fake-ass aircraft like this big bulbous like something that someone made to like hang up in a museum Or a fancy art exhibit somewhere.
Speaker 0: It looks like something an air pirate would fly in tailspin.
Speaker 1: Yeah, very cartoonish vehicle of the sky.
Speaker 0: So I saw a lot of people talking online like wait, there's no way that's real.
Speaker 0: What's the deal?
Speaker 1: cannot fly this unless you have a scarf.
Speaker 1: that with a long trail?
Speaker 1: Those goggles and the leather hat.
Speaker 1: otherwise, it won't even start.
Speaker 1: you'll just get in it.
Speaker 1: Nothing will happen.
Speaker 1: Like where's your scarf?
Speaker 1: I ain't starting for you.
Speaker 0: This is the kind of plane where instead of having a gun on it You just pull out your pistol and start shooting out the side.
Speaker 1: Also, you got a. the key is a mustache.
Speaker 1: You have a bill mustache.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: You got to shove it in the ignition in turn.
Speaker 0: So what I wanted to link to my thing of the day is yes, it's real and here is video.
Speaker 0: Well, here is a film converted to video from Showing that.
Speaker 0: yes, it's real.
Speaker 0: Yes, it flies.
Speaker 0: and if you're curious as to what the deal is with this plane It was not intended to be a plane to be used.
Speaker 0: It was basically a prototype to test some ideas about making airplanes, right?
Speaker 1: I mean I've seen.
Speaker 1: I thought that the shape would fly because I had I remember making paper airplanes in roughly circular shape.
Speaker 1: Tie the wings together at the bottom and they totally flew.
Speaker 1: they flew great on some occasions right based on how well you made it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but the original image I saw showed something really fat and not and I was like that doesn't look right.
Speaker 1: But now that I've seen the video here and some other images, I believe obviously it's it's a flying shape.
Speaker 1: Yeah Yep, it's gonna work.
Speaker 0: It looks kind of fun to fly.
Speaker 1: It's kind of dangerous to fly.
Speaker 0: Yeah It's not.
Speaker 0: it can't be any more dangerous than like a BG.
Speaker 1: I mean, you know.
Speaker 0: So anyway, what do you got?
Speaker 1: So here's a technical thing of the day.
Speaker 1: In fact, it is technical metal.
Speaker 1: So Some don't play it.
Speaker 1: So somebody took machine learning slash neural network, whatever stuff and They trained it to produce audio.
Speaker 1: Right, so it's basically a computer program and it constantly produces audio at all times and it sends This audio Via RTMP I presume to YouTube where it is streaming this audio 24/7.
Speaker 0: right Just turn it on and don't really pay attention to it.
Speaker 0: You'll think oh, it's just a music channel, right?
Speaker 1: So what they did is they trained it to make audio by feeding it.
Speaker 1: the discography I presume of the technical death metal band was an arc spire.
Speaker 0: Yeah arch spire arch spire Which I'm not actually familiar with.
Speaker 1: I'm not familiar with their of word But or whatever.
Speaker 1: however gonna pronounce that over a yeah But yeah, it sound it basically is producing.
Speaker 1: if you listen to this It sounds like kind of messy technical death metal that doesn't stop and never repeats itself and is constantly new and fresh.
Speaker 1: Yep, and if this advances a few more, you know generations of technology worth.
Speaker 1: That will be really something because it asks a lot of fucking questions like who owns the goddamn rights to this shit?
Speaker 1: Yep, can I make if I forget your monkey taking a photo?
Speaker 1: Property question.
Speaker 1: that's old hat compared to this bad boy.
Speaker 0: I can fit ten monkeys taking a photo in this and like I put it on last night Just listen to it for a while.
Speaker 0: I was playing overwatch.
Speaker 0: It just sound like unless I pay attention to it It just sounds like death metal.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but if I pay attention to it like you hear the voice like it's death grunting But it doesn't make words.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and how much is our spire supposed to get from this?
Speaker 0: Yeah, there's a lot going on here But also hey, it's running 24/7 non-stop metal to I feel like you could make you could have a club that just plays this and make a thing about it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so this is this is metal.
Speaker 1: This is intellectual property.
Speaker 1: And this is computer.
Speaker 1: This is a great geek nice thing.
Speaker 1: in a day It's good biz.
Speaker 0: So in the meta moment the geek nice book club book is the most painful book we have ever chosen.
Speaker 0: is Troy Dennings Branded Planescape novel pages of pain.
Speaker 1: There are no like sequels or prequels, right?
Speaker 0: Okay, it starts.
Speaker 1: I am one-third of the way through this book.
Speaker 1: I'm nearly there.
Speaker 1: I'm a major Turning point in the book.
Speaker 0: Is this where they start walling them into the labyrinth?
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's.
Speaker 1: I'm out there running around the labyrinth right now.
Speaker 0: Yep, that's it.
Speaker 0: That's the scene.
Speaker 1: I don't know how they got in the labyrinth.
Speaker 1: to begin with That wasn't really clear but kind of got built around him.
Speaker 1: It's I like how this book is like.
Speaker 1: I'm like how fast are these dudes building?
Speaker 1: It doesn't make any sense.
Speaker 1: But well, they're in now I right.
Speaker 0: one thing I'm realizing reading this with adult eyes very specifically is that If you don't already know some shit about the planescape universe good fucking luck.
Speaker 1: I know what I've been told by these other nerds and I've learned that everything these nerds have told me they learn by reading this fucking book.
Speaker 1: Yeah, everything everyone's ever said to me about planescape is just like in the first five pages of this book.
Speaker 1: I'm like, oh, I'm like you nerds didn't play any fucking planes.
Speaker 1: Shit, you just all read this one book and are telling me what you read.
Speaker 0: There ain't?
Speaker 0: no they read two books.
Speaker 0: they read this book and there's one planescape source.
Speaker 1: I thought you said there were no sequels or prequels.
Speaker 1: Well, no the other book is the one that comes in the box.
Speaker 0: is the bar in the box There's a book that's like this is the fucking deal with planescape.
Speaker 0: It's right over there.
Speaker 1: You want to say all the same shit.
Speaker 1: That's in this died.
Speaker 0: it's The thing about planescape.
Speaker 0: is that the moral of planescape is that that city fucking sucks.
Speaker 0: Do not go anywhere near it.
Speaker 0: It just sucks there.
Speaker 0: Okay smells like pee forever.
Speaker 0: So otherwise our real arm of games panel is on YouTube.
Speaker 1: That's good.
Speaker 0: Our rare game mechanics panel is on YouTube.
Speaker 0: Judge anime is on YouTube.
Speaker 1: That's good.
Speaker 0: And we're gonna make it a bunch of board stuff as fast as we can.
Speaker 0: So stay tuned.
Speaker 0: We have no geek nights obligations Until PAX West.
Speaker 0: so as long as it is not too nice outside, we're gonna be making a bunch of content.
Speaker 1: starting next week.
Speaker 1: It's gonna be nice outside.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so we got to make a bunch of content.
Speaker 1: like this week I did playing a bunch of auto chess.
Speaker 1: this weekend a big patch just came out that made a lot of good stuff happen And I may be able to play auto chess because the overwatch season just ended.
Speaker 1: Well, the auto chess season is about to end.
Speaker 1: you got today to set your rank.
Speaker 1: tomorrow Is a no rank day where it just doesn't matter and then May 1st, the new season will start and everyone will be like I guess zero rank.
Speaker 1: I don't know how it works.
Speaker 0: I can start from scratch.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but anyway, I'm gonna play a lot of objects.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I Started thinking real hard.
Speaker 1: I like that gap day because the other like to let you learn the meta or whatever.
Speaker 1: The other games don't do that.
Speaker 1: Like Hearthstone is like, okay reset go go go.
Speaker 1: It's like so everyone's a good idea.
Speaker 1: gives everyone a chance to like Settle and figure out how they want to play without affecting their rank.
Speaker 0: And so you know overwatch does that you can.
Speaker 0: you can always play quick play Which is the same as competitive just like doesn't count for anything.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you can do that in Hearthstone too, but it's like you're not gonna be playing against people who are right.
Speaker 1: This makes everyone forced to play right in the know.
Speaker 1: the experiment, you know, no ranked mode.
Speaker 0: you can play competitive Went between seasons and overwatch.
Speaker 0: It's called the offseason.
Speaker 0: It's competitive rules competitive matchmaking.
Speaker 0: with your previous rank.
Speaker 0: It just doesn't count.
Speaker 0: Oh, it's it's actually pretty cool.
Speaker 1: That's basically what this is.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but actually I really like the fact that the offseason exists.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but there's no offseason in Hearthstone and other games don't have season.
Speaker 1: But basically there's gonna be a one-day auto chess offseason.
Speaker 0: So now that it's sort of an aside I'll talk about this more next Tuesday.
Speaker 0: But because we can now script in maps in overwatch and make like really custom game modes I started musing on how to make a geek knight's overwatch An overwatch auto chess kind of thing and I actually came up with a pretty good idea.
Speaker 0: So I got to read the scripting like the SDK.
Speaker 1: Just make geek knight's overwatch instead.
Speaker 0: What it's just me and you?
Speaker 0: Like what would geek knight's overwatch?
Speaker 0: All our friends as characters?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 0: It's just skeletons.
Speaker 0: It's just a map full of skeletons.
Speaker 1: Yeah, now we're talking.
Speaker 1: We're getting there.
Speaker 0: I feel like I could make an auto chess-y thing and I figured out like what it would look like.
Speaker 0: I just have to read the documentation to see if what I want to do is possible and Feasible with the scripting and if it isn't just completely like trivial to do.
Speaker 0: if I just write the scripts I ain't doing it.
Speaker 1: Oh, you could do it as like a mod for you know source engine I could or Arma or you know, all those other engines that allow mods.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I really only want to do it for overwatch.
Speaker 0: Otherwise, I don't care that much.
Speaker 0: Okay, otherwise, I'll go back to Grease the wheels which needs second round.
Speaker 1: Quake 2 mod.
Speaker 1: Quake 2 auto chess mod.
Speaker 0: Dude, if I'm gonna make Quake 2 I'll just make a Doom 2 mod cuz that's the only game engine I actually know inside and out.
Speaker 1: All right, Doom 2 auto chess.
Speaker 1: Let's go.
Speaker 1: Oh, I get three imps.
Speaker 1: They become the super imp and you watch.
Speaker 0: you just watch him fight.
Speaker 0: You're like floating above and you just watch him fight.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, we could make that the doom engines.
Speaker 0: not hard to learn.
Speaker 1: I got three cyber DVs.
Speaker 0: level two cyber DVs Oh shit.
Speaker 1: It's just got two rocket hands.
Speaker 0: The scripting is shockingly versatile in Doom 2 As long as there's a limited number of action frames you can take advantage of though.
Speaker 1: Anyway, anyway, let's talk about non-games.
Speaker 0: yes, so it is Monday and And We were talking about fishing.
Speaker 1: somehow We never did a show about fishing and can't believe this and my news reminded me about fishing.
Speaker 1: So now we're gonna show my fishing.
Speaker 0: So they're fishing is it with a pH?
Speaker 0: is an industry term like a technology term?
Speaker 0: It's changed a lot over the years because the internet has changed a lot.
Speaker 0: But the basic idea is that you are trying to trick someone into Thinking that they are interacting with a thing, but really it was.
Speaker 0: do We're interacting with you.
Speaker 1: this doesn't only apply and most of the time it applies to a fake website or a fake email that looks like it came from a Bank or some official place.
Speaker 1: Google, right?
Speaker 1: Facebook or you know an app that looks like the real app, but it's not.
Speaker 1: it's another app that just you know Looks like the real app, but it actually applies to a lot of situations where anything is a fake front.
Speaker 1: For example, I give you a phone call and I say this is your so-and-so Bank.
Speaker 1: It's like yeah, that's tell a scamming tell them, you know, whatever Robo calling.
Speaker 1: but it's also fishing because I am pretending to be Some official thing.
Speaker 1: when I'm not right I can set up a fucking store.
Speaker 1: I can set up a bank branch, right?
Speaker 1: It looks like a real bank branch.
Speaker 1: I trick you to come in and You come and you swipe your card in my not official ATM.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right It's all sorts of things like that Usually only reserved for trying to get someone to Authenticate with or otherwise click on a link, right?
Speaker 1: Because that's the.
Speaker 1: that's why it's called fishing because you're fishing for their information, right?
Speaker 1: He's sort of a fake storefront and you're trying to collect somebody's username password pin number codes Numbers.
Speaker 1: you're trying to collect their most secret personal information.
Speaker 1: That's what you're fishing for and when you catch a sucker and get their info you get the credit card number you get whatever It is you need and now you take all their money.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna do whatever.
Speaker 0: go all the way back to in the early like the early days of just steal their identity a Unix machine Or a Linux machine.
Speaker 0: What do you make?
Speaker 0: a screen that looks like the logon screen?
Speaker 1: You make a screen that you make a terminal a shell.
Speaker 1: Yeah is the bash shell?
Speaker 1: you dig the bash shell source code.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right you modify it to send anything that they type to you.
Speaker 1: Yep, they type in their password.
Speaker 1: eventually They type SSH.
Speaker 1: eventually you got him.
Speaker 0: So fishing really came to be in a modern sense when email became Widespread like.
Speaker 1: that is the beginning of modern fishing right because people were not able Set unsavvy people still to this day.
Speaker 1: Yeah cannot tell an email, you know, if it looks like an email from their bank They don't.
Speaker 1: in order to tell that it's not.
Speaker 1: you have to look very carefully.
Speaker 1: It's a look at like the email headers, which are unreadable to most human beings.
Speaker 1: Yeah You have to look at the from address and the user interfaces on.
Speaker 1: most email clients do not highlight that information Widely, the biggest thing is like the subject right of the email and then the contents of the email far outweigh the from area.
Speaker 1: Well, so unless you look closely you can easily be fooled and before spam filters are any good You actually saw those emails in your inbox like a lot.
Speaker 0: It was kind of a thing.
Speaker 0: Like I remember the first time I got one Like.
Speaker 0: I remember being like.
Speaker 0: wow, someone's trying to trick me.
Speaker 0: That's funny.
Speaker 0: I wonder if anyone else has thought of doing this before Like.
Speaker 1: and then it's super widespread.
Speaker 1: People are trying to do this constantly and it works because they send so many of them That even if they're all blocked like it all blocked across all Gmail block.
Speaker 1: Sorry, it's like someone who's like at cable company.com using that email somewhere gets hit by it Or you just sneaks through a spam filter one some sucker Right you hit one or two and it's like it cost you basically nothing to cast all those fishing lines out in the sea.
Speaker 1: If you catch any fish, it's like alright, that's thousands of dollars.
Speaker 1: I just got from their credit card.
Speaker 0: No There's two main kinds of fishing and it is worth bringing up.
Speaker 0: Regular old fishing is like what Scott should describe but most security officials will refer to another kind called spearfishing Which is you are targeting an individual, right?
Speaker 1: I know this person.
Speaker 1: I know their bank.
Speaker 1: I know that they recently done a thing.
Speaker 1: There's something I know about them that I probably got from publicly available or easily available information.
Speaker 1: Yeah, or maybe I'm their friend and I'm evil.
Speaker 1: I'm not their friend.
Speaker 1: I'm there.
Speaker 1: Here's the here's the modern.
Speaker 0: I know them cuz I don't get too much into the history of like how this used to be Because none of that stuff it matters anymore No, but typically someone will go and buy like there'll be some storefront not Amazon But like a second or third tier storefront.
Speaker 0: that's legitimate.
Speaker 0: but as for security and they get hacked someone will buy that information on the dark web and then they'll look through that information find profiles of individual people Who they know bought something from this third tier storefront and will try to use that information To target that individual to have a higher rate of success in stealing their credit card or whatever.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean, you know if I buy something from Geek night store calm and then I get an email like his geek night store calm We we had a security problem.
Speaker 1: Everyone's got to reset your password.
Speaker 0: come and tell your password in yep And in fact, that's one of the most common techniques.
Speaker 0: It's all.
Speaker 0: this really is just like crafted social engineering.
Speaker 0: you tell someone yo your security is compromised do this to fix it Not them not realizing that the initial statement you gave them was in fact do it's a Specific subset of the social engineering.
Speaker 1: Yeah, where you do a fake you socially engineer via providing a fake front And then get someone to input their information that is real into your fake front and then saving it.
Speaker 0: Yep, so there's a lot of babies first ways that this happens that unless you're really on the savvy.
Speaker 0: You shouldn't be able to fall for like.
Speaker 0: the link is clearly just like not your bank's website, right?
Speaker 1: a lot of times it'll be like WWW dot Chase dot something that's not chase.
Speaker 1: And it's like yeah, and I see the green lock there, but it's not chase calm It's something else.
Speaker 1: dot not chase calm.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you got to look at the whatever's closest to the calm is what counts right.
Speaker 1: there might be like, you know WWW chase that doesn't matter.
Speaker 1: I could make a W to chase that front row crew calm if I wanted to right.
Speaker 1: It's gonna be the last one before the calm.
Speaker 1: that's the one.
Speaker 0: so in the old days it used to be pretty easy to spot these just because the emails themselves look dodgy as shit, but modern technologies come a long way and people will literally just like apply the exact same style that a Legitimate email has from that bank.
Speaker 0: Like they will look a hundred percent right.
Speaker 0: the URLs even look right when you hover over.
Speaker 1: They'll use a lot of times.
Speaker 1: You'll see URL shorteners.
Speaker 1: You're all.
Speaker 1: shorteners are a big problem because Oftentimes they are used legitimately right.
Speaker 1: or even if they're not shorteners Various redirects will be used legitimately often for advertising purposes, right?
Speaker 1: I can Google you click on an ad you're actually getting the link for that ad.
Speaker 1: It looks like you're going to say let's say we've got a geek night's ad.
Speaker 1: It looks like it's gonna recruit a calm.
Speaker 1: It's an ad for front row crew that's purchased on Google You.
Speaker 1: if you actually look closely at the link it goes to Google ad something something and then it that's gonna redirect you to front Row crew after tracking all your ad biz, right?
Speaker 1: So a court in some emails a lot of emails that people send from legitimate places They send out their email newsletter from their company to their customers.
Speaker 1: They fill that email up with all these redirecting ad links so that they can track people Who are clicking on the newsletters so that they can you know get stats on their newsletter design their newsletters better all that kind of Stuff.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: And so now you're used to having these redirects and URL shortened links in your newsletter.
Speaker 1: So then someone sends out a fake one and you look at all the links and none of them make any sense and it's like Okay, obviously these aren't gonna be at the actual place.
Speaker 1: calm because you know It's it.
Speaker 1: they're all ad blinks, but you click one and I redirects you to shady site.com.
Speaker 1: No, but you couldn't tell when you clicked on it because it was a short shortener or redirector.
Speaker 0: With this escalation of like increasingly advanced phishing techniques and like the news we just talked about with the inception bar There's really only one real defense against this like being smart.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: Well being smart being knowledgeable and Find if you're not that smart or not that knowledgeable.
Speaker 0: There's a simple set of rules You can follow.
Speaker 0: rule number one Never ever click on a link you received in an email even if the email appears legitimate.
Speaker 0: if your bank emails you saying Hey, there's a thing like whatever it might be.
Speaker 0: I yep.
Speaker 1: I do this even myself.
Speaker 0: I I see that email and I don't care if it's a real email or not.
Speaker 0: It made it through my spam filter.
Speaker 0: So it may well be legit.
Speaker 0: I then type my bank comm into a browser Yep, and go to it independently.
Speaker 0: And if I don't see the information in my account that the email purported should be there.
Speaker 0: I know it was fake.
Speaker 1: Yeah, whenever I get an email from some site where I have important like an email like say from steam Yeah, it's like hey, you know, we gotta you gotta you know, check out some steam thing.
Speaker 0: I go log into.
Speaker 1: I go to steam.
Speaker 1: doc.
Speaker 1: I just open my browser and go to steam to see if I can corroborate what the email says and if I can't I Whether I can't I can't I delete the email.
Speaker 0: it's similar to if your bank ever calls you saying Anything.
Speaker 0: you should tell them that you're gonna hang up and you're gonna call them back at the number actually printed on your card Yep, and be like, yeah, I'm gonna call you back.
Speaker 0: That's like that'll that following these two rules Basically makes you immune to fishing.
Speaker 0: It is very hard to get trick if you follow those two very simple rules.
Speaker 1: Yep If you want to technologically stop avoid fishing, right?
Speaker 1: One way to do it is like I was just talking about those redirects and you're all shortness, right.
Speaker 1: ad block Of course is really good at helping you avoid a lot of fishing things because a lot of fishing stuff Right is hosted in shady parts of the web.
Speaker 1: a lot of those redirectors which are used for ad tracking are used for fishing.
Speaker 1: right and ad block for example, like my pie hole like DNS ad block them or Actual ad block will.
Speaker 1: often not it's you know, they're geared mostly towards ads But they will often block a lot of shady fishing things and not legit things.
Speaker 1: So I there have been often times where you know something shady comes up and I noticed that it's shady Even faster than usual because half of it is blocked and the links don't work.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like oh my ad block is blocking all of this thing.
Speaker 1: Oh because it's a bunch of bullshit.
Speaker 1: That's why yep So I got all ads everywhere always.
Speaker 0: it does really sad me how effective fishing is considering how?
Speaker 0: Desperately easy it is to avoid being caught by a head like even my company.
Speaker 1: They said it's it's a game of numbers.
Speaker 1: right if you cast enough lines, you still catch people.
Speaker 1: Yeah, send it up It's the same thing.
Speaker 1: My spam is such a big deal.
Speaker 1: Even still today You try to sell Viagra to enough people.
Speaker 1: someone will buy.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: Someone's clicking on that link There's still someone out there.
Speaker 0: Mostly what I'm amazed by is that there was ever a time where if you clicked on that Viagra email Someone actually sent you Viagra.
Speaker 1: I always assumed at least once there was.
Speaker 0: I assume that if you tried to buy Viagra you would in fact just get your credit card overdrawn.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean all those Nigerian scams.
Speaker 1: there was someone on the other end.
Speaker 1: They just weren't someone with a pile of gold that needed help.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they were just someone who needed help.
Speaker 0: But what's all that was also interesting about this kind of fishing is that They really have to trick you.
Speaker 0: you say you click on a link because you're dumb.
Speaker 0: even then they still have to make the website look legit enough.
Speaker 0: you type your credentials in and The other way to protect yourself is to enable two-factor authentication for everything.
Speaker 0: Yep, because if even if you try to log into one of these fishing sites And you type your real password, it won't be able to do the like two-factor TOTP.
Speaker 1: However, there have been some more developments along this way.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: There's an OAuth vulnerability, isn't there?
Speaker 1: Yeah, but no but what people do is like yeah, they'll just fish the two-factor part also, right?
Speaker 1: You log in then they take that and they Immediately use it to log in.
Speaker 1: while you're waiting for the lot the fake login to happen there at the computer.
Speaker 1: That's evil.
Speaker 1: is immediately using your username and password to try to see if it's real.
Speaker 1: It's like in the background of that some server somewhere is now trying to log into your bank account With the username and password you just gave.
Speaker 0: it waits for the prompt for the TOTP.
Speaker 1: You're sitting there waiting and it notices wait.
Speaker 1: This person's got two-factor.
Speaker 1: It comes back to you and is like Hey, can we have a two-factor?
Speaker 1: And then if you type it in and they'll immediately log into your bank account and then change your password You know, then they got you, right?
Speaker 0: Yep But that is a note like that is more sophisticated than a typical fish.
Speaker 1: that is a very sophisticated one But they do exist.
Speaker 1: I've seen people.
Speaker 1: I haven't seen them necessarily in the wild But I've definitely seen proofs of concept and such-and-such.
Speaker 0: Yeah, most of the proofs of concepts I've seen involve SMS because it's just way easier to mess with SM.
Speaker 0: I've
Speaker 1: seen similar stuff used for captchas where It'll try to log in and because the bot the capture comes up and it'll send the capture to the person who's being fished To get it to solve the capture for them and then it will send the capture solution and now it's logged in even though It's a bot.
Speaker 0: Yep so I Don't know what else there is to really say fishing.
Speaker 1: Well, I think it's.
Speaker 1: it's strange that despite, you know, you think internet savvy people right would know about fishing already.
Speaker 1: But actually this is the thing that comes up not like at every job I've had.
Speaker 1: this comes up often like the IT people are emailing pretty constantly like saying Hey, we noticed a fishing thing.
Speaker 1: Don't click on this thing everybody.
Speaker 1: We've seen an email that looks like this Don't click on it like constantly like once every week couple weeks.
Speaker 0: Well, see I work very much more sophisticated and larger organization that has much more like security is a big deal.
Speaker 0: so we pretty much regularly we get a lot of emails that are fake phishing attempts and From the company like with they have this whole system.
Speaker 1: So your company is sending fake phishing attempts to its own employees.
Speaker 0: Yep, and if you click on one you're in a lot of trouble.
Speaker 1: But I mean the fact that it gets through the spam filter.
Speaker 0: Well, no, it bypasses the spam filter because it's coming from inside the house on purpose, right?
Speaker 1: But that's what I'm saying.
Speaker 1: Is that it becomes sort of now like a standout in my inbox like what the fuck is this weird thing in my inbox?
Speaker 1: Yeah, but at the same time only one that gets through.
Speaker 0: I would argue that savvy people what the fuck is this thing?
Speaker 0: In my inbox is how I regard almost any email again.
Speaker 1: I Don't trust email But the fact that it came through and it would need to have like lots of company right.
Speaker 1: like if I didn't have a spam filter then it would sort of come in and Sort of look like everything else on my inbox and blend in with the crowd.
Speaker 1: if it comes in when I have a spam filter Blocking all the other real fishing then it now is like a black sheep and a pile of white sheep.
Speaker 1: It's like what the fuck is that?
Speaker 1: Yep, but I guess it needs to be a white sheep to sneak fast.
Speaker 0: But the thing is it's not trying to sneak fast because this the filters are already really effective.
Speaker 0: So stuff really doesn't make it through anyway.
Speaker 0: It's more just to like make people who aren't that good at this afraid of emails Which honestly if someone can't figure this out on their own the only alternative is to make them afraid of clicking on links and emails.
Speaker 0: That's good Like they have to actually be afraid of it and then they won't click on them and then they'll accidentally follow the rules We just provided.
Speaker 1: hmm I think spearfishing is the real like upcoming frontier because that is a fake house That looks like your house where you live and you put your key in the door And now I copy the key and go open the door to your real house.
Speaker 1: But it is that I moved to another county and then see all your stuff.
Speaker 0: I think you don't need to do that because one if I get even like one because if I can pick up your house I can smash the door down.
Speaker 0: Well, if I get one photo of your key, I can make your key or don't let anyone see your keys, by the way Yeah, like don't hold your keys up in front of cameras.
Speaker 0: Nope, but to even without that bump key It's like people don't really realize how easy it is to pick a lock.
Speaker 1: I'm you know I'm just trying to say I get to.
Speaker 0: I. I'm just saying I could teach you Scott in about Ten minutes.
Speaker 1: I could learn from YouTube if I cared.
Speaker 1: it's a hobby of nerds that I'm just not that's not mine.
Speaker 0: Yeah, thing is don't learn how to really pick a lock.
Speaker 0: just use a bump key just pop up.
Speaker 0: Oh it just opens.
Speaker 0: Mmm, you don't have to do anything.
Speaker 0: some of them most most locks most locks on tours.
Speaker 0: You could bump key open pretty easy Maybe.
Speaker 0: Yeah, fishing.
Speaker 0: I think it like it's growing to the point that it I think the reason I say spearfishing is actually a danger.
Speaker 0: is that Increasingly the the sources of spearfishing attempts seem to be state-sponsored actors Like targeting journalists targeting researchers targeting government officials.
Speaker 0: That is literally what happened in America 2016 election.
Speaker 1: there is one other thing to discuss right?
Speaker 1: You know how?
Speaker 1: whenever you're in your browser and something's gonna go full-screen like gonna make a full-screen video Yeah, it's like.
Speaker 1: hey, do you want to give this permission to go full-screen?
Speaker 1: It's always asking for permission for things to go full-screen and like in Windows.
Speaker 1: It's like when it with the screen is locked and like it makes you press ctrl alt delete to like get past And make the login screen come up, right?
Speaker 1: It's like why the reason it's doing all these things is to prevent Full-screen fishing because if you have an application that is allowed Full-screen access to draw to all the pixels on the screen.
Speaker 1: I could just redraw all of Windows I could redraw your entire desktop and I could have some app.
Speaker 1: and you think you're just using your computer But actually my app is full screen on top of all your other apps eating all your keyboard commands Right not letting you actually get to your real apps behind me Just pretending to be your real apps behind me and capturing everything you type in.
Speaker 1: you're typing into my evil app.
Speaker 1: That is full screen.
Speaker 1: full screen is real dangerous And that is why your computer always asks for permission to let things go full screen and you should think more More about what you let go full screen.
Speaker 1: if you let websites go full screen That shouldn't be.
Speaker 1: you could be in a world of hurt.
Speaker 1: and the reason Windows makes you press ctrl delete To get the login screen to show up is because if there was some sort of fake login screen, right?
Speaker 0: That was actually remember the thing I said in the very beginning the first fishing arguably, right?
Speaker 1: If there was a fake login screen and you pressed ctrl delete on Windows that makes you know The things happen of when you press ctrl delete, right and that would get you around and make you suddenly realize Hey, wait a minute.
Speaker 1: There's an app running.
Speaker 1: That looks like a login screen that happened to be full screen.
Speaker 1: What's up with that?
Speaker 1: whereas the control cuz ctrl delete always go get sent to windows around any kind of app Even if it's full screen.
Speaker 0: But seriously, I cannot stress this enough All you need to do to never be caught by fishing is to never click on a link that gets sent to you by anyone Even if you think that is a legitimate source, and if you click on one of those links, like let's forget We're not talking about malware deployments or malware payloads.
Speaker 0: We're just talking about fishing.
Speaker 0: So if you click on something and it takes you to a login screen Don't log into that.
Speaker 0: like.
Speaker 1: type in the URL Unlike a malware right which will only hurt you.
Speaker 1: like you could like click on a file and get hurt, right?
Speaker 1: It's like you're not gonna get hurt by fishing unless you type in your real infos.
Speaker 1: like you can go to the fishing site and like Look around as long as you don't type in like your security number.
Speaker 1: It's not gonna hurt you.
Speaker 0: granted The fishing site may itself have like malware payloads.
Speaker 1: Who knows what else is doing.
Speaker 0: don't go to those sites, right?
Speaker 1: I mean unless you got like a secure sandbox virtual machine or a spare computer with nothing on it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know something like that.
Speaker 1: But yeah, just don't type anything in.
Speaker 1: that's the real.
Speaker 0: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at front row crew comm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 0: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and in Discriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 1: But unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 0: It's actually recorded at night and the patreon patrons for this particular episode of geek knives are Craig Oliver, Ellen Joyce, how do you mean nickel?
Speaker 0: just like you do guy chart ovation?
Speaker 0: Link Iji Jennifer Hitchcock Chris mink if my stage a calm.
Speaker 0: Jay Bants coodle only.
Speaker 0: Roberto Kingsley Sean Yeager Nicholas Brando Mr.
Speaker 0: Strong stretch in 4-2-1 creations.
Speaker 0: the dwarfs know me as zonin Hoog Stange's Shervin on Horrell Rory Rachelle, Montana Superboy sailor Vista Clinton Walton run from New Zealand Ryan Penn drew open-lander Finn dread Lily Tenebrae Sean Klein Chris Reimer Thomas Hahn and now I leave you with the musical stylings of You.