Speaker 1: It's Thursday, August 15th, 2019.
Speaker 1: I'm rim.
Speaker 1: I'm Scott and this is geek nights.
Speaker 1: tonight We are talking about fruit.
Speaker 0: Let's do this All right, so my company right.
Speaker 0: when I for uh, when I first got there like over a year ago Yeah, they were in this office.
Speaker 0: It was like, you know above a place where a store would usually go right but if you know pretty big But it was filling rapidly because they keep hiring people like crazy.
Speaker 0: Ah, so they got a space.
Speaker 0: that's not we It's not like a we work but it's basically like similar ish you rent a space from another place.
Speaker 0: That's rent ads actually renting the space and they put someone on the other team in there.
Speaker 0: But then a new manager came in and they did some stuff.
Speaker 0: So now my team has been in there all year, basically And the company was like, yeah, this is a problem and they've been working on getting a new space.
Speaker 0: So at the end of the month, we're gonna move to a new space.
Speaker 0: Basically, they're moving while I'm at pecs and when I come back from pecs, I'll go to this new office.
Speaker 1: Yep I'm not way back my old company.
Speaker 1: we moved to the fashion district And we went to a nice building from the kind of crappy building we used to have downtown.
Speaker 0: So they got like two whole floors at the top of this building.
Speaker 0: It's you know, so there's a few issues, right?
Speaker 0: So good.
Speaker 0: I mean going to the new building.
Speaker 0: good in general, right?
Speaker 0: Slightly bad news.
Speaker 0: when I moved to where I live now to over 10 years ago because I was working in an office and right outside the office was the yellow train and I said Well better get an apartment near yellow train.
Speaker 1: so I can just go straight to our funny similar thing when I moved here Like not too long after you moved here.
Speaker 1: I worked at next to Grand Central right on the purple train.
Speaker 1: Yeah So I Moved to an apartment that was also on the purple train and then I changed jobs that work way downtown.
Speaker 1: take the fucking yellow Train.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: Anyway, but now I work back next in the exact same place with the purple train again.
Speaker 0: So then cut place.
Speaker 0: I work now also yellow train and the temporary place they put us in this year also yellow train.
Speaker 0: But now the new office are going to blue train.
Speaker 1: You're taking the E to work.
Speaker 0: Well, I get.
Speaker 0: maybe I don't know I could.
Speaker 0: we got to figure it out.
Speaker 0: It's not great I could just keep taking the yellow train and then just walk a bunch once I get there.
Speaker 0: So, you know what sucks the E for biking is no issue.
Speaker 0: right by bike to work No problem, but in the winter or if it's raining, right?
Speaker 1: So issue number two I asked about the E would be really good for me to get to work if I like because living here the E is right There anyway from the seven.
Speaker 0: next issue is asked about biking to work and they said yeah Apparently this loading dock at this new office building has bike racks that are first come first serve.
Speaker 0: Oh, so I got to go check it out to see.
Speaker 0: how early do I have to get there?
Speaker 1: Seven and it's already full.
Speaker 1: that's not gonna work.
Speaker 0: No, it's not gonna work.
Speaker 0: So I got to check that out, but it's promising at least right?
Speaker 0: So issue number three when I got there and to the way, you know in the previous office right the one that's too full Yeah, they had real shitty chairs.
Speaker 1: Oh That's a deal breaker, right?
Speaker 0: So What I did is I found I got lucky.
Speaker 0: someone in near my near where I live Was moving to California and sold me a legit Aeron chair.
Speaker 1: Oh, so you're gonna do the thing that I did it a pretty $200.
Speaker 1: You're gonna bring your own chair to hold on.
Speaker 0: They sold me this Aeron chair for $200.
Speaker 0: I don't need it at home.
Speaker 0: I got a freedom chair at home I don't know right.
Speaker 0: So I dragged that fucking chair all the way on the subway all the way to that office and then when they moved us to The temporary office this year.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I dragged my chair.
Speaker 0: There's also shitty chairs, right?
Speaker 0: So they told us, you know, we're doing.
Speaker 0: they're doing like a companies, you know companies move.
Speaker 0: They always do a thing where they put a box on your desk you fill the box You can't put more stuff in the box than fits right and then they bring it to the new office.
Speaker 1: I've done this three times in my current job.
Speaker 1: Just moving between it's always.
Speaker 0: it's always the same.
Speaker 0: I've been doing this to just move between floors of the same building Yeah, and you show up at your new desk on the new day and all your stuff is there.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and that's how it works when you're a company that moves, right?
Speaker 0: But I'm like, hey How do I get my chair to get moved to this new place?
Speaker 0: So I'm like, do I just put a sticker on it.
Speaker 0: cuz I already put a sticker on the bottom.
Speaker 1: This is probably gonna move your chair.
Speaker 1: So
Speaker 0: I I'm like, I really don't want to drag it Right, and so I asked and they said him they said yeah in the new office we got these really great chairs and if you don't have a medical reason bring your chair home, and I'm like I don't care what chair you got unless it's air on chair.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right if it's not air on chair freedom chair, right?
Speaker 0: I'm gonna fight you.
Speaker 1: so now like I cannot stress enough the air on chair is the second best chair there is on earth Right.
Speaker 0: So now I have to fight I guess tomorrow to send an email just get a crooked doctor to give you a medical.
Speaker 0: I don't want to happen but it's like I shouldn't have to do that.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, Scott in the real world There's a lot of things we shouldn't have to do.
Speaker 1: I shouldn't have to choose between two political coalitions.
Speaker 0: before Before I go get a crooked doctor I'm gonna go to the HR person and look I'm gonna say look don't make me go to a crooked doctor cuz I Will.
Speaker 0: that's right and just let everyone bring their gut.
Speaker 0: there's people in my office, you know, we're all programmers, right?
Speaker 0: Someone's got the bouncy ball.
Speaker 0: Yeah, someone's got the weird like knee chair that rocks with.
Speaker 1: no are we're the same way Don't you?
Speaker 1: my engineers have the balls that they sit on.
Speaker 0: everyone's got weird-ass chairs.
Speaker 0: You're really gonna make everyone drink their fucking chairs.
Speaker 0: Almost everyone has giant standing - it's like it's like those chairs that you got.
Speaker 0: They might be good chairs.
Speaker 0: I'm willing, you know, they haven't sat in them In them or seen them.
Speaker 0: they could be good I don't fucking know but they're not.
Speaker 0: Aaron, you know They're not my $200 air hunt chair.
Speaker 0: That's worth 800.
Speaker 0: Yeah, maybe six at the lead, right?
Speaker 0: So I'm not sure which model it is.
Speaker 0: It was in amazing condition, but I don't think it's the newest model.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, cuz there's been a lot of versions, but I mean it's legit.
Speaker 0: Herman Miller air on chair.
Speaker 0: That's a knockoff one.
Speaker 0: Right?
Speaker 0: So and it has all the possible adjustments.
Speaker 0: It's not that one because that one has a different back thingy There's.
Speaker 1: so there are a ton of - mine just has the horizontal rubbery back thingy.
Speaker 0: other than that It's exactly the same as that only black.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it doesn't have the modern style back thingy where it's like vertical.
Speaker 1: ish It's more trying to figure out how much they're on.
Speaker 0: chair actually costs a brand new one.
Speaker 0: It costs a lot depending on what model you bought this brand new one.
Speaker 1: I still have the receipt.
Speaker 1: brand new ones are gonna be at least Whoa, the air on chair no longer has a lifetime warranty.
Speaker 0: That's interest 12 years.
Speaker 0: All right, how much is a new one cost for the minimum model minimum?
Speaker 0: 1275.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: That's not what you if you actually went to an office store.
Speaker 0: It wouldn't cost 1275.
Speaker 1: That's I paid 1100 I think for this one.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think if you buy them new at like a store, they're gonna be eight or nine hundred.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Oh if you get the basic back, it's cheaper.
Speaker 1: It's 11.
Speaker 1: It saves you like 70 bucks.
Speaker 0: That's not a big savings now.
Speaker 1: Yeah, anyway, you can get a leather armpad.
Speaker 1: Why?
Speaker 0: Because you're just.
Speaker 0: you know, why?
Speaker 0: why do people get leather and all kinds of stuff?
Speaker 1: Yeah, maybe leather shoes leather jacket not a vegan errand chair anymore.
Speaker 0: No Anyway, yeah, I'm curious about this 12-year warranty and I think the thing that I really don't understand about it right is it's like.
Speaker 0: Okay, maybe you know, it's like.
Speaker 0: it's like.
Speaker 0: just tell me your reason right?
Speaker 0: It's like there's a reason.
Speaker 0: What is the reason that you don't want me to bring my own and everyone else to bring their own guy?
Speaker 0: Why do you insist on me using this chair you bought?
Speaker 1: I have learned in my life that there are exactly two possible reasons Why anything like that happens in the world?
Speaker 1: Reason number one is the people in charge do not want to deal with anything That isn't uniform because they just don't want to have any hassle in any capacity.
Speaker 0: No hassle for you.
Speaker 0: Just bring up.
Speaker 1: No, there's.
Speaker 1: everyone has the same chair.
Speaker 1: We control the chairs.
Speaker 1: There's no exceptions to that.
Speaker 1: So we don't have to ever think about it Making me your consequences unhappy employee.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know because it's not like it's such a minor issue Why would I be so upset?
Speaker 0: It's not the chair that I'm actually upset about It's I'm upset that the company makes a big deal about such a minor issue.
Speaker 0: They can't just say yes Right the fact that they're gonna be such sticklers about something so minor is what makes me upset.
Speaker 0: not actually sitting in that other chair Which would probably actually be a fine.
Speaker 0: Just got.
Speaker 1: if you worked in more like in more companies over your career You'll find that most places are way worse than that.
Speaker 0: That's why I don't work in most places?
Speaker 1: because reason number two is Someone made an arbitrary decision and no one who has decision-making power is willing to make a different arbitrary decision.
Speaker 1: they want to defer to someone else and Everyone will collectively defer to the last person in power who made an arbitrary decision.
Speaker 1: Well the last reason I make so much money is that I am very willing to make Incredibly capricious and arbitrary decisions very quickly.
Speaker 1: well I may not be right.
Speaker 0: when I got to this company They had that policy of like sick day.
Speaker 0: if you if you're sick if you take a sick day you lose a vacation day Yeah, and then I complained and then they changed it.
Speaker 0: so to their credit that has been different than every other place I've ever worked well, and they've also been very open right all their meeting.
Speaker 0: You know it's like they share everything with all the employees.
Speaker 0: They don't keep a lot of secrets.
Speaker 1: so do you care enough to be like let me bring my chair or I quit.
Speaker 0: I care enough to send an email.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'm gonna send an email tomorrow
Speaker 1: because long ago in a different different company I was literally like I'm going to PAX and they're like oh But you don't have enough if
Speaker 0: they said you can't go to PAX out and I literally
Speaker 1: was like well
Speaker 0: I wouldn't I wouldn't quit.
Speaker 0: I would say I'm going.
Speaker 0: that's basically.
Speaker 0: I said if you fire me all right Whatever you're gonna.
Speaker 0: Do you're gonna do, but I'm going.
Speaker 0: And I would say I'm going and if you punish me in a way that is less than firing like dock my pay Then I will quit.
Speaker 1: yep Or the alternative is I will just show up until you fire me.
Speaker 1: So in some news.
Speaker 1: There's a bet a whole bunch of stories.
Speaker 1: I've been seeing about this.
Speaker 1: They're all kind of the same story.
Speaker 1: there have been multiple incidents of this at different places.
Speaker 1: I
Speaker 0: saw a one tweet about it And the tweet was pretty much a cover of a saga issue with the relevant princey like character yeah, and then a link to this video of Someone seemingly cosplaying as you know the prince from saga with a big TV on their head yeah, putting a TV on a porch and running away
Speaker 1: just showing up at people's houses in the middle of the night and just
Speaker 0: Leaving
Speaker 1: and old teeth.
Speaker 1: now the news articles are often saying vintage TVs.
Speaker 1: These are not vintage TVs They're just.
Speaker 0: these are shitty TVs.
Speaker 1: There's a very clear distinction if someone dropped off like a 50s era TV.
Speaker 1: that would be awesome.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I would take that.
Speaker 1: but these are basically what these are my suspicion.
Speaker 1: I have a read into what's going on here.
Speaker 1: this person or these people have all realized that They have a bunch of old TVs, which are basically toxic waste.
Speaker 1: yep old CRT's are filled with dangerous toxic shit.
Speaker 1: It's difficult to throw them away.
Speaker 1: It's often expensive to throw them away.
Speaker 1: They can't be recycled like Depends on where you live right.
Speaker 0: so for example in New York you could bring them to the safe disposal.
Speaker 0: Yeah, once a year right.
Speaker 0: and where my mom lives in Connecticut You can drive to the transfer station and put them there in a special place.
Speaker 0: But they're generally difficult to get rid of if you have a lot of them Especially if you're like commercial.
Speaker 0: like if you're a commercial business you can't go to either of those disposal places right.
Speaker 0: also If the TVs are not good quality CRT's no one wants them.
Speaker 0: if they are good quality Maybe some Smash Brothers players who need game cubes would want them.
Speaker 0: But they only want them if they work really well and are good.
Speaker 0: so it's like odds.
Speaker 0: are most CRT's you have are broken or bad.
Speaker 0: the very very few are good and Working.
Speaker 1: I remember trying to get rid of that 1974 color RCA.
Speaker 0: yeah a lot of arcade machines actually old arcade machines.
Speaker 0: It's like the boards all still work great or can be fixed, but it's like well the CRT's busted.
Speaker 0: I guess I had to.
Speaker 0: you know I can't play Dig Dug now yep.
Speaker 1: So I suspect that whoever is doing this very cleverly realized that if they make it look like a prank They can basically just leave their toxic waste at people's houses.
Speaker 0: This is just totally get away with right?
Speaker 0: It's like.
Speaker 0: I'm not sure.
Speaker 0: you know we don't know what the real thing is going on here.
Speaker 0: But my first my immediate reaction was oh illegal dumping.
Speaker 0: yeah It's illegal Should I?
Speaker 1: I should dress up as a book and just start leaving all my old books on people's porches.
Speaker 0: and like outer queens Yeah, like yeah, I mean there's a place in Brooklyn ish known as the hole which is.
Speaker 1: we just ran a u-haul drive upstate Place to go, but it's.
Speaker 0: it's basically this triangle of land where people kind of live that floods a lot Connected to any utilities really well and is really bad place.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you could go dump your shit there.
Speaker 1: So I'm pretty sure that is the full extent of what is going on here.
Speaker 0: But in the meantime it is also in addition to illegal dumping helping them the illegal dumpers It has also provided the world with some great videos.
Speaker 1: Yep Like it is and it's kind of like there was a trend a while ago where people would like dress up as clowns or dress up as scary things or like leave weird dolls on people's porches.
Speaker 1: these kinds of pranks are happening more and more because It's really easy to pull them off and now everyone has a camera on their door.
Speaker 1: So it's really easy to like get people to spread your viral message.
Speaker 1: Whatever it might be.
Speaker 1: So in some other news As you all know Twitter is mostly filled with like Russian bots and Nazis and stuff.
Speaker 1: there are some people talking but it's mostly bots and As you know China is trying to destroy Hong Kong and these kids are fighting for their lives to maintain some level of democracy there.
Speaker 1: so China unlike Russia Does not know how to play the bot game.
Speaker 1: So basically over like the last few days The Chinese government it looks like they have just made thousands and thousands and thousands of bot accounts on Twitter and they're all tweeting the same Propaganda and it's so ham-fisted and so pathetically done Like.
Speaker 1: it's like they're not even trying like they're doing the kind of bot attack that you would try to do in the 90s of social Media existed.
Speaker 1: so there's this legion now of these accounts with like random art.
Speaker 0: I mean it could just be really poorly skilled Chinese sympathizers and not China itself.
Speaker 1: Yeah I do doubt it right.
Speaker 0: like if you see in Australia There are like some students who are pro-china who are getting rowdy and I'm pretty confident.
Speaker 0: Like I'm not have obvious information.
Speaker 1: Oh, they're more like a standalone complex type situation.
Speaker 0: I think that they're lit.
Speaker 0: I think that they are just honestly.
Speaker 0: they're from China They're Chinese.
Speaker 0: They're in Australia and I think they're they're honestly just pro China.
Speaker 0: Well, I like if some Trump people from America just went to France and got rowdy it's like they're just legitimately.
Speaker 1: However, I I would make the counter-argument that much like stochastic terrorism that is simply stochastic stochastic Memetics.
Speaker 1: Yes, that is.
Speaker 0: second But the point is there is still a difference between that and an actual government explicit directive like the CIA Operation to overthrow a government or something true, but then there's the weird gray line Like what about when the government just encourages people to do that?
Speaker 1: And then there's unrelated to the government entities that funded and there's a shadowy circle of money Like.
Speaker 1: what's the exact line?
Speaker 0: It depends on a lot of things.
Speaker 1: so details if you see Twitter accounts talking about how bad these protesters are in Hong Kong Click on one or two of them.
Speaker 1: They probably.
Speaker 1: you'll probably literally find thousands of accounts that are identical with no followers.
Speaker 1: They were all created in August.
Speaker 1: They have no followers They're following no one and they've all tweeted one thing which is a tweet with the same text.
Speaker 1: and these like really obvious terrible propaganda images that are anti Hong Kong freedom.
Speaker 1: What's really bothering me is that Twitter lets this shit happen.
Speaker 1: Like this is so easy to stop, right?
Speaker 0: It's like really you're this like one of the most major websites in you know applications in the world.
Speaker 0: You have an army of talented programmers Some of them right and in the developers and designers and all kinds of people working there are huge and get all this money Even though you're not making money.
Speaker 0: you got money And you can't just stop people from just making a bunch of fake accounts like the simplest thing that you can do with the WordPress Blog.
Speaker 0: stop you from making fake accounts.
Speaker 0: I mean you can't stop that.
Speaker 1: click on any tweet by like any Democratic politician in the US and the replies are just thousands and thousands and thousands of obvious bots maybe hundreds, but the point is On the to make a Twitter account.
Speaker 0: It shouldn't be so easy to just make an account and start tweeting that without being a real person.
Speaker 0: How hard is this?
Speaker 1: Well, I've said this on Twitter on Twitter a bunch of times But it's harder to make an account on our forum than it is on Twitter.
Speaker 1: So what people seem to forget because it's before the living memory of most people online today.
Speaker 1: Is that email?
Speaker 1: Was kind of like Twitter and all these things anyone could just make an email server.
Speaker 1: in the early days All email servers just trusted all other email servers.
Speaker 0: Now you could well because in the beginning the only email servers were the few people that were on the internet And they were all sophisticated yep like colleges and labs and shit.
Speaker 1: and then spam appeared and spam Literally overnight destroyed email.
Speaker 1: and the only reason the sole reason that we can still use email even exists today is because AI's Automatically block like ninety nine point nine nine percent of all email.
Speaker 0: right a mad go to your email And I dare you to dump your spam folder on Gmail into your inbox, and it's unusable alright.
Speaker 0: So the only reason email even exists today is because we invented and perfect or almost perfect And we didn't need to perfect people right very willing to lose the real emails just to Nazis right.
Speaker 0: We made a good enough that got even better to be.
Speaker 0: it's now really really good.
Speaker 0: not perfect But extremely good.
Speaker 0: spam filters and now email is usable and good again.
Speaker 0: What in the meanwhile Twitter Facebook etc.
Speaker 0: etc.
Speaker 0: there's no spam filter on in the other way.
Speaker 1: Because you know in the early when spam first became a thing there were big debates about what to do.
Speaker 1: people worried like oh Free speech like you can't block email content and we realized blocking email content was literally the only way.
Speaker 1: The alternative was to charge a nominal amount of money to send an email and there was no way to make that happen.
Speaker 1: No, but with something like Twitter Twitter could just say it costs one US dollar per year to have a Twitter account.
Speaker 1: almost every bot account would disappear overnight because a dollar a year times millions of fake accounts is Not feasible for anyone to pay for and to be able to pay now.
Speaker 1: There's an accountability traceability Aspect.
Speaker 0: I think a better idea, right?
Speaker 0: Which I've wanted to do for some time is to just have fines the same way that fines exist in like sports leagues.
Speaker 0: It's like I you did performance dancing drugs for game suspension and million-dollar fine or a hundred thousand dollar fine Whatever.
Speaker 0: and the way you do this is you force everyone to have a credit card attached to their account.
Speaker 1: So poor people can't use Twitter because they don't have credit cards or some kind of thing attached.
Speaker 1: People can't use Twitter they don't have a bank account.
Speaker 1: it's a positive some kind homeless person can't afford any amount of money.
Speaker 0: You got to do something.
Speaker 0: You got to have some amount of money.
Speaker 1: That's why I'm saying the real way to do this point is have a eyes like literally just shadow ban 99.9% of all.
Speaker 0: Twitter should be doing that also.
Speaker 0: Yes fan filtering but just make people have some kind of deposit or some sort of thing linked to their account.
Speaker 0: Check it to make sure it never like closes or goes away or anything.
Speaker 0: So you don't just like use a stolen credit card, right?
Speaker 0: And then if the person ever misbehaves if I can take all their money I do also still like the idea.
Speaker 0: it's like you could do it for counter-strike like, okay You have to have a valid credit credit card.
Speaker 0: you can play a free counter-strike But if you cheat we take you take the fold up and we take your full balance of credit card.
Speaker 0: That's it Cheated.
Speaker 0: you got us $1,000 now cheater So the other even better.
Speaker 0: give that cheating money to all the people you cheated against.
Speaker 0: That'll make people want to play and not cheat.
Speaker 1: Oh, did you see I was gonna save this news for Monday?
Speaker 0: everyone who saw your spam.
Speaker 0: now you owe them all a dollar.
Speaker 1: Did you see all those kids who have fucking owned?
Speaker 1: because all the counter-strike cheats on the internet are like really bad malware Mmm, and a bunch of?
Speaker 0: I mean, I'm pretty sure like there are plenty of ways to get cheats for games.
Speaker 0: But I imagine if you go to Google and type in fortnight cheats, you're not getting any fortnight sheets that work.
Speaker 0: or To get the real fortnight sheets You got to go to the secret webs, you know and get in the IRC channel with the people who make the fortnight And be their friend.
Speaker 1: these kids don't know what it was like to get wares.
Speaker 0: No, they don't.
Speaker 1: but I always think back to that idea we've had that we've never really tried to do anything with of you.
Speaker 1: have you have a thing like Twitter.
Speaker 1: that's invite only and Whoever invited you can cut you off if they want.
Speaker 1: so they're responsible for you And if - and basically if too many people you invited end up being pieces of shit you get kicked off the network.
Speaker 0: Well, I think it's just.
Speaker 0: you're responsible for the people under you, right?
Speaker 0: So if I invite you and you invite Joey Jojo and Joey Jojo invites his uncle and the uncle invites a Nazi Right, Joey.
Speaker 0: Jojo is just right.
Speaker 0: The uncle is responsible for getting rid of the Nazi.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if he doesn't do it Joey Jojo is responsible for getting rid of the uncle.
Speaker 0: Yeah, Joey Jojo doesn't do it.
Speaker 0: You're responsible for getting rid of Joey Jojo and if you don't do it, I'm responsible for getting rid of you.
Speaker 0: Yeah so it's like you're basically under this pressure from the top of whoever invited you because they're vouching for your Goodness on the network and you basically if you misbehave on the network Then you lose your standing and if no one is vouching for you on the network, then you're out.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and it's it's really good.
Speaker 0: The reason the system is good is because it solves this problem of prevent bots from joining and mass.
Speaker 0: Because okay, Joey Jojo invites his uncle the uncle wants a Nazi.
Speaker 0: the Nazi invites a bot network Although that you can just ban the Nazi and the whole bot network falls off.
Speaker 0: You don't need to like, you know figure out individually with some advanced AI or spam filter type stuff.
Speaker 0: Advanced AI though!
Speaker 1: You don't need an advanced AI.
Speaker 1: Just have something that looks for anyone who tweets the hashtag.
Speaker 1: I stand with Vic and they're gone.
Speaker 0: But the point is you can just.
Speaker 0: you can just drop huge numbers of accounts with like a single click really easily And it's very hard for anyone to flood the network with that biz.
Speaker 0: But what's
Speaker 1: funny about this China thing is that the Russian bots like all these Russian bot accounts have all this like Almost normal-looking activity that's scripted and you really got to look at it to find the trend of like, oh
Speaker 0: they try hard Yeah,
Speaker 1: but China's like not even trying like.
Speaker 0: I don't know if China itself is doing it stuff.
Speaker 1: It's either China directly or China stochastically.
Speaker 1: It's one of those two.
Speaker 1: So in some other news YouTube is changing how copyright claims work.
Speaker 0: Well sort of right?
Speaker 1: So they're only to read this article at all.
Speaker 0: So the only way they're changing it is with regards to music, right?
Speaker 0: So the way it works now is let's say you got a little bit of music in in your YouTube video.
Speaker 0: I may be a little I don't know a little.
Speaker 0: Rolling Stone maybe right?
Speaker 0: So currently the Rolling Stones come along.
Speaker 0: They could be like, all right Take that shit out of your video or we're gonna put ads on your video and make money.
Speaker 1: And they can do that even if it's just like two seconds of the audio in the background of a four hour long.
Speaker 0: So the new what they're changing it to is it basically gives them two choices.
Speaker 0: now right choice Number one is They can prevent you from making money on the video which okay, but you can't.
Speaker 0: they can't make any money that I like Right, so it's basically like okay We're you know more money for you person who made the video with my music in it, but no money for me either.
Speaker 0: I didn't make this video.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, the article says this really well.
Speaker 1: now when a copyright claim is manually filed specifically for very short clips, right?
Speaker 0: So it's only manual Takedowns not the automatic takedowns.
Speaker 0: Those are still the same and it's only for short clips.
Speaker 0: There's only two.
Speaker 0: there's gonna be fewer choices.
Speaker 0: choice One is no money for anybody on this video and choice two is take the video down.
Speaker 0: Now the problem is well the thinking behind this change is alright.
Speaker 0: people who want to make money are incentivized to sort of go out and find any video with even a clip of their music in it and Claim it so they can make a lot of money Primarily because it's like a money.
Speaker 1: those claims like if like all I a lot of my antenna videos have claims like that on them That I gave up on.
Speaker 0: there's a monetary incentive like go out and claim every video that you can possibly claim and you will make some money and Clean them out and you'll make enough money.
Speaker 1: Just go and do it.
Speaker 1: There's also a disincentive from people who have Legitimate fair use rights like say me with do ten of videos to fight those claims because those claims don't actually take your video down.
Speaker 1: You just lose ad revenue and someone else is making money.
Speaker 1: But if you fight those claims you could get a copyright strike and you could lose your whole account.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you lose my whole gig nights account by fighting one of those.
Speaker 1: I usually don't.
Speaker 0: somehow YouTube does a good job of keeping people from making a thousand accounts Or at least you never see them right.
Speaker 0: you just see the Nazis who have made real accounts.
Speaker 0: Yeah Yeah, not bought Nazis anyway.
Speaker 0: so The other option is to just take your video down.
Speaker 0: So the thinking is people will stop take bothering with manual takedowns of short clips because they won't make money on it.
Speaker 0: There's no incentive for them to go do this Manually, but the other thinking is like yeah People will probably just take down all these.
Speaker 0: there'll be more takedowns and let instead of letting videos be up with.
Speaker 1: Everyone involved in this doesn't understand about these music companies.
Speaker 1: They would rather fucking just destroy you.
Speaker 0: Well, some of them would write to them in my experience, right?
Speaker 0: Well, I think it.
Speaker 0: you know, they're really aggressive.
Speaker 0: America depends on the Japanese ones.
Speaker 0: They just want to take down everything.
Speaker 1: Yeah, Japan like.
Speaker 1: it's interesting when I get Japanese.
Speaker 1: They're the worst against my videos.
Speaker 1: They never monetize.
Speaker 1: They just globally block instantly, right?
Speaker 1: And actually a lot of my youtube videos.
Speaker 0: Well, we just thought about Nintendo is aggressively going after videos that contain Nintendo music them and trying to take them down, right?
Speaker 0: But you know, it's clearly if you look at the evidence that is a dumb strategy Right.
Speaker 0: Japan is a country with many people in it Right and creates as a lot of money and creates many things both physical and artwork and otherwise, right?
Speaker 1: Yet kids ain't talking about j-pop these days They're talking about kpop.
Speaker 0: Korea South Korea a very tiny country that may actually Mathematically people are concerned.
Speaker 0: It's not a joke may run out of people because they're not making enough babies Right or they could allow more immigration.
Speaker 0: Right a miniscule country on the scale of things with way less stuff than Japan Right has made a huge global impact.
Speaker 0: right with music and our things that are popular worldwide simply because There are many reasons.
Speaker 0: but the number one reason is they just let their shit spread.
Speaker 0: They just dump every to constantly uploading everything to YouTube.
Speaker 0: They're constantly letting all their TV shows be KBS Which is basically like the the the national TV station, right?
Speaker 0: They put most of their shows on YouTube with subtitles for free.
Speaker 0: Oh, it's just like they just do it worldwide.
Speaker 0: everyone.
Speaker 0: Please watch Korean TV with subtitles.
Speaker 0: and they just have been doing this for years and years and years like Ted like almost 10 years Maybe even that long.
Speaker 0: I don't even know.
Speaker 0: since 2012 when I started paying attention.
Speaker 0: They become a global media phenomenon and Japan still to this day is like yeah Nintendo We're not gonna release mother 3 in the u.s Well, it's like yeah, you're making a remake or whatever.
Speaker 0: you take that shit.
Speaker 0: Oh, we're gonna take down every live stream.
Speaker 1: Anyone's ever done of Zelda.
Speaker 0: Yeah, j-pop.
Speaker 0: We don't want anyone outside Japan to listen to that.
Speaker 0: take all that down.
Speaker 0: No one's allowed to listen to j-pop unless they live in Japan.
Speaker 0: j-rock.
Speaker 0: Nope.
Speaker 0: Can't listen to it.
Speaker 0: You can buy our $80 CD.
Speaker 0: yes buy an $80 CD or $50-100 DVD.
Speaker 0: That's the only way you can watch any Japanese stuff.
Speaker 0: subtitles.
Speaker 0: No only unlike this one service.
Speaker 0: No, not allowed anime All right.
Speaker 0: Well, maybe are a crunchy roll.
Speaker 0: Maybe you know manga.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I have ten bucks.
Speaker 0: It's like Jesus Christ.
Speaker 0: if Japan if I was like, but you know the I guess what?
Speaker 0: Prime Minister Japan I would just be like.
Speaker 0: look everybody.
Speaker 0: Put all media online with subtitles in every language possible for free.
Speaker 0: We're doing it.
Speaker 0: Now.
Speaker 0: This is the new policy.
Speaker 0: Just government And Japan.
Speaker 0: if they did that they could even still even after all this bad juju of all these years of holding back.
Speaker 0: They could become like how almost Hollywood level media worldwide power if they just did that.
Speaker 0: Imagine if you just watch all Japanese TV with subtitles all those wacky shows all the not wacky shows All the animes all the musics all the video games.
Speaker 0: Just like just fucking do it.
Speaker 0: Jesus Christ.
Speaker 1: So there is a big problem with this change.
Speaker 1: Quote from the article.
Speaker 1: youtubers themselves will have no say in the process.
Speaker 0: No, they never do.
Speaker 1: No No this you can't even dispute these.
Speaker 1: Uh-huh.
Speaker 0: You cannot dispute these claims anymore All right, so I mean if you're trying to make money, so if I have a legitimate fair use video, I'm just fucked.
Speaker 0: Well, I mean you can get your lawyer.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you have to get your lawyer which and by YouTube I can get my lawyer and I might be able to win because these are pretty clear-cut cases, but Random livestream kid cannot afford a lawyer.
Speaker 0: No, I think if it's a if your video gets taken down I feel like then you should be able to dispute.
Speaker 1: but if they're removing the dispute process for this particular kind of claim Yeah, that's that's BS.
Speaker 0: But if you're just get D monetized, right?
Speaker 0: You know, there's a lot.
Speaker 1: if you just get D monetized honestly I don't care.
Speaker 1: because right you're not making enough money from YouTube to live.
Speaker 0: Well, even people who are making enough money from YouTube to live I basically have no simply like, you know people get all up in arms.
Speaker 0: Okay, that money comes from advertising which is already unethical right but or YouTube premium, but point is is like People because YouTube started paying creators, which I guess they should or shouldn't depending on how you feel about it, right?
Speaker 0: It's like, you know Twitter doesn't pay me for my fucking tweets Facebook doesn't pay me for Facebook posts, right?
Speaker 1: Maybe I should nationalize YouTube and just make it the national.
Speaker 0: that would be a good thing.
Speaker 0: But regardless it's like you don't have some right to be paid for putting your content on voluntarily Putting content on this other platform.
Speaker 0: It's like you put it there.
Speaker 0: It's like you're not get it there.
Speaker 0: You're lucky that they're agreeing to pay you.
Speaker 0: Well even right so they decide not to pay you.
Speaker 0: I don't really think you have a lot of calls to complain.
Speaker 0: You're lucky that it's even possible to make a penny from that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like people don't seem to remember that the fact that I can just upload videos to the internet is still crazy.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like you're lucky that they're even letting you do this.
Speaker 0: That's great.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like but yeah, it's of demonetization.
Speaker 0: I have no, you know sympathy.
Speaker 0: I think this is demon.
Speaker 0: I think they were as actually maybe a mistake to add any monetization to YouTube.
Speaker 1: And just you know, they should have provided API's for people who want to do whatever they're gonna do to self monetize or and then.
Speaker 0: but if you want to self monetize you Got to pay for the account Yeah, or something and all the bandwidth and or you share revenue with YouTube or something like something like that.
Speaker 1: But well, we've talked about this before and I wanted to rail it because they take you down.
Speaker 0: There should be a way to complain.
Speaker 1: there isn't so we'll see how this goes.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but it's time for things Of the day.
Speaker 1: so, you know, I like weird internet shit, I like shit posting like.
Speaker 1: I just enjoy that.
Speaker 1: I enjoy Consuming a certain type of shit posting on the internet, but like old-school shit posting.
Speaker 1: So I found this weird hole on the internet of you know, like Simpson wave became kind of its own thing.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I found a video that was called Simpsons old Jewish man posting
Speaker 0: Okay,
Speaker 1: and it was very specifically scenes from the Simpsons and then they would Re-cut the audio or like composite the scene or do something to insert that one old Jewish grandpa Who dances once in one episode?
Speaker 1: Into the scene somehow.
Speaker 1: Okay, and It was moderately funny.
Speaker 1: but what stood out to me was the incredibly like high attention to detail and Craft that was put into this like this was whoever did this put way more effort effort than was warranted.
Speaker 0: Well, it doesn't look like a long video, right?
Speaker 0: If you had some Adobe software, it's not too much work skilled at it.
Speaker 0: So I take me a while, but someone who was good at it would not take a while.
Speaker 1: I saw the one video and I thought maybe it was one of those situations Like I made one AMV and I put a lot of effort into it and I thought it was really good But I only made one.
Speaker 1: I thought someone made this shit posting joke once but then I saw Simpsons old Jewish man shitpost or man posting two and three and then I found a ton of videos made by a bunch of different people that are different kinds of Simpsons something.
Speaker 0: they haven't been taken down.
Speaker 1: They haven't been taken down and they're all really really like high production value for the type of content that it is and They're way funnier than they should be like way funnier.
Speaker 1: So I'm gonna link to this one and I want to find out if you think this is funny as funny as I think it Is.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: So what do you got?
Speaker 0: So one of the original nerderies from even before the time of personal computers before the time of vidya games But even before the time of tabletop RPGs.
Speaker 0: You know back in the day if you were a nerd and the only things you had were maybe like miniatures war games like working on Cars or something collecting golden age comic books.
Speaker 0: Yeah, something like that in those people didn't even really collect comic books in the golden Kids buying them and then throwing them out right.
Speaker 0: the collecting didn't happen till later really which is why golden aid comic books are rare and valuable.
Speaker 0: Back in those days the key nerdery what we would have been doing if we were alive then is model trains.
Speaker 0: Yep, model trains is like one of the core Nerderies.
Speaker 0: the word hacking comes from the MIT model train club because somebody said that.
Speaker 0: I don't know how true the story is But it's just story that's always told is that someone made a comment like ah those, you know, those train guys hacking away?
Speaker 0: Right, because when you're working on model trains all the electronics are underneath the train board, right?
Speaker 0: Where all the tracks are mounted and there's a whole bunch of wires and shit under there So you usually crawl under there and you hack away at all, you know shit.
Speaker 1: I was really into this as a kid.
Speaker 1: I had a whole bunch of big hardcover books that were like this instructional guides on how to do the train stuff.
Speaker 0: I had an oval train.
Speaker 0: we had a chain in a box.
Speaker 1: So we had some liquid smoke.
Speaker 1: We had a bunch of HO scale stuff, but that was just too small to work with and got him a pain in the ass.
Speaker 1: We had a really old set of O scale and I had one of those like triple track ones, right?
Speaker 0: So it's like Gundams.
Speaker 0: if you do Gundam gunpla They have they always measure things and how big it is compared to how big a real Gundam would be.
Speaker 0: So in Japan that giant Gundam, that's a 1-1 Gundam.
Speaker 0: That's how big a Gundam would be if it was real.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and when you make Gundams at home, you're usually doing like one one hundred one one thirty three Which means it needs to be a hundred or more times bigger than it is and then it would be the size of a real Gundam model trains have that same sort of scaling one slash number.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like yeah If this was ten times bigger it would be the size of a real.
Speaker 1: well We just looked up the one because there's like O and HO and there's this whole system, but they have a system of letters.
Speaker 0: So it's like O. HO corresponds to numbers, right?
Speaker 1: So we looked up that's 1/5 scale, right?
Speaker 0: So Gundams sort of do something similar, but not exactly the same.
Speaker 0: We're like HG is 133 but so is RG but MG and NG are one hundred and like perfect grade of like 166 sometimes really big ones something like that.
Speaker 0: I don't remember the exact numbers.
Speaker 0: But yeah trains have the same thing.
Speaker 0: So HO is one of the sizes of train that is standard and usually if you're a train person All the trains you get are in the same scale.
Speaker 0: because then you all your tracks work with the same.
Speaker 0: All right, you get the tree all your trains link together, right?
Speaker 0: Your trees won't be too big.
Speaker 0: You're you're.
Speaker 0: you're.
Speaker 0: the station that you build would be the right size.
Speaker 0: if you mix the stuff together Then it just doesn't work like you have a giant fucking tree or a. really your track will be too small.
Speaker 0: All right, you want to buy all the stuff you buys in the same scale?
Speaker 1: I wonder I gotta see if I can find someone who does like really advanced craft in model trains, but Does it all in the wrong fucked up scale?
Speaker 1: So it looks weird and dystopian.
Speaker 0: anyway My thing of the day is a video a train video and this person in the HO scale train set.
Speaker 0: Is this Junji Ito?
Speaker 0: they made Just not like the usual thing that people make with trains which is like a fancy set with all sorts of finely crafted You know towns and people and all no no into any that they just made a huge ass fucking spiral of track.
Speaker 1: Yeah They filled it with like the most basic sheep like coal and they made the longest fucking train.
Speaker 0: That pretty much fills up the whole goddamn spiral and it's sort of I don't know Hypnotic and calming and whatever to watch because it's just so, you know Interesting and and to look at this is perfect spiral this train going around at a constant speed.
Speaker 0: I think the most interesting thing is how many engines they had to intersperse between the coal cars To give it enough power to because one engine ain't pulling this train.
Speaker 1: You need a lot of engine Right to move all them cars depending on the scale because of the smaller scales like sometimes all the cars will have motive power Just for reasons.
Speaker 1: Yep depends, but this one looks like the trains themselves are motive and the cars are not There.
Speaker 0: if you look at the person's channel, what's their name?
Speaker 0: James Risner James Rizzi?
Speaker 0: if you look at their channel It is full of you know similar kinds of videos.
Speaker 1: Hot Wheels minecraft cars converted to HO scale.
Speaker 1: long triple crown trailer train with HO ski up.
Speaker 0: This is a train this person is making good stuff happen with HO scale trains.
Speaker 1: Tyco pulls long triple crown crane from dot dot dot.
Speaker 1: There's a lot.
Speaker 0: this is a person who owns a lot of HO track and train and goes nuts with it.
Speaker 1: So this is a hobby that as a kid I always wanted to get into and I like I'd make stuff and we had a little set.
Speaker 1: but as I got even a little Bit older it like it went from being really interesting to being Terrifyingly boring.
Speaker 1: my
Speaker 0: friend's dad was big into it You know in the 90s early 2000s and they had a huge setup in the basement and would part when was part of like You know old-school mailing list forums with like AOL email To talk to the other old guys who didn't know how to use technology.
Speaker 0: so I Think they were.
Speaker 0: he was doing bigger than HO scale though in the meta moment.
Speaker 1: The geek nice book club book is the first novel the tale of Genji.
Speaker 1: We'll be live in Seattle real soon.
Speaker 0: Oh, no on Friday, August 30th We'll add news.
Speaker 0: some are coming to an end.
Speaker 0: good news packs coming to a start and then this packs followed by packs and packs.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I have some news.
Speaker 1: Just booked my travel to packs.
Speaker 1: unplug.
Speaker 0: if you are going to PAX West to see or to see or not see us In 2019 in a couple few weeks Make sure you go and read.
Speaker 0: there are lots of changes logistically to PAX West.
Speaker 1: They have added a ton of bullshit security.
Speaker 0: Really fuck up your nose notable of which is a bunch of bullshit security And the consolidation of all tabletop stuff into the Hyatt Regency.
Speaker 1: We're gonna be in the Hyatt for almost the entire time that is right.
Speaker 0: Make sure you figure this stuff out before you go whether you or not you are a PAX veteran to get your shit together.
Speaker 1: I'm a little sad because like a lot of my nostalgia of packs is just memories of being in the WCC in that tabletop area with the good small rooms that were quiet Yep, and now we'll now.
Speaker 1: basically I'm literally only gonna go into the WCC once Yep to do the expo hall video thing and then maybe not maybe Literally, that'll be the only time I go in.
Speaker 1: that also means I probably won't go to that bodega because there's no reason to go To that bodega unless you're in the WCC.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we'll see.
Speaker 1: Yeah, uh, if you are a Brave and normal person who realizes the security is all fake I highly urge you to complain to packs about this because based on a leak on a reddit It appears that it is read and the patent packs that wanted this fake security Not the city.
Speaker 1: No one forced this on them.
Speaker 0: They asked for this.
Speaker 1: Yep Which is a narrative that has people have tried to argue the opposite and we seem to have evidence that it is.
Speaker 1: In fact Reed wanted this unlike say Boston where Boston forced it on conventions.
Speaker 1: who did not want it.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm Thankfully magfest has none of this nonsense.
Speaker 0: Yep, and hopefully anyone at magfest.
Speaker 0: Yep I feel like if magfest afraid to go to I mean there are some reasons to be afraid to go to magfest.
Speaker 0: Honestly, if magfest instituted this you should be more afraid of creepy dudes just creeping at magfest.
Speaker 1: Then you are afraid of guns because magfest is a con that I go in and out of a lot.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm, if magfest added metal detectors, I would stop going to magfest.
Speaker 1: I literally I would just stop going.
Speaker 1: probably would not be willing to because I go in and out of magfest like 20 times in The course of a day.
Speaker 0: Yep packs.
Speaker 1: I tend to settle in the tabletop for like seven hours.
Speaker 1: Yep All right.
Speaker 1: Let's talk about some fruits.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so I tried to see if we did a fruit show.
Speaker 0: We probably did in rim deleted it, but we did do an Apple show way back in the day.
Speaker 1: Well, yeah.
Speaker 1: So we did a show on apples to apples the game and we did a show on apples on the fruit on November 13th 2014.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: So we can.
Speaker 1: we are not allowed to talk about apples.
Speaker 0: I mean, we we obviously said everything we need to say about apples.
Speaker 1: So just assume New York.
Speaker 0: Apple is the thing in New York.
Speaker 1: Yeah And part of the reason why we're doing this show is that one People seem to really like it.
Speaker 1: when we do like food episodes.
Speaker 1: That's just like people love that and do.
Speaker 1: Scott did not want to do any my other show ideas Which include such things as let's rank American cities from best to worst.
Speaker 0: I haven't been to that many.
Speaker 1: Let's talk about when you should call the cops.
Speaker 0: Almost never.
Speaker 1: let's talk about being stolen from cuz.
Speaker 1: I've had a lot.
Speaker 1: I've had things stolen from me recently.
Speaker 0: All right locks.
Speaker 1: I feel like we could do a whole show just on cured fish.
Speaker 0: I don't ever need that many cured fish.
Speaker 1: spices good spices bad spices that cardamom.
Speaker 0: action fruits are better than spices.
Speaker 1: luggage The worst we've ever been on car accidents.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Anyway, we're gonna talk about fruit.
Speaker 1: Okay, so Scott What is your favorite fruit related joke in media?
Speaker 0: Why why?
Speaker 0: no, no, no, no.
Speaker 0: Let's talk about the actual fruits that you eat.
Speaker 0: right?
Speaker 0: melons, you know stone fruit.
Speaker 1: So I gotta get this out of the way cuz we have to.
Speaker 0: we've argued a lot I gotta say I gotta say something in general about all fruits.
Speaker 1: right it applies even to Apple I think not allowed to talk about Apple son.
Speaker 0: a lot of people out there right are You know have opinions, you know, they like some fruits.
Speaker 0: They don't like others.
Speaker 0: Right?
Speaker 0: The thing is just about every fruit is Delicious except for a few.
Speaker 0: and the thing is though.
Speaker 1: I think there are a lot of fruit.
Speaker 1: You have never eaten.
Speaker 0: That's true also There.
Speaker 0: but any one of those delicious fruits Can be gross.
Speaker 0: a fruit is only delicious when it is at the correct level of ripeness.
Speaker 0: I don't think a lot of people
Speaker 1: form
Speaker 0: an opinion about a fruit when they eat one that is not a good example of that fruit and then are Unwilling, you know if it is actually depending on where they live may or may not be hard to get a good Version or variety of that fruit They go.
Speaker 0: Oh, I hate that fruit and they won't even eat it anymore.
Speaker 0: Cuz they're closed-minded.
Speaker 1: I think they don't.
Speaker 1: that has this to the highest degree of any fruit in the United States.
Speaker 1: is the pair the pair Absolutely the pair because a bad pair it tastes like sand.
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 0: a pair that is not good basically tastes like nothing.
Speaker 0: It's just like you're eating fruit Cellulose material.
Speaker 1: this was even a long-form joke on.
Speaker 1: it's always sunny in Philadelphia Cuz there's a character Charlie who they're like on a road trip and it comes out that he has never had a page.
Speaker 1: He doesn't know what a pair is never heard of.
Speaker 1: a pair never eaten a pair.
Speaker 1: So they go to get him a pair and he just like oh and he's really excited.
Speaker 1: He bites it.
Speaker 1: He's like, uh, it just tastes like sand and nothing.
Speaker 1: And then there's this whole bit about oh, it's not right.
Speaker 1: Pears are real dangerous because I would argue that most pairs are bad.
Speaker 0: Yeah, most pairs are bad not varieties of pairs.
Speaker 1: all varieties of pairs are great.
Speaker 1: It's that most pairs are either not ripe overripe package poorly.
Speaker 1: They there's some problem with.
Speaker 0: Why is it?
Speaker 0: you get there hard?
Speaker 0: They're not juicy enough.
Speaker 1: Usually it's probably something was done to prevent them from ripening so they could ship them right and then they never like ripen.
Speaker 0: well that is that is.
Speaker 0: the number one reason that people end up with bad fruits that don't taste good is because If you buy a fruit, let's say, you know a banana, right?
Speaker 0: What they do is that banana is grown way near the equator, right, you know If you don't live down in tropical areas, no bananas fucking growing in New York.
Speaker 0: Yes, you got some kind of crazy greenhouse set up for some shit, which I don't think anyone does.
Speaker 0: so they got to use chemicals.
Speaker 0: They spray things right to trick the banana into ripening or not ripening and The result is that they ship the banana to you super green.
Speaker 0: then, you know It gets yellow and then it turns brown right away.
Speaker 0: You can actually do some tricks, you know Using these gases on your own if you can acquire them To you know control the ripening of the fruit like the old trip of putting in trick of putting an apple in a bag With certain other fruits things like that.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: There's all sorts of tricks.
Speaker 1: You can do.
Speaker 1: look at the fun line.
Speaker 0: We're not just that.
Speaker 0: it's simply because a fruit that travels Just loses flavor period regardless of how good it was to begin with.
Speaker 0: If you go to Florida and you go to the grocery and get some pineapples It's like that came from a nearby pineapple place.
Speaker 0: if you go to Hawaii where there's a pineapple farm and eat a pineapple It's fucking delicious.
Speaker 0: See the same pineapple in New York.
Speaker 1: So usually what happens there?
Speaker 1: because there's two factors of play.
Speaker 1: It's actually pretty complex.
Speaker 1: I don't want to.
Speaker 1: I don't think we should try to get too deep into it because we are not experts in this.
Speaker 1: But on one hand these techniques end up giving you a very narrow window where it will actually be the right amount of ripe.
Speaker 1: So you can get a really good pineapple in New York But the odds of any given pineapple being at that moment of ripeness at the time you cut it up to eat it pretty low.
Speaker 0: I've actually learned how to tell when a pineapple is ready if it's all green obviously too soon.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if it's all brown, it's obviously mushy and bad.
Speaker 0: You want the pineapple because you know has a little like little hexagons.
Speaker 0: You want each hexagon to be brown with green around the edges.
Speaker 0: you want green on the edges and you want brown in the middle.
Speaker 0: And that's a pineapple.
Speaker 0: open that shit up eat it right now.
Speaker 0: but every time I go to the grocery store in New York, the pineapples are either green usually green and Occasionally super brown super rare to find one that's in between.
Speaker 1: That's why I end up with pineapple.
Speaker 1: I tend to get a like package pre-cut pineapples.
Speaker 0: It's so much more money.
Speaker 1: If you buy a whole pineapple is four dollars.
Speaker 0: a tiny can of delicious canned pineapple will be like two or three dollars.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right.
Speaker 0: It's like you put a whole pineapple for a dollar more.
Speaker 0: if you can only find it's got it in my 30s.
Speaker 1: Wait a whole pineapple.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna be sick.
Speaker 0: I share I cut it up and I put it in a container and I eat it slowly or share it.
Speaker 1: No, but the other factor is that What constitutes a forgiven fruit is a really complicated question because there are a lot of Technically fruits We can head.
Speaker 1: that technically very We can head that off because and uh, if you go to the Wikipedia article just go there's a section it's the first section in the fruit page of Wikipedia that talks about the difference between Fruit as a botanic term and fruit as a culinary term.
Speaker 1: Haha.
Speaker 1: We are saved.
Speaker 0: we can avoid that fucking art Talking for that.
Speaker 0: We are talking about culinary fruits.
Speaker 0: I don't give a shit about your botanic fruits.
Speaker 1: Here's the definition of culinary fruit.
Speaker 1: in case you want to be a pet in a fruit is usually any sweet tasting plant part.
Speaker 0: Yeah, fuck.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's it.
Speaker 0: Take that full Definition.
Speaker 0: stop me now.
Speaker 1: if it came off a sugary plant I eat it.
Speaker 1: It's like yeah, if it's even remotely sweet It's a fruit.
Speaker 1: Fuck it.
Speaker 0: Take that.
Speaker 0: Yeah Yeah, go fruits.
Speaker 1: All right, but with all these cultivars and everything What that means is that you look at ten different apples ten different sets of grapes.
Speaker 1: they could have drastically different tastes drastically different ripening periods everything.
Speaker 1: oh, yeah, and Generally the things that make a fruit easier to transport long distances tend to make it less flavorful.
Speaker 1: That's why the grapes you get in the grocery store are all like Concord grapes because they have a really thick skin.
Speaker 0: Oh, that's where we live.
Speaker 1: They can make Concord grapes near here But also because they have a really thick skin and they're really easy to transport.
Speaker 1: But like the best grapes are the ones that have such thin skins that if you look at them the wrong way They just disintegrate.
Speaker 0: I think it's just part of the way that the history of you know fruit growing and generally, you know Agriculture in general is that they have been breeding, you know Things to you know have lots of features.
Speaker 0: right like doesn't get killed by bugs Grows real big, you know, you know stays in good shape and condition looks nice.
Speaker 0: they've been breeding for all these factors and Somehow flavor was not one of the factors that was emphasized in the u.s.
Speaker 0: In particular all the others.
Speaker 1: There was a trend to focus on Consistency over good flavor, right?
Speaker 0: So the result is that you know It's like they could and they probably.
Speaker 0: there are people who probably are working on right cultivating fruits vegetables Whatever that have all the other good qualities like durable easy to grow Those Right Zima tomatoes or whatever.
Speaker 1: They're way more flavorful than just like red cherry tomatoes, but also tastes great.
Speaker 0: But the fact is most of the great tasting varieties of things that are grown Do not have those other features already bred into them and they end up being rarer more expensive can only get them locally.
Speaker 1: They end up being difficult to grow.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I tried to grow a fancy strawberry and it didn't work out Shitty.
Speaker 1: Apparently, this is a big thing among people who grow cannabis like hobbyists because the really high quality cannabis plants They call them prima donnas because they're just.
Speaker 1: if anything goes wrong like fuck it.
Speaker 1: I'm just gonna die I give up.
Speaker 1: but if you get a shitty cannabis plant, it's just invincible.
Speaker 0: It's like the weed it makes us crappy.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the weed it makes us crappy.
Speaker 0: Like you don't want that.
Speaker 1: we fruits are the same way.
Speaker 0: Oh, I think all agriculture is the same.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: That's just how it goes At least in terms of things we're eating or consuming like potatoes.
Speaker 1: We bred potatoes to be less poisonous so we can eat them But that makes them prone to being eaten by other animals and bugs and stuff.
Speaker 1: If you go in the wild and dig up like a random to mate like a random potato out in the woods It'll probably fucking kill you.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I thought that was a rumor.
Speaker 1: No wild potatoes are dangerous as shit.
Speaker 1: Anyway, lots of wild like things that look like carrots in the wild can be very toxic as well.
Speaker 1: Lots of wild or the worst are squashes.
Speaker 1: if your garden if you're growing squashes in your garden The kinds of squashes we eat tend to taste really good But they you need to do a lot of care to make them grow.
Speaker 0: All right, so worst possible fruit Grapefruit.
Speaker 1: Well grapefruits are delicious.
Speaker 0: The fuck's wrong is the worst.
Speaker 1: free grapefruit juice is my favorite juice.
Speaker 0: Now a grapefruit is first of all granted.
Speaker 0: I'm even if it tasted good.
Speaker 1: Really have the the xkcd strip called quote fuck a grapefruit up on the screen right now?
Speaker 1: No, okay, I'll talk about this chart in a minute cuz it's important.
Speaker 0: so a grapefruit, right?
Speaker 0: Here's all the problems with a grapefruit number one.
Speaker 0: It tastes bad.
Speaker 1: It tastes delicious.
Speaker 1: Your is your.
Speaker 0: it is sour.
Speaker 1: Bad way it is sour in a wonderful way.
Speaker 0: I could eat a lemon.
Speaker 0: I could eat a lime just um, but a grapefruit It's just like.
Speaker 0: it's like it's like acid.
Speaker 0: It's like burning nasty.
Speaker 1: I think I battery.
Speaker 1: I think I could eat an entire grapefruit before you could eat an entire lemon.
Speaker 0: Alright, so second problem with grapefruit right is that it's kind of big.
Speaker 0: It's like an orange is a good size.
Speaker 0: I could eat a whole orange.
Speaker 1: There are oranges that are as big as grapefruits.
Speaker 0: You don't eat those look like a navel orange a navel orange.
Speaker 0: I can eat a whole navel orange.
Speaker 1: There's some grapefruits are about that size.
Speaker 0: Yeah, grapefruits are too big.
Speaker 0: You can't eat the whole grapefruit.
Speaker 0: usually end up chopping it in half and the other half goes in the fridge.
Speaker 0: It gets even more sour Right.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: number three to eat a grapefruit You can't just like an orange.
Speaker 0: you can peel it and then break it into wedges and eat it.
Speaker 0: Yeah an apple.
Speaker 0: you can just bomb into it.
Speaker 0: a banana peel it just on right a watermelon or a pineapple.
Speaker 0: you cut it.
Speaker 1: Yeah to your credit.
Speaker 1: There is.
Speaker 1: there's a reason why there's a fruit you got.
Speaker 0: you need a fucking weird-ass spoon.
Speaker 0: There's a holy grandma has.
Speaker 1: there's a pop culture meme from the 80s that mostly disappeared.
Speaker 1: Like it's not in modern media really.
Speaker 1: if you watch old 80s movies old TV shows There will always be a joke about someone in the family is eating a grapefruit for breakfast and it squirts someone else in the
Speaker 0: eye Right and you use the grapefruit like sharp like serrated spoon and it'll still squirt you in the eye Right, which is the thing that really happens in a special spoon for this fucking fruit and only grandma
Speaker 1: has one.
Speaker 1: All right, so Scott I'm gonna.
Speaker 1: actually I'm gonna almost agree with you.
Speaker 1: We are talking about fruit.
Speaker 1: We are not talking about fruit juice because and this gets me to this chart fruit juice Removes like there are fruits that are a pain in the ass to eat or prepare that Prickly pear.
Speaker 1: that being said quickly pair one time delicious fruit And I will never try to prepare you again in my life.
Speaker 0: that being said one time I went and I bought some orange juice and I didn't realize it was orange grapefruit juice and it tasted like poison.
Speaker 0: I threw it out.
Speaker 1: No grapefruit juice is delicious.
Speaker 1: No, but I'll agree with you here.
Speaker 1: I do not like to eat grapefruit as a fruit, but I love grapefruit juice.
Speaker 0: Yeah So this xkcd see me in a perfect one is grow.
Speaker 1: This is the most important thing to talk about fruit.
Speaker 1: We discount juice.
Speaker 1: This xkcd strip is called fuck grapefruit.
Speaker 0: Oh a wise person.
Speaker 0: Randall Monroe knows how great fruit is disgusting.
Speaker 1: But the important thing is this is the most important one Scott plus Randall Monroe versus rim.
Speaker 1: There are only two axes you to one for which you there only two axes to describe fruit.
Speaker 1: one axis is Difficulty.
Speaker 1: how easy it is it to prepare and eat?
Speaker 1: how difficult is it to prepare and eat?
Speaker 1: The other axis is is it tasty or is it on tasty?
Speaker 1: case in point?
Speaker 1: Seeded grapes very tasty but much more difficult to eat then unsee than seedless grapes.
Speaker 1: Seedless grapes not as tasty but so much easier to eat that most people prefer seedless grapes Yeah, but like seedless watermelon.
Speaker 0: whenever I go to the grocery whenever I get grapes At the grocery is one of the only things at the grocery It's you're allowed to eat one of each color grape Yep at the grocery to test to see if they're good.
Speaker 0: and then if they're good then you buy great.
Speaker 0: Yeah But you can always eat one green grape and one red grape at the grocery to test them out.
Speaker 0: because this chart shows a lot Of times you go to the grocery you eat a great but it's like that's tasteless not buying those.
Speaker 1: but this chart then allows us To make four quadrants.
Speaker 1: So in the upper right quadrant are the magic fruit.
Speaker 1: the fruit are the tasty ones that are easy to eat and the king Of those on this chart is a combination of peaches strawberries and blueberries, right?
Speaker 1: So I don't disagree with no.
Speaker 0: So the thing with peach though, it's like strawberry.
Speaker 0: It's like you can it's.
Speaker 0: you can kind of get good strawberries.
Speaker 1: Oh good peach Good peach.
Speaker 0: if you live in Georgia, you're just like buried in them, right?
Speaker 0: You can just get them all over in New York.
Speaker 0: It's hard to get good peach.
Speaker 1: Oh my if I get a good if I get a peach as a rock.
Speaker 1: and when I say this good It goes when I say peach.
Speaker 0: I don't just mean peach.
Speaker 0: I mean all varieties of peach white peach yellow peach, California peach.
Speaker 0: I mean nectarine, which is just a peach.
Speaker 0: It's not fuzzy.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean plum.
Speaker 0: I mean pretty much.
Speaker 0: all those are not peaches.
Speaker 0: all of the I know but I mean all the same things all those stone fruits Okay, so yes, I do.
Speaker 0: all of those have the same problem there.
Speaker 0: I when you go to the grocery in New York they're either hard as a fucking rock or mushy and disgusting.
Speaker 0: If you take one home that's hard as a rock.
Speaker 0: You have to sit there and look at it and wait for it to be a little squishy then eat it immediately and the second One you bought will already be mush.
Speaker 1: No and whenever you say look at it you have to literally just sit in the room with it and wait if you like leave the Room to go to the bathroom.
Speaker 1: We come back.
Speaker 0: No pile of mold.
Speaker 0: So I buy one at a time and I wait for it to be good.
Speaker 1: now I eat it.
Speaker 1: So this is where Randall Monroe made a mistake.
Speaker 1: There is a third axis.
Speaker 1: The axes is risk.
Speaker 1: How risky is this fruit?
Speaker 0: Yep, so I fruit and then well it goes bad.
Speaker 0: You just lost it.
Speaker 1: and if you take risk into account or even if it doesn't go bad like grapes They don't really go bad so much as some grapes are just bitter.
Speaker 0: Well, yeah, those are bad, but you don't you don't risk it cuz you taste like.
Speaker 1: oh they got like it.
Speaker 0: So taste them before you buy them.
Speaker 1: Yeah But as a result, but strawberries tend to just be good or rotten, but they tend to be good a lot longer.
Speaker 0: I've heard about a special strawberry.
Speaker 0: That's like the best driver.
Speaker 1: Oh, I saw people tweeting about that the other day.
Speaker 0: Well, no, that was a melon.
Speaker 0: They were tweeting about.
Speaker 1: I also saw people tweeting about the melon.
Speaker 1: I didn't see strawberry the head the heirloom melon that has gone from this earth.
Speaker 1: and there's another melon.
Speaker 1: That's the closest thing you can get to it.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna try to get that melon.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah I was thinking about that kind of like how they gross me Cal.
Speaker 1: It's hard to get.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and that's what old bananas taste like.
Speaker 1: Yep Bananas are complicated because bananas are pretty good.
Speaker 1: They're not great.
Speaker 0: I love banana.
Speaker 1: I like bananas.
Speaker 1: Okay, I actually prefer plantains But that doesn't count as fruit.
Speaker 0: It depends because that is something I just eat.
Speaker 0: a fucking plan.
Speaker 1: Plantain is something you cook that is savory.
Speaker 1: It does not count because we were talking about botanical fruit whatever.
Speaker 1: So what about the melons?
Speaker 0: There's a lot of good melons out because I was talking.
Speaker 1: I was at work literally a couple days ago because where I work You know money melon.
Speaker 1: every morning There's just four cups of fruit for anyone who wants them.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm and bring me home for those people that I talked to hate honeydew.
Speaker 1: Okay, like people don't like honeydew and I don't understand why the money I mean honeydew.
Speaker 1: the money melon is a great melon, but I think the problem is honeydew is like other.
Speaker 1: it's like pears.
Speaker 1: Most people have bad honeydews.
Speaker 0: That's also true But I do think you know It is.
Speaker 0: even though a good even a good honeydew the flavor of the good honeydew is not Powerful right handy if you get a really ripe one.
Speaker 0: Yes, but it's mostly a milder fruit.
Speaker 0: So when you eat it, even if it's you know, it's it's like alright, I taste delicious honeydew.
Speaker 0: But it's like, you know, most honeydews are not the most delicious.
Speaker 0: They're often a little firm and tough.
Speaker 0: They don't like Like say watermelon or cute or even cantaloupe, but if you get a good honeydew, it's a strong flavor.
Speaker 1: It just melts in your mouth.
Speaker 0: Most people not had a good honeydew and even the best honeydew.
Speaker 0: It's like it's great.
Speaker 0: It's the money melon.
Speaker 0: I want it I want to eat it Yeah, but it's just not it like if it can put the best honeydew in the best cantaloupe and the best watermelon.
Speaker 0: The honeydew is less powerful.
Speaker 0: It's less sweet.
Speaker 0: It's less delicious less sugary, you know.
Speaker 1: Watermelon is interesting because it doesn't have that strong a flavor either.
Speaker 1: But what I like about watermelon is I can just eat.
Speaker 1: well good watermelon has a strong flavor Yeah, but you can eat as much what you could just eat watermelon forever.
Speaker 0: Well, it's mostly water exactly.
Speaker 0: He's got a fee.
Speaker 0: That's why it's mushier than the honeydew.
Speaker 1: I have an anecdote from when I was a young child.
Speaker 1: I was like six or seven years old maybe younger.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I could try to figure out how old I was.
Speaker 1: But basically we had a Gigantic watermelon like a huge one and we cut the whole thing up.
Speaker 0: sure He doesn't remember it being big cuz you were small.
Speaker 1: No, it was.
Speaker 1: it was big like the whole thing Like we were talking about like this is a big watermelon like, uh-huh so anyway, the per that what it was all this man was I Basically ate the whole fucking thing.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm and the family I kind of mad at me cuz I like literally just ate the whole thing Over the course of like the morning and I kept having to pee.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm I had to pee so much that I kept going.
Speaker 1: I went to the bathroom peed again and again and again and again cuz I Basically drank like a gallon and a half of watermelon juice And I was young and at some point apparently I started crying Because I was peeing so much that I thought I was gonna pee forever And I was worried that I wouldn't be able to go play with my friends anymore because I kept having to pee.
Speaker 0: Just go play in the pool and pee.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that might have worked.
Speaker 1: I didn't think about that I didn't.
Speaker 0: I was playing the ocean and pee.
Speaker 1: kid brain couldn't figure out that I should just go stay in the pool all day.
Speaker 1: Kid brain just kept crying and going back into the bathroom and peeing.
Speaker 0: Bring a big ring game boy.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: But I think actually if I have to say my favorite fruit It is not as easy to eat as say strawberries peaches seedless grapes.
Speaker 1: But the mango mangoes good.
Speaker 1: I love the mango.
Speaker 1: I'll just eat mangoes all day.
Speaker 1: Mmm, the problem is the best mangoes are the ones you get right off a tree in a tropical place.
Speaker 1: we don't have access to those.
Speaker 1: or For the grocery store by us.
Speaker 1: every now and then they'll have champagne mangoes.
Speaker 1: They're really good.
Speaker 1: They rot instantly.
Speaker 1: It's not like ripe.
Speaker 1: It's not like rock ripe a badge Like if they're in the grocery store, they're always ripe and they will be bad by the end of that day.
Speaker 1: So if you ever see champagne mangoes in the grocery store, just buy them and eat them all that night.
Speaker 0: It's hard for me to have a favorite fruit because it's like.
Speaker 0: there's so many delicious fruits I love whichever one is in season and high quality, right?
Speaker 0: It's like I'm not you know, it's like I love fucking Apple.
Speaker 0: It's Apple season.
Speaker 0: I'm like, yeah, give me all the Apple.
Speaker 0: But then it's like, you know if I'm sitting there in the summer and it's like, okay Here's an apple and then here is you know an in-season like fucking strawberry.
Speaker 0: That's perfect.
Speaker 0: It's like oh, I don't want the fucking Apple.
Speaker 1: That is one thing I took with fruit.
Speaker 1: I tend to eat seasonally and I tend to avoid out of season fruit, even though I could get them.
Speaker 1: I live in New York and get any fruit.
Speaker 1: I want just about if you spend money Yeah, but even then like I tend to like to eat the things that are most in season.
Speaker 1: So like when it's blackberry season, I'm just eating blackberries in the winter.
Speaker 1: I'm eating whatever fruits you can get in the winter.
Speaker 0: Another fruit.
Speaker 0: I don't like is the cherry, right?
Speaker 1: So I love wrong with you cherries are great.
Speaker 1: Every cherry is great.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I love cherries.
Speaker 1: I like sour cherries.
Speaker 1: I like black cherries.
Speaker 0: You know cherry the red the red cherry that they put on like ice cream sundae that's discuss.
Speaker 0: Those are so good.
Speaker 0: Those are the words put.
Speaker 1: those think I just gotta get the good ones.
Speaker 1: The fancy one the looks right.
Speaker 0: then It's like but cherry flavored stuff is great.
Speaker 0: Right cherry like juice on stuff or like in stuff like a cherry pie.
Speaker 0: That's great.
Speaker 0: I could eat that right?
Speaker 0: No problem.
Speaker 1: That's got your head the Luxardo cherry.
Speaker 0: No, but maybe it's good.
Speaker 0: I don't know the Luxardo cherry.
Speaker 1: It's basically like that's black cherry.
Speaker 0: I can eat.
Speaker 0: right We're talking about the red ones are the ones that I can't do.
Speaker 1: why they're so good.
Speaker 0: and it's like I can do them Pretty much in any form except I can't just eat them directly Right, so it's like even a red cherry, which I know I love the black cherry in all forms, right?
Speaker 0: But the red cherry if you put it into some other form I can eat it.
Speaker 0: But if it's just sit in there like a Mario fucking - right where it's just like - little I'll eat those all day Right, just like.
Speaker 0: um, I can't eat that.
Speaker 0: Why not?
Speaker 0: No, I can't eat like.
Speaker 1: what don't you like about him?
Speaker 0: I'm just no good.
Speaker 1: What's not good about them.
Speaker 1: I just I don't know like you can't articulate the specific thing that bothers you.
Speaker 1: No, that's okay.
Speaker 1: I just don't like weird why I'd like, okay I'll give you a Luxardo cherry and you can try one of them.
Speaker 0: I mean that looks like a black cherries.
Speaker 0: I probably love it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but they're.
Speaker 1: they're soaked in the sweet like.
Speaker 1: they're basically like the cherries you'd put on a Sunday.
Speaker 1: They're just the fancy version of that.
Speaker 1: Okay, they're not it's only.
Speaker 0: the only ones I don't like are the red ones in their Unprocessed form.
Speaker 1: No, I do really like pomegranates But they're too much of a pain in the ass.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I do pomegranate.
Speaker 0: when someone else does the pain in the ass someone else does the pomegranating.
Speaker 1: I will eat the pomegranates, but I'm not willing to do the pomegranating myself anymore.
Speaker 1: Yeah Prickly pear is the same deal like.
Speaker 1: I'll just eat prickly pear But someone else has to make it for me and no one is willing to do that.
Speaker 0: Another fruit that I don't like that everyone else seems to love is the lychee.
Speaker 1: Lychee is delicious.
Speaker 1: It's got someone just brought up the lychee in the forum in the live stream.
Speaker 0: Oh interesting like she's really good.
Speaker 0: Everyone else seems to love lychee, but I'm not into it.
Speaker 1: The thing is the lychee is one of those fruits kind of like pear.
Speaker 0: It tastes too much like a flower.
Speaker 0: I love you like to eat flowers.
Speaker 1: I'm like Homer Simpson.
Speaker 1: I'll just eat flowers rose water.
Speaker 0: I'll just drink it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't need flowers.
Speaker 1: Cherry just like get some concentrated violets.
Speaker 1: Oh my god.
Speaker 0: That's delicious.
Speaker 0: I don't do that.
Speaker 1: I I would I will eat raw roses.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: No, I won't do that.
Speaker 1: In fact, uh, I am thinking about.
Speaker 1: I saw a good recipe to make basically make roses and cook them into candies.
Speaker 1: Alright now rose water not like making rose candy the way you're thinking like basically putting sugar on Roses and cooking them.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: No, thank you.
Speaker 1: That stuff's delicious.
Speaker 1: That's a big part of Turkish cooking.
Speaker 1: is the rose.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: But we're not talking about roses.
Speaker 1: We're talking.
Speaker 1: we're not talking about flowers.
Speaker 1: It's all about fruits and actually we've gone on for over an hour.
Speaker 1: So I think we're talking about me going to eat some food.
Speaker 0: No, yeah, I'm hungry.
Speaker 1: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at front row crew comm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 1: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 0: But unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 0: It's actually recorded at night.
Speaker 1: and the patreon patrons for this episode of geek nights, ah Craig all around enjoys how many little just like a do-gag your television.
Speaker 1: William Eisen rose link eg Graham Finch Jennifer Hitchcock Chris midkiff my state e.com j-ban Sean Yeager Nicholas Brando, mr Strong stretchin four to one.
Speaker 1: creations like Johan Sebastian Bacharach ominous Mac and I were sound man to Thunder Sherman horrible Rory Superboy Clinton Walton Ren from New Zealand Ryan Perrin drew open Lander Finn Dread Lily Tenebrae Sean Klein Chris Reimer Thomas Hahn.
Speaker 1: and here's something for your head holes Oh.