Speaker 1: It's Wednesday, June 26th, 2019.
Speaker 1: I'm rim.
Speaker 1: I'm Scott and this is geek nights tonight Being puppycat because the whole first series is just out on YouTube.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: So, you know, let me start a gig guys episode and every day We always talk about the opening bit like we want to say something before we actually start the show.
Speaker 0: tiny bit warm today Yeah, not much, but you know tiny bit.
Speaker 0: It's definitely not cold today.
Speaker 1: So something happened in three things happened to me that are all open a bit worthy and in in an Increasing like manner like of the three things.
Speaker 0: well down the stairs you got shot.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you went to the hospital to rescue.
Speaker 1: It's something like that.
Speaker 1: So I want to relay the three interesting things that happen to me today in order of weirdness.
Speaker 1: so first things.
Speaker 1: first I My company has like this big annual company picnic on Randall's Island and I've only done today.
Speaker 1: It's this weekend Sunday Yeah, so last year I didn't go cuz I was you know I joined this company and then they're like, oh there's a company picnic and I was like Now that I know good luck getting in.
Speaker 1: that's why this is my open event.
Speaker 1: So I'm like, okay, there's a company picnic.
Speaker 1: I don't really care.
Speaker 0: I thought we're gonna judge animans on this.
Speaker 1: Uh, yeah, I forgot about the company picnics.
Speaker 1: left to defer that.
Speaker 1: No, I'm going to this thing.
Speaker 1: We could do anything we could judge in the evening.
Speaker 1: I can just stop there on my way home.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm cuz I'm biking there.
Speaker 1: Anyway, I didn't go to this thing because you know, I worked at IBM.
Speaker 1: I worked at places that a company picnics and I got better things to do.
Speaker 0: usually that's right.
Speaker 1: But then so I die.
Speaker 1: so while I was working at this place last year I get all these emails like the fucking company picnic is coming like go here to Register for it and there's like a whole big hullabaloo.
Speaker 1: So I was like, wow, I'm definitely not going That's right.
Speaker 1: Then as the date approaches like a month before it happens all around the building like every building I go to everyone I talk to.
Speaker 1: people are like, oh, yeah, I'm going on Saturday.
Speaker 1: I'm going on Sunday.
Speaker 1: Oh, it's a two-day picnic.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you go on one of the two days only.
Speaker 1: Wow So people are like buzzing about it And as it gets closer people are like really getting excited about it and we people find out I'm not going.
Speaker 1: they're like what?
Speaker 1: Really?
Speaker 1: You're not going why not?
Speaker 0: It must be so great.
Speaker 0: If the fact that you're now going So there must be something that I was too late like by the I didn't sign up.
Speaker 1: You have to sign up like months in advance.
Speaker 1: You can't go good.
Speaker 1: So this year like, you know what?
Speaker 1: I'm gonna sign up for this thing.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna see what the deal is.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm So that was last year that ever there's a hole.
Speaker 0: Yeah last year.
Speaker 1: So a big hullabaloo and I didn't go.
Speaker 0: So this year you just signed up.
Speaker 1: So this year I signed up Saturday.
Speaker 1: was it's like PAX tickets to go on Saturday Uh-huh.
Speaker 1: So I'm going on Sunday.
Speaker 0: Okay, so But it's just food.
Speaker 0: and like sports Huge there's rides.
Speaker 0: There's food stalls like car rides.
Speaker 1: Like.
Speaker 1: it seems like it's what like.
Speaker 1: it's more like State Fair level, okay It seems like it's about as big as a State Fair.
Speaker 0: The state fairgrounds of New York State are enormous.
Speaker 1: It's not as big as the New York's Island.
Speaker 1: Yeah Well, yeah, then the Michigan State Fair fairgrounds were big but most of it was giant.
Speaker 0: You can probably fit several Randalls Islands in New York State.
Speaker 1: Giant fields filled with animals.
Speaker 0: New York State Fair is like a permanent town place.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like when we go to the Michigan State Fair.
Speaker 1: It's on a huge amount of land, but we don't really go to this tiny part of it.
Speaker 0: That's partially because it's far away from everything.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but think of thing I remember.
Speaker 1: actually as a kid we went we went to the State Fair once and on the way home The family agreed to never go to the State Fair again.
Speaker 1: There was not much going on.
Speaker 0: Connecticut didn't really, I don't know if Connecticut has this.
Speaker 1: That was way better.
Speaker 0: I don't know if Connecticut has a State Fair but they had a thing called the Big E that you could go to.
Speaker 1: I have no idea about that.
Speaker 0: It's like a big food deal.
Speaker 0: Anyway, yeah, so so you're going to the thing now.
Speaker 0: Was there like something announced at the thing that's suddenly worthy of going?
Speaker 1: So I saw the map of the thing like a concert with an amazing musician.
Speaker 1: There's like all this stuff.
Speaker 1: like it looks like a pretty big deal.
Speaker 1: It'll be fun.
Speaker 1: So, uh It's big enough to where when I had to go get my passes to the event in the office today.
Speaker 1: So I think like whatever and I stopped down there It's there's a giant booth like when you go to PAX to pick up your like speaker badges And I have to like go through a whole rigmarole.
Speaker 1: they give me these big PAX looking badges in a sealed envelope and It's like like I gotta bring all this ID and there's gonna be security checkpoints.
Speaker 1: And it's like I can bring one person and I have a special badge for them.
Speaker 1: They have to bring ID.
Speaker 1: the name on the ID has to match the name on this PAX looking badge in the sealed envelope.
Speaker 1: It's like it's it was way more security.
Speaker 0: Let's just forge that fucking shit.
Speaker 1: Yeah Sell them.
Speaker 1: So if you want to try to crash this party on Sunday, like good luck.
Speaker 0: I see the badge.
Speaker 0: so I can see if it's forged in the sealed envelope.
Speaker 0: So you can open the envelope now.
Speaker 1: It's got a seal on it.
Speaker 0: open the envelope now.
Speaker 0: No, I'm not supposed to you had to open it there.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna bring the envelope there and show another badge and then use these badges.
Speaker 1: There's a whole thing.
Speaker 0: so you can't open the envelope in advance.
Speaker 1: I don't think so.
Speaker 0: Otherwise that they're no good.
Speaker 0: So that's how they prevent.
Speaker 1: yeah, because apparently the thing is big enough and popular after where people try to like sell the badges on a Secondary market.
Speaker 0: I mean the fact I mean didn't even know this thing existed, but now it's like hey Let's try to get into other big companies picnics, right?
Speaker 1: I want to find out where credit are probably not as secure as yours.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I want to go to like Credit Suisse's company.
Speaker 0: Suisse is like of all the companies in New York.
Speaker 0: They are like one of the tops in terms of pamper the employees Like every sports league in the city has.
Speaker 0: like a Credit Suisse team.
Speaker 1: I went to a lot of Mets games.
Speaker 0: Anytime you go to a thing There's always like a group of people wearing like Credit Suisse like shirts.
Speaker 0: There is a bike ride.
Speaker 1: There's a past life where I saw many Mets games at Shea Stadium and luxury boxes.
Speaker 1: because of companies like Credit Suisse.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think I've actually been in their box.
Speaker 0: Maybe I should try to get a job.
Speaker 0: They're hiring.
Speaker 0: Maybe that's the purpose of them.
Speaker 0: doing all that shit is to try to get people to work there.
Speaker 1: I know for a fact they're hiring.
Speaker 0: They're always hiring.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you could get a job there anyone.
Speaker 1: You'd make a lot of money.
Speaker 1: I don't know if you'd want to do that kind of work.
Speaker 0: Well, it depends how many hours I got to work.
Speaker 0: So that is how many of those special things like.
Speaker 1: so this whole like badge rigger mall.
Speaker 1: It's just like the least weird thing that happened to me today.
Speaker 1: Okay, so the second thing that happened on the way to work You know that shitty deli that basically or the bodega that basically just sells vapes The one right one right next to Queensborough Blot.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so I'm walking to the subway to go to work.
Speaker 1: It's a lottery tickets and I see a guy who's like standing Outside of it like peering into the window.
Speaker 0: All right, there's always shady people in that area.
Speaker 1: and I noticed as I walked by.
Speaker 1: He has a gun.
Speaker 1: All right He has a gun in a holster like kind of hidden but like not like an open carrier like check out my gun But a fucking like handgun.
Speaker 1: All right, so I don't like stop or react cuz I don't want to be involved in this.
Speaker 1: I keep walking and I just walk up to you know The viaduct like the bridge and then I kind of look over the corner to be like, so what's the deal with this?
Speaker 1: And the guy's just standing there peering into the bodega Like the shitty bodega selling the vapes and you can't see the gun from there, but he has a gun.
Speaker 1: I know he has a gun and I'm like, is he a plainclothes police officer?
Speaker 0: So I thought of just now because having a gun in New York City is not the easiest.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like if you have a gun legally you are either a problem or you're a cop.
Speaker 0: Yep So and these are not any nine percent chance of one of those teeth and these are not mutually exclusive.
Speaker 0: That is true.
Speaker 1: So that is not the weird part.
Speaker 1: All right, because I clearly like there was no police like there was no news of a shooting Or a robbery.
Speaker 1: so clearly yes, probably a cop.
Speaker 1: But while I look over the corner like from the bridge to be like what's going on should I call the cops?
Speaker 1: No, well if I give someone has a gun who is not a cop that is 100%.
Speaker 1: call the cop situation.
Speaker 0: You don't know.
Speaker 0: he's not a cop.
Speaker 0: if he pulls it out, then you couldn't call.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like.
Speaker 1: if he pulls it out to like brandish it.
Speaker 1: Yes, then you can call or also you could call the cows and be Like yeah, so do you have a plainclothes officer like doing something here because there's a guy with a gun here?
Speaker 1: Gun like gun is a hundred percent cop situation some one way or the other.
Speaker 1: but that is not.
Speaker 1: I ended up not calling the Cops because I look over the corner.
Speaker 1: I see him.
Speaker 1: He's still peering in the window doing this thing, but like 20 feet behind him where that bus stop is.
Speaker 1: There's a woman standing in an open suitcase Disrobing slowly and she's taking her clothes off and like some weirds going on.
Speaker 1: Okay, and I these two things are happening and I just think you know what?
Speaker 1: I ain't got time for this and I just kept walking and got on the subway and went to work.
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 1: The third thing that happened to me was on my way home from work today.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: So I'm just walking toward the subway.
Speaker 1: I have to stop at a light and there's much traffic going by and there's a dude standing there and His skin color looks wrong and weird to the point that I really had to resist doing a double take.
Speaker 0: He's got a skin condition.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there's.
Speaker 1: no no no that's so yeah, like.
Speaker 1: he has a pallor about him like death itself Mm-hmm, but and I would have just ignored that like so like that is not something I would talk about because people have skin conditions Whatever, but and I avoided doing a double take but I'm standing next to him and then I noticed something else.
Speaker 1: He is clearly wearing a fake mustache.
Speaker 1: Like I can see the plaster He's wearing a wig that's like glued to his head.
Speaker 1: Like I can see the little line.
Speaker 1: I can see like the wig bits.
Speaker 0: All right, maybe it's like a you know, a practical joke or a setup for a video.
Speaker 1: All I'm saying is that basically the dude was like 100% wearing an elaborate disguise carrying a big briefcase and wearing a suit and like Elaborate disguise with like makeup because I could even see like his regular skin tone.
Speaker 1: Like I saw it could be a clown.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so, uh, all I don't know what he was up to but I like.
Speaker 1: maybe there's a film shoot Maybe it's a practical joke.
Speaker 1: Maybe he's a spy.
Speaker 1: Maybe he's about to rob a bank An actor at like a place or something.
Speaker 1: Maybe he's looking for the guy Who has the gun that he's gonna buy to go rob the bank and he showed up places in the city where someone would wear A costume on any given day.
Speaker 0: like is that weird?
Speaker 0: but Jekyll and Hyde restaurant.
Speaker 0: Is that still fucking there?
Speaker 1: I assume.
Speaker 0: I assume that place plenty of tourist traps or someone might wear a costume of any kind at any day.
Speaker 0: And if that person who works there goes home, it doesn't change, you know.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it was just.
Speaker 1: it was very interesting to like look at someone and be like, well don't wanna don't want to call attention to That wait a minute.
Speaker 1: dude's wearing a costume.
Speaker 1: All right, it's makeup interesting.
Speaker 1: and then I went home and that was it.
Speaker 1: Three weird things that happened to me today.
Speaker 0: Wasn't the disrobing person weirder than the costume person?
Speaker 1: I mean it was but it was the the gun and then the disrobing person and then I just didn't care anymore.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: So, uh, what do you got in the news?
Speaker 0: So some comic news going on.
Speaker 0: obviously the big comic news that's going on is the vertigo comics Which is a long-standing and historic imprint of DC Comics Which if you don't know that means that basically vertigo comics is DC Comics.
Speaker 0: It's the same company the same, you know, whatever but it's like a separate department and when they print comics They put a different label on the side.
Speaker 0: and usually you would do this for two main reasons.
Speaker 0: number one to your internal Organization, right?
Speaker 0: It's like okay.
Speaker 0: We have a team of editors that makes these comics and we have a team of editors That makes those comics.
Speaker 0: We're all the same company, but they're focused on these properties and these people over here doing superheroes, right?
Speaker 0: It's sort of like, you know, they're separate teams.
Speaker 0: So we'll have separate, you know things going on, right?
Speaker 0: And the other reason is simply for the audience, right?
Speaker 0: So you go to the comic book store.
Speaker 1: You don't want someone to be like ooh Marvel and like wait, where's my spider-man, right?
Speaker 0: You see a cut you see a logo in the top corner the comic you're gonna buy and it says DC.
Speaker 0: So you're expecting.
Speaker 0: well, that means this is in the DC Universe the Superman and Batman Wonder Woman, you know, right?
Speaker 0: but you know when it says vertigo in the top left that means ah this you know, you might whether you may or may not know as a Customer a reader that that's actually DC Comics, but you know, you know, well, this is not Superman Batman, whatever.
Speaker 0: This is.
Speaker 0: you know, Sandman Why the Last Man Fables is why it's one of those guys, right?
Speaker 0: So that's that's the reason imprints exist.
Speaker 0: So vertigo as I just said is printed many historic all-time great comics over the years Like vertigo was a go-to for the good stuff, right?
Speaker 0: 1993 it was formed right and You know burger was.
Speaker 0: she was the Karen burger Karen burger, right?
Speaker 0: She was the editor-in-chief of vertigo comics basically during all the great times and we did several news bits about
Speaker 1: her
Speaker 0: Leaving and then going to Dark Horse to start burger books, which I guess is an imprint at Dark Horse Yeah, but they've only printed like not too many burger books.
Speaker 0: It's like I feel like all those books they have came up with number ones.
Speaker 0: They should have been coming up monthly like two or three.
Speaker 0: They aren't.
Speaker 0: it's like you go and look at the website for it And it's like there's not really too many comics coming out over there.
Speaker 0: It's disappointing really now.
Speaker 1: She definitely knows what's up, though, because I know she's like the best she tweeted.
Speaker 1: She's actually right like after.
Speaker 1: this was now and she tweeted and what she said was not quoting her exactly.
Speaker 1: Corporate thinking and creative risk-taking don't mix.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: DC nixing vertigo was a long time coming.
Speaker 0: Yep It was that was that that's the main news here is like they should have nixed it when she left.
Speaker 0: since she left vertigo has Been like this complete like nothing right?
Speaker 0: It's like they're reprinting the same nothings over and over again.
Speaker 0: They don't have new original content there.
Speaker 0: It's like I don't even understand why like I would open up the order form every month that I kept seeing vertigo there.
Speaker 0: And I'm like, why is vertigo still here?
Speaker 0: She left.
Speaker 0: They're not printing anything new or anything meaningful.
Speaker 0: Why do they even exist?
Speaker 0: who's working there?
Speaker 0: Why does it still exist?
Speaker 1: Also vertigo had a ton of scandals like one after another after she left.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'm sure.
Speaker 0: after she left Yeah, it was basically a shit show.
Speaker 0: Nothing, right?
Speaker 0: Well like in 2018 one of the people working on it had some sexual misconduct stuff.
Speaker 1: Some things got canceled.
Speaker 0: No surprises there.
Speaker 1: There was that issue with Batman's dick showing up.
Speaker 0: I didn't know about that.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna quote this to you.
Speaker 1: I think we talked about it on gig nights.
Speaker 1: DC has also struggled with public shock over mature content and comic books.
Speaker 1: in the fall of 2018 a quote production error that resulted in Batman's penis being visible in several panels of Batman damned number one.
Speaker 0: was that DC Comics or doesn't a vertigo?
Speaker 1: Yeah So this was DC having problems in general and the article seems to be implying that all of DC's scandals coupled with the issues with Vertigo meant that vertigo was just at best Baggage that could call even more attention to their problems.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so that's that just.
Speaker 0: it's finally done.
Speaker 0: and but you know, I guess Symbolically a great era in comics is over and that's that's the thing.
Speaker 1: I'm just looking to see if I can find Batman's penis.
Speaker 0: Yeah, go find picture of Batman's dick.
Speaker 0: You want to see it, right?
Speaker 0: That's probably all black and twisty anyway So or sharp and pointy, I don't know.
Speaker 0: What finally happened is Neon Genesis Evangelion, what are the greatest TV?
Speaker 0: Animations of all time in human history that was ever created?
Speaker 1: you may like Ava you may not.
Speaker 1: you may think it's brilliant.
Speaker 0: It's once again legally available.
Speaker 1: It's it's always been illegally in the United States of America But it does not matter what you think the fact that we're still talking about it.
Speaker 1: It is really really important.
Speaker 0: Anyway, it's legally available once again in North America.
Speaker 0: Thanks to Netflix You keep.
Speaker 0: you have Netflix app.
Speaker 0: you can open it and watch it.
Speaker 0: I Expected when they announced this that the release on Netflix would be imperfect.
Speaker 0: There would be something to complain about.
Speaker 0: we already knew that they were doing a new dub.
Speaker 0: I assume that that dub would have issues.
Speaker 1: I assume the dub would be better than the first dub though.
Speaker 0: Well, yes that I mean but still not as good as because any adults from that era are not right great.
Speaker 0: I assume that something was going to happen where they would fuck it up.
Speaker 0: But still I did not expect.
Speaker 0: I still expected it to be not so fucked up that I would tell people Yeah, just pirate it don't watch the Netflix one.
Speaker 0: Yeah But no, they have somehow managed to fuck it up.
Speaker 0: Well, you know not surprisingly but like more than expected right here the list of fuck-ups that I'm aware of number one The script is fucked up right.
Speaker 0: the subtitle dub script itself has been changed severely in several ways in very meaningful ways That make it noticeably inferior Less gay less correct.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, there are various Discussions online about why exactly this is.
Speaker 0: some blame it on the Japanese some blame it.
Speaker 1: You know a student common theme I see is that it was that it was the jet.
Speaker 1: someone who has the reins on the licensing agreement in Japan Wanted the script to be changed.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't know anyway, so that's that's one who knows why.
Speaker 0: it's uncertain But regardless it is changed and the script on the ATV one is better, right?
Speaker 0: to The biggest most important change that they have fucked up is they did not get the rights to use the song Fly me to the moon in the closing of the episode.
Speaker 1: that That's like what initial D was released without the bitchin music.
Speaker 0: right if you do not know without eurobeat There's no initial D. when you watch an episode of Evangelion at the end of the episode There's a closer and the animation in the closer is always the same and the song is always the same.
Speaker 0: the song Is fly me to the moon by Frank Sinatra, but you know They never use the Frank Sinatra rendition is always a cover song and each episode has a different cover song.
Speaker 0: There are 26 cover while 24.
Speaker 0: I don't know if the last two have it.
Speaker 0: I don't know, but there are different covers for every single episode.
Speaker 0: Some of them are only slightly different like I think like episode one and two are the same exact vocal track But like one has the strings and one doesn't.
Speaker 0: yeah, but there are still 20-something unique covers of the song.
Speaker 0: it's still a thing.
Speaker 1: It's a part of how you experience Evangelion.
Speaker 0: It is a significant thing even if you don't watch the full closer That comes.
Speaker 0: that song comes in at the end and is very meaningful and important To the show and in Japan they still included it, but in some other countries they did I think as well But not in the United States.
Speaker 0: they didn't pay whatever.
Speaker 0: they could have just paid the money.
Speaker 0: their Netflix Had the money.
Speaker 0: they chose not to considering how much they read for the license, right?
Speaker 0: There's some other song at the end and that's the main reason.
Speaker 0: I'll say just don't watch the Netflix one.
Speaker 0: or at least if you do go on YouTube There is a video that is literally all 20 whatever endings just in a row.
Speaker 1: now It's weird.
Speaker 1: this happens a lot with anime partly because the music licensing globally is completely fucked like it is Crazy hard to get global rights or to get rights sorted out across regions.
Speaker 0: just pay money.
Speaker 0: It's like it would make sense if it was a TV trying to do it.
Speaker 0: again I remember even if these doesn't even exist even if the East had that Oasis song and wasn't that speedgrapher?
Speaker 1: No speedgrapher also had a render and song.
Speaker 1: yeah Yeah, they had girls on film right and even these had the Oasis song that was the official like proper opener.
Speaker 1: But then they changed it to this like generic j-pop song because they didn't even have the rights in Japan in perpetuity Mm-hmm just pay yeah, if you're gonna do it you gotta pay.
Speaker 1: So in a little bit of a gig bite Emily, and I we started watching the watership down Netflix animated series, right?
Speaker 0: That's like.
Speaker 0: it's not the original movie or whatever.
Speaker 0: It's a series, and it's 3d animated, okay I didn't even know this is a thing.
Speaker 1: Oh, it's.
Speaker 1: so it's.
Speaker 1: it's okay.
Speaker 0: Is it just?
Speaker 0: or is it just the same story telling book?
Speaker 1: yeah few tweaks few changes.
Speaker 0: read the book.
Speaker 1: Yeah, very it follows the book.
Speaker 1: few tweaks few changes.
Speaker 0: Cover the whole book.
Speaker 0: is it like a full thing or you got to wait for it to finish?
Speaker 1: I mean, it's Netflix.
Speaker 1: they release everything all in one go full thing.
Speaker 0: so if you watch all of the things that they have put Up you're gonna get the whole book pretty much.
Speaker 1: Yeah, okay Not not many.
Speaker 0: oh, I mean it's not a long bug.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we watched the first one and what I want to say about it is it's pretty good.
Speaker 1: It's probably worth watching the voice acting and like.
Speaker 1: the script is great.
Speaker 1: The pacing is pretty good But the rabbit animation is pretty garbage Like they got a skim somewhere.
Speaker 0: I mean it seems like they're skimping somewhere on all this stuff.
Speaker 1: right skimp on not licensing the songs Skimp on the animations like the opening bid and the trailer and everything looks great, but then when you watch it They don't look like rabbits.
Speaker 1: They look like hairs like Like they look not like the way a rabbit would look.
Speaker 0: well They probably outsource the animation to like some foreign.
Speaker 0: You know place It wasn't doing research who knows.
Speaker 1: but beyond that the rabbits are drawn wrong like they have foot pads like their dogs And they don't act at all like rabbits.
Speaker 1: They move like someone who is vaguely familiar with how dogs and cats move and has never actually seen a rabbit before.
Speaker 1: So they dig and move and act like dogs and cats kind of randomly like they're almost a puppycat sort of situation.
Speaker 1: but at no point do they actually look and act like the movements or the way a rabbit would move.
Speaker 1: and The backgrounds are great and like the scenery everything looks great except the rabbits themselves.
Speaker 1: they kind of look like cutscenes from a single a video game.
Speaker 0: speaking of Animals that are animated right the mouse guard movie.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, was we all know this is already old news.
Speaker 0: is that it was gonna be a thing.
Speaker 0: They had a cast lined up They had all kinds of money the other sizzle reel which was like up.
Speaker 0: They had all kinds of stuff going on and then Disney bought Fox and then they canceled the mouse guard movie.
Speaker 0: So it never happened, but today Many people released many of the production materials For the mouse guard movie including this like I guess treatment of some kind where they use I think a video game engine.
Speaker 0: They used unreal turn unreal engine.
Speaker 1: It's hard to say unreal without saying tournament.
Speaker 1: if you were born Early enough to have played the early on real games.
Speaker 0: they use the unreal engine to create like this animated I guess short.
Speaker 0: that would.
Speaker 0: they would show to people to like convince them to invest in the mouse guard movie.
Speaker 0: and there's a big Disclaimer at the start of the video that's like hey We made this with unreal.
Speaker 0: the actual movie will look nothing like this.
Speaker 0: We'll send it off to weta to actually animate.
Speaker 1: Yep, it's basically the movie was in pre-production But it had not entered.
Speaker 0: principal photographer right as far as I know.
Speaker 0: like they had all these actors signed on like big You know big names like famous actors to be the voice actors But nobody recorded like a single line of dialogue or they didn't actually shoot anything for real.
Speaker 0: But they were getting close when they were canceled right there basically canceled as far along as like.
Speaker 0: like.
Speaker 0: We're all ready to actually do stuff and start spending all the money.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: Don't spend all the money.
Speaker 0: We're just kidding Yeah, right such a shame Preparation.
Speaker 0: like you pack all your stuff to go on a trip and then you just Refund your plane tickets and your refund your hotel and you stay home.
Speaker 1: You know I did that once I was flying to Chicago and the flight was delayed by a lot, and I just went to the Delta desk.
Speaker 1: I was like you know what fuck it.
Speaker 1: I'm just not going to Chicago give me a refund.
Speaker 0: Anyway, but the point is all the all the stuff has.
Speaker 0: all these materials of great interest have been you know released Onto.
Speaker 0: you know the Instagram accounts of you know people.
Speaker 1: yep I feel it is a shame because if you haven't read the mouse guard comics, which is sure they're fantastic And I feel like that story as a movie would have been fantastic I think it's just you know.
Speaker 0: I think the reason these materials is great because hopefully just bring some more attention to people to go Buy and read Mouse guard cuz.
Speaker 1: I can't say that that's what happened here But there's a long trend of whenever there's an executive shakeup or a merger and acquisition in TV or Hollywood of any kind what tends to happen is all the projects that were championed by the people who are no longer there Or from the company that was bought.
Speaker 1: get canceled because you can't have the people that you're getting rid of Have a thing that would have been successful.
Speaker 1: It's all like weird corporate politics that has nothing to do with the viability of the actual projects themselves.
Speaker 1: Get canceled.
Speaker 0: someone with a lot of money should just buy this.
Speaker 0: I'm sure you can buy it.
Speaker 0: I'll sell it to you for a pile.
Speaker 1: I would sign on to executive produce, but I haven't cost.
Speaker 0: You know it cost millions, but Disney would.
Speaker 0: they're not gonna make it.
Speaker 0: They will definitely just give it to someone for millions of dollars.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like I if I was able to I would put money behind this.
Speaker 1: not all the money But like I would invest in this, but I am not.
Speaker 0: if you were another movie studio You could like trade something to Disney for it, right?
Speaker 0: I'm sure it's possible.
Speaker 1: trade you two marbles and this pre-tune gum I found.
Speaker 1: yeah but anyway, it's time for Things of the day, this is just a Twitter thread.
Speaker 1: I 100% believe that this happened as described.
Speaker 1: I've experienced a similar thing where I worked at a company.
Speaker 0: this happened or not it doesn't matter because Even it like it might not have it like if this case one didn't happen.
Speaker 1: this has still happened.
Speaker 0: This has happened many times basically or something close to it.
Speaker 1: The story is basically big.
Speaker 1: company hires a bunch of interns and the people who are supposed to give those interns work are Not good at their own jobs.
Speaker 1: Yes, so they give the interns like.
Speaker 1: they don't understand computers.
Speaker 1: so they give the interns work that they think will take 12 weeks to do and Interns finish this work in 12 minutes by writing a Python script.
Speaker 1: Yes, so now interns are like well What do you want me to do next?
Speaker 1: and no one ever gives them anything to do mm-hmm?
Speaker 1: So this is the story of a hero.
Speaker 0: right the company wants to have an internship program But they don't know how to like.
Speaker 0: give Continuously give people.
Speaker 0: I've had jobs from a full-time employee, and they can't give me work.
Speaker 1: I worked at a place in New York where I spent no interest in firing me or getting rid of me.
Speaker 1: I was a full-time employee with full benefits getting paid for six months to do nothing Mm-hmm nothing.
Speaker 1: I would literally go to other project managers other bosses other departments.
Speaker 1: be like yo You want got some routers you want me to configure.
Speaker 1: you want me to do anything.
Speaker 1: any work now?
Speaker 1: Do you care if I just go to City Island like lay on the beach all day?
Speaker 1: No really okay?
Speaker 1: And eventually I quit cuz that's that'll drive you crazy.
Speaker 0: They will but you're happy several times.
Speaker 1: interns have even less to lose.
Speaker 0: It's so real.
Speaker 1: so the hero of this story this Twitter thread shows What to do in this situation.
Speaker 1: if you are a hero if you are a legend?
Speaker 1: And that's all I'm gonna say about it.
Speaker 1: It's not a long Twitter thread.
Speaker 1: Just read it alright.
Speaker 0: So here is some stop-motion animations for Wednesday.
Speaker 0: right this person did a very clever stop-motion animation I guess the person is Daniel cloud campos and what they did is rather than use you know clay or action figures or I saw a great stop-motion animation at the LGBT animation thing.
Speaker 1: we I still can't find.
Speaker 0: I gotta find the list of pride animation where they used like you know crocheted characters rice and knitted.
Speaker 0: You know things for their their animation.
Speaker 0: anyway Instead of any of that they have used just a bunch of clothing on a floor.
Speaker 0: They bought a whole bunch of clothing, and they got the camera aimed at the ground.
Speaker 0: It looks like a wooden floor in some house, and they just lay the clothing flat on the floor and move it around.
Speaker 0: So it looks like you know people are moving, but obviously the it's just empty clothes with so looks like there's ghosts in them.
Speaker 1: I think what really makes it work is the hat like that hat.
Speaker 0: well the hat lets you know that there's a head there right.
Speaker 0: It adds expression to the head movement because without the if you just had the suit with no hat You couldn't have any expression in the head area.
Speaker 0: It would only be expression of the arm and leg movement.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: so you can see some of the characters that don't need head movement expression.
Speaker 0: don't have a hat right.
Speaker 0: But see like that one has the hoodie.
Speaker 0: yep, but anyway regardless This is a really awesome stop-motion animation.
Speaker 0: that is about what.
Speaker 0: four or five minutes long Yeah, and worth your four or five minutes.
Speaker 0: You're probably whatever you're gonna do with those four or five minutes.
Speaker 0: It's like what.
Speaker 0: listen to geek nights.
Speaker 0: This is better than way use of your five minutes than listen to fucking geek nights.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so in the meta moment the geek night's book club book was pages of pain.
Speaker 0: Oh, that's the thing I forgot to do.
Speaker 1: you didn't update the page.
Speaker 1: So there might be a new book club book that we're about to read, but I don't know.
Speaker 0: It's.
Speaker 0: it's the tale of Genji the first novel ever created by human beings ever.
Speaker 0: Well one human being.
Speaker 1: yep, it's uh Historic.
Speaker 1: it'll be fun.
Speaker 1: There's no Emily Wilson translation of this.
Speaker 1: we can't have the kind of fun we had with the Odyssey.
Speaker 0: no, but it is.
Speaker 0: I'm still recommending the best possible translation according to my 20 minutes of research and that is the translation found in the penguin classics Deluxe unabridged edition.
Speaker 0: yep, not the non deluxe penguin classics because that one is abridged.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we don't use abridged anything.
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 0: No baby mode here.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you're playing you're playing Scrabble.
Speaker 1: nope unabridged.
Speaker 1: Oh, Edie.
Speaker 1: Let's go.
Speaker 1: That's right All right, and we got no conventions until packs.
Speaker 0: so X West Labor Day weekend is actually Surprisingly soon.
Speaker 0: it is out to be July and then there's August and then there's bags Yep, and then after that eight weeks till pack.
Speaker 1: after that There's a packs like every month and then mag fast and then more packs.
Speaker 0: also a new anime season should be starting very soon.
Speaker 0: We need to judge right about now, but apparently rim has to go to some crazy picnic.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so a little judge Don't worry.
Speaker 1: Hmm.
Speaker 1: I actually got to go back and watch some of the anime We judged because I remember that a lot of it looked really good.
Speaker 0: I wanted to watch one punch man season two, but I couldn't find it anyway.
Speaker 1: Yeah All right.
Speaker 1: So as you may recall Natasha Alegre put together this BN puppycat as a pilot.
Speaker 0: Yep It was like 2013 on YouTube on the Frederator channel, which I'm sure like how those organizations line up.
Speaker 0: like.
Speaker 0: what is the relationship between?
Speaker 0: like Cartoon Network This was cartoon hangover venture time Frederator cartoon hangover like.
Speaker 0: what are all those?
Speaker 0: I don't understand how they're all what they all do differently.
Speaker 1: So it was really weird and cute and funny and the voice acting was great and everyone liked it.
Speaker 0: Like what's there's even bravest warriors and being puppycat, right?
Speaker 1: Well, I mean, there's two completely different saying.
Speaker 0: how are they connected?
Speaker 0: production wise company wise?
Speaker 1: Yeah, that is all discoverable by reading some of the things we'll link to but we're not gonna talk about all those details.
Speaker 0: Anyway, BN puppycat got put up there as a pilot.
Speaker 0: We watched it.
Speaker 0: It was amazing Yep, compared to all the other pilots they put up there.
Speaker 0: It was probably the best one after bravest warriors.
Speaker 0: I mean we could better than that dolphin president guy, whatever.
Speaker 1: It's it's notable when I think back We actually quote BN puppycat kind of a lot.
Speaker 0: It's not too many quotes, but the quote you took too long.
Speaker 1: Now, you know something's gone.
Speaker 0: That's pretty much as what happened.
Speaker 0: That's pretty much the only one now whenever I'm feeling a little bargaining.
Speaker 1: I tend to do my guts my guts.
Speaker 1: Anyway, I tend to say that.
Speaker 0: so It was really cool.
Speaker 0: And then they did a Kickstarter to produce all the episodes.
Speaker 0: Yep, and I gave money to that Kickstarter.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I remember going to the launch party and that was a good time and then there was a bunch of drama.
Speaker 0: Because like they're making episodes, but the way they distributed the episode Well, the production was like delayed which is fine.
Speaker 0: That's what I expect from like a cartoon that's not on TV or anything, right?
Speaker 0: I didn't expect it to be out really quickly.
Speaker 0: I was patient.
Speaker 0: There's even an official comic book by the way.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but The production took a long time.
Speaker 0: delays, whatever not a big deal.
Speaker 0: I'm okay with that.
Speaker 0: I'll just wait till it's all done.
Speaker 1: But unless you like TV there was no way to watch it.
Speaker 0: Well, they put out the episode.
Speaker 0: I don't think was on TV TV.
Speaker 0: They put out the episodes Sporadically, right which is that it's like.
Speaker 0: I don't care if I had to wait a year two years.
Speaker 0: Just put them out, you know on a consistent thing so I can write.
Speaker 0: but they put out like one or two.
Speaker 0: Then there's a big gap and then they weren't on YouTube.
Speaker 0: They put him on like some VRV or some kind of other site or something And I wasn't gonna sign up for that weird ass other side.
Speaker 1: and then Bravest Warriors got moved there And it kind of fell off the radar.
Speaker 1: So basically
Speaker 0: because they put it on a weird site, even though I had kick-started it It was like a huge pain to watch even if I tried and then I found I knew that it was like done Ish at least the first season but it was just too much of a hassle to find it all.
Speaker 0: so I didn't Like one or two episodes.
Speaker 1: of most people who have seen it have only seen the pilot and then the first four episodes.
Speaker 0: I think that's what I had seen.
Speaker 1: Yeah, because the first of our episodes are the food one the creepy farmer one.
Speaker 1: The one true is the beach.
Speaker 1: Right the beach one is very like I like the other.
Speaker 0: the beach one is is the the the pretty Patrick, right?
Speaker 0: I remember.
Speaker 0: that's basically what I remember is getting up to pretty Patrick and then not seeing anything after and then like a few people Seeing the cats one where she becomes the pet of that bathhouse of giving me spirited away.
Speaker 0: Yeah, oh my.
Speaker 1: and then pretty much no one was able to see the rest of them unless they backed it on Kickstarter.
Speaker 0: I did back it on Kickstarter.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you could have watched two more episodes.
Speaker 0: You sure I could have but anyway the point and then there were more for more that you basically just couldn't watch.
Speaker 0: Anyway, but the point is now or at least as of not super recently But relatively recently as of December 1st of 2018, right?
Speaker 0: So not so like a half a year ago.
Speaker 0: It was all on YouTube in a single video all ten episodes an hour long effectively a movie Right an hour long movie.
Speaker 0: They just squished all the ten episodes back to back to back and you get anyone who was YouTube so everyone could just watch it.
Speaker 0: Yep, and we finally got around to doing that.
Speaker 1: I'm hearing tell that this YouTube video is blocked in Europe.
Speaker 0: That's interesting.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna find out right there another place in Europe to watch it.
Speaker 1: That's one of the stream just said that there's no way to watch this stuff in Europe.
Speaker 0: All right, that is interesting.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'm sad.
Speaker 0: So I'm sure it is piratable.
Speaker 0: regardless.
Speaker 0: We're gonna review being puppycat because there are ten episodes in order to crank out an easy Wednesday episode.
Speaker 1: I spent one hour watching it and there we go Yep, so we'll avoid spoilers to the end because there are actually things to spoil.
Speaker 0: I didn't think there would be but I guess there are.
Speaker 1: uh Being puppycat is really interesting because after the like pilot like there is a consistent Surreal nature to the show that continues all the way through to episode 10 and I really appreciate that not in the way that like bravest warriors is surreal and like It skips around a lot and never really gives you any context but more in the way like it's very dreamlike And it like it's very inconsistent in that It's hard to tell what's important or like where the show's getting bravest.
Speaker 0: right.
Speaker 0: bravest warriors is is Sort of that like we're showing you literally crazy shit, and you're begging for explanation.
Speaker 0: like yep I need to understand where this time Lord guy.
Speaker 0: He's actually the character for the future I guess but that's not a full explanation.
Speaker 0: What's up with the horse, right?
Speaker 0: They show you the crazy shit literally happening and you need it explained and being puppycat this weird shit Happening, but there aren't really too many questions.
Speaker 0: like.
Speaker 0: you're not asking too many questions of this show the only questions You know.
Speaker 1: what I was asking is where.
Speaker 1: what is puppycat right?
Speaker 0: What's what is puppycat?
Speaker 1: Is he the pirate dude or not?
Speaker 1: pretty sure he is yeah or related to the right?
Speaker 1: I feel like it's not gonna be that straight forward, right?
Speaker 0: What's the deal with this?
Speaker 0: others how they get to space and do things and get money.
Speaker 0: yeah like u.s.
Speaker 0: Early I guess America Island money.
Speaker 0: wherever they are they live on an island.
Speaker 0: whatever money They get is clearly like usable right, but they get it from a TV.
Speaker 0: like and is you know?
Speaker 1: What's the explanation of that setting and that setting like that TV and the temp job?
Speaker 1: She does.
Speaker 0: there is 10, but 10 bot has deeply disturbing Undertones.
Speaker 1: yeah once the incinerator everybody not just that but like all the jobs are really really broken fucked up things.
Speaker 0: Well it's also the jobs aren't Explicitly just like there's no task.
Speaker 0: It's like go to this place do your job, and it's like What do I do there like it doesn't matter if you succeed right.
Speaker 0: sometimes when they get there?
Speaker 0: Someone will tell them what to do because they've.
Speaker 1: they're hiring a temp, but oh apparently the video.
Speaker 1: We just were we watched is Viewable in Europe.
Speaker 1: so there we go okay, so now this person is able to watch it for the first time.
Speaker 0: there you go.
Speaker 0: Congratulations Europe good job.
Speaker 1: I'm happy for you But the jobs are well, it's sort of like imagine Terrible secret of space intergalactic temp jobs.
Speaker 1: meaning these are jobs No one actually wants to do right.
Speaker 0: so some people just in space Must put jobs they need done into this temp agency like this.
Speaker 1: I'm a creepy farmer who needs to murder someone when someone come and be murdered.
Speaker 0: so they put the jobs in and this robot Hires the cat wearing a bell.
Speaker 0: it sends a letter to get it to come to space and do the job and play.
Speaker 1: That's it.
Speaker 1: We don't know how.
Speaker 1: where puppycat really came from.
Speaker 0: yeah We assume puppy cats the space prince from the pilot.
Speaker 1: and puppy cat is apparently tasked with these temp jobs and has been ignoring them I guess or Apparently has been doing well.
Speaker 0: I mean if you can.
Speaker 0: just.
Speaker 0: it seems like they can just choose like when they want to do when they can do one And if they don't they don't have to.
Speaker 0: there's like a million.
Speaker 0: they can just whenever they want do attempt job.
Speaker 0: Well base someone else I guess is also doing temp jobs You know with the same policy based on.
Speaker 1: you ever see anyone else doing based on the events of the one?
Speaker 1: where?
Speaker 1: Does all the side quests to destroy the eye in the sky?
Speaker 0: puppycat had been doing these previously yes And I guess other people might also be doing them.
Speaker 1: yeah I. What's interesting though is that a lot of these jobs seem like they would have ended in the death of the person who did them.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if you actually do them and it was interesting that be continued to survive these jobs So there's that.
Speaker 1: but so there's like this surreal and Sinister like undertones everywhere coupled with a Very vague setting a very dreamlike setting right it's like they're in this island Which is somewhat Western society.
Speaker 1: ish right and there's people doing people stuff And it's all seems pretty normal except for you look at like all this weird stuff like the kid is literally her landlord And that seems a little weird.
Speaker 1: yeah, but it's kind of working.
Speaker 0: the puppycat that speaks of the Vocaloid voice.
Speaker 1: Understand puppycat except be but at the same time the crab that talks.
Speaker 1: yeah But only puppycat can understand that grab cleavage like but it's.
Speaker 1: but it's not just that crab cuz.
Speaker 1: look there's the bird and there's the bug and puppycat understands them all.
Speaker 1: yeah, no one else does and People think puppycat is weird.
Speaker 1: like this isn't an anime situation.
Speaker 1: We're like the weird stuff happens and everyone's cool with it.
Speaker 1: when the Deckard ends up joining be in one of these missions He's completely freaking out and can't deal with right, so that's what the thing is.
Speaker 0: it's like usually when you have a superhero Disguise situation or a transport to another world situation.
Speaker 0: It's either like name of eska flown It's like okay.
Speaker 0: We go to the other world and everything happens there.
Speaker 1: Yep, right But even eska flown I had those moments were like.
Speaker 1: that is weird because there's this one scene that to this day stands out to Me as being an unaddressed thing where her pager goes off.
Speaker 1: pager cuz you're 90s even though she's on But the pager goes off while she's in the fantasy world makes no sense And you're like no cell towers there And you're like what.
Speaker 1: and then a bunch of drama happens, and then you've kind of forget about it.
Speaker 1: But then at the end of the episode it just cuts back to earth And it just this dude is trying to call her on the phone Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: so things like that don't happen in being puppycat.
Speaker 1: It's just right, but there's also right.
Speaker 0: But there's also when you have a secret super thing right cuz there's basically B is like a secret Superhero in a way and that like she you know or she goes and does like you know these other Semi heroic things with costumes and powers.
Speaker 1: I guess kind of she gets the powers from temp pot.
Speaker 0: I guess so, but regardless.
Speaker 0: It's not like Superman where he's right there with all the people.
Speaker 0: She's not like doing all this shit in front of all the people like Deckard and whatever she like leaves Earth goes to a separate place and comes back.
Speaker 0: so the only thing any earth people would notice is like mysterious Disappearance of B, and then she comes back, but she's not even trying to hide it.
Speaker 1: She just doesn't tell people yep, and she was also initially freaked out by it like this is not something She was aware of until puppycat like dragged her into it.
Speaker 0: yep, so all those things together That makes it like a unique un unique thing.
Speaker 1: yeah, but all these factors together.
Speaker 1: Just make it a Really dreamlike surreal and interesting show to watch because I can't think of other things.
Speaker 1: I've seen that are like it The clothes like the characters act and talk in a very adventure timey way yep And the backgrounds in the setting are very Steven University right it's like.
Speaker 0: B Is sort of you know wacky kooky sort of like a you know like a like a Jake or a tree trunk?
Speaker 1: Very important point.
Speaker 0: if you watch this recording girl is much more grounded like a princess bubblegum is but even then she's got there.
Speaker 1: So there is weird surreal crap that everyone does know about like the whole wrestling subplot with her.
Speaker 1: like the world is weird and in the weird world B puppy and Puppycat are pulled into an even weirder world.
Speaker 1: The weirder world is very video game like.
Speaker 0: yeah, there is actually a world that like is a video game.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think most of the other worlds are parodies of things in a way.
Speaker 0: Yeah the one with the plant is Slightly little prince.
Speaker 0: ish in that it's like a tiny planet with things living on it.
Speaker 1: Oh, that's the other thing all the time.
Speaker 1: I quote the.
Speaker 1: are you sad.
Speaker 1: Do you want a nap?
Speaker 1: Do you want a snack?
Speaker 0: anyway Though these the cat thing is clearly spirited away.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know is a hundred percent spirited away.
Speaker 0: homage.
Speaker 0: the video game one is just video game Right doing all the side quests yep
Speaker 1: But in terms of like the show itself and like why to watch it in Steve giant
Speaker 0: kitchen in a ring thing
Speaker 1: Aside from all the like fun surreal stuff and the plot bits We're not gonna talk about until the end because they're kind of spoilery and the show goes in directions You might not have expected.
Speaker 1: but the voice acting in the script is just really funny like Character way good be as a character is just really really really funny.
Speaker 0: Yeah, also that the you know like I said before the idea to use a vocaloid to voice puppycat is I think unique.
Speaker 0: I don't think any other character No one else has used it for voice usually use it just for music and they don't use it in a like normal consistent way.
Speaker 0: It's just really funny right and it's not overused or bad or awkward Sounding or anything like that and no one else is like, you know, if anyone else tried to do it would be like, ah Really?
Speaker 0: You're just gonna steal that idea, but it also gets saved the money on production.
Speaker 1: I have to hire an actor, but I guess what I would say is that piece of software all the weird stuff that happens.
Speaker 1: you know we talk about this when we talk about shows like utana or even Evangelion to an extent where weird anime crap happens or weird nonsense happens and Like you as a viewer sort of excuse it as well.
Speaker 1: This is just a cartoon.
Speaker 1: So weird stuff happens and then later the cartoons like no that stuff's weird, right?
Speaker 0: Like there's the kid who's a landlord and you're like, oh, okay, you know That's just a weird thing.
Speaker 0: and that the kid landlord and it's like nope Actually, the kid is forced to be the landlord because his mom is like some space princesses in a coma or something Like.
Speaker 0: there's a serious real plot there by the way, that's the thing that happens in a real life.
Speaker 0: I read a story about a kid whose parents like something happened to them I forget if what it was but like he had to run the motel even though he was like a kid he ran it like His whole life.
Speaker 1: I remember I saw years ago.
Speaker 1: There was a movie.
Speaker 1: It's a sort of dramatization but this happened in Japan where this woman just Left her three kids in the apartment and they just had to get by for a long time by themselves.
Speaker 1: And they did mostly but like one of them died.
Speaker 1: it was a really tragic situation, but that does happen.
Speaker 1: and Being puppycat does that do ten a thing?
Speaker 1: You see this landlord like haha the kids a landlord that this is just a cartoon thing.
Speaker 1: and then later It's like no that kids alone.
Speaker 1: That kid is alone eating candy and his mom is in a coma in the other room, right?
Speaker 0: He's fixing the toilet with like a weird hammer or whatever.
Speaker 0: It's like no he actually fixed the toilet.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So what I would say is if you've not actually watched all this being puppycat as you watch it Pay attention to the weird stuff.
Speaker 1: and I'm not saying this is gonna be an Evangelion Montana not even good, but I'm saying there is a thread.
Speaker 1: there are multiple threads.
Speaker 1: There is a plot There is an under the undertones.
Speaker 1: You're you're feeling getting hints of they're real and there's a lot of Darker or more interesting stuff.
Speaker 1: that is pretty clearly foreshadowed if you're trying to look for it.
Speaker 0: There's quite a bit going on for an hour of animation.
Speaker 1: Yeah a lot more than you might have expected Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: It's also like the human plot right of Deckard, you know, does he stay, you know Does he stay and take care of you know?
Speaker 0: is he likes being in the town?
Speaker 0: He likes the people in the town.
Speaker 0: But he's you know He's giving up on his dream career of being a chef if he goes to the cooking school.
Speaker 1: and even without the more surreal stuff Like that's a pretty compelling not even like he's not even struggling to apply.
Speaker 0: He got accepted.
Speaker 0: He just has to send in the okay.
Speaker 1: I accept I'm coming Yep, and B has to struggle with.
Speaker 1: I don't want to hold him back But at the same time I want him to stay cuz.
Speaker 1: I like him cuz.
Speaker 1: I got him ice for his junk.
Speaker 1: that one time Yep, and it's just.
Speaker 1: it's like now that I've seen a season of it.
Speaker 1: That's complete.
Speaker 1: It's a really solid show and it's going somewhere.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: Like it's legit going somewhere based on the events of the last episode Mm-hmm, which before we get into spoiler territory The other thing I'll say is that if you didn't notice we even talked about this on geek nights.
Speaker 1: Cuz that happened last year.
Speaker 1: Actually almost exactly one year ago It was announced that being puppycat is getting a second season Produced by Pokemons.
Speaker 1: Oh LM.
Speaker 1: Okay, like full-on production full half-hour episodes full season.
Speaker 0: How many emphasis?
Speaker 0: I don't remember these eggs?
Speaker 1: I've Somewhere between 13 and 26, I think but it doesn't actually say but they are half-hour long episodes.
Speaker 1: The show is called being puppycat lazy in space.
Speaker 1: It is season two.
Speaker 1: It just picks up from where season one left off.
Speaker 0: So that sounds good.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I was Lee supposed to come out in 2019.
Speaker 0: If you didn't notice it's 2019.
Speaker 1: So they don't have a lot of time left.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so we'll see.
Speaker 1: but it's a like.
Speaker 1: this is a real-deal show and now is the time to watch being puppycat season one.
Speaker 0: So wait until lazy in space actually comes out.
Speaker 0: Then you can just be like whoosh.
Speaker 1: Thing is if you watch being puppycat season one kind of like.
Speaker 1: when I first got into a ten of the anime I saw like the first few episodes and I was like, yeah, this show seems generic and not good like.
Speaker 1: I'll watch it later Maybe I don't care.
Speaker 1: But then I saw a couple of random episodes from later in the show and I was like, oh it's going somewhere It's going somewhere.
Speaker 1: good I gotta figure out how the show I saw one episode of gets to this other episode that I saw.
Speaker 1: So if you're on the fence about this show watch this YouTube video cuz we gotta be on the fence about a show.
Speaker 0: It's an hour long.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's an hour of cartoons and At the end while you're eating dinner like I did and then you when you're done eating dinner go back to playing video games.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so, uh, if you didn't watch it yet like spoilers spoilers spoiler because we're gonna talk about it.
Speaker 1: We're going to spoil the.
Speaker 1: the secret.
Speaker 0: There's only once the thing about the secret.
Speaker 0: right is pretty much only one secret in the whole.
Speaker 1: It's really foreshadowed.
Speaker 1: every episode has a bunch of clues.
Speaker 0: it is heavily foreshadowed but Unlike other things right?
Speaker 0: For example, when you're what you watch a show there's questions.
Speaker 0: you're asking Yeah, like there's mysteries presented to the audience and the audience is like I want it that explained.
Speaker 0: How is it tenable?
Speaker 0: keep going with utenna?
Speaker 0: Yeah, how does that elevator work?
Speaker 0: Yep, how these rings work?
Speaker 0: Who's the end of the world?
Speaker 1: What's in that castle?
Speaker 1: Later the horse is gonna come.
Speaker 0: what is up with that, right?
Speaker 0: You're kind of showing you stuff and not explaining it and you ask about it being puppycat this one main mystery.
Speaker 0: You never ask about it.
Speaker 0: They foreshadow it heavily.
Speaker 0: It's not like some thing that doesn't make any.
Speaker 0: Let's back up a little bit with utenna, but you're never asking this question because they're not you know.
Speaker 0: You're asking instead about puppy guys puppy cats the weird thing.
Speaker 0: that's unexplained.
Speaker 1: So with utenna when you watch the show the first time as you may recall from a rotenna series We're talking about this in detail.
Speaker 1: There's a bunch of questions You're asking.
Speaker 1: later in the show the show turns it around and says yeah Here's a question.
Speaker 1: You weren't asking that you should have been and then it like in it like doubles down on the stuff.
Speaker 1: You weren't thinking about being puppycat kind of does that?
Speaker 1: you weren't asking about B?
Speaker 0: You're right asking about puppy cat.
Speaker 0: cuz puppy cat is unexplained.
Speaker 0: It's a puppy and a cat and it talks and it came from space and it does mission Kind of like a Escaflowne though like a man.
Speaker 1: like Escaflowne is about a normal girl like it's transported to a magical world.
Speaker 1: All your questions are about the magical world.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and you're not like.
Speaker 1: what's Hitomi's deal?
Speaker 1: Like she's just a girl who like got caught up in magic gem.
Speaker 1: But then at the end of the show Escaflowne even without spoiling anything goes back and like yeah You probably should have been asking about why this one particular girl anyway, so Spoilers.
Speaker 0: Isaac Newton said so right you're not asking about B. Everything about B is relatively explained throughout the course of the show, right?
Speaker 0: She's a lazy not so good at too many things girl who's kind of kooky and crazy.
Speaker 0: So you can understand how come she can't hold a job or take care of herself.
Speaker 0: that well Yeah, she had a dad but the dad is dead or missing or something.
Speaker 0: You don't know anything about her mom, but I mean that's just RPGs.
Speaker 0: There's no mom.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right You know, she lives alone in this town.
Speaker 1: She's does friend, but it's a clever misdirection of right.
Speaker 0: It's like.
Speaker 0: it's like.
Speaker 0: okay, you know, we know we can see what her deal is, right?
Speaker 0: But you know, we're not like, you know There are some things in there that you could get more information about like what exactly happened to the dad.
Speaker 0: Where is mom?
Speaker 0: is there?
Speaker 0: right, but you know, you're not deeply asking about those because they're not terrible secrets of space They're just you know, sort of just general things.
Speaker 0: They're they're fine You're okay with just going with it, but I do it's often done.
Speaker 1: Well, like a lot of the good media I've thought of like Utena and Eska Flon are both examples where the question you weren't asking ends up being very Interesting and then in retrospect you realize additional things about the show right because I was going back through the show.
Speaker 1: after the revelation I noticed like one Her house is really weird like really weird.
Speaker 1: other people's houses in the show are not that weird.
Speaker 1: there's a lot of weird computer crap and The dead box and all those things that all makes sense.
Speaker 1: now She's repeatedly like she's very afraid of getting wet.
Speaker 1: That makes a lot of sense now.
Speaker 1: Yeah, she's really really strong like a co strong.
Speaker 0: Yep, that was.
Speaker 1: I didn't even think anything about that head.
Speaker 0: No I barely even noticed it.
Speaker 0: the first thing is that at the beginning of the earliest episodes they talk about her like not growing up.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right Literally, right.
Speaker 0: and I was like.
Speaker 0: I was like, oh, I think she literally she must have some kind of thing.
Speaker 0: She literally doesn't grow up, but it's like.
Speaker 0: I didn't care about it too much But I did.
Speaker 0: I did notice it and the first I didn't notice it like in retrospect.
Speaker 0: It was clever because it's it right away.
Speaker 1: She's kind of a weird loser who is not growing up and like maybe we'll hold back other people who are growing up But in the sense of growing up to become an adult not in the sense of she is not physically changing and that's weird Right.
Speaker 0: I think I think I got the impression even on the first go that she was not literally not growing up But I didn't really care too much about why or whatever.
Speaker 1: and then like she understands puppycat But no one else does makes a little more sense.
Speaker 1: Maybe depending on what puppycat is.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: Yeah anyway The dad box which you discover like the only show with you like one time on in the birthday episode.
Speaker 1: Yep Which is like the birthday episode.
Speaker 0: It's like my dad made me this box.
Speaker 0: you learn about the dad every year.
Speaker 1: It gives me a piece of candy and you learn.
Speaker 0: Okay, dad was clearly some guy who was like Technological cuz he made like this whole arcade full of awesome games and her house is full of like old weird real to real Looking mainframe computer.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like her dresser or something her closet like is a mainframe thing.
Speaker 0: She opens it and right.
Speaker 1: Yep, but it's like when she when she cries her tears like are weird.
Speaker 1: Mmm, I just clicked on I saw a frame and I remembered that like she cries at one point and it zooms in and the tear Like falls to the ground and shatters.
Speaker 0: Mmm Isn't that?
Speaker 0: I thought that was cold, uh Well, maybe maybe anyway Looks a lot like the bits that come out of dad box like on her birthday gives her like this candy and she just shares It whatever.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like oh the you know, the dad was clearly some sciency, dude he made an arcade and he made this other stuff.
Speaker 0: and then At the end of the show when they reveal the spoiler that she's actually like some kind of robot.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like she's small wonder it's that like she's the small wonder girl, right like straight up.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like.
Speaker 0: it's like.
Speaker 0: oh that makes perfect sense.
Speaker 0: I wasn't asking but now that you told me the answer Yes, I can see that that is absolutely makes perfect sense.
Speaker 1: Well, so this is way back when I was like there is no mom.
Speaker 0: The dad was a solo dude who made a robot girl.
Speaker 1: I don't remember the fullness of this conversation but I was actually at the launch party talking to Natasha about the show like we're just hanging out and She said something.
Speaker 1: she referenced small wonder in casual conversation Mm-hmm and that in retrospect makes sense in the context of being puppycat because she's just like this girl, but yep I like.
Speaker 1: and it also makes sense now because you like I love that scene the scene where it's revealed because you just hear that like Chunking.
Speaker 0: no, she has all these weird dreams, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, and the dreams and whenever she gets caught like ribbons come out of her and it seemed like a rule, right?
Speaker 0: I thought it was like a dream thing when it happened.
Speaker 0: It's like no that's what happens if she actually She's literally made of like these weird components.
Speaker 1: But just like you hear that chunk and she like makes a weird look and then the ribbons come out of the black hole Then she pull her hands pulls her hands out and they're just mangled.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm and Deckard sees it like that secret is out now and Deckard is freaked out by it And then they don't actually see each other again in season one.
Speaker 1: But he's not that freaked out because he wrote her that letter.
Speaker 1: He made like.
Speaker 1: he wants to say something to her.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: I The princess girl and the kid and the jellyfish story.
Speaker 1: that is Clearly similar to the space pirate story who may or may not be puppycat.
Speaker 0: Yeah I'm hoping that you know It's like the.
Speaker 0: the second season focuses on the mystery of puppy because that's the question I actually am asking right?
Speaker 1: It's like I really want to know what's up with her dad Is B and her dad and like he's just a dude who made a robot but why did he make her what for once?
Speaker 0: He was lonely.
Speaker 1: I feel like that's gonna be a Boy right.
Speaker 1: come on it might be it might be Astro boy.
Speaker 0: She's Astro boy.
Speaker 0: Yeah So, uh, I'm looking for hopefully only Astro boy living on his own instead of with a cool family.
Speaker 1: Hopefully season two actually does come out and you forgot to do the same thing.
Speaker 0: You know that Astro boys dad did and you know doctor whatever.
Speaker 0: Yeah and make a robot family.
Speaker 1: I Doubt B's dad cast her out because she wasn't exactly dad.
Speaker 0: No, the dad probably died or went away or something.
Speaker 1: Yeah So we'll see.
Speaker 1: Ah, this show is like I said, if you didn't listen to the spoiler warnings, whatever now You know one of the secrets still lost the show.
Speaker 1: It's really good.
Speaker 1: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Speaker 0: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 1: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursday.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 0: But unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night and the patreon patrons for this episode of geek nights are Crag, Oliver Allen, Joyce, I'm an English is like a dude guy.
Speaker 1: charge option linkage You Jim from his car.
Speaker 1: Chris mid give my state air.
Speaker 1: I'm Jay Bansko lonely Roberto Kingsley Sean Yeager mid Nicholas Brando Mr.
Speaker 1: Strong stretching for to run creations.
Speaker 1: and there may be other secret names You do not even know sure about horror.
Speaker 1: or Rory Rochelle Montanona super boy sailor Vista Clinton Walton run from New Zealand Ryan parent rope and lender Finn Fred Lilly Tenebrae Sean Klein Chris Reimer and Thomas Hahn.
Speaker 1: as you may have seen we posted to the patrons the Rim and Emily.
Speaker 1: we are going to discuss every Disney theatrical release every movie.
Speaker 1: We're gonna talk about all of them in chronological release order.
Speaker 1: The first episode is on the patreon.
Speaker 1: You can go see it all of you.
Speaker 1: if you are a patron You need any amount of money $1 enough.
Speaker 1: if you don't even want to pay for that you should subscribe to the patreon Anyway paying nothing because the episode will be public to everyone on July 4th Regardless of if you give us money.
Speaker 1: and now I leave you with.
Speaker 2: Okay, this is gonna be pretty cheesy But they say that every day the universe expands and we discover certain things that we don't understand.
Speaker 2: Well dark matter ain't the only mystery at hand.
Speaker 2: I'm wondering how I got a girl like you to say that I'm her man.
Speaker 2: It's a statistical anomaly, but girl You've got me.
Speaker 2: gravity is pulling me to your heavenly body.
Speaker 2: No astronomical phenomenon could ever stop me.
Speaker 2: You've got a smile that every star in the galaxy copy the constellations couldn't make is beautiful a pattern.
Speaker 2: the conversations every night I ring you up like Saturn.
Speaker 2: the telescopes tell us folks that you're the coolest view a Supernova scooting over to make room for you because you eclipse every wonder of the cosmos.
Speaker 2: It's almost unfair to them, but you're the one I want most.
Speaker 2: It's a miracle that Galileo never found you.
Speaker 2: if he did he'd say the universe revolved around you.
Speaker 1: fly me to And let me play The stars.
Speaker 1: let me see what spring is like on Jupiter Mars.