Speaker 1: It's Monday March 4th 2019.
Speaker 1: I'm rim.
Speaker 1: I'm Scott and this is geek nights tonight.
Speaker 1: It's finally time.
Speaker 1: It is a tech news roundup.
Speaker 0: Let's do this as long time.
Speaker 1: listeners of geek nights will know we Periodically run out of good ideas for Monday shows because a lot of things we could talk about on a month Yeah, technically you mean frequently are not technically technology news.
Speaker 1: They are mostly business news because most technology news is actually business news And none of you care when like Linux kernel 5.0.0.0.0.1.8 comes out.
Speaker 1: so Every year around this time.
Speaker 1: I start thinking to myself.
Speaker 1: Oh, we're really out of Monday shows and then I think to myself Hey, why did we do a tech news roundup?
Speaker 1: and Scott always says nope we just did one.
Speaker 1: That's a cop-out show.
Speaker 1: That's a BS.
Speaker 1: We're not doing it unless it's been a while.
Speaker 0: Well, they used to be the dynamic.
Speaker 0: the new dynamic is pretty much every Monday.
Speaker 0: rim is like Let's do tech news roundup and I say no you can wait until March.
Speaker 0: Yep, and it.
Speaker 0: so now rim knows his March is smart.
Speaker 1: just coming stupid smarts weather.
Speaker 0: Yeah Hey, it is stupid smart your weather And he's like all right first Monday show March or do a tech news roundup in the next Monday He'll probably ask to do one again, and I'll be like no yeah I got some.
Speaker 1: I think I got some ideas for some Monday topics, but good luck.
Speaker 1: We're doing a tech news roundup today, so in the opening bit We didn't do a show on Thursday, so we were gonna do 2001 a space Odyssey Which is the current geek nights book club.
Speaker 1: I didn't finish reading it in time because I was busy Uh-huh, but I ended up having to do a work thing that night anyway Uh-huh, so we couldn't do the show where you will be doing the geek nights.
Speaker 1: But book club.
Speaker 1: on to lies your opening bit the meta moment a space Odyssey Cuz.
Speaker 1: we're not.
Speaker 1: we're just gonna go straight into the main bit.
Speaker 1: It's a weird day.
Speaker 1: It's tech news roundup day, okay.
Speaker 1: Also, we're not live-streaming this one because I got water flooding in through one of my bathroom ceilings And I hear it splashing even more over there.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I hear it escalating so I'm gonna pause recording the show to go look at that, and then we're gonna get ready for Things of the day, I just closed the door so I can't hear that water dripping anymore.
Speaker 0: I still hear it dripping.
Speaker 1: I hear it, but less so.
Speaker 0: So what do you got thing of the day was so you know in Japan does that the mega earthquake way back?
Speaker 0: When you're at PAX East that one time yeah, and it messed up most notably a lot of most a lot of Japan But it messed up Fukushima where there's nuclear power plant that was poorly maintained famously and basically everyone evacuated there and hasn't really gone back because You know
Speaker 1: yep,
Speaker 0: it's like Chernobyl not Chernobyl bad, but close.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I hope this is not bad.
Speaker 1: I hope this is not late breaking news to any of you.
Speaker 1: You can read like a book or talk to an old person if you want like documentaries.
Speaker 0: What is don't go there, but someone did go there stupidly?
Speaker 0: And what?
Speaker 0: I'm always glad that someone else does this sure great, and they went to the arcade.
Speaker 0: there's like a mega Sega Game Center there and Nobody has looted the Sega Game Center for some reason maybe because everything's covered in radioactive dust.
Speaker 1: yeah Like I imagine it'd be hard to get all that radioactive dust out of an area.
Speaker 0: It's like an arcade that first of all some of the things in there still work, right?
Speaker 0: But it's basically frozen in time right.
Speaker 0: usually you go to old arcades And it's like you know you can see like the remnant pieces and stuff like that.
Speaker 0: right But here the arcade has been frozen in time just abandoned and unchanged.
Speaker 0: I guess it was flooded at one point at least in the bottom level probably, but it's like it's just sitting there.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like you look at these pictures it stuff's just covered in dust and so the ceiling.
Speaker 0: if you're curious about what year was that 11 2011 11 okay, so in 2011 you can basically see forever.
Speaker 0: I guess for a long time.
Speaker 0: We're gonna have it like a museum of arcade technology Japanese arcade.
Speaker 1: It's kind of like a mini Vesuvius.
Speaker 0: yes, there's a video and there's some other stuff To so you can examine it.
Speaker 0: similarly I did see I don't have to find the link for it again There was a. there was a Twitter thread about the metreon in this thing.
Speaker 0: It's in San Francisco right which was like the Sony building that Sony made in the 90s.
Speaker 0: That was sort of like like a Disney Quest sort of situation thing with like fancy arcade.
Speaker 1: I don't know if I know about that or I just think I know about.
Speaker 0: I knew about it when it was a thing.
Speaker 0: I feel like I saw a YouTube video about it But I wasn't paying because basically GDC is this year is gonna be in it or near it.
Speaker 0: Oh the Twitter was like hey all GDC people go here and Look at the remnants of what was once the metroid and is now just like a sad movie theater.
Speaker 0: But you can still see you know in these areas of the building What's left from the days when it was awesome in 90s.
Speaker 1: so Scott what in your memory?
Speaker 1: Let's go back to like middle school social studies or geography class.
Speaker 1: What's the longest river in the world?
Speaker 0: You know give me Amazon could be Nile.
Speaker 0: you know something like that all right.
Speaker 1: so as far as I can tell looking at Wikipedia Both the Amazon and the Nile are listed as the longest river in the world, okay I am 100% right.
Speaker 0: I got both right answers.
Speaker 1: So this is in my style recently a lot of my things that they have been things like this because this is the YouTube hole I've been going down.
Speaker 1: But it basically it's one of those questions where there's a simple question And it turns out that for reasons the answer to that question is Potentially impossible to give
Speaker 0: right because you you could you know the other end of a river That's pretty easy to find it usually at the ocean or something yep.
Speaker 0: And then you go up the river, and there's the main part of it right.
Speaker 0: That's all thick and tons of water Really river really easy to measure that right, but eventually you reach.
Speaker 0: well eventually you reach a point we're like hey this river like has a fork and Each half of it is kind of yeah.
Speaker 0: So maybe you take the wider half and they get another fork.
Speaker 0: me like am I still on the same river Really, and then you see like your middle of the river And you see some water just going down from a hill nearby going into the river.
Speaker 1: It's like tributaries.
Speaker 0: It's like there's so many tributaries Right how can you measure?
Speaker 0: and then there's also like you know rivers might get twisty and turny But there might be water like cutting across the twisty turny part.
Speaker 0: so there's all sorts of things.
Speaker 0: and then this way maybe Elevation changes in the river right.
Speaker 0: it's like Oh, you know there's so many things You know how you you need to set a rules for measuring river length that are consistent.
Speaker 1: yep.
Speaker 1: So the trickiest part is that even if we just go for that first part where you jumped in like say we agree on What part counts as the river and we ignore the whole tributary problem.
Speaker 1: rivers lengths change so often?
Speaker 1: that you'd have to constantly remeasure them.
Speaker 1: and If you measure with more granularity the length of every river eventually becomes infinite.
Speaker 1: Because what is the actual length?
Speaker 1: which side of the river?
Speaker 1: Do you measure like it gets?
Speaker 0: I found I found the drop of water?
Speaker 0: Hitting a leaf that goes and lands on the ground and rolls down a hill and goes in Slowly absorbs out of the soil and made it just moist enough for some flowing to happen.
Speaker 0: So part of that eventually goes into the ocean And that's the river starts at that leaf on that tree.
Speaker 1: so part of this is the same question as How long is a coastline?
Speaker 1: because the answer is they're all infinitely long, and there's no way to measure that.
Speaker 1: I Guess if you're measuring like what if it's really a really twisty tourney Coastline how much of that nonsense do you measure it versus just ignore?
Speaker 0: It's still not infinite.
Speaker 1: It's there.
Speaker 0: There is definitely finite landmass.
Speaker 0: It's just really big yeah, but Zoom all the way in now.
Speaker 1: You've got the curvature of every individual molecule and atom of every piece of that land.
Speaker 1: That's really stupid Yeah, but I'm saying what?
Speaker 1: what is the unit of granularity that makes sense?
Speaker 1: because fucking ruler well What?
Speaker 0: so you can't measure it with a ruler you can't measure so you quantize it into a straight one size one foot.
Speaker 1: I'm just saying you got a size measuring depending on the number you pick.
Speaker 0: if I'm at the beach I take my tape measure and I go and I'm measuring the the.
Speaker 1: the fact that one grain of sand is slightly set back Yeah, but all I'm saying is that depending on the granularity you pick and I'm talking even like one foot versus one inch Completely changes the answer, but see this is the point.
Speaker 0: see it's interesting to say I'm measuring a river.
Speaker 0: tricky because tributaries.
Speaker 0: if you're making this argument You're basically saying nothing can be measured which is completely stupid.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 1: so pointless know because you can measure straight line distances easily And you can actually measure like road distances the air molecules.
Speaker 1: What's hard to knock is what's hard with a curvature of space-time?
Speaker 0: We might be.
Speaker 0: how fast is that ruler moving?
Speaker 1: we can account for all those things the one.
Speaker 1: This is the specific problem of if you're trying to measure an outline of a thing Like a coastline I very specifically a coastline Depending on if your granularity is an inch or a foot or a yard.
Speaker 1: the answer to the question Like say what state has the longest coastline changes Because some coastlines are really craggy and some aren't.
Speaker 1: if you measure it a yard granularity that might make more sense.
Speaker 1: But that also ignores all the crazy twisty tourney that might exist in like parts of Maine.
Speaker 0: measure it with a fucking.
Speaker 0: if you can See it from a plane then accounts all right, but someone was 20/20 vision Boris vision good vision Some sort of laser measuring device from the play.
Speaker 1: How is that plane flying?
Speaker 0: It's a low flying plane.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'm just saying like like the kind that carries an advertisement for the beach.
Speaker 0: That's how you pay for the measuring research.
Speaker 1: So yeah in the meta moment like I said the book club The geek nights book club is a long and storied tradition of announcing books and then Not actually getting to do them for a while and then reading them in a hurry and doing a show.
Speaker 0: I read the book.
Speaker 1: Yep, I will ever read by well before next Thursday when we will do the next game.
Speaker 0: Not only I've did I read that book.
Speaker 0: I've mostly read a much longer book.
Speaker 1: Oh, you're getting back into the show.
Speaker 0: I mean, that's the book that was on my kindlef.
Speaker 1: That's is so yet.
Speaker 1: Did you get to the part where you where you might say wow this is actually Evangelion.
Speaker 0: yet, I mean it's been like this is book one.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but it gets you think you might think okay It's Evangelion, and then it hits a point where it gets way more Evangelion.
Speaker 0: I mean it gets more even gel in every chapter.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it keeps getting more Evangelion and the end is Evangelion there.
Speaker 0: it is it's good biz.
Speaker 1: But the geek nights book club has done a lot of books And if you don't want to worry about the fickle realities of rim and scott or particularly rim in this case actually finishing the book That we're currently reading we've read a ton of books and not
Speaker 0: because you read them often Just because geek nights has been going on for too long Yeah
Speaker 1: And we've done pretty intense episodes of us talking about those books like Steppenwolf a farewell to arms snow crash Great, etc.
Speaker 1: Otherwise we will be live at PAX East doing a panel the real harm of games.
Speaker 0: I guess I had to finish making.
Speaker 1: yes You do only got a few.
Speaker 1: geek nights will also be at Zenkaikan doing a bunch of panels.
Speaker 1: I At some point.
Speaker 1: I should look up what panels were doing.
Speaker 1: I think I will try to do that tonight and make a post about it because I need to figure out what I need to prepare For Zenkaikan.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna be there.
Speaker 1: my panels are probably all on Saturday.
Speaker 1: There's a chance.
Speaker 1: There's one on Sunday I will not.
Speaker 1: The only geek nights panel that'll occur on Friday is I will be drinking at one of the pubs near the convention center And I will probably not at any point enter the convention center.
Speaker 1: if you find me in one of those pubs You can talk to me, and I guess that'll count as a geek nights event.
Speaker 1: so yeah other than that I think we should get right into the tech news roundup.
Speaker 0: all right.
Speaker 0: What tech news did you round up mr.. Tech news round.
Speaker 1: Oh, all right, so I put these in random order based on what?
Speaker 0: Tech news rodeo rim yep, so wrangler here.
Speaker 1: first thing.
Speaker 1: first the news that it's a big news And there's a lot to talk about here.
Speaker 1: It's technology and it's technology adjacent, but there's a whole clusterfuck around YouTube cracking down on the monetization of YouTube videos where Pedophiles and Nazis have posted things in the comments.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so like you know some kids say have like you know Gymnastics or something.
Speaker 0: yep, so you got like elementary school kids doing gymnastics and say the school.
Speaker 1: So the video that parents.
Speaker 0: some parents take an innocent video and they put it on YouTube so that the other parents can watch it.
Speaker 0: yep, and then some pedophiles find it and one person's innocent video about Elementary school gymnastics is someone else's fat yep, and then you know that is a problem.
Speaker 1: as old as internet is The internet is exist now people have been able to post content.
Speaker 0: That would just be a thing that people realize.
Speaker 0: try not to think about yep If it weren't for the fact that those people on the fab side then go into the comments and trade Links to other similar videos and do not say lots of bad things in the comments.
Speaker 0: So those videos that they show me saying so that's one aspect.
Speaker 1: you've got this problem That has always existed, but is now existing at scale because of the cruel realities of a modern People Collecting lots of video footage of children.
Speaker 0: that is not technically child porn But you find a playlist that make you know something that makes it through YouTube's.
Speaker 0: you know It's it's just videos of children.
Speaker 1: But then yeah but here's the problem.
Speaker 0: so they feel like if I went to the beach and I videoed like Hot girls in bikinis because they're on the beach, and then I just made a compilation video.
Speaker 0: It's like I'm like.
Speaker 0: it's not porn here.
Speaker 0: It is on YouTube.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I'm watch my.
Speaker 0: I'd get a lot of hits with that.
Speaker 0: I'm sure there is that on you, too.
Speaker 1: so you know the problem of you find a YouTube video and then you find like a playlist that that YouTube video is in and then you look and that playlist is Oddly specific.
Speaker 1: it's definitely someone's fat material.
Speaker 0: there are lots and lots of things that are not technically in and of themselves Crossing the line, but yeah, not just pornography, but hate speech and Nazi stuff too, but yet are obviously Crossing the line.
Speaker 1: yep like for example.
Speaker 1: There is another terrible Parallel to this that YouTube is not doing anything specifically about.
Speaker 1: but it happens, and I've seen discussion about it There'll be a lot of videos that are all clustered together that are all themselves Innocently uploaded or at least ostensibly initially up innocently uploaded by like police stations and security cameras.
Speaker 1: But someone will collect all those videos selectively only include Certain of those videos and make a compilation.
Speaker 1: That's basically people of race X committing crimes Because they've removed all the white people that were in the other videos that committed those same crimes.
Speaker 0: So why don't we make white people committing crime?
Speaker 1: Maybe we should.
Speaker 1: that's what we should make the YouTube channel white people committing crimes.
Speaker 1: I Feel like I don't want to watch that channel.
Speaker 1: I don't know any of these channels.
Speaker 1: It's called cops.
Speaker 0: It was on national television.
Speaker 0: I'm sure maybe it still is so.
Speaker 1: So that is in itself a problem.
Speaker 1: the reason why this becomes a technology issue is a Related orthogonal thing that happened.
Speaker 1: YouTube has a video recommendation engine that tries to figure out based on what you looked at what videos you would be likely to Continue to watch so that you just keep fucking watching YouTube forever.
Speaker 0: So and it works by looking at other people and it's like.
Speaker 0: well that person other people who watch this video Also watch these videos.
Speaker 0: so that means if you watch this video You'll probably like the things that other people who watch this video like yep.
Speaker 1: So let's see I'm gonna go to my youtube right now and see what it thinks like.
Speaker 0: if I just go to youtube.com It's gonna tell you to watch like.
Speaker 1: Okay, here's what it wants me to see.
Speaker 1: here's a whole bunch of likes clips from Star Trek bunch of Star Trek nonsense.
Speaker 1: Here's a bunch of games done quick stuff a bunch of more Star Trek nonsense.
Speaker 0: Oh, it seems like it works.
Speaker 1: Yeah, this is all.
Speaker 1: these are all things I would click on because that is the kind of stuff that I watch on YouTube.
Speaker 1: So it knows.
Speaker 1: but let's say and a reporter I forget what note that was for did this for this YouTube story if you watch a bunch of unrelated videos that happen to prominently featured children on YouTube YouTube will start recommending to you Only those videos and you see a really bad cluster in a hurry that gets really rapidly into actually bad like bad on purpose content mm-hmm, so the algorithm is Allowing pedophiles and Nazis and bad people to more easily find the kinds of stuff they want to see even if what they want to see was not uploaded with the intention of giving it to them.
Speaker 1: and Those kinds of people tend to use the internet very heavily and comment very heavily and the algorithms seem to over represent them.
Speaker 1: That's why if you take a blank YouTube account and watch any video about movies You're almost immediately going to be recommended some misogynistic shitbag.
Speaker 1: talking about why the new Ghostbusters is anti-male Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: Like this is a technology problem.
Speaker 0: that probably real technology problem is That there is so much video uploaded to YouTube every second That it is impossible to check it all with humans now that also wouldn't be a problem.
Speaker 0: Maybe the algorithms just say and the algorithms know even the best algorithm in the world is not any good.
Speaker 1: So maybe the algorithm should ignore channels that have less than like 5,000 subscribers or something.
Speaker 0: I mean there's things like that they can do.
Speaker 0: but you know, yeah, so how do you know those channels?
Speaker 0: Probably don't have less than so.
Speaker 1: this intersects very heavily people with the huge Monetization model of YouTube right?
Speaker 0: so people get mad when I say this.
Speaker 0: But I don't think YouTube should pay anyone who uploads videos.
Speaker 1: I agree a hundred percent right.
Speaker 0: people are like, oh no, but all these youtubers like that's their job.
Speaker 0: You're saying they shouldn't.
Speaker 0: I say this fully full disclosure.
Speaker 1: I make decent money from our YouTube videos, right?
Speaker 0: I'm like, you know, you're like.
Speaker 0: no these craters need to be compensated and it's like well, hold on You're being compensated because you're getting free video hosting.
Speaker 0: Do you have any idea how much free video hosting costs?
Speaker 0: because a fortune.
Speaker 0: try to buy a web server and serve video.
Speaker 0: Look at your bandwidth bill.
Speaker 0: if you have any kind of viewership Yeah, right Look at your storage that it's gonna take up.
Speaker 0: look at all the trans coding you have to do to deliver though that video to every single possible device on earth and high quality and like such fast loading times to run your own personal YouTube would cost you a Fortune.
Speaker 1: now the proper your own videos.
Speaker 0: now.
Speaker 1: I would be fine with YouTube providing a way for you to make a deal with an advertise.
Speaker 0: You are so big on YouTube that you're you know, you deserve to be compensated.
Speaker 0: You could get compensated by you know Making deals with people for like product placement your videos sponsored videos all kinds.
Speaker 0: I'd also be okay.
Speaker 0: I just don't think YouTube should be paying you because then we can well, oh well, here's the caveat.
Speaker 1: I don't think YouTube should be paying you for revenue from a generic sized ad distribution service.
Speaker 1: right if you make it fine if you Because someone subscribed to your channel and agreed to pay a dollar a month for you Like you're a tiny cable channel.
Speaker 0: This monetize demonetize based on your content thing.
Speaker 0: It's like no no, no.
Speaker 1: Well, because there's the problem that monetize.
Speaker 1: demonetize specifically means that if it's quote unquote monetized Advertisers you will never interact with are paying YouTube Directly for ads and YouTube is using other algorithms to say put these ads on these random videos.
Speaker 0: What it should be is by default.
Speaker 0: No one is monetized.
Speaker 0: to get monetized You have to like make a contract and sign a deal.
Speaker 1: Yeah with an Advertiser.
Speaker 1: Yeah, not YouTube.
Speaker 1: Maybe more YouTube.
Speaker 1: You do.
Speaker 0: my YouTube is like, okay, we're just let's sign a deal.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you specifically your content is good.
Speaker 0: We like you.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and otherwise nothing you make should be monetized.
Speaker 0: You should be glad that you're getting free hosting.
Speaker 0: That's your monitor.
Speaker 1: But the fact that YouTube is trying to monetize this based on basically AI and algorithms and ad networks Made this come to a head because the advertisers who buy YouTube ads tend to just buy them in bulk And it just makes sense to do like.
Speaker 1: that's how you advertise.
Speaker 1: and then suddenly they all realized.
Speaker 1: Wait a minute.
Speaker 0: The reason Google doesn't want to do this is basically that kills their inventory.
Speaker 0: Yep It also like but but it would also jack up the price on the inventory that it have.
Speaker 1: Well, I would also say that most of the people who are the loudest about how monetization like the monetization as exists today has to Stay alive.
Speaker 1: our channels with like less than a thousand subscribers Like if even if you're quote unquote monetized you're making like 20 bucks a month.
Speaker 1: That is not enough money to bother.
Speaker 1: Yeah If you rely on that to make your channel.
Speaker 1: your problem is not with YouTube model is monetization.
Speaker 0: your problem with People Problem is they already did it right.
Speaker 0: so people get real mad.
Speaker 0: if you take any money away from them, right?
Speaker 0: They're getting a dollar.
Speaker 0: you take away that dollar.
Speaker 0: Oh, that's so mad.
Speaker 1: Yep Well, they also seem to think that they're gonna get big one day.
Speaker 0: But anyway, the problem is I also think the editor shouldn't have comments at all.
Speaker 1: Uh, yeah, we'll get back to that.
Speaker 0: So why does that have cut?
Speaker 0: what everyone all people do is talk about bad YouTube comments are they're so rarely Worthwhile.
Speaker 0: the only YouTube comments that are ever worthwhile are the ones that have a timecode so you can skip to the good part of the video like like in a speedrun and The ones that give you extra info that the video didn't include.
Speaker 0: otherwise comments on YouTube are pretty much 99.9% worthless.
Speaker 0: I'm willing to sacrifice the good ones.
Speaker 0: Just delete all YouTube comments and never bring them back.
Speaker 0: I would you want comments on your videos?
Speaker 0: Let people email you and contact you the creator directly somehow like Twitter or something.
Speaker 0: or or embed your video on your blog with the Comments under and then it does come into your problem.
Speaker 1: or if I were YouTube, you know what I would do Provide an API because if you're big enough you might want comments, but YouTube just provides the UI In YouTube for that but the comments actually go through whatever internal system you've got for moderation.
Speaker 0: Because the main reason that's got a lot of problems.
Speaker 1: Well Well, that's just another platform.
Speaker 1: It's a commenting plan.
Speaker 0: I put my comments on YouTube and that's it's like.
Speaker 0: that's a huge problem.
Speaker 0: Why?
Speaker 0: Technologically speaking?
Speaker 0: now, it's like I'm infesting YouTube with my with my comment.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I've built that semi federated.
Speaker 1: The problem with YouTube comments too.
Speaker 1: is that like on our channel the comments are actually pretty good Because the kinds of people that watch our videos.
Speaker 1: we're not like mass-market.
Speaker 0: I'm willing to sacrifice my YouTube.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well also I'd leave comments on but I every now and if I gained any sort of traction on YouTube I would I would.
Speaker 1: just I would end comments permanently if I had my druthers.
Speaker 1: Don't worry.
Speaker 1: Don't get me wrong.
Speaker 1: this is the same conversation that webcomics had back when webcomics first became big and suddenly every webcomic had its own forum.
Speaker 1: that was full of bullshit and A bunch of voices came out and said why does a webcomic even need a forum?
Speaker 1: Like.
Speaker 1: why does it?
Speaker 0: because the reason of a form is because you're trying to build a community.
Speaker 0: Yeah for your audience right be to have you have a community.
Speaker 0: You got to manage the community.
Speaker 1: I'm like the geek nice forum we manage.
Speaker 0: You know if you're trying to make money and not like.
Speaker 0: we're not trying to make money But if you are you got to translate the community into money somehow.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: The only reason the geek nights community works.
Speaker 1: I think the geek nice community is really good.
Speaker 1: I really like our forum.
Speaker 1: culture is because one we're not trying to make money.
Speaker 1: So we're more than willing to tell Nazis and pedophiles to fuck off.
Speaker 1: But YouTube as much as they don't want to admit it Rely on pedophiles and Nazis for a big enough percentage of their revenue to where now they're in trouble over it.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: So this situation is big and the solutions are things no one wants to hear.
Speaker 1: because the end result of all this so far is that Advertisers said whoa YouTube unless you can guarantee that my video my ad will not be shown next to some pedophile nonsense I'm not buying any more YouTube ads.
Speaker 1: full stop.
Speaker 0: if you're an advertiser The thing is usually I'm in favor of things to hurt advertisers.
Speaker 0: Both of these policies are pro advertiser.
Speaker 0: If you're an advertiser you buy YouTube ads.
Speaker 0: they put your ads on all kinds of videos videos that are probably Mostly by bots.
Speaker 0: you target them somewhat, but you don't target them, you know, you know like perfectly, you know You can't narrow it down that much.
Speaker 0: Yeah Your ad could show up on my video if someone done without adblock watches it.
Speaker 0: if you like buy a gaming ad or something Right.
Speaker 0: that can happen and that was just a worthless ad buy for you.
Speaker 0: They should make it to where.
Speaker 0: if you're an ad buyer you specifically list the exact Videos and channels that you want your ad to appear on and it will not appear anywhere else Right, and it's like, okay all you other people everyone can be monetized now,
Speaker 1: but all right, and then YouTube just provides
Speaker 0: ripping off advertisers by playing their ads and making them pay to show those ads on All these garbage videos all over YouTube with all this worthless inventory.
Speaker 1: So I think a lot of people are buying ads.
Speaker 1: I mean this is my speculation.
Speaker 0: Google lets you have some of the YouTube money But they're every time someone watches that ad.
Speaker 0: they also get money from the advertisers by selling your worthless video inventory.
Speaker 1: I suspect a lot of the people buying ads are starting to question the value of the YouTube advertising network as a whole.
Speaker 0: Yeah, pretty much.
Speaker 0: I mean, I don't know why people who buy ads buy any online ads.
Speaker 0: They're all worthless.
Speaker 1: Well, I think the big difference is that Because it's a lot of work to figure out where to advertise assuming an advertisers acting in good faith that Everyone who tries to sell an advertiser ad space is probably ripping them off and the ad networks just made the problem disappear But not go away.
Speaker 0: It's because ad buyers right.
Speaker 0: if you're an ad buyer, that's your job.
Speaker 0: That's actually a job You can have.
Speaker 0: yeah is you're not you don't make.
Speaker 1: I have been an ad buyer.
Speaker 1: I've done that professionally.
Speaker 1: it fucking sucks.
Speaker 0: No, like there's people that's their full-time job is yeah, someone else makes the ads they you know Like they're not the creative person like comes up with cool ads.
Speaker 0: They just go around buying ad inventory to and then getting those ads to play there And what they do is then they go and show their boss Look look where I got our look.
Speaker 0: if you watch this awesome popular YouTube video our ad shows up.
Speaker 0: Look, if you look at at this billboard in Times Square.
Speaker 0: our ad is there.
Speaker 0: Yeah, aren't you proud of all the places our company is?
Speaker 0: look we're on the Super Bowl.
Speaker 0: Look look at all the places I got us.
Speaker 0: They don't have ever actually proved because they can't that those ads were effective or those are good buys or anything like that.
Speaker 0: All they do is impress the boss by making them proud of all the places their company logo has appeared, right?
Speaker 0: So that's the person who decides where to buy ads.
Speaker 0: they don't give a fuck if they're effective or if the money is well spent.
Speaker 0: They just want to increase their department's budget and impress the boss by having the company logo and ad appear in the most, you know Prestigious places, so there's a lot going on with that and we'll just move on to something else.
Speaker 1: So here's the funny one cops in Winnipeg.
Speaker 1: I guess they use encryption software to encrypt the Communication they do on their radios to prevent people like me from just listening to the police blotter I guess in Canada.
Speaker 0: It's not like the US where the police radio has to be Unencrypted or whatever.
Speaker 1: I'm pretty.
Speaker 1: I think there are jurisdictions in the US now where it's encrypted It's.
Speaker 0: I don't know what the law is regarding that but I mean there is a culture in the u.s Of people listening to police when I was a kid has historically been very unencrypted.
Speaker 1: when I was a kid Or you can just listen when I was a kid We had a 14 channel police scanner that we just left on in the house.
Speaker 0: They just sold him a RadioShack.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you can go to RadioShack buy one of these things and then be a crazy old man listening to police radio.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but then what you had to do is know which crystal you have citizen app.
Speaker 1: You don't need it yeah, you have to know which crystals to buy to put into the slots because Variable frequency tuning radios like that for police stuff.
Speaker 1: We're not available to the public are much easier.
Speaker 0: now In fact is out.
Speaker 1: there's a software that there's.
Speaker 0: also.
Speaker 0: there are certain kinds of radios that are gonna be going like out of.
Speaker 0: Possibly might be illegal soon.
Speaker 0: So people are ham nerds are buying them up lately.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: It's a certain kind I forget but yeah as a kid like when we were driving around we'd listen to the police because it was fun.
Speaker 1: Like did we'd listen to?
Speaker 1: we just listen to cops like heaven thing is like.
Speaker 0: doing it like a little bit is fun Right, but doing it a whole bunch gets real boring and real.
Speaker 0: it's like if you keep doing it then it becomes a problem.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like I feel like at that point you're storing jars of your own pee.
Speaker 0: Yeah It's like I only check citizen app when like I heard way too many sirens people were like staring at citizen app.
Speaker 0: That's a problem.
Speaker 1: So basically is best I can tell.
Speaker 1: what happened here is that the police were using these encrypted radios and there's a company that provides the encryption software and And they need to be updated frequently and to update them.
Speaker 1: You need to buy a refresh key from the company.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm and Motorola charged $94 per update per radio.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm, and there were lots of radios.
Speaker 1: so Someone bought a bunch of these keys and I made finger quotes here because they bought them.
Speaker 1: the same way You're buying a Windows 10 key on a website somewhere and bought 65,000 of them and told the police you don't want to know where these came from and the police have been pirating the software and It's a big goddamn deal now.
Speaker 0: Oh The police should be pirating.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think the problem is I don't want Civil infrastructure in any country to be reliant on a single privately held vendor or Public company that is not public in the government owns it.
Speaker 0: The best thing to do would be for the government to just say a law and be like, hey Guess what?
Speaker 0: You have to provide you have to give it to us for free top shit.
Speaker 0: We make a law we can just tell you to do whatever we want.
Speaker 0: But if they're failing that piracy next best choice?
Speaker 1: or how about a law that says, you know police radios have to be encrypted blah blah blah.
Speaker 1: and here is a. vendors have to provide it at a statutory cost.
Speaker 1: and here's the list of vendors that have to provide it.
Speaker 1: and you could make a Regulation that balances free market economics with the fact that the government shouldn't rely on private companies for shit like this.
Speaker 1: But instead it looks like these couches pirated it.
Speaker 1: I didn't read the full story.
Speaker 0: Sounds good.
Speaker 1: All right, let's move on.
Speaker 1: So as we know for a long time They have like the FCC.
Speaker 1: one of the things the FCC is supposed to do is get public comments to inform decision-making around the kind of technology the FCC is in charge of.
Speaker 1: mm-hmm makes sense, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, so If it wasn't obvious to all of you basically those comments for a long time now have been entirely fake generated by like.
Speaker 1: Russian bot farms and Lobbyists in the US filled out that form to make comments.
Speaker 0: It's hard to fill out that form with a lot of stuff.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it shouldn't be hard to figure out which ones are fake.
Speaker 1: I think before the Russian trolls and bot farms and lobbyists started doing it automatically I'm pretty sure.
Speaker 1: even in the old days they made it hard to do on purpose to keep people like us Because it's an old shitty government website and you got to fill in all those bureaucratic crap.
Speaker 1: Yep so I guess the broader question is One.
Speaker 1: there are only two ways to address this problem now because I we can't do a whole show on this right now.
Speaker 1: We got a lot of news to cover.
Speaker 1: either We need to Forget the idea that the FCC gets comments from the public because there's literally no way to do it Effectively like it's just gonna be spammed.
Speaker 1: There's no way to control it.
Speaker 1: or Nerds need to make their own troll farms to flood the FCC With the actually right things to do around things like net neutrality.
Speaker 1: I feel like the collected nerds in America could send more comments to the FCC that are prone at neutrality than all the lobbyists Next time there's a thing.
Speaker 0: I'm not even hiding it.
Speaker 0: I'm just going for it.
Speaker 0: I think we should.
Speaker 0: we're gonna go We're gonna flood that shit and we're gonna go to tech war because that's not hard to do.
Speaker 1: It's like the toner war.
Speaker 0: It's a really easy tech war to fight.
Speaker 1: It is bot bot farmers bot farm.
Speaker 0: I'll make a program and I'll say everyone run this program run it instead of your Bitcoin miner.
Speaker 1: Yep, right Maybe you use a simple pseudo AI on grandma's.
Speaker 1: easy.
Speaker 1: It generates a slightly different message from everybody.
Speaker 0: All kinds of stuff.
Speaker 1: I mean Russia's ahead of us and I've had of our country on this game.
Speaker 1: I feel like nerds in the u.s.
Speaker 1: Needs to step up.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: All right, let's move along too.
Speaker 1: So I saw this article and a lot of people think that they because they pay some random Scandinavian or Nordic sounding company like Nord VPN.
Speaker 1: Yep, five bucks a month.
Speaker 1: It's not a bad VPN Yeah, but there's a lot of them that are vaguely Nordic sounding.
Speaker 0: Yeah that I think Nord VPN is actually from Panama.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you see where I'm going with this.
Speaker 1: Anyway, if you pay one of these people some amount a month and you have all your internet traffic on your phone go through a VPN Then your privacy is protected Somewhat and that is sort of true, but not really to protecting yourself.
Speaker 0: Your ISP won't see your traffic, right?
Speaker 0: So you got one of those ISPs that keeps shutting you down for downloading, you know, brand-new Hollywood movies all the time.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the VPN will 99% probably protect you from that To this day.
Speaker 1: I I will not confirm or deny but I'm confident that that kind of traffic is traverse this network In volume.
Speaker 1: over the last decade in my entire life an ISP has never come after me.
Speaker 0: No I don't understand how this happens to other people as I'm downloading not Like the brand-new because they're only looking at like specific things right like who's downloading.
Speaker 0: What's a really new movie?
Speaker 0: That's super hot, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, like a movie that was in theaters like fucking right now.
Speaker 0: They're looking for that shit.
Speaker 0: They're not looking for.
Speaker 0: Korean variety shows out bit torrent Season six of Adventure Time that door.
Speaker 1: they're not looking for that, but there's this article that's just like How do you decide which VPN to trust in?
Speaker 1: the one there's a website Scott's linked to a million times.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's I think it's called that security that one privacy site.
Speaker 0: Yep, and it basically has a whole spreadsheet of every major VPN provider and all the you know Basically details about which ones have which features and you can decide for yourself which one you want to trust.
Speaker 0: And if you trust this site, I trust that one privacy site.
Speaker 0: You know what?
Speaker 1: It has the same kind of look that the actual putty site has.
Speaker 0: This has the look of a trustworthy website.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it actually kind of does which is funny We're not joking.
Speaker 0: It looks like a certain a site that a nerd a certain kind of nerd put a lot of effort into.
Speaker 1: It is definitely not fake a site that has in all caps.
Speaker 1: Please be patient as it may take some time for the sheet to load.
Speaker 1: There's a certain kind of person who types those words into a website.
Speaker 1: But this this question comes up a lot in mainstream technology news.
Speaker 1: I want to address it right now.
Speaker 1: Anytime you're using anything to control what people people see about your data like VPNs privacy stuff.
Speaker 1: You've just the question is do you trust company a or company B or company C or nerd D who emailed you?
Speaker 1: The only question is how do you decide who to trust?
Speaker 1: because you gotta trust someone Like.
Speaker 1: there's no way to know that a VPN is secure.
Speaker 1: You've got to trust someone's word on it at some point.
Speaker 1: There's no way for you to ever figure this out on your own.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I talked to rim through a secret tunnel.
Speaker 0: great We know no one is spying on us.
Speaker 0: What if rim is spying on?
Speaker 1: Yep If I'm spying on Scott or Scott spying on me One of us is fine.
Speaker 0: All right, the connection between my computer and Amazon's computer is a hundred percent sealed and secure.
Speaker 0: No one can spy on us and I tell Amazon my credit card number so they can let me buy something and then Amazon steals my credit card, yep, it's like Alright, here's one.
Speaker 1: so in gaming a big problem in online gaming competitive gaming competitive online ortho gaming is Cheating right?
Speaker 0: So most games these days, you know big multiplayer online games have some sort of anti-cheat Technologies built in the steam vac.
Speaker 0: There's all kinds of stuff, right?
Speaker 0: So there's some very popular anti-cheat software that has not been named and for some reason In Windows 10 in this one preview built.
Speaker 0: so Windows 10 If you don't realize most of you are probably just using normalize Windows 10 or Windows 7 even and maybe Windows 8 Who knows not.
Speaker 0: was there a 9 and skip 9 right anyway?
Speaker 1: Yeah, they skip 9 because they were worried that the string like win 9 X like win 9 would be confused by Shitty old programs who look for win 9 5 anyway win 9 a. there was a string problem.
Speaker 0: Anyway, the point is that There's preview builds you can get and you can get newer future versions of Windows 10 before they're released.
Speaker 0: And there's one that like updates every day.
Speaker 0: That's like super hot.
Speaker 0: and there's one that's like, okay This one's more stable, but it's it's still way ahead of the one that normal people are using, right?
Speaker 0: So that super hot one has this bug where if you're using playing certain games Which is actually quite a few serious big-name games that have anti-cheat certain anti-cheat software You will get the green screen of death trying to play those games pretty much consistently because of this bug.
Speaker 1: now I would suspect part of the issue is that anti-cheat software to be successful needs to do a lot of the kinds of things that computers don't want you to do like Inspecting the memory that another application is using right?
Speaker 0: So Microsoft I guess knows which patch they made.
Speaker 0: that's causing this.
Speaker 0: But they're not unpatching it.
Speaker 0: They want the anti-cheat software to make a patch and it has not done.
Speaker 0: So the result is that that other preview build the sort of more stable one, which is used a lot by gaming people who kind of people would overclock and yeah frames rates and all those kinds of people are actually one of the biggest consumers Of that build.
Speaker 0: the more stable not super nightly, but way ahead of normal people build.
Speaker 0: I forget they have names for them.
Speaker 0: But anyway They're big consumer of that build.
Speaker 0: so even though Microsoft would like to update that build more frequently They haven't updated it in a super long-ass time you know because They can't because they'll crack the green screen of death.
Speaker 0: Everyone is playing games with that build.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: Ah And they could undo their patch, but they don't seem to want to do that either.
Speaker 0: They need this unnamed anti-cheat software to update itself.
Speaker 0: And I guess they don't want to go without that patch and the cheating people don't want to make that patch.
Speaker 0: So the windows 10 is like all held up by this By this one some anti-cheat software somewhere.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I presume, you know, maybe it's valve steam vac.
Speaker 0: I don't know it could be anything.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't know which one it is.
Speaker 1: I don't know a lot of that guy just saw it.
Speaker 0: It's like some other company is holding up windows Unless Microsoft undoes its patch and they don't seem like they want to.
Speaker 1: yep I guess their anti-cheat software is difficult to do because the problem is that people are running third-party software that somehow fucks with software that is itself already verified.
Speaker 1: all the I all the Obvious ideas you can think of to solve this problem are already being done and aren't enough.
Speaker 0: like no It's a. have your entire game server side the end.
Speaker 0: That's all you gotta do.
Speaker 0: if somebody does some sort of cheating that only manipulates like the inputs good for you You win.
Speaker 1: yeah The thing is there.
Speaker 1: we are cheating.
Speaker 0: software looks at the screen and then moves the map.
Speaker 0: you looks at the frame buffer Five uses computer imaging to find targets and then moves the mouse.
Speaker 1: I want to see cheating software.
Speaker 1: You're allowed to do that.
Speaker 1: I want to see cheating software that looks at your screen and moves the mouse but also Searches twitch and YouTube to try to find other people who happen to be streaming the game you're in and incorporates that data.
Speaker 0: I mean, that's just automated stream sniping.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there's No way to detect or stop that right but as long as you know You're not like messing with the game itself as long as you're cheating on the the input output side.
Speaker 0: That's okay.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'm okay with that But just keep the entire game server side that we know could cheat unless the hacker server wish they can.
Speaker 1: so really tiny news Someone pointed out.
Speaker 1: I think this was from some RIAA report.
Speaker 1: More people bought physical CDs and vinyl then bought iTunes songs last year, which duh I think that was I assume is still buying CDs and vinyl right?
Speaker 0: Well, I guess old people are buying CDs.
Speaker 0: yeah, right because they just won't go digital.
Speaker 0: and then All kinds of people are buying vinyl because they're not buying the music that like they're not buying the vinyl Buying it to collect the vinyl.
Speaker 0: a lot of you and some people for some reason have this You know idea that vinyl is better and they're wrong.
Speaker 1: Yeah, absolutely wrong.
Speaker 0: Some people admit the vinyls worse, but they have a nostalgic thing for and do it.
Speaker 0: Anyway, fine.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: I like I can.
Speaker 0: That's your thing.
Speaker 1: I can see.
Speaker 1: like I do enjoy the ritual of putting a vinyl record on a turntable because I remember doing that.
Speaker 0: People buy vinyl cuz they're a DJ and they use two turntables and a microphone.
Speaker 1: Yeah, maybe they use that digital vinyl.
Speaker 0: Yeah, maybe.
Speaker 0: But who the hell would buy an mp3 when you see Apple music Spotify?
Speaker 0: Yep I stream music because if you're already getting an mp3 Why not use some higher up?
Speaker 1: because the vast majority of people who listen to music Don't care about music enough to buy every song they care about.
Speaker 1: they're gonna just stream the music that's popular.
Speaker 0: That's the only time I ever buy an mp3.
Speaker 0: in these days is when there's a super Not, you know indie band such that I could not pirate their mp3 on Pirate Bay because they're too small.
Speaker 0: They're also not on Spotify or Apple or Apple music or Google Play or whatever because they're for whatever reason But they're on like bandcamp.
Speaker 0: pretty much bandcamp is the only site I buy music from yep these days and I will go I'll Say oh your albums there.
Speaker 0: Okay, here's $2 or I already kick-started you.
Speaker 1: Give me that mp3s for free and then or else I I have individually bought wave and flak files from individual artists who sold them directly from their websites.
Speaker 0: That's basically a bank.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but there's just like one.
Speaker 1: It's not even a bandcamp.
Speaker 1: It's just like here's my website So rare that's like yeah twice a year Maybe but even then that music was also on a shocking number of streaming services.
Speaker 0: It is shocking how much Spotify is really like got everything.
Speaker 1: There's not much That's not there but I think that the end the world is moving toward on demand streaming for music and a small number of people who care a Lot about music itself are going to do things like collect vinyl.
Speaker 1: I feel like there should be market in the future of everything streams But you can pay to get a flak file.
Speaker 1: That's like mastered or I think audio file nonsense.
Speaker 1: Multitrack split out, you know what?
Speaker 1: I really like to see.
Speaker 1: you could buy an album for like 40 bucks But it comes with all the tracks like the actual mastering data from the studio.
Speaker 0: No one's gonna give you for remixes and it comes no as giving you that.
Speaker 1: and it comes with a license to remix.
Speaker 0: No one's giving you that.
Speaker 1: I'm saying that's not for 40 bucks.
Speaker 1: For 400 bucks.
Speaker 0: master license cost way more than that depends on what you're doing with it.
Speaker 0: anyway, the point is what I would like to see is You know, like I just said Spotify for example has fucking everything almost.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but there are things it doesn't have.
Speaker 0: it's not a hundred percent It's just.
Speaker 0: it's really hard to find something doesn't have all right.
Speaker 0: And what they should do is they just be like, all right If I search for something on Spotify and it's not on there and even the Beatles are on there now.
Speaker 0: Okay, so it's like it's like come on you searches on and it's not on there.
Speaker 0: That's when it should say all right look This album is not here.
Speaker 0: Give us five dollars and you will.
Speaker 0: you don't bother downloading mp3s.
Speaker 0: You just give us five dollars right now and then you will work it out.
Speaker 0: this specific artist.
Speaker 0: Well, you know who doesn't want to be on Spotify.
Speaker 1: They'll get four dollars, right?
Speaker 0: We'll give them the money and then you can have that on Spotify, right?
Speaker 0: Well, so they unlock the streaming of it for you forever.
Speaker 0: Yep, right by paying this money and maybe even give you the mp3s if you want them also sure go ahead and download them You don't have to.
Speaker 0: it's like do you?
Speaker 1: I used to collect music because you know The world was different and I have a directory that I've copied from computer to computer to computer forever.
Speaker 0: That's a lot of mp3s I have that I have that directory also.
Speaker 1: I've added maybe a hundred mp3s to that directory in the last five years like nothing to it.
Speaker 0: so actually now would be you know, it's like I could go back and organize.
Speaker 0: it.
Speaker 0: now would be a good time because Yeah, it's so, you know, it's not changing.
Speaker 0: So it's not hard to you know, once I organize it, I'll be done forever.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and I can also delete a lot of things from it that are on spot.
Speaker 1: Yeah like I have a lot of my mp3s are.
Speaker 1: I have every OC remix because I downloaded a package of all of them from OC remixes in like Only need to get the music from there that I can't get anywhere else.
Speaker 0: If there's a song in there that I can get easily from another source.
Speaker 1: I don't need it all right, let's burn through a few of these.
Speaker 1: so Real technology news Linux 5 came out.
Speaker 0: whatever they did.
Speaker 0: The numbers now are arbitrary.
Speaker 1: literally doesn't matter They're not.
Speaker 0: they're no longer changing the number in relation to a significant software change.
Speaker 0: Here's the thing most of arbitrarily making the number go up when they feel like it.
Speaker 1: nerds Like us would care about Linux kernels back when Linux was used on the desktop and it was like I need the kernel to support My weird bullshit hardware like there was a reason like my Wi-Fi won't work yet stuff like that.
Speaker 1: Nowadays, it's just server operating system software and If you're the person who manages servers, just keep your stuff reasonably up-to-date And that's it very rarely.
Speaker 1: Is there a feature coming in the kernel that you need in production today?
Speaker 1: for a reason?
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm, like DRB.
Speaker 1: D is already there.
Speaker 1: like stuffs already there Linux kernel releases are about as newsworthy even to nerds as like what's in the next Windows patch.
Speaker 1: Yep Uh, here's an interesting tech news that none of you will care about.
Speaker 1: w3c approved a Standard for password free logins on websites like a universal standard.
Speaker 0: all your browsers already have this but they're not using it because Websites aren't using it properly.
Speaker 1: Yep, or maybe in your phone like you want to you want to have a standard where I could say log into website X with My thumbprint.
Speaker 1: so there is an official standard kind of like the standard that we use with our TOTP for two-factor and our Fido keys.
Speaker 1: This is in that same suite to allow you to use things like Fido keys and Biometrics or whatever you want to use for password direct passwordless authentication to websites instead of just relying on your browser Saving the password in a store to paste into a form.
Speaker 1: It's good news and only people who held the only people who will care about the fact that the w3c approved This are the people who work in companies and are implementing this for websites and for authentication systems Like nerds won't care.
Speaker 1: It'll just start working on your phones.
Speaker 1: I think we can stop there.
Speaker 1: We've gone on for a long time.
Speaker 0: Okay, good.
Speaker 0: I'm hungry.
Speaker 1: Yeah, let's just stop cuz I'm also hungry.
Speaker 1: I don't use before is not that interesting to talk about yet?
Speaker 1: foldable phones.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's all I got.
Speaker 1: we're gonna eat some food.
Speaker 1: Oh one last news.
Speaker 1: this one's really funny.
Speaker 1: Apple Has Apple stores all over the world?
Speaker 1: They're a part apparently closing two of their stores in, Texas Because those are the only two stores they have in a particular judicial district the Eastern District of Texas Which for various reasons is where?
Speaker 1: Almost every patent troll in the world files their lawsuit to try to extort money out of tech companies in the u.s.
Speaker 0: Right because there's some Corrupt judges there.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: There's a lot of reasons Updated February 22nd as this news a little old Apple has confirmed.
Speaker 1: They will be closing the stores And they're relocating the employees like they're helping everybody out.
Speaker 1: So basically Apple saying if we close these two Apple stores And we don't do any business in this Eastern District of Texas clearly won't do.
Speaker 0: then you cannot get you know Patent suits for us.
Speaker 0: do it in that district because we're not doing business in that district.
Speaker 1: and it's interesting because I suspect a lot Of these patent troll cases could not easily get past the first round if they file in any other district in America Yep, so we'll see how this plays out.
Speaker 1: This is the kind of thing that
Speaker 0: they are putting one Apple store basically right across the board yep,
Speaker 1: so on one hand I don't think gigantic multi-billion dollar corporations should be able to Skirt the judicial system by closing a star, but on the other hand Apple is generally not in the wrong in these patent troll lawsuits and the judicial system and Congress have failed to address this fundamental problem in copyright and patent law.
Speaker 0: well I think part of the problem is not just you know the lack of the the Congress's ability to fix the patent laws yeah, there's no more patent trolls, but also this question of like Districts and jurisdiction don't work in the modern world when it's like.
Speaker 0: it's like there needs to just be sort of like this Federal like general federal court court of the internet right where it's like.
Speaker 0: It's like Apple is a countrywide deal.
Speaker 0: if you sue them you shouldn't be able to like pick a spot.
Speaker 0: So here is the old side about the geography have to do with it, right?
Speaker 0: It's like if Apple fucks up everyone's iPhone battery.
Speaker 0: They fucked up everyone's iPhone battery.
Speaker 0: There should be an everything federal court district for when there are lawsuits involving Big things that aren't actually G don't matter geographically, right?
Speaker 1: It's the sideshow Bob conundrum.
Speaker 0: the old episode is a federal crime in Eastern, Texas.
Speaker 0: Then it makes sense to go to the federal court in Eastern, Texas.
Speaker 0: But if someone commits a federal crime or some sort of you know isn't necessarily a crime But you know the reason to sue them.
Speaker 0: under a federal statute I guess whatever.
Speaker 0: it is not a lawyer that doesn't have any geography related to it.
Speaker 0: Why should you have to pick a geography?
Speaker 1: It comes down to where the crime occurred and the question of where the crime occurred is really complicated in the modern world.
Speaker 0: I want to make some sort of central federal thing.
Speaker 0: then the rule should be all right.
Speaker 0: You're a nationwide international company.
Speaker 0: the lawsuit involving you someone's suing you on for on federal.
Speaker 0: You know matters.
Speaker 0: We pick a random federal court.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we don't.
Speaker 0: you don't get to pick which one.
Speaker 0: it's random.
Speaker 0: because so remember Sideshow Bob was gonna kill bar and distribute the workload across all the different federal Districts.
Speaker 1: sideshow Bob was gonna go to that spot where five states meet Hold a gun stand in one state hold a gun over the border in the second state to shoot Bart Who's standing in a third state and then Bart's body would fall in the fourth state.
Speaker 1: like a plan like that to confuse?
Speaker 1: The jurisdiction so much that he couldn't be prosecuted.
Speaker 1: The internet actually has a problem like that times a hundred.
Speaker 1: Where did the crime occur when a phone made by a global international company uses software developed by someone in a third-party country that violates Ostensibly a patent filed by a patent troll that was formed in Texas specifically to extort money out of the first company, right?
Speaker 0: So why does Eastern Texas?
Speaker 1: Yep All right.
Speaker 1: That was our tech news roundup.
Speaker 1: We will see you again in one year for the next gig nights.
Speaker 1: tech news around.
Speaker 1: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Speaker 0: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 1: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 0: Heat nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows It's actually recorded at night and the picture on patrons for this episode of the ignites are Craig Oliver.
Speaker 1: I'll enjoy citing McNichol just like a dude guy.
Speaker 1: jar topics and linkage you Jennifer Hitchcock Chris midkiff And why st a dy calm J Bants to scoot alone Lee?
Speaker 1: Roberto Kingsley Shawn Yeager Matthew Smith Nicholas Brando mr Strong Strachan for to one creations Chris Reimer and Thomas, huh?
Speaker 1: Shervin von Harl Rory Michelle, Montana Superboys sailor Vista Joshua Joe star Clinton Walton written from New Zealand Ryan parent drew open Lander Finn Daniel Redmond Sean Klein Chris Reimer and Thomas on.
Speaker 1: now I leave you with two sides of the same coin.
Speaker 1: and if you're curious what was going on between the Beginning of the show and the main bits the next Thursday episode will be 2001 in a space odyssey book club review and the following Thursday episode will be a three-part special Water in the ceiling featuring such wonderful moments as rim and Scott living in colony rim living here Scott living in his apartment.
Speaker 1: all this can be yours.
Speaker 1: two Thursday episodes from next Thursday you.