Speaker 1: It's Monday March 18th 2019.
Speaker 1: I'm rim.
Speaker 1: I'm Scott and this is geek nights tonight.
Speaker 1: Algorithmic content curation and why it keeps recommending Nazi shit to your kids.
Speaker 0: Let's do this All right, so yeah, this is podcast I've been listening to.
Speaker 0: you know, I don't listen to too many podcasts But I added one recently called the war on cars.
Speaker 1: That's a very Scott podcast.
Speaker 0: three New York Viking people talking about how shit cars are.
Speaker 1: Yeah Having rented and driven a car recently.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so the thing is that every episode of the show I've listened to has been great except for two.
Speaker 0: the first one Was one where they talked about self-driving cars and everything they said was right except they just have a more Pessimistic outlook and they sort of assumed the worst-case scenario for self-driving cars where I tend to assume a better-case scenario For self-driving cars.
Speaker 0: I assume a pretty good.
Speaker 0: They're basically like assuming like some company will own the cause and and You know, you'll buy one and like who says you'll buy one It's like, you know that they have these assumptions about how it's gonna be right.
Speaker 1: anyway I mean, I don't I don't want any.
Speaker 1: I don't mean to own a car even if there's.
Speaker 0: I have different assumptions about how it's But the point is the current episode.
Speaker 0: their most recent one was simultaneously the best and worst podcast episode I've ever heard.
Speaker 0: Ooh, they interviewed the surviving dude from NPR's car talk.
Speaker 0: Whoa Whoa, that was my face second favorite radio show and revealed that the the dead guy and to some extent the living guy Actually hated cars.
Speaker 1: You know, that sounds about right.
Speaker 1: You know thinking back to the way they talked about cars and it was fantastic.
Speaker 0: the problem is this particular podcast episode.
Speaker 0: They interviewed this guy.
Speaker 0: Uh They did not play the interview.
Speaker 0: they played like a single sentence from the interview of him saying something and then Basically spent like five minutes Commenting on his comment.
Speaker 0: What watch like if I took an email interview Covered out one sentence and wrote three paragraphs after it cut out one sentence and but three paragraphs after it and no point in the Podcast.
Speaker 0: did they play the interview and now I want to punch all of them in the face.
Speaker 0: Just play the fucking interview.
Speaker 1: Jesus Christ is oh my god.
Speaker 1: Is this?
Speaker 0: if you interview someone you can comment on it like after.
Speaker 1: so Scott is what have you just play the fucking interview?
Speaker 0: Is this what happens?
Speaker 0: you can edit it, but just play it.
Speaker 1: when we're at the stage of content creation where?
Speaker 1: Successful relatively large content creators don't know the basics of like radio production and journalism.
Speaker 1: So as a result, they do things like that Like a room.
Speaker 0: is that just what I guess is actually, you know, I don't is somewhat professionally produced.
Speaker 0: You know, it sounds great.
Speaker 1: Well, yeah, but you can hire someone really cheap to make a podcast sound great.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean, I don't I don't think they do.
Speaker 0: they're not like.
Speaker 0: they're not one of those podcasts.
Speaker 0: It's done at a radio station, but they sound like they are.
Speaker 0: Oh, but at the point is just play the fucking interview Jesus Christ.
Speaker 1: Oh my god.
Speaker 0: I have such a low tolerance If you interview someone all I want to hear is what the interview.
Speaker 1: I mean the only podcast I listen to at all these days.
Speaker 0: I imagine if we had like interview with so-and-so on geek night.
Speaker 0: So we played like five sentences from the interview and spent the rest of the time talking.
Speaker 1: I feel like we should do that.
Speaker 0: That's literally what they did in this episode.
Speaker 1: I mean that's even worse than baby's first mistake of get someone on a show to interview and spend most of the time talking at them instead of Asking them questions and listening to them there.
Speaker 0: You want to hear that first?
Speaker 0: You've heard to us talk enough right?
Speaker 0: every fucking episode you want to hear the other person talk.
Speaker 0: yeah, the best interview the best interviewer is someone who gets the other person to talk and talk a lot and say good stuff and then when that person stops talking they ask the question that All you got to do right?
Speaker 0: when you're interviewing your goal is it is not to do anything except say words that catalyze the other person into talking more and better.
Speaker 1: unless Your interview is a buzz-altering of the person you're interviewing Mmm, like if you've cornered some anti-vaxxer Do you be like children?
Speaker 0: even then to a large extent your job is still to make them make a fool of themselves by talk.
Speaker 0: Ah, I want to get them to talk.
Speaker 1: Here's the difference.
Speaker 1: Are you good?
Speaker 1: You know, are you know burning wheel?
Speaker 1: You're not gonna rebut because you're interviewing someone to get them to talk.
Speaker 1: But are you making are you doing something to get them to talk?
Speaker 1: Are you just taking the insight action over and over again?
Speaker 0: You don't rebut by firing at them.
Speaker 0: you rebut by laying there a path before them which includes a spiky pit trap.
Speaker 1: Yep, they're gonna say about.
Speaker 1: they're gonna say something.
Speaker 0: you just need to talk enough to make them walk forward into that pit trap Get out of it and then turn around and walk right back into it again.
Speaker 1: I mean these days.
Speaker 1: the only podcast I can even Dane listening to unless someone else puts them on like casually like when I'm on my own are like NPR like professional ones.
Speaker 0: this finally war on cars podcast sounds like an NPR podcast only it's not.
Speaker 1: well It sounds like they might have some baby's first mistake problems based.
Speaker 1: I can't listen.
Speaker 1: Did you listen to the whole episode?
Speaker 0: I Was hoping the interview would eventually start.
Speaker 1: see there was your false.
Speaker 1: Hope I didn't know I. uh, I have a much dimmer view of podcasting.
Speaker 0: But anyway, listen to all the episodes of that show except for the most recent one where the interview the car tuck.
Speaker 1: So I got to save this.
Speaker 0: my only opening bit is as you might have recalled a while on a Thursday There's best one was the one where they reviewed the Super Bowl commercials and pointed out all the evils of car culture present in them.
Speaker 1: No, all right.
Speaker 1: I'm glad they're singularly focused on hitting cars.
Speaker 1: It was really.
Speaker 0: it was a really good episode.
Speaker 1: They should get you on the show.
Speaker 1: I feel like you'd be their star witness.
Speaker 0: I Wouldn't have anything to say that they don't know.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I just got emailing me like you're gonna get this guy Scott the gig night's guy.
Speaker 1: just trust me get this guy on the show.
Speaker 1: He hates cars Possibly more than either of you.
Speaker 1: So, uh Well, I'll save the full story of this for when we do our next Thursday episode Which is called water in the ceiling, but I have an update.
Speaker 1: my I now have a brand new bespoke door Bathroom made custom to my apartment.
Speaker 0: It was more.
Speaker 0: He's not happy about the door.
Speaker 0: He's happy about the opportunity to use the word bespoke.
Speaker 1: I use that word a lot.
Speaker 1: But the People doing the work, you know I was working from home and they were doing the work and I was sitting here and they come in there and he's kind of Giggling.
Speaker 1: he's like, uh, I assume you want to keep the poop sign cuz I forgot the poop sign is there.
Speaker 1: So the poop sign was affixed permanently to the dull door.
Speaker 1: So I had to carefully remove the poop sign without damaging it so I can put it on the new door as soon as I get The door painted.
Speaker 1: so the poop sign is safe and we'll have a new home at pooping eye level Right in front of my toilet and the full story of this will be on our next Thursday episode of geek.
Speaker 0: So the poop sign is a piece of metal.
Speaker 0: I feel like it's not going anywhere, right?
Speaker 1: You could clean it those little splatter on it slightly bent because it was very difficult to get off the door.
Speaker 0: The thing is about the poop sign is that it's always been attached with adhesive.
Speaker 0: Yep I feel like what you should do is you should perhaps Mount the poop sign onto something or perhaps attach a hook or something else to the back of it So that it may be mounted in a non adhesive fashion.
Speaker 1: But I want it to be fixed and have no movement or flutter at whatsoever.
Speaker 0: cuz bathroom doors get open and closed a lot Yeah, but you can find some way of mounting it.
Speaker 0: Oh, no, I know the way to manage does not involve.
Speaker 1: You know why it's not with adhesive.
Speaker 1: That was the adhesive that came with the poop sign.
Speaker 0: I have evidence In that on the back of the poop sign are two sets of adhesive.
Speaker 1: Oh, you're right.
Speaker 1: So there I replace it with a second adhesive.
Speaker 0: I Phoenix righted you objection.
Speaker 0: Ah, oh my god Presented the evidence immediately.
Speaker 1: Hey, so I do have.
Speaker 1: the real solution though There's that there is the 3m adhesive that is solid but has this tiny little tab.
Speaker 1: You can reach in there and pull on and if you pull on it, it just lets go.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm completely That's how I hold all these hooks around the studio.
Speaker 0: It's called the command hook.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so I'm gonna use that That adhesive on here.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm, and then I can remove it without this trouble ten years from now And I have to replace the door again.
Speaker 1: Poop sign.
Speaker 1: But anyway, I have a thing of the day.
Speaker 1: I'll say for later.
Speaker 1: That is this lawyer who watches Media and comments on like how accurate the lawyer stuff is.
Speaker 0: you watch his law and order and shit.
Speaker 1: Oh, yes, and I don't care about any of that but a while ago.
Speaker 1: He did it's always sunny in Philadelphia.
Speaker 0: Which are lawyers in that?
Speaker 1: Uh, yeah, there's multiple courtroom scenes.
Speaker 1: Okay, and that is some of the funniest shit I've ever seen.
Speaker 1: but someone got him.
Speaker 1: He's an anime fan and someone told him Phoenix Wright exists and he watched episode of Phoenix Wright the anime.
Speaker 1: Yeah, oh no, but he came in being like, I don't know anything about the Japanese legal system So I'm just gonna treat this like it's the US legal system and the rest of this episode is him going.
Speaker 1: Oh my fucking.
Speaker 1: oh I hope Japan isn't like this.
Speaker 0: good lord Japan.
Speaker 0: the thing is Japan is more like that than Japan isn't like that But it's more like that than it should.
Speaker 0: it's enough like that to make him go Like I was.
Speaker 0: one email and be like buddy says this guy if you don't know about this guy I thought I've been following him on social media for many years called Jake Adelstein.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I follow him because He's Jews.
Speaker 0: It was like into Japanese stuff and lives in Japan.
Speaker 0: and he wrote a book about the Yakuza and he wrote a recent book Called Tokyo vice.
Speaker 0: and he wrote a recent book What's it called the devil.
Speaker 0: pay the devil in Bitcoin?
Speaker 0: He wrote a book, right?
Speaker 0: He's a really cool dude.
Speaker 0: Anyway, uh But I think he recently tweeted that like back in the day when he was just a cub reporter in Japan.
Speaker 0: He would go to the the the court or whatever every day and say hey Were there any not guilties?
Speaker 0: because they were so rare.
Speaker 0: any one of them would have been news.
Speaker 0: He went and asked for not guilties like every day to make sure All right, so we got some tech news.
Speaker 1: It's Monday.
Speaker 1: I think Scott's news is first.
Speaker 0: Yes It's a big deal.
Speaker 0: It's the weekend and you know, I'm sitting around my apartment like you do And looking for something to watch like you do and I hope the twitch Habit I have studiously avoided for a long time now.
Speaker 0: and of course in this house of Scott There are so many layers of ad block happening.
Speaker 0: There is the pie hole.
Speaker 0: there is you block origin There is so there is every reasonable ad block Deployment technology.
Speaker 1: you see an ad in the Scott household.
Speaker 1: that is Where you turn around kids?
Speaker 0: Look at the magic.
Speaker 0: It's like finding a rat in the kitchen.
Speaker 0: How the hell did you get it here?
Speaker 1: No, it's like finding a raccoon in the kitchen.
Speaker 1: Like where did you come from?
Speaker 0: It's like when I open the balcony door and a fly comes in and I get my fly swatter.
Speaker 0: Yep Anyway, so I turn on Twitch where I never see an ad and a fucking ad comes up and I'm like what the fuck is This?
Speaker 0: yeah, why I mean like?
Speaker 0: sometimes I see an ad because it's one of those ones like the streamer put it in their stream.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I happens a lot of times during eSports tournaments But this was an actual twitch pre-roll ad.
Speaker 0: the stream was happening and I was not seeing it.
Speaker 0: I'm like, what the fuck is this?
Speaker 0: Why am I seeing this shit and I go and I search and sure enough the top post on the you block origin?
Speaker 1: Reddit already voted the hell up.
Speaker 0: I think twitch just changed their ad system.
Speaker 0: It seems that twitch has changed their ad system in such a way that the ads are somehow like in the real stream With some kind of new technology and the only way to block them is to either pay for twitch turbo which is nine bucks a month because remember twitch prime doesn't block it anymore or to Subscribe to that particular twitch channel and twitch prime only lets you do that to one channel per month.
Speaker 0: Otherwise, you got to pay whatever the streamer is charging if it's even if you do my channel I'm not even a twitch affiliate or whatever.
Speaker 0: It's called Twitch partner.
Speaker 0: you can't subscribe to my twitch channel.
Speaker 0: You're just gonna see ads on it if I stream there.
Speaker 0: So I'm paying for YouTube red because I watch a lot more a premium YouTube premium I pay.
Speaker 0: I watch a lot more YouTube than I watch twitch so I'm gonna still pay for that.
Speaker 1: I know most you block ads.
Speaker 1: it also includes way more than you get from because four fifths of the Revenue that the geek nights like my youtube channel gets is from YouTube premium people who are watching our content.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the ads are like the last fifth.
Speaker 0: So I'm gonna be probably streaming for now on YouTube only cuz I don't want anyone to have to see ads to see my stream.
Speaker 0: And also I'm probably watching a lot less twitch in general.
Speaker 0: I'll only be watching like, you know Much much less.
Speaker 1: I mean, I honestly like I'm gonna have.
Speaker 0: instead what I'm gonna do is watch a lot more Crunchyroll and Netflix that I fucking pay for and don't watch enough of.
Speaker 1: yeah Because once the cost of paying for something like twitch starts to approach the cost of like crunchyroll Which one provides more content, yes good Streams.
Speaker 0: if I'm gonna sit down to watch some autocross fuck it.
Speaker 0: I'll just play some autocross.
Speaker 1: Yep I mean, it's kind of like my.
Speaker 1: my strategy lately has been.
Speaker 0: I hope I don't watch twitch.
Speaker 1: I will watch like the YouTube video of the good twitch stream later because I won't see ads in YouTube.
Speaker 1: I would never watch something live on twitch.
Speaker 0: My hope is that the Streamers will notice that their viewer counts going down.
Speaker 0: I don't think it will be big enough, but hopefully it's big enough that impacts the streamers.
Speaker 1: Well, it's interesting because I feel like there is a heavy overlap between people who care about video game streams And people who know about ad blocking.
Speaker 0: this would actually be less of a problem if twitch made one change And that is because basically subscriber to someone's twitch channel is five dollars a month.
Speaker 0: That's a lot of money for one person.
Speaker 0: if it was it should be 50 set but a dollar a month.
Speaker 0: I would actually probably subscribe to five twitch channels easily.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right but for five dollars a month.
Speaker 0: I'm subscribing to like the AG the AGDQ channel the one month that AGDQ is happening.
Speaker 1: Ah, but AGDQ is if you wait like until later that day.
Speaker 0: It's just on YouTube Yeah, but sometimes you like to watch it live and also they donate that money to the charity It doesn't go to.
Speaker 1: I can just donate money to them.
Speaker 0: I do that also.
Speaker 0: It's just an extra five bucks to make the viewing easier and then you can make your donation five dollars less Even it out.
Speaker 0: No, yeah, whatever but yeah, and then I'll use my free twitch prime on like one person.
Speaker 0: But that's it.
Speaker 1: It'll be interesting to see where this all goes because up until now every time there's been an escalation in the ad wars The ad blockers have always won.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: This is there are ways feels hard to beat though the pie hole can't beat it because it's a DNS based blocker and It would have to just block all of twitch DNS for that to work.
Speaker 1: I would be happy with adblock where I'm watching the twitch stream and it's gonna show me the ad in stream.
Speaker 1: If my ad blocker just blanked the video out Put a little banner that says there's some ad playing and just showed me cat videos instead until the ad was done.
Speaker 0: That would be fine, too But it doesn't do that.
Speaker 1: I know but I'm saying that I don't even care that I lose the time.
Speaker 1: I just don't want to see the ad ever under any circumstances.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: However, it is disappointing though It's like I would be happy with what you just said.
Speaker 0: That's perfectly fine.
Speaker 0: Just blocking the ad is priority one by far.
Speaker 0: But it is kind of upsetting on twitch in particular because on twitch when there is an ad there are things happening behind me.
Speaker 1: I miss it.
Speaker 0: Usually most of the time on a normal stream It's the streamer.
Speaker 0: has you know pushed a button to play an ad to make money and gone to the back.
Speaker 0: Well, I can you do.
Speaker 0: you're not missing much.
Speaker 0: if you're watching eSports, you could be missing something.
Speaker 1: I can push this button right now and make an ad play for all of you.
Speaker 0: Don't do that I'll be mad.
Speaker 1: I could though do not?
Speaker 1: I there was a long time ago.
Speaker 1: We're at a PAX.
Speaker 1: I was actually responsible for pushing that button.
Speaker 1: All right for the like the PAX YouTube live stream for Square Enix and stuff.
Speaker 1: I had to push the button on a schedule and it felt real dirty every time I clicked it.
Speaker 1: That was a long time ago.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so yeah, but We've never encountered the situation yet where the ad blocker the nerds are using no longer works.
Speaker 1: Hopefully it will work soon like ad blocks still work on YouTube.
Speaker 1: Like I pay for the fancy YouTube, but ad block works.
Speaker 1: I actually don't know if it does or not because I always logged it does because I'm not logged into my Personal YouTube account on the HT PC.
Speaker 1: Okay, cuz it's in a public room.
Speaker 1: Like I don't want to risk that I might like something Someone might do something.
Speaker 1: It's a full YouTube.
Speaker 1: like it's a Google account Mmm, I don't want to have to log into it every time I use the HT PC.
Speaker 1: So we have like this dummy throwaway Constantly like that.
Speaker 1: Well, yeah, cuz you don't have people just like sitting at your HT PC when you're might not even be in the room.
Speaker 1: They're in attention, I guess.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's a more public situation.
Speaker 0: people come over.
Speaker 0: I'm not exactly watching the keyboard.
Speaker 0: I guess you could go and like some garbage videos.
Speaker 1: I could go and send you send people emails from your account.
Speaker 1: Okay?
Speaker 1: So in some other news Apparently Scott didn't know this was happening.
Speaker 0: I knew I knew something was happening.
Speaker 0: I just didn't know the full extent.
Speaker 1: I said I want to make the 737 story my news and Scott was like why?
Speaker 1: That's not a big deal.
Speaker 1: And I was like what?
Speaker 0: That's not what I said.
Speaker 0: I said, oh, I don't know why that people are going so crazy about this.
Speaker 0: It's just a plane.
Speaker 0: that's like messed up or something.
Speaker 0: I didn't read the news.
Speaker 0: I just saw a bunch of headlines about it.
Speaker 1: And so you didn't realize that one the 737 max is a pretty brand new plane.
Speaker 0: Okay - I figured it was.
Speaker 0: I thought it was like a mod of the 737 because 737 is an old plane.
Speaker 1: So mod of the 737. what you just said is interesting.
Speaker 1: we'll get back to that.
Speaker 0: Okay, I'm gonna explain this plenty of it.
Speaker 0: that happens all the time right?
Speaker 1: this a 380 a 380 a that's the thing that planes do yeah, and That sometimes means the mod is an entirely new plane Like okay an f-18 Hornet versus like the more the other f-18 Hornet like the enhanced one Basically a completely different feel less disingenuous, right?
Speaker 0: It's like if you make a car and it's a completely new car You shouldn't keep calling it like, you know, if I make a completely new car I shouldn't keep calling it the Ford Taurus if it's not.
Speaker 1: Ah, but what's the right?
Speaker 1: Between an f-16 ABC or D at the same time?
Speaker 1: if I make a for a car and call it the Ford Taurus a it Shouldn't be a completely different car like f-18 versus the super like the Hornet versus the Super Hornet is like a completely different plane Situation even though they have the their origin in the same.
Speaker 0: I will give a pass.
Speaker 0: I'm not super okay with it But I will give a pass to the addition of the word super because Mario Brothers and Super Mario Brothers are nothing alike true
Speaker 1: But they share a common origin and a lot of common like control schemes
Speaker 0: Do they share as much as the f-18 Hornet and Super Hornet?
Speaker 1: Yeah, maybe That gets complicated in a hurry sure and full disclosure I know a lot more about the f-16 and if I talk too much about the f-18 Certain people who listen to the show are gonna come up into my ass about it.
Speaker 0: I Would have to guess if you put them into photos and I had to pick one you could.
Speaker 1: I think you could pick which one.
Speaker 1: Maybe the Super Hornet has more shit on it.
Speaker 1: Okay, that's you look at the Super Hornet like a. wow that has a.
Speaker 0: I can't even give you like the the names of like different Valkyries and Macross except for like two.
Speaker 1: I could from pictures tell the difference between f14 f15 f16 f18 Yeah, f22 f35.
Speaker 0: I could make educated guesses.
Speaker 1: You could tell the f1.
Speaker 0: so F1 17 I can do b2 I can wait.
Speaker 1: said you get a guess is what.
Speaker 1: what's any difference between an f14 and f15?
Speaker 1: Bigger Faster between an f14 and literally any other plane I mentioned.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: Okay older cuz it's a lower number.
Speaker 1: Uh, yeah, you're technically correct Said educated guess.
Speaker 1: Anyway, here's the deal.
Speaker 1: So the 737 max is Pretty Fundamentally different from a 737 in some ways and that it uses much larger engines.
Speaker 1: So the engines had to be moved on the wings.
Speaker 1: So the flight profile is More different than an effort 737 than you might expect.
Speaker 1: Okay, it's designed to be much more fuel-efficient.
Speaker 0: That's kind of why even with bigger engines is more fuel-efficient.
Speaker 0: Uh, yeah, generally big right they run at lower rpm or whatever that you measure for jet engines base There's more to it than a jet engines don't have rpm.
Speaker 0: Do they or do they?
Speaker 1: Baby, I mean they do.
Speaker 1: Okay, basically It's easier to make a larger jet engine more efficient fuel wise for reasons.
Speaker 1: Okay There's a lot of reasons why that's the case.
Speaker 0: I know as little as I know about regular engines.
Speaker 0: I know that's about jet hitch.
Speaker 1: I'm going.
Speaker 1: so my knowledge is going off.
Speaker 0: I know the fundamental theory of how a jet engine works and that's it.
Speaker 1: I went to Starbase which was this like Air Force recruitment program.
Speaker 1: when I was a kid at the Air National Guard base I learned all I learned like a scary lot about like fighter jets and like Military nonsense around planes.
Speaker 1: and then I am a nerd who cared a lot about the f-16 Falcon in particular.
Speaker 1: That's pretty much the extent of my knowledge.
Speaker 1: But anyway, so this is a new plane that is based on the hull and like the systems of a 737 It has a system in it called MCAS.
Speaker 0: What's that stand for?
Speaker 1: Maneuvering Characteristics Augmentation System.
Speaker 0: Okay Yeah, that's like something from a Gundam anime.
Speaker 1: So basically modern planes are mostly fly-by-wire like yeah, you move the stick this it is not pneumatically directly moving a control surface somewhere because that ship sailed a long time ago don't say.
Speaker 1: the reason why I'm obsessed with the f-16 is because it was like The modern fly-by-wire system like that the I've flown a real f-16 simulator.
Speaker 1: The control arm is like off to the side and it's fully fly-by-wire.
Speaker 1: It's fucking crazy and weird Because the computer has to fly the plane.
Speaker 1: So Airliners are the same way.
Speaker 1: There's a lot of systems at play.
Speaker 1: MCAS Effectively does a bunch of things to make.
Speaker 1: the 737 max that has bigger engines and a higher danger of stalling And different flight characteristics at low speed and during certain situations feel like a regular 737. so pilots don't have to be like completely retrained on this new plane.
Speaker 1: Someone who can fly a 737 can read the documentation and then ostensibly fly a 737 max.
Speaker 1: It'll feel pretty much the same.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I never really.
Speaker 0: I mean I figured you know, it's like flying is obviously, you know Something you have to train a lot for and spend a lot of hours learning.
Speaker 0: But I sort of had the idea that like hey if you can fly like, you know one plane one commercial jet You can fly another commercial jet without having to learn too much different their systems.
Speaker 0: I can drive a car I've never driven before.
Speaker 0: pretty much immediately They will.
Speaker 0: you have to do some work to fly a different plane, but how much really?
Speaker 1: they will have many complex systems and characteristics.
Speaker 1: It'll often be very different.
Speaker 1: things like speeds Like the way to get out of certain kinds of situations might be radically different.
Speaker 1: Like no this plane if it gets into this situation You got a nose down hard.
Speaker 1: that might be very counterintuitive to another plane that has a different characteristic in that particular situation.
Speaker 1: Interesting, so and I'm skipping a lot because this could be a whole show and if I go deeper I'm gonna get something wrong.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you probably already got something.
Speaker 1: I probably already gotten some minor things wrong.
Speaker 1: So here's the deal.
Speaker 1: this system Was not well publicized to the people who were trained in the 737 or in our flying 737 maxes.
Speaker 1: assuming they will behave similarly to the 737 as they flown before they will behave similar.
Speaker 1: similarly This system will actually take control of the stick in a certain situation and bring the nose down Automatically, okay to avoid a stall.
Speaker 1: there appears to be a bug in this system.
Speaker 1: Oops where?
Speaker 1: During takeoff or shortly after takeoff It will think that the plane is entering this dangerous stall condition that is only a problem on the max and not on a regular 737 and then start nosing down.
Speaker 1: if The pilot and co-pilot the flight crew don't know that the system will automatically fucking do this on its own And will override you They'll pull the stick up because the planes nosing down.
Speaker 1: That's not good Assuming that like the previous system their input were all will supersede any automated system.
Speaker 1: in this situation.
Speaker 1: The MCAS will then say oh shit.
Speaker 1: The pilots fighting me nose down more.
Speaker 1: Fuck you and the plane will just crash.
Speaker 1: Okay, the procedure is to disable this system and take control of the plane.
Speaker 0: that makes sense.
Speaker 1: Best I can tell and this is the topic.
Speaker 1: you can read the details.
Speaker 1: This change was not well documented for pilots and This might be an utter fucking shit show.
Speaker 1: This is killed there.
Speaker 1: There have been two full fatality hull losses.
Speaker 0: in short I only knew about one of them.
Speaker 1: Yeah, cuz you don't read the news or know anything about the real world at all.
Speaker 0: I just go past the headline and I only read what I actually seems like it matters to me.
Speaker 0: So to 737, but whatever that doesn't seem to matter to Scott to brand new 737 max has had complete hull losses that killed everyone aboard.
Speaker 1: That's a big goddamn deal.
Speaker 1: I mean one is a big deal I didn't know is - so you can read the stories because this is all developing about like the whole this.
Speaker 1: This is a big deal.
Speaker 0: That is my main thing.
Speaker 0: Is that yet again?
Speaker 0: I can guarantee you what should happen if there was justice in the world Is that the executives at Boeing should all go to jail forever for murdering all those people?
Speaker 0: Including all the way down to whoever is responsible, you know the whole chain But no one will go to jail even though they are mass murderers.
Speaker 1: This is escalating rapidly.
Speaker 0: negligence So, let's see doesn't need to be a life sentence.
Speaker 1: But you know, here's why this is important for technology.
Speaker 0: Meanwhile, some guy robbed the convenience stores in jail for a long time because I want to.
Speaker 1: I don't want to make this the whole Show.
Speaker 1: I want to get into the main bed.
Speaker 1: There are two Technology things that happen here.
Speaker 1: They're very important one.
Speaker 1: This is there act 25 all over again.
Speaker 1: Do you know what there are?
Speaker 1: 25 is?
Speaker 0: Google and there are 25 and then trying to act like he's smart because he knows about there.
Speaker 0: I know a lot about.
Speaker 1: there are 25 because I studied it.
Speaker 0: Yeah listeners don't know what it is either.
Speaker 1: I'll bet some listeners know some most don't.
Speaker 1: so there are 25 long story short.
Speaker 0: I'll just go find something.
Speaker 0: I know about that.
Speaker 0: You don't?
Speaker 1: there are 25. software controls a radiation therapy machine.
Speaker 1: Oh bug and software fucking kills people.
Speaker 0: just give some cancer.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: Wait, what burns them?
Speaker 1: shoots them with a deadly radiation laser.
Speaker 1: You know what?
Speaker 0: This is actually relevant.
Speaker 0: I was watching.
Speaker 0: My mom wants it.
Speaker 0: My mom loves James Bond, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, but there's a James Bond exhibit in the city She wants to go to whoo.
Speaker 0: Emily Amanda has not seen enough James Bond really.
Speaker 0: Oh never even a Sean Connery James Bond at all.
Speaker 1: Oh, so dude, here's the quiz the fundamental question.
Speaker 1: Do you even tell her Lazenby exists or you just skip that one?
Speaker 0: I'm just saying so.
Speaker 0: he was.
Speaker 0: I like that one to be watch Thunderball yesterday and the scene in which James Bond is getting therapy because he just got beat up.
Speaker 0: yeah, he's in like a health spa resort and The she gets put on like this, you know Obviously not good.
Speaker 0: machine.
Speaker 0: that like basically shakes you to sort of stretch out your spine a little bit, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, and the bad guy comes in and cranks it up to the max which is super dangerous and it's gonna kill him.
Speaker 0: Yeah And my question is why does a marital therapy?
Speaker 0: Machine even have a setting to go that high to where that why would you would never put it on that setting?
Speaker 0: and I was Thinking and my the thing that immediately came to mind is like yeah you go to the dentist x-ray.
Speaker 0: It doesn't have a setting to where you could like aim it at someone and kill it like it doesn't Option.
Speaker 0: Well, I mean it did way back in the day But like a lot of a modern one does not have the setting of zap.
Speaker 0: someone with x-rays until they have cancer.
Speaker 0: It's just not an option.
Speaker 1: Oh Scott.
Speaker 1: How do you think?
Speaker 0: radiation therapy machines generate their radiation Isn't there just like a piece of uranium in there and then it opens up a little field and then it zaps.
Speaker 0: So they're all.
Speaker 1: they're all different.
Speaker 1: There's a lot of different ways to do.
Speaker 0: It's like there's a radioactive thing in there and some of them Yeah some of them also have like tubes cuz like, you know old fancy electric like cool those glass tubes.
Speaker 0: you zap electricity through them and Then they zap x-rays out everywhere.
Speaker 0: You could just make one of those.
Speaker 0: It's aimed.
Speaker 1: There's a bunch of modern and smaller and better.
Speaker 1: but the Boeing thing and the therac 25 thing share something very much in common software changes that affect the real world.
Speaker 1: if design chitily will fucking kill people.
Speaker 1: and Computer science and software engineering the world over continues to largely ignore this kind of programming treating programming more like traditional engineering in certain situations.
Speaker 0: I think that the the people who are the best at programming are not necessarily working on You know these sorts of things.
Speaker 0: So if you're not familiar is not as someone who is a programmer who has had plenty of opportunities to go work on say software for medical devices.
Speaker 0: That is not a thing you desirable to go work on.
Speaker 0: I'm sure there are smart people working on those things somewhere But most of the smartest people are working on stupid shit like social networks.
Speaker 1: So the other thing that happens is that traditionally like with this is the internet.
Speaker 1: governments governance right the u.s.
Speaker 1: For a long time set the state like the u.s.
Speaker 1: Would regulate something and the rest of the world with either follow suit or Ignore us and we would basically win by default like that's how things have generally gone with the internet.
Speaker 1: The same has been true for a lot of things and one of those things is aviation regulation.
Speaker 1: Until this incident for basically all of modern history the entire world looked to the FAA for things like should this plane be grounded?
Speaker 1: After the first hull loss the FAA didn't do anything.
Speaker 1: after the second hull loss the FAA also didn't do anything.
Speaker 1: The Chinese equivalent of the FAA said fuck it these planes are grounded in China.
Speaker 1: Europe and the rest of the world said we're doing what China did And the FAA still refused to ground them probably because of some combination of corruption and incompetence.
Speaker 1: and What happened because of this disaster?
Speaker 1: is that as of now?
Speaker 1: The FAA basically lost its credibility as like the guiding light of aviation regulation Around the world and the EU and China have already come in to fill that.
Speaker 1: I don't know if that can ever be repaired.
Speaker 1: I think we I think the US just lost control of aviation regulation.
Speaker 1: For the foreseeable future and for the lives of anyone alive today like that was a fundamental She see change that will have drastic ramifications for the time to come.
Speaker 1: Okay, just like with the internet No one cares what the US thinks about the internet anywhere because their FCC has very similar problems now to the FAA.
Speaker 1: So yeah, you can read more about that.
Speaker 1: That's plenty of news, I think we should just get right into Things of the day.
Speaker 1: what he got.
Speaker 0: so this looks like it's about Mario maker protection about programming.
Speaker 1: Oh, I saw this video, but I didn't watch it yet.
Speaker 0: So this video is kind of long, so I'm just gonna explain it to you.
Speaker 0: real simple like right.
Speaker 0: so Basically they have a situation where you want to trigger certain events to happen in your Mario level right and That would otherwise be impossible to trigger, but they found out this bug To where?
Speaker 0: basically if you have two pal blocks and then a bullet bill gun on top of the two pal blocks all
Speaker 1: right This is already very specific,
Speaker 0: and they're on one of those like tracks that goes up and down You know like the kind you would normally have a moving platform on a line.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right so you.
Speaker 0: so basically they go up and down right.
Speaker 0: if normally that is like when you set that up.
Speaker 0: It's a. it's like a global object.
Speaker 0: and that global object like spawns is when the screen spawns And is always there even if it's not on screen all right, so you don't to see it right.
Speaker 0: And the thing is even though that's his global object.
Speaker 0: What can happen is if Any sort of lag in the game happens.
Speaker 0: so for example touching a checkpoint taking damage?
Speaker 0: Picking up a mushroom those things Mario goes doot doot doot or like you right.
Speaker 0: these certain lag causing events Will cause the the second pal block and the bullet bill gun to separate by a few pixels.
Speaker 1: Oh, I see a little gap there to separate.
Speaker 0: It's called the big gap the giant gap.
Speaker 0: It's called the giant gap because the guy who discovered it his internet name includes the word giant.
Speaker 0: It's not actually a gap.
Speaker 0: It's not actually a big gap.
Speaker 0: It's a gap.
Speaker 0: that was you know the same way.
Speaker 0: I need giant gasps like how kaizo block isn't is about the guy who yeah named kaizo.
Speaker 0: It's a giant gap because anyway it causes the top two things like become separated right and then Disappear bounce away, whatever.
Speaker 0: so now you can basically set up your Mario maker level such that if Mario you know takes damage touches a checkpoint or gets a mushroom you can now trigger a cascade of events Right because that pal block and that bullet bill gun that now fly away Right from their their original position can trigger p-switches Or all kinds of make make bat push bad guys into the scene do all sorts of crazy shit And is a really fascinating way of programming.
Speaker 0: you know using You know Mario maker and also this guy's channel is full of all kinds of stuff like they made turn-based games in Mario maker All sorts of nonsense.
Speaker 0: so check out the whole channel, but this video in particular You don't have to watch because I just explained it to you.
Speaker 1: this reminds me a lot of something I haven't used as my thing of the day yet where someone figured out why there's this one mole playing rough in one specific spot in all of earthbound and It's.
Speaker 1: it's a very similar discussion about how important this one encounter is in the game, but I'll save that for another time because my thing of the day is Something that our friend chase would love.
Speaker 1: I got a video tearing this thing down Scott.
Speaker 1: what is the best way to cook a hot dog?
Speaker 0: Mr.. Cook a hot dog?
Speaker 0: yeah fire all right.
Speaker 1: so on a fire in a grill?
Speaker 0: no no no I mean like you put the hot dog on a stick and you put okay So in a fire.
Speaker 1: so would number two be like on a grill with fire under it.
Speaker 0: That's not.
Speaker 0: that's not a bad way.
Speaker 0: You could do a lot worse.
Speaker 1: Yep number three.
Speaker 1: I guess would then be just boiling water.
Speaker 0: Boiling water is really bad.
Speaker 0: I'm sure you could there.
Speaker 0: I'm sure the boiler I guess there must be a lot of ways better.
Speaker 0: You know what I don't.
Speaker 0: actually you know what's better than boiling water.
Speaker 0: It's not a good way, but it's better than boiling water.
Speaker 0: now Just toaster of it on the highest setting yeah, put it on a piece of tinfoil in there.
Speaker 0: I do that when I'm really lazy.
Speaker 1: So what if I told you that there was a way in the 60s to cook hot dogs in an entirely novel way?
Speaker 1: And this shit is horrifying.
Speaker 1: The presto hotdogger would just put mains voltage through the hot dog.
Speaker 0: That'll work.
Speaker 1: Yes, it does work.
Speaker 1: This is a device where it's a little dangerous.
Speaker 0: Uh yeah It'll work.
Speaker 1: Crazy dangerous.
Speaker 0: Totally works though.
Speaker 1: This is like those Asian In a lot of countries like in Southeast Asia.
Speaker 0: It's a little fire hazard, but you know it works.
Speaker 1: Or like in the Philippines Like you'll you'll have instead of a hot water heater You just have a shower head with like just current running through it.
Speaker 0: There's plenty of other ways to cook the hot dog.
Speaker 0: You like take a welding torch to it.
Speaker 1: It's like yeah, so this was basically this will cook a hot dog in 60 seconds.
Speaker 1: You can put a bunch of hot dogs in it.
Speaker 0: Takes that I figured it would do like instantly like electric chair like pshh.
Speaker 1: Well it takes 60 seconds because it's six hot dogs, and you only got 120 volts.
Speaker 1: and However much amperage comes out of a wall outlet in the US in 1967.
Speaker 0: What if you use the the dryer outlet with the?
Speaker 0: So the power pump.
Speaker 1: My thing of the day is not that the presto hotdogger exists as ridiculous as this is.
Speaker 0: I thought that that would be the thing of the day.
Speaker 1: My thing of the day is big Clive Demonstrating the hotdogger because he got one.
Speaker 1: Oh, no, and then he puts it in a 220 line to see what happens.
Speaker 0: Oh, no, that's an exact thing I just suggested without even knowing that's what was gonna happen.
Speaker 1: There are only two possibilities either it cooks the hot dogs twice as fast or the hot dogs explode.
Speaker 0: I'm not gonna spoil it please.
Speaker 1: So the video is called turbo charging a 120 volt presto hotdogger on 250 volts.
Speaker 1: In The meta moment the geek night's book club book was 2001 a space odyssey.
Speaker 1: we talked about it.
Speaker 0: finally What's the new book?
Speaker 1: I got to finally make my argument that hell and the leopard are the same goddamn thing.
Speaker 1: Okay, did you watch the movie again?
Speaker 1: No, I'm gonna watch the movie again soon.
Speaker 1: Okay, cuz I haven't seen the movie since I was in.
Speaker 1: I Think either fifth grade or sixth grade too long.
Speaker 1: It's been a long time.
Speaker 1: I gotta watch the movie again.
Speaker 1: Maybe I'll watch it on the train to Zenk icon this weekend because geek nights will be live at Zenk icon this weekend doing three panels on Saturday the secret guide to running panels on Saturday Not so long after that the 40 table.
Speaker 1: take on tabletop games.
Speaker 1: You must play and on Sunday morning play dirty to win.
Speaker 0: and while rim is at Zenk icon I will be preparing a panel for PAX East which is the week after that the real harm of game.
Speaker 1: Oh shit, it's gonna be a good panel.
Speaker 1: I found a tweet about some shit Google's doing.
Speaker 1: that we got to include in the panel.
Speaker 1: Did you make a presentation at least yet?
Speaker 0: I made a Google Doc that it was now easily going to be made into a person.
Speaker 1: Scott I'm just saying I wrote the entire nostalgia versus game design panel four days before we did it.
Speaker 0: Oh good I'm way ahead of you good.
Speaker 0: All right, so my Google Doc is waiting.
Speaker 1: I'm curious to see how well how you put this panel together because I got I got some content I got to give you.
Speaker 0: Oh give it to me cuz I make the slides.
Speaker 0: I've already put together most of the panel.
Speaker 1: also Google that remember I pay for a Google or an Adobe stock account.
Speaker 1: So I can make slides that are 100% copyright free.
Speaker 0: All right Well, I usually you know, I'll make all the slides without photos.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we'll just start filming it.
Speaker 1: Let me know when you start making those.
Speaker 1: I'll start filling in like good images.
Speaker 1: If we need images because I pay for this I'm gonna use it.
Speaker 1: So beyond that after PAX East We have no conventions until PAX West.
Speaker 0: It's summer.
Speaker 0: go outside.
Speaker 1: Oh my god.
Speaker 1: We used to go to a lot of cons in the summer, but we don't anymore.
Speaker 1: But I haven't picked the new booklet book yet.
Speaker 1: This is your last chance.
Speaker 1: you either have.
Speaker 1: I'm either gonna pick nine Fox Gambit or Troy gambit or ten Fox game or Troy Dennings pages of pain, which is a licensed planescape novel That I read once a long time ago.
Speaker 1: Okay, it's gonna be one of the two.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you gotta tell me I can tell you this though if you pick pages of pain I will also pick a bad fantasy novel.
Speaker 0: I read when I was young.
Speaker 0: That's fine.
Speaker 1: I'm all about reading bad novels as a kid so I can just look on my past self with shame.
Speaker 1: But interestingly Multiple listeners have already coming out telling me to not pick nine Fox Gambit because they're afraid of it.
Speaker 1: But so far all the things they've said about it just make me want to read it more.
Speaker 1: Oh, no, so they're like, oh, it's too dense and full of like ridiculous like what like the prince of nothing like, okay Throw the proper noun gobbledygook at me.
Speaker 1: My body is ready.
Speaker 1: Linear algebra something something sure the gnosis the gnosis man.
Speaker 0: So yeah, what do you see?
Speaker 1: We'll be judging anime soon.
Speaker 1: I'm doing some work to get gig nights presents.
Speaker 0: You tell the judging anime might be a week late again cuz we got a bunch of convention.
Speaker 1: Yep after PAX East is when all the other content will start up again because We got nothing to do but bike around in the Sun after that.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: so this is becoming a much more serious problem recently than it was in the past, but We haven't actually talked about this.
Speaker 1: We've talked about some related items, but here's the deal.
Speaker 1: in the modern world there's a bunch of platforms that have content hosted on them and Their entire business model is centered on the idea that People who are not them make content that is on that platform and they monetize that content in some way.
Speaker 0: Because hosting your own content on the internet is far too difficult for the vast majority of people.
Speaker 1: now, dude It's too difficult for us.
Speaker 1: We can host we're like on our own effectively by paying people to like provided Podcasts and our website but YouTube live streaming video.
Speaker 1: this shit would not be on anywhere in the internet Dude, I just can't pay for it I can't.
Speaker 0: we could tell their people can't even host a blog without Someone hosting like making a website like blog spot for them.
Speaker 1: I could host this stuff if we had like four listeners Anyway, so we could use bit torrent.
Speaker 1: Yeah, no one would listen, but this applies to a lot of things.
Speaker 1: this applies to like YouTube and it applies to like Twitch But it also applies to things like Amazon where other people sell stuff on Amazon.
Speaker 1: Amazon just provides the platform for people to buy that stuff and they take a cut.
Speaker 1: now They're also dipping into selling stuff direct app stores instead of going to a website and downloading the XE Yep, so this is a. this is a big common primary part of the modern internet.
Speaker 1: ostensibly it might have replaced a lot of a web 2.0 was supposed to be and made the Internet much more consumer oriented and there's a whole other can of worms there.
Speaker 1: This is a big primary reality of the modern internet.
Speaker 1: the problem is Thus the content sets are so big that I'm not saying it's impossible to curate it with humans.
Speaker 1: I'm saying no one is willing to put the effort and money forth to curate this with humans.
Speaker 1: It is not part of their business model.
Speaker 1: I mean listen.
Speaker 0: I couldn't even sort my mp3s.
Speaker 1: I still haven't.
Speaker 1: I have that same same directory, but I've been copying 1994.
Speaker 0: imagine if your job is to sort through YouTube videos.
Speaker 0: look at the people whose job It was to like flag content on Facebook who went crazy because they're seeing all that garbage content.
Speaker 1: Have any of you read that expose of what it's like to be a Facebook content moderator like.
Speaker 0: it's like It's like a third-party outsourced place.
Speaker 0: It's like the worst job ever.
Speaker 0: you get clinical depression like they Sit in a building of an Arizona or some shit reading the worst of the internet all fucking day.
Speaker 0: just in Trying to you know figure out not only do you have to look at all that garbage, but you have to like Carefully know what's which stuff is okay on the Facebook guidelines and which stuff isn't.
Speaker 0: you can't just use your own common sense And if you mess up even like a few times you like lose your job.
Speaker 0: So it's super high pressure, and you're looking at all this garbage content.
Speaker 1: You're looking at the worst the internet has to offer at any given day.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's not good times Your brain.
Speaker 1: so the even if we were even if like Companies committed to having human curation There is a human toll.
Speaker 1: that is.
Speaker 0: even South Park had the episode that showed like all the like.
Speaker 0: you know they showed Kids in like a foreign country.
Speaker 1: you know moderating The year I was the like deputy manager of the packs like live streaming team the people who would literally sit during packs and Moderate and curate the twitch comments on our live streams like I saw some shit.
Speaker 1: That was really depressing to do.
Speaker 1: I Was blocking people so fast it was.
Speaker 1: it was actually like honestly disturbing to deal with that And that was just for a few hours for a couple of nights once text only.
Speaker 1: yeah text only.
Speaker 1: I saw some shit that I can't forget.
Speaker 1: So all that aside We have moved on to the idea like most companies have algorithmic ways to curate content.
Speaker 0: now We're not.
Speaker 0: this has worked really well for example for blocking spam in your email.
Speaker 0: Yeah curate your emails now.
Speaker 1: Here's the problem.
Speaker 1: the reason it works for spam blocking and emails is that one as a society we all agreed We'd rather miss a legit email than ever see spam again.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I look at my spam folder like whenever I remember to once in a while just to double-check.
Speaker 0: I see some stuff in there.
Speaker 0: usually it's like a newsletter that I tried to unsubscribe to and failed or An email from someone weird yep, but it's a real person, but you know what.
Speaker 1: even then I'm willing.
Speaker 0: I don't get.
Speaker 1: I don't care like with phone calls I don't get spam phone calls cuz I'm willing just not ever answer my phone again.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like I just a white list only anyway, but who mod the people who monetize email.
Speaker 1: They are served by You not seeing spam because they don't get a cut of the spam.
Speaker 1: the spam just angers you.
Speaker 1: you lose their service.
Speaker 1: less Mmm, but with say YouTube is a good example.
Speaker 1: with YouTube How does YouTube make money?
Speaker 1: YouTube makes more money if you watch more videos.
Speaker 0: yep?
Speaker 1: Just the more hours you watch content the more money They make mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: so they have incentive to get you an individual user to watch as much YouTube as possible.
Speaker 1: So how do they do this?
Speaker 1: they use?
Speaker 1: Algorithms to look at you and try to figure out based on the stuff this person likes and the videos They've watched and what other people like them like.
Speaker 1: what video could we recommend right after they finish this watching this video?
Speaker 1: To where they'll just keep watching forever right?
Speaker 0: yeah They don't.
Speaker 0: they tune this algorithm a court right.
Speaker 0: the the the gmail spam algorithm is tuned to be like all right.
Speaker 0: Only show this person real emails and not spam emails right.
Speaker 0: we want to you know get the garbage emails in the trash as much As possible.
Speaker 0: the YouTube recommendation algorithm is tuned.
Speaker 0: make this person watch as much YouTube as possible.
Speaker 0: It's not tuned to make this person as happy as possible or make this person as good as possible or anything like that.
Speaker 0: It's just make this person watch as much YouTube as we can get them to watch make them stay on the site And now that such it exceeds in doing what it says it wants to do.
Speaker 1: now Let's skip the other problem that just came up from this.
Speaker 1: if You design something like that on one hand you are providing a stream of content.
Speaker 1: if like say it works perfectly the algorithm is 100% accurate.
Speaker 1: I watched some ridiculous like Sonic the Hedgehog Neil, Sisorega matchup, and then it immediately recommends some weird Garfield he-man mashup.
Speaker 1: like it 100% knows what rim wants to see next.
Speaker 0: yeah, that's great right definitely where he wants to see.
Speaker 1: But is that not also creating a highly addictive stream of content That could cause addictive behaviors in someone like rim?
Speaker 1: What's the difference between designing a game that people play a lot because they like it and designing a game that people play a lot?
Speaker 1: Because they're addicted to it?
Speaker 1: And is it different if you design the thing to addict people in the first place?
Speaker 1: same can of worms.
Speaker 0: There's a big can of worms around the word addiction to right cuz like addicted to a video game isn't the same as being addicted To heroin.
Speaker 1: ah though.
Speaker 1: They're.
Speaker 1: they're clinically shockingly similar, but also not well.
Speaker 1: the way that they're not is Interesting because the physical heroin addiction is actually way less dangerous than most people realize.
Speaker 1: It's easier to get off a hair, and then they get off a say alcohol.
Speaker 0: That's true.
Speaker 1: But anyway, I want to skip that conversation of what if the algorithms actually worked perfectly.
Speaker 1: It's still a problem because the algorithms don't work perfectly.
Speaker 1: the garbage the algorithms are causing Specific real harms.
Speaker 1: that arguably led to that massive shooting in New Zealand.
Speaker 1: right it just happened.
Speaker 0: so the One major problem is the way that most of them work including the ones that are like Amazon You.
Speaker 0: this is what you should buy.
Speaker 0: is they?
Speaker 0: just look at what other people who do the same things as you also did Right?
Speaker 0: so you know if I watch a lot of kpop videos, and I just watched one and that video I just watched.
Speaker 0: it looks at the says all right.
Speaker 0: who else watched similar videos to Scott and also watch this video?
Speaker 0: He just watched all right.
Speaker 0: What video did a lot of those people watch that Scott hasn't seen yet.
Speaker 0: oop this one like almost everyone who watches the first?
Speaker 0: Video Scott just watched also watch this, but Scott didn't watch it.
Speaker 0: yet there you go Right.
Speaker 0: so the problem is is if you hang in a community Say a video game community, and you watch some Mario video And it just turns out that there is a large community of Mario people who are also.
Speaker 0: I don't know Nazis.
Speaker 0: Then the Mario video will at the end suggest to you hey You know there's a lot of Mario people out there who are Nazis.
Speaker 0: you should check out this Nazi shit and This one you might say.
Speaker 1: why would so many Mario fans be into Nazis?
Speaker 1: well you saw a gamergate right the out there.
Speaker 1: It's a problem.
Speaker 0: algorithm can't actually tell what's in the content of the video at really much at all.
Speaker 0: It's mostly just.
Speaker 0: this is a video ID.
Speaker 0: This is also a video ID.
Speaker 0: the correlation between the viewership of both of these videos is high.
Speaker 0: Someone has watched video a. I will recommend video B. I don't know what's in them.
Speaker 1: This is why if you watch it is blind.
Speaker 1: any video on the internet about like a recent movie Anything that gets like Nazis and Gomer Gators and all the shitlords active For various reasons those people tend to be the kinds of people who watch a lot of YouTube videos So they tend their tastes tend to be over represented and overlap heavily with other non shithead non Nazi people.
Speaker 1: But if you watch any content stream on YouTube It's only a few videos before.
Speaker 1: you get like some Jordan Peterson nonsense.
Speaker 1: you get some anti-feminist nonsense.
Speaker 1: you get straight-up Nazi recruitment video right.
Speaker 0: there are lots of cases where for example Maybe you are really into gardening right and you go find some nice gardening videos.
Speaker 0: Well, it just so happens that on the internet They're a large part of the community for gardening are people who want to grow their own food because they're all like.
Speaker 1: you know You're going with this.
Speaker 0: I have specific examples of this.
Speaker 0: they're all like hippie-dippie right and they're you know They're all into like clean eating and some other nonsense.
Speaker 0: Oh, and they're also anti-vax people.
Speaker 0: So you just looked up your innocent gardening because you wanted your flower to grow and by the way vaccines will kill your children, so Conspiracy type.
Speaker 1: people who arguably have their own mental disorders Tend to go down YouTube rabbit holes and further reinforce this.
Speaker 1: so YouTube Tends to just funnel people toward a relatively small number of Extremely toxic rabbit holes and then just keep them there forever Because that generates a lot of controversy and a lot of views.
Speaker 1: and the algorithm says wow Those white kids started watching a lot more Mario videos and a lot of Mario adjacent videos and here's Hitler, right?
Speaker 0: So the thing is like we said having humans do this is not is not perfect.
Speaker 0: Having algorithms do is even worse.
Speaker 0: and the thing is there is a solution to this.
Speaker 0: That's sort of obvious, but no one really implements it and if they do they do it reluctantly.
Speaker 1: I'm curious what you think because I have a lot of ideas about how to handle right?
Speaker 0: Well, I mean, it's not nothing's ever gonna be perfect perfect.
Speaker 0: But the thing is it's like.
Speaker 0: You know.
Speaker 0: You can't handle tons and tons of content with just human beings and there is the human cost for those human beings who would be Doing it.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: The algorithm is clearly fuck not gonna do it, right?
Speaker 0: You need some sort of combination of the to a human wielding an algorithm.
Speaker 0: Yes, right Editorial input into an algorithm.
Speaker 0: So it's like, okay listen YouTube algorithm, you know I see that, you know, these people have watched this but seriously just like no Nazis ever right seriously No anti-vax shit ever doesn't matter what other people watch.
Speaker 0: just don't recommend this to anyone ever.
Speaker 0: just you know This whole swath.
Speaker 0: just get it out of here, right some editorial human input into the algorithm.
Speaker 0: that will sort of you know Carve things up in a mostly as good as we can way constantly work on improving it all the time Right.
Speaker 0: So hopefully, you know, you won't have bad shit like this happen Now.
Speaker 0: the reason so most companies are willing to do this?
Speaker 0: Well, no, there are cases where they do this.
Speaker 0: For example, they do it on Google search.
Speaker 0: true Right, Google search does this.
Speaker 0: they just do it as little as possible, right?
Speaker 0: When people are searching for like do stuff and Nazi stuff was coming up They like they went in and they put in a fix for that.
Speaker 0: It's like they can do it.
Speaker 0: It's like they're just really hesitant to do it because they believe in algorithms They have like its philosophy of not interfering of being fair with the algorithm.
Speaker 0: I think other people have the opposite flow.
Speaker 0: No one has this mixed middle philosophy.
Speaker 1: I think it's more nuanced and more insidious than that.
Speaker 1: I think part of the problem is that These platforms not so much regular old Google search because who Google searches for things anymore.
Speaker 1: They type into good.
Speaker 1: I think most people type into Google just to get the first link.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but the the monetization models of these platforms Kind of don't want to turn away revenue.
Speaker 1: They want them they.
Speaker 1: I think they want the shitheads and Nazis to keep using the platform and just not cause Advertisers to stop advertising on the rest of the platform Mmm, I think they don't want to turn away audience and every time they exhibit editorial control It'll cause quote-unquote controversy and they'll lose some percentage of the people who would use their platform.
Speaker 1: And they'll also now have set a precedent to where when some other group complains they now have editorial control.
Speaker 1: It opens up to potential legal liability and all sorts of stuff.
Speaker 1: There's a lot of reasons why they don't want to exhibit editorial control.
Speaker 1: They'd rather be able to play in the platform and only react as opposed to be proactive.
Speaker 0: the platform That'd be like if you know, you're at a party at my house and some Nazis came over and you blame my house.
Speaker 0: Yep, it's like not my house's fault.
Speaker 0: It's like you decide who comes to your party and not it's your house.
Speaker 0: It's not the house's fault.
Speaker 0: if Nazis are in there.
Speaker 0: That's because you're a Nazi sympathize.
Speaker 1: Twitter will not just say white supremacy is banned.
Speaker 1: They just won't do it.
Speaker 0: They can.
Speaker 1: they could trivially say it.
Speaker 1: They could also trivially enforce it.
Speaker 1: they refuse to that.
Speaker 1: we disagree on the first principle.
Speaker 1: They tend to these tech companies tell you what's like.
Speaker 0: we believe in free speech, right?
Speaker 0: The thing is free speech means the government coming in and saying white supremacist talk is not okay.
Speaker 0: I actually don't want anyone to go to jail purely for say waving a Nazi flag.
Speaker 0: That should not put you in jail.
Speaker 0: It might get you beat up.
Speaker 0: That's okay.
Speaker 0: Right doing you know, if you if you then, you know act on any of your Nazi beliefs Yeah, you should be.
Speaker 1: you know, waving the flag in so many.
Speaker 1: if the thing you're doing can be construed as a threat Yeah Which often it can be could be.
Speaker 0: but purely just waving a flag that happens to be a flag of evil Should not get you in trouble with the government.
Speaker 0: First Amendment I believe in that but it should get you banned from my house then from any place That's private place where anyone has the power to kick you out of.
Speaker 0: Basically, you should be confined to your own home because nobody will allow you into their home.
Speaker 0: You can't do it in the grocery store.
Speaker 0: Go sir.
Speaker 0: Kicks you out, right?
Speaker 1: Well, I'm gonna take a very more direct approach here can't?
Speaker 0: can't?
Speaker 0: go on Twitter These slippery throw private places that have the absolute right to decide what can't get a job because no one has no one has to hire You.
Speaker 0: it's not a protected class.
Speaker 1: a slippery slope here can be pretty narrowly defined to not be a slippery slope.
Speaker 1: You could just say a very small list of certain fascist white supremacist misogynist and hateful ideologies are just banned from these private platforms and That could be the end of the slope.
Speaker 1: Let all the other shitty stuff just happen and get dealt with.
Speaker 0: Pudges a goat.
Speaker 0: see it's like all right.
Speaker 0: They put up a goat.
Speaker 0: see again.
Speaker 0: You're gonna take a guess, you know, at least it wasn't a swastika.
Speaker 1: yep, but the algorithms because of this laissez-faire approach are Basically funneling red like radicalizing content for these very narrow and very violent ideologies into the minds of children like.
Speaker 1: PewDiePie is honestly a white supremacist advocate who is probably tainted a generation.
Speaker 1: hmm and This is only going to continue until the platforms take a stand as we saw with the simplest example Alex Jones that crazy guy Dangerous person cause dangerous things to happen.
Speaker 0: nut job.
Speaker 1: when Twitter and Facebook and YouTube banned him He basically disappeared overnight.
Speaker 1: You didn't I'm sure.
Speaker 0: his fans are still all into him.
Speaker 1: Well, what seems to has happened is his hardest core.
Speaker 1: crazy fans followed him to like whatever den of like shittiness.
Speaker 1: His content is on now But the vast majority of his audience disappeared.
Speaker 1: because really is people don't know how to use the internet that well.
Speaker 1: They lack object permanence and especially the kinds of people who fall for this kind of conspiracy nut job nonsense.
Speaker 1: Not that good at searching for stuff.
Speaker 1: if you take these people off of a very small number of highly used platforms They disappear from the hearts and minds of most people and they lose their monetization stream.
Speaker 1: They.
Speaker 1: it basically ends them without the government having to get involved.
Speaker 1: All you need is for YouTube Facebook Twitter and maybe like two other platforms to agree to ban like Specific fascist stuff.
Speaker 1: and they disappear from most of the internet, right?
Speaker 0: The internet itself in the web allows anyone with access and enough money to turn on a computer and host it Right get an IP address to publish any content They want to the internet and there's nothing you can do to stop them really and there shouldn't be really anything you do to Stop them.
Speaker 0: Yeah, this is child porn or something like that, right?
Speaker 0: But the thing is is actually quite a high bar to actually do that It's not.
Speaker 0: most people are not capable of doing that.
Speaker 0: They need some sort of help.
Speaker 0: They need a YouTube.
Speaker 0: Otherwise, you know, they would never be able to post a comment.
Speaker 0: Anyway, they need this bar crossed for them by someone else and thus these organizations these social networks or whatever You want to call them platforms, you know YouTube Facebook Twitter Reddit all these right are simply Helping people get over that bar.
Speaker 0: Right, and if you they didn't help those you'll get over that bar.
Speaker 0: Those people would be on the other side.
Speaker 0: So stop helping people over who suck only good people on this side.
Speaker 1: Yep It's a pretty easy trivial stance to make and the only people you're actually gonna anger are Nazis.
Speaker 0: so And your and your investors who are probably Nazis.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: Well like Twitter is a particularly wealthy and probably white supremacist VC investors I assume they're all white Silicon Valley douchebags.
Speaker 1: Twitter is such a weird specific example because Twitter seems to go out of its way to protect white supremacists on the platform like Beyond what would be coincidence and it's really bothering me.
Speaker 1: Mmm like if policies tend to get enforced more against people calling Nazis out than actual Nazis and And Twitter I think relies too much on a lot of the traffic on Twitter is Nazis and if you kick them out Twitter's metrics go way down in a hurry and Twitter can make money but can't make VC money and I feel like there's a really perverse Incentive there to keep the Nazis on the platform for the controversy.
Speaker 0: The biggest problem is you've always we want to leave Twitter and people keep trying to make other Twitter's that are just fine.
Speaker 1: Those Twitter's always fall into two categories either one not good enough yet for people to migrate to en masse or two They were created by the people who are banned from.
Speaker 0: there are actually some good Non-twitters that have been around and people just can't go to migrate because you can't get everyone to leave all at once.
Speaker 0: Yep, you got to get it.
Speaker 0: It's like if I just go alone and bring a few friends with me.
Speaker 0: That's not good enough.
Speaker 0: It's like I'm there because the other good people are still there and they're not leaving so I can't leave.
Speaker 0: and if they do leave It's like we need everyone to get up and go all together.
Speaker 1: Yep, but it's even worse than that because I use Twitter not just as a social media network which is the primary way I use it, but I also use it as a Content distribution platform to a broader audience of people.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm If I just like chat with my.
Speaker 0: I want to.
Speaker 0: I would delete my Facebook except we got like a geek nights page there.
Speaker 1: No, I don't have a Facebook.
Speaker 0: I gotta keep my.
Speaker 0: I gotta keep my that geek night's Facebook page up.
Speaker 0: Yep Someone looks at it.
Speaker 1: All right, it's been over an hour and I'm hungry.
Speaker 1: Let's just stop here.
Speaker 1: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Speaker 0: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 1: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays and make comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 0: Geeknights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 0: But unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 0: It's actually recorded at night.
Speaker 1: And the patreon patrons for this non algorithmically curated list of people or this episode of geek nights Remember that I only ever do this in one take and some of you have been messing with me lately looking at you Chris Thomas rhyme or Han and Anyway without any further ado the patrons Craig Oliver Alan Joyce, Heidi McNichol Just like a dude guy chart obviously linkagey Jennifer Hitchcock.
Speaker 1: Chris made.
Speaker 1: give my state a calm.
Speaker 1: J Bad scooter lonely Roberto Kingsley Shawn Yeager Matthew Smith Nicholas Brando, mr.
Speaker 1: Strong.
Speaker 1: distraction for two one creations Chris Thomas rhyme or Han and Shervin von Horrell reori Rochelle Montanona super boy sailor Vista Joe sure Joe star Clinton Walton.
Speaker 1: written from New Zealand Ryan parent Robenlander Finn Daniel revenue Sean Klein Chris rhyme er and Thomas.
Speaker 1: on.
Speaker 1: Like I said, I'll see you guys at Zen Chi con.
Speaker 1: I'll be there pretty much just Saturday in part of Sunday.
Speaker 1: But you see the schedule.
Speaker 1: Yeah, pexy's is gonna be awesome.
Speaker 1: I will probably be hanging out in forcing in maine theater at night, but you never know.
Speaker 1: I might get an interesting or different ship.
Speaker 1: But now I leave you with.
Speaker 0: I'm your dad.
Speaker 0: Better like it cuz I'm your new dad.
Speaker 0: You're gonna like it.
Speaker 0: Your old dad is out.
Speaker 0: The new dad is in No appointments.
Speaker 0: I keep office hours for five to seven Tuesdays and Thursdays.
Speaker 0: be there on time.
Speaker 0: I'm your new dad.
Speaker 0: You better like it.
Speaker 0: It's your shit together.
Speaker 0: Now cut your hair Now.
Speaker 0: don't care if you're a man or a woman.
Speaker 0: Don't care if you're a boy or your girl.
Speaker 0: cut your hair.
Speaker 0: cut your hair off.
Speaker 0: I'm your dad.
Speaker 0: Feel your skin back.
Speaker 0: It feels bad.
Speaker 0: I am your father.
Speaker 0: You need to learn not to bother.
Speaker 0: I got a recliner.
Speaker 0: It's pretty good.
Speaker 0: I got the money to buy it from your college fund.
Speaker 0: I am your dad.