Speaker 1: It's Wednesday April 17th 2019.
Speaker 1: I'm rim, I'm Scott and this is geek nights tonight.
Speaker 1: We have our final full thoughts of adventure time.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: So yesterday we we finally went me Scott and Judith who was recently on geek nights to go see us Because I generally had I don't.
Speaker 0: I don't see us all the time.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't see.
Speaker 0: I see us right now.
Speaker 1: I don't see a lot of horror movies in the theater because a lot of them.
Speaker 1: well also I don't tend to see a lot of movies in the theater.
Speaker 1: the movie has to be like an a-plus Important movie or has to have some reason for me to see it in the theater as opposed to just seeing it via the high seas or Netflix later, but Horror movies are few and far between unless you count a really really shitty horror movies.
Speaker 1: So us is a hundred percent worth seeing.
Speaker 1: it's a legit horror movie.
Speaker 1: it's good and we saw it last night.
Speaker 1: and the only thing I got to say without getting into a review of it is that when you live in New York City, and you see a spooky movie the walk home is Very not spooky compared to the travel home in any other place.
Speaker 1: Like I remember as a kid we'd see a horror movie and then there was like the quiet drive through the dark roads home And then the house is all dark and you lock all the doors.
Speaker 1: It's hard to think about spooky stuff in New York when there's just like a bunch of people in the street everywhere And it doesn't actually ever get dark because of the light pollution And there's just like stuff going on everywhere and you get to an apartment that has a doorman and like one door.
Speaker 1: That's the only way into the apartment.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean, you know try to try to make a horror movie that takes place in New York City.
Speaker 0: This is actually scary is my heart all horrible.
Speaker 1: I got one.
Speaker 1: so you get on a subway train.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you realize it's the hobo car.
Speaker 1: The doors lock.
Speaker 0: This is
Speaker 1: my horror movie and then the power goes
Speaker 0: out usually start including the one we just saw us With people
Speaker 1: leaving the city
Speaker 0: going somewhere remote and out of touch right like you know one of the best horror movies ever Maybe the best you know John Carpenter is the thing they go to?
Speaker 0: Antarctica.
Speaker 0: yeah, it's like.
Speaker 0: I know it's horrifying.
Speaker 1: It's like when you're a kid and you're in your house You'll hear like a creak in the distance or like something taps on the window, or there's a noise outside.
Speaker 1: in New York It's just like seven train went by again.
Speaker 1: There are literally millions of people within like a quarter mile radius of me.
Speaker 1: If there was a ghost that ghost is waiting in line.
Speaker 1: So I got any news.
Speaker 0: I do add some news.
Speaker 0: so Initial D is a thing.
Speaker 0: Right It is a thing that started out as a manga and that was adapted into anime and video games.
Speaker 0: The arcade video games are very good.
Speaker 0: Maybe those are the best initial D thing there is.
Speaker 1: yeah The every initially arcade game is just better than the last one.
Speaker 0: the anime is not good But I like it anyway.
Speaker 1: the anime is good at being something I like.
Speaker 0: the anime gets worse over time.
Speaker 0: so the very first season is the best and as it gets newer and newer later seasons And movies and as you go on dumber and dumber and dumber it gets better animation.
Speaker 0: by some measures The cars look better kind of yeah, but it just gets worse.
Speaker 0: just watch the first 26 episodes of initial D. If you're gonna watch anyway, maybe you shouldn't.
Speaker 1: the 26th episode of the original initial D Just ends and like this sort of poignant moment and a character had an arc and it's like a real story and after that It's just like project D. We're still erasing cars on this mountain for some reason.
Speaker 0: yeah anyway.
Speaker 0: And then there is the manga the original thing which is poorly drawn except for the cars poorly written.
Speaker 0: Yeah, when it was released in America originally I bought every volume the Tokyo pop put out.
Speaker 1: I kept reading it.
Speaker 1: Scott would buy it.
Speaker 1: He'd read it He'd put it in the pile.
Speaker 1: I would pick it up off that pile, and I would read it.
Speaker 0: they put out all the volumes.
Speaker 0: They renamed some of the characters talk which people got really mad about.
Speaker 0: right yes instead of Itsuki and Takumi And They've made some other modifications that you know whatever But they only put out I think 30-something volumes.
Speaker 0: basically I think there are four or five volumes.
Speaker 0: They didn't put out they just stopped.
Speaker 0: I bought all of them and then got rid of all of them.
Speaker 1: I just can't imagine.
Speaker 0: What could have happened.
Speaker 0: Anyway, if you are the kind of person who wants to read the initial D. Manga I believe this is not the Tokyo pop translation.
Speaker 1: Oh, thanks, Satan.
Speaker 0: I believe it's not.
Speaker 0: I can't imagine it would be because it's being put up by wait wait wait.
Speaker 1: No, I think it is because from the article Comixology describes the stories.
Speaker 1: this is quoting Comixology.
Speaker 1: Tak Fujiwara Spends his time.
Speaker 0: maybe maybe it is the same translation, but it's being not put out by Tokyo pop.
Speaker 0: But it's now available not in physical print anymore.
Speaker 0: It is now digitally available Including all the volumes right up to the end are now.
Speaker 0: So the part that I could never read before because it was never available before is now digitally available in the United States on Comixology and all associated digital platforms.
Speaker 1: I guess if you really got to find out if he ever loses a race other than that one race the one where his engine Exploded he didn't really lose.
Speaker 0: He's kind of lost yeah.
Speaker 0: And it's kind of like when Astro boy needs to lose to get powered up and come back stronger.
Speaker 1: Yeah, because then they get that magic naturally aspirated engine season power up.
Speaker 1: You know by pretending to lose that magic engine they put in the 86 he still just can't get over anyway.
Speaker 0: The point is you if you really want to for some reason read all the initial D Manga like I will soon have done.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you can go now and do that.
Speaker 1: Very important is whenever the cars are driving while you're reading the manga.
Speaker 1: put some euro bead on.
Speaker 0: while you're reading it You got to play euro bead on the on the stereo.
Speaker 1: deja vu.
Speaker 1: I've just been in this place.
Speaker 0: Also those pages flip through them real fast.
Speaker 0: You can read this manga like in a few minutes.
Speaker 1: I mean half the pages.
Speaker 1: just cars cars.
Speaker 1: Talking me says something cars now.
Speaker 1: There's a whole bunch of drama with like and the Linger on it.
Speaker 0: Yep alright, so in a Not so good news right there is a person who you may know monkey punch named monkey punch Whose real name escapes me?
Speaker 0: But it's written all over the internet now because sadly the person known as monkey punch has passed away at the.
Speaker 0: I could Accept this age of 81.
Speaker 0: I think they said 81 and from 81.
Speaker 1: from what I've read Dude was really active and happy and like kicking ass as recently as when he was a.
Speaker 0: yeah It didn't fade away in some sad hospice or anything.
Speaker 0: yeah, but monkey punch is the creator of Lupin the third and also a really good artist and Also, you know someone who liked a bit of a bit of lewdness.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but it's a. it's a.
Speaker 0: it's a more elegant lewdness from a more civilized age But generally an awesome amazing dude and artist Who created a legendary set of characters that have still keep.
Speaker 0: they still keep making more Lupin shit even to this day.
Speaker 0: Not only that Lupin is decades old.
Speaker 1: there was an era where Lupin specials would come out and they were not great But there weren't always good.
Speaker 0: but they just keep coming.
Speaker 1: but the Relatively recent Lupin's basically everything they've made from fujiko Mina onward is at least B Plus a minus level Lupin.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but it's it's kind of sad because like, you know monkey punch made a lot of other stuff That wasn't Lupin but basically was only known for Lupin.
Speaker 1: only Lupin was successful and basically was like, you know in terms of Making money, it's like the guy who made snatch nothing He ever made after that or before that will be remembered.
Speaker 1: or know anyone care about it.
Speaker 0: But it's like, you know, he made Guy Ritchie made other movies that were basically also like snatch.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the problem is that they were.
Speaker 0: but you know the same thing can be said of To mix, you know any other director was a Tim Burton.
Speaker 0: You can tell a Tim Burton thing when you look at it, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, but he's making different stuff.
Speaker 0: But monkey punch rode on one thing didn't make other lupin ish things that were successful?
Speaker 0: Yeah, right, but yeah Kind of sad.
Speaker 0: but you know also, you know, I guess kind of good people remember Lupin.
Speaker 0: yet again Lupin's not going anywhere.
Speaker 1: So speaking of which if you live in New York There's a theater in Brooklyn called Nighthawk cinema and Nighthawk cinema is a place that serves food Like you put your order in when you sit down in your assigned seat or whatever and then they're like you write your order down.
Speaker 1: It's fancy.
Speaker 1: Yeah, no waitress comes and brings you like booze and fancy food and it's a full-on movie theater.
Speaker 1: Otherwise, like you don't even have to pay your check.
Speaker 1: You just like leave because they'd like put it on your credit card.
Speaker 1: It's fine.
Speaker 1: It's awesome, but they Often show anime there.
Speaker 0: They often show lots of things there because you know, you're not gonna you're not gonna just do the Dinner movie thing for just like the latest top movie, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know, they're not gonna pay to get the latest top movie.
Speaker 1: But last weekend they did a brunch movie on Saturday where they showed metropolis, which is a good movie.
Speaker 0: It's not not Fritz Lang's metropolis.
Speaker 1: Oh the anime one.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the way the anime one that if you don't know if you don't know why metropolis the movie was made Then it's probably just confusing but I digress.
Speaker 0: Yeah, Rintaro is metropolis.
Speaker 0: I feel like you have to see before you can watch metropolis.
Speaker 0: You have to see Metropolis yeah, then you have to see.
Speaker 0: you have to read Tezuka's manga metropolis.
Speaker 0: then you have to watch at least one.
Speaker 0: Tezuka anime could just be like an episode of Astro boy or something.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and then you gotta finally like you're nearly right.
Speaker 0: and then you got to see a Rintaro movie Like maybe Galaxy Express or something.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and then you can watch metropolis the movie and understand what the hell's going on.
Speaker 1: But this weekend in a few days on Saturday at 10 45 a.m They are screening is a brunch movie.
Speaker 0: Lupin the third the castle of Cagliostro might be the one of the best Lupin movies Directed by Miyazaki.
Speaker 1: It is the best Lupin movie with the caveat that it is nothing like any other.
Speaker 0: it is the least Lupin ish, but the best at being a movie.
Speaker 0: Yep, maybe the worst at being Lupin ish.
Speaker 1: It depends on what color jacket you're talking about.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but anyway, and they didn't just schedule this because of the passing of I bought tickets this a while ago But it's not sold.
Speaker 0: I've seen it recently.
Speaker 0: So I don't really feel like I need to go again.
Speaker 1: I have not seen it recently.
Speaker 1: So if you live in New York and have not seen any Lupin Go to Night Dog Cinema on Saturday and see the castle of Cagliostro.
Speaker 0: Oh 20 and also.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, I guess it is.
Speaker 1: And also the following Saturday plays it.
Speaker 1: they're showing in the same brunch format penguin highway.
Speaker 0: So maybe that will be the thing that I go and then on my schedule a and then we can review that.
Speaker 1: the only problem Is oh, yes, so Saturday they always do this Saturday and Sunday.
Speaker 1: So it is also Sunday.
Speaker 1: Saturday is always subbed.
Speaker 1: Sunday is always dubbed.
Speaker 1: Oh, no, so, uh, you know what to do.
Speaker 0: So Saturday is subbed.
Speaker 0: Saturday subbed the 27th.
Speaker 0: you say the 27th.
Speaker 0: my schedule is good.
Speaker 1: I think mine's good, too.
Speaker 1: I think we should do it.
Speaker 0: Maybe yeah, see some anime penguin highway plus brunch.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but anyway, it's time for wings of the day.
Speaker 1: What do you got?
Speaker 1: so?
Speaker 0: Normally, I hate commercials and I won't block all ads right, but there are those occasions where?
Speaker 0: Advertisements happen to be made are also works of art, right like a segata sashiro, right?
Speaker 0: That's a good example.
Speaker 0: or you know various Super Bowl commercials, you know, you have a lot of old-school ads You know, they had really good design and stuff going right.
Speaker 0: so it's hard to separate that like block all ads Which you should do in your daily life always especially on the internet.
Speaker 0: where can mess up your computer with evil malicious ads?
Speaker 0: But also someone says he recognized the art of ads, right?
Speaker 0: So here is an ad.
Speaker 0: for unless we got any Thai listeners any listeners in Thailand shout out Yeah, that'd be awesome.
Speaker 0: If we had a listener in Thailand I don't think I don't think we do so which means I don't think anyone listening is Very unlikely to be able to buy this product because I think it is a product is definitely not sold in the US.
Speaker 0: I don't know where else.
Speaker 0: it's old.
Speaker 0: It's some sort of termite killing spray and here is a commercial presumably on television in Thailand for this termite killing spray and it is a Quite long for a commercial.
Speaker 0: I got to know how long commercials are there.
Speaker 1: Usually it's two minutes and 20 seconds.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know 30 second spot, you know when you see the beginning you might think okay, that's why it's funny.
Speaker 1: but no the moment where you realize that this is a true work of art is Right.
Speaker 1: at a minute and 23 seconds.
Speaker 0: watch the whole thing.
Speaker 0: It doesn't get bad It just keeps getting better and better all the way through.
Speaker 0: It's not like you know.
Speaker 0: That's the joke and you can stop watching.
Speaker 0: just watch the whole two minutes 20. don't buy the termite spray.
Speaker 0: Let's you got termites in which case call it help.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's bad.
Speaker 0: Yeah, this commercial is magnificent.
Speaker 0: I wouldn't be.
Speaker 0: I don't even know cuz I'm not.
Speaker 0: this could be like a fake commercial someone made But it's so well done and highly produced, right?
Speaker 0: I feel like I want to make.
Speaker 0: someone should make a YouTube channel where they make ads this good for fake products And that would be.
Speaker 0: this is basically like wait a minute.
Speaker 1: Wait a minute.
Speaker 1: I can think of one example of that already.
Speaker 0: It's basically a funny YouTube.
Speaker 1: You may recall fuck you Baltimore.
Speaker 0: anyway.
Speaker 0: Yeah, watch this watch.
Speaker 0: this ad is great.
Speaker 1: So When I first got into anime I've told the story and gig nights before but it's very important that it was on the sci-fi channel when I was in fourth grade.
Speaker 1: They showed.
Speaker 0: I mean I keep.
Speaker 0: this keeps coming up.
Speaker 0: Everyone always wants to know like the first anime you saw.
Speaker 0: no one cares like the first book you read or the first movie You saw the first adult the first big boy book I ever read was the Hobbit.
Speaker 0: I was really young right but the point is people seem to always want to know like.
Speaker 0: the first anime you saw like you knew Was anime.
Speaker 0: it's like I saw Voltron and shit.
Speaker 0: and then I saw on TV as you know There was Dragon Ball and say there's all this shit on TV.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like it's.
Speaker 0: I can't tell you what.
Speaker 0: the first anime as I was there was something on sci-fi channel.
Speaker 1: See but I can because I may have seen things like Voltron vampire hunter D's.
Speaker 1: but I got really into anime when I was in fourth grade, which was a long goddamn time ago.
Speaker 1: So in middle school, and even like late elementary school I was the kid who was like into anime when literally no one else in my city had ever heard of anime.
Speaker 1: So like I was getting VHS fan subs good times The first anime I saw as I've talked about a lot was a vampire hunter D Which is great because I was a little kid and that probably made me the way I am.
Speaker 1: but the second anime I ever saw Was project a co because it was on television.
Speaker 1: Yep The dub.
Speaker 1: now at the time I was so young that while I thought project a co was funny.
Speaker 1: I did not quite get that.
Speaker 1: it was just a comedy.
Speaker 1: I kind of treated it like it was a Serious superhero story.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm, but This YouTube video is the entirety of the original project a cause.
Speaker 0: there's a legal YouTube video.
Speaker 0: who even knows I don't think it is.
Speaker 0: what channel?
Speaker 0: is it some lady?
Speaker 1: Uploaded in 2016.
Speaker 0: Yeah, this seems not legitimate.
Speaker 1: It's been up a while.
Speaker 0: That's true, but it definitely seems not legitimate.
Speaker 1: This is the exact dub the exact anime the second anime I ever saw pretty much in the format that I saw it complete with not the format.
Speaker 1: I want to see it Yeah, so if I don't know I got weirdly Nostalgic hearing this dub like to up to a degree to where I feel like I'm gonna sit down and watch This whole YouTube video.
Speaker 0: I'm not doing that this weekend.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna spend two minutes watching the cut the termite video again.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So in the moment the geek nights book club book The one we're about to read that I'm gonna post soon is a Dungeons & Dragons Planescape branded novel I read when I was young called pages of pain.
Speaker 0: Yeah, my my subway read books on my phone plan continues once I finish the book I'm reading now, which is gonna be done in 20 minutes according to the Kindle app.
Speaker 0: No, I'm going to Acquire some painful digitally acquire some painful pages.
Speaker 0: So this book club will be done for me very soon.
Speaker 0: Yeah, unless biking to work makes me read a lot less because most of the reading happens on the train I feel like it will not take us long to read this book.
Speaker 0: We'll find out.
Speaker 0: but you know, my my readings rate is like super high.
Speaker 0: I'm basically constantly reading book now for like a couple months.
Speaker 0: It's been going strong.
Speaker 0: Yep I'm gonna continue it for as long as forever.
Speaker 1: So beyond that we don't have any conventions for a while.
Speaker 1: but I recently uploaded to YouTube the rare game mechanics panel, which was a new one.
Speaker 1: that we did at magfest is just on YouTube and Yesterday I uploaded the real harm of games another new panel.
Speaker 1: We just did a PAX East.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I went to work editing the judge anime by its cover spring 2019 season.
Speaker 0: There's some good anime coming up.
Speaker 0: almost completed the video editing.
Speaker 0: Maybe I'll finish that tonight if I got nothing better to do and upload that biz.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so good times ahead on the YouTube channel.
Speaker 1: Stay tuned for other YouTube content.
Speaker 1: That is not just geek nights that we'll be cranking out now that we don't have to prepare for conventions for a while.
Speaker 1: So I figure we'll get right into it.
Speaker 1: Adventure time we've talked about on geek nights before there's a forum thread about it.
Speaker 1: I actually try to figure out the first time or the last time we talked about it.
Speaker 0: You know adventure time was a thing that you know.
Speaker 0: I couldn't escape seeing those characters everywhere right in nerd land at conventions at all kinds of places And I recognize them and I remember we watch the like original original original adventure time like Pilot thing when it was brand new right and I saw
Speaker 1: I'm curious when do you think that was?
Speaker 0: we were living in Beacon?
Speaker 1: I think yeah, you're correct.
Speaker 1: the original adventure time like the thing that became adventure time was made by Fred Rader and debuted on December 7th 2008
Speaker 0: right so we watched that but I never made the connection between like that one shot pilot thing we watched and Like the Cartoon Network Show that became you know the thing right.
Speaker 1: in fact What was funny is I remember that adventure time was big in like the comic-con scene like I saw everywhere.
Speaker 1: I saw art I saw people dressing up But I just kind of ignored it because it seemed like kind of a kids show and I didn't know a lot about it And I had a lot of other things to watch.
Speaker 0: I didn't really think about it, and then so basically a few seasons into adventure time Maybe like I don't know five or so.
Speaker 1: I can't know the exact moment.
Speaker 1: It was season three episode ten.
Speaker 1: What was missing?
Speaker 1: the one with the door Lord?
Speaker 1: okay, and the good music.
Speaker 1: that episode happened and Someone just randomly said oh my god You got to watch the show.
Speaker 1: like look at this.
Speaker 1: and I ended up just seeing the song doesn't seem about right.
Speaker 1: So I saw the songs they sang.
Speaker 0: so this was Remember seeing that YouTube video of that song that was so good.
Speaker 1: Yep, that song is the reason I watched all of adventure time.
Speaker 1: basically I saw that song.
Speaker 1: I was like whoa this show is not what I thought it was.
Speaker 1: then I watched that whole episode.
Speaker 1: whoa this show is great.
Speaker 1: And then I just went to episode one and binge watched Everything I could find as fast as possible.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I was I guess somewhere around that time.
Speaker 0: I went to episode one watched it all the caught up Yeah, and then watched episodes kind of mostly as they came out as I could get them until Sometime around like one or two seasons before the show ended maybe like, you know, the the vampire stakes part.
Speaker 0: I've watched all of that.
Speaker 1: I just kept watching every.
Speaker 0: I watched some more episodes after that and then they announced that it was gonna end and I hadn't watched in a little in a few Months.
Speaker 0: I like it and not kept up on it just out of laziness or doing other stuff.
Speaker 0: So I said, oh you say the show's gonna end.
Speaker 0: All right, I'm just gonna hold off then and let you finish.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna let you finish.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and then I figured okay I'll figure out where I left off and catch up.
Speaker 0: But then what ended up happening instead is Maybe a month or so ago.
Speaker 0: You know Amanda hadn't seen any Avenger time.
Speaker 0: So I just went back to the beginning and it already ended.
Speaker 0: so I went just from beginning to end.
Speaker 0: like whoosh Adventure time is in the heart To the end than I thought when I when I stopped.
Speaker 1: it's kind of like cowboy bebop in the sense that if I start watching Any part of that show?
Speaker 1: I'll probably just keep watch.
Speaker 0: The episodes are 50 are short.
Speaker 0: right because it's.
Speaker 0: it's like a you know, it's almost like a Looney Tunes situation Have a 30-minute TV block with two episodes in it.
Speaker 0: So they could.
Speaker 0: they go bam bam.
Speaker 0: It's not like you're you know There's no time for you to like get tired or bored and then like if you set it up when if you pirating it or Streaming it or whatever Depending on how you set up your video.
Speaker 0: like you're gonna load your videos in and we push play in VLC and it just goes and goes and goes and goes and just Doesn't let go of your attention which makes it a great television show to trap kids in front of the TV watching ads.
Speaker 0: So five years ago in May so almost especially when there's no ads you really get trapped by it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, almost exactly five years ago We did a show about adventure time and how it was still ongoing.
Speaker 1: and just talking about it at that point Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: and funnily enough, you know who is on the show is one of our guests Judith.
Speaker 1: Okay, who is just so I guess.
Speaker 1: every five years Judith will be on geek nights.
Speaker 0: All right, Judith get ready 2024 here on this here on the hook.
Speaker 1: Yep, and in 2014 Also we in April.
Speaker 1: so like almost exactly exactly five years ago We talked about the Masaaki Yuasa episode of Adventure Time.
Speaker 1: Mmm, which itself was was Exactly what you might expect it today.
Speaker 0: Yeah And I also found that no bearing on the plot though.
Speaker 0: You can skip it.
Speaker 1: But yeah, that's it's not canon, right?
Speaker 0: But that's the thing about Adventure Time.
Speaker 0: Is that in addition to its story and characters?
Speaker 0: Which are like the number one reasons to watch it?
Speaker 0: right story character The epic plot and the amazing characters and the music right?
Speaker 0: is that also because there's so many episodes over such a breath of time?
Speaker 0: You know, it was an avenue for lots of you know, kooky pop art Experimental art lots of different styles.
Speaker 0: It wasn't just like, you know watching My Little Pony where every episode is drawn The same way by the same people by the same, you know, you know studio machine Right is.
Speaker 0: there was lots of like, you know, crazy offshoot episodes that have nothing to do with nothing But are just like this creative outlet for somebody here and there right like there was a. it was some CG one.
Speaker 0: Yeah, everything was all glitched out.
Speaker 1: Best part of that episode is when the princesses just looking shit and she just pulls out that gun and tries to shoot him Right.
Speaker 0: It wasn't just the Yuasa one There was the you know, there was all the episodes with Fiona and Kay, yeah, which are right.
Speaker 1: there were the which ended up becoming Canon in quotes sort of well because they're there they are a fictional work within that universe right.
Speaker 0: and then there's the Greville's Right, which you know are just sort of like little episodic dealies.
Speaker 1: but I guess the important part about all that biz is that even though each episode is very self-contained and very fond and Doesn't like they kind of mostly self-contained well toward the arm are some are toward the end of the show They started having long arcs.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Well, so I mean episodes were largely self-contained except for there's a couple.
Speaker 0: two-part is here And yeah.
Speaker 1: But every episode the little bits in the background of like things characters do and things people say and like little off-end Comments, they all build up to the final full story.
Speaker 0: Well, but I mean there's also some where it's like yeah, it's a self-contained episode.
Speaker 0: But if you didn't know for example that like king of who is currently in charge You know during this set of episodes and it's like that's just like the state of the world changes Yeah, and that might throw you off guard if you had missed The episode where the state of the world changed like Princess Bubblegum becomes young.
Speaker 0: at one point It's actually much earlier in the show than I remember and also very much more brief than I remember that happening.
Speaker 0: It was very short But like if you were to watch one of those like handful episodes where she's young and just like wait Why the fuck is she young right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's just like okay.
Speaker 1: Of course at the same time with adventure time if something weird is in the universe you kind of just go, huh?
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: Yep, just roll with it.
Speaker 0: But you know and it's you know, much like actually a lot of anime, you know, it has this long continuing plot.
Speaker 0: It doesn't really repeat stuff or hold your hand very much.
Speaker 0: So, you know, they're just like throwing out names of stuff.
Speaker 0: and if you don't know you don't know yeah, you could get lost.
Speaker 0: and I you know, I don't.
Speaker 0: I don't have the experience of being lost cuz.
Speaker 0: I watched It from beginning to end straight every time I watched it But I could imagine how you could get lost cuz.
Speaker 0: even then I there were some things where I had to like roll back Go to Wikipedia make sure my remember what I remember that kind of thing.
Speaker 0: So if I was watching them randomly on TV, it would have been way worse, especially if I miss them.
Speaker 1: Oh god, so one last very important warning about adventure time and we'll save spoilers for a bit.
Speaker 1: We're just gonna do like a full-on review because it's it's such an important and long-running show.
Speaker 1: but In 2013 we talked about something bad.
Speaker 1: There were some adventure time video games and I just need to impress upon you They are utter garbage or adventure time comics.
Speaker 0: They're great.
Speaker 0: Well, I've only.
Speaker 0: I have a whole bunch of them.
Speaker 1: the ones I've read were great.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I haven't read that many of them.
Speaker 0: I probably should but they actually did a thing which has been done successfully in the past.
Speaker 0: I don't know people know this but I don't know how many seasons of Buffy the Vampire Slayer there were on TV.
Speaker 0: But they basically continued the TV show of Buffy the Vampire Slayer in comic book form and they actually comics were like season Whatever season whatever like as if they were writing more of the TV show just straight up and I pretty sure it's just canon.
Speaker 0: They continued the show but because they didn't have a TV deal our actors or anything They just continued it in comics same just right from where the TV show left off adventure time I was.
Speaker 0: they've done this with other things too, but Buffy's probably the only the most successful example.
Speaker 0: They tried to do the same thing with adventure time.
Speaker 0: They were like adventure time.
Speaker 0: season 11 is the would be the next one, right?
Speaker 0: There were ten seasons of adventure time depending on how you count.
Speaker 0: Anyway, I think they called it season 11 or 12.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: It's it's 10 11 or 12 I don't know.
Speaker 0: but they basically like adventure time comics.
Speaker 0: season 11 just continued where the show left off in comic form and Then it was abruptly Surprisingly cancelled.
Speaker 0: apparently no one was buying it which I was like, hey, you didn't even put out the trade.
Speaker 0: yet I'm gonna buy the trade.
Speaker 0: then how do you know how not popular it's gonna be?
Speaker 0: Yeah I assume they'll put out a trade because they didn't put out some issues.
Speaker 0: So I will get the trade of the issues that were made which I'm sure will come at some point And I'll see what the deal was with the continuing I guess effect.
Speaker 0: effectively cannon next season of adventure time.
Speaker 0: that just wasn't on TV.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it was only a comic book.
Speaker 1: but I cannot stress enough the adventure time games unlike the 3ds than the DS are in no Universe worth playing just about anything with adventure time branding on it.
Speaker 0: That isn't say high quality merchandise.
Speaker 0: the show itself.
Speaker 1: Yeah, or the comics.
Speaker 0: the comic some of the comics maybe most of them Is something that's not good.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like it is that game.
Speaker 1: Why did you steal our garbage is egregiously bad?
Speaker 1: I just remembered how bad it was because we spent time talking about how bad it was.
Speaker 0: You know the balloons tower defense game that I play.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there is an adventure time balloons tower defense, which is basically Same game with adventure time same game only more more microtransaction II and worse but with lots of adventure time theming on it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so I think adventure time is going to be one of the like.
Speaker 1: it is going to be a legendary show.
Speaker 0: It is it is.
Speaker 1: Yes, it will stand the test of time.
Speaker 1: It is an important show.
Speaker 0: I sort of put it there with like a fist of the North Star or a Sailor Moon.
Speaker 0: It's like a show that's got like a shit pile of episodes, but not anything.
Speaker 0: It's.
Speaker 0: it's a lot but it's not some insane amount that you can't watch.
Speaker 1: not one piece It's Sailor Moon right.
Speaker 0: one piece is too insane and too big.
Speaker 0: You can't watch it, even though it's probably equally legendary.
Speaker 0: I mean like.
Speaker 0: there's 283. most legendary shows are 26 episodes or less.
Speaker 1: There are 283 episodes of adventure time and because they're short that is less Time than watching Sailor Moon.
Speaker 0: It's definitely consumable, but still long and epic and big.
Speaker 1: But the thing that I think is the most important about adventure time the two things.
Speaker 1: there are two things I think that really make the show important.
Speaker 1: one it used music really well, and I do credit it as Well in there.
Speaker 0: in there ending they were like, you know leaning on the music hard as like, you know, they're their deal.
Speaker 1: I mean the music.
Speaker 1: like we said the music is what got me to watch the show in the first place.
Speaker 0: That's partially true Yes.
Speaker 1: and two I credit adventure time as one of the things that caused a lot of kids cartoons or Cartoons like this to start to.
Speaker 1: also I mean ponies lean heavily into the music.
Speaker 1: Steven Universe leaned into the music.
Speaker 1: I do think adventure time is a big part of that trend and I approve of that trend.
Speaker 0: I agree as well.
Speaker 1: Also, the second thing is that the sheer scope not of the story adventure time though It is big but the scope of what the show was like season by season episode by episode.
Speaker 1: you almost don't notice it if you just watch it sequentially, but The show goes in a lot of different directions and covers a lot of surprising grounds, right?
Speaker 0: Well, I think part of what it is is because the show went on so long and had a continuous plot Even if it wasn't necessarily perfectly serial.
Speaker 0: Yeah Is that?
Speaker 0: it was on Cartoon Network aimed at children.
Speaker 0: is that the children watching the show from the beginning were?
Speaker 0: Like 10 plus years older when the show ended?
Speaker 1: like they were kids were about Finn's age watching the show So it aged in real time.
Speaker 0: So unlike some sort of episodic thing like say a Looney Tune where you know You watch it when you're young and then it's episodic so you can just sort of grow out of it and move on to something Else.
Speaker 0: right you were sticking with adventure time as you grew up and it grew up with you.
Speaker 0: So even though I was already growing up when I started It's plain to see how a generation a certain generation grew up with adventure time side by side grew up.
Speaker 0: The show didn't did not attempt to like stay and it's like keep aiming at.
Speaker 0: you know The original age group that it was aimed at.
Speaker 0: it grew along and it said okay.
Speaker 0: It's a year later.
Speaker 0: We started with a show for 10 year olds.
Speaker 0: now, we're a show for 11 year olds.
Speaker 0: the next year They're like, okay now we're a show for 12 year olds or whatever.
Speaker 1: It was what I'd always been kind of hoping would happen, but I'm good.
Speaker 1: It's probably fine.
Speaker 1: They didn't cuz the ending was great.
Speaker 1: But I was kind of hoping the show would just keep going and then like 30 years or no Finn's just 40 Like I would.
Speaker 1: I would have kept watching if they did that but not to spoil yet.
Speaker 1: But the ending was perfect and I cannot.
Speaker 0: it was a excellent ending.
Speaker 0: But the thing was I feel like the the lead up to the ending could have could have been a little stretched out.
Speaker 1: The episode the the series the little arcs they used to lead up to the ending felt a little rush Like yes stakes and all those stories elements that they did before the end Like they all should have been about twice as long.
Speaker 0: That's the only come right because the main plot is over the course of so is is over such a long period of time and like that feels like the pace of the show like Introduce the Lich season or two later fight the Lich, right?
Speaker 0: It's like that.
Speaker 0: make the epicness of stretching those those lines out, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, is then at the end.
Speaker 0: It's like introduced the evil gum family And it's like a few elements.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: Now we dealt with the elements into like it's just like bam bam bam.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they knew they had to end the show because there was a physical to like money deadline.
Speaker 1: Do you finish?
Speaker 0: the show accelerates in the last season or two?
Speaker 0: Quite dramatically and that's you know.
Speaker 0: It takes away a little bit from the epicness that the rest of the show prior to then islands I think was this had a good pace.
Speaker 0: Islands was definitely after Islands is when the pace got too fast yep, but also I place of the placing and pacing of the islands part was like perfect and after that is when things got a Little.
Speaker 1: I really like the islands part.
Speaker 1: I think all the like mini arts.
Speaker 1: That's probably the best one Stakes if it had been a little longer because I like how.
Speaker 1: I like the real talk that happened in stakes.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm, but uh the show just went on for so long and it ended and It was kind of a loss for a show that I had watched for so long to end.
Speaker 0: I can't.
Speaker 0: yeah it is.
Speaker 0: but on the other hand, I kind of like it when stuff I mean, I mean, I like endings as endings are epic and awesome, but I guess there's.
Speaker 0: no I can always rewatch it.
Speaker 1: There's a visceral.
Speaker 0: I'll get more out of it if I watch it again and again.
Speaker 1: There's a visceral difference between a show that had aired and finished before I watched like Sailor Moon.
Speaker 1: I was just like I'm a watch all the Sailor Moon this weekend and I watched all the Sailor Moon in one weekend.
Speaker 1: Well, I'm starting with s because I'd already seen up through our hookup.
Speaker 1: So we watch s super s stars over the course of a ridiculous three-day weekend.
Speaker 1: That was all those in high school.
Speaker 0: The point is ending is good because it frees me up to get something else.
Speaker 1: But I was pretty much once I saw that what was missing episode?
Speaker 1: I just watched Adventure Time as it came out like all the way to the end.
Speaker 1: I never stopped.
Speaker 1: I never paused.
Speaker 1: I don't want to get into how the season numbers were all fucked up Depending on if you watch them like Amazon or like the numbers don't matter as long as you're watching all the episodes in the right Order, I think.
Speaker 1: what happened though, like it's interesting that Adventure Time as a show spanned the Like the television era the early internet era and the current internet era of how you get TV shows Which is part of the reason why I think the end got a little rushed and like it was like it was hard to watch Unless you had TV like the show spanned three distinct eras of the monetization of television shows And that is that is an interesting thing that I'm sure will be studied in universities in years to come Because there aren't many shows that have done that.
Speaker 0: yeah, even though other shows like say Flintstones went on for a long I'm pretty sure it went on for longer than Avenger the world of TV didn't change.
Speaker 1: It was just like ad supported broadcast television, right?
Speaker 0: But you know if you want to look for examples, I mean you can't beat Simpson
Speaker 1: Yeah,
Speaker 0: or even South Park right is still bigger than you know but
Speaker 1: the Simpsons went from traditional show with traditional format to Still a traditional show with the traditional format still supported by ads on like Hulu.
Speaker 1: Adventure time like started as a Frederator.
Speaker 1: Let's make something cool.
Speaker 1: Became a non-traditional television show that then had to be monetized in a non-traditional way instead of just becoming a Hulu show Like it's a. it was in a weird situation as a result.
Speaker 1: Mmm It also had an a-plus voice cast like.
Speaker 1: the writing was great.
Speaker 1: Everything about the show was great.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm I say best this point.
Speaker 1: We're gonna assume you saw the show all the way to the end so we can talk about specific moments specific things the end itself.
Speaker 0: So well the number one crime in all adventure time that spoilers have upset me very greatly Is that having watched all of it every single episode very recently fresh in the mind, right?
Speaker 0: my favorite character choose goose does not appear as often nearly as much as Deserved right And that is a crime against humanity.
Speaker 0: I demand the choose goose spin-off.
Speaker 0: That is all.
Speaker 0: choose goose.
Speaker 1: all the time I would watch that I Would a hundred.
Speaker 0: normally when people ask for that stuff like I want cowgirl at nine It's like no, let's not go there.
Speaker 0: But no, I want choose goose.
Speaker 0: Yep Give me all the choose goose you got.
Speaker 1: But in terms of like the ending in the story in the plot The show was primarily about the characters and the world building happening around them was just interesting and then bit by bit It started to morph into.
Speaker 1: let's actually follow this plot And if I and I think I like the fact that the plot itself ended up being a sort of Lovecraftian like there is a terrible secret of space and earth is a tiny speck with tiny humans and the cosmic scale of nonsense and the people in Adventure Time Interact with that cosmic nonsense in the way that tiny people on a tiny planet.
Speaker 1: could I like that?
Speaker 1: Well, there's gods out there and civilizations on Mars.
Speaker 0: Well, it's a lot like a Marvel Universe situation.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you watch you you read me Marvel Comics, right?
Speaker 0: And it's like, okay, you've got real small level stories, right?
Speaker 0: You know, it's like a single superhero dealing with their bullshit like, you know, spider-man having problems in high school.
Speaker 1: Then you got your New York story.
Speaker 0: So in Adventure Time, that would be like the ooh level story like something is threatening ooh, right?
Speaker 0: The land of ooh, there's trouble in ooh, right?
Speaker 0: Then you've got like bigger stuff, right?
Speaker 0: Okay, Magneto is threatening the earth, right?
Speaker 0: Something is happening.
Speaker 0: That's threatening the Ice Kingdom and the Candy Kingdom and the Fire Kingdom and right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, something bigger is threatening the whole planet Right, then you got your cosmic, you know infinity gauntlet shit with.
Speaker 0: you know You're Lich and you're glob and you're king of Mars and you're all that kind of stuff.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right and he's like you're telling stories and all the levels right of epicness that weave in and out of each other.
Speaker 0: The same care, but you know your main characters are always the focus, right?
Speaker 0: So even though you know infinity gauntlet Marvel Comics, guess what?
Speaker 0: There's Captain American spider-man right there at the front.
Speaker 0: That's that stupid high school kid is dealing with like, you know, the right.
Speaker 0: and there it is There's stupid Finn that kid who lives in a tree dealing with gob and glob, right?
Speaker 1: The god of the solar system basically just started as they wanted to say oh my god But as a kid show.
Speaker 1: so they would say stuff instead of poop and they would say so glob instead of God.
Speaker 0: It's interesting because you having watched the whole thing recently again.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'll keep bringing that up.
Speaker 0: You know, I've heard some people say in the best Oh the first season of adventure time has like a different feel right?
Speaker 0: It doesn't get epic in story things.
Speaker 1: It's all there though.
Speaker 0: No, everything is there from the beginning.
Speaker 0: That's complete horseshit.
Speaker 1: The only question is some of it was might have been throwaway things that were just jokes.
Speaker 1: Right that they went back in mine.
Speaker 1: It
Speaker 0: is hard to tell and without interviewing someone Which it's probably a mixture right which things were planned and written from the beginning to the end and which things were simply Masterfully taken from older episodes by writers and then given new life and meaning in later episodes Like oh, yeah, that was that one off character.
Speaker 0: You just wrote into that scene.
Speaker 0: Well now I've written a whole episode about that character and it looked.
Speaker 0: if you watch you it feels like that was done on purpose right You know.
Speaker 0: and it's like almost the whole the hope the main plot is like yeah They're on this land of who which is a post-apocalyptic earth.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right we're.
Speaker 0: in the past was a society similar to ours with cars and buildings and planes And I love all the just little hints about this over the course, but it's like in episode one in the intro.
Speaker 0: It's like yeah there's like busted up modern job just like in the woods.
Speaker 0: and it's like did they just draw busted up modern junk in the woods by accident and then Decide the course of the whole plot based on that or no, it was on purpose, right?
Speaker 0: You know and they were wise enough to drop that stuff, you know and leave it everywhere Even when it wasn't the focus cuz it was rarely the focus.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: But also I like the fact that the Lich was effectively a Cthulhu like the priest of Some great cosmic evil.
Speaker 1: Yep, like that worked really well.
Speaker 1: I especially like how magic man and Marga magic man comes back and just like yeah, we talked up.
Speaker 1: And then Galba Pierce.
Speaker 0: Well, I wish that they had You know, that's that's part of it the ending that with the Russian ish.
Speaker 0: Yeah, is that they didn't spend the time To you know, it's like, okay.
Speaker 0: I know all the terrible secret to space I'm gonna know.
Speaker 0: but you know, I really like to see all the details like what exactly What exactly happened.
Speaker 1: the show pulled an Evangelion on you for that because the actual end of the show is BMO the new king of ooh There's that moment where the kid the new character is like.
Speaker 1: so what happened then?
Speaker 1: and he's like They kept living their lives.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: Thank you.
Speaker 1: Goodbye Leave my house.
Speaker 1: Like the whole point is that a long-running show has to end and Stories don't have to end at like the end of time or the end of the universe.
Speaker 1: You don't need the show that takes you through the next 80 years of like.
Speaker 0: no No, I'm not but I'm saying the part that you did cover right?
Speaker 0: It's like you didn't show me what Matt what normal man and You know Betty and you know the witch did.
Speaker 0: yeah, how did they dunk that up?
Speaker 1: I I'm glad we didn't see it because I want to hear that they cut like when Jake farts Funnier when they come in and they're like, yeah, we fucked up.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean that was right it was it was a funny joke But you could have still you know, especially cuz Maja wakes up and then just recently It's like cuz.
Speaker 0: I really did care about Gob gob gob ground who's I guess still a bunch of heads floating in around the planet.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I cared about them a lot.
Speaker 1: Well, I'm on a wiki here every reference.
Speaker 0: I really wanted to know their deal, but we really didn't get too much about gold.
Speaker 0: It was just sort of like oh, yeah gold big bad guy.
Speaker 0: So and then we didn't learn enough to make me care enough about gold.
Speaker 1: I think we know enough.
Speaker 0: You know what gobb is?
Speaker 1: Well, all we need to know he is a cosmic evil.
Speaker 0: Yeah beyond Comprehension even even worse than or galore like.
Speaker 1: do not like don't just hope.
Speaker 1: it never looks at you.
Speaker 1: It's like a black hole coming.
Speaker 0: I'm aware of that but it's like a really, you know, so the first You know where gold first appears?
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm in the episode where Finn becomes a pillow?
Speaker 1: Gold is in that episode where when Finn dies in pillow world and remember there's the scene where he like Warps through space-time back to his body.
Speaker 0: No guy.
Speaker 1: He passes gold.
Speaker 1: Aha, they put him there.
Speaker 1: He actually bounces off of gold move.
Speaker 1: So Finn coming back from that universe might be what attracted gulps attention back to earth.
Speaker 1: Maybe he's mentioned again in the magic one of the magic man episodes where betty betty I'm reading from the wiki here betty witnesses a memory of him and Grob gob glob Grod Discussing gobb at some point in the past.
Speaker 1: There's like this flashback because Margils was tote taken by gold and that's right.
Speaker 1: magic man was mad right.
Speaker 1: Mars is like the advanced space society.
Speaker 0: That is.
Speaker 0: Well, Mars is Mars basically the people of Mars because they're you know, they have Abraham Lincoln king of Mars.
Speaker 0: They're like society and gobb gobb gobb grab basically lives there as their leader also.
Speaker 0: and you know normal Slash magic man also lived like Mars.
Speaker 0: That is a mark.
Speaker 0: That is a society that was Connected with like what's going on in the universe right sort of like a foundation situation Right where it's like, oh that society basically doesn't have interstellar travel yet They're sort of like just a you know, like an ant colony is to us.
Speaker 1: Well, I got the people of who could fight the Lich.
Speaker 1: the Mars people were the ones who could fight something like Orgellar.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and then gold is just.
Speaker 0: I mean, I mean the first time Orgellar came in the past.
Speaker 0: You know gobb just basically took a sword and swacked them.
Speaker 0: Yep, and that thing and turn them into Gunther just like whacking them.
Speaker 0: That's how strong gobb is Right.
Speaker 0: Yeah gobb is you know, he is God.
Speaker 0: to the people of who right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like but to the people of Mars He's just a dude of forehead.
Speaker 1: Well see also Prismo and the cosmic hour.
Speaker 1: Four dudes Prismo and the cosmic owl and all these entities are just gods out there doing their thing, right?
Speaker 1: But I like how they're all framed as themselves being mundane just on a different scale.
Speaker 1: Yeah I mean that's just hanging out with the cosmic owl.
Speaker 1: The cosmic owl is not that smart.
Speaker 0: No, he's not.
Speaker 1: cosmic owls got issues, but when he's first presented he is like this Supremely spiritual important being to the people of who yep with their whole thing about the croak dreams, right?
Speaker 0: But meanwhile on ooh The only people like even the people I knew who've been alive for a very very long time like say Marceline Yeah, Prince Bubblegum.
Speaker 0: That's the final.
Speaker 0: they don't know what's up.
Speaker 0: only Billy on earth really knows What's all that stuff.
Speaker 1: and Billy might have gone insane, you know and retired partly because he knew these things.
Speaker 1: Yeah, probably like Billy was too powerful.
Speaker 1: Also, it is implied heavily that Billy is part of an ancient race That was way more powerful than anything that came on earth since yeah, cuz remember when almost like a dinosaur They didn't become extinct.
Speaker 0: Well, cuz when?
Speaker 1: what's-her-name?
Speaker 1: the other Nereator?
Speaker 1: whoever the girl who was can you Billy's girlfriend?
Speaker 1: Yeah, Billy's girlfriend.
Speaker 1: She clearly is Terrifyingly powerful.
Speaker 1: Yes, and I liked how her and Finn just kind of hung out like that was a cool thing.
Speaker 1: Man, this show was good.
Speaker 1: I feel like we could talk about it for hours.
Speaker 0: Well, I mean there's so much show.
Speaker 0: Yeah when we do an episode we we made a video show about a single episode of utenna and our video show is longer than that single episode of utenna.
Speaker 0: and now you want to talk about a 10 11 season Show.
Speaker 1: I feel like I have between 5 and 25 minutes of things to say about every single episode of adventure time.
Speaker 0: Right every single character every single right, you know, alright, let's get the fun.
Speaker 1: Who's your favorite character?
Speaker 1: You're really really at its choose goose.
Speaker 0: Yeah, why wouldn't it be Tuesday?
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's tough Cuz.
Speaker 0: on one hand a lot of great characters, you know, especially and as always right I end up liking side characters more than me.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I really like huntress wizard Like I like.
Speaker 1: they just threw her in a lot at the address.
Speaker 0: wizard is cool and not as cool as peppermint butler.
Speaker 1: Oh, I love how fucking evil peppermint butler is But also how at the end of the show like there were Consequences of that fight like that little tiny scene of peppermint butler like they couldn't fix him.
Speaker 1: They're just raising him again.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but they're raising him to be evil again because why not?
Speaker 0: Well, I think he's just All right.
Speaker 0: Well, that's you know, that's one of the main Themes of the show is that in every different universe and you know You see the same people over and over again and only
Speaker 1: Marceline and the space people ever know Like the cycle
Speaker 0: right and Also, even in the same timeline the same things repeat themselves Right those two characters that go to visit BMO and then in the final episode
Speaker 1: are basically Jake
Speaker 0: They're like a Finn and Jake of their time,
Speaker 1: right?
Speaker 1: Cuz that world is too clearly post-apocalyptic to the world that right elements Right are the except for one of them.
Speaker 0: the other three are like, oh, yeah The same people keep getting reborn.
Speaker 1: look at that other the sex also.
Speaker 0: why you don't need to see Oh, they live the rest of their lives.
Speaker 0: cuz you know It's just a cycle of the same shit in every timeline and in every you know universe.
Speaker 0: Look at all these things happening over and over again.
Speaker 1: Look at the cycle looks slightly.
Speaker 1: so the characters who break the cycle are all themselves broken in some way.
Speaker 1: Marceline being immortal also never grew and Couldn't change and that was the whole plot of stakes of.
Speaker 1: she had to experience that cycle to like understand herself.
Speaker 1: The Lich is an entity that's trying to end the cycle forever.
Speaker 1: So he's all messed up.
Speaker 0: Well, that's why you know and that the exact opposite of the Lich is Prisma who is basically is the cycle, right?
Speaker 0: I was whereas, you know, there's a sleepy guy who's dreaming of Prisma.
Speaker 0: He gets woken up Prisma goes away and then a past Prisma pulls a trick to make a sleepy Jake That is then dreaming of Prisma and then Prisma's there again.
Speaker 0: There's a sleepy Jake there for all eternity and it's like that Cycle there.
Speaker 0: that happens in that like one or two episodes.
Speaker 0: that thing where Prisma goes away and comes back is I guess the cosmic, you know loop that holds all the other cosmic loops in in the in the cannon.
Speaker 0: And you see the same thing with what's like a Prisma had failed at that mission Then there probably would have been it.
Speaker 1: what pin the the ice elemental Instead of dying like she should in the cycle.
Speaker 1: She just never changes is trapped.
Speaker 1: Basically.
Speaker 1: She's trapped herself She'll wake up and anytime she wakes up Nothing will be different or better.
Speaker 1: and she's basically destroyed herself by being outside of the cycle.
Speaker 1: And then you've got things like gold that are themselves outside of the cycle because that's that's terrifying secret of space incomprehensible nonsense.
Speaker 0: Yeah wonder it's like, you know There was a Lich in every different universe right that we went to right like the the weird one that would like quaint country time Fin right and the bandit dudes or whatever, right?
Speaker 0: There was a Lich there who wasn't the exact same Lich as the other one, right?
Speaker 1: Then you see characters in the cycle breaking the negative aspect of their cycle like sweet pea Who is just good in the end?
Speaker 1: He's like, nope.
Speaker 1: I'm not gonna be like you Lich.
Speaker 1: Fuck you.
Speaker 0: Yes He is awesome.
Speaker 0: He's the next.
Speaker 0: did you notice the very end of very end of the show?
Speaker 0: There's a giant sweet pea walking past the bemo mountain.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I got enormous like bigger than I think that might be the giantest thing I get like.
Speaker 0: as big as sweet pea was there was bigger than gold was.
Speaker 1: Yep real big.
Speaker 1: I just love that moment where sweet pea one scares the shit out of that evil squirrel in the king of ooh.
Speaker 1: Because they were the worst characters in the show, right?
Speaker 0: You know, I think the most The thing that really I feel needed more tying up or maybe the juice juice or maybe was appropriately not tied up Was Tree trunks.
Speaker 0: cuz tree trunks is so she's there.
Speaker 1: from the beginning I noticed they hinted at things in the old old flashback episodes with the original elementals that we see There's those weird tree trunks looking being.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: I'm saying she is ancient and Basically as best I can tell it's like a magic elf who gave up on all the weird magic elf stuff and just wanted to be Perverted forever.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like.
Speaker 0: it's like Cuz tree trunks spans like the cosmic and the mundane and like this crazy weird fucked up way.
Speaker 0: and it's like sometimes She's just insane and sometimes she's super lucid and knows that Relations with aliens and knows about aliens and doesn't care that much The pig guy.
Speaker 0: Yeah, he cares a lot.
Speaker 0: then she goes to the woods and deals like crystal whatnot?
Speaker 0: craziness?
Speaker 0: Yeah, also just makes a pie as delicious.
Speaker 1: But all these I love the way all these different characters and how they interact with this like cosmic cycle are threaded together.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: Goddamn.
Speaker 1: The show is good.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm I Got a little choked up at the very end just because of I saw it coming as soon as like it was wrapping up and they Start walking back.
Speaker 1: I knew the way the show had gone.
Speaker 1: The last moment was gonna be the theme song.
Speaker 0: But that montage that was the name of the last episode is You know.
Speaker 0: But is the name of the first episode at Adventure Time?
Speaker 1: I think so.
Speaker 0: Like come grab your friends or something?
Speaker 0: Yeah, and I guess the name of the last episode is you know Come along with me.
Speaker 1: the fact that they did it like they did the perfect ending of the final scene is just The song that has ended the show that you watched for like a decade.
Speaker 0: Well, it's good because they didn't do a new tenor.
Speaker 0: where it's like this horse is all the time.
Speaker 0: I never see the horses like this.
Speaker 0: is me All right, we'll put the B at the end I just imagine.
Speaker 1: to this day dammit Dwayne is where is wherever he is and is.
Speaker 1: he's in a crazy room Filled with pictures of those horses trying to figure out where they happen.
Speaker 0: I like how they hide a snail.
Speaker 0: I don't know if they hide a snail in every episode, but it's 99% of the episodes.
Speaker 0: But the thing is I feel like I only saw the snail and like half the episodes.
Speaker 0: So I'm always like did they really put one all the time because I feel like I noticed it a lot.
Speaker 0: I'm really good at noticing the snail.
Speaker 1: Well, the fact that the snail is the only reason the Lich even gets out.
Speaker 0: I know right a plus Yep, it's like.
Speaker 0: it's not just a hidden snail.
Speaker 0: It's a plot snail.
Speaker 1: Yeah But just it's heavy and good the way that like Marceline's arc and stakes in particular
Speaker 0: I'm sure there's a website that says every time the snail is like
Speaker 1: the snail busts that out and like there's all these breaking the cycles just the fact that there's those little moments of the Handful of characters who live long enough to see the cycle repeat even a little bit.
Speaker 1: They get bill bowed like they're different.
Speaker 0: So one of my favorite episodes is actually an episode that doesn't matter for the plot really at all.
Speaker 0: Is the infinity train one?
Speaker 1: Oh, I like that one a lot because it has aka why you shouldn't play MMOs?
Speaker 0: Yes, exactly because there's this strong message right of don't play most Right, but also it's actually pretty cool fighting all these monsters not cool training the world.
Speaker 1: You got to know when to stop right.
Speaker 0: but it also has you know this sort of greater message Right where it's like Finn sees that like Jake's been following him forever, right?
Speaker 0: And he's like, oh my friend is maybe more important than this Serotonin loop whatever whatever it is.
Speaker 1: I think my favorite episode is what was missing with the door Lord.
Speaker 0: It's a real good one.
Speaker 1: But my second favorite episode is the hall of egress.
Speaker 0: It's a good one, too Cuz.
Speaker 1: that episode feels a lot like Don Jean the comic like that kind of thing that sort of existential surreal experience.
Speaker 1: That episode really stands out among the great episodes of Adventure Time as being my favorite.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm I'm sure there's one.
Speaker 1: I like that.
Speaker 1: I'm forgetting though just scrolling through.
Speaker 1: there are a lot of freaking episodes.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there's tons of way a plus episodes.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: I Think we'll just leave it there.
Speaker 1: cuz as much as I would love I gotta go eat dinner.
Speaker 1: Yeah We are not going to make nice presents Adventure Time because that would be harder that would take.
Speaker 0: I'm sure other people are doing things like that.
Speaker 0: You know, there's plenty of it.
Speaker 0: You don't need us.
Speaker 1: I'll tell you what.
Speaker 1: if somehow geek nights makes me a bit of money to where I'd never have to work again I will make that.
Speaker 0: All right, you're on your own.
Speaker 1: Yeah Come along Scott, you know you want to know I don't.
Speaker 1: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Speaker 0: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 1: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays and a comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 0: But unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night and the patreon patrons for this episode of geek nights are Craig Oliver Ellen Joyce had a vehicle just like a dude guy.
Speaker 1: chart option link Jennifer Hitchcock Chris mick if my stay there come.
Speaker 1: J Bants cuda lonely Roberto Kingsley Shawn Yeager Nicholas Brando, mr.
Speaker 1: Strong stretch in 421 creations devourer of chaos champions of the great halls of Terrakis Sheriff not horrible or Rory Rochelle, Monta notice super boy sailor Vista Joshua Joe Stark Clinton Walton Renford, New Zealand Whoa, Ryan Perrin drew open Lander Finn Daniel Redmond Sean Klein Chris Reimer Thomas, hon.
Speaker 1: and now I leave you with Me and the butterflies and bees.
Speaker 1: We can wander through the forest And you.
Speaker 0: so as we please Come along with me To a cliff under a tree Or we can gaze upon the water as a never-lasting dream.
Speaker 1: All of my collections.
Speaker 1: I'll share them all with you.
Speaker 1: Maybe by next summer We won't have changed our tune.
Speaker 1: Let's go on to be with the butterflies and bees Making up new numbers And living so merrily.
Speaker 1: All of my Collections, I'll share them all with you.
Speaker 1: I'll be here for you always And always.
Speaker 0: be with you.
Speaker 0: Come along with me and the butterflies and bees.
Speaker 1: We can walk.
Speaker 1: Check it out, dude, very pretty Lift that sword sure me.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah.