Speaker 0: It's Wednesday July 10th 2019.
Speaker 0: I'm rim.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott and this is geek nights tonight.
Speaker 0: We are judging Anime by its cover the summer 2019 anime that we have not watched.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: So back in the day way back in the day, New York like 1857 1940 something.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there were parades in New York all the fucking time.
Speaker 1: You didn't really mean.
Speaker 0: what else do you do back then?
Speaker 1: Sure, but like back in those days you had you started to do something really great to get a parade.
Speaker 1: But like if you were just a fancy person like a king or something and you visited New York You would get a parade.
Speaker 1: if you did something like win some Olympic gold medals You would get a parade right now again because there was nothing else going on.
Speaker 1: Like you're bored and then someone's like hey this Kings in town right nowadays Right the bar that there's much fewer parades Okay, and and the bar for getting a parade is so much higher.
Speaker 0: I mean what the Rangers got won by winning Lord Stanley's car so you can win one.
Speaker 1: Basically, they're almost these days almost every parade.
Speaker 1: I think the last parade that I can remember Happening.
Speaker 1: I'm sure someone might find one on Wikipedia or something.
Speaker 1: I'm like list of parades, but the last parade I remember being in New York City.
Speaker 1: That was not sports related was when the Pope visited.
Speaker 0: No, we gotta be clear.
Speaker 0: We're not talking about like the Puerto Rican Day Parade like.
Speaker 1: We're talking about the actual right.
Speaker 1: so if you don't like the ticker tape, right.
Speaker 1: if you're not in New York City You had to realize there is an area downtown.
Speaker 0: There's a Wikipedia page that lists everyone.
Speaker 0: ever, right?
Speaker 1: So if you if you don't know New York City Right Battery Park is at the bottom of the city and you go north a little bit on Broadway It's called Battery Park because there were batteries of cannons there.
Speaker 1: Anyway, it's called and that stretch of Broadway is known as the quote Canyon of Heroes And then it ends at City Hall.
Speaker 1: and what you do is if you did something really fucking awesome You get your.
Speaker 1: you get a parade that goes down that little bit of road.
Speaker 1: Oh, dude, it's real narrow and everyone throws shredded paper out the window.
Speaker 0: This is great because the list of them there aren't that many These days there are that I want to list the first few because they're really funny.
Speaker 0: So the first one 1886 October 28th The Statue of Liberty was dedicated and people just had an impromptu parade like it just happened Sounds good.
Speaker 0: that started the tradition.
Speaker 1: That's the bar That's like.
Speaker 1: that's how great a thing has to be to be parade worthy.
Speaker 0: three years later in 1889 the centennial of George Washington becoming the first president.
Speaker 0: Oh Okay, uh Admiral Dewey returning from Manila Theodore Roosevelt returning from his African safari That's not that that's a pretty low bar that one.
Speaker 1: That's the US Olympic Games.
Speaker 0: athletes returning in 1912.
Speaker 0: There you go, not even winning just coming back because the Olympics were kind of new back.
Speaker 1: Let us hear a bigger deal then.
Speaker 0: Yeah General Pershing coming back from the with the commander of the American Expeditionary Force Edward Albert the Prince of Wales Daining to visit.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's why I say a lot of them are like fancy person the marshal of France.
Speaker 1: That was a lot of the visit ones were before there were planes.
Speaker 1: visiting a place is a big fucking deal right?
Speaker 1: Yeah Titanic before it crashed Sending off parade, but they basically they slowed.
Speaker 0: it looks like they slowed down in the 70s, right?
Speaker 1: So the reason they slowed down at least as far as I'm aware is not like a specific mandate or anything.
Speaker 1: it's simply that you know a Humanity has achieved a lot less things that are parade worthy.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there hasn't been an Apollo like moon landing in a while, right.
Speaker 1: And be even if you did something worthy, right?
Speaker 1: So for take for example Like Michael Phelps if Michael Phelps who won a huge mountain of gold Olympic medals had just been born 50 years earlier he would have gotten one or more parades.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right but in you know 2015 whatever.
Speaker 1: whenever he won his you know pile of medals and when was the last Summer Olympics 2016?
Speaker 1: I don't remember.
Speaker 1: I mean in the point is who would show up for the Michael Phelps parade?
Speaker 1: who would even show up for the American Summer Olympians parade, right?
Speaker 1: It's like you will.
Speaker 1: people would not turn out for that.
Speaker 0: in the 70s There were a grand total of one two, three, four five six of these.
Speaker 0: Yeah in the 80s.
Speaker 0: There were four.
Speaker 0: Yeah in the 90s.
Speaker 0: There were a few more.
Speaker 1: right now you got it.
Speaker 1: You know, I I will take all the New York sports team parades As long as they're not Yankees or Islanders.
Speaker 0: or I was about to say these 70s were in order.
Speaker 0: Yes, Apollo 14.
Speaker 0: Yeah, Apollo 15.
Speaker 0: Yeah, uh Some bicentennial operation sale thing with sailors.
Speaker 0: Yeah Yankees winning the World Series Yankees winning the World Series and Pope John Paul the second day.
Speaker 1: I see I was tired, you know, then the Pope visiting all I get over 81 the Iranian hostages being released.
Speaker 1: That's one of them.
Speaker 1: yeah, right but the point is Oh 86 the Mets right?
Speaker 1: Yeah I was like, it's like right, you know, I was thinking I was like I was there at the parade for you know The women is a lot of World Series.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you don't say yeah It's almost like there are great baseball teams like that evil team.
Speaker 0: I like the evil teams.
Speaker 1: It's like yeah, the women's team won the World Cup which is way, you know, that's like American All right, so New York level stuff.
Speaker 1: you happen to get in New York parade because it's New York.
Speaker 1: I mean the last three the last seven were sports victories right - Yankees Giants Yankees Giants World Cup World Cup, right, but the World Cup ones are significantly better because that's a world accomplishment Not a New York us-only account.
Speaker 1: I mean the Super Bowl is a world accomplishment kind of Right, but I'm thinking like what the fuck do you have to do to get a parade?
Speaker 0: Well, like you said it's like one higher honor come back from Mars, right?
Speaker 1: That's what I'm saying.
Speaker 1: Like what honor aids, right?
Speaker 1: How great do you have to fucking be?
Speaker 1: It's like you could win the Nobel Prize and not get a parade.
Speaker 0: There are a lot of people win the Nobel Prize and don't get this parade.
Speaker 1: I mean like you have to be an American.
Speaker 1: Yeah, a lot of how many Americans win the Nobel Prize a lot of Nobel Prizes.
Speaker 0: Sure Obama won a Nobel Prize.
Speaker 1: Pray no praise.
Speaker 1: or Obama.
Speaker 1: to get a New York parade is like it's like harder than like almost anything.
Speaker 1: Like sports are like the only reasonable route because it's like.
Speaker 1: it's just like the bar of accomplishment and heroism required.
Speaker 1: So it's just so high.
Speaker 1: Here's another list.
Speaker 1: You have to be like an all-time great human to be like this.
Speaker 1: Is there even a person alive?
Speaker 1: Right that you can just say, you know what that is a person who is alive and they're just so great that they are parade worthy.
Speaker 0: So I learned some great facts about human being alive in 2019 anyone.
Speaker 0: so there's a list of People who were so fucking awesome.
Speaker 0: they had more than one.
Speaker 0: There's not many Richard Byrd Bobby Jones, Amelia Earhart, Eisenhower, Charles de Gaulle, John Glenn.
Speaker 0: Yeah, not many people In terms of sports teams honored the Yankees have had nine.
Speaker 1: Yep, and they've won a lot more than nine World Series.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they didn't get a parade every and we've rescinded one of them.
Speaker 1: Well, there's the Nazi guy.
Speaker 0: Yeah Yeah, these are the Marshall pretend but basically the Collaborator shithead who ran the martial law state that was later occupied by the Nazis.
Speaker 0: They removed the plaque and they were like, nope, that parade does not count.
Speaker 1: His name's still on the ground over there.
Speaker 0: Uh, apparently they tore it up.
Speaker 1: It's over there.
Speaker 0: Oh, they are planning to tear it up.
Speaker 1: They said they wouldn't haven't done jack shit.
Speaker 0: Yeah Duh-duh-duh.
Speaker 0: Apparently so France is giving a shit because they removed in 2010 the last remaining plaque with his name on it in the entire goddamn country, and New York still has one plaque.
Speaker 1: We should go vandalize it.
Speaker 0: We'll get a jack full disclosure if it gets vandalized.
Speaker 0: We did not do it.
Speaker 0: We did it but we didn't do it Jack.
Speaker 1: Oh, what's this jackhammer rental receipt for them to cost?
Speaker 0: You bought a jackhammer Overalls, a mask, and a fake permit, and a clipboard Some orange vests, some cones, a white econolied van.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: You live-streamed yourself doing it?
Speaker 1: All right, the point is is like if you set your goal in life to get parade good fucking luck.
Speaker 1: It's like what honor.
Speaker 1: like you I can't imagine an honor greater than having the parade for you.
Speaker 1: Yep It's like what it's like you you know.
Speaker 1: yeah, Emily was saying at the parade like yeah She can make an animation and win like every single Oscar at every single category and would not get a parade.
Speaker 0: There's the plot of the next Lupin movie.
Speaker 0: Lupin steals a parade.
Speaker 0: Steals a New York City parade.
Speaker 1: Steals a parade for himself.
Speaker 0: It's for him.
Speaker 1: Now there's a parade for Lupin.
Speaker 1: What did he do?
Speaker 1: It starts as a parade for like- It's someone else's parade, but he stole it.
Speaker 0: Yeah It starts as a parade for world peace and then all the floats turn into Lupin's.
Speaker 0: Yeah So there's actually a whole bunch of anime news.
Speaker 0: We're gonna pick and choose random bits.
Speaker 1: cuz well cuz anime expo just happened which means a lot of anime news happened.
Speaker 1: Yep, now I gotta be clear.
Speaker 1: Anime expo is a garbage con.
Speaker 1: You should never go to anime expo Just like you shouldn't go to New York Comic Con or San Diego Comic Con.
Speaker 1: It's a con like it's not like all these small medium sized anime cons.
Speaker 0: Like New York Anime Festival.
Speaker 1: Even Anime Boston Which is large.
Speaker 0: Anime NYC good to go to.
Speaker 1: New York Comic Con?
Speaker 1: Completely different from anime expo.
Speaker 1: Anime expo is bad.
Speaker 0: But anime expo is not just bad for those reasons It's also really badly run.
Speaker 0: It's a miserable experience.
Speaker 0: Like every year you can watch Twitter and see the garbage fire.
Speaker 1: There is no reason to be at it.
Speaker 1: and this year They were earthquakes.
Speaker 1: Yeah That's why I don't go to- I've never been to California.
Speaker 1: earthquakes are part of the reason.
Speaker 0: I mean the oh the.
Speaker 0: I've never been to California except for work.
Speaker 1: I've been there for the airport.
Speaker 0: I've been there for work a bunch of times.
Speaker 1: I might go there soon, but I gotta wait for earthquake season to stop.
Speaker 0: I mean earthquake.
Speaker 0: the earthquakes are not causing that much damage because of regulations.
Speaker 0: Uh-huh.
Speaker 1: I still don't really want to be in one.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I've been in minor earthquakes.
Speaker 0: They're a big deal.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I've been in New York earthquakes.
Speaker 1: They're fine.
Speaker 0: Yeah I remember that earthquake.
Speaker 0: cuz I was on the street and suddenly people come running out of the buildings and running out of the subways.
Speaker 1: You know, it feels like someone, you know, like stomped around a little bit.
Speaker 0: Well, cuz if you're on the street, you know, feel it.
Speaker 0: But if you're in a old building in New York the buildings sway a lot Cuz they're old.
Speaker 1: It just feels like someone was stomping around on the on the roof above you and like hey cut it out And it's like no that was the whole world joking.
Speaker 0: So I'm gonna go through.
Speaker 0: some of the news is from Anime Expo.
Speaker 0: number one Katsuhiro Otomo.
Speaker 1: If you don't know who is the creator of Akira.
Speaker 0: Yep Directed part of robot carnival done a lot of stuff.
Speaker 0: He is getting a new movie, right?
Speaker 1: So I guess he's running out of money because this is like the least You think about.
Speaker 1: most of the creators of great animes and mangas are known for being Ultra prolific work of workaholics like Satoshi God made as many movies as he could while he was a lot He's like, uh, he just freaking cranked him out like a machine.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but Otomo is famous for barely making fucking anything.
Speaker 1: He made a handful of Really awesome artsy indie mangas the most famous of which is like Domo right, which is great.
Speaker 1: And then he made Akira which is like one of the best manga ever created.
Speaker 1: He sort of did some work on this manga called Legend of Mother Sarah.
Speaker 1: That was sort of published in the u.s.
Speaker 1: It's really hard to get and he was actually by another dude metropolis Really involved in metropolis.
Speaker 1: that much.
Speaker 0: Well, he was involved.
Speaker 1: His name was on it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right But basically he made the Akira movie, which is great, even though it you know only bore some resemblance to the manga.
Speaker 1: And then he didn't make anything fucking else until steam boy, which was not great.
Speaker 0: Nope See boy was really pretty but it was not good.
Speaker 1: and then he sort of I don't know how much he worked on the frame Cup noodle freedom thing.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like I don't even know Everything is great because it just has a line at the end that says it's like the things they picked.
Speaker 0: to associate Him with is pretty funny quote.
Speaker 0: He also collaborated on Harmageddon barely erosion Z.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah Reagan Which everyone forgets.
Speaker 0: who remembers spring in?
Speaker 0: yeah metropolis cup noodle?
Speaker 0: and he pira the little vampire.
Speaker 0: We've reviewed it on fucking gig nights.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 0: I don't remember you don't remember he.
Speaker 0: it was not great.
Speaker 0: Okay, the point is Like show with the cute little vampire.
Speaker 1: I don't remember this anyway.
Speaker 1: Otomo is like this dude who's clearly shown the potential to create like all-time great parade worthy works 2011 tonight on gig nights the cute he Peter and the fun walk food Both.
Speaker 1: the point is Akira is parade worthy But Otomo is not because since then he's done jack and shit basically, right?
Speaker 1: So they're redoing Akira in HD, which I guess is a good thing.
Speaker 1: You know, you know, but he's making another thing called the orbital or something.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the image the promotional image looks very Otomo esque and involves.
Speaker 0: All I think of Otomo is there's someone probably wearing a helmet of some kind Standing in the middle of a big mostly empty thing holding something maybe with a motorbike, right?
Speaker 1: So, I mean, I hope it's good obviously because I love Otomo when he's good.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I really wish the thing is if you look at the things he's worked on animation wise You know where he's had heavy involvement.
Speaker 1: He's only had the one hit where it was based on a manga.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right But all of his manga which he I don't.
Speaker 1: he's made any manga since Akira none of note or significant.
Speaker 1: anyway I really wish he would just make manga cuz he's basically never made a bad manga.
Speaker 0: You know what?
Speaker 0: I was about this.
Speaker 0: This is the monkey's paw situation.
Speaker 0: You're like, I wish Otomo would make more stuff.
Speaker 0: The monkey's paw is like he's gonna make another mediocre movie, right?
Speaker 0: Makes great comedy anime and what he ends up like.
Speaker 0: all he wants to do is make a really boring Terrible live-action stuff that nobody likes.
Speaker 1: It's like if Otomo would just make a manga.
Speaker 1: it would be great Hopefully and then he could make an anime based on that manga.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right and then that would hopefully also be great, but you just go and direct to you know movie and it's not.
Speaker 1: you know.
Speaker 1: I I can.
Speaker 1: I can hope it's great, but I'm going to set expectations low because that way I won't have any disappointment or Excitement or anticipation.
Speaker 1: Yep, you know if it is I do hope it's great though.
Speaker 1: That'll be awesome.
Speaker 0: so in another news from Expo promare, which Imagine just kill la kill - right promare is a new animated movie from studio trigger Who.
Speaker 0: it looks like it's made by studio trigger.
Speaker 1: It is studio trigger the movie you.
Speaker 1: it was shown at anime Expo.
Speaker 1: It's gonna be shown at Otakon and tickets are on sale to go see it in a theater near you.
Speaker 1: I bought a ticket to see it in the theater near me.
Speaker 0: I think I'm gonna be out of the country when it's in the theater.
Speaker 1: I think it's showing sometime in October.
Speaker 1: There's only two days.
Speaker 1: It's showing.
Speaker 1: the weekend date is a dub showing.
Speaker 1: in the weeknight showing is a sub.
Speaker 0: So make sure you go see it on the weeknight after work like I am so crunchy roll now There's an update to this crunchy roll adult swim and a bunch of other people are joining HBO max, right?
Speaker 1: So if you don't know about this Let's say you want to do legal streaming and you don't want to pirate anything.
Speaker 1: You don't have cable, right?
Speaker 1: So if you want if you're interested in HBO your options are HBO go.
Speaker 0: Well, your options are your parents.
Speaker 1: HBO go exactly you don't have HBO go means you have cable and you log in with your cable And then you can watch HBO.
Speaker 1: HBO now is a thing that lets you watch some limited amount of HBO mostly Game of Thrones.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's pretty much the Game of Thrones.
Speaker 1: HBO now effectively is Pay money to watch Game of Thrones if you don't have HP.
Speaker 1: if you can't get HBO go or pirate or do anything else I mean, yeah, right And I don't even care about Game of Thrones right.
Speaker 1: HBO max is a new thing.
Speaker 1: It's basically going to be like a real streaming service just like fucking Netflix and you pay for it.
Speaker 1: And not only do you get a bunch of HBO stuff?
Speaker 1: You're also gonna get all the Warner stuff, right?
Speaker 1: You're gonna get Cartoon Network stuff.
Speaker 0: You're gonna get all kinds of Almost all the Warner media brands like Warner Brothers stuff new line DC entertainment CNN TNT TBS Out of the box.
Speaker 1: If they put enough content into this out of the box then like that is a Netflix level competitor right there.
Speaker 1: you're gonna be choosing between like.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna be switching between Netflix this one and the Disney one like.
Speaker 0: I hate that.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna get the Disney ones.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna switch between the three depending on what I'm watching.
Speaker 0: So what's interesting is because they're gonna bring a bunch of content from their subsidiaries Subsidiaries because one of the subsidiaries of Warner media is otter media and I otter media owns a whole bunch of crap Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: I can think they own crunchyroll.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 0: So all this stuff is gonna be on HBO max, but to be clear here I'm gonna just quote anime news network crunchyroll.
Speaker 0: clarified with anime news network on Wednesdays like recently that only select content from crunchyroll Will be available on HBO max, right?
Speaker 1: For crunchyroll, so if you want deep cuts from crunchyroll, you're gonna have to get crunchyroll.
Speaker 1: But if you just want to watch some anime and you have HBO max, you're gonna see some anime.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right.
Speaker 1: So if you're the kind of person who maybe watches like the top animes and not the deep cuts then maybe HBO max.
Speaker 1: or you Know Netflix or any, you know Any of this?
Speaker 0: all the services seem to have a little bit anime going on with my my current strategy of I have Netflix I have crunchyroll and I have pirate Bay.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I mean, that's what I have right now.
Speaker 1: But I also I do know I have those two things and I have Criterion Channel, but yeah, I do Movies and shows on Amazon.
Speaker 1: I haven't been watching crunchyroll recently, but the problem is I have an annual membership So I can't cancel and uncancel Right.
Speaker 1: So but I probably won't renew it until there's a show I need to watch on crunchyroll.
Speaker 0: So lastly is Neon Genesis Evangelion we talked about at length is now available on Netflix.
Speaker 1: We talked about that last and yeah Wednesday show.
Speaker 0: I just want to point out if you for whatever reason listen to geek nights, but haven't watched Evangelion we don't need to re-review it because back in 2007 we reviewed Neon Genesis Evangelion and We in 2008 did a full deep final thoughts spoilers everywhere Like talk about Neon Genesis Evangelion.
Speaker 0: So rather than us do this again You can just go listen to those old geek nights episodes And you'll get the weird novelty of Scott doing the opening introduction to the show instead of me because we used to alternate back in 2007.
Speaker 1: you get some old ass 2007 news.
Speaker 0: Oh, well, what's the news here?
Speaker 0: Let's see in the news Michiko and Hachin is an anime and Tatsunoko vs.
Speaker 0: Capcom is going crazy.
Speaker 0: go nuts.
Speaker 0: I don't know what that news was.
Speaker 0: and for the other show Let's see, we review Neon Genesis Evangelion in the news.
Speaker 0: Speed Racer and Boku Ra.
Speaker 0: I think Boku Rano came out.
Speaker 0: Maybe we?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 0: None of these links are valid anymore.
Speaker 0: They're all 404s.
Speaker 0: There's no way to find out what the hell.
Speaker 0: Oh Boku Rano.
Speaker 0: Oh, you know our news was Boku Rano.
Speaker 0: the anime Changed the ending because the manga ending was too depressing.
Speaker 1: the manga and anime are significantly different.
Speaker 1: I watched all the anime.
Speaker 1: I have all the manga.
Speaker 1: I haven't read it all yet.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that anime is pretty good.
Speaker 0: Actually.
Speaker 0: It's way good I could watch it again someday.
Speaker 0: go finally this weekend.
Speaker 0: If you are not aware there is a convention in Connecticut in Hartford called Kinetic Con.
Speaker 1: now Isn't it usually the same weekend as San Diego Comic Con?
Speaker 0: Yeah, it moves around But it's this coming weekend like this weekend.
Speaker 0: All right If you live within like a couple hours drive San Diego Comic Con if you live within a couple hours drive or a reasonable train ride You should go to Kinetic Con.
Speaker 0: It's a pretty good con, but it's not a fly to Connecticut convention.
Speaker 0: Don't fly there.
Speaker 0: But if you live nearby, you should probably go.
Speaker 1: Okay, San Diego Comic Con is the week after that.
Speaker 1: It's the 18th through the 21st.
Speaker 0: So we used to go every year.
Speaker 0: We used to run the entire like panels and workshops department.
Speaker 0: We were tired from that position our good friends cold guy and they took over Running that area and they do a really good job.
Speaker 0: The convention is just as good as it's always been.
Speaker 0: So we'll probably return someday.
Speaker 0: We can't return because actually Scott has something going on this weekend.
Speaker 0: So it would have been just me and the only just me con I do is Zenkai Con.
Speaker 0: But if you're anywhere near Connecticut, you should totally go to this con.
Speaker 0: They got a lot of Steven Universe voice actors and it's always a good time.
Speaker 0: also, frankly Other than PAX's and magfests like weirdly enough Kinetic Con is like one of the better Tabletop gaming cons you could go to in the East Coast.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, like you wouldn't think that you wouldn't even know that It is a better gaming con just inside of this con than most gaming cons are And gaming is just like one area of the con.
Speaker 0: But anyway, it's time for things of the day.
Speaker 0: What do you got?
Speaker 0: So here are some people presumably in Russia But maybe not right, you know I also got a Russia vibe based on the with the laughter and based on that old ass control.
Speaker 1: So what's the name of the Twitter account?
Speaker 1: men's corner?
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't know but I don't know about this Twitter account.
Speaker 0: Oh this Twitter account probably just agree I don't know.
Speaker 1: But the point is the video in this tweet is excellent.
Speaker 1: There are two stupid people on train tracks walking Yeah Don't.
Speaker 1: and reason the train which the camera is inside of is Sneaking up on them and they don't hear that train even though it's going slow.
Speaker 1: trains are loud slow.
Speaker 0: Well electric trains that are not accelerating or decelerating that are relatively modern and well maintained are actually really quiet.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but anyway, uh hilarity ensues.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's a real good tweet.
Speaker 1: very very you're not gonna get much more laughter in 25 seconds than you are with this one.
Speaker 0: So thing of the day So my thing of the day, I'm like 70% sure this is real because I've seen some shit in my life.
Speaker 1: I mean, I it could be real could be fake but in the absence of proof that it's real I have to lean towards fake.
Speaker 1: even though I don't I'm not gonna say a hundred percent.
Speaker 0: I feel like it's real because I have encountered Similarly weird situations like that.
Speaker 0: saxophone house is clearly fake and Sephiroth house is pretty but this feels like it happened.
Speaker 0: but basically, you know, there's a place on reddit where people will semi anonymously ask for relationship advice and The most common reason you would go to that place is to see what a shit show other people's lives are so you can feel Better about yourself, right?
Speaker 1: Well, I mean the person who wrote this relationship advice post says they originally Posted on our a ITA which if you don't know is am I the asshole?
Speaker 1: Yeah, which is another great place to go on reddit because basically you have people who either are assholes or People who are.
Speaker 1: you know in situations?
Speaker 0: Entangled with assholes how we should make one.
Speaker 1: you get to go there and you get to basically vote on.
Speaker 1: You are the person posting this.
Speaker 1: you're the asshole or no?
Speaker 1: the person you're posting about is the asshole Assuming you're not lying.
Speaker 0: I feel like we should make the spin-off.
Speaker 0: Am I that guy?
Speaker 1: Okay, yes, you're that guy if you have to ask well To ask if you're that guy you're not that guy.
Speaker 0: like I have almost anyone who's ever worried about a guy.
Speaker 1: You're not that probably not that guy.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that guy has no idea that he's that guy and hates all the other that guys.
Speaker 0: So anyway, I'm just gonna read the very beginning of this because you got to read it.
Speaker 0: It's it swerves Very delicately and in a wonderful way that I love.
Speaker 0: I'm female 34 pregnant and struggling with my husband.
Speaker 0: male 35 lack of support regarding my regarding my in-laws behavior.
Speaker 0: How could I prove the situation?
Speaker 0: I've been happily married for 10 years.
Speaker 0: I'm very much in love.
Speaker 0: I'm not sure of the blah blah blah, but basically quote the relationship with his parents has been strained.
Speaker 0: They own a number of mouse figurines.
Speaker 0: Okay That's already.
Speaker 1: a lot of people collect stuff.
Speaker 0: They're made from different materials and one is a giant papier-mâché one called Timothy.
Speaker 0: Okay, each of them has a whole character profile with backstories personal pressure preferences family relations, etc.
Speaker 1: Okay So they not only do they collect but they take it the extra mile with fan fiction and all of them are seen as part Of the family.
Speaker 0: Timothy is my in-laws grandchild.
Speaker 0: What unsettles me is that they constantly talk to them and with other my.
Speaker 0: they constantly talk as them With other mice or each other and guess they used high-pitched tones and they'll talk in this manner that little children to use for instance.
Speaker 1: Okay, so that they have mental problems and they need help.
Speaker 0: My father will squeak.
Speaker 0: My husband's father will squeakingly say my tummy hurts.
Speaker 0: I am hungry while wiggling a mouse plushie in my face.
Speaker 1: Assuming this is true.
Speaker 1: He's got problems that needs help, but the entire family is in on the whole family needs.
Speaker 0: Oh, all I'm gonna say is that You're if you read this like usually when you read these stories the swerve is like oh wow Your husband's an incel.
Speaker 0: or like yeah, your wife is cheating on you.
Speaker 0: This one swerves in a direction that I did not anticipate.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's so weird and so specific that it's it's like it would be a very creative person who made this up.
Speaker 0: Yeah like I'd like.
Speaker 0: I feel like if someone made this up they need to make a choose your own adventure video game because they would Come up with like the best adventure book ever.
Speaker 1: Yeah with their creative mind.
Speaker 0: in the meta moment the geek nights book club book is apparently still pages of pain By Troy.
Speaker 1: it is the first book ever.
Speaker 1: Well the first novel ever which is the tale of Genji.
Speaker 0: so let's get right into it.
Speaker 0: because Usually as you know, we do a YouTube show on Scott's YouTube channel Which you subscribe to called judge anime by its cover.
Speaker 1: We used to do it in anime Boston as a panel.
Speaker 0: Yep One year we were like, let's review all the anime that's coming out based on a screenshot And it was really fucking funny and really fun to do.
Speaker 0: and we're like, we're really accurate.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's I'm not gonna say we're 100% accurate.
Speaker 1: we get stuff wrong But we're still.
Speaker 1: the thing is people, you know who say oh, we're super dumb.
Speaker 1: It's first of all.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we admit we're super dumb We don't know stuff.
Speaker 1: and be you know, it's like yeah, we got something super wrong, but percentage-wise We're getting mostly hits.
Speaker 1: It's like yeah.
Speaker 1: Look I got ten bull's-eyes You know two in the red and like one missed the target.
Speaker 1: It's like really you're gonna say that I suck cuz you know.
Speaker 1: to mr.
Speaker 1: Target three.
Speaker 0: So normally we do temples as we do this with high production value is not as a podcast But just as a YouTube thing, but we've had a lot of travel and we've been busy So we did not have time to do that, right?
Speaker 1: Well, I mean as we speak the summer season of anime is happening.
Speaker 1: episodes twos and threes of different shows are coming out Like within a few days I have avoided or watching.
Speaker 1: so we're already late even though we haven't watched any anime Some of these shows.
Speaker 0: so we could do this and we haven't done it.
Speaker 1: We didn't have any other show idea for tonight.
Speaker 1: I didn't have any video stuff set up in my house.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the weather is You know, the AQI is not so good.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the air quality is pretty bad today in New York, right?
Speaker 1: So yeah a variety of circumstances like alright, let's be lazy bums.
Speaker 1: We are no reason to deny that we are lazy bums.
Speaker 1: We will make one episode the some, you know The summer episode of this show just as a geek nights episode and not make a video.
Speaker 0: So what I will say if you like this go subscribe to Scott's YouTube channel because we've been doing this on his channel for a while.
Speaker 1: Yeah I guess our policy is like whoever edits the video posted on their channel because we don't have the geek nights YouTube channel You can give them to me to post on mine cuz mine has a lot more followers.
Speaker 0: Yeah, whatever mine makes my makes money.
Speaker 0: Yeah, actually my youtube channel covers the Libsyn bills now like completely, okay, that's actually.
Speaker 0: I was surprised by that.
Speaker 0: I looked I didn't notice for a while that it's been making money.
Speaker 0: Right, but I know the listener is smart because that money is almost entirely YouTube, right?
Speaker 0: Well not read anymore YouTube people who pay for YouTube.
Speaker 0: YouTube gives us money because they watched our videos because anyone who's not paying for YouTube I assume is blocking ads.
Speaker 0: if you're not blocking ads block ads like ad block works on YouTube guys.
Speaker 0: So, let's get right into it.
Speaker 0: Scott can't really see this.
Speaker 1: unless I got my own I got my head.
Speaker 0: so Dr.
Speaker 0: Stone One day I'm already feeling this.
Speaker 0: It looks good.
Speaker 1: You build his confesses to a girl He loves and the sky is filled with a strange light.
Speaker 1: Everyone's touched by the light is turned to stone.
Speaker 0: Oh kind of like the everyone's trapped to stone.
Speaker 1: He breaks out and he explores a crazy world And he finds some other people who were freed from stone, but not everyone.
Speaker 1: So basically it's like what if everyone was turned to stone.
Speaker 1: it's like that old sci-fi on the whole planet.
Speaker 1: But then some people were slowly released over time and then the main character gets released and he's not necessarily the first or only to Be released but you then explore the world of what happened And when everyone was turned to stone for an unknown amount of time and then unstoned Through the eyes of that character great concept definitely unique.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the art looks like interesting at least Some kind.
Speaker 0: Yeah, this reminds me There's that old sci-fi movie where the comet goes over and anyone who looked at the comic is permanently or comet is permanently blinded the Next day and then just like the world disintegrates.
Speaker 0: Mmm This is definitely worth a one episode watch.
Speaker 1: Yeah, this is one of those Concept ones but the concept is I think way more unique and way better than a lot of the other concept ones.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like we just talked about Bocorano, which is great because this is like a no concept is a lot less Unique and interesting than this one.
Speaker 0: Yeah, this one.
Speaker 0: I definitely want to watch.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah Dungeon, I'm getting a.
Speaker 1: my guess is that it will be pretty close to like the abyss show.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, which I really liked.
Speaker 0: Dungeon knee day.
Speaker 0: I will mote a metal.
Speaker 1: No, that's all you're gonna pronounce all these now.
Speaker 1: Yeah, don't you know day?
Speaker 0: I will mote a metal.
Speaker 0: No, wah matcha got a root out.
Speaker 1: Okay - Okay - sequel to another dungeon.
Speaker 0: second season of a show We didn't watch that has vague fantasy like Goku do kind of not Goku more like Sarah more serious than Goku?
Speaker 0: No, maybe it just looks like serious people.
Speaker 1: No one listening to this knows what Goku do is.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I said I feel like people listening to this are the only people who know what Goku do is.
Speaker 0: Okay Uh, I see a girl with fox ears.
Speaker 0: I see generic the most generic possible characters This shows.
Speaker 0: This show is probably as Generic and fantasy and self-insert as Utawarerumono.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: Remember that show?
Speaker 1: just know the English translation is Something I have heard of which is is it wrong to try to pick up girls in a dungeon?
Speaker 1: Oh, that's what.
Speaker 1: that's what it is.
Speaker 0: It's probably genero comedy.
Speaker 1: You've never heard of it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I heard of that.
Speaker 1: I've heard of it.
Speaker 1: It's uh, yeah No one the reason.
Speaker 1: I've heard of it and then have not bothered to investigate any further beyond the title.
Speaker 0: No one talked much about season one in our circle.
Speaker 0: So I assume season two.
Speaker 1: I think it was a long at first, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't know.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: Oh shit ain't in no show.
Speaker 0: bow tie firefighters.
Speaker 1: This looks like firemen.
Speaker 1: They're not actually so.
Speaker 0: if you read that the text in year 198 of the solar era in Tokyo special fire great brigades are fighting spontaneous human cabal I'm less interested in this now.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they look like firefighters, but actually they're just doing some you know action Kind of stuff.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: It's a shonen anime about fire firefighters who fight spontaneous human combustion caused by I guess demons Mm-hmm Faction of people creating infernals.
Speaker 0: Yeah, this is a proper noun.
Speaker 1: It's just a dark shown an action show, but they happen to use the aesthetic of firefighting Right dark Gir than black firefighters.
Speaker 0: There's a lot of proper nouns Special fire force company aid the infernals.
Speaker 0: There's a lot of capitalized words here.
Speaker 0: The show's gonna be dumb.
Speaker 1: Vinland saga Fantasy anime.
Speaker 1: I've heard the name of me everyone who talks about it.
Speaker 1: I don't know anything about it other than that.
Speaker 1: It's a Known fantasy thing.
Speaker 0: This looks great.
Speaker 0: It looks like historical drama set in like Viking times.
Speaker 0: Uh-huh Thor Finn is son of one of the Vikings greatest warriors But when his father is killed in battle by a mercenary leader, he swears to have his revenge.
Speaker 0: He joins a band.
Speaker 0: This is just Viking shit the show.
Speaker 1: I mean, I've heard of it and I know it's like a fantasy anime.
Speaker 1: That's all I know.
Speaker 0: I will say this the people I know who have talked about it and liked it are people who know and like the prince of nothing okay, that that's a. That could be a warning sign to certain people, but I feel like this is gonna be good.
Speaker 0: Sure I feel like this is worth a couple episodes to see if it's good.
Speaker 0: I think it's gonna be serious drama.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm, you know that's.
Speaker 0: you don't think that I don't see any indication.
Speaker 0: That's not.
Speaker 0: maybe berserk adjacent Could be berserk adjacent but historical like fictionalized Viking drama.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't know how much historic this is gonna be.
Speaker 0: It's all I did based on this.
Speaker 0: This is not like fantasy.
Speaker 0: It just looks Vikings.
Speaker 0: There's even a little YouTube trailer.
Speaker 0: This just looks like Viking stuff.
Speaker 1: I Will see about that.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: Let's keep going.
Speaker 0: Ah What the fuck is this generic girl anime among the class?
Speaker 0: It was transported to another world.
Speaker 0: an ordinary male student who doesn't have ambition.
Speaker 0: This is gonna be a self-insert garbage anime.
Speaker 0: Proper nouns re food at - Shoku go - I Become heroes in another world.
Speaker 0: The main character is an ordinary male who has doesn't have ambition or aspiration is called incompetent by his classmates.
Speaker 0: This is self-insert bullshit.
Speaker 1: Yeah, this is one of those.
Speaker 1: I mean, this is our main character.
Speaker 0: the girl sidekick to this guy looks way too young.
Speaker 0: I'm calling this bad.
Speaker 1: There's a lot of these where you know, the whole class is like has to as to you know, like it is like a unit.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right.
Speaker 1: There's like assassination.
Speaker 1: classroom and battle royale are two that come to mind immediately.
Speaker 1: But in this one You know that addition of main character being weakest boy in the class situation is what you know.
Speaker 0: It makes it like no it even talks about stats.
Speaker 0: Like this is one of those.
Speaker 0: This is garbage.
Speaker 0: This is utter genre garbage Dumbbell non kilo motor.
Speaker 1: Ooh, is it a Sport show?
Speaker 1: two girls weightlifting Girl.
Speaker 1: how porn is it though?
Speaker 1: The Translation is how heavy are the dumbbells you lift?
Speaker 1: It seems like every character is a girl except for one.
Speaker 0: It could be a harem one girls getting a little chubby and she decides to join a gym tries to find a casual gym meet someone else who is a weightlifter and It's like a romantic seems like an excuse to draw lots of athletic girls with boobs.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and then have people look at that.
Speaker 1: It even says comedy ecchi.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: So there you go See lots of scenes of like someone bending over to lift some weights and you look down their shirt.
Speaker 1: That's what you're in for.
Speaker 0: What is going on here Lord El Maloy?
Speaker 0: It'll say no chicken bow rail zeppelin grace notes.
Speaker 1: It's like a steampunk.
Speaker 0: I think so.
Speaker 0: when Lord El Melio the second the later waiver valve is a lot of Capitalized words here gets asked to claim his inheritance over Adara castle Assembled contestants in something they all have ridiculous Gundam names Luvia Galita and felt must compete in a game of wits to win a castle.
Speaker 1: It's another one of those, you know typical right scenario type shows.
Speaker 1: It just has this sort of dark steampunk Victorian ish aesthetic going on.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I feel like this show is gonna have the thing where aesthetically it looks a little bit like La.
Speaker 0: I don't like Dura Dura kind of characters, but I feel like it's gonna be super generic and Feel like it's going somewhere and feel like it's the second time rem said generic.
Speaker 0: I feel like it's not gonna go anywhere though.
Speaker 1: put a counter on this on the non screen.
Speaker 0: This is the generic.
Speaker 1: every time rim says generic ding.
Speaker 0: This show is going nowhere.
Speaker 0: There's gonna be no interesting mystery.
Speaker 0: All right I Karakai juzu no taka guys on to Takagi-san to the second season of tatagi-san.
Speaker 1: I didn't see the first season.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and do we?
Speaker 1: I don't.
Speaker 1: it's so weird.
Speaker 1: We're seeing these second seasons of things.
Speaker 1: even though we've been judging anime for like over a year now I don't remember ever judging the first season of this.
Speaker 0: Maybe we have and I just forgot maybe they were so generic No one talked about them.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't know but it had.
Speaker 1: it would have been on the any chart if they were just airing right.
Speaker 1: so that first season Was either so long ago or so mad that we just brought breezed over it without even thinking about it.
Speaker 0: Yep I feel like that happens a lot.
Speaker 1: Anyway, it's this comedy slice-of-life romance.
Speaker 1: It's just like a cute little show with you know, kids middle school ish romance.
Speaker 1: Maybe I don't know.
Speaker 0: All right, here we go kind of town.
Speaker 0: Oh, astra Space travel.
Speaker 1: I think it's Astra cuz.
Speaker 1: it's like space.
Speaker 0: Yeah Commercially viable high school students embark to planet camp.
Speaker 0: an unforeseen sentient light sphere warps them to outer space Stranding them.
Speaker 1: This is the second show where a whole class of kids has been warped to another place.
Speaker 0: Is that is that the theme for this summer?
Speaker 1: have to work together?
Speaker 0: This does not look like.
Speaker 0: however Here's the big difference in space.
Speaker 0: This one does not appear to have the generic shitty self-insert character from a light novel.
Speaker 1: not in the description.
Speaker 0: This looks like it has the ensemble cast of co-equal main characters.
Speaker 1: One person with the spiky hairdo does drawn much larger than the other characters Yeah, but I feel like he will be a character as opposed to a self-insert.
Speaker 1: Yeah Yeah, I think this show could be good.
Speaker 1: if the mystery of how they were Teleported is like a good terrible secret of literally space.
Speaker 0: There's a it edges into.
Speaker 0: they were 11 territory.
Speaker 0: They find an old.
Speaker 1: It's a group of kids in space.
Speaker 0: Yes They they find an old unmanned spaceship and they must stay strong and manage their limited resources and remain united in the darkness of space.
Speaker 1: Maybe it is.
Speaker 1: they were 11.
Speaker 0: I feel like this could be like only as they were nine.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I Am much more interested in watching this than the other show.
Speaker 0: That is a class of people sent somewhere.
Speaker 1: I mean, I think they just because Because it doesn't have the self-insert light novel You don't know it just not in the description but the just the space theme.
Speaker 1: I think it gives it that extra boost Yeah, versus the teleported to another fantasy world where there are stats on the people Speaking of stats.
Speaker 0: isekai cheat magician.
Speaker 0: It's even in the title centers around a guy and a girl like a transported to a fantasy world in that the guy is a normal person who has higher than Average reflect.
Speaker 0: Yeah, not even to talk about this.
Speaker 1: Oh, so you get transferred to a fantasy world where you're a badass, which is basically what Superman is.
Speaker 1: It's like I'm creeped on.
Speaker 1: he's a normal bro, but he comes to earth and he's a bad In the title, there's no way this is good.
Speaker 0: It's got.
Speaker 0: yeah, it's not even gonna talk about it.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm Toharu kagaku no accelerator The espers, okay.
Speaker 0: No, this is bad too.
Speaker 0: the espers of Academy City are classified into six levels where level zero lacks power.
Speaker 0: Well level five possesses an overwhelming amount of isekai crap.
Speaker 1: It's so weird how like these RPG elements started out as stats on like a war game D&D character sheet.
Speaker 1: Then they edge their way into video games which lacked all the agency of the player in storytelling But still had the combat of sort of.
Speaker 0: but no the nerd actually.
Speaker 1: But now they've even taken that away and they're bringing the RPGs with stats, right?
Speaker 1: I mean, they've been in anime for a while now, but it's like it feels like it's getting even worse.
Speaker 0: Imagine imagine an anime based on Final Fantasy.
Speaker 1: It's like you're a Final Fantasy character.
Speaker 1: You don't know that your strength is 47, right?
Speaker 0: But here Dragon Ball Z it was a joke right in Dragon Ball Z.
Speaker 1: They joked like oh your power levels are 9,000. but here it's like nope, literally not a joke.
Speaker 1: Your power level is 9,000.
Speaker 0: You know what this is?
Speaker 0: It's a Final Fantasy.
Speaker 0: 6 was turned into an anime and the anime was literally just every fucking fight.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's it Yeah, and then like looking at the character screens and like oh my his strength is too higher.
Speaker 0: now We can cast white and it'll do a little more damage.
Speaker 1: Whoo, at least anime like get baggers with abstracted away and like oh we're going we've made it to the next level of the spooky Tower As opposed to like literal god damn it Astro boy.
Speaker 1: He leveled up mid, you know, now he has X thousand horsepower, but it wasn't like, you know That was.
Speaker 1: that's the thing that makes sense here.
Speaker 1: It's literally like aha.
Speaker 1: Your stats are up.
Speaker 0: All right, that's a really long title.
Speaker 0: Uchi no kono.
Speaker 0: Tame nara.
Speaker 0: They are a wah moshikashi Tara.
Speaker 1: Wow, no Tausaru Kamo shit and I in English it translates to if it's for my daughter I'd even defeat a demon lord.
Speaker 0: I'm already not Super into this because I see a lot of really young girl characters.
Speaker 1: So a dude goes into the forest.
Speaker 1: He comes across a devil girl who's not doing too Well, he's gonna leave her there to die, but nope takes her home become her adopted father.
Speaker 1: She's really cute.
Speaker 1: It seems kind of like a moe situation.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I worry this is gonna be scary moe and I worry that if it's based on a manga It's okay.
Speaker 1: I brought a demon girl home.
Speaker 1: I didn't bring an actual little human girl.
Speaker 1: Huh?
Speaker 0: My worry Thousand years old.
Speaker 0: I guess my worry is that this might be a bunny drop situation.
Speaker 1: It's bunny needs demon drop.
Speaker 1: even drop demon drop.
Speaker 0: Alright, oh, I'm just gonna read the English names of these.
Speaker 0: from now on No maidens in your savage season.
Speaker 1: I think that one.
Speaker 1: you should read the Japanese name Arabaru he said soon.
Speaker 0: Oh, oh tomorrow.
Speaker 0: Oh, oh tell me Domino.
Speaker 0: Okay, the girls in a high school literature club Do an icebreaker?
Speaker 0: One thing you want to do before you die.
Speaker 0: one of them says sex.
Speaker 0: I think it's just a Slice-of-life funny like it's just a story about girls and sex.
Speaker 1: Oh, is this like it depends?
Speaker 1: isn't no automata show.
Speaker 1: Maybe it seems like it might be romance slice-of-life drama.
Speaker 0: I think it's a serious.
Speaker 1: These are girls Based on a manga.
Speaker 0: Yeah, this could possibly be good.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it seems like this is not, you know a perverted situation.
Speaker 1: This is like an honest, you know legit, you know Situation.
Speaker 0: Yeah, this could be an earnest show about sexuality and growing up.
Speaker 1: Mmm.
Speaker 0: I don't see a lot of warning signs.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's a good deal.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: No one's drawn in a perverted way or is highly exposed.
Speaker 1: I don't even see a male character here.
Speaker 1: I see ladies It doesn't say the word Yuri on it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, not that that would be bad But you know the genre stuff people saying it's a coming-of-age female protagonist school club like.
Speaker 1: yeah.
Speaker 1: Mmm.
Speaker 0: Wow I'm a good job anime.
Speaker 1: Hey, good job Japan.
Speaker 1: You're getting there.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: What is this one?
Speaker 0: - do you love your mom and her?
Speaker 0: to it multi-target attacks?
Speaker 1: What the what would you do if you got transported into a video game?
Speaker 0: We know in one hand every video game I play the mom that that is a fantasy world.
Speaker 0: The moms are the only good characters and you can't date them or really interact with that, right?
Speaker 1: So this does have the leg up and that the mom is gonna be there like all the time because that's the point of the Yet another RPG stat show yet another.
Speaker 1: well, my life is actually literally a video game now.
Speaker 0: But is this is this milfs?
Speaker 0: Is this where this is going?
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm hard you and your mom is a new sailing overpowered dual wielding multi-target specialist.
Speaker 0: So on one hand an Anime in a fantasy world where like you're trying to be an adventurer But your mom is way stronger than you and follows.
Speaker 0: you could be great But I don't think this is gonna be that.
Speaker 0: I think this is gonna be another stat based garbage.
Speaker 1: It's mostly just gonna be like silly and try, you know pandery and that sort of thing.
Speaker 0: Yep All right, the hentai something already not interested in this.
Speaker 1: Oh, they're in the clerical free club, but they found a love Someone's desk.
Speaker 0: Are you willing to fall in love with a pervert as long as she's cute?
Speaker 0: She found a love letter.
Speaker 1: Yeah, no pain makes a girl the pervert.
Speaker 1: that way You don't feel like you're a pervert dude watching it.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: Nope.
Speaker 0: The show is male gaze.
Speaker 0: I'm just gonna ignore it.
Speaker 0: Yep, Mausama retry the story centers on a girl.
Speaker 0: Nope, I'm already worried.
Speaker 0: a regular guy who works at a company that manages an online game.
Speaker 1: Is this like in the summer?
Speaker 1: every anime is about games and evil beam being in game world.
Speaker 0: He often plays in the game as a character who is a dark lord But one day when he logs on he's whisked into the game's world as his character and he meets a one-legged girl.
Speaker 0: Yeah, fuck the show.
Speaker 1: Can we ban all anime where people go to video game worlds?
Speaker 0: Yeah, fuck that done Alright katsu take a katsu.
Speaker 0: take kamidata kimono tai chi day.
Speaker 0: Serious looking shonen show I guess war werewolf guns dragons.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it looks like a you know a shonen action show.
Speaker 1: or there's like a you know people fighting and stuff, right?
Speaker 0: It's about the Civil War the north against the south.
Speaker 0: the outnumbered northerners use dark magic to create a monstrous super soldier called.
Speaker 0: There's a lot of proper nouns now and it's incarnates sacred beasts all uppercase.
Speaker 0: The show is gonna be proper noun II and super serious.
Speaker 0: Probably not that good.
Speaker 1: Well as a show that takes itself seriously Yeah isn't?
Speaker 0: actually that series shows gonna act like it's serious and it's going to substitute good plot and character development for upper like proper noun names of things Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: So this one looks interesting but also not right.
Speaker 1: so you have it says cop craft.
Speaker 0: that art looks Different.
Speaker 1: so what I'm getting the vibe here a buddy police action series follows a detective and The alternate world night, right?
Speaker 1: So there's like a Girl wearing it, you know, not not the most boob armor I've seen but still not very protective armor.
Speaker 0: It's panty boob armor, but it's like Naga from slayers level as opposed to like really perverted.
Speaker 1: It's not an armored bikini It's armored one-piece bathing suit.
Speaker 1: But anyway, so you have a serious detective like imagine like guy and it's like guy.
Speaker 1: Who's the guy the human and goes in the shell?
Speaker 0: Oh God, why do I forget his name?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I forgot his name right now.
Speaker 0: Yeah Why did I forget his name?
Speaker 1: I forgot right but like imagine a Serious detective who's you know, but the the buddy partner Togusa Togusa, right?
Speaker 1: I actually was thinking that but I'm like, no, that's not right.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I was same thing.
Speaker 1: I was like Togusa but his buddy cop isn't also the serious major It's a magic girl from a buddy cop is a magical girl wearing, you know Slightly not great armor where the sword.
Speaker 1: so it's like crossing the two genres in a way But seems like she's also serious.
Speaker 1: Like she's actually trying to solve whatever demon problem.
Speaker 0: Couple buddy cop except it's a fancy girl and a normal guy with a gun.
Speaker 1: You know what?
Speaker 1: And this is a unique idea.
Speaker 0: It's not set in an RPG.
Speaker 0: I will give this one episode.
Speaker 0: Yeah, two worlds.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we still didn't watch a single episode from last season.
Speaker 0: I know cuz I've been.
Speaker 0: I've been watching other stuff.
Speaker 0: Yeah busy not gonna hito genome All right.
Speaker 0: Popular game footage uploader.
Speaker 1: one day he wakes up and so he's not a streamer He's someone who just uploads stuff to YouTube.
Speaker 0: Wait, wait.
Speaker 0: what?
Speaker 0: taken to a strange place along with other youtubers Okay, who are specialized in different genres of games a mysterious alpaca alpaca headed host gathers them.
Speaker 0: This is a nine doors nine dollars nine dreams scenario.
Speaker 0: Yeah, nine something's.
Speaker 0: they're all in a Situation like assassination classroom of the East.
Speaker 1: you got a million bajillion dollars on your phone, but they're all YouTube streamers.
Speaker 0: No, no, they're not YouTube streamers.
Speaker 0: They're YouTube Uploaders, which is a thing in Japan.
Speaker 0: It's not as much of a thing here.
Speaker 1: I mean this.
Speaker 1: people upload video game stuff to you.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but it's every twitch streamer uploads like the best of us to you.
Speaker 0: Oh, no, but these?
Speaker 0: I've seen some of these channels.
Speaker 0: They're more like they just upload footage from the games without like commentary.
Speaker 1: Okay?
Speaker 0: It's like.
Speaker 0: oh I uploaded footage from the game so you can see it.
Speaker 1: Anyway, all right I assume looks like it's got some school action.
Speaker 0: Lot of the llama headed guy.
Speaker 0: Yeah, this is this is a Type stuff.
Speaker 1: the next one has the school action.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Oh one dad Joshiko say no mood does it guy?
Speaker 1: Ridiculous days of three high school friends at the height of their youth.
Speaker 1: It's just a high school comedy show.
Speaker 0: We you know, one of my favorite anime ever is just a high school comedy show.
Speaker 0: Basically.
Speaker 0: Here's Greenwood.
Speaker 1: I Don't think this is here is Greenwood.
Speaker 0: No But it could it's.
Speaker 0: but I like shows like that.
Speaker 0: this could be good.
Speaker 0: it looks like it's based on a manga Mmm, the manga like the art of the manga looks pretty good.
Speaker 0: Actually, I don't know if anyone says this is good.
Speaker 0: I'll watch it Mmm.
Speaker 0: All right, we've been going on for a while and I'm hungry.
Speaker 0: I'm running out of steam.
Speaker 0: So let's move quicker.
Speaker 0: grandbelm Magic disappeared from the world.
Speaker 0: in the present day a normal high school student who moved back to Japan from Germany Meet on a. there said there's some two characters meet on a full moon.
Speaker 0: They learn about magic and giant magic combat dolls with proper.
Speaker 0: It's all proper nouns.
Speaker 1: That's magic plus Mecca.
Speaker 0: Yeah magic plus Mecca and a lot of proper.
Speaker 1: now Mecca has been gone from the world But then this girl moves back to Japan from Germany and rediscovers magic and brings Mecca back to the world.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah All right, BEM The port town Liberty or all?
Speaker 0: this is the.
Speaker 0: this one's the one with this.
Speaker 0: this has a terrible secret of space.
Speaker 0: The whole anime is gonna be around the mystery of someplace.
Speaker 1: It says a supernatural horror show.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it has of canal that separates the city Spanned by a single bridge.
Speaker 1: people have to fight sort of dark spooky monsters or the.
Speaker 1: it seems like some of the characters have Monstrous forms.
Speaker 1: right if you look at like the poster there, right?
Speaker 1: There's like four characters at the bottom.
Speaker 0: Art actually looks pretty good.
Speaker 0: Maybe it'll be more like boogie pop fans.
Speaker 1: It's three characters above them.
Speaker 1: all have like, you know monsters behind them indicating that they're actually monsters in human form or something like that.
Speaker 0: They fight for the sake of humanity, but due to their horrible form will humans accept them?
Speaker 0: It looks pretty stylish, I guess this is another one where if anyone else tells me it's good I'll give it a watch.
Speaker 0: I'll watch one episode.
Speaker 0: All right, give in.
Speaker 0: Ah It's stuck deep inside me and I can't get it out of my head.
Speaker 0: Mafu's voice is an insane and dangerous weapon.
Speaker 0: that day I started to feel that playing the guitar and playing basketball Both of which I didn't like like both of which I liked very much previously.
Speaker 0: We're becoming boring.
Speaker 0: The hell is this show about.
Speaker 1: it's one of those music shows.
Speaker 1: There's been a lot of these ladies.
Speaker 1: It was like the jazz one.
Speaker 1: What was that called?
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah something on the hill.
Speaker 0: I forget Yeah, which was forget there's kids on the slope, but that's the one Really wanted to like it, but it was so boring.
Speaker 1: I think this is one of those.
Speaker 1: There's been a quite a few of these lately about like one every few seasons where it's like.
Speaker 0: it's not the bones on either.
Speaker 0: The bones one look good.
Speaker 0: This one doesn't look good.
Speaker 1: It's like a somewhat serious is show about.
Speaker 1: that's about You know a band or kids in a band or playing music or something like that band.
Speaker 0: boys love music slice of life.
Speaker 0: I think this is gonna be boring.
Speaker 0: Yeah, probably All right, some simple gear, you know, if you're on the symphogear train, you're on the symphogear train.
Speaker 0: I am NOT on the symphogear train.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I just know the symphogear is the thing.
Speaker 1: I don't anything about it.
Speaker 1: This is no I just know I don't need to watch it.
Speaker 0: This is called symphogear 15. it is the fifth season of symphogear.
Speaker 1: What happened to the other 10 symphogears?
Speaker 0: Fuck if I care Ensemble stars has way too many characters and it's an idol thing.
Speaker 1: Oh, it's an idol show.
Speaker 0: Okay, uh Machikado mazuko 15 year old girl awakens with demonic power.
Speaker 0: Is it a magical?
Speaker 0: It's a magical girl show.
Speaker 1: It says comedy fantasy.
Speaker 1: So it's like.
Speaker 1: I guess, you know, maybe it has the kind of feel of Risky safety.
Speaker 0: Well, I could see that but it looks more like straight magical girl.
Speaker 1: Hmm So she has a curse.
Speaker 1: the curse is you have to live on 40,000 yen a month 365 US dollars a month.
Speaker 1: You gotta live poor.
Speaker 1: you got you can live but you live somewhere cheap.
Speaker 0: move upstate and away from the throughway.
Speaker 0: You could live pretty well on 365 dollars a month.
Speaker 1: All right, the next one.
Speaker 1: actually that looks like it has something going on.
Speaker 1: The anime will have its no bunga.
Speaker 1: No, no, no, but no banaga.
Speaker 1: So basically it's a dramatic sort of crazy interpretation of the story of Oda Nobunaga and his life as an early teen.
Speaker 1: So basically taking history and then making it really sort of outrageous and anime Turning him into a moe girl or anything.
Speaker 0: No, nothing like that, you know, I Don't feel like I need to give this a try because if I'm gonna give a show like that a try I'm gonna watch Vinland saga first.
Speaker 1: Try nights, it looks like a sports show about a high school rugby team.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it probably takes itself seriously.
Speaker 0: It's probably really hyper accurate to the rules of rugby.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm feel like it's me about the rugby, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah is a cute Super young idol.
Speaker 1: girl show like elementary school level idols Re-stage dream days Pony Canyon.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's not gonna be for it It's just.
Speaker 0: it's for kids.
Speaker 1: and this star move 3 which looks like boys idols again third season of that.
Speaker 1: and then there's Wari show our Shota Butsu.
Speaker 1: I go link I which translates to looks like a funny weird short anime.
Speaker 0: Yeah Girls come from another planet to save mistreated animals on earth.
Speaker 0: Black cat squirrel and rabbit all make their way to earth.
Speaker 1: It looks just like a little cutie kids show like yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think this is in the genre of yay Notably this season there were no card games.
Speaker 1: There were no beyblades cuz it's all.
Speaker 0: It's all generic dudes with no lives getting transported into RPG worlds.
Speaker 0: pretty much Don't watch shows that are generic dudes getting transported in RPG worlds.
Speaker 1: No Do not.
Speaker 0: if you really feel like you should go watch One episode of hack sign and pretend that's the entire show and it was just a movie, right?
Speaker 1: So, yeah that we have now judged all the TV anime from the summer season of 2019 according to the amazing website Annie chart net a n ich a RT net.
Speaker 1: that's where we figure out what animes are coming out.
Speaker 1: We look at the Scant information on that site.
Speaker 1: we judge the anime based on what that site says and no other information because we don't know anything else because we're dumb dumbs and We didn't bother research.
Speaker 0: We tell us if we're right.
Speaker 0: tell us if we're wrong.
Speaker 0: I will link to Scott's YouTube channel.
Speaker 0: you subs if you're subscribed to the geek star channel Also subscribe to Scott's channel starting in the fall season.
Speaker 1: So probably shortly after packs Labor Day We will go back to judging in video form and not do this as a podcast anymore Except maybe next summer.
Speaker 1: Who knows?
Speaker 1: Yeah We'll see if we made how lazy we are.
Speaker 1: We've actually been doing this for like a surprising amount of time now, even though we're frequently a few weeks late We do manage to somehow never not do it.
Speaker 1: We've been doing it for like over a years and I guess it'll continue even no matter how people care or not.
Speaker 0: Whatever, you know if only anime and my NYC were earlier or later We could start going there and doing it as a like an event at a kind of anime NYC like mid-november Exactly when like November 15th through 17th.
Speaker 1: We don't have anything that weekend.
Speaker 1: Yeah could finally go to it.
Speaker 1: It's like its third year already, right?
Speaker 0: I did fairly.
Speaker 0: it's great.
Speaker 1: Like I always want to go I just I'm always a little bit of stuff like VIP tickets I'm not a fan of but it does seem to be a high-quality Anime con.
Speaker 1: the true successor to New York Festival is the packs of anime cons.
Speaker 1: Yeah You know, it may it might be worth my time, especially since it's right there.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I can take.
Speaker 0: I could take the subway to it's right.
Speaker 1: exactly that makes it sort of me.
Speaker 1: You know something I would go to I cannot stress just conflicted with so many other things in the past years.
Speaker 1: But yeah, I'd be willing to go to it.
Speaker 0: I can get free badges to New York comic-con and I can take the subway to it without even Transferring like from my apartment across the street to done at New York comic-con.
Speaker 0: and I still refuse to go.
Speaker 0: All right, we're done.
Speaker 0: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Speaker 1: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 0: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 1: But unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 0: It's actually recorded at night And the patreon patrons for this episode of geek nights are Craig Oliver Allen George Heidi McNichol.
Speaker 0: Just like a dude guys are tops and linkage.
Speaker 0: you Jennifer Hitchcock Charisma'd give myastati.com J band scoot alone Lee Shawn Yeager Nicholas brand on mr Strong stretch and four to one creations.
Speaker 0: and there may be other secret names You do not even know Shervin von Hororish Superboy Clinton Walton render, New Zealand Ryan Perrin drove and lander Finn dread Lily Tenebrae Sean Klein Chris Reimer and Thomas on.
Speaker 0: don't forget that Emily and I have launched a separate sideshow on The geek nights.
Speaker 0: patreon patrons will get exclusive access early access But in time the shows will be public.
Speaker 0: on the patreon subscribe to the page around you'll see those episodes.
Speaker 0: We are talking about every Disney theatrical animated release ever in chronological order.
Speaker 0: It's gonna be a fun time.
Speaker 0: and now I leave you with Chocolate rain.
Speaker 2: Some stay dry and others feel the pain.
Speaker 2: chocolate rain.
Speaker 2: Our baby porn will die before this.
Speaker 2: in chocolate rain The schoolbooks say it can't be here again.
Speaker 2: chocolate rain.
Speaker 2: The prisons make you wonder where it when.
Speaker 2: Bill a tent and say the world is dry.
Speaker 2: chocolate rain.
Speaker 2: The zoom the camera out and see the light.
Speaker 2: chocolate rain Forecast to be falling yesterday.
Speaker 2: chocolate rain Only in the past is what they say.
Speaker 2: chocolate rain With your neighborhood insurance rates.
Speaker 2: chocolate rain Makes us happy live and and again.
Speaker 2: chocolate rain Made me cross the street the other day.
Speaker 2: chocolate rain Made you turn your head the other way.
Speaker 2: chocolate rain Is straight quickly crashing through your veins.
Speaker 2: chocolate rain Using you to fall back down again.
Speaker 2: chocolate rain Tell them mentioned on the radio.