Speaker 0: It's Tuesday, July 16th, 2019.
Speaker 0: I'm rim.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott and this is geek nights tonight.
Speaker 0: bloodstained ritual of the night.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: So this weekend was basically perfect weather Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: We saw I spent the whole week by I spent Sunday at the beach did something We've never done before.
Speaker 0: we're at Sandy Hook and instead of eating the food drug food We just got on our bikes and we just biked over to Highland and ate at a real restaurant.
Speaker 0: It was great didn't even take that long.
Speaker 1: some New Jersey food.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there's a bunch of seafood places like right there.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm Yeah, I mean I would have gone to beach but I was dragged upstate.
Speaker 1: Oh Since I was dragged upstate I made the most of being dragged upstate.
Speaker 0: gotta hit the de Bellas en route got to stop at the cafe Maya.
Speaker 0: I gotta stop at his two letters.
Speaker 1: visited visited some nerds played some games You know ate some cake.
Speaker 1: Went to cafe Maya to Sue Leonard.
Speaker 1: You know, it's pretty much everything possible that I could do on a trip upstate to make it Almost as good as going to be.
Speaker 0: like when we went to Rochester and we all went to the Wegmans That was that was like going to an amusement park.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, pretty much.
Speaker 0: It was a good time.
Speaker 1: I wish I had a Wegmans.
Speaker 1: right now I'm trying to find some ingredients and I cannot find them at the store and I can't go to Whole Foods because until tomorrow.
Speaker 0: yeah, so you brought up the topic of Speed cloth.
Speaker 1: You're the one who brought.
Speaker 0: You asked me rim.
Speaker 0: Do you know about?
Speaker 0: Speed?
Speaker 1: well for a while I've been Researching right because you go to gaming cons and some gaming cons are ultra fancy and they put tablecloths in the tables But most of them do not.
Speaker 1: you got a plastic table, right?
Speaker 1: So it's like hey, you know, you're playing a board game with cardboard chips.
Speaker 1: You're playing card games You're playing something and you want to put down a cloth.
Speaker 1: you could you know CCG players.
Speaker 1: They just have the personal CCG mat, which is fine If everyone has one.
Speaker 1: you're playing CCGs, but you're playing a big old board game.
Speaker 1: You need a tablecloth to cover the whole table.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I feel like I should start bringing a play mat just to put it in front of myself.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but it doesn't cover like that center board area and sometimes it's too big for the game.
Speaker 0: Well, I gotta I gotta get one that's like small.
Speaker 0: I can eat a weird shape one That's only like I don't know seven like four to five inches.
Speaker 0: What tall?
Speaker 1: Is why mouse pad anyway weird mouse?
Speaker 1: I've been researching for a while.
Speaker 1: Okay, what's a good cloth to get to use as a tablecloth and just you know, fold it up put it in my luggage You know, it should fold up pretty tight, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah and bring it to cons.
Speaker 1: It would take up as much room.
Speaker 1: My luggage is like a towel.
Speaker 0: What's funny is I have that goldenrod tablecloth I bought along with those two butt pads to bring to conventions to deal with crappy chairs and crappy tables And I've never actually brought them to any convention.
Speaker 1: So I was researching, you know, what material to use.
Speaker 1: someone once told me there was some kind of like like brush something brush Something something like that or something like that.
Speaker 0: What do you want a velour tablecloth?
Speaker 1: I don't know, but I found out more recently that there's a thing called speed cloth and like now this already reeks of gamer Goo to me.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, it reeks big-time.
Speaker 1: And I researched and I found out that basically people who make poker tables Which I guess people who are really into poker they get way into the materials The exact right cards the exact right chips the exact right table the exact right everything.
Speaker 0: I mean look at the nerds buying the wormwood like special wooden dice thing.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you think that right?
Speaker 1: It's like a man, you know, it's like all nerds are the same and those nerds are using that dice tower for a variety of Games, this is someone who plays one game.
Speaker 0: I mean, I was thinking about making custom pieces just for myself when I play Tigris and Euphrates.
Speaker 1: But anyway Apparently poker people are fans of this material called speed.
Speaker 1: cloth is better than felt.
Speaker 1: I also saw some people may be using it for pool tables possibly which seemed weird cuz I think that sounds like What sounds like any pool tables are made out?
Speaker 1: Yeah, it sounds like you need a regulated felt surface for a pool table.
Speaker 1: You can't be using.
Speaker 1: I mean, I'm seeing alternative cloth.
Speaker 0: I have seen all their coverings for pool tables usually because those are not even slate pool tables.
Speaker 0: but there are honeycomb pool tables also known as So garbage.
Speaker 1: that's like getting a non-photon air hockey.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you can't play on that.
Speaker 1: I don't even play pool and I know that much.
Speaker 0: when we were kids Well, I was wanted a pool table because like the whole family played pool and weird like one day We finally got one cuz.
Speaker 0: my parents saved up to make sure we got a single piece slate pool table.
Speaker 1: That's fucking right.
Speaker 0: I don't even I can't even barely hit the ball and I know that my dad spent like an entire day Leveling it before we were allowed to touch it.
Speaker 1: good did it right?
Speaker 1: Yeah Point is this thing called speed cloth and it's a. it's a cloth poker people are a fan.
Speaker 0: Oh, it's just polyester as far as I can tell.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I want to see some in person and feel it up to know if it's actually any worth the damn.
Speaker 1: But it doesn't sound like it.
Speaker 1: but almost all the speed cloth I could find online is what's known as Suited speed cloth, which means it's not the smooth solid color it has basically the symbols of the four suits of cards spades clubs diamonds hearts and Sort of a grid and all of it in the whole world that I could find online as the exact same pattern on it.
Speaker 1: Only one place makes it.
Speaker 0: it's almost like if you were selling this stuff to nerds and you called it I don't know D&D because it has or like I don't know nerded cuz.
Speaker 0: it's got like the Dyson.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the only places I could pictures of dragons and elves I could only find a very few places to get unsuited speed cloth and it was like an auto upholstery place.
Speaker 1: So I'm gonna.
Speaker 1: I'll see if it's actually worth it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, my worry as I'm looking at the speed cloth more and more is that I don't think it would work Well for a gaming surface because if it's polyester the way I'm imagining then it requires Tension to be a nice man.
Speaker 1: It is I think it is meant to go up, you know onto a poker table where it's pulled tight.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so we'll see.
Speaker 0: yeah, I just I feel like we've thought about this a lot and a lot of nerds have because frankly most gaming cons like Actual spaces you have to play games Tend to kind of suck like PAX is a weird exception.
Speaker 0: and even then Yeah, but packs has all those side rooms while these packs West has all those side rooms.
Speaker 0: No, it's that are small and not that loud.
Speaker 0: No tablecloths.
Speaker 0: I feel like we need to put together our kit of the stuff we bring for the premium experience gaming at Nerd tabletop conventions.
Speaker 1: We'll go to fabric store in the city and feel up some cloth.
Speaker 0: I feel like we should feel them up.
Speaker 0: So there's a whole bunch of gaming news.
Speaker 0: We're just gonna touch on a little gaming episode in a while.
Speaker 0: I know which is usually the show that's easy to do.
Speaker 1: It's really hard to you know, you know Keep like several weeks of gaming news.
Speaker 1: We always end up doing the gaming news from like fucking today.
Speaker 0: Yep, so, uh one thing I saw this that I'm pretty excited about.
Speaker 0: this is posted actually yesterday at 7.
Speaker 0: So it's pretty new.
Speaker 0: but as you know overwatch Among other great like it has pretty good game design.
Speaker 0: There's a lot of things I like about.
Speaker 0: overwatch is one of my favorite games But one of the things that Kaplan the game the game equivalent of a showrunner the game director He has taken a very hard line on leavers on toxic people on cheaters Etc.
Speaker 0: because as far as I'm concerned zero tolerance zero forgiveness.
Speaker 0: No appeals.
Speaker 0: You're just done all these things.
Speaker 1: I agree.
Speaker 0: So They're implementing a much more comprehensive Cheating response System.
Speaker 0: Okay, and the way it'll work.
Speaker 0: Is that in any overwatch game?
Speaker 0: Even if it's competitive just like any game if the system detects that even one player is cheating in any way The game will instantly end Will not count at all and the cheater will be banned.
Speaker 1: What if it's a false positive?
Speaker 0: Uh Frankly, I'm willing to take that chance.
Speaker 1: What if it's you?
Speaker 0: I Doubt that will happen because I am upper silver.
Speaker 1: What if it happens?
Speaker 0: I doubt it.
Speaker 0: I mean if their algorithm is wrong, it'll destroy the game.
Speaker 0: That point out there thing is I'm pretty sure kind of like look with leavers and everything.
Speaker 0: They've been done pretty good at giving people like the right number of strikes before they're just done because you know You might be playing a competitive game and you leave because your house literally is on fire.
Speaker 0: So I feel like everybody gets one like sometimes your house burns down.
Speaker 1: I just feel like you know, that's a good thing because at least now there won't be any tainted games on record Right, which is good.
Speaker 1: But also it's sort of annoying to have your game just end.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I'd rather the game end than play at all with a cheater.
Speaker 1: Sure, but also I feel like if your cheats Even with just a system like say VAC which just bans you if you cheat and that's it, right?
Speaker 1: Presumably It's like.
Speaker 1: well if it detects you you're banned and you're not gonna get into too many games.
Speaker 1: and if it doesn't detect you Well, this system isn't gonna really help with that.
Speaker 1: You're still gonna.
Speaker 1: you're gonna play cheaty games with people of undetectable cheats.
Speaker 0: Yep I think this is mostly in response to.
Speaker 0: I think what's going on is they have a better way to detect cheaters that they're comfortable turning on mid game instead of like post game review follow-up bans.
Speaker 0: So, I mean the update was I think what they.
Speaker 1: you know, I think the biggest thing is simply just like let you know when you're a player Who's not a cheater, right?
Speaker 1: It's you know, you never know if someone was cheating or not, right?
Speaker 0: Well, yeah.
Speaker 0: and to that point 99% of the time when I'm in a game and someone says oh so-and-so is cheating No, so-and-so is just good and you're bad and you think that guy's cheating because he actually knows how to shoot exactly.
Speaker 1: So the point is it'd be really nice if you could just know for sure like aha that guy was cheating the whole time.
Speaker 1: And also if you see aha that guy was cheating the whole times like a game end and it call out a person and ban Them and you say aha then in that situation You just described where someone is just good and not cheating someone says so-and-so is cheating.
Speaker 1: Well, how come this game hasn't ended yet and they haven't been man yet.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I guess they're not cheating Are they?
Speaker 1: I was just in a game.
Speaker 1: I saw that the anti cheating thing clearly works.
Speaker 1: I've seen it happen.
Speaker 0: I was and it's not happening now.
Speaker 1: Therefore either this is undetectable cheats, which is or They're not cheating.
Speaker 0: where I was playing a game the other day where someone on the other team was getting salty and kept complaining that like our our Tracer was cheating like all that tracers will see me through walls and like freaking out like kill me all the time.
Speaker 0: So then I end of global chat.
Speaker 0: I was just like hey, I'm gonna start cheating too.
Speaker 0: And all I did was focus fire at that guy Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: I didn't do anything different.
Speaker 0: He was just really easy to kill cuz he was really bad.
Speaker 0: Yeah So there is actually some other overwatch news, I think is the biggest gaming news today here.
Speaker 0: because Right now eSports is still in this interesting sort of liminal period where it's big money and it's growing But it's also inheriting a lot of the problems of non eSports and it's a panel on this once and almost no one was there.
Speaker 1: Yep, and it's hard to tell I don't blame it was like Monday morning at PAX West.
Speaker 0: Yep But so tired, there's a whole big space going on there.
Speaker 0: But one of the biggest problems with eSports is that while there is a home team The home team in most eSports does not play in its home.
Speaker 1: I mean overwatch League is like one of the only sports like with you know teams going on.
Speaker 1: You know, even the other ones that have teams like MOBAs.
Speaker 1: It's like well they all get together and all play and all the all the whole.
Speaker 1: you know Dota International.
Speaker 0: everyone's there and it's easy for nerds to underestimate the power of that.
Speaker 0: cuz like.
Speaker 0: I don't like baseball I don't really care that much about baseball but because I live in Queens if the Mets win I feel a little good and I'm a little bit inclined attention.
Speaker 1: This is the thing that you know.
Speaker 1: nerds may not realize.
Speaker 1: they don't pay too much attention to real sports.
Speaker 1: Which you should is that you know a sport like football, you know, NFL football is a You know national sport, right?
Speaker 1: It doesn't matter where.
Speaker 1: if you are interested in football You can follow the whole football, right?
Speaker 1: You know every team what every team is doing, you know, a football game is like a nationally televised program, right?
Speaker 1: Soccer is like a world, you know, some of it at least is a world level sport like the Premier League.
Speaker 1: You know those teams have fans around the entire world.
Speaker 1: There are people in like, you know, all sorts of random countries is a Premier League game.
Speaker 1: That is a world broadcast event, right?
Speaker 1: Usually.
Speaker 1: but you know Major League Baseball in the United States is a Super local event, even if you follow it and are into it you are following most likely almost entirely your team in your area.
Speaker 1: There's a lot of content for a lot of people but in a small Geographical space, right and people who aren't in New York or for some reason a Mets fan who doesn't live in New York You're paying no attention to anything.
Speaker 1: The Mets are doing you can't name a player on their team, you know Right Mets games are broadcast in the New York area.
Speaker 1: You have to like do crazy shit to watch them outside the New York area, right.
Speaker 1: and baseball is a very local sport.
Speaker 1: so all eSports right since they're digital and broadcast to the whole world are sort of Global events to everyone who cares about them, right?
Speaker 1: It's the Dota International.
Speaker 1: It's like I. everyone who plays Dota is watching this doesn't matter where you are.
Speaker 1: All right, so trying to introduce Locality to eSports sort of is a mismatch but is sort of also desirable.
Speaker 0: Yep I think it's the right move commercially to help eSports grow and like really enter the mainstream in the long run.
Speaker 1: Right because when you have something an eSport like, you know a MOBA where especially the player count on teams is low, right?
Speaker 1: Then you and you bring the whole world together.
Speaker 1: There's a very small number of people who can make enough money on that, right?
Speaker 1: But if you can get people to care about, you know, the local eSports team Right, right.
Speaker 1: That's playing in regular stuff.
Speaker 1: that greatly Increases the audience and the revenues.
Speaker 1: so
Speaker 0: as much as I want to know
Speaker 1: And then also mostly the number of people who can make a living by being athletes But
Speaker 0: as much as I want to be a fan of the New York team versus other teams They all didn't know them played in New York.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the New York team does not play in New York.
Speaker 1: They visit New York a lot and they like do events here and stuff.
Speaker 1: I've never gone to one even though I thought about it, but like I wouldn't I wouldn't watch all their games.
Speaker 0: I would just decide randomly.
Speaker 0: Hey, I feel like watching overwatch.
Speaker 0: I was looking to see if a game was on and I would watch whatever game was on did not care who was playing.
Speaker 0: Nope So now the changes are.
Speaker 0: they're moving to a division based format, which is more like traditional sports and so there'll be four divisions and Every team is now required to host at minimum two and at maximum five local weekend events.
Speaker 0: The teams are responsible for selecting and operating their own venues and the league will be in charge of the broadcast.
Speaker 1: So if you're interested enough in the sport to attend it locally, right?
Speaker 1: You're suddenly going to care about that team because you're gonna see them every time you go to the local event, right?
Speaker 1: You're gonna see other teams mixed up, but you're always gonna see that same team when you go to the place near you Yep, whereas if you're only watching online you're seeing whoever's on at the time you happen to be on.
Speaker 0: I think this is big news because the experience of seeing a sport in person as to my knowledge No one has done this.
Speaker 0: Yeah with fans around you.
Speaker 0: It's a very different.
Speaker 0: I love hockey but hockey is just better if you're with a crowd of screaming idiots.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so I want to be in a crowd of screaming idiots watching overwatch Yep, so I will go to any games that are in New York if I'm able to.
Speaker 1: there have been games in New York.
Speaker 1: You didn't go.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well that cuz I didn't know about them till after because I didn't expect it I told you about them before.
Speaker 0: no, I don't think you did or you told me too late.
Speaker 1: They had a thing at Barclays didn't they?
Speaker 0: Well, yeah Barclays does not count.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 0: I'm not going Under no circumstances while I go to Barclays right where it's gonna be then.
Speaker 0: I'm not going.
Speaker 0: Barclays is a hole.
Speaker 1: It's super new that's all.
Speaker 0: yeah, it is a hole.
Speaker 0: So in some other sort of meta news as you know, and we talked about a while ago Civilization 6 added a feature that has been lacking from Civ games since the beginning of time.
Speaker 1: But since the beginning of time has been added to Civ by players doing it their own way Which is play by email.
Speaker 1: you play a game of Civ you take your turn you save the game You send the file to someone else they open the game They take their turn and they save the game and they send you the file.
Speaker 1: so then this was first done with floppy disks then done with emails then now it's done with apps like giant multiplayer robot Play your damn turn Third-party apps that handle it for you and arrange things for you and make it a little bit easier.
Speaker 1: They finally after six versions of civilization the game have added an official version of this to the civilization 6 client at least on PC not on any other release on iPad or anything or Now.
Speaker 0: I have played multiplayer save online Extensively for years.
Speaker 0: I have games that have been going multiple years that I'm still playing.
Speaker 0: I'm currently in five active games.
Speaker 1: I'm only in two games.
Speaker 0: However The Civ 6 play by cloud does not fucking work at all.
Speaker 1: What if I as of today see they added it and I was like.
Speaker 1: finally they added it.
Speaker 1: now I will never.
Speaker 0: you had all the right features.
Speaker 1: I was like they will that I will never use this unofficial thing again.
Speaker 1: Let me finish the two games I'm in.
Speaker 1: then I'll start games using the official but more importantly and never had Uninstall these unofficial.
Speaker 0: it had the features that no one could do with a third party.
Speaker 0: the main feature that would make it a killer App is that if you take your turn you can also go back in and just look at the map anytime like oh Which is there?
Speaker 0: that's in the Civ 6 thing.
Speaker 1: Very nice.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so you're thinking like what should I do?
Speaker 0: Someone else's turn is happening and they want to maybe coordinate some some raiding and pillaging with you.
Speaker 1: Oh, you can open up and take do diplomacy Just like get into a discord and be like, okay So you can open up the game at the same time and do diplomacy with them.
Speaker 0: You can know you can open up the game at the same time and just see you can.
Speaker 0: I can look at the game as Though it's a single-player.
Speaker 1: Oh, it's like yeah, I got an extra citrus.
Speaker 0: Yeah Yeah, send me send me that you a spear man in three turns and if Multiple players are online at the same time and I take my turn and you're already in the map It'll just turn into your turn for you.
Speaker 0: Like you're playing a real live online game.
Speaker 0: So you can have a play by mail game during the week But then say every other Sunday you agree to just all play a whole bunch of turns together for a few hours and as
Speaker 1: of today 100%
Speaker 0: of these civ6 play by cloud games I have started or joined
Speaker 1: have failed
Speaker 0: The main.
Speaker 0: there's a lot of bugs a lot of UX issues But the main problem is that it seems to just randomly kick Players out of the games and replace them with a eyes.
Speaker 0: There's no way to put the.
Speaker 1: who fucking knows What does it look like when it happens?
Speaker 1: Okay, you take your turn and then and then an AI just takes the next person's turn and then it's the next person's turn.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like yeah stuff like that happens.
Speaker 0: So if I go into my games now one of them shows two out of eight players.
Speaker 0: that game had eight humans in it.
Speaker 0: None of them quit on purpose.
Speaker 0: None of them did anything weird.
Speaker 1: No one tried to kick them out and take too long to take their turn and there's no.
Speaker 0: that feature doesn't exist.
Speaker 0: You can't set timers to kick people out.
Speaker 0: Okay, that feature only exists in all these third-party things.
Speaker 1: and what feature is there for the AI taking over?
Speaker 0: Uh, it just happened and now the games are all ruined.
Speaker 0: So we've quit them all and now we've started a new civ6 game using player damn term because it actually works.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it seems like we have to use a thing called GMR to place it five and you IDT to place it.
Speaker 0: so What I don't understand the reason I'm talking about this?
Speaker 0: This is not a hard feature Is it?
Speaker 1: you like online plenty of games get online real-time multiplayer, right?
Speaker 1: Look at overwatch, right?
Speaker 1: You play online in real time and it works.
Speaker 1: it works.
Speaker 1: It's this turn-based multiplayer.
Speaker 1: How come almost no games used to have it and almost no games get it, right?
Speaker 1: It's way way way easy compared to doing real-time multiplayer, which several games do.
Speaker 1: yep Why can a tiny game studio make like a rocket league with effectively perfect online multiplayer?
Speaker 1: Nintendo can't make an online multiplayer, but that's besides the point.
Speaker 1: But how come?
Speaker 1: like even civilization the world's number one turn-based game, which I assume is the number one turn-based game in the world Wasn't able to do this even since the 90s?
Speaker 0: Yeah It's just.
Speaker 0: it's amazing to me But it did.
Speaker 0: it has failed us so consistently that we're just going to ignore it and maybe in a couple of years I'll look and see if maybe save seven seven gets it, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah Until someone tells me that it's working I'm just never gonna use this playbook cloud feature again, because it's just not fucking work the same.
Speaker 0: so some other news.
Speaker 0: The nation of Jordan you may have seen recently banned pub G Yeah And now they're on a spree of banning lots of other games and it seems like the main criteria for being banned is being online Multiplayer and popular.
Speaker 0: Yep, so they're going to ban fortnight.
Speaker 1: All right, so everyone start playing a game that is not popular and keep switching FPS is they'll never find them all start playing Quake 1. let's see him ban that.
Speaker 0: yep.
Speaker 0: Ah They could trivially ban that.
Speaker 1: how?
Speaker 0: Well, well, so I guess yeah, if someone runs a local server someone could play it.
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 0: Here's the thing.
Speaker 0: There's no point in banning games that aren't just online with modern services because kids have no idea and will never be able to Connect to an off-the-grid game.
Speaker 1: Let's start popularizing quake 2 in Jordan and create the ultimate FPS gods and then Get them to come to the US and be overwatch guys.
Speaker 0: Just make make a battle royale in like the quake 2 or quake 3 or unreal engine and just to see Mod battle royale.
Speaker 1: then get it popularized and go to Jordan bring it on a DVD or whatever.
Speaker 0: All you got to do is teach people.
Speaker 0: It's not there.
Speaker 1: It's like yeah, it's just quick to just got to teach people how to run.
Speaker 0: Well, the thing is what they seem to be going after is games that kids will play online.
Speaker 0: Yep Which goes back to a point that I bring up a lot on geek nights that the US government has a lot of problems But the only thing that would be worse than the US having control over what games are allowed to run online Would be if literally any other country on earth had that power.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah Destiny 2 which is a game that I have zero interest in playing but it's basically like an online Loot shooter kind of game.
Speaker 0: you either know about it and play it know about it and have the same opinion.
Speaker 0: I do like that.
Speaker 0: This is one of the popular games but there keep being Exploits and ways to quote-unquote cheat and the newest one is extra funny that all come down to the same thing.
Speaker 0: People want to get a whole bunch of loot in this game, but you can't get the loot without grinding.
Speaker 1: Yep, the grinding game.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: So Lately, the latest exploit is that there's this one kind of match you can play in the game.
Speaker 0: I don't play destinies.
Speaker 0: I got no idea what this is The Forge Whatever it is, and if you join a Forge match and just walk away from your computer You'll just stand there and eventually you'll lose and then you get loot and then the game Automatically puts you in the queue to be added to another game of Forge where you will then die and lose and get more loot.
Speaker 1: And it's gotten to the point to where a huge number of people like a scary person are leaving their computers on computers on playing this mode Just collecting loot doing nothing What they're basically doing progress quest, but they're actually getting actual progress in an MMO effectively.
Speaker 1: Yep
Speaker 0: I feel like the main warning sign that a game is not actually fun and is just addictive or is using addictive things to trick You is if you would feel the desire to do something ridiculous like this to level your character up in the game like that is.
Speaker 1: This is what happens.
Speaker 1: You have video games.
Speaker 1: You've had them for a long time.
Speaker 1: They're rewarding mastery or Rewarding learning or rewarding it.
Speaker 1: they reward time spent and they don't reward and the only way they can measure time spent is not They can't actually measure your human time.
Speaker 1: They can only measure your CPU time and that's basically what Bitcoin is.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's basically all right.
Speaker 1: We'll rank each other by who will spend the most CPU time.
Speaker 1: and now you know video games do it coins do it.
Speaker 1: It's all bullshit.
Speaker 1: But I feel like they're not.
Speaker 0: waste your CPU time on bullshit like Like trying to think of a good example like Borderlands right.
Speaker 0: Borderlands was kind of fun to play.
Speaker 0: We were playing it for a while, but the game that rewards time spent Yeah, and then we quit because we saw everything we could see and everything else to see just involve waiting.
Speaker 1: Oh, I got a different colored gun that shoots different colored bullets and kills different looking bad guys faster.
Speaker 1: But it's the basically the same thing.
Speaker 0: But in that game if someone gave you an option to just give yourself max stats and the best weapons Would you do it?
Speaker 1: I'd play through the entire campaign once and then stop yep.
Speaker 0: And that that's how you can figure out if a game is tricking you and it's tricking your rat kid brain Into doing something addictive and dumb like Final Fantasy 6.
Speaker 1: I play the whole game beat beat Kafka and then be done.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right.
Speaker 0: Well granted as a kid.
Speaker 0: I farmed dinosaurs until I got everyone could cast Ultima.
Speaker 0: That was kid brain.
Speaker 1: you had nothing better to do.
Speaker 0: Yeah adult brain would not do that time.
Speaker 1: for that time I might.
Speaker 0: But anyway things of the day so breath of the wild is still in my opinion the best Zelda game ever released.
Speaker 1: Have you played them all?
Speaker 1: how do you know?
Speaker 0: I played a lot of them.
Speaker 0: name name a Zelda game better Than breath of the wild and your direct personal opinion?
Speaker 1: Hmm No, no, it's basically tied with like, you know Zelda ones all the three?
Speaker 0: Ah, yeah, but I think it's just a better Zelda one like Zelda one.
Speaker 0: I would not expect kids to play today.
Speaker 1: So the one just has kids suck.
Speaker 1: It's not cuz all the ones.
Speaker 0: so Zelda one was a product of its time.
Speaker 0: It's not that good by a completely naive modern standard.
Speaker 1: I think it's very good to think people just lack Imagination because they have been exposed to the modern times.
Speaker 1: if you're if your brain was not exposed to breath of the wild and you had You know, you grew up at the time cuz my kid brain was willing to burn every bush until I found every secret.
Speaker 1: That's right a kid have?
Speaker 1: I made a baby right now and that baby never saw breath of the wild.
Speaker 1: They would burn every bush.
Speaker 0: I would just put the kid in breath of the wild and let them experience a modern good game Yeah, and then later show them Zelda one in a museum.
Speaker 0: Zelda 2 is also arguably a better game the Zelda one, but I think so.
Speaker 1: The two is down at the bottom, but it is above Minish cap and Minish cap is above the train one.
Speaker 0: Oh, I did.
Speaker 0: I played like two ish hours at the train one and then I sold it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, what's the train one called a phantom hourglass?
Speaker 0: No, not phantom hourglass is better than yeah, but I didn't beat phantom hourglass either.
Speaker 0: It's better than Zelda 2, but it stood now.
Speaker 0: Zelda 2 was better than phantom hourglass.
Speaker 1: Nope.
Speaker 0: I I did not beat phantom hourglass cuz I got really bored Wasn't as boring as Minish cap?
Speaker 0: But one of the things that makes breath of the wild so particularly good is that among other things the sound design is Utterly fucking phenomenal.
Speaker 1: I mean, that's how it is, you know, they paid attention to all that's.
Speaker 1: you know That's what Nintendo does.
Speaker 1: is they polish?
Speaker 1: the fuck right and they pay attention to all these.
Speaker 1: ridiculously tiny Is semi procedurally generated like music.
Speaker 1: people don't know, you know, they're all these crazy crazy detailed.
Speaker 1: Very, you know tiny were intricate work like when people paint like, you know, there's really tiny things you can only see with a magnifying glass and basically, you don't notice it when you're playing you just go wow, this game is fucking incredible.
Speaker 1: and then you know If someone actually takes out the magnifying glass and points out these details, you're like, oh my god I didn't know that was there.
Speaker 1: I didn't know that tiny owl was hidden on my dollar bill.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 0: so this video in about 10 minutes goes into a lot of detail on the specific techniques that the sound design of breath of the wild did and Some of these things are really subtle or they're things that an average player even after beating the game May have never encountered.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, the thing that really bothers me the most is that you know I've seen quite a hint quite a lot of videos about not only breath of the wild but other Nintendo games and other games in Pointing out.
Speaker 1: look at this really subtle thing that you would never notice that they did to make this game great Right, and it's like.
Speaker 1: well everyone watches these videos.
Speaker 1: They get tons of views They get posted links everywhere and all the gaming news sites, right.
Speaker 1: and then you look at other games.
Speaker 1: Pretty much don't do them.
Speaker 1: It's like gee Christ if you're making a game Right.
Speaker 1: It's like.
Speaker 0: go watch all the videos like this and I can tell you why.
Speaker 0: it's the same reason why there's no more advanced Wars games because the amount of human effort it takes to actually You might not be able to do it to the same degree
Speaker 1: But you could at least do learn something from it and incorporate some amount of it into your other game Right instead of putting out an unpolished, you know blocky ass, whatever.
Speaker 0: Well one thing I can say from I have seen a lot of industry stuff internally talking about how Among like the bigger studios They spending about as much effort on polish as you spent on core design is the norm.
Speaker 0: yeah, that's very and that is not feasible for a smaller game unless that game is Basically just entirely polished and basically just a proof of concept.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: No, no, you can't spend equal to if you're a small place You can't spend equal time but you can spend a little bit more than I see a lot of places spending.
Speaker 0: the way the music in the Grasslands and breath of the wild works and the way the day-to-night transitions happen and the way town music works.
Speaker 1: Holy shit I mean, you know she gave me a motto.
Speaker 1: he once famously said a delayed game is eventually good.
Speaker 1: Oh a bad game is just bad forever.
Speaker 0: by that logic Half-life 3 is the greatest game any human has ever conceived.
Speaker 1: Maybe it is but that's actually what happened with half-life 1. is they just get?
Speaker 1: they didn't set a release date.
Speaker 1: They just kept fucking delaying that shit.
Speaker 1: delaying it delaying it Eventually came out like oh it's perfect.
Speaker 0: now the craziest one at the end of this video.
Speaker 0: The thing that's so subtle is there is a thing that happens and you can only experience it if you are in The upper parts of the atmosphere like on the highest mountains that are usually dirt like constantly raining or snow storming Mm-hmm, and it happens to be daylight and the weather which happens very rarely happens to get sunny and clear While you are standing up there.
Speaker 0: something specific and coded just to that moment happens And it's pretty cool.
Speaker 0: So what do you got?
Speaker 1: What did I have?
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, so Hockey's far away and all the summer sports, you know, we had a lot of them just ended like the international ones.
Speaker 1: We won some soccer.
Speaker 1: You know some tennis just ended.
Speaker 1: No baseball is not going to great.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I I've been.
Speaker 0: I'm planning to watch that Wimbledon match later.
Speaker 1: I know the outcome but I saw when I was standing in a Verizon store.
Speaker 0: I saw the outcome so I know spoilers I guess but I actually want to watch it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's really good.
Speaker 0: tennis is real good to watch.
Speaker 0: She's one of my favorite sports.
Speaker 1: Yeah, tennis is one of the best sports.
Speaker 0: Anyway, you want to learn how to play tennis?
Speaker 1: No, I hate playing tennis cuz I got to run back and forth.
Speaker 0: Not if you're good.
Speaker 1: I Just like hitting the could.
Speaker 1: I stand perfectly still just hit the ball only.
Speaker 0: Uh, if you're really good at racquetball You could.
Speaker 1: let's just play badminton instead.
Speaker 0: Let's play right badminton.
Speaker 0: Yes, you think you don't have to run around in bad man As far.
Speaker 1: yeah Much smaller court.
Speaker 0: Yeah, let's play some badminton.
Speaker 0: I want to see how this goes.
Speaker 1: Actually, I recently found out there's like a super like badminton place over in like Regal Park.
Speaker 1: Oh anyway The point is it's not.
Speaker 1: most of the sports are not happening.
Speaker 1: Especially our favorite sport of hockey is not happening right now.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but I found some interesting Off-season hockey stuff is actually really old but it doesn't have too many views and basically it is real behind-the-scenes shit Right.
Speaker 1: It's like you hear all the time about, you know teams and sports trading players, right?
Speaker 1: And it's like up on the news.
Speaker 1: suddenly on the news They're like so-and-so traded so-and-so for this and that and the other thing, right?
Speaker 1: or people are reporting it Beforehand and all kinds of stuff like that, right?
Speaker 1: It's like what actually fucking happens when teams trade.
Speaker 1: It's like how do you like if I oh if I'm a GM of a team and I want to trade player I call the other GM on the other team.
Speaker 1: We agree.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 1: I'll trade your rim for Joey.
Speaker 1: Jojo Shabbadoo, right?
Speaker 1: All right, we've agreed now.
Speaker 1: What the fuck do we do?
Speaker 1: How do we make this trade happen now, right?
Speaker 1: Well, here is a video that shows you 100% with nothing cut out of the phone call and paperwork and such that is required To make a trade happen in the National Hockey League.
Speaker 1: as of what year like 2011 and you can date it partly by it hasn't changed much since then?
Speaker 0: according to what people have said the phone on this dude's Desk is the exact IP phone that I used to have Like he.
Speaker 1: like it is the exact same phone Right, so the dude in the video is the NHL official whose job it was in 2011 to do this.
Speaker 1: I'm sure it might be a different person now Maybe not who knows?
Speaker 1: and the two GM's call the person they have a discussion and then the trade is officially in the books.
Speaker 1: It is quite fascinating to see how it is done.
Speaker 0: in the meta moment Book is the tale of Genji.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah updated that website.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you did.
Speaker 0: That's right, not just a novel but arguably the first one.
Speaker 0: No, not.
Speaker 1: arguably.
Speaker 1: It's literally the first novel in human history that was ever written.
Speaker 1: I feel like if you're gonna read novels You should maybe start with the first one.
Speaker 0: So we will be reading this.
Speaker 0: click on the link to make sure you get the right translation.
Speaker 0: Yeah, Mike's the best one we can find.
Speaker 1: There is a newer translation But my research has told me that the second newest translation is I guess the one to read as of 2019 unabridged.
Speaker 1: also.
Speaker 1: I get the feeling that it's important to read this book because this is one of those situations We're like.
Speaker 1: I feel like lots and lots of media and other stories reference this all the fucking time and you don't know it.
Speaker 1: And as soon as you read the tale of Genji You're gonna see tale of Genji popping up and every all these other things like oh my god.
Speaker 1: It's a tale of Genji reference.
Speaker 0: I missed it in high school.
Speaker 0: I read a bunch of excerpts from it, but I didn't read the whole thing.
Speaker 0: I don't know the whole story.
Speaker 1: I think it's gonna take a while to read the whole thing.
Speaker 1: So this book club ain't happening for moons.
Speaker 0: Also, you might have noticed that Emily and I have started a sideshow which is posted on the patreon and I Joe is that?
Speaker 1: is it a?
Speaker 1: is it a bearded lady?
Speaker 0: Yeah, is it?
Speaker 1: Is it a snake charmer, you know?
Speaker 1: fire eater It's kind of what kind of side show it's the geek now.
Speaker 0: so we are doing a Analysis review and commentary on every Disney theatrical animation from the beginning to today.
Speaker 0: in chronological order.
Speaker 1: That means you're gonna have to watch a lot of garbage.
Speaker 1: You haven't watched.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I've never seen Pocahontas either.
Speaker 0: I've never seen the hunchback of Notre Dame.
Speaker 1: I did not either.
Speaker 0: I've seen scenes from them But I've never actually seen them as movies.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: I seen TV commercials for them back in the 90s.
Speaker 0: Yep, I had seen however all the shorts in the first one that we just reviewed.
Speaker 0: That's up on the patreon and will be up publicly for people who give us no money soon.
Speaker 0: Academy Awards review of Walt Disney cartoons, which was technically the first Disney theatrical animated release.
Speaker 0: Uh-huh.
Speaker 0: It was shown in theaters as a movie as a promotional thing ahead of Snow White.
Speaker 1: coming to theaters There were quite a few anthology type things like my favorite fun and fancy free.
Speaker 0: Ah, that was later.
Speaker 1: It was later.
Speaker 0: but one thing we noticed though in Academy Award review Walt Disney cartoons that Characters on a table where there's big food everywhere happens more often than you might realize.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah in silly symphonies Yeah, but I mean can't beat goofy in the jello.
Speaker 1: That was the best know.
Speaker 0: goofy the jello is the best one but you can see the precursor to goofy in the jello with Kitten looking at the jello like substance.
Speaker 1: I mean everyone is seen right how Disney would often, you know What was the?
Speaker 1: I think it was like Jungle Book and they showed like and then they showed another.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, they were used like roto the old animation, right?
Speaker 1: Was it Robin Hood and Jungle Book?
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, and Snow White they all they've reused a ton of stuff.
Speaker 0: Did you see the documentary or all the animators were like?
Speaker 0: it didn't save us any fucking time.
Speaker 0: It was harder to do that than just to animate it from scratch.
Speaker 0: Yep, but it's such a pain like the animators hated it.
Speaker 1: Apparently it was but I think even though it may have been a pain that didn't save time because you still had to draw the Drawings is a different character, right?
Speaker 1: I do think that it's like well one person animated something fucking incredibly.
Speaker 1: It's like well, we can just have something else animated incredibly as well.
Speaker 0: Yeah I saw it in multiple interviews in this documentary with the animators who literally said things to the effect of Yeah, it would have like if I copy link sword swing from breath of the wild.
Speaker 1: now Fucking badass sword swing in my game and you probably won't notice Same thing.
Speaker 1: It might be take just as much work.
Speaker 1: It's not gonna save me any time but it is gonna make sure that my game has the best sword swing without me having to invent my own.
Speaker 0: and Finally if you are not planning to be at the penny arcade Expo in Seattle You're missing out because we will be there and as of today Only Friday and Monday badges are available and Friday is almost sold out.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: No one wants to go Monday, apparently Monday.
Speaker 0: luckily our panels are not on Monday.
Speaker 0: All right In fact our panels are on on one hand if you have seen these panels before One of them will not have new content.
Speaker 1: which ones you submitted?
Speaker 0: I submitted a bunch but for various reasons the ones packs want us to do are on Friday at 1230 p.m In Hippogriff theater the 40 tabletop games you must play And on Saturday at 11 a.m.
Speaker 0: In Hippogriff theater the 40 games you must play.
Speaker 1: So we're just doing two clickbait garbage panels.
Speaker 1: click they want to do harm of games again.
Speaker 0: I didn't submit harm of games again, cuz you didn't say you wanted to do it.
Speaker 0: I submitted a whole bunch of other ones.
Speaker 1: I mean we did it already.
Speaker 1: Why don't we just keep doing it?
Speaker 0: Well, the difference is harm of games.
Speaker 0: we have a really good YouTube video of it and That is the panel that I don't have any YouTube videos of 40 whatever.
Speaker 0: So actually we've never done because 40 games we did like a trial run at magfest.
Speaker 0: so now I'm gonna like rewrite that panel to make it really good.
Speaker 0: and In terms of 40 tabletop games at packs West This is the kind of thing that will attract the audience of people who don't know who the hell we are.
Speaker 1: I mean, I'm just taking my free badge.
Speaker 1: But yeah, we should.
Speaker 1: if they're gonna give us two panels at least one of them should be a non garbage panel.
Speaker 0: I don't I think that remember our selling point is that our panels have the clickbait title, but they actually teach you.
Speaker 1: This is not as good as the usual situation.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 0: These are some of our based on.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna have to write some new panels to get your clickbait out of the rotation.
Speaker 0: I'm just saying I have the stats on the YouTube channel and our panels with the clickbait titles are far and away the most popular.
Speaker 1: Yes, the my poison sugar sold way better than my healthy vegetable.
Speaker 0: Therefore the poison sugar is better But in turn like real harm of games like a tenth as popular as nostalgia versus game design.
Speaker 0: Neither one of those was a clickbait title.
Speaker 0: Hmm.
Speaker 0: So I don't know if the panels I write seem to get more traffic.
Speaker 1: Yeah, cuz you're trying to get traffic with your poison sugar, how is nostalgia versus game design poison sugar?
Speaker 0: That was just a straight-up good panel.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we'll see.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we will see I got the stats are.
Speaker 0: Actually, our most popular panel is still designing game rules.
Speaker 0: Oh my panel Uh, the one that I mostly made the slides for and wrote no That one the one where I have the change log in Google of me making almost all those slides I'm sure I made the rules panel.
Speaker 0: Uh Did you?
Speaker 0: are you sure?
Speaker 0: do you really want to have this fight with me on the air?
Speaker 1: No, I don't care.
Speaker 0: I have the change log.
Speaker 0: I know who made that panel Panel in detail is the stats are not what is important.
Speaker 1: It is the quality of the content.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and I think this is cool.
Speaker 0: I mean you you don't have to do these panels you want.
Speaker 0: I'll do them.
Speaker 1: So I need a free badge.
Speaker 0: You can be my camera.
Speaker 1: guy bought the purchased badge I have given to someone.
Speaker 0: you can just be my cameraman and I'll do the panel.
Speaker 0: no so Long time ago, there were measured games and there were Castlevania games.
Speaker 0: They were both good.
Speaker 0: They did their things right?
Speaker 1: Well, actually the original Castlevania games were just side-scrolling with several levels.
Speaker 1: Yeah even though the levels were structured in a way with ladders and several rooms to give you the impression of You know going into this big castle even cut.
Speaker 0: it was side scroll like varied weapons plus a whip of some kind.
Speaker 0: Fight some monsters spooky Dracula, right metric, right?
Speaker 1: It was.
Speaker 1: it was that you know, that's cool.
Speaker 1: based hard right platformers Platforming and combat involving enemies all over the place and not just the ones right in front of you.
Speaker 0: Metroid Early concept of leveling up and that like you make your whip stronger by collecting the numbers and all that early.
Speaker 0: But it was there that like there was a. the precursor technology was there.
Speaker 1: it had these sub weapons at least Self weapons and Metroid 1 was the game that really invented going in all different directions Exploring but is L. I mean Zelda had that too.
Speaker 1: But but I think Metroid does.
Speaker 1: Metroid one predates all to one.
Speaker 1: I feel like it does but anyway It was side.
Speaker 1: scroll II platform II explore II right shooting bad guys in all directions.
Speaker 0: Metroid 1986 Zelda 1 1986.
Speaker 1: Yeah, yeah.
Speaker 0: So February 21st 1986 for you have to imagine they were making these Zelda came first All right.
Speaker 0: Anyway, August Metroid didn't come out till August.
Speaker 1: They were developing at the same time Anyway, but Metroid had to get different items unlock different areas of the game situation, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, the high jump to get over there.
Speaker 1: You need the bomb to get over there that whole thing, right?
Speaker 0: There was a third kind of game that was basically just level up your shit like Final Fantasy or whatever, right?
Speaker 1: So as time went on right the these formulas were improved right and the ultimate versions of these games were Super Metroid right which basically perfected what Metroid was?
Speaker 1: Yeah, but at the same time when Castlevania switched from being you know on the NES Right and then it went to SNES Super Castlevania Which is Castlevania 4 which is basically the same kind of deal only way fancier, but when they moved to PlayStation Symphony
Speaker 0: of the night was the pen pineapple apple pen right of all these genres.
Speaker 1: Symphony of the night.
Speaker 1: They took the Metroid bits and merged them into the Castlevania bits to create the masterpiece game.
Speaker 1: And then while there weren't that many more Metroid games basically Not too many for a long ass time.
Speaker 0: remember the first-person shooter on the DS, right?
Speaker 1: And then when they're finally were Metroid games again They were like, you know Metroid Prime and stuff in that span.
Speaker 1: There were many Castlevania games holding that torch for the Metroid style game Without you know, but still incorporating the Castlevania bits, you know the GBA Castlevania Right, basically Symphony of the night Not to review Symphony of the night.
Speaker 0: But basically what it did is it had the ability to level up and get a whole bunch of different weapons and fun stuff coupled with the Metroid level of exploration coupled with the Castlevania aesthetic and combat
Speaker 1: coupled with being fucking enormous at least relative to other games in the genre
Speaker 0: by having the Square
Speaker 1: boss the upside-down castle motherfuckers
Speaker 0: instead of just having the square boss of fight a guy then fight the real guy.
Speaker 0: It was beat the game then beat the whole game again.
Speaker 1: You could beat the game pretty early quickly and it's like you.
Speaker 1: it would just be like, okay you won Congratulations beat Dracula, but if you beat the game the right way you went into the middle area fought that other boss, right?
Speaker 0: It's kind of like in final fantasy.
Speaker 0: Oh really?
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: Well, guess what?
Speaker 1: Here's the whole game again.
Speaker 1: We're gonna take the whole map of the game turn it upside down.
Speaker 1: on top of itself It's actually twice as you're just twice as much game as you thought.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you thought you were at a hundred percent.
Speaker 0: you were at 51%.
Speaker 0: that's right.
Speaker 1: And also this entire upside-down copy of the entire map is full of completely different bad guys and bosses and different secrets and different everything.
Speaker 1: good luck.
Speaker 1: and While there are some magic super Metroid was like, oh you beat mother brain.
Speaker 1: Guess what?
Speaker 1: There's actually an entire flip side of the map That's as big as the map.
Speaker 1: We just played.
Speaker 1: nor fair to meridia - everything everything - and is like it's completely Populated completely differently.
Speaker 1: Keep going.
Speaker 0: So it it's not a perfect game.
Speaker 0: It has some flaws and like time like we've evolved the genre since then But it started something important and basically since Symphony of the night.
Speaker 0: One of the things I've wanted out of gaming.
Speaker 0: It's just more of that just pump it into my veins, right?
Speaker 1: Exactly, there are so many genres of game and we always talk about, you know, we do want originality in gaming.
Speaker 1: We wish people wouldn't just keep doing cookie cutter.
Speaker 0: FPS is no keep doing, you know cookie cutter platform But at the same time you want to see a genre like reach its culmination like fully explore.
Speaker 1: Yes was not enough, but we've now had so many FPS as we got too many, right?
Speaker 1: There's certain time It's like your favorite food.
Speaker 1: Maybe your favorite food is ice cream.
Speaker 1: Okay, I eat some ice cream.
Speaker 1: I could eat more ice cream.
Speaker 1: There's a point at which okay too much ice cream.
Speaker 1: I want to eat something different, but at the same time more ice cream is still good.
Speaker 1: There's a time and a place for just having more ice cream.
Speaker 1: So that is why so many indie games have gone down this Metroidvania route because it is a genre that is was not milked to Death by the big studios
Speaker 0: and while there had been a ton of games on the DS and 3ds that scratch that itch and we're
Speaker 1: good.
Speaker 0: I could have still played more.
Speaker 1: They weren't quite at the same level.
Speaker 1: a lot of those.
Speaker 0: while they were good I would argue some of them were better in some ways than Symphony of the Night.
Speaker 1: like No, I don't think any DS Castlevania is as good as Symphony of the Night.
Speaker 0: A Portrait of Ruin was pretty fucking solid.
Speaker 1: Solid is not Symphony of the Night.
Speaker 1: Anyway, the point is it's still good, right?
Speaker 0: But I'm saying you could list a lot of the DS 3ds games and Symphony of the Night Together and like rate all their different attributes and they're all in the same league Right.
Speaker 1: So anyway, since everyone abandoned Konami or Konami purged everything good about itself Quite right a while ago.
Speaker 0: Yeah, one of the people who?
Speaker 1: Fled that key person.
Speaker 0: Yeah, these Koji Igarashi basically the person who is Responsible for Symphony of the Night if you can pin it on one person because all those indie games that try to make Metroidvania is The reason those games probably fall flat is that they didn't have Igarashi, right?
Speaker 1: So Igarashi comes along a while ago.
Speaker 1: I think it already feels like years ago.
Speaker 1: I don't know exactly when.
Speaker 1: when was it the Kickstarter?
Speaker 0: Oh the Kickstarter.
Speaker 1: Oh my god I kick-started it the day they put it up, but I forget what it was.
Speaker 1: Oh feels like a long-ass time ago.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean, let's see.
Speaker 0: He left Konami in 2014.
Speaker 1: yeah, when was the Kickstarter?
Speaker 0: I'm trying to figure that out on the Kickstarter page.
Speaker 0: No Kickstarter sucks at that because it doesn't want to remind you that.
Speaker 0: oh this thing.
Speaker 0: So the Kickstarter says the game will be delivered in March of 2017.
Speaker 0: Okay, so definitely before then.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so put up a Kickstarter and said hey, we're gonna make a game called blood-stained ritual of the night wink-wink.
Speaker 1: This is just gonna be fucking Symphony and I obviously we can't use any Castlevania intellectual properties.
Speaker 1: We're gonna make all new artwork and characters.
Speaker 0: Castlevania!
Speaker 0: Spooky castle!
Speaker 1: We're just gonna make more Symphony of the Night that Konami never let us do.
Speaker 1: Kickstart it give us money.
Speaker 1: We will make it for you.
Speaker 1: And I said shut up and take my money.
Speaker 0: Based on everything I saw the Kickstarter like the people involved the level of detail I said well, I have to bet on this and I don't have to bet too much.
Speaker 1: So any of them right?
Speaker 1: then I waited a long-ass time.
Speaker 0: They were at 64,000 people pledged five and a half million dollars to this.
Speaker 1: So we waited a long-ass time and eventually we got blood-stained Not ritual of the night.
Speaker 1: We got blood-stained.
Speaker 1: curse of the moon.
Speaker 1: Yeah, blood-stained curse of the moon was basically a redo of Castlevania 3 Dracula's curse.
Speaker 1: It was that style of game.
Speaker 0: Castlevania 3 is not Dracula's curse.
Speaker 1: Which one is Castlevania 3?
Speaker 0: Castlevania 2 is Dracula's curse.
Speaker 1: Castlevania 3, Akumajou Dracula.
Speaker 1: I'll give you a Japanese name cuz I forgot the English one.
Speaker 1: This is Castlevania 2 is Simon's Quest.
Speaker 1: Castlevania 3 is Akumajou Dracula Dracula's curse.
Speaker 1: How could I be wrong about it?
Speaker 0: I think you were right.
Speaker 0: I was wrong.
Speaker 1: Anyway, Castlevania 2 is Simon's Quest.
Speaker 0: Anyway, I never beat Castlevania 3 because it was too hard.
Speaker 1: Because it's hard as fucking balls and so is curse of the moon.
Speaker 1: It's a little easier.
Speaker 1: Yeah, anyway Yeah, so curse of the moon is basically a Castlevania 3 style game.
Speaker 1: That is pretty good.
Speaker 1: It has several characters.
Speaker 1: you can play through it as and you know, it's not bad.
Speaker 1: And if you needed to hold over while you're waiting for ritual of the night, there you go.
Speaker 1: But finally just a couple weeks ago, right?
Speaker 1: Ritual of the night blood-stained ritual the night finally released on all platforms.
Speaker 1: it came out on PC PS4 Xbox first and then a week or two later it came out on Steam.
Speaker 1: and here it is.
Speaker 1: I Foolishly had chosen the Steam version, but I chose it way back.
Speaker 1: See, I should have stuck with my.
Speaker 1: I usually have that steam policy.
Speaker 1: My policy has.
Speaker 1: yet again I basically proved myself right.
Speaker 0: I deviated from a policy and I got burned now in one hand like for example There are games like wargroove or slay the spire that I really want on a switch because I'm just Chose PC for those games as well.
Speaker 0: Why wisely so slay the spire and wargroove are both great to play like on a plane.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well, I wisely chose them for PC as well as well.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I Think they're better on switch.
Speaker 0: this game if it was just fine on switch would be better on switch But it's as of today not just fine doesn't work that well on the switch, right?
Speaker 1: So the switch version has shittier graphics is lower FPS and it's like.
Speaker 1: I don't care about graphics too much.
Speaker 1: But the FPS is low, but also it lags and crashes way worse than the versions on the other platforms.
Speaker 1: I should have gotten the PC one now.
Speaker 0: Meanwhile, I have it on the PC.
Speaker 0: I turned every single setting up to the maximum possible and it runs like a champ and it looks beautiful.
Speaker 1: My plan is to since I already bought I couldn't change my mind I had the switch version right is to.
Speaker 0: I kick back and spire twice like I did with.
Speaker 1: no I'm going to keep playing the switch one, which I've been managed to get through despite being meh I can still.
Speaker 1: it's still playable right kind of mostly right?
Speaker 1: Oh, it's crashed on me a couple times.
Speaker 0: the the other Castlevania - I forgot about the Gameboy games.
Speaker 0: That was Belmonts revenge.
Speaker 1: Okay Anyway, my plan is to play it until I you know, I did.
Speaker 1: I did beat it But that was the easy beat.
Speaker 1: that doesn't count, right?
Speaker 1: I plan to beat it.
Speaker 1: beat it for real beat it, you know upside down castle beat it.
Speaker 1: and then When I feel in the future that I must replay it because I mean Symphony night was good enough to replay several times.
Speaker 1: I play that again.
Speaker 1: Even this will be get replayed.
Speaker 1: So when it's time to replay it and is a big steam sale Then I will get the PC version and stop playing the switch version.
Speaker 0: Yep So in terms of a short review like switch issues technology issues Notwithstanding if you have it on a PC or you just want to talk about the gameplay It's great.
Speaker 0: It's everything I wanted.
Speaker 1: Yeah regardless of the switch issues this game blood stain ritual for the night is a Another symphony of the night exactly as advertised.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: It plays the same.
Speaker 1: It feels the same boss fights.
Speaker 1: It's a new it's a. it's new map But with you know new enemies new story new characters new difficulty curve is right like it feels right.
Speaker 1: Everything feels right basically as it might as well be symphony of the other night or symphony of the day or any of next month or Orchestra the I don't know whatever.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you get the idea.
Speaker 1: if you like symphony night You will like this game.
Speaker 1: if you haven't played symphony tonight play some of the night Then play this game.
Speaker 1: I get more.
Speaker 0: just play this game.
Speaker 0: This game's great.
Speaker 1: I think you want to play simply night first.
Speaker 0: No, yeah, honestly, though You should play all the DS ones as well because they're great.
Speaker 1: and if you can't get enough after playing symphony night and Curse ritual of the night curse of the blood-stained ritual night Right, then you can play the DS ones and and then you're gonna start running out of stuff to play.
Speaker 0: But it especially in terms of because what makes this game great Is that the maps really big and there's a lot like every monster has its shard and most of them are useless.
Speaker 0: But you still want to mess with them Say like that's the kind of things I liked about.
Speaker 1: all has the Metroid thing where you get different shards Which will let you unlock different areas.
Speaker 1: like I finally get a shard let's me go in the water.
Speaker 1: I finally got the shard.
Speaker 1: let's me shoot the reflecting beam.
Speaker 1: But then some areas you got the shard.
Speaker 1: let's me do the double jump.
Speaker 0: But then some areas you can just go to like any time or like pretty early in the game.
Speaker 0: But the monsters are just ray too strong unless you're way good.
Speaker 0: So you want to come back when you've leveled up or when you've gotten better shards or just gotten more HP.
Speaker 0: Yep It's got a good food system, this is the thing.
Speaker 1: the crafting food system in this game pretty fun is When usually I ignore all that bullshit, so here's the genius things this game has done in terms of quests and whatnot, right?
Speaker 1: So first of all, there's a person who gives you quests to kill ex bad guys, right?
Speaker 1: So first of all, the game really helps you find those bad guys by putting little symbols on the map showing you where they live.
Speaker 1: Guys respawn.
Speaker 1: when you leave the screen you can just easily find the bad guy.
Speaker 1: kill him leave the screen.
Speaker 1: come back kill him leave The screen come back kill him and complete the quest.
Speaker 1: in no time, right?
Speaker 1: As you go through the game, they give you quests in batches.
Speaker 1: So it's like, okay, here's five guys I'll give you quests for.
Speaker 1: when you complete all those they give you quests for the next set of guys and Those guys are in an order.
Speaker 1: that is the order that you were going to be exploring the map in Right, so it's like as you go through the game naturally You are then encountering the next set of enemies along which there are quests to beat those enemies.
Speaker 0: So it gives you like Excuses to go poke at things and it gives you reasons to mess with stuff.
Speaker 1: then you go back to you teleport back to the Beginning of the game to visit the quest person after completing the quest and they give you rewards, right?
Speaker 1: There's another person who gives you quests to get certain foods Right and to get the foods you have to go to this other guy who will let you Basically cook food and you need combinations of things like crafting, right?
Speaker 1: So you get combinations items you visit the dude you craft the items, but here's the brilliance.
Speaker 0: There's recipes right.
Speaker 0: every unique recipe you eat gives you a one-time Permanent stat boost the first time you is.
Speaker 1: that gives you a huge incentive To cook every kind of food once and eat every kind of food once even if you're not using the food to restore your health.
Speaker 0: I mean, that's me tonight.
Speaker 1: There was no reason to do all these foods.
Speaker 1: They were just there for fun.
Speaker 0: Tonight you find some wall meat good enough.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: Wall meat is all you needed exactly.
Speaker 1: And then you give the foods to this person.
Speaker 1: They're looking for specific foods.
Speaker 1: You give them the quest food and then they give you rewards, right?
Speaker 1: And as you go through the game You're encountering the enemies that drop the things that you need to cook the foods that are in and the quests are in the right Order.
Speaker 1: Yep There's another person who gives you quests For items and you craft items much in the same way that you craft food only you don't eat them for a permanent stat boost And the person is giving you rewards for getting certain items and crafting.
Speaker 1: most of them are the items you need to craft.
Speaker 1: Yeah, bring them back to them and they reward you with items right that you can maybe then use to craft other things or use or who knows and these three different quest II people.
Speaker 1: They reward you with items that are often needed to complete the quest of the other quest Right back and forth with the food person in that right and the and it's like a. really, you know as you progress through the game, it's really smooth.
Speaker 1: and then the best thing is That this game gives you a reason to have money because there's a shopping person.
Speaker 1: the shopping person does two amazing things.
Speaker 1: one They sell things that you actually need for cooking and crafting.
Speaker 1: I went to the as soon as I had a bunch of money.
Speaker 1: I went to that shop and I was about five of everything.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right because it was actually you everything was good.
Speaker 1: But also as soon as you go out into the world, right?
Speaker 1: For example, I needed this like mako oil to do a lot of cooking because I needed like oil for pizza dough and I had to kill these makos or whatever the fuck they're called.
Speaker 1: There's like these plants in this one area and I really didn't want to sit there farming these fucking plants, right?
Speaker 1: After I got some oil and then I did some cooking with some oil then I visited the shop person.
Speaker 1: They're like, guess what?
Speaker 1: I'll just sell you the oil now.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I got any stock.
Speaker 0: I got a guy.
Speaker 1: It's like as soon as you get an item and start like, you know shopping or I don't know what the exact requirement is, but the shop starts selling it and then you don't need to farm it anymore and It's like holy shit.
Speaker 1: Now.
Speaker 1: I can just craft all those oil based things No problem.
Speaker 1: As long as I have money and you just get money by playing easily.
Speaker 1: No problem.
Speaker 1: So that setup is like one of the best that I have seen in terms of quest craft recipe Shop money actually matters.
Speaker 1: I want money.
Speaker 1: Yep things the other.
Speaker 1: any game is better than the way Symphony Night does it with library guy The other thing that I very much like.
Speaker 0: there are a lot of different kinds of weapons and they all act Very differently.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah when it comes to armor and equipment, I choose just what gives me the best stats.
Speaker 0: I don't care what it looks like even but it does change like 20 different kinds of swords that are all Different in right like meaningful interesting ways.
Speaker 1: Yeah So there was a sword I got that is like really fast and really short-range a lot like Strider here.
Speaker 1: use sword Using that but then I turned it in for a quest and then I went to go get another one.
Speaker 1: but while I was trying to get another one, which it did eventually get I Discovered the flying sword which is a sword that when you swing it It flies straight out like a projectile super far like almost half the screen.
Speaker 1: then it comes back.
Speaker 1: But on its way back it goes up and spins Most bad guys.
Speaker 1: this thing hits them two or three times in one swing.
Speaker 1: It's a little bit slow.
Speaker 1: Yes, you throw it out and wait for it to come back, but it's basically cheating.
Speaker 1: I just hide behind something and keep throwing the sword over and over and then the bad guy dies and I'm well out of Their range and they're no problem for me.
Speaker 1: so I don't care that this thing doesn't do a lot of damage because it does multiple hits and Basically is like infinite armor because it protects me from so much damage.
Speaker 1: I very much enjoy not really switch to any other weapon because I haven't found anything better.
Speaker 0: in every metro in any game I always enjoy like what are the cheap?
Speaker 0: What cheap way?
Speaker 0: Can I beat this boss?
Speaker 1: Yeah I just try to figure out the cheapest way to do everything the whole game with the flying blade.
Speaker 1: There might be some better weapon, but why even bother flying blade?
Speaker 0: I like.
Speaker 0: I in these kinds of games I tend to like the super slow super heavy mega damage weapons.
Speaker 1: I like the fast.
Speaker 1: I like whatever keeps me safe and I like whatever I like super risky Like anything that'll get rid of our Things that are fast.
Speaker 1: so I could as I can fast as I can press the button I can swing the sword.
Speaker 0: I like to be super slow.
Speaker 0: No armor.
Speaker 0: Like I only got to hit the guy once.
Speaker 1: I just got it actually kill the guy in one hit.
Speaker 1: That's okay.
Speaker 1: But when sometimes when you can't kill a guy in one hit I hate the slow.
Speaker 1: Well because I have to go in Swing and then do a bunch of dodging and running away.
Speaker 1: It's like a swing again.
Speaker 0: But that's why I don't like along these lines a lot a lot of the different Castlevania games.
Speaker 0: Some of the weapons have been guns.
Speaker 0: They've always been just pointless and stupid and like you never want to use those things.
Speaker 0: Yeah in this game the guns are actually interesting and good and there's tons of different kinds of ammo.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you got to make and learn and craft all kinds of different ammo.
Speaker 1: That is all kinds of different effects and they're all fun.
Speaker 0: But here's the genius.
Speaker 0: every gun you might have special ammo But if you run out of ammo or you don't want to waste your a good ammo There's always an infinite ammo option that just kind of sucks, but works.
Speaker 0: Yep, so you can have fun with the gun if you want to play with the gun.
Speaker 0: It's like a subtle little game design decision that makes the guns fun and interesting to use Without you hoarding them like you hoard elixirs in a Final Fantasy game.
Speaker 1: Yeah Also, you know the game that the all the weapons most of them at least have some sort of fancy move you can do.
Speaker 1: Yeah, where you input a street?
Speaker 0: Oh, that was it as soon as I noticed that that like.
Speaker 0: oh with this kind of weapon like do a hadoken and it'll do A thing.
Speaker 1: Yep, but I haven't found the one for the flying sword yet.
Speaker 1: Maybe I should google it.
Speaker 1: The game smartly all around the game are these bookcases.
Speaker 1: if you go to a bookcase and read it Sometimes it gives you a journal entry with some lore and plot.
Speaker 1: Yeah half of them will just tell you the input commands for the special moves and it tells you which weapons those special moves apply to.
Speaker 1: And it's like oh, there's a weapon called that.
Speaker 1: maybe I'll try to find one.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the game always tells you everything.
Speaker 1: There's no hidden learning and knowledge based stuff.
Speaker 1: It's like, oh you want to craft that recipe?
Speaker 1: You're gonna need a consomme a black pepper This into that.
Speaker 1: it's like there's no hidden info nothing to look up No strategy guide needed.
Speaker 1: all the info was shown to you on the screen.
Speaker 1: You and you can always go look at all these guidebooks and menus in the press.
Speaker 1: start.
Speaker 1: Everything's there.
Speaker 1: It's really great Pretty good.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: The music's good.
Speaker 0: The background is good.
Speaker 0: The arts good.
Speaker 1: The animation is good, but not simply not good.
Speaker 0: Well now but simply the night was good for a lot of reasons.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's hard to start to recreate that amazing characters are not as interesting or The main character is female which is great.
Speaker 0: frankly most of the DS ones even had better plots than this.
Speaker 0: the plot of this Is just yeah Dracula's castles back and some alchemists did something a long time ago.
Speaker 1: Yes, there is a guy you can visit who's basically Edward Scissorhands who can change your characters look like your colors Your haircut and you can get books with different hairstyles in them to unlock different looks.
Speaker 0: I guess I'm not playing Metroidvanias for the plot.
Speaker 0: I go into them assuming now it's gonna be dumb.
Speaker 0: They're gonna tell me there's a boss.
Speaker 0: The boss is not the real boss.
Speaker 0: There's gonna be a side.
Speaker 0: character ends up being evil.
Speaker 0: There's gonna be a boss.
Speaker 0: We've never even heard of who shows up like two-thirds of the way through.
Speaker 0: There's gonna be a secret way to fight a boss to unlock even more of the game.
Speaker 0: That's all I care about.
Speaker 1: The other thing I care about you didn't mention is the thing that symphony night and Metroid Super Metroid at least both do which is Having lots of really unique interesting rooms.
Speaker 1: Yes unique looking rooms unique Places so that you really feels like you're traveling around in different areas.
Speaker 1: Like I remember this is the blood room.
Speaker 1: I remember this is the train.
Speaker 1: This is the water room.
Speaker 0: This is I have not.
Speaker 0: I've not unplugged the blood room yet.
Speaker 1: I have unplugged the blood room.
Speaker 1: This is the.
Speaker 1: this is the room with the giant cat in the middle of it, right?
Speaker 1: It's like is the flying sword room.
Speaker 1: This is the paintings that come to life.
Speaker 1: This is the clock room.
Speaker 1: This is this.
Speaker 1: the room where you can sit in a chair is the room where the guy takes you on his chariot And it's I love the chariot guy and it's like.
Speaker 1: this is what makes it interesting to explore that Metroid.
Speaker 1: one doesn't really have as much where it's like, okay, you're in the yellow room in the green room Yeah, but Super Metroid.
Speaker 1: It's like oh you're in Norfair in the lava zone now now you're in the plant zone.
Speaker 1: It's like making the different areas feel like different interesting areas Memorable landmarks and interactive bits and just interesting eye candy and all sorts of flavor.
Speaker 1: You know that that is what makes these games, you know That's what.
Speaker 1: that's what encourages you to keep exploring and going and you know Not getting bored when you go back to the same place.
Speaker 1: and they definitely did a good job.
Speaker 0: So the takeaways from this game one is great like just get it and play it like it's great But - Sometimes you need that like you need the talent like the person who knows how to make this game and happen to be Igarashi Yep, like that's the magic sauce.
Speaker 1: I'm so in terms of negative things, right?
Speaker 1: I got to say I'm not a fan of the controls for the map, right?
Speaker 1: So you can.
Speaker 1: actually there's one good thing which is that the the mini-map in the corner shows you where you came from.
Speaker 1: Oh, not only that.
Speaker 1: you can customize the fuck out of the mini-map.
Speaker 1: Yes, you can make it bigger.
Speaker 1: You can make it smaller.
Speaker 1: You can zoom it in.
Speaker 1: You can zoom it out.
Speaker 1: You can make it transparent.
Speaker 1: You can make it opaque.
Speaker 1: You can do all sorts of crazy stuff.
Speaker 1: That is awesome.
Speaker 1: The actual map.
Speaker 1: you press like the select key.
Speaker 1: you bring up the actual map.
Speaker 1: it zoomed the fuck out right.
Speaker 1: by default.
Speaker 1: You got to press a to center it on yourself.
Speaker 1: It doesn't default to centering on where you are.
Speaker 1: That's annoying.
Speaker 1: and then you got to zoom your ass in.
Speaker 1: It's like the main the.
Speaker 1: if I press select to open the big map It should start centered on me already zoomed at a reasonable level.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's really kind of annoying.
Speaker 1: I had to do that.
Speaker 0: I got used to it But it was.
Speaker 0: it wasn't ideal and it works.
Speaker 1: if you open up the big map you press select to open it Right.
Speaker 1: My natural inclination is to press B to close it.
Speaker 1: No if you press B, it puts like a marker on the map.
Speaker 1: It's like a fuck.
Speaker 1: and then you like you have a marker on the map.
Speaker 1: now You have to move the cursor exactly onto that marker to press B to remove it.
Speaker 1: Then you got to remember you press select again to close.
Speaker 1: Yeah It's like I keep putting markers all over my map.
Speaker 0: I am still putting markers on the map Unintentionally.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so it's like that is really annoying.
Speaker 1: They need to fix the can.
Speaker 1: that is something that applies to not not just the switch version all the version.
Speaker 0: I saw some people complaining that they thought the controls were sluggish, but I think they are which I don't know If it's just the switch or not.
Speaker 1: But yeah, it is love it's like it.
Speaker 0: the.
Speaker 0: the fighting like attacking feels right.
Speaker 1: jumping depends on the weapon.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I mean some weapons are slow on purpose.
Speaker 0: The jumping feels like a Like a fraction of a millisecond too slow.
Speaker 0: But other Castlevania games have had far worse problems with their control.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but at the point of sympathy tonight has no flaw and these in the control department It is, you know flawless.
Speaker 0: It feels like the difference between Mario 3 and Mario world like how jumping works between the two.
Speaker 0: This feels more like Mario world and Symphony of the night felt more like Mario 3.
Speaker 0: That is how granted I have not played symphony tonight in like six years Symphony night controls are ridiculously tight.
Speaker 0: I should play symphony the night again.
Speaker 0: It's been a while.
Speaker 1: if you did that you might come back to this and be like, uh, why am I in jail?
Speaker 1: Why is going on?
Speaker 1: Oh, no.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think it'll just be a mario 3 mario world situation.
Speaker 1: See, I'm only like according to the percentages in the game.
Speaker 1: I'm only 60 something percent done with the game out of what?
Speaker 1: I don't know what percent that's out of so we're gonna see.
Speaker 0: but the other takeaway I think from this game
Speaker 1: it is not short like you are not gonna be disappointed from the game being too small
Speaker 0: if You're gonna take a classic genre that you feel like just needed more and you're gonna try to do the bloodstain Treatment to it.
Speaker 0: You've gotta spend all your time Polishing it.
Speaker 1: you did you got it, you know do what made the original one great.
Speaker 1: There are a lot of other indie and non indie metroidvanias out and about that.
Speaker 1: people have tried to make in You know in between but they're all just kind like they're very Satisfying.
Speaker 1: one that was a dude who's like a gun dude who sneaks into a base, right?
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah Yeah, that was what it was called.
Speaker 0: and the game of cube, right?
Speaker 1: No, I played on an Xbox, but I don't know what it's available on.
Speaker 1: But the point is that game was actually great in so many ways.
Speaker 1: But the problem with it is it was just too small.
Speaker 1: It was really small map and you finished it and then you were done.
Speaker 1: if they would have made that game bigger like ten times As big it would have been an all-time great game.
Speaker 1: Now.
Speaker 1: It's a shadow complex.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's the one.
Speaker 1: that's the one.
Speaker 1: Then there's games like Hollow Knight, which a lot of people are huge fans of and I get you know It is Metroidvania, but personally it's not.
Speaker 1: it's not in anything like Super Metroid or Castlevania And I was not into it as much as all these other people who love it.
Speaker 1: I couldn't play it too far at all.
Speaker 1: yeah, and you know it also I think part of its problem it focused a lot more on like being difficult and having bad guys that Were like hard to deal with and they kept killing me.
Speaker 1: and it's like that's not what these games are about, right?
Speaker 0: So I guess take that to heart if you if there's a kind of game Like me with Advance Wars that you feel like just needs to be remade polish and really understanding what specifically about that game you wanted more of.
Speaker 0: Very few people can truly figure that out, right?
Speaker 1: And I think you know, it's like if you're in a genre that has been overdone like say FPS That's when you need to mix things up and go your own way and show some new flavor and creativity.
Speaker 1: If you're not right make something crazy, but if it's an underserved genre Like Metroidvania, you should literally just copy from the steal from the forgotten masters Make the same fucking thing and just change what you got to change.
Speaker 0: You don't get sued Yep, right and then just take that and make more of it.
Speaker 1: Yep, you know, it's like all these people made adventure games.
Speaker 1: now They're out of business telltale of it, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, but it's like you should have just fucking directly cut.
Speaker 1: did exactly Lucas arts adventure games just more of them.
Speaker 1: You shouldn't have done your own thing.
Speaker 0: Well, there were.
Speaker 0: Well, there are other factors with them many.
Speaker 1: I feel like you get the idea.
Speaker 0: I feel like a studio will reemerge to make those kinds of games.
Speaker 1: Yes, and they should just make Lucas arts adventure games.
Speaker 1: literally.
Speaker 1: they should look like they were made in the 90s.
Speaker 1: Yeah, same stupid mechanics of nonsense garbage.
Speaker 1: Just new ones.
Speaker 0: No, I would go the other route.
Speaker 1: I'd make them more like just straight-up visual novels and not even pretend well, but then that's not that's not really that's a different thing It is.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but they were trying to straddle a line between like narrative branching choices versus puzzle-solving.
Speaker 1: Yeah, anyway Play you're playing too much attention to my specific example.
Speaker 1: Okay, if you want to make a platformer just make a fucking Mario just not Mario like.
Speaker 0: look super meat boy.
Speaker 0: as an example super meat boy took SMB and just polished it down to this little made it smaller this little.
Speaker 1: I was watching a Mario maker on twitch a Mario maker player on twitch like last week.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well not watching twitch, you know right now obviously.
Speaker 1: But and they were in a level that was basically it was just super meat boy.
Speaker 1: They were doing wall jumps in between chainsaws and I was like, well, that's super meat boy.
Speaker 0: Yeah This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Speaker 1: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 0: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 1: But unlike those other late shows It's actually recorded at night.
Speaker 0: and the patreon patrons for this episode of geek nights.
Speaker 0: Ah Craig Oliver, Ellen Joyce, how do we nickel just like a dude guy?
Speaker 0: He's our television link.
Speaker 0: eg Graham Finch Jennifer Hitchcock Chris midkiff my state calm j-band scootalonely Shawn Yeager Nicholas Brando Mr.
Speaker 0: Strong distraction for two more creations.
Speaker 0: and there may be other secret names You do not even know.
Speaker 0: Jordan Munhall Rory Superboy Clinton Walton ran from New Zealand Rhine parents ropenlander Finn dread lily tenebrae Shawn Klein Chris Reimer Thomas Hahn.
Speaker 0: check out our second episode of Raymond Emily talking about Disney theatrical animation.
Speaker 0: and
Speaker 1: now
Speaker 0: I leave you with
Speaker 1: Ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha bah bah
Speaker 0: bah bah
Speaker 1: bah bah bah bah bah bah bah bah BAH BAH BAH
Speaker 0: BAH BAH BAH BAH BAH lu ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ba ba ba ba
Speaker 1: ba ba ba ba
Speaker 0: ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba
Speaker 1: ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba
Speaker 0: ba
Speaker 1: ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba
Speaker 0: ba ba ba
Speaker 1: ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba.