Speaker 0: It's Tuesday November 5th 2019.
Speaker 0: I'm rim.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott and this is geek nights.
Speaker 0: tonight We are talking about the untitled goose game.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: So it was finally time to buy a new laptop.
Speaker 0: my plan for my laptop to last a decade Totally worked.
Speaker 0: I bought a fancy laptop a decade ago, and it's on its last goddamn legs.
Speaker 1: I just switched iPad and I only use my laptop in like emergency situations when I need it and so works.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I actually do use laptops.
Speaker 1: I might put some Linux on it instead of the windows.
Speaker 1: That's on it though Because it's kind of sad.
Speaker 1: I mean you try to turn it on and it's like oh really you're turning me on.
Speaker 0: My laptop is falling.
Speaker 0: it boots quick battery still lasts like three or four hours unless I'm playing games with it.
Speaker 0: Then it lasts like an hour now because the battery is ten years old.
Speaker 0: the main problems with it Were that one.
Speaker 0: the battery is held in with tape.
Speaker 0: I recently replaced that tape because the tape gave way the other day, and I lost some work.
Speaker 0: I was working on and the screen resolution By modern standards is basically like 40p.
Speaker 0: It's like 1366 by whatever.
Speaker 0: that stupid form factor is only five peas not many peas.
Speaker 0: So I got a laptop that has a lot of peas.
Speaker 0: Even a crappy laptop you buy today has mad P Yep, but the other day don't forget a decade ago that Lenovo was a top-of-the-line laptop.
Speaker 1: Yeah, a long-ass time.
Speaker 0: That's Hane years ago.
Speaker 1: What the hell year did I even get mine in?
Speaker 0: I know I got mine in 2009 because I remember very specifically planning even talked about on gig night.
Speaker 0: So this is gonna be a 10-year laptop because I spent like four fucking thousand dollars on it.
Speaker 1: I didn't spend that much.
Speaker 1: Let me look up.
Speaker 0: I mean that laptop.
Speaker 0: I bought a core i7 on a laptop back before direct sales in 2010.
Speaker 1: I think this is it.
Speaker 0: I mean that laptop had a fancy SSD that was very high capacity.
Speaker 0: Before SSDs were default standard on every laptop.
Speaker 1: like yeah, I guess I bought the laptop in 2010.
Speaker 0: yeah Yeah, this must be it Which works out because the previous laptop I bought was the Fujitsu life book.
Speaker 0: I do not buy laptops many often very often.
Speaker 0: I think this is my third laptop because I continue to buy extremely expensive laptops and use them for goddamn ever.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I guess I bought the Fujitsu in beacons like 2005.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and that lasted five years.
Speaker 1: in 2010 I bought the Lenovo and then I bought the iPad.
Speaker 1: a few years ago I don't know when did I buy that stupid iPad?
Speaker 0: you've already had it for a few years now.
Speaker 1: This is actually the second I've had.
Speaker 0: yeah Well, it's actually I had a mini iPad and then the pro iPad and then the even pro where I've had yeah, but I did something different because My plan was to buy a surface book 3 because Microsoft is really bad at naming things.
Speaker 0: So the so yeah, bro is the less powerful Tablety one.
Speaker 0: but the surface laptop is also not that powerful It's just a normal laptop.
Speaker 0: and then the surface book is actually the crazy powerful desktop replacement one and Also a tablet.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: That's the one that has a fucking like real video chip in it.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm like a gtx-6.
Speaker 0: 1060 is what's in there?
Speaker 1: No, it's like some mobile version.
Speaker 0: No, it's a it's what do you mean?
Speaker 0: a mobile version?
Speaker 0: That would be the 1050.
Speaker 0: This is the 1060.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they make a lot of things have the same number, but it's not actually the same.
Speaker 0: Benchmark wise benchmarks the same as 1060 with the caveat that it cannot overclock itself because it cannot cool itself.
Speaker 0: that well Because it's in a laptop.
Speaker 0: but I got the laptop as opposed to the book partly because I Really need a new laptop.
Speaker 0: The old one's not doing it for me, but to As much as I wanted to get a laptop that's crazy powerful like I always have.
Speaker 0: like I could render video on this if I need to I Have never actually needed for like five years now to edit Serious video on the go.
Speaker 0: it can always wait till I get home.
Speaker 0: So this laptop can edit video enough on the go.
Speaker 0: So I saved myself like a thousand dollars by getting a normal laptop Instead of a laptop that could be a full desktop workstation replacement.
Speaker 0: Weirdly prudent of me in the laptop department.
Speaker 0: Another Opening news or opening bits.
Speaker 0: the election just happened.
Speaker 1: No, it didn't finish it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's happening.
Speaker 0: I forget when the polls closed because New York has early voting now.
Speaker 0: I voted over the weekend like a pro.
Speaker 0: You do you vote really?
Speaker 0: I forget.
Speaker 1: Oh, I didn't need to vote early.
Speaker 1: I had to go farther away.
Speaker 1: So I voted this morning.
Speaker 0: See we could vote at the Museum of the Moving Image, which is like yeah That could have voted there also for us.
Speaker 0: That's not really further away than our regular polling place.
Speaker 0: Hmm So, uh, we don't know the results the elections happening right now, but based on some tentative numbers.
Speaker 0: I saw an interesting thing.
Speaker 0: I hope this is a real trend.
Speaker 0: Turnout appears to be really really really high like crazy high.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Well people, you know, we're talking like 20 22 percent of voters.
Speaker 1: people are much more upset.
Speaker 1: They want to vote and now it's easier to vote with the early voting.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and this is an off-year election If you're not Americans every four years We have a quote-unquote real election meaning like presidents and shit get voted for.
Speaker 0: That's every four years and like 40% of us vote in these things maybe 50%.
Speaker 0: Every other year we have a midterm election, which is like the middle of a president's term.
Speaker 1: That's because well, it's the House of Representatives.
Speaker 1: half of the Congress is out.
Speaker 1: It has to be elected every two years.
Speaker 0: You got to keep getting elected.
Speaker 1: so basically some some of them like people died or quit and stuff.
Speaker 1: So some of those elections, you know happen in the middle years, but most of them are Every two years.
Speaker 1: so you go to vote for a president and you vote for the house and then two years later It's like house only.
Speaker 1: Yep, and they usually like some senators and senators every fucking six years.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so it's like any year at random depending on where the hell you live.
Speaker 1: Oh, by the way one of your two senators, yep, and those are only the federal elections every state is different and then every town is different.
Speaker 0: Yep, and Then there's yet another kind of election the off-year election.
Speaker 0: most Americans barely know these exist and they don't vote in them Right.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean depending odd-numbered years every single leaf years like 2019 is an off.
Speaker 1: Well, every single thing we voted for just now today was New York City specific.
Speaker 1: Not there wasn't.
Speaker 1: there wasn't even a single New York State thing to vote on.
Speaker 1: So you could live in somewhere else in New York State and if there was nothing in your town Happening that year based on your town charter or whatever the fuck you live There's literally you would go.
Speaker 1: there would be nothing to vote on today.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there would be no just literally nothing Like judges.
Speaker 0: Yeah, usually it's judges.
Speaker 1: It depends where you live there But judges are really easy to vote for.
Speaker 0: just always vote for all Democrats and never anyone else under any circumstances.
Speaker 0: Like don't even look these people up doesn't matter.
Speaker 1: It depends.
Speaker 0: No, it doesn't depend any.
Speaker 1: what if you happen to know Let know that like in your town the crazy judge like got you know on to the distance Shenanigans and got on as a Democrat or you know, it's still better
Speaker 0: to vote for that than someone who's a Republican
Speaker 1: I mean, but they are Republican.
Speaker 1: They're just on the Democratic part of the ballot.
Speaker 0: Yeah Shenanigans, that's pretty rare at that level.
Speaker 1: It's actually surprisingly not rare.
Speaker 0: It's usually more that it doesn't matter because most of those judge elections are either unopposed or It's like vote for six and there are six Democrats and like one Republican and no one else is even running.
Speaker 0: Like there aren't options in those elections.
Speaker 0: Anyway, I hope you voted and New York City will be interesting because it's not in the voter.
Speaker 0: One of the things we got to vote on is whether or not our own city will do a form of ranked choice voting.
Speaker 1: It's IRV.
Speaker 1: so the thing is that mean it'll only apply to city election.
Speaker 1: So for mayor you'll be like this is my bet the best mayor the second best mayor the third best mayor and you can vote For as many as you want to like.
Speaker 1: I'll just pick one and if they don't win, I don't fucking care who wins.
Speaker 1: Oh, right But the thing is it'll.
Speaker 1: I think it'll be weird like we go to vote for mayor in two years And it's like well at the same time.
Speaker 0: Well, as he was not my first choice, but he'll be my second choice, but it's like well, he's not gonna be on the thing All right.
Speaker 1: Yeah, he's done.
Speaker 1: You're gonna go for Cory?
Speaker 1: probably yeah, so unless someone else appears.
Speaker 1: So the point is if the city things you're gonna be doing these rankings Right, and then if there's non city things you're gonna be doing regular.
Speaker 1: So it's like in the ballot would be mixed between ranking and not.
Speaker 1: okay.
Speaker 0: It'll be a little little messy Yep, but it might mean New York City has a better chances of putting actual progressives in power.
Speaker 1: No, I mean, you know even even with the old voting.
Speaker 1: Yeah, probably still gonna get covered.
Speaker 0: Yeah So, I don't think it'll matter too much But anyway, let's give them some gaming news because you guys don't care about this stuff that much even though you should.
Speaker 0: all things are Political.
Speaker 0: so, uh first and foremost, this is just really funny.
Speaker 0: This is like what does Scott say in the discord the most geek nights news, right?
Speaker 1: So there was a fortnight tournament and the fortnight tournament.
Speaker 1: I don't know the structure of a fortnight tournament, whatever It doesn't matter play your fortnight, right?
Speaker 1: This was a third party tournament So it wasn't run by epic, but it was run by a legit organization with real prizes.
Speaker 1: Yeah, really trying to keep shit together.
Speaker 1: the Vanish Cup, right and They have some sort of system I don't know the full details of Where there is some sort of support from epic for like running the tournament where there's like some codes and they give the codes To the participants.
Speaker 1: so to it's like matchmake only the tournament participants.
Speaker 1: So no one can like.
Speaker 1: no public people can like sneak into the games.
Speaker 1: Right, you know, it's basically the equivalent of like passwords and the counter-strike server kind of thing.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but there's a matchmaking involved to some kind.
Speaker 0: now It's cool because that means you there can be tournaments like eSports usually like there's physical concerns and all this nonsense.
Speaker 0: But this kind of tournament anyone who qualifies right can compete from anywhere in the world.
Speaker 1: Right now the thing is these kinds of third-party tournaments happen in all sorts of video games competitive video games with Limited or no support from the actual game company and usually this third-party software Yeah, all sorts of ramshackle duct tape solutions.
Speaker 0: I remember competing in Quake tournaments where like legit Someone would call you on the phone and tell you an IP address to connect to.
Speaker 1: right.
Speaker 1: There's a lot of tournaments where it's like, you know befriend, you know It's like.
Speaker 1: they'll send you like the steam ID or you know Basically the ID of the person you have to play against.
Speaker 1: Yeah Connect you friend them and connect to them and play them and then both of you report your results to the tournament organizer.
Speaker 1: I won right?
Speaker 1: Yeah Yeah, or send you know stream or you know, but you can't.
Speaker 0: if they're clever They'll have like saw judge whose job is to like spectate in your game like depends on the game.
Speaker 1: Yeah Anyway, stuff like that.
Speaker 1: So the point is for this particular fortnight tournament Some people who knows we don't know even three people right Decided to grief the fuck out of the tournament.
Speaker 1: They they had the code so they must have either gotten the codes from players or where
Speaker 0: it was them
Speaker 1: or was them with different accounts that were anonymous and they went into the game as a team and basically like Spammed and shot rockets everywhere and grief the hell out of everybody.
Speaker 0: They like back-to-back and just teamed up and fucked everybody over, right?
Speaker 1: It would be like if you know we've had a counter-attack tournament and then we just like Join and like start a team killing and nobody could get a game going on.
Speaker 1: That was legit.
Speaker 1: So rather that they couldn't do anything about these griefers because they don't have enough.
Speaker 1: It's all you know, they don't have enough support from epic.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right, so they just had to cancel their whole fucking tournament.
Speaker 1: We just go, you know, it goes back to a general point I want to make again and again until someone fucking gets it right is basically There's no video game out there competitive multiplayer game even in 2019. there's basically none that has full real tournaments organized tournament support in game.
Speaker 1: Right, that is perfect and complete such to the point where you won't even need third-party tournament organizers.
Speaker 1: People should be able to open the game.
Speaker 0: I should be able to go to overwatch.
Speaker 1: Real people right.
Speaker 1: join a real legit organized tournament and the game takes care of everything for you And you can customize the formats and do all these these really basic things.
Speaker 1: make sure people show up and force the rules Right.
Speaker 1: make sure right.
Speaker 1: nobody.
Speaker 1: zero games that I'm aware of have built this thing.
Speaker 0: I feel like a game that you can build.
Speaker 0: that right, right?
Speaker 1: I feel like you could build a really simple game Right, like a really man kind of game not just something good enough and then just build a really strong tournament system and people would play it just because.
Speaker 1: Wow, I can play real legit competitive tournaments in this thing.
Speaker 1: Right, like you go to say you've met your local game store and you go for like Friday night magic or whatever And that tournament is better organized than any video game has tournament
Speaker 0: Unless it's video game tournaments run by the companies that make the games Because they use the kinds of like internal tools that players don't have access to or they're
Speaker 1: usually in physical spaces.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they're just controlling everything.
Speaker 0: They do things like make a special build of the game.
Speaker 0: That's only for the tournament.
Speaker 0: Yes, like developers are like hacking stuff together all sorts of not usually when it's in person.
Speaker 1: You just don't have to worry about so many of the concerns you have with the online turn But there's something else going on.
Speaker 0: You don't need the tooling.
Speaker 0: I think it's very easy to explain why this happened in this particular tournament.
Speaker 0: The prize pool for this tournament was a total of three thousand dollars.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so the odds of winning any reasonable out of money are pretty low.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you have to be basically in first place to win any written, you know meaningful amount of money, but
Speaker 0: If you just assume you're not gonna win money from this tournament anyway Griefing a tournament that's being live streamed on such a scale the
Speaker 1: amount of really
Speaker 0: funny
Speaker 1: the amount of fun You would get from that is worth more than the prize that winning
Speaker 0: like My utility.
Speaker 0: if I was in this game if I was part of that that crew.
Speaker 1: also the culture of fortnight the game doesn't help.
Speaker 0: Yeah, cuz the culture of fortnight is just jump around hitting people with a dildo.
Speaker 1: It's not a super serious game Right a super serious game.
Speaker 1: the griefing would have been met with much different, you know, right like if it was pub G.
Speaker 0: I feel like the griefing would have been met with other players.
Speaker 0: Here's all summing up to get rid of the reefers.
Speaker 0: Here's all someone has to do.
Speaker 1: make a game.
Speaker 1: It doesn't matter what fucking game it is.
Speaker 1: It has to have just as long as it's some amount of skill in the game doesn't have to be a full skill game.
Speaker 1: it could even be a mostly random game.
Speaker 1: right and Make a system where people create a tournament right enter the tournament possibly even with an entry fee could be like a dollar $10 whatever.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right you the game maker take a cut of the total entry fees, right?
Speaker 1: So let's say it's a $10 entry fee 10 players in the tournament.
Speaker 1: So maybe they could make the poker casino and write the big you take a dollar Right as the cost to start to launch a tournament.
Speaker 1: Everyone pays a dollar to join a tournament, right?
Speaker 1: The winner of the tournament gets the $10.
Speaker 1: what something simple like that is the problem.
Speaker 0: I feel like the governments of the world would regulate and be mad about that.
Speaker 0: It's a skill based game.
Speaker 0: Like you can't fight with gambling I feel like they might just pass laws and crack down on that because they care way more about that kind of thing.
Speaker 0: Then they care about.
Speaker 1: I mean Belgium.
Speaker 1: Belgium would wisely but I think is I actually have no problem with that.
Speaker 0: It's like Perception wise.
Speaker 0: they go after that problem.
Speaker 0: They would go after this loot crate bullshit.
Speaker 0: That's the actual problem.
Speaker 1: Some places are going after the loot crate bullshit.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but it's like it's like you.
Speaker 1: look at magic cards.
Speaker 1: I have a problem with paying for a pack of cards with random shit.
Speaker 1: That's the gambling part the playing magic and whoever wins the magic tournament gets a prize.
Speaker 1: I have no problem with that.
Speaker 1: That's a skill bait.
Speaker 1: most at least, you know, there's.
Speaker 1: everyone has the same cards.
Speaker 1: You know netrunner tournaments a better example, but it's like you play the game and whoever wins gets the prize.
Speaker 1: That's totally fair.
Speaker 1: As long as it's you know, not some bullshit game Right.
Speaker 1: So it's like I actually am okay with.
Speaker 1: Everyone puts in a dollar the game company keeps all the dollars and whoever wins the tournament gets ten dollars worth of loot.
Speaker 0: So I had friends who made a lot of money doing that in middle school with magic tournaments.
Speaker 0: They were just put flyers all around the school like hey magic tournament on Saturday this kid's house $10 entry fee.
Speaker 1: but that's what game stores do.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and it's like no.
Speaker 1: video game Digital the online multiplayer game of any genre has implemented that local game store tournament mechanism Digitally such that that kind of tournament could just happen all day long Constantly even for no money.
Speaker 1: money or not, right?
Speaker 1: There is none that do this.
Speaker 1: do it now.
Speaker 1: So shit like this can stop happening.
Speaker 1: What is taking so long?
Speaker 0: what I'm also kind of waiting for is we have not seen like an ultimate Griefing moment in a bigger eSports tournament because the bigger eSports tournaments are all in person.
Speaker 1: once you get big enough It's suddenly in person and not online anymore.
Speaker 1: Right all in all and even like the serious online ones have a lot more controls in place.
Speaker 1: So, you know unless you have a the equivalent of like the basketball player just like hold off and punch someone These are tournaments that like the you know are not like, you know, they're like small things off.
Speaker 1: There's like minor league baseball like you would never see it.
Speaker 1: It's happening somewhere else.
Speaker 1: unless you know where to look for it in your inside on it You would even never even know it's happening.
Speaker 0: So now the vanish cup like officials are trying to figure out who actually were like the griefers were.
Speaker 0: good luck.
Speaker 0: Yeah, what do you?
Speaker 0: they're definitely behind seven proxies and they have to go work with the fortnight people to get any data.
Speaker 0: Yep Let's see, duh-duh-duh Extremely like setting everyone's excited.
Speaker 0: the impression I get though looking at like people talking about this is Other than some people who really cared about the tournament in the game people seem to find this more funny than annoying.
Speaker 1: Of course That's the point.
Speaker 1: really fun.
Speaker 1: That's the point.
Speaker 1: That's the news.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: I Like online tournaments even with controls.
Speaker 0: if the prize pool is low enough You're just gonna see.
Speaker 0: people call like stern shit up.
Speaker 1: and well sure but at least that's within the context of the tournament, right?
Speaker 1: I bring my wacky deck to the magic tournament.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and I just do stupid shit and lose every game.
Speaker 1: It's like, okay Well now you're eliminated right?
Speaker 1: Oh, you can't just go fucking with it.
Speaker 1: You know, you know, I guess the local game store you could go.
Speaker 0: well, you can look at someone else's table Illustrates.
Speaker 1: no, you wouldn't be able to have a proper digital tournament.
Speaker 0: What if your shtick is just to be so annoying that the other player flips the table?
Speaker 0: or more importantly?
Speaker 0: This brings in a game theory thing because fortnight having more than two players and not being a race is Inherently political.
Speaker 0: it is capital P game theory.
Speaker 1: political it is.
Speaker 1: I mean I was talking generally about all games and not about the problems of any particular game because to talk about any particular game Yeah, we would go down a rabbit hole so deep.
Speaker 1: Yeah, okay, right and that's why I will not have the discussion.
Speaker 0: Some other news Blizzard among other things Those Blizzcon it happened.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the usual the hot expected Hong Kong protest also happened.
Speaker 1: Yep at the start of Blizzcon They apologized without actually mentioning Hong Kong.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you didn't read the news about this, which I assume you have if you care?
Speaker 1: Yeah, right They won't unban the hearthstone guy.
Speaker 0: He said they fucked up, but they won't unban the guy Because China is too important to Activision Blizzard.
Speaker 1: right and the tencent that company owns like six percent of black division blizzard for the first time a non-dude one The major eSports thing the great real exciting grand master of hearthstone does not have a penis which is kind of awesome.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'm actually really excited about that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's good, but Overwatch 2 is the news.
Speaker 0: that's really interesting.
Speaker 1: Diablo 4 they're making a Diablo to make a bunch of money yeah, and Oh hearthstone is getting like a movum like some kind of Auto chess mode, but it's hearthstone.
Speaker 1: I don't know what the fuck's up with that.
Speaker 1: I'm done with that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I've not played an auto chess in a while
Speaker 1: But rim wants to talk about his overwatch - the most
Speaker 0: because what what overwatch - is is actually really interesting Because no one's quite sure
Speaker 1: Watch is a game where there are loot boxes you can buy but mostly you truly cosmetic don't do any right.
Speaker 1: mostly you just pay For it once and that's it.
Speaker 1: So in order to make more money from people who don't buy loot boxes They have to make like an like, you know The World of Warcraft model where there's expansions that they charge more or entirely new games that they charge money for now.
Speaker 0: No, because another way to make money off of it is it's the e-sport.
Speaker 1: How do you make money off the e-sport?
Speaker 0: with the advertising and the sponsorship, right?
Speaker 1: I'm saying to make money from the players unless they're buying Maybe the players other than that initial payment.
Speaker 0: They have to make to play the game.
Speaker 0: That's just to make sure there is a community.
Speaker 0: It's almost like making sure the minor leagues exist so you can have the major league.
Speaker 1: Sure Sure, but there's a strategy there.
Speaker 1: I find the point is they want to make money from the consumers.
Speaker 1: They had to make another overwatch or overwatch expansion and charge money for it.
Speaker 1: So they're making overwatch - well Yeah, cuz there's a little bit of money for overwatch - overwatch in general.
Speaker 1: Can you buy overwatch - without buying overwatch one?
Speaker 0: So overwatch in general has a - the problem it has is the problem that all Truly skill based competitive games that are serious have.
Speaker 1: Even regardless of skill cap.
Speaker 0: Yep Most people suck at these games and get really mad when they continue to suck at them and the player base Falls off and you end up having like all the problems that all competitive games have had for all time.
Speaker 1: Well also competitive or not all games for all time have player.
Speaker 1: They start off big and people they players fall off over time Sometimes except counter-strike which somehow just continued to grow for a long long long long time Counter-strike strategy was.
Speaker 1: this is why I'm bringing this up.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they kept releasing more counter-strikes.
Speaker 1: And here you go overwatch is now released.
Speaker 1: This is basically CS source only overwatch source.
Speaker 0: Here's something else overwatch Many many of the people.
Speaker 0: this is now my opinion as opposed to like anything.
Speaker 0: an analyst has done detailed analysis On a lot of the people who like to play overwatch or we're into overwatch when it first came out.
Speaker 0: We're into it for a lot of reasons other than being super serious competitive.
Speaker 0: Of course.
Speaker 1: That's why there's arcade modes.
Speaker 1: That's why counter-strike has like no these other modes.
Speaker 0: They don't even like the arcade modes because they're still competitive.
Speaker 0: These are people just like casual modes.
Speaker 0: I know you Most of the arcade modes are still competitive.
Speaker 0: Uh-huh, like as in you're competing with other players, even if it's not ranked.
Speaker 0: Okay, people don't even like that.
Speaker 0: a lot of the people Seriously care about the character lore and the story and all this shit that is literally just there For like for the game to exist.
Speaker 0: but Those people are now not playing overwatch anymore because that's what they cared about and it seems like the thing that started to get those People to come back to overwatch was adding these entirely non-competitive purely cooperative PV emotes.
Speaker 0: Like people love those things Yeah And they want like cutscenes and leveling up characters and all that shit that I literally like.
Speaker 0: the thing It's completely different game.
Speaker 1: It just happens to be on the same engine the same platform the same piece of software.
Speaker 1: You just put lot, you know modes that are effectively completely different.
Speaker 1: They just use the same models or environments or whatever.
Speaker 0: But what's fascinating about this is that appeal to different.
Speaker 1: that way you can have a game that services everybody.
Speaker 1: the world of warcraft had PvP PvE You know do all kinds of stuff.
Speaker 1: It's neither ERP.
Speaker 1: Yeah go you can do on raids You can you know, you make lots and lots of different ways for people to play.
Speaker 1: You know, you have this one piece of software.
Speaker 1: you chart you've run on one platform Yeah and you just Make it so that it has so many different nets to catch so many different kinds of people because it's a lot cheaper than Making a different game for every different kind of person.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: So this gets back to remember.
Speaker 0: way back We talked about how fortnight had to make the game less competitive in order to keep the majority of their players.
Speaker 0: Yep, and they get like they completely gave up on the professional scene entire, right?
Speaker 1: That was what they had the rule in fortnight where killing people would get you loot So people would actually try to kill each other.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and then people didn't like that.
Speaker 1: So they got rid of it.
Speaker 0: So What overwatch is basically doing now is overwatch - it seems like all the things that are actually Competitive in overwatch - we'll also make it back into overwatch.
Speaker 0: one like the new modes and everything and all overwatch - seems to be is a Player versus environment mode that can be single-player or co-op where you fucking level your character up like an action RPG or a loot shooter and Do like co-op missions to unlock story.
Speaker 1: Yeah, ah I mean that's not gonna have anything to do with like overwatch league.
Speaker 0: Nope.
Speaker 0: Oh, that's my only fear is that?
Speaker 1: no Kim There's.
Speaker 1: no you can't even have a league based around that game.
Speaker 0: My only fear is if PvE type mechanics not the leveling up or anything But like having mobs of like neutral things to fight and all that shit that I hate about mobas.
Speaker 0: That seems to be really popular the certain type of gamer.
Speaker 0: Well, there
Speaker 1: have been a lot of attempts to make an FPS That's also a MOBA basically and they've been have that varying success But none of them have achieved the hugeness, you know in popularity of any FPS like Counter-Strike Yeah, any MOBA like Dota or LoL or you know any any Fortnight or any.
Speaker 1: you know, they've all been like, you know middle-ish games all the ones that trying to do that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right.
Speaker 1: So I don't know if that game genre is of doing that because you think like oh, you know.
Speaker 1: Actually making a MOBA as an FPS game instead of an RTS But having the same map the same idea of trying to capture the base the same hiding in the woods Yeah as long as you you'd have to because it's an FPS you would have to add more about the shooting skills and You would have to take out some of those item.
Speaker 1: crazy business.
Speaker 1: I probably should.
Speaker 1: you don't have to you look at like People love that item.
Speaker 0: bullshit though.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well pub G has it right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, right, but You know, you couldn't make it any more complicated than pub G has.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right That could be a good game that I might even want to play maybe but no one's made one.
Speaker 1: That's really taken off and killed.
Speaker 1: so I don't know if it the idea itself is not popular or if no one's just made a Good one yet.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: So based on it could they could make a good overwatch one if they you know They could or no one can and I feel they can't make one.
Speaker 1: No one can.
Speaker 0: this will be a test to see how far they can push that side of overwatch while still having competitive game.
Speaker 0: So it is best I can tell The kinds of people I don't play games with will all buy overwatch 2 and I will not because everything that's being added to overwatch 2 that I care about will also be an overwatch 1. overwatch 1 will basically be action quake weapons factories serious competitive asymmetric FPS game.
Speaker 1: They're not gonna add new characters and stuff and over.
Speaker 0: so you open an overwatch to watch to new characters and modes will also go.
Speaker 1: So there were basically.
Speaker 1: so overwatch 2 is literally not a new a different game.
Speaker 1: It's literally just modes.
Speaker 0: It seems like it's just the PvE mode.
Speaker 0: It seems like it's better graphics Slightly different art effectively.
Speaker 0: I don't know if it's actually better.
Speaker 0: So if you stick with overwatch 1 seems like I'll can you play again?
Speaker 1: So let's say I open over.
Speaker 1: yes same pool of if you play competitive mode same game But the game will just look worse as far as I can tell and you'll have everything else.
Speaker 0: Yep It seems like overwatch 2 is just get the people who care about it's like the only thing.
Speaker 0: you're fine.
Speaker 0: They want to know who is McCree fucking.
Speaker 0: is it Reaper?
Speaker 1: Is it may know the only thing you're buying when you buy over finding out who's fucking her and play our game modes?
Speaker 1: Well and and graphics improve game modes.
Speaker 0: that include all the stuff I hate about games like Borderlands coupled with all the lore and backstory stuff that I also don't care about.
Speaker 1: Okay, and you can watch on YouTube.
Speaker 0: Yes, which I probably will.
Speaker 1: so I Thought you didn't care about it.
Speaker 0: Well, I mean, I'll watch it because those things are interesting But I'm not willing to play a game to find that stuff out.
Speaker 0: the thing I hate more than anything in a game is To click on things to get walls of text and backstory and lore like that is the least interesting.
Speaker 1: There probably won't be a while.
Speaker 1: It's extra probably like, you know cinematic stuff.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: But it seems like one of the specific complaints the people who stopped playing overwatch one had is that the story was only from the Cinematics.
Speaker 0: they want the story to be in the game Half-life style.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm, which is weird.
Speaker 1: life is way back.
Speaker 1: Cinematics are garbage.
Speaker 1: I think if you're gonna make cinematics Why are you and making video games?
Speaker 1: go make movies?
Speaker 1: I've always said that.
Speaker 1: Yep So I think you have life too and have life.
Speaker 1: one were like a revelation in like.
Speaker 1: hey You're telling a story with your fucking video game.
Speaker 1: You're not like cutting away and showing a movie.
Speaker 0: Well except half-life 2 at many points locks you in a room with people talking at you for five minutes.
Speaker 1: Yes, but you can walk around and mess with stuff.
Speaker 1: Yeah It is a little bit hackneyed, but they still.
Speaker 1: well that game is also ancient Yes, but I mean the thing is at the time of half-life 1 there was no, you know Even though they lock you in a room also No other game did it that way?
Speaker 1: Yeah, right.
Speaker 1: It was.
Speaker 1: it was no game and so half-life 2 is just doing a half like one did.
Speaker 0: so TLDL version of this overwatch 2 is probably a really smart move for Blizzard and it is not a game that I am in any Interested in playing.
Speaker 0: but I think it'll do well and I think it'll make more money.
Speaker 1: I mean remember about you know, how many counter-strike mods were something along those lines?
Speaker 0: You know, well all the people who would play that Wow mod of counter-strike.
Speaker 0: That was literally just garbage.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but it was garbage.
Speaker 0: You could level up over time Persistently and it was the Skinner box of level and shit.
Speaker 1: I think you can talk.
Speaker 1: we have talked since the beginning of time About how you know people would rather Improve a digital character with a Skinner box.
Speaker 1: that makes them feel like they're improving rather than actually improve their own human body.
Speaker 0: But anyway It's time for things of the day.
Speaker 0: So I'm actually a pretty big fan of horror fiction in general and I actually do really like creepypastas Yeah, and that kind of stuff, but this is pretty cool.
Speaker 1: This is a Pac-man, I like Pac-man.
Speaker 0: It's a ROM you can play.
Speaker 1: it's a real game Okay, but the game doesn't look like a legit pac-man to me.
Speaker 0: Well, cuz it's basically if pac-man were a creepypasta.
Speaker 0: It's like a horror version of pac-man.
Speaker 1: Pac-man's already a horror.
Speaker 1: There's ghosts chasing him.
Speaker 1: These are ways.
Speaker 0: These are way scarier ghosts Jerry.
Speaker 1: What's scarier than fucking Clyde coming up?
Speaker 1: Like, what's up?
Speaker 0: You know what?
Speaker 0: you already used all four power pills.
Speaker 1: So instead yeah, I'm gonna block you from getting that pretzel.
Speaker 0: instead of making a creepypasta That's just a wall of text of someone found a cursed cartridge of Super Mario World where Luigi's dead And you have to figure out the mystery and then you died in real life.
Speaker 0: It is just a ROM.
Speaker 0: that is a game you can play and that game you can play is a legit good Pac-man game.
Speaker 0: that is also a scary horror game.
Speaker 1: So instead of making a creepypasta Story they actually made the game from the creepypasta Environmental storytelling.
Speaker 0: the game itself is the scary story and it's also a game you can play And it's a cool mechanic where pac-man can only see what pac-man can fucking see.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm, like it looks it looks fun.
Speaker 0: Like it looks like it's worth plan.
Speaker 1: All right, it's just map memorization I think.
Speaker 0: well also you got to figure out because all the ghosts are crazy different and scary and do different things.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well, that's just gonna kill you.
Speaker 0: It looks way fun.
Speaker 1: It doesn't look as fun as pac-man CEDX.
Speaker 0: Uh, yeah, but pac-man CEDX is way more fun than the sequel.
Speaker 1: Sequel I think it just is a different way of thinking that doesn't match most human brains.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's why I'm not continuing to play.
Speaker 0: Anyway, what do you got?
Speaker 1: What was my thing of the day?
Speaker 0: Oh, right.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so there was this Christian rock band.
Speaker 1: What's the name of the band?
Speaker 1: skip around the video so I can remember prodigal prodigal.
Speaker 0: I fucking know prodigal.
Speaker 1: Anyway, oh my god.
Speaker 1: Okay sing a prodigal song.
Speaker 1: Uh, no, I just I've heard no prodigal song.
Speaker 0: I know, you know where I know prodigal from.
Speaker 0: in high school There was this one really annoying dude who was really into Christian rock And he brought up prodigal all the side all the time.
Speaker 0: and when we made this like we made this project for a class once in like French class and he Insisted on putting this specific prodigal song into our project anyway.
Speaker 1: So this Christian rock band rim claims to know named prodigal.
Speaker 1: they put out a vinyl album way back in the 80s I'm pretty sure was 80s and 1984. they knew about computers I guess somehow and they hired some dude at some computer place in Florida to write them a Commodore 64 Program that would display like a quote from Albert Einstein and a quote from Jesus.
Speaker 1: It was a really simple basic program like really short and it would just display these two quotes on the screen.
Speaker 1: and that was it.
Speaker 1: And if you don't know right?
Speaker 1: you back in those days in the early 80s, right?
Speaker 1: Especially in other countries in the u.s.
Speaker 1: The Commodore 64 and other computers, you know, we mostly went with floppy disks and cartridges And we didn't need to use cassette tapes, you know Some computers did but we sort of got past that whereas other other countries especially UK had a lot more cassette tape.
Speaker 1: Game just you know got game software distribution going on right where you basically encode the bits which is just as an analog signal.
Speaker 1: Yep, right, but the signal isn't like quadratic amplitude modulation.
Speaker 1: played the cassette tape.
Speaker 1: It sounded like how your modem sounds right?
Speaker 1: It's zeros and ones just in an analog signal and if you look at the analog signal on your oscilloscope It's like I'll look zeros and ones.
Speaker 1: right.
Speaker 1: there they are.
Speaker 1: And in fact, I'm like my apple 2gs.
Speaker 1: I have a trick I can do where You take pretty much anything that plays audio for example your phone, right?
Speaker 1: You take the headphone cable you plug it in the back of the Apple - right you go online Like a website and you can go on YouTube and you find like a video that has Software in the audio and just play the YouTube video real loud out your phone and into the Apple - and lo and behold You'll run the piece up, right?
Speaker 1: It works.
Speaker 1: You could just distribute Apple - software on YouTube or any or SoundCloud or whatever the fright.
Speaker 1: So here what they did is on prodigal's vinyl album on a hidden track in like the inside cuz in the middle of every vinyl There's like a runoff area where the needle goes to spin around forever after the out records done.
Speaker 1: So it doesn't go like into the middle of the.
Speaker 0: yeah, right?
Speaker 1: And some most record players had a thing that auto detected when the needle hit the runoff and would reset the needle back to the start.
Speaker 1: so you had to disable that in order to.
Speaker 1: If you had it not every record player had it but if your turntable had that you have to disable it so that the needle can go inside the runoff track.
Speaker 1: and There was a Commodore 64 program right there.
Speaker 1: So in this video, that is my thing of the day This guy shows the whole process of getting that, you know programs are run on a real Commodore 64.
Speaker 1: He I guess this person Honorably, but also stupidly takes the audio from the vinyl to a cassette to the Commodore.
Speaker 1: I'm like, bro Why don't you just make a digital recording and then play it from your computer into the Commodore?
Speaker 1: Why did you use the in-between of the cassette?
Speaker 1: That was obviously a pain in the ass.
Speaker 1: I get the authentic thing, but you could have saved a lot of hassle.
Speaker 1: Yeah Just going from vinyl to wave then from computer to come feels very much like the audio and like record.
Speaker 1: I old you to take an audio cable from your computer sound card into the input on the Commodore.
Speaker 1: You don't need to do the cassette tape thing But it works pretty awesome.
Speaker 0: So, yeah, yeah in the meta moment the game guys book club book will take a while.
Speaker 0: it's the tale of Genji.
Speaker 0: We're gonna do some checkpoint episodes along.
Speaker 1: It's a big-ass book.
Speaker 1: So we're gonna have some kind of strategy.
Speaker 0: I'm into it though.
Speaker 1: Genji's kind of a dick.
Speaker 1: That's the point.
Speaker 0: like Genji He sucks, but I feel like he might get better.
Speaker 0: Well, or maybe he won't.
Speaker 0: I'm not sure if he's gonna get better or not.
Speaker 1: You'll see all of Genji's life.
Speaker 0: I mean the katamani crystal went through a pretty good evolution, but I feel like a lot more is gonna happen here.
Speaker 0: Yeah Otherwise, we're gonna be live at packs unplugged in December then at mag fest in January right after New Year's then at Probably pack south and then right after that packs east and then not too long after that packs west again.
Speaker 1: life never Quite a while after that few months.
Speaker 0: Yeah before you know it all tickets are on sale for unplugged south and east.
Speaker 1: East actually only sat.
Speaker 1: east went on sale like I think a while ago.
Speaker 0: Yep May a couple weeks the not even Saturday is sold out but four days or not which Confirms something I've sort of suspected for a long time because double-check all the good hotels are completely sold out.
Speaker 0: so a Four-day badge is kind of worthless to most people because if you're not staying in a hotel next to the convention center Really sucks to go to packs More than one day.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right like if you live in say I don't know, Maine Right, you could wake up early drive to Boston pay for an expensive parking spot.
Speaker 1: Right go to packs all day even on Friday or Sunday or Thursday.
Speaker 1: Right, even if it's not Saturday, you got a full packs day get in your car drive home to Maine late at night, right?
Speaker 1: State New York, you could take 84 across right?
Speaker 0: That's how I used to go to like uber con and all those kinds.
Speaker 1: Jersey you can get to Boston right?
Speaker 1: I guess, you know DC might be a little far.
Speaker 1: you could take to a cellar trains.
Speaker 0: Yeah, man, also just there's a ton of people that live nearby that just want to go for a day.
Speaker 1: but if you have nowhere to stay any more than one day is Right, even worse.
Speaker 0: There are still hotels, but they're the ones that are way over by the hinds.
Speaker 1: You got to use those If you stay in a faraway hotel and use a shuttle bus never for a day.
Speaker 1: That's not a great pack experience.
Speaker 0: Also, it's interesting to watch how packs East other than like tabletop fucking clears out at dinnertime For all the reasons.
Speaker 0: we've talked about pecs East.
Speaker 1: Well, it doesn't hurt that the you know, the area It's not like if it was say in the hinds, of course, the building is a problem.
Speaker 1: But location you could go out immediately across the street eat on Newberry Street and walk right back into packs.
Speaker 1: Right same thing in you know in Seattle.
Speaker 1: It's like okay expo hall closed walk outside eat dinner.
Speaker 1: Yeah, go back in.
Speaker 1: I'm still right near packs.
Speaker 1: If you want to eat, it's like you gotta go far away waiting along the line by the time you're done eating.
Speaker 1: You're already far away.
Speaker 0: You'd rain because of the security.
Speaker 0: it takes forever to get back into packs, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean, you know late at night There's not gonna be late at night.
Speaker 0: everyone who saw this right in the morning and they just bailed.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but the security is just walk in late at night.
Speaker 1: but the point is To go back to packs versus go back to your hotel when after you've eaten dinner and left the expo hall is a kind of Hassle.
Speaker 1: you can just go.
Speaker 1: you rather just go back to your hotel room and sleep at that.
Speaker 0: Yeah There's also the thing that most people who want to go to any kind of nerd convention now like there's a set of people who want to go for the Whole weekend and make it a weekend long nerd experience which like us a lot like anime cons.
Speaker 0: Most people go to anime cons do that.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah most like tabletop cons Like.
Speaker 0: that's what people want to do mag fest.
Speaker 0: not many people go to mag fest for one day.
Speaker 1: No They should just actually sell only full badges.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but Paxes and Comic cons that have big expo halls.
Speaker 0: the number of people who want to go to these things just to see that expo hall is probably more than the number of people Who want to actually go to see the whole con.
Speaker 0: and this continual like pull between these two groups with very different?
Speaker 0: Desires from the conventions is continuing to be a problem and there's no good solution.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean the solution is I just have two different events.
Speaker 1: Yeah, or Let's say packs unplugged at the expo hall is like, all right, even if you go there for it You're not gonna be doing too much there because it's you know, it's tabletop, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah big on tabletop That's your main thing.
Speaker 1: The expo hall won't occupy you for that much time.
Speaker 1: Even Gen Con won't.
Speaker 1: it's like you're gonna spend your time playing games, right?
Speaker 1: If you're there for video games, then you might not spend your time playing games that are real packs Yep, and that's why you just go to expo and leave.
Speaker 0: This is why packs unplugged Increasingly other than pecs West cuz it's back to West.
Speaker 1: It's my favorite back.
Speaker 1: If only it wasn't in Philly.
Speaker 0: I know If it was anywhere, but Philly, I'd be a lot happier anyway.
Speaker 0: Anyway, let's get right into it.
Speaker 1: Untitled goose game.
Speaker 1: speaking of packs packs 2018, right?
Speaker 1: We're in this packs and suddenly everyone's going wild about this fucking goose game.
Speaker 1: We're like, what the hell is this?
Speaker 1: and we find out there's a game and they got a big-ass booth.
Speaker 1: the booth is there again this year in 2019 and Made by these developers that were sort of newish on the scene.
Speaker 1: house house or sorry is house house.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and the game is called untitled goose game.
Speaker 1: The game doesn't have a title, right?
Speaker 1: It's just you call it the untitled goose game because that's the way you refer to the game.
Speaker 1: that has no title But it is a game with no title.
Speaker 1: That is a goose game And it's a game where you are a goose 3d walk around real-time video.
Speaker 0: No, you are specifically a Horrible goose.
Speaker 1: Yes Here's horrible goose and you go around like honking flapping your wings and making people miserable stealing shit.
Speaker 1: No, any.
Speaker 1: and so that concept alone It's all we saw.
Speaker 1: all I saw of it was that and I was like that's a genius idea for a game.
Speaker 1: There's no game like it.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna buy that and play it.
Speaker 1: That's gonna be a thing.
Speaker 1: Yep Yeah, I could tell already it's it.
Speaker 1: as soon as they showed it at packs It was a thing and I'm like that's gonna be a thing.
Speaker 1: and just like a week ago.
Speaker 1: Maybe it came out For a while as it.
Speaker 1: how long's it been out?
Speaker 0: a while?
Speaker 0: you just didn't play now.
Speaker 1: When did it actually came out recently?
Speaker 0: I mean we've been.
Speaker 0: I play beat it a while ago.
Speaker 0: I even tweeted about it.
Speaker 1: wasn't as long ago as you think.
Speaker 1: this game came out super recently.
Speaker 0: it came out in September.
Speaker 0: Oh, wow.
Speaker 0: Okay, Scott.
Speaker 0: Come on.
Speaker 0: Well, I beat it Moldels every Tuesday show.
Speaker 0: I was like, did you play the goose game yet so we can do a show on it?
Speaker 0: You kept saying no.
Speaker 0: Well, I'd have the record and this I was beating.
Speaker 0: I beat like this awakening again.
Speaker 0: We'll probably talk about.
Speaker 1: you had never played to begin with.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'm almost done.
Speaker 1: I'm playing it.
Speaker 0: I got a whole bunch of instruments.
Speaker 0: I just got the mirror shield and I've never played it before.
Speaker 0: but I don't fucking trust that owl at all.
Speaker 0: But all this bad fucking news.
Speaker 1: Anyway, it's the same alpha lay the Zelda game.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but I don't trust this owl anyway, so Yeah, so then I played this and like people said goose game is hella short.
Speaker 1: it is.
Speaker 1: It's the right length like right length for an adult who's got better shit to do.
Speaker 0: But it's also the right length as in it is it like the game is brilliant.
Speaker 0: but the reason I say it's brilliant is that the thing that I'm most focused on in game design is always this concept of elegance and fun economy In the sense that a four-hour game that's a fun for four hours is not as good as a one-hour game.
Speaker 0: That's really fun for that one hour.
Speaker 1: Yeah I think I think that's what the thing is is like.
Speaker 1: on the one hand if you were expecting More 70 hours of goose right if you're spending more goose and you're set because it is super short It's like four areas.
Speaker 1: Maybe it's basically.
Speaker 0: there's the game which You know the the other concept we kind of get into in games that allows the idea of if you have a simple set of Mechanics, do you fully explore those mechanics?
Speaker 0: So the goose game is a very simple set of mechanics and in the first half of the game like the real game until you Quote-unquote beat it and get the ending which I won't spoil because I laughed so hard.
Speaker 0: I almost choked.
Speaker 1: the ending was so perfect Wasn't that funny?
Speaker 0: I thought it was really funny.
Speaker 0: Okay, but the the very simple mechanics that has are Fully explored and then you beat it and then if that wasn't enough it like Legend of Zelda 1. there's a second quest.
Speaker 0: That's just more.
Speaker 0: if you really want to challenge it You can do the same thing again slightly harder slightly different.
Speaker 0: a few of the parts of the second quest are way harder.
Speaker 1: Yeah So yeah, it's you know, you walk around you can flap.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Well, yeah, you can walk you can run You can walk run.
Speaker 1: You can crouch your head down low to the ground up.
Speaker 1: You can grab your wing.
Speaker 1: You got wings up your wings and you can honk and you can.
Speaker 1: you know what you?
Speaker 1: it's not just grab It's you can interact with anything that has like these action lines.
Speaker 1: So most of the time you put your head near something and has action lines to grab it.
Speaker 1: But there's other things you can interact with like, you know, ring a bell Push a button knock something over Trim a hedge, you know, very basically push a to interact with an interactable item.
Speaker 0: Yep, and there's a. There's a lot of items to interact with.
Speaker 0: most of them are not strictly necessary.
Speaker 0: Like if you want to speedrun this game You can skip most of the things you could.
Speaker 1: you're gonna see speedruns of this game at like, you know A GDQ event and it's probably gonna take minutes like single-digit minutes.
Speaker 0: I've watched some speedruns and of this already and the funniest part was one dude was doing this pretty fast speedrun and Literally in the middle of the run.
Speaker 0: He's like, oh wait, I think I can route this way better.
Speaker 0: He's like fuck it I'm starting over.
Speaker 0: I think I can set the world record right now.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: Cuz the world record is evolving rapidly.
Speaker 1: Yes But you know the fun of the game is that you know You walk around and you interact with all the things that goose can interact with and it's funny.
Speaker 0: It's subtle and understated and it trusts the player to get the joke.
Speaker 0: because literally the game.
Speaker 0: after you get into the first area You see this farmer and then suddenly this little notebook appears with your agenda for the day And it's some of them are very straightforward like steal the farmers keys
Speaker 1: So you walk you sneak up behind the farmer grab his keys and run and that that's it.
Speaker 0: Some of them are more vague like just well not vague really but more funny.
Speaker 0: Like one is just raking the lake.
Speaker 1: Yep It's pretty straightforward Yeah But some of them are not straightforward and you have to figure out Which items to interact with in which order with which timing in order to make the thing happen.
Speaker 0: But along the way like the list itself is a joke.
Speaker 0: and then when you play the game like as you figure out like some of the puzzles when You figure out how to solve them the way they are solved is itself funny.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm they like.
Speaker 0: the game is just really really good subtle clever comedy as An interactive entertainment software that lets you explore the comedy on your own terms on your own time, right?
Speaker 1: I think what it really is this game is it's basically a point-and-click adventure game in disguise plus a real-time element.
Speaker 0: Yep, right so you say well with the quest for glory piece meaning for any given task There are a lot of different ways to accomplish it usually not too much.
Speaker 1: some subtly Yes, kinda no.
Speaker 0: some of them.
Speaker 0: there are like eight or nine different ways to solve it.
Speaker 0: some of them There's only like one or two but many of the things you have to do I think it's like.
Speaker 1: it's like that the the basic structure of how to accomplish any given thing is Basically always the same.
Speaker 1: It's just the details of your specific execution can vary, right?
Speaker 1: So like rake in the lake, it's like, okay, you have to grab the rake and run to the lake.
Speaker 1: But maybe you know, I might do it in a way where I sneakily Sneak around with the rake and don't get spotted.
Speaker 0: Maybe I'm just like fucking Go go go.
Speaker 1: Maybe I just brute force it and run right so fast that I'm not caught, right?
Speaker 1: And maybe I have to drop the rake a few times.
Speaker 1: then they go back for it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, maybe I grab some other.
Speaker 1: I grab the rake I get caught.
Speaker 1: So then I grab something else.
Speaker 1: the farmer Prioritizes that something else more than the rake.
Speaker 1: so I distract the farmer with something else.
Speaker 1: they go back for the rake before Dealing with like his spade or something, right and it's like yeah The fundamental way to get the rake in the lake is you grab it and you have to carry it to the lake.
Speaker 1: There's no other way to do it.
Speaker 1: Like another one of the details of how you succeed at dragging it all the way to the lake might vary Like.
Speaker 0: there's one where you basically tells you get this lady trapped in her garage.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there's a lot of ways to get her into that garage and trapper like a lot of different ways.
Speaker 1: Well, it's like you have to open the garage and then you have to wait for her to be in the garage And once she's in the garage, you have to pull the rope.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I didn't get her into the garage, right?
Speaker 1: Well, there's pretty much any way to get this.
Speaker 1: so many different ways to get her attention in the garage.
Speaker 0: So here's the other cleverness.
Speaker 0: the mechanic of the game like the way the humans work is really clever in that The humans have like different.
Speaker 0: humans have different levels of aggression.
Speaker 0: meaning if you the goose enter a certain human space They just kind of look at you.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like the kid like the kid.
Speaker 1: He doesn't really care too much about you.
Speaker 1: Let's attack him.
Speaker 1: It's kind of scared of you.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we're like the farmer just kind of looks at you unless you fuck with him.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but like the guy at the pub like actively assaults you if you get.
Speaker 1: no, yeah The bouncer at the pub is the strongest dude.
Speaker 1: It's like he doesn't let you in the pub.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right It's sort of an.
Speaker 1: it's slightly annoying in one sense because you know the the.
Speaker 1: it's like yeah humans can like make you drop But you're holding.
Speaker 1: they can take things from you.
Speaker 1: They can push you around.
Speaker 1: There's nothing you can do about it.
Speaker 1: And I'm like, wait a minute.
Speaker 1: First of all geese can fucking fly Right as you will just fly to.
Speaker 0: uh Geese have a hard time taking off unless they're in water.
Speaker 1: That's good.
Speaker 1: That's news to me.
Speaker 1: Anyway, the point is - geese can shit Right.
Speaker 0: Oh, that should have been another option to get on lock shitting.
Speaker 1: Yeah, she could shit on people.
Speaker 0: Take it away from the like benign charm of the game.
Speaker 0: I'm not.
Speaker 1: I'm not saying the game should have done these things.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm just saying in the fiction I was constantly annoyed by humans us not constantly but slightly annoyed at humans being able to push me around.
Speaker 1: I'm just like it doesn't make sense.
Speaker 1: I just bite that fucker as like if a goose.
Speaker 1: even if you're a bouncer at a club if a goose comes up and is All biting and flapping at you.
Speaker 0: You're not pushing it around If you're if you're willing to harm the goose, it's trivial to stop a goose.
Speaker 0: But most people are attacked by geese don't want to hurt the goose.
Speaker 0: They just want the goose to stop biting them, right?
Speaker 1: I mean, it's like no human would behave the way these humans do and the goose.
Speaker 1: I was worried but a real goose Could if it desired be much more vicious than this goose is.
Speaker 1: this goose is such a for being in such a jerky goose That fucks with people.
Speaker 1: It's such a nice goose.
Speaker 1: It doesn't fucking bite people and poke them and whap flap them and fly in and poop on them.
Speaker 1: And it's like, you know, they just like go rake in the leg.
Speaker 1: It's like Jesus Christ, but you know The farmer shouldn't be able to stop the goose unless it's an evil farmer to shoot the goose.
Speaker 0: But the other why is it goes dropping that rake?
Speaker 0: The other cool thing about the way the humans work is that they basically they all have like things they do and over their heads It'll always float an icon of like the thing they wish to interact with Mm-hmm, and they kind of go about their thing.
Speaker 0: You can watch them and sort of time thing to solve puzzles.
Speaker 0: But they also if they see the goose with anything, they'll be like goose shouldn't have that thing.
Speaker 0: They'll come take it from you.
Speaker 0: They also if you take something that they then later want to interact with they'll start roaming around the map looking for it
Speaker 1: Right and they seem to have a priority of things that are most important
Speaker 0: like that old man If I take his stool like fucking he will get that stool back before he'll go after other stuff.
Speaker 0: I stall right.
Speaker 1: It's like they care.
Speaker 1: each human cares more about certain items than others.
Speaker 1: So it's like you might steal an item that they don't care about too much and they won't go looking for event, you know for a long time, but It like if you steal ten things you can readily predict which the order in which they'll get the ten.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's back.
Speaker 0: You can also softlock like when Natalie was playing at her house I didn't have that she won't know.
Speaker 0: she permanently trapped the farmer in a spot where he could never leave and never correct himself.
Speaker 1: No I didn't mean so.
Speaker 0: She walked up to him later like took his keys and just like walk back and forth past him because he could not get out Of the thing she trapped him in it.
Speaker 0: It was permanently there interesting and at the end of the game when you go all the way back through the world He was still trapped.
Speaker 1: Yeah
Speaker 0: The another part of the humor is that some of the things you interact with
Speaker 1: are
Speaker 0: Basically just little set pieces that are really funny along the way like there's one moment where you get into someone's house But the camera doesn't actually show you what's happening in the house.
Speaker 0: you just see like some wing flaps through the windows and you hear a bunch of noises and crashes and like Eventually you get shoved out the front door on the other side and it's like it's really funny and it's almost just like an Interstitial before you get to the next part of the game, right?
Speaker 1: I think that's really you know, it's like that's.
Speaker 1: you know the game's like.
Speaker 1: You know greatness is like all this polish that has gone into the.
Speaker 1: you know the environment and you know the things and they write and all that.
Speaker 1: and I think if this game didn't have the theme of being a goose Right if this is literally any other thing like just a dude walking around This would be a garbage game.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: It would be completely worthless.
Speaker 0: We're hard.
Speaker 0: It would just.
Speaker 1: it would literally just be like if you you know, like say monkey island only real time.
Speaker 1: But imagine if you took away all the funny monkey island biz.
Speaker 1: It was.
Speaker 1: it's just literally figure out which things to interact with in which order with which timing.
Speaker 1: it's the saw.
Speaker 1: It's just an answer but also and it.
Speaker 0: sometimes it would be actually kind of frustrating also if the quests were harder It wouldn't have been as fun.
Speaker 1: Yeah harder would have been like even more.
Speaker 0: there's already a slight amount of frustration But it's the right amount like a few of those pretty hard.
Speaker 1: It is.
Speaker 1: the amount of frustration isn't the problem, but it's occasionally the kind of frustration is that sort of escape room?
Speaker 1: You know point-and-click adventure game stuff.
Speaker 0: I never ran into that.
Speaker 0: My question was never how do I accomplish this?
Speaker 0: My question was always Like how do I get around this obstacle in my way of?
Speaker 0: Accomplishing the thing that I know I want to do like I got to trick this guy out of the way or something Hmm.
Speaker 0: The only one I had trouble with was for some reason I had troubles getting the guy to fall on his ass Like I could well Frank.
Speaker 1: for example, there was one where I get a candle.
Speaker 1: I looked all the fuck over.
Speaker 1: I didn't see any fucking candle.
Speaker 1: No, I didn't go over in that where it was.
Speaker 0: I went everywhere cuz I just wanted to poke at the world.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I just I did.
Speaker 1: it took me forever to find that fucking candle.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and it's like it wasn't hard.
Speaker 1: It was just I didn't see it over there, right?
Speaker 0: And there's one of my favorite.
Speaker 1: There's another thing that looked candle.
Speaker 1: ish, right?
Speaker 0: I think my favorite area is still the two gardens.
Speaker 1: Yeah The area that has the most going on and that tells the most story and tells the human story of the two neighbors.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right It's.
Speaker 0: that's what makes it better the little bits like you see the lady like spying on the dude when he's not looking And all the stuff going on between the two of them is really fine And then whatever.
Speaker 1: So yeah, it's it's you know, I think it's like.
Speaker 1: on the one hand It's like the game on its own.
Speaker 1: just the game part of it on its own with known to the goose part and the theme Part right is basically a game that I probably wouldn't even like.
Speaker 1: hate it.
Speaker 1: Like this is garbage, right?
Speaker 1: It's just what it shows how important.
Speaker 0: polish style theme humor.
Speaker 1: It's literally just a point-and-click adventure or escape room with some real-time Elements and the real-time elements were even frustrating because it'd be like most only frustrating because of the waiting like.
Speaker 1: alright I want to do this thing.
Speaker 1: I need this human to be in this position.
Speaker 1: Well, just I got a fucking wait.
Speaker 1: I'm like Jesus Christ.
Speaker 1: How are your ass up human?
Speaker 0: See I would never wait.
Speaker 0: I just saw the problem a different way.
Speaker 1: There was no other way.
Speaker 1: It's like you want to do a thing.
Speaker 1: It's like why need this human to not be in that area.
Speaker 1: I need to wait for them to go to the other area.
Speaker 1: Well, then I could get something they wanted and trick him to go out of the way It's not you know, I need a human to be like, you know It's like oh I can.
Speaker 1: oh I have to scare the human when they're doing a specific task.
Speaker 1: Alright stand and wait for them to be doing that specific task.
Speaker 0: You can honk do it to get him to do it pretty quick though by like taking the other thing They want to play with stealing kids plane and then he'll go try to do the other thing instead.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but it's like you're down to.
Speaker 1: the one thing you need to do is I can't you know.
Speaker 0: But the game is just short enough charming enough interesting enough.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if it was any longer the frustrations would have built despite the funny goose, right?
Speaker 1: If it was any harder the frustrations would have built despite the funny goose, right?
Speaker 1: But because it was so short and so polished in the environment and so funny and the way the music plays.
Speaker 1: Right because they polished that is the music's dynamic like it, right Because the theme and the art and the style and the humor and because all those things were so strong and so short.
Speaker 1: Right, you don't you didn't need a strong game to carry that weight.
Speaker 1: You just needed enough game to carry that weight, right?
Speaker 1: And So there was right before I was ready, you know, it's like if they had added like two more levels.
Speaker 1: I might have actually been here saying this game's garbage.
Speaker 1: Don't play no goose game.
Speaker 0: What's fun too is that the animation of the goose.
Speaker 0: in particular if you watch people play this game?
Speaker 0: The goose ends up acting a lot like a real goose like it's interesting fly or shit.
Speaker 1: Well or bite
Speaker 0: I mean, it's a relatively nice goose, but part of that is because the way there's like a priority animation system You can see where the goose is always kind of looking at the most interesting thing near it at any given time And when a person walks over the goose just kind of looks up at it.
Speaker 0: So the goose is natural.
Speaker 0: idle animations interacting animations coupled with your interactions Sort of trick the player into like cosplaying as a goose while you're playing and doing goose like things that are not strictly necessary to win the game or solve a puzzle.
Speaker 1: Yep, it's yeah, that's the thing is like if you're not just trying to win the game.
Speaker 1: the inner the environment is so interactive way beyond What a point-and-click adventure game can do.
Speaker 0: right when I broke that lady's broom I like ran away with it and hit it like so far.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, just a fucker like that lady.
Speaker 0: I was so mad at her in that shop.
Speaker 0: when I busted that broom I hit it like in the top corner over by the walkie-talkie by that other house that table.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there was one where I had to collect like a whole bunch of things in like a bucket or something.
Speaker 1: What the hell was that one?
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah I forget what that was and I had to collect a bunch of items and they all had to be in the same like Container.
Speaker 1: I was like, oh, it was go shopping There's a grocery list.
Speaker 1: But I had to.
Speaker 1: I picked up the basket for the grocery list and I carried it all the way the fuck over by the car Super far away.
Speaker 0: I did the same thing.
Speaker 0: I went the opposite direction.
Speaker 0: I went to the east Okay And then yeah went all the way to the car and then at one point the lady started walking that way and I was like Oh, no She's gonna find.
Speaker 1: basically took as many items that weren't on the grocery list as I could and put them over in the east.
Speaker 1: And then I stole items for the grocery thing one at a time and ran them all the way.
Speaker 1: Right, because if I leave the grocery thing too close, she's just gonna go for it and put it all back.
Speaker 0: Also a subtle game design point Into avoid frustration.
Speaker 0: This is pretty clever.
Speaker 0: The game gives you the list of things to do and you have to get all of them done To get to the next area except once you get all but one of them done.
Speaker 0: It adds like a bonus one like it adds one more.
Speaker 0: So I did all of them.
Speaker 0: Yeah, yeah, I did all of them too.
Speaker 0: But if you're getting frustrated or having trouble Getting that bonus one also means the thing that's preventing you from getting to the next area opens up so you could move on Without finishing every item.
Speaker 1: Yes, you could always.
Speaker 1: you could skip one item Every.
Speaker 0: I can do them eventually.
Speaker 0: But that is good subtle game design because if you're frustrated like you just can't solve one particular puzzle Like you can't figure out.
Speaker 0: I get the farmer to put on his son had you could just let it be.
Speaker 0: Go interact with a totally different area and sleep on it and come back later.
Speaker 1: Yeah design It's also, you know, the humans are stuck in these certain patterns, but like after you accomplish certain tasks Occasionally completing those tests will cause some of the human patterns to change.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and that allows you to accomplish a different task, right?
Speaker 1: Oh, it's like that bouncer guy we talked about.
Speaker 1: It's like you got to drop a bucket on his head.
Speaker 1: And it's like well at the start and when you get in that area, he won't move.
Speaker 1: He only hangs in the front He doesn't go anywhere else.
Speaker 1: He doesn't go near any buckets.
Speaker 1: So how do you get a bucket on his head?
Speaker 1: It's like eventually you complete other tasks and then he'll start walking around And then there's a way you can get him to go near a bucket and drop it on his head.
Speaker 0: So if you have not played the goose game, it's a hundred percent worth playing.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's not such a delightful.
Speaker 1: It's not too expensive It doesn't take too long.
Speaker 1: you buy the goose game you play it once and then you're done with it.
Speaker 0: Maybe if you're really into it, you can futz around with the second quest.
Speaker 1: I think you could come back to it later for a second quest, right?
Speaker 0: I don't know if I'm like bored on a plane.
Speaker 0: I might just do like one of the second quest items, right?
Speaker 1: Maybe I think if you're the kind of person who doesn't get frustrated at a point-and-click adventure game And also can handle the real-time elements, right, you know, some people aren't so great with the gamepad.
Speaker 1: Right, if you have gamepad skills at least moderate ones and you don't hate point-and-click adventures You could probably play goose game like through several times and get like there's a super bonus I think you get if you beat it enough, right?
Speaker 0: Maybe even enjoy just watching other people play it even though I've already.
Speaker 0: yeah watching people play it is fine, too Right, but cuz everyone I've sat down in front of it has already solved some puzzles in very different ways from how I solved them.
Speaker 1: Right, but even if you're someone like me who would hate it if not, but for the humor and style It's still worth buying and playing through one time.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right.
Speaker 1: Just do all the missions once you completed the game.
Speaker 1: You don't need to complete it a second time.
Speaker 1: Just there you go.
Speaker 1: You saw the great goose game and you've learned valuable lessons for other games, which is you should you know?
Speaker 1: The college is what matter.
Speaker 0: Yep And also think your games don't all have to be 70 hour monsters.
Speaker 0: a game can be short, right?
Speaker 0: Good experience that ends right?
Speaker 1: It's like a lot of people people who complain the goose game is short.
Speaker 1: It's like well Those are little kids with tons of free time who can play fortnight ten hours a day.
Speaker 1: Yeah, people complain that RPGs are too long or old people who are like yay goose game.
Speaker 1: I was able to beat a game.
Speaker 0: meanwhile despite being an adult with the job I'm feeling this weird powerful urge to play Death Stranding.
Speaker 1: Oh The coach.
Speaker 0: apparently it's 70 hours of main gameplay.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean I can't get past the first room in Metal Gear Solid.
Speaker 1: So, how would I play that?
Speaker 1: I know but Something why would I pay money for that?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: It seems like it's a literal walking simulator and it's calling to me.
Speaker 1: Oh, it doesn't have any like shooting or anything.
Speaker 1: It's just a Metal Gear Solid.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 0: What do you know anything about this game?
Speaker 1: Do you?
Speaker 1: I thought it was just Kojima made a Metal Gear Solid game, but it wasn't Metal Gear It's a male.
Speaker 0: Kojima made a Kojima game, but the core mechanic is you're just delivering packages by walking Package.
Speaker 1: delivery skills required the walking game.
Speaker 1: So why not just fucking watch it on YouTube?
Speaker 0: cuz I want to walk I want to do it Feeling it.
Speaker 1: Yeah Maybe you should make a movie instead.
Speaker 0: I Feel like a movie wouldn't work.
Speaker 0: I think it's gotta be.
Speaker 0: you gotta have that long experience gonna walk for 10 hours desert bus style.
Speaker 0: Anyway, I think we're done with the goose game.
Speaker 0: Yeah This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at front row crew comm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 0: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 0: But unlike those other late shows It's actually recorded at night and the patreon page runs for this episode of geek nights.
Speaker 0: are Alan Joyce hiding minicule just like a dude guy?
Speaker 0: chair television William Eisnerose Linky G hydrated gandola Ganon supports Hong Kong Jennifer Hitchcock Chris mink if my state II calm J Bantz Sean Yeager Nicholas Brando.
Speaker 0: Let's see if rim says try to properly for two on creations when a couple of guys who were up to no good Sure from not all Rory Superboy Clinton Walton run from New Zealand Ryan parent rope and later Finn Gentlelily Tenebrae Sean Klein Chris Reimer Thomas on and now.