Speaker 0: It's Thursday November 7th 2019.
Speaker 0: I'm rim.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott and this is geek nights tonight mailing things in boxes and envelopes and stuff.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: You can tell when we're really hitting the bottom of the barrel for like idea for a good show.
Speaker 0: I Mean.
Speaker 1: I thought of the show cuz I I was.
Speaker 1: we were discussing it while I was out eating lunch And I saw I was just looking around like is there anything I see with my eyes?
Speaker 0: I've done the same thing.
Speaker 0: I sit at my desk.
Speaker 0: Let's do a show on.
Speaker 0: I look and I'm like Microphones, and then we did a show on microphones like wallets cuz I'm looking at a wallet right now.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm that's.
Speaker 0: uh that's what happens when you Simpsons yourselves and do a podcast for 14 plus years.
Speaker 0: So actually if you weren't aware on October 31st, which was literally one week ago today We didn't do a show because it wasn't scheduled to be a show but that was The anniversary of geek nights.
Speaker 0: geek night started.
Speaker 0: the first episode went live on October 31st.
Speaker 0: That was a long goddamn time ago.
Speaker 0: We have done a lot of episodes of geek nights And you should be thankful that all of them all like 2000 or whatever of them are just on YouTube for free or YouTube.
Speaker 0: They're all just on the internet for free hosted in a variety of places.
Speaker 0: But I'll warn you not really met a moment cuz I'll talk about where I'm going, but it's kind of as a. you know It's Thursday.
Speaker 0: It's the lounge.
Speaker 0: We can talk about whatever in the first part of the show.
Speaker 0: I'm uh When I had my old job I traveled a lot and a lot of times you can actually get disrupted for a week or three because I'd like go live in Istanbul for a while or something.
Speaker 0: But that stopped for a while because I have a new job or work somewhere different.
Speaker 0: But now for various reasons, I'm traveling again for this job.
Speaker 0: So for the next two weeks, I will be in Asia and over the course of two weeks I'm gonna go to Manila Singapore Bangkok Melbourne Sydney and then back home and it's gonna be a pretty grueling trip.
Speaker 0: So no geek nights the next two weeks.
Speaker 1: if I have good for me I can do other shit.
Speaker 0: Yeah, work on some kind of.
Speaker 0: we got a lot of geek night stuff.
Speaker 0: We got to work on Yep, a lot of cons coming up a lot of biz, but I'll try to post some pictures.
Speaker 0: watch follow me on social media.
Speaker 0: Maybe I'll do a few live streams on the patreon like from these cities because I've I've never been to Bangkok or Manila before So I'm actually excited about that.
Speaker 0: See I'm stuck in Singapore over the weekend, but I've been to Singapore a lot.
Speaker 0: So, I don't know what I'll do.
Speaker 0: I might just go to Universal Studios or something cuz like.
Speaker 0: what else am I gonna do?
Speaker 0: Hmm, I spent a lot of time in Singapore.
Speaker 0: Like I don't think there's anything I need to see that I haven't seen.
Speaker 0: maybe I'll go mountain biking But I don't know.
Speaker 0: it's gonna be like a hundred degrees so that might be a little too hot even for me to go mountain biking.
Speaker 0: uh the other things going on in my life is uh My mattress is.
Speaker 0: I actually tried to figure out how old my mattress is my the mattress I sleep on this queen-size mattress with a pillow top is At least 15 years old.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think you know you had one.
Speaker 1: you had the bed the bed frame you had before our at college.
Speaker 1: Yep, right, but I do think you replaced the mattress at one point.
Speaker 0: I've replaced the mattress when I went to college.
Speaker 0: Okay, so the mattress was new when I went to college.
Speaker 0: Okay, so 2000 right.
Speaker 1: I mean I bought so it's 19 years old or Anyone to college.
Speaker 1: then I replaced it when I moved to New York ten years ago.
Speaker 1: But then I just moved and I just threw the whole bed out.
Speaker 1: I guess just Amanda's bed was way new.
Speaker 1: So just use that one that one's like less than a year old.
Speaker 0: maybe looks like a pretty nice bed.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's fun.
Speaker 1: It's like it's some kind of mattress from one of those.
Speaker 1: It's not the you know the.
Speaker 1: it's from one of those websites where it's.
Speaker 1: yeah You know we send you a mattress.
Speaker 1: you send it back if you don't like it.
Speaker 0: I think we talked about occasionally on gig notes of the mattress industry for a long time was kind of messed up and Like mattress technology kind of sucked.
Speaker 0: and now a bunch of internet people are disrupting it with varying degrees of success.
Speaker 0: There's a lot of these companies that like mail you a mattress that like inflates itself.
Speaker 0: So, uh, because we live in New York There's actually a place we went to where they have like every mattress that all the different online places sell.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's like it's really in New York City.
Speaker 1: It's weird like you.
Speaker 1: on the one hand You have so much ability to get things delivered and order things online from pretty much anywhere right and get anything.
Speaker 1: but They also have in Manhattan these places that are usually online only businesses Right for like the rest of the world.
Speaker 1: It's like, you know, you could never go to a Newegg store.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right.
Speaker 1: It's like there's no Newegg store, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, I guess there's no Newegg store anywhere that I know of.
Speaker 1: there might be one somewhere but not that I know of.
Speaker 1: but for other places like there was There was like a clothing store and they only sold clothes online and that was it right?
Speaker 1: It's like well, there's a crazy thing in my head, but in Manhattan, they have us does like their only store.
Speaker 0: There's a store in Manhattan.
Speaker 0: That is an Amazon store that weirdly enough sells books.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well it sells only things that are rated four stars and up.
Speaker 1: yeah, right I've been at store was near my previous work.
Speaker 0: Look, yeah, I was hanging out there cuz it was cold.
Speaker 0: I was waiting for.
Speaker 1: so it's like there's so many stores Especially in Manhattan that are like the only.
Speaker 1: they're like showrooms for a web only business And it's literally the only showroom in the whole world for that web.
Speaker 0: Well, which I think is a trend that's going to increase over time because many things I don't need to try it in person Like my laptop.
Speaker 0: I can do my research just buy a laptop.
Speaker 1: Well, I think the thing is is that there's so much tourists and shopping tourists in Manhattan that they're not only are the people who?
Speaker 1: Live here going to occasionally think that that's convenient Right to be able to go try a product in person before ordering online.
Speaker 1: It's out of doing the whole by return by return.
Speaker 1: You don't even know about online business right but tourists come through they see those places they go in and they become a customer.
Speaker 1: Or I think a lot of tourists, you know are a customer and then they come and they see a store.
Speaker 1: It's like oh my god a store of that thing.
Speaker 0: Holy I remember we went to Seattle and then we were like Oh shit a Timbuktu store now.
Speaker 1: We've got multiple times
Speaker 0: a bunch
Speaker 1: here
Speaker 0: but I think part of it too is just that if you put a store like that cuz there's this mattress thing exists here and Like two other places and that's it because there's just so many people in New York that like it makes sense.
Speaker 0: So we went and it was super chill and there's a lot of people just coming in Chumming all these mattresses and I tried a whole bunch of these mattresses and they're all really good.
Speaker 0: Like.
Speaker 0: the only problem is the more a lot of people sell lemon mattresses though.
Speaker 0: One thing I noticed the I didn't look at product.
Speaker 0: we laid on them all and then we went back to see what they were And how much they cost.
Speaker 0: the more expensive ones were just better.
Speaker 0: like they felt better.
Speaker 0: They were more comfortable.
Speaker 0: like everything about them was just better.
Speaker 1: I mean, you know, that's how they do.
Speaker 0: So I went.
Speaker 0: we went with the Spartan hybrid because it was called Spartan.
Speaker 0: now It had a better.
Speaker 0: like it felt better.
Speaker 0: It's just way more comfortable and I like a way soft bed and this one is way soft Like a not-so-soft.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you Scott basically likes to sleep, but I can't.
Speaker 1: the thing is even though I like a rock Yeah, I can sleep on anything.
Speaker 1: So it's like whatever I did.
Speaker 1: I just sleep on the bed we got.
Speaker 0: I think what really sealed the deal was we went to that wedding upstate and we stayed in a hotel that had a Particularly good bed and laying in that bed.
Speaker 0: We both were just like Like.
Speaker 0: this bed is comfortable.
Speaker 0: why isn't our bed this comfortable?
Speaker 0: what the fuck?
Speaker 0: Yeah So So, uh, we actually did a show on beds already back in 2017, so I'll link to that.
Speaker 0: there is some news.
Speaker 0: So if you have our friends the other night, we're just like whoa weird thing happened.
Speaker 0: I got a bunch of texts from like February And apparently that was a thing across the entire country Seems to have mostly affected the US.
Speaker 0: like I can't find instances of this happening except for US carriers.
Speaker 0: But basically something happened and a whole bunch of text messages that were sent on like specific days around Valentine's Day this year either never got delivered when they were sent and Suddenly got delivered just now
Speaker 1: or were
Speaker 0: delivered back then and then just got redelivered just now
Speaker 1: Like yesterday.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like yesterday like a whole bunch of people just got text which led some interesting situations Like family member is dead and you get a text from them like stuff like that happens.
Speaker 0: Yep There is no clear explanation of exactly what happened yet.
Speaker 0: We can speculate Reporters like reaching out to these companies But and we're not gonna go deep into this because this is way more a Monday topic than a Thursday topic Like I don't explain to you SMS works But here's the TL DL version or TL DW version or TLDR crap.
Speaker 0: SMS should be banned.
Speaker 0: SMS is shit garbage technology that should not exist.
Speaker 1: It is a lot of the world depends on it.
Speaker 0: Uh, yeah, but in like in the US it should be banned or Phones should be able to send messages to phone numbers using modern technology.
Speaker 1: Well, they should do.
Speaker 1: is they should?
Speaker 1: you know They should force, you know, it's like we have these other standards for sending messages like iMessage or whatever.
Speaker 1: When Apple came out with iMessage written in the Monday Territory They claimed they claimed go back and watch the first the keynote where they announced iMessage.
Speaker 1: I can't tell you what year it was right.
Speaker 1: they claimed That iMessage and FaceTime we're gonna be like open standards.
Speaker 1: They said, you know giving me the impression and like oh I'll be able to write my own Software my own iMessage client like you'll be able to use.
Speaker 1: I don't know what they call these days pigeon like the old Right, or I miss those days or like that, you know, remember our Laconica servers Make Android apps that let you iMessage people right.
Speaker 1: they gave that impression that it would be open.
Speaker 1: But no, it's closed.
Speaker 1: only people with iPhones can FaceTime and iMessage people.
Speaker 1: It's even at the point where like if you're at rim doesn't have an iPhone's.
Speaker 1: doesn't realize this?
Speaker 1: When you when you text people on an iPhone if you text someone who is not an iPhone person All your the text bubbles are green.
Speaker 1: Yeah And that lets you.
Speaker 1: even if you make a big group chat if everyone in the group chat has an iPhone except one person All the bubbles are green.
Speaker 1: It uses regular old SMS and your features are limited.
Speaker 1: You can't do too much.
Speaker 1: You know, we send text messages and the basic standard Unicode emojis, and that's it.
Speaker 1: So what happens is like I've heard stories of my kids at school.
Speaker 1: They got an Android phone all their friends got iPhone and They'll be like because they're in the group chat.
Speaker 1: right it?
Speaker 1: all the other kids are like fuck.
Speaker 1: I can't do all the cool.
Speaker 1: I message stuff like Right, you know like animojis and all the cool stuff.
Speaker 1: So they'll just make another group chat without that person once they figure out who it is.
Speaker 1: Yeah Android phone just so that they can use iMessage because Apple didn't go through with their promise to make it open.
Speaker 0: Yep, but SMS like text messaging is basically using like Extra space on legacy Carrier technology like it's almost like trying like using power lines to transmit data like it's that level of ridiculous nonsense and I think on our next Monday show, we'll talk about this a little more detail because basically, the reason this happened is that SMS is Way bad and needs to be destroyed and replaced by some standard that works with modern technology.
Speaker 1: I feel like they should just make like SMS - yeah We don't have problems making things like Wi-Fi - and you know Genes.
Speaker 1: replacing 4g with 5g I don't replacing SMS with SMS - will not be any more difficult than replacing 4g with 5g.
Speaker 1: And yeah, you basically had got.
Speaker 1: you're gonna have phones for a while to do both and then eventually Not have phones to do the old one.
Speaker 0: I mean I use signals.
Speaker 0: So if you text me and you also have signal it'll just use signal instead of texting.
Speaker 0: Mmm.
Speaker 1: Anyway, that's I message works.
Speaker 0: Yeah, pretty much Some other news.
Speaker 0: we talked about how the election happened.
Speaker 0: We got the results and it's pretty important what's going on in the u.s Cuz.
Speaker 0: this was a really high turnout for an off-year election.
Speaker 1: mad people vote in the man.
Speaker 0: Yeah, obviously there were some returns of like 20-something percent of people voted someone's.
Speaker 1: that's low But it's a high compared to what we usually get.
Speaker 0: Yep, and for an off-year election.
Speaker 0: That's like triple what we usually get like people don't fucking vote in these elections.
Speaker 0: No but the biggest thing that happened was one of our states.
Speaker 0: Virginia has always been a problem and It went completely Democrat.
Speaker 0: It's both chambers of its of its equivalent of Congress like it's legislature.
Speaker 0: Yes, it's how you're looking for.
Speaker 0: No, cuz it's like I don't think they have a house in the Senate.
Speaker 0: They have like a Senate and a something else.
Speaker 1: It's a legislative body.
Speaker 0: Yeah as opposed to an executive body Yes, but also their executive.
Speaker 0: when blue basically everything went blue.
Speaker 0: It's a blue state.
Speaker 1: love.
Speaker 1: Virginia already had a Democratic governor, Kentucky gained Which is also crazy.
Speaker 0: But this means something crazy could happen in the US and it sounds so crackpot Like you wouldn't believe it.
Speaker 0: But it's actually like real to the point that real news is talking about it.
Speaker 0: back in the 40s And I'm not gonna go deep into this there was a thing in the US that was the Equal Rights Amendment like the 1940s and it basically just says men and women should be equal under the eyes of the law.
Speaker 0: Like that's basically it.
Speaker 0: it was an amendment.
Speaker 1: It's not very long.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's an amendment to the Constitution saying you can't discriminate against men and women like.
Speaker 1: well He can't discriminate based on sex.
Speaker 0: yes, it's the language is?
Speaker 0: I mean this was like conceived in the 40s like it's not.
Speaker 0: it could be done a little better and Basically, it never it did.
Speaker 0: all this shit happened and it never actually got ratified as an amendment because a lot of American states are Stupid.
Speaker 0: but a whole bunch of states ratified this amendment and there's complicated rules about what that means.
Speaker 0: but It just so happens.
Speaker 0: Virginia is one of the few states that didn't ratify it and still.
Speaker 1: well we need one more state to ratify it and Most of the states that haven't never will like.
Speaker 1: you're not gonna see Alabama What's even funnier.
Speaker 1: but Virginia tried just this year earlier this year to ratify it and failed by one vote.
Speaker 1: And now the people who are in the legislative body of Virginia who are the people who would be voting to ratify it are now Completely different people very much more in favor of it and they could just try it again.
Speaker 0: But it's even crazier.
Speaker 0: a whole bunch of states that ratified it a long time ago Since then turned Republican and tried to own ratify.
Speaker 0: they voted to say fuck it No, we don't want this amendment, but because this is constitutional law you can't do the head can't undo?
Speaker 1: Yeah, so it's like it's like sign a contract say I want to unsign.
Speaker 0: Yep, right?
Speaker 1: It's like oh wait Let me take my name off that Declaration of Independence.
Speaker 1: No, so You're in.
Speaker 0: you can read about this go out, but basically Some crazy constitutional shit that isn't related to our traitorous criminal of a president might go down like pretty quickly because People actually begin their you know their session.
Speaker 0: I want to say in January, but I don't know if Virginia does something I don't know what the fuck Virginia does.
Speaker 1: Yeah, Virginia the place I go once a year only because of the magfest.
Speaker 1: there I mean another I touch I touch the very edge of Virginia and then escape.
Speaker 1: Yep Just like just to graze the side of it where a magfest is happening.
Speaker 0: What I know about Virginia is that it is the it of the of the Virginias.
Speaker 0: It's the better one.
Speaker 0: Yeah But anyway, it's time for things of the day.
Speaker 0: so, you know you got Video game consoles and old computers and electronics where if you just turn them on Some sort of splash screen or opening screen or startup sequence happens.
Speaker 1: Well, I think the thing is is that you know people are used to PCs right and with a PC you if you turn it on with no disk, it doesn't do jack shit, right?
Speaker 0: Well, but the thing is like BIOS would load.
Speaker 1: Well, it would.
Speaker 1: yeah, you could load your BIOS But you can't actually do anything with your BIOS.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's not computationally useful, right?
Speaker 1: You would need to somehow Get a disk drive of some kind with a master boot record and some and put software there that the computer would load when it Turns on.
Speaker 1: Yep But the thing is actually most computing devices are set to with some sort of firmware or some sort of included software.
Speaker 1: So when you turn them on they do a thing.
Speaker 1: I turn my Apple to GS on.
Speaker 1: yeah If you don't put anything if you put something in the discs that the disk drives sure they'll boot that software.
Speaker 1: But if you don't put anything in there, you get a useful terminal that you can do things.
Speaker 1: Yeah You just need the manual to understand.
Speaker 0: like a lot of old video game consoles and things which is boot something turn in a Commodore 64 you can do stuff but they'll be like yo put a disk in.
Speaker 0: dude, right my boy, you know.
Speaker 1: But you know video game consoles I think a lot of them.
Speaker 1: you need to put a disk in an NES need to put a Cartridge in a game boy.
Speaker 1: You need to put a cartridge in.
Speaker 0: no independent.
Speaker 1: I'm starting around, you know Xbox PlayStation times You know.
Speaker 1: then you could like I think play stage you could turn it on and you would actually use like a menu.
Speaker 0: It's like a menu.
Speaker 1: you could do stuff.
Speaker 0: But anyway Regardless of whether or not you had software ready to do something like a disc or cartridge in there Most of these devices had some sort of logo splash startup animation that would play with or without sound.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like you're playing a cube did you do?
Speaker 0: Yeah say it up.
Speaker 1: Well, it's Sega wouldn't do a Sega if you'd have a cartridge in it.
Speaker 1: I don't think.
Speaker 0: uh, I think the game gear did.
Speaker 0: Don't remember I don't.
Speaker 0: but anyway, this is an 18 minute and 7 second long YouTube video of Basically every game console that was ever released.
Speaker 0: and if it had and whatever like startup thing happens.
Speaker 0: Boo GameCube like.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna read some of the random systems on the list the Vectrex.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the Satellaview The mega CD one in Japan.
Speaker 0: the mega CD 2 in Europe.
Speaker 0: the Atari 37800. the Xbox 360 post-update HDMI and non HDMI.
Speaker 0: the oh, yeah All the game of cube ones because there's a bunch of them.
Speaker 0: Yep This video is just really fun to watch.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: Okay, so we got.
Speaker 1: So, you know, there's something that like my whole life despite being alive for 37 years Right despite working for and at several businesses, right?
Speaker 0: Yep it's like I never went to business school and I'm like one of the only people who does my kind of job and didn't go to business school.
Speaker 1: I'm in a weird position right and it seems like there's like there's a lot of mystery about how to actually Run like the real nitty-gritty details of how to actually run a small business.
Speaker 1: like I worked in a dry cleaner For example, there are only like the only other people there were like the two other people that work there and the person who owned It.
Speaker 1: that was it.
Speaker 1: So it's like I'm pretty close to seeing how everything works there But I learned basically nothing if you gave me if you gave me a dry cleaning business I wouldn't know what the fuck to do it's.
Speaker 1: I don't know how to do anything.
Speaker 0: and I'm like I only know how to like work in giant companies at a big scale Like I can run.
Speaker 0: I can do like a multi-million dollar like addressable market assessment and commercial model.
Speaker 0: But if it's like a fifty thousand dollar your business, I literally don't know how to make that happen, right?
Speaker 0: I don't understand it Right.
Speaker 1: It's like and it's you know, you look online and there's a lot or you just look around the world.
Speaker 1: There's a lot of scams going on like learn how to you know, make a bunch of money with you know, real estate everybody Right the shady biz going down.
Speaker 1: Here's a YouTube channel of this dude, and he's mostly a real estate dude, right?
Speaker 1: So his channel if you look at his older videos, he's in Ohio somewhere in a. you know Nick I think near Columbus ish like Southwest, Ohio.
Speaker 1: Most of his older videos are like real estate related.
Speaker 1: He's like check out this building.
Speaker 1: I bought it's a complete dump.
Speaker 1: It used to be like a train station in 18, you know, 60 or something like 1880 Civil war.
Speaker 1: look at you know, people are living here.
Speaker 1: It wasn't great.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna fix this place up and you know, whatever right but that those aren't that interesting, right?
Speaker 1: The interesting videos is that one of the recent properties he bought has a laundromat.
Speaker 1: So So he's got people renting the apartments above and behind the laundromat, right?
Speaker 1: But he basically took this laundromat that was uncared for forever and he's like do.
Speaker 1: it's a lot like the project x-manga.
Speaker 1: He's like.
Speaker 1: he's like.
Speaker 1: the video shows him like taking all the coins out of all the machines Counting them right showing you he's like I put my vending machine outside.
Speaker 1: Look how much money I'm making I've got.
Speaker 1: he got a coin pushing arcade machine.
Speaker 1: It's the money half and half with the person he rents it from.
Speaker 1: He's like.
Speaker 1: he's like I got when I bought the laundromat.
Speaker 1: I got all these bags and soap that just came with the laundromat.
Speaker 1: I'm selling them for.
Speaker 1: you know I'm basically making tons of money on those cuz it has to buy them right and he basically shows you Every detail of him, you know, like.
Speaker 1: he's like.
Speaker 1: these machines are broken.
Speaker 1: people are texting me at night.
Speaker 1: I'm changing the light bulbs to be more efficient to save on the electric bill.
Speaker 1: Here's what the electric bill is.
Speaker 0: This is fat.
Speaker 0: Look at that spreadsheet.
Speaker 0: This is fascinating, right?
Speaker 1: He's like, here's how much money I get from the coins.
Speaker 1: Here's how many hours I have to work on the laundromat per week.
Speaker 1: I'm making this much per hour for me in profits.
Speaker 1: Here's the rent.
Speaker 1: Um, he's like.
Speaker 1: he owns the building, but he has the laundromat pay rent to him.
Speaker 1: Right?
Speaker 1: That's some train game pays $500 in rent to the building a month.
Speaker 1: He owns the building but that's like it right?
Speaker 0: I was like an 18xx game where I cut the corporation that I am a shareholder in buy a small business.
Speaker 1: So the YouTube channel is called investment joy, which makes it seem like one of those shady dudes Who's like gonna tell you real estate scams like, you know make money doing nothing, right?
Speaker 1: but no this guy's actually just showing you the Complete reality and the complete details of all the secrets of what you actually do to run a business.
Speaker 1: It's like he's not being like some bullshit like oh don't have to work.
Speaker 1: He's like guys working hard.
Speaker 1: He's doing all this great.
Speaker 0: Yeah, he's managing all these fucking Feel like this would be more satisfying than the kind of work.
Speaker 0: I actually do I Totally right.
Speaker 1: and he's fixing washing machines.
Speaker 1: and then the latest video is even better.
Speaker 1: The latest video is the dude's brother.
Speaker 1: So I guess it runs in the family.
Speaker 1: The dude's brother is like a real introverted quiet guy.
Speaker 1: You know, you'll see he has a lot right and to a couple years ago the dude's brother started his own business basically getting appliances washers dryers refrigerators dishwashers right stoves getting them Repairing them and reselling them.
Speaker 1: and He shows you he's got this huge warehouse.
Speaker 1: it's like a it's like a big mess Right, and he's got this whole business.
Speaker 1: he makes like, you know tons of money and he shows you every detail of running and Accounting and everything that how he went from not even knowing anything about washing machines at all.
Speaker 1: He knew nothing.
Speaker 1: and he went to running this business making a bunch of money, you know buying and reselling and fixing Appliances.
Speaker 1: he's even like yeah, if we can't fix him at all We just bust him up and sell him for parts on eBay.
Speaker 1: shows you how much money he makes on eBay.
Speaker 1: It shows you like he made it.
Speaker 1: he built a testing rig where they can test stoves and washers to see if they work Right.
Speaker 1: It's like it's real.
Speaker 1: This is the stuff that you know, you can't learn easily like nobody shares this info, right?
Speaker 1: even if you try to buy a business from someone I remember someone was trying to buy a game store once and The person who already owned the game store was trying to sell it wouldn't show the next person the accounting.
Speaker 1: It's like it's like am I buying a business that's in debt.
Speaker 1: Like what are you hiding from?
Speaker 1: It's like, you know, I don't know what happened there But it's like people who run small businesses tend to keep see like it's hard to learn.
Speaker 1: So the fact that someone made a YouTube channel Teaching you the real deal is really fascinating is really unique And I guess he's making bad money.
Speaker 1: on the YouTube also There's a lot of subscribers and viewers and I think he's at a patreon.
Speaker 0: even so that doesn't he doesn't.
Speaker 0: Oh, no.
Speaker 0: Yeah, he has 82,000 subscribers.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's it's pretty unique content.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I have not seen anything like this and always wanted it.
Speaker 0: Okay, I'll throw him stuff throw sub his way.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So investment joy guy in the meta moment the geek nights book club book Which will be a long running book with multiple sub episodes along the way the tale of Genji the first book ever The first novel now ever.
Speaker 0: yeah, not the first book.
Speaker 0: No, not the but uh, I still can't use kind of a piece of shit.
Speaker 0: Just I cannot stress that enough.
Speaker 0: Come on Genji, like people around you are better than you be better.
Speaker 0: You've got to be better Genji.
Speaker 1: Maybe and you know with a different cultural perspective you would maybe think Genji was good.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but then you look at everyone else around.
Speaker 0: it was like, oh these people are all like way better like they're okay He's a main character doesn't have to be good true death note.
Speaker 1: Yeah country wrote death note and the tale of Genji.
Speaker 0: So the packs unplugged which is coming up in December.
Speaker 0: the schedule is live.
Speaker 0: We are doing on Friday from 3 p.m.
Speaker 0: To 5 p.m Daddy two hours Learn and play three short but essential games.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: So you can come to this session.
Speaker 1: how long is it?
Speaker 1: two hours two hours and in two hours?
Speaker 1: We will teach you three tiny game cockroach poker gone.
Speaker 0: Shane clever and Wizard.
Speaker 1: they'll teach you three small games and you'll play three small games.
Speaker 1: It's not learn and win like we did before.
Speaker 1: it's learn and play but it's three instead of one.
Speaker 1: Daddy.
Speaker 0: Yep Well, we'll help you win three PP Three horrid whirling PPS.
Speaker 0: We might teach you how to win cockroach poker because there's a pretty good strategy.
Speaker 1: there is some okay strategies But I can't actually for none of these games.
Speaker 1: Can I can I even in one hour?
Speaker 1: Tell you I know I could do it.
Speaker 0: I could in an hour Outline a complex set of wizard heuristics like I could do give you some heuristics But I like how to win at wizard would be another carcass own.
Speaker 0: where I'm like do a do be do see Guaranteed victory or guaranteed equal chance of win among pros.
Speaker 1: I mean, even if we did do a panel like strategies of trick-taking games No one would come.
Speaker 0: but also like no, you know People like us would come and no one else.
Speaker 0: Scott and an old suspender guy Expecting us.
Speaker 1: I like bridge is like we don't fucking know fucking bridge.
Speaker 1: Let's talk about you curtain and hearts bridge.
Speaker 0: memorize the Betty bidding conventions.
Speaker 0: Don't fuck them up.
Speaker 0: the end like bridge sucks.
Speaker 0: Sorry, anyway, which is not fun Euchre cheat.
Speaker 0: learn how to cheat cut card dog deal from the bottom.
Speaker 0: Just fucking she.
Speaker 1: that's the same for bridge.
Speaker 0: Nah, well bridge or contract bridge or old lady bridge.
Speaker 0: a lot of ways people play bridge.
Speaker 0: Anyway, and then on Sunday also at 3 p.m.
Speaker 0: But in the Leviathan theater instead we are doing a Panel that I'm looking forward to more than many panels.
Speaker 0: We've done in a long time.
Speaker 0: Take your fucking turn.
Speaker 0: We are going to talk about why people take a lot take a long time to play board games.
Speaker 0: We're gonna talk about why some games Force people who would otherwise take a short amount of time to take a long amount of time.
Speaker 1: We're talking about why some games feel like a long amount of time.
Speaker 1: They're short and feel like a short amount of time even though they're long.
Speaker 0: and then we're gonna teach you in the last 20 Minutes how to take your turns quickly and how to start being like us and hating anyone who does not take their turn quickly.
Speaker 0: That's right All right.
Speaker 0: Let's get into the show mail and stuff.
Speaker 1: I Yeah I was walking by a post office today while at the same moment that I had to talk to him about the show topic for Tonight.
Speaker 1: and there you go.
Speaker 0: I just mailed something to.
Speaker 0: because I mailed our lease back I had to actually mail a big venvel over the pieces of paper.
Speaker 1: So In a society where people have things and you know back in the day the only way to communicate over a long distance was by mail because we didn't have phones or internet.
Speaker 1: and then we invented the Phone and we didn't need to send letters so much.
Speaker 1: but you know nowadays even you know We still need to send some letters.
Speaker 1: Sometimes you need, you know, even if someone doesn't have a phone, you know Someone's phone they might not pick up their phone, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah internet who you know, you can't get no one has like a guaranteed way to contact them on the internet.
Speaker 0: But you need to have for a functioning society some way to Guaranteed be like hey to send a piece of physical object with possibly words on it to an anyone else in the entire country.
Speaker 1: Guaranteed a contact a person right so that they can't you know deny that they.
Speaker 1: you know, you never contacted me.
Speaker 1: It's I need an official way to send a thing to a person you are Associated with an address the place you live.
Speaker 1: if you live somewhere, you know, I sent you a thing.
Speaker 1: It was brought to you if you chose not to open it.
Speaker 1: Well, that's on you now.
Speaker 1: Yep, right now before we go too deep and also send objects as a much more thing in the modern times We debated because there's actually two shows here.
Speaker 0: one show topic would be Government postage and the United States Postal Service and like the necessity of these kinds of things.
Speaker 0: but that show would be all about things like postal banking and how I think the post office should also be an ISP and like all that kind of stuff.
Speaker 0: and That's not what we're gonna talk about today But we will do that at some point in the future because we're both very opinionated about it.
Speaker 0: We're gonna talk about actually like mailing shit and shipping so we can talk about UPS and FedEx and all those other biz.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so the first thing is obviously you send a letter you get some stamp action.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'm we're old enough to remember when stamps had a variable cost that like every now and then it'd be like Oh stamps are gonna cost more.
Speaker 1: Well, yeah when I was a kid right stamps were 20-something cents 25 cents.
Speaker 0: I think.
Speaker 1: yeah It kept going up a few cents every once in a while cuz I had to get a bunch of one cent.
Speaker 1: fucking stand Like I were raising the stamp price by two cents.
Speaker 1: So if you had like ten old stamps left You would go and buy ten like tiny stamps to add so that when you mailed something you would put two stamps on there your Old stamp and the few cents extra to get up to the new price.
Speaker 1: And then when you ran out you would buy new stamps that were the new price.
Speaker 1: and they kept doing this a bunch of times.
Speaker 1: And eventually they invented the forever stamp, which you buy the stamp at the current price, whatever it happens to be.
Speaker 0: I think it's 55 cents right now.
Speaker 0: Nothing.
Speaker 0: I know I just looked it up cuz I don't know what stamps cause.
Speaker 0: yeah Like six years ago and I still have that book.
Speaker 0: cuz I failed.
Speaker 1: like that's what I'm saying.
Speaker 1: Is that six things in US stamps in the US?
Speaker 1: They now just say forever on them.
Speaker 1: You don't know what they cost when you unless you calculate it when you buy them.
Speaker 1: And then even if the stamp price goes up like a zillion dollars You can still mail a letter with one stamp.
Speaker 0: This was not long ago.
Speaker 0: This was 2007.
Speaker 1: yep that they invented the forever stamp.
Speaker 0: Yeah And I remember people were worried like what will people like buy a lot of stamps?
Speaker 0: and like Arbitrage this and like cut revenue out of the postdoc dude.
Speaker 0: It is not enough money to matter.
Speaker 0: There's no way to make money hoarding stamps.
Speaker 1: Nope.
Speaker 1: I also don't know why That They even have stamps.
Speaker 1: it's like we could just tax people to make letter-sending free.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I feel like unlike other government services.
Speaker 0: That should just be free.
Speaker 0: Like I'm not worried about people over.
Speaker 1: Feel like you should just be able to go to a post like a mailbox and dump a million letters.
Speaker 1: now You want to know why not spam?
Speaker 0: Imagine what spam would be like if that was literally just free right non-commercial mail.
Speaker 0: It's not commercial.
Speaker 0: I'm just happy dude asking for a dollar If You can make that many letters Pretty easy to print things.
Speaker 0: I it is remember when I printed some keep nice flowers a long time ago.
Speaker 0: It is cheaper to print a hundred thousand of something then to print ten thousand of something.
Speaker 1: Anyway, they also got the postcard.
Speaker 1: you buy a postcard.
Speaker 1: It has.
Speaker 1: it's a piece of cardboard.
Speaker 1: The stamp is already built into it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and then you just write on the outside, you know envelope know nothing.
Speaker 1: Everyone can see what you wrote.
Speaker 0: What's interesting is as a kid for than a regular letter though, like I used to mail letters and cards and things a lot Yep.
Speaker 0: But I can't really remember why and I feel like I didn't want to and I was forced to like, uh You've got a mail Christmas cards to every relative every year.
Speaker 1: I didn't do that.
Speaker 1: But what you know, I would send letters and I was younger because pen pal in elementary school and he wrote back once.
Speaker 1: These are days, you know before email.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and you know phone calls were not.
Speaker 0: you know Ten cents a minute was considered a really cheap long-distance.
Speaker 0: long-distance phone calls were a thing Long-distance meant like the next town over right.
Speaker 1: but even socially speaking phone calls were not always the best for every occasion.
Speaker 0: Well, cuz people weren't home people only had phones in their houses, right?
Speaker 1: So yeah, you would sometimes send letters to people right or receive letters from people right and it's like even nowadays.
Speaker 1: It's like if I'm you know text message someone I can send them like a link.
Speaker 1: Right, even if I call you on the phone, I can't send you like Information.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so I had to clip a newspaper article put it in an envelope and mail it to you.
Speaker 0: No in the modern era like talk using a phone to call someone just like almost worthless.
Speaker 1: Yeah You know, so yeah letters were a thing and there were.
Speaker 1: some times you would be in a situation Where you'd be away from technology like summer camp.
Speaker 1: That's when I would send the most letters because the only you couldn't.
Speaker 1: oh, yeah There's no calling people.
Speaker 1: when you're in summer camp you you would write letters to people and then they would send letter or you have A pen pal.
Speaker 0: see Ben can.
Speaker 1: now I don't need pen pal I could just meet people from other countries on the internet, you know, right?
Speaker 0: It's funny because by the time I went to band cam I just had a cell phone.
Speaker 0: so just brought the cell phone to band camp and if I've needed to call anyone I just called them.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know only rich people had him in those late 90s.
Speaker 0: We were not rich late 90s.
Speaker 1: only rich people had the cell phone.
Speaker 0: The thing is what the cell phone we had.
Speaker 0: the caveat was because we were not rich.
Speaker 0: You had very short conversations on that phone or it was a problem.
Speaker 0: it's my conversation with things like Sunday.
Speaker 0: I've got 45 seconds left to explain to you where to pick me up.
Speaker 1: Okay, that's when you would buy minutes for your cell phone.
Speaker 1: play minutes.
Speaker 1: Do you have now?
Speaker 1: Everyone just says unlimited talking text.
Speaker 1: They don't remember the times when it's like.
Speaker 1: yeah, you only bought 10 minutes of talk.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you talk for 10 minutes.
Speaker 1: if you talk for 11 minutes, you're poor.
Speaker 0: but nowadays I really only need to send.
Speaker 0: When I renew my lease I need to send a giant like the envelope full of like a really thick document somewhere like so once every couple years and I Don't have to ever send letters.
Speaker 0: Otherwise.
Speaker 1: just about every company has updated.
Speaker 0: even my rent is just automatically paid now.
Speaker 1: paperless billing You know, so you don't have to send anything.
Speaker 1: when you pay a bill you get your bill in an email like just about all the uses of Mailing things have been eliminated and replaced with digital equivalent.
Speaker 0: Well mailing things like letters right information, right?
Speaker 1: So it's like I have.
Speaker 0: our friend Chase was in Singapore and I had a and I had a whole bunch of Singapore dollars and I didn't think I'd go Back there anytime soon.
Speaker 0: and here I am going back to Singapore.
Speaker 0: So we just stuffed all the Singapore money we had in an envelope just mailed it to him, right?
Speaker 1: It's like you can't.
Speaker 1: you know, I guess you could wire the money but it's yeah.
Speaker 0: Why are you money?
Speaker 0: would it cost more than that money was?
Speaker 0: wiring money is crazy expensive, right?
Speaker 1: And the point is you have Singapore dollars wiring money.
Speaker 1: Well, you could just wire any fucking currency.
Speaker 0: Yeah Then I would still have had these Singapore dollars.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but the post office is transformed from something that was to send Information and stuff to send stuff and sending stuff was super expensive and kind of rare, right?
Speaker 1: You would usually all the stuff would be sent to stores and like by freight and you would go to stores to get stuff.
Speaker 0: Yeah, my parents when we bought furniture.
Speaker 0: like many times it was freight shipping meaning it would be delivered to a freight distribution center and then we had to pay someone else to Drive it to our house or we had to go to a freight distribution center and pick it up right.
Speaker 1: and nowadays The post office and other shipping companies are all about sending stuff and not really about sending information.
Speaker 0: Thanks primarily to Amazon.
Speaker 0: So nowadays it's I very rarely ship things, but I very commonly receive shipments.
Speaker 1: Yes And that's it's so weird.
Speaker 1: It's like even when I'm thinking it's like well, I haven't bought anything in a long time.
Speaker 1: I'm done buying stuff everything I need for like months.
Speaker 1: The only things I'm buying are like, you know Consumable goods that like, you know have to keep replenishing.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right.
Speaker 1: And meanwhile, I still keep getting fucking packages in the mail all the time.
Speaker 1: I'm like, Jesus Christ this, you know I feel like every other day some Amazon package shows up and like Fuck it on Amazon in like a month.
Speaker 1: What the hell?
Speaker 0: Yeah, but then I open the box.
Speaker 0: I'm like, oh, yeah It's that thing I needed.
Speaker 1: It's like oh, I needed that shoe hard for my boots or whatever.
Speaker 1: But it's like, you know the the doorman are now like, you know in the city Didn't?
Speaker 1: they used to be people that open the door for you or helped you out, you know?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't have.
Speaker 0: 90% of what they do.
Speaker 1: Dorman do now is collect all the packages and distribute them to the people who are.
Speaker 0: building only has like 140 something apartments in.
Speaker 0: it's a pretty small building and despite that the mail room where like the doorman keep like all the packages is Stuffed to the brim with packages.
Speaker 1: literally every day I think everyone comes home and picks up all their packages probably within a day or two unless they're out of town and meanwhile More just keep coming.
Speaker 1: So that room at night after all the deliveries have come in It's empty should be pretty empty and then it's literally the next day is like just completely full overflowing when the deliveries come.
Speaker 0: And even funnier there isn't even a break on Sunday because a lot of people use there's.
Speaker 0: you know It used to be like when I was a kid.
Speaker 0: I remember there was the post office or like UPS or if you were a business FedEx.
Speaker 0: there weren't really other ways for normal people to ship things.
Speaker 0: There weren't that many companies, but now there's all these Semi-independent.
Speaker 1: there were but it was.
Speaker 1: it wasn't so easy, right?
Speaker 1: It's like you had to go.
Speaker 1: They were either specialized or I had to go and get like UP.
Speaker 1: They're like UPS store is a thing that only came into existence like during in my memory.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like I remember when there were no FedEx and UPS stores, right?
Speaker 1: You wanted to mail a thing.
Speaker 1: you had to like package it up yourself.
Speaker 1: You couldn't like go and print out a shipping label and your computer like go to the post office Go to a special place and do special stuff and prepare.
Speaker 0: it was you know, shipping was not simple Yep, and when I actually raw ship something it is really easy now mostly because like remember my camera broke So I had to ship that giant camera.
Speaker 1: Well, if you go to a UPS store type place, you know or a FedEx King They just handle it.
Speaker 1: you can give them an object.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, and be like mail this object to this address and you pay them enough money.
Speaker 1: They will box Bubble wrap.
Speaker 0: Oh, I did that.
Speaker 0: I don't trust myself to box a like $4,000 giant camera.
Speaker 1: just give them the objects you want to send and they will Take care of literally every aspect of the shipping and you just give them money.
Speaker 0: Yep, and it wasn't that much they wanted like $11 to like.
Speaker 1: right if you box it yourself, you can save some money.
Speaker 1: Also, they'll have like in the store like boxes and tapes like you could just buy the supplies.
Speaker 0: Yeah yourself, but they'll make if I box it myself They were like.
Speaker 0: you can boxes yourself But then you have to sign this thing saying if it breaks it's not our fault.
Speaker 1: The biggest hassle is that if you're in a situation where you're a seller of things, right?
Speaker 0: Oh my god the geek night t-shirts I'll tell my anecdote.
Speaker 1: You're silly if you're selling things.
Speaker 1: First of all, you got quantity problems, but the big problem we have is pricing problems.
Speaker 1: because much like we talked about long-distance phone calls Sending stuff unless you use flat rate shipping, which is usually not the most economical is just simple.
Speaker 1: Sometimes it's most economical but it's you had to calculate.
Speaker 1: to figure out if it is right is you need to know the weight Based on the weight of the things you're sending their shape and also where you're sending them to.
Speaker 1: the price will vary and it is very hard to accurately calculate in advance the shipping price.
Speaker 1: and But when you sell something to someone you want to charge them shipping and handling before right?
Speaker 1: Yeah want to be like, okay Give me money for the thing then I'll mail it.
Speaker 1: then you then I'll tell you what it cost to set me to mail it And then I trust you to send me that money.
Speaker 1: They'll send you zero because you've already mailed it, right?
Speaker 1: It's like you got to charge the shipping in advance not being able to completely accurately calculate what that shipping will be Unless you have like a postal scale and all sorts of stuff going on.
Speaker 0: and you see this especially with Kickstarters.
Speaker 0: so many people will do a Kickstarter But they don't really understand the logistics of shipping things and then they end up losing money on their whole Kickstarter because I couldn't afford to pay the shipping costs
Speaker 1: like, you know, okay, I start a Kickstarter right and it's like, okay I'll charge, you know $5 to US shipping and $20 for international shipping, right and then Somehow your project gets really popular in I don't know Lithuania.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and it turns out it costs $30 to ship to Lithuania and a hundred people bought your thing.
Speaker 1: They're a hundred people from Lithuania kick-started you.
Speaker 1: that's now a hundred times ten.
Speaker 1: You just lost $1,000.
Speaker 0: Yep, right now the easy thing is that like the gig nights t-shirt, which stay tuned That design is so old like it's Scott still has hair.
Speaker 0: I'm making some new geek night's t-shirts.
Speaker 0: I'm working on that.
Speaker 0: So stay tuned.
Speaker 0: but in the old days I did all like.
Speaker 0: we made the t-shirts ourselves like directly working with t-shirt companies and screen printers and In the house and later the apartment.
Speaker 0: I just had this giant giant shelf filled with t-shirts of every different size and Like three different days like on Monday Wednesday and Saturday.
Speaker 0: I would just look at all the orders that came in Package all of them up and then I'd go to work and over lunch I just lugged this like box full of these packages to the post office and one by one I'd put them on the scale and I'd mail them all away.
Speaker 1: That sucks scale and print out a thing.
Speaker 1: You'd slap it on scale print out of things slap it on.
Speaker 0: Yep sucked ass Yep, so what I ended up doing now is I just can't.
Speaker 0: Amazon just makes the t-shirts for me prints them on demand They handle everything and they handle the shipping just in Amazon.
Speaker 1: There's a lot of like these fulfillment services now for people who just they want to.
Speaker 1: you want to.
Speaker 1: your business is Buying and selling stuffs, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, and so you will focus on the stuff.
Speaker 1: there are a lot of businesses that just focus on the shipping logistics part and You will you can like just send them your stuff and then they take care of distributing it to all the different place.
Speaker 1: You know, it's like distributors, you know Sometimes it's a distributor, but sometimes it's not sometimes like a fulfillment center.
Speaker 1: Now basically, you know you outsource that biz and you lose some money on it.
Speaker 1: Like if you do if you let Amazon do it yet You have to pay them for like the time if you leave something in an Amazon warehouse You got to pay them for the space it takes up and the time it's there.
Speaker 1: Yep, but you know at least.
Speaker 1: then you know if someone buys it you don't have to do anything You just let you just get a notification like someone bought your thing.
Speaker 1: Here's your money.
Speaker 0: The thing that I find the most annoying is the times I've had to return like it's sort of like the consequence of our delivery culture.
Speaker 0: now if something shows up broken and I have to return it or if something Doesn't work out and end up having to return it to get it repaired or serviced or something But I've already thrown out the box that came in because I live.
Speaker 1: Big mistake.
Speaker 0: that's happened many times.
Speaker 0: I don't keep the boxes very long.
Speaker 1: You still have the box.
Speaker 1: you can just print out a return label.
Speaker 1: sometimes there's even a return label in the box.
Speaker 1: Yep you just put the thing back in the box put the thing on and I can actually go like the.
Speaker 1: There's like bodegas in my neighborhood that are like UPS centers or FedEx centers.
Speaker 1: I could just bring it.
Speaker 0: Your your device is making a noise.
Speaker 0: Why are you interrupting the show with your weird device noise that you don't recognize?
Speaker 0: anyway I don't think that noise came from any of my devices.
Speaker 1: Anyway, the point is You can just drop it off there, you know tape it shut.
Speaker 1: all you need is tape and a label and you're good.
Speaker 1: However, I've had this sometimes depending on where you live.
Speaker 1: could there's an even more convenient return option?
Speaker 1: Right buy something and you know from online.
Speaker 1: But if that place you bought it from online is Zappos, well, you have to mail it back.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right But buy something online and that store happens to be in your neighborhood the Microsoft store for my laptop.
Speaker 1: Walk to the market.
Speaker 1: Buy something online from Apple and then it you get a broken iPhone in the mail.
Speaker 1: You go to the Apple store and then you can deal with that much more easily.
Speaker 0: But again, that's something that only applies to people who live in cities.
Speaker 0: Yeah aren't that?
Speaker 1: many of those can also Buy things online and have them sent to a store of the same brand and pick it up at the store.
Speaker 1: I know if the store is near you.
Speaker 0: I remember the only time we've I've ever really had like a Mailing failure like a bad one was you and me.
Speaker 0: wasn't that bad.
Speaker 0: Remember we went to the first packs, Australia Yep, and we had that.
Speaker 0: there was that giant Animal Crossing poster.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah that we got.
Speaker 0: that was like the official thing from the booth.
Speaker 1: It was a special Animal Crossing poster that you would like.
Speaker 1: you would take a photo with QR codes on it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and then you would get Animal Crossing biz on your D and after Pax Pax was like you guys are still around for some Reason go home.
Speaker 0: But also do you want any of this garbage?
Speaker 0: We're just gonna throw it away.
Speaker 1: So we're just hanging all over.
Speaker 1: we took, you know, I guess Pax Os people got exclusive Animal Crossing biz.
Speaker 1: So we took the poster.
Speaker 1: we mailed it to our Animal Crossing loving friend at the very very good Australian post office.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we went to the post office and it was great.
Speaker 0: Like everything seemed like a post office is way better.
Speaker 1: the American post office is.
Speaker 1: I guess they spend more money on it They're not.
Speaker 1: the government isn't trying to make it suck.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: Our post office It's pretty hard to make it good.
Speaker 0: our post office is good is actually really great considering that the Republican Party has spent 80 years both not 80 more like 40 years trying to destroy it, right?
Speaker 1: It's like.
Speaker 1: it's like, you know, we talk about that all the time how the people will complain.
Speaker 1: It's like governments always fuck up everything.
Speaker 1: Therefore.
Speaker 1: We shouldn't have governments run things.
Speaker 1: Let's cut funding to things that the government sucks at doing.
Speaker 1: and it's like well actually you're.
Speaker 1: it's a self-fulfilling prophecy.
Speaker 1: If you just give gave more money to the thing it would stop sucking.
Speaker 0: It'd be like if I wanted gig nights to fail and I just made gig nights bad on purpose So it would fail.
Speaker 1: right for example, right the government never says our military sucks.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right Let's cut funding to it instead.
Speaker 1: They continue to fund it and I mean regardless of whether you think we should be doing that Which right is a separate issue.
Speaker 1: Oh, look, it doesn't suck because you spent money on it You made it not suck.
Speaker 1: if you spend money in the post office you make it not suck.
Speaker 1: Australia clearly spent money in their post office and made it not suck.
Speaker 1: But I don't think that poster ever got.
Speaker 1: poster did not get where it was going.
Speaker 0: It just disappeared.
Speaker 0: It's gone for about a tube.
Speaker 1: I put the thing in the tube.
Speaker 1: I wrote the address on the tube.
Speaker 1: I walked up to the counter.
Speaker 0: have photos of you putting it in the tube?
Speaker 1: Yeah, I guess it never got there.
Speaker 1: cuz no one ever told me they got it.
Speaker 0: maybe one day it'll get delivered.
Speaker 0: Is it a dead letter bin somewhere?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: Is occasionally like I get letters or I see letters?
Speaker 0: but people definitely don't know how to fill out envelopes anymore.
Speaker 1: They taught us in school was like how to format a business letter how to write addresses on an envelope how to do all this stuff and You know, I still it's a useful skill.
Speaker 1: But I think a people aren't taught that anymore because you don't do it as much.
Speaker 1: but there's what bothers me.
Speaker 0: I'm not the old man who's gonna complain.
Speaker 1: office will surprisingly deliver things if the address is written.
Speaker 0: really Remember when Penn Jillette said hey try to mail shit to me.
Speaker 0: Just write Penn Jillette Las Vegas Yeah.
Speaker 1: and like a weird person like a high percentage of those letters made it to him the The threshold for which what you write on an envelope will get to where you think it's gonna go.
Speaker 0: Just won't quit Pretty low.
Speaker 1: you could probably write like Scott Reuben Queens, New York.
Speaker 1: It might get to me.
Speaker 0: Yeah Penn Jillette did an experiment with that where a bunch of the letters made it to him.
Speaker 1: also surprised seen people do stuff like Just take objects and just write just like put a sticker or literally write the address on the object Yeah, and then mail it with no box and it goes.
Speaker 1: I saw something like mailed a baseball bat with like.
Speaker 1: they just wrote on It with a sharpie and it got there.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the post office is really good because they had.
Speaker 0: they use a lot of technology like zip codes and OCR and like systems To handle all the mail that can be handled automatically, but then if none of these automated systems work There's always some letters or something's funky.
Speaker 0: a human being literally looks at it and decides with their human intelligence How to solve this problem and it works surprisingly Well, the post office is a model for that kind of your design.
Speaker 1: The thing is they're used for return addresses on things You know, you don't have to.
Speaker 1: but yeah you can.
Speaker 1: and if you say put an envelope in a mailbox With a return address and you forgot to put a stamp on it.
Speaker 1: They send it back to the return address.
Speaker 1: Yeah, or I always thought why don't I put the return address as the place I wanted to go to.
Speaker 0: Oh Yeah, the good old return address scam, right?
Speaker 0: I always thought about that too and you know why I never looked into actually trying to do it because the stamp was a quarter.
Speaker 1: Yeah That's also why I haven't actually tried to do it.
Speaker 1: I've always wondered like what if I put the return address as the address I wanted to go to and my address is the Main address and then not put a stamp and shove it in a mailbox and see what happens.
Speaker 1: I think if it was a faraway place, they would be like, yeah return address, Florida.
Speaker 1: I don't think so.
Speaker 1: New York post a post box mailbox.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I looked this up a few times, but if I did like another person in the neighborhood, I feel like it might work, right?
Speaker 0: I'm pretty sure they have way like they can detect that this situation has happened.
Speaker 0: But the question is would they care unless it was something big and expensive?
Speaker 0: Yep, in which case I'm pretty sure they would care.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: I don't care enough because I don't need to save what I guess.
Speaker 1: 55 cents Effectively zero because my forever stamps are so old.
Speaker 1: I'm like saving money by using those stamps.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I bought those stamps when they came out.
Speaker 0: Well, not when they came out.
Speaker 0: I bought them.
Speaker 0: I want to say five or six years ago is the last time about stamps.
Speaker 1: You know, I know some trivia.
Speaker 1: So, you know Ponzi scheme Ponzi, yeah, you know what the original the guy Ponzi the actual person is named after.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know what their original scam was Sam collecting.
Speaker 1: No It was a stamp scam where basically there was a way to buy like stamp prices, right?
Speaker 1: It was basically arbitrage.
Speaker 1: You know how we talk about steam games are cheap elsewhere.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right He was basically like listen I got this thing where I buy stamps in another country and then resell them in the US at.
Speaker 1: you know Undercut post office stamp prices But they're still way higher than the foreign stamp price.
Speaker 1: and then I make a lot of money selling all these stamps Invest in my business.
Speaker 1: everyone invested in the business.
Speaker 1: He Ponzi schemed.
Speaker 1: He never bought a goddamn stamp.
Speaker 1: That was just a lie But that was the scam.
Speaker 1: Yeah, not bad original Ponzi scheme was Claim that you're buying cheap stamps in a foreign country and selling them for a few pennies less than American price in America.
Speaker 0: Oh in the stream to someone from Canada as a question Do we have mail machines for returning prepaid packages at post offices?
Speaker 0: Apparently Canada has that a mail machine a machine.
Speaker 0: You can just return a prepaid like something that was shipped to you with a prepaid thing.
Speaker 0: You can just return it generically via the post office.
Speaker 0: We do not have anything like that.
Speaker 1: No, you have to get.
Speaker 1: yeah, if it's like UPS like a Zappos, right?
Speaker 0: You need like a specific.
Speaker 1: I print a return label I tape it on the box with the shoes inside and I go to a Has to be a UPS place and then I need this has to be a person with a scanner.
Speaker 1: that goes peep and then it's Like.
Speaker 1: you don't have to do much.
Speaker 1: Usually I could walk into the store put a Zappos box in the counter and they'll just give me a thumbs up.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and you're good to go now.
Speaker 0: what we do have that's pretty good.
Speaker 0: If you go to a US post office in the modern era, they have self-service machines.
Speaker 0: They're actually pretty amazing.
Speaker 1: it's basically a scale a touchscreen and you put your thing on a wheel.
Speaker 1: you mess with the touchscreen.
Speaker 1: it prints out a Basically a digital but it'll do label and you slap it on your box.
Speaker 0: It'll do Anything.
Speaker 0: you can mail something almost anywhere in the world with all kinds of like.
Speaker 0: you can just do Anything and it just works.
Speaker 0: It's really easy to use.
Speaker 0: but every time I have to use that what I find is that there's only like three machines, which is fine and I've never seen a human being other than myself interact with one of these machines.
Speaker 1: I see him use all the time in a manner that is intelligent and rational.
Speaker 1: You mean?
Speaker 0: Yeah, people are really slow Literally like when I had to mail our lease.
Speaker 0: I couldn't just put stamps on it because it was big.
Speaker 0: it there was a giant envelope and it was kind of heavy because it's Thick.
Speaker 0: so I was gonna use that.
Speaker 0: I did wait for that machine.
Speaker 1: Oh, I just crammed it in a regular envelope.
Speaker 0: It's way too.
Speaker 0: It does not fit in a regular.
Speaker 0: It's like 30 pages long.
Speaker 1: I managed it somehow.
Speaker 0: How thin is your lease?
Speaker 1: I tear off only the pages that have The.
Speaker 0: oh, no, we have to mail the whole thing back.
Speaker 0: I have to sign it like 10 times.
Speaker 1: We'll see about that.
Speaker 0: I have a lot of riders on my lease.
Speaker 0: Uh-huh.
Speaker 0: Anyway, also this year it had a whole bunch of like because there's a new law.
Speaker 0: Here's things that your landlord has to tell you that I had to initial that I read and all this nonsense.
Speaker 0: Anyway, I was there.
Speaker 0: There's three machines.
Speaker 0: One of us broken, you know America.
Speaker 0: the other two there was no line.
Speaker 0: There's just one person each one late lady was trying to like mail a small package somewhere And the other one was just a man trying to mail what looked like a normal letter.
Speaker 0: Neither one of them was finished with these machines after 20 minutes.
Speaker 1: They were just like usually when I go to the post office, they'll be a postal worker who's like helping people with the machines.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they seem.
Speaker 0: neither one of these people seem to quite understand how mail works.
Speaker 0: Yeah It was.
Speaker 0: it was really frustrating to the counter.
Speaker 0: the counter had a crazy long line of people mailing giant packages that I wanted nothing To do with.
Speaker 0: yep, because the post office I go to is the one next to Grand Central Like the big one the big one.
Speaker 0: That's the one where I go to like passport stuff.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you can do that almost.
Speaker 1: Yeah, yeah, we're not gonna talk about all the services the post office like money orders certified mails registered mails express mails.
Speaker 0: It's funny whenever I mail just like a letter like the few times I do it It costs a little that I'm almost just like I'll go full-on signature.
Speaker 0: You got a fucking sign to get my letter.
Speaker 0: I said you a Christmas card.
Speaker 0: You have to sign and I'm gonna get a signature receipt because it costs like a dollar And it's just funny to do that.
Speaker 0: So be I have had fun Many times more earlier than now because I don't mail things that often anymore.
Speaker 0: But I could put a lot of stuff into a flat rate box.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, I have put terrifying amounts of weight in a flat rate boxes before lead brick.
Speaker 0: I Think we killed enough time in this show.
Speaker 0: I also hungry so stay tuned.
Speaker 1: send me some food in the mail.
Speaker 0: There will be careful.
Speaker 0: I just imagined someone's gonna put like.
Speaker 0: they're gonna write Scott Ruben Queens on an apple and just drop it in a post office box.
Speaker 1: I'll peel it and then you Don't eat that Sharpie.
Speaker 0: But there will be no geek nights for two weeks, but there may be some live streams and things I might post while I'm traveling.
Speaker 0: I'll be posting photos and social media.
Speaker 0: Scott might be live streaming some games.
Speaker 0: We'll see what happens.
Speaker 1: Don't promise me.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna do anything every year around this time It's hard for the geek night just has a bunch of weird.
Speaker 0: I atis is until January and then things get back to normal.
Speaker 0: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at front row crew comm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 0: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 1: But unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night
Speaker 0: And the patreon patrons for this episode of geek nights are Alan Joyce, Heidi McNichol, Just Like a Dude Guy, Kajar Taubjian, William Eisnerows, Link Iji, Hydrated Gannon, Supports Hong Kong Jennifer Hitchcock, Chris Midkiff, MyStady.com, Jay Bants, Sean Yeager, Nicholas Brando Let's see if rim says Toronto properly, 421 Creations, Started Making Trouble in My Neighborhood, Shervin Van Horl, Rory, Superboy, Clinton Walton, Ren from New Zealand, Ryan Perrin, Dropenlander, Finn, Dread, Lily Tenebrae, Sean Klein Chris Reimer, Thomas Han.
Speaker 0: Here's something that you don't hear every day and Stay tuned as you know won't be a lot of geek nights for two weeks because I will be In Asia Pacific wandering around but I will try to do a few live streams and a few little like hey Here's the thing.
Speaker 0: I learned about this place because I've never been to Bangkok or Manila before but now I leave you with.