Speaker 0: It's Wednesday, March 20th, 2019.
Speaker 0: I'm Rim.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott.
Speaker 0: And this is Geek Nights.
Speaker 0: Tonight, cute Twitter comics.
Speaker 0: The little guys.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: So if any of you saw some of our recent panels that were uploaded, you might have noticed that all our panels from PAX is for a while now and MagFest have been, not just in 4k, but multiple camera angles.
Speaker 0: Not the old way where there's one really good camera and then one really bad camera because I got that fancy new camera and Scott has his good camera.
Speaker 0: So we actually have two good 4k cameras to record our stuff.
Speaker 0: However, my fancy new camera suffered from an internal lens crash.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'd never seen anything like that in my life short of a camera being physically, you know, manhandled in a bad way.
Speaker 0: If I had dropped this camera down the stairs, I would have expected something like that to happen.
Speaker 0: But from what I gathered talking to people about it, because the camera's gonna be fine, this is the kind of thing that can happen with running guns and studio cameras if they are spun or moved too quickly while they're being powered down or right after they're powered off because the lens has a pretty big stabilizer thing in it and it basically has to move the lens to a spot and like lock it and it's a race condition that can happen in a lot of different cameras like that.
Speaker 0: Anyway, what happened was one of the internal lenses crashed into another internal lens and scratched the shit out of it.
Speaker 0: So after the last PAX, I go to turn it back on and it just doesn't turn on.
Speaker 0: I'm like, what the fuck?
Speaker 0: And then it's like lens error and I shook it a little bit and then I tried to turn it on again and it turned on.
Speaker 0: fine, but then I had like.
Speaker 0: the video quality looks kind of bad, like there's something wrong with it.
Speaker 0: I turn around and look inside and there's this big, these two white lines on the lens like way inside.
Speaker 0: I show it to Scott and Scott's like, what the fuck?
Speaker 1: I don't know what the hell happened.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's weird that you said they're gonna repair it for nothing.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so I guess when my camera had a problem, it was actually a well-known problem that the HDMI port, it was like this micro HDMI port and it was weak.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: And it was well-known to be weak, but when I wanted to repair it after it finally broke, which it lasted much longer than what other people had, other people had to break right away.
Speaker 1: They would not repair it for cheap or even or free at all.
Speaker 1: They wanted me to pay a ridiculous amount of money.
Speaker 1: So I ended up just buying a newer camera, which is basically this, you know, the, the, I went from GH4 to GH5 and mostly because GH5 has a full size HDMI port that is like invincible.
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 1: And they even give you like this little bracket so that like the wire can't get tugged on and stuff.
Speaker 1: It screws in.
Speaker 1: So I don't think I need to upgrade.
Speaker 1: I wouldn't have upgraded if it weren't for that.
Speaker 1: So then I sold my GH4 to someone who did not need the HDMI port because the rest of it worked just fine.
Speaker 0: So basically, if I had just bought the camera, I would have had to pay for that repair probably.
Speaker 0: But it's probably, it looks like it'd only be like a thousand bucks or something because it's a lot of money.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but relative to the cost of the camera.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but for me, a thousand dollar repair was basically, I could have bought a GH4 new for $800.
Speaker 0: I mean, to be fair, a thousand dollars would be like approaching, like that's actually a little less than a third of the cost of the camera.
Speaker 1: By the way, if anyone out there is listening and is like, you know, thinking, I want to get a camera, you can buy like GH4 or GH4 era digital cameras for like almost no money.
Speaker 1: And they are ridiculous for what you're paying.
Speaker 0: Even for video, they won't have like the really common like usability features of a fancy camcorder.
Speaker 0: But if you're willing to put up with that annoyance, the picture quality is phenomenal.
Speaker 1: I don't think there's that much annoyance.
Speaker 0: Well, like having XLR built in and stuff like that.
Speaker 1: You can get the thing that attaches to the bottom.
Speaker 1: How much does that thing cost?
Speaker 1: Yeah, but you can probably get it for way cheap because no one fucking wants it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, last time I looked, it was still expensive.
Speaker 1: Yeah, to buy like a new one at MSRP.
Speaker 1: But I'm sure you can find someone with a used one who's like, I got rid of my GH4.
Speaker 0: Basically, for a camcorder like this, like the cost of the lens is about a third the cost of the camera itself.
Speaker 0: The lens is a big part of the cost of a camera like that.
Speaker 0: But because I bought this camera on Amazon, even though I got it direct from the manufacturer, just like through Amazon, one, I got the 5% off because Amazon card like, duh.
Speaker 0: And two, I bought the like $70 will fucking fix it, no questions asked thing that Amazon always tries to sell you.
Speaker 1: Whenever I see a pop up for any kind of warranty or anything like that, I never get it unless it's AppleCare.
Speaker 0: Well, so my policy has always been if it's technology that I'm spending more than a couple thousand dollars on and it's technology that I'm going to be using and carrying around as opposed to just it's in my house and it never moves, I'll often pay the pittance for whatever insurance company to do the.
Speaker 0: we'll just fix it, no questions asked for like three years thing.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but I also feel like, you know, I already have, you know, like renter's insurance, renter's insurance wouldn't have covered this.
Speaker 1: No, but I also have like.
Speaker 1: if you buy something with your credit card, you have like purchase protection that depends on your credit card.
Speaker 1: But like just buying something with a credit card.
Speaker 1: if your credit card offers purchase protection means you automatically have like a warranty against theft and damage for some amount of time.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't actually know if my card has that because I haven't had to use it.
Speaker 0: So here's my thinking, this is a big ass, like run and gun professional camera that I'm going to be carrying around conventions.
Speaker 1: And then there's the warranty you get just by default for the manufacturer.
Speaker 0: And the warranty on it's really good because it's a fancy camera.
Speaker 0: But I paid seventy dollars for the insurance that says if you fucking drop this in the ocean because you're dumb, we'll just replace it.
Speaker 0: No questions asked.
Speaker 0: So I assumed at some point, like over the next three years, like some nerd would like trip on me and break my camera in an expo hall at a PAX or something.
Speaker 0: But this thing happened and I'm going to get it fixed for free that I just got to ship it to him.
Speaker 0: They're going to fix it and it's all going to tell me most of the time those insurances are a scam, but I guess they still actually work.
Speaker 0: So if you do pay, I had to do a lot of paperwork, but I did it all and it seems like it's going to work.
Speaker 0: But the only reason I trusted this one at all was that a lot of paperwork for a thousand dollars seems fair.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Like if you crash your car and you're going to have your insurance company like pay for the whole car, they're going to make you fill out a couple of forms.
Speaker 0: They're not just going to do it.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So the more.
Speaker 0: the only reason I trusted this was that I bought it through Amazon because when I bought the camera, what I assumed was suppose I try to use this insurance and it doesn't work.
Speaker 0: I'm going to call I'm going to go after Amazon.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I'm going to go first of all, tell him as on customer service and then I'll go to.
Speaker 1: I'll go to small claims court if I have to say, hey, I bought this fucking warranty.
Speaker 1: It says this and they won't pay up because in my interactions with Amazon over, you know, a small claims court for a thousand dollars.
Speaker 0: I guess it's like three grand the limit.
Speaker 0: I forget.
Speaker 0: I don't know what is.
Speaker 1: what the hell do I know?
Speaker 0: I think it's actually three grand.
Speaker 0: What is the limit?
Speaker 0: Ten grand to change?
Speaker 0: Except the plaintiff may not file a claim for over twenty five hundred dollars more than twice a year.
Speaker 0: That's actually a good rule.
Speaker 1: You can't be an asshole.
Speaker 0: And if you take someone to small claims court more than like once every few years, I feel like you're the asshole.
Speaker 0: Yeah, most likely.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so I figured every time I've ever had a problem with anything I bought on Amazon, even if it was possibly my fault or like it's a dubious situation, Amazon's response has always been.
Speaker 0: Here's the thing for free.
Speaker 0: Sorry.
Speaker 0: That's why we have multiple of this leather.
Speaker 1: Only one time did they fuck me over.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they've never fucked me over.
Speaker 0: I think they in fact, for reasons.
Speaker 0: Remember when I thought that monitor that got shipped to me was a bomb?
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So the end result of all that was I got a free four K monitor because Amazon.
Speaker 0: So one of these four K monitors was free in the end.
Speaker 0: And the person who was holding the bag is either Amazon or the scammer.
Speaker 0: I don't care who held the bag because the bag contained not a bomb, but a free four K monitor.
Speaker 0: That is a legit ultra sharp that I registered for the warranty to make sure it wasn't like weird gray market.
Speaker 0: No, it's legit.
Speaker 0: It's real.
Speaker 0: It's good.
Speaker 0: So, yeah.
Speaker 0: So what this means is that I'm not videoing any of our panels as thank icon because I don't care.
Speaker 0: I don't.
Speaker 0: I just don't video anything in a small town because they're not going to have like lighting or like the stuff.
Speaker 0: And do it means we're only going to have one camera on the new panel at PAX East, the real harm of games, because my camcorder is not going to come back until shortly after PAX East.
Speaker 0: So I feel like that's fine.
Speaker 1: You can rent a camera if you really want.
Speaker 0: I don't care that much.
Speaker 0: All this means is that if your camera messes up, there's no video.
Speaker 0: because every now and then we mess up like there's a couple of panels where like Scott's camera was fine.
Speaker 0: But like I derp the autofocus or I derp the focus.
Speaker 0: So mine's blurry.
Speaker 0: So we didn't use mine like that's happened.
Speaker 0: Sometimes Scott's camera was set up wrong and mine was fine.
Speaker 0: Sometimes like Scott's camera is perfect, but nerd like bumps it while we're on stage and then it's ruined for the second half of the panel.
Speaker 0: So anyway, that's what happened to me.
Speaker 0: My camera is going to get fixed.
Speaker 1: OK, so for as long as I've been, as long as I can remember.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Conan the Barbaro comics came from Dark Horse Comics.
Speaker 1: And no one was really reading new ones so much.
Speaker 1: There are legendary old ones that are amazing and they kept making new ones occasionally.
Speaker 1: I don't really know because I didn't pay that much attention, but I always knew the Conan the Barbaro comics are in the Dark Horse section of previews.
Speaker 0: I will admit, I know almost nothing about Conan or the canon of Conan.
Speaker 1: By Grom.
Speaker 1: Conan is basically just like sword and sorcery, but it's best incarnation, but also its most classic incarnation.
Speaker 1: Anyway.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Regardless, what's happened is Marvel, meaning Disney, has the rights for publishing.
Speaker 1: Conan comics have fallen away from Dark Horse and gone back to the Marvel after a very long period of time.
Speaker 1: And they got some new Marvel Conan comics that are brand new.
Speaker 1: Don't know how good they are.
Speaker 1: Don't care.
Speaker 1: Craziness.
Speaker 1: They just can't fucking help themselves.
Speaker 1: Conan the Barbarian is now an Avenger.
Speaker 0: I've all right.
Speaker 1: Conan, for all history, Conan comics have always been their own thing, not in any universe.
Speaker 1: For the first time, they're like, you know what?
Speaker 1: Because we can.
Speaker 1: We're just going to throw Conan on some Avengers team.
Speaker 1: It's like Savage Avengers or some shit.
Speaker 0: So what can Conan and Thor go?
Speaker 1: Like, I don't fucking know.
Speaker 1: Like Conan and the Vision and Scarlet Witch.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: Whatever.
Speaker 1: Why not Conan and Wolverine?
Speaker 1: Probably that's what you're going to see.
Speaker 1: But anyway, don't give any shits about that.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: What I do give a shit about is thanks to these rights, going to Marvel again, the original Marvel Conan.
Speaker 0: There was a what if, I think.
Speaker 1: OK.
Speaker 0: What if Wolverine battled Conan the Barbarian?
Speaker 1: There you go.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: Anyway, thanks to this, the original Conan comics, which Marvel ran for a very long time, I think, to the 90s from, you know, way back.
Speaker 1: That was like the ended in the 90s.
Speaker 1: They began way back.
Speaker 1: The amazing 1970, something like that.
Speaker 1: Super long time ago.
Speaker 1: They ran for like super.
Speaker 1: Those are now available legally.
Speaker 1: And digitally from Marvel comics that have been somewhat difficult to obtain and read, unless maybe you find any legal scan somewhere or found the originals, because it's like, you know, Marvel couldn't publish a compilation of them.
Speaker 1: Dark Horse couldn't either, right?
Speaker 1: So it's like these comics, which are really, really good, although obviously a product of their time.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's a good disclaimer to put there.
Speaker 1: Yes, but still really good with amazing story and artwork.
Speaker 1: So if you like Sward and Sorcery and Conan, these are now available again after a very long period of time where they were not available.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: For those of you who might be too young to even know anything about Conan, like if you didn't see the movies, which you don't need to, I haven't seen those movies since I was pretty young.
Speaker 0: It's one of those things where, like, is it going to be a He-Man situation if I watch these movies again?
Speaker 0: Because I liked them.
Speaker 1: This is one of those things where the comic is like the one true Conan and all other Conan's are like, they're not the same, not the real deal, get them out of here.
Speaker 0: So I think we talked about this briefly and I don't want to linger on it, but conventions are coming up and...
Speaker 1: Isn't this Metamoment?
Speaker 0: Oh, no, no, no.
Speaker 0: I'm not talking about our convention stuff.
Speaker 0: So in the anime world, that Vic Mignona thing is actually getting worse.
Speaker 1: See, it's weird when people say this, not that I just believe you, but in all the media, I read a lot of Internet, a lot, the most.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there's a difference between the two of us.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: And I see all these tweets and I see all these Facebooks and, you know, a week or two ago, a few weeks ago, and we talked about this, I saw tons and tons of tweets about this all over the place.
Speaker 1: But I always saw the tweets from the good people saying, you know, how fucked up this thing was.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: And then now I have not seen a Vic related tweet in since then.
Speaker 0: Not at all.
Speaker 1: So you say it's getting worse, but like I see nothing happening.
Speaker 1: I see no tweets from bad or good people or on any other site.
Speaker 1: I see like no news about any developments whatsoever.
Speaker 0: So part of that, I think, is that you like the people who are involved in this are increasingly so isolated from people like us that we would never encounter them unless we looked for them.
Speaker 0: And that also applies to most of the people we would even want to interact with on Twitter.
Speaker 0: Like, for example, you know, it's getting worse because the one difference between you and I is that I go to the dark places of the Internet to see what's going on on purpose.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Also, I am still tuned into a lot of the convention management that you ignore.
Speaker 0: And this is still a problem at conventions.
Speaker 0: Basically, it's gotten to the point that it's basically gamer gate.
Speaker 0: now, like the people who are mad about this are going full gamer gate and are just directly harassing and doxing other voice actors and people who run conventions.
Speaker 1: You know, this seems to be a thing that that keeps happening and, you know, where there's some sort of hubbub with a hashtag and then a war or a battle.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 0: But the battle is always like the worst neckbeards on earth, just doxing random people that they feel like I'm saying there's a gamer gate.
Speaker 1: This is there's plenty of things like this.
Speaker 1: We should probably like learn how to win these things because they're going to happen over and over and over.
Speaker 0: This is like legit meme warfare.
Speaker 1: We should learn how to win these things.
Speaker 1: So when the next one happens, we can easily a recognize up one of those things is happening and then be deploy our arsenal and extinguish it.
Speaker 0: Well, never forget, when gamer gate first happened, a lot of people who should have known better were tricked by it.
Speaker 0: I remember in the first week you and I were both like, what is this fucking bullshit?
Speaker 0: And then immediately I see people like not getting it and scheduling panels and like companies like not understanding it.
Speaker 0: It keeps happening and people still get tricked by it.
Speaker 0: I feel like people aren't being tricked by this one, like the conventions all know.
Speaker 0: I mean, look, all the anime conventions that just disinvited Vic from the convention, they know what's up.
Speaker 0: They know exactly what's up.
Speaker 0: They did the right thing.
Speaker 0: The handful of conventions that didn't.
Speaker 0: They also know what's up.
Speaker 0: They're just evil.
Speaker 0: Like they're the bad conventions, like they're doing it on purpose.
Speaker 0: So it's not a matter of people being tricked anymore.
Speaker 0: It's a matter of what do we do about these harassment, doxing brigades, because they're really going after.
Speaker 0: Monica Real was nothing to do with this.
Speaker 0: It's just that's the person in the industry these neckbeards decided to go after.
Speaker 0: So if all I'm saying is if you work at a convention or do anything with fan conventions, if you aren't aware, this is the same bullshit as gamer gate and you need to take the same kinds of actions you took.
Speaker 0: Just blanket ban these people from the convention.
Speaker 0: Watch for fake panels coming in, trying to do stuff, put extra staff in the rooms.
Speaker 0: If you have any good voice actors, meaning most of them who might get harassed, especially if they're women, by these shit brigades.
Speaker 0: And on lighter notes, it's time for things of the day.
Speaker 0: What do you got?
Speaker 1: Which one did I go with?
Speaker 1: You door lock guy.
Speaker 0: You went with door lock guy.
Speaker 1: All right, so check this out.
Speaker 1: This dude is in his house.
Speaker 1: And he hears some kind of noise at the front door, like someone messing with his knob, the door knob, not his other knob.
Speaker 0: You know, the trope in every horror movie on earth.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Door knobs moving a little bit and you're like looking at it.
Speaker 1: So he goes and looks at his people and he sees someone's messing with his door lock, like trying to picket or some shit.
Speaker 1: So he gets out his camera and starts filming a video, you know, just because that's what you do.
Speaker 0: That's what you do.
Speaker 0: Like my old thing of the day of the guy in Scotland who like, he's like, he's holding his camera out the window and he's like, this guy's trying to crowbar into my house.
Speaker 0: And he already called the police.
Speaker 0: He's just watching and waiting.
Speaker 1: And then because the gentleman who is recording the video apparently ain't afraid of shit, he opens the door and produces an excellent thing of the day.
Speaker 0: He does what you and I should have done that one time at Anime Boston.
Speaker 0: One of my regrets in life is that I didn't do what is in this video that one time.
Speaker 0: Yeah, no spoilers.
Speaker 0: Just watch the video.
Speaker 0: It is.
Speaker 0: It's pretty good.
Speaker 0: The best part, I think, without spoiling anything, is that the excuse the guy has is 100% BS.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but the thing is, it is 100% BS, but it's amazing how he comes up with such a crazy excuse so quickly.
Speaker 0: But it's the kind of excuse that the kind of person who would break into someone's apartment by picking the lock would have at the tip of their tongue.
Speaker 1: And it's like, if that excuse is true, why didn't you just knock on my door and talk to me?
Speaker 0: Yeah, first, I'm pretty sure that individual was trying to steal things to buy either meth or spice.
Speaker 1: It doesn't seem to be high at the moment.
Speaker 0: No.
Speaker 0: Well, because if he was high at the moment, he doesn't need any money to go buy meth or spice.
Speaker 0: The problem is he is out of either meth or spice.
Speaker 1: He seems like a sober individual.
Speaker 0: Yes, he's sober now and he wants to not be sober.
Speaker 1: Wouldn't he be all sick, though?
Speaker 0: No, it depends.
Speaker 0: I mean, I don't want to tell a lot of anecdotes because a lot of the anecdotes I have are sad.
Speaker 0: But the kind of person that would do something like this is the kind of person that I often interacted with when I was in middle school because people like this lived in our suburb.
Speaker 0: And these are the kinds of excuses they would come up with when they were caught trying to break into people's houses in, like, middle school.
Speaker 0: I wasn't doing anything.
Speaker 0: I was just trying to ridiculous nonsense.
Speaker 0: that somehow does not involve me stealing shit from your house.
Speaker 1: Usually you'd find these kids like, here's the reason why I smashed your window and was trying to lift it up and climb inside with the step ladder.
Speaker 0: It's like that king of the hill where it is not because I was burgling.
Speaker 0: It's like that king of the hill where Dale Gribble like breaks into Hank's garage and Hank just like comes in with a baseball bat because he sees like a shadow rummaging through his stuff and he's like, "Halt,
Speaker 0: thief!".
Speaker 0: And then he turns on the light and it's Dale and Dale's like, "No, no, no, Hank, it's just me,
Speaker 0: Dale.".
Speaker 0: And then Hank stands over a second and then he menaces him with the baseball bat anyway and he's like, "Halt,
Speaker 0: thief!".
Speaker 0: I don't give a shit that it's you.
Speaker 0: So my thing of the day is near and dear to me because I had a similar incident happen to me at De Bellas.
Speaker 0: Oh, really?
Speaker 1: I didn't know about that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, never thought to tell the story.
Speaker 0: The video is simple.
Speaker 0: So I'm just going to read the tweet.
Speaker 0: So a couple of days ago, one of my co-workers accidentally let 22 quarts of ranch dressing slip out of her hand.
Speaker 1: And first you see- Why would you have 22 quarts all together in one thing?
Speaker 0: You've never worked in a restaurant before, have you?
Speaker 1: I'm just saying you could do one quart at a time.
Speaker 0: I remember at one point carrying what was probably, like, imagine a container that is big enough to put a body in, completely filled with pickles.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean, that's just efficient because you want to pick them all in the same brine.
Speaker 0: No, that was just how they were shipped to us to then distribute.
Speaker 0: I had containers of mayonnaise that were bigger than my monitor.
Speaker 0: So the video is great because first you see the aftermath.
Speaker 0: Then you see the security camera footage of the actual incident.
Speaker 0: It's tragic.
Speaker 0: But so there I was.
Speaker 0: I was in De Bellas.
Speaker 0: Well, we had someone because we had a bunch of meatballs that weren't going to make it too long, like we had extra meatballs.
Speaker 0: So we had decided, like as a group, to just cook them all in a giant pot and just make them.
Speaker 0: And everyone could eat meatballs for the next few days.
Speaker 0: Like any time you want free meatballs for anyone who works here, take as much home as you want.
Speaker 0: Like meatballs and sauce.
Speaker 0: I was trying to put a giant, giant container of paper towels on the highest, highest shelf, and the ladder was just fucking missing.
Speaker 0: So I'm just trying to like toss it up there and I keep failing.
Speaker 1: Seems like a bad idea.
Speaker 0: Oh, it was a terrible idea.
Speaker 0: And I eventually get it up there and then it immediately falls back down, hits me, hits this giant pot and falls on the ground.
Speaker 0: Ah, I look, no damage appears to have been done.
Speaker 0: The pot is intact.
Speaker 0: It's still full.
Speaker 0: No sauce got on me.
Speaker 0: No disaster.
Speaker 0: So I picked the things up and I keep tossing it up there and I get it up there and it's fine.
Speaker 0: I wait for a few minutes to make sure it doesn't just like fall.
Speaker 0: It doesn't.
Speaker 0: And I leave.
Speaker 0: The next day, I come back into the office, the office, I come back into De Bellas and the manager is like, did you spill autonomy balls yesterday?
Speaker 0: And I was like, what?
Speaker 0: No, and I didn't.
Speaker 0: And he's like, let's look at this footage.
Speaker 0: And I look at the footage and I see the incident as I described.
Speaker 0: There is no evidence that anything has gone wrong.
Speaker 0: What had happened that I did not see was that the container had tipped the pot sideways long enough for a shit ton of meatballs to slosh out.
Speaker 0: And just missed the wall and fall under the table behind a bunch of stuff.
Speaker 0: So you would not know anything had spilled unless you moved all that stuff out of the way.
Speaker 0: It was just like a perfect storm of a situation where no one would know that there was probably a couple pounds of meatballs hiding behind a table that no one could see unless they went looking for them.
Speaker 0: So that is my story.
Speaker 0: It is not that exciting.
Speaker 0: I did not get covered in meatballs.
Speaker 1: How did they find out that that happened to the smell or rats eating them?
Speaker 0: As far as I can, like that night, someone like went to get something from the bottom of the shelf and they pulled a bunch of stuff out and then they just found a pile of meatballs and they were like, WTF, what happened?
Speaker 1: Otherwise you could have had a real bad problem if no one discovered them or picked them up.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we could have had a...
Speaker 1: Like a health inspection that night?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think that it could have.
Speaker 0: that could have been a. what's that smell?
Speaker 0: It smells like a corpse.
Speaker 0: Oh, no, there are potatoes that have rotten.
Speaker 0: So in the minute moment this weekend, I will be at Zekicon doing three panels next weekend.
Speaker 0: Scott and I will be at PAX East doing one panel.
Speaker 0: It's going to be awesome.
Speaker 0: The Book Club book was 2001 A Space Odyssey.
Speaker 0: I'm going to pick by the end of this weekend, either Troy Dennings Pages of Pain or Ninefox Gambit.
Speaker 0: I'm going to make a Twitter poll.
Speaker 0: I'm curious.
Speaker 1: You can't.
Speaker 1: you can't have the balls to choose on your own.
Speaker 0: I'm pretty ambivalent.
Speaker 0: On one hand, Ninefox Gambit sounds up my alley.
Speaker 0: On the other hand, multiple listeners have said that it is a terrifying book that they don't think people should read.
Speaker 0: But that actually makes it more up my alley.
Speaker 0: But at the same time, I'm really curious to find out if Pages of Pain is actually good or if my kid brain, coupled with the opinions of a lot of people I trust, are just way wrong.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: Well, we got to the main bit pretty quickly.
Speaker 1: So back in the day, we read a lot of webcomics since the year 2000, tons of them.
Speaker 0: And then what happened is since the year 2000, Scott, I was reading webcomics in 1998.
Speaker 1: All right, sure.
Speaker 0: I was reading webcomics before I even went to our IT.
Speaker 1: We've been reading webcomics for a long time.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: And then what happened was is sometime, but like maybe earlier this decade, I sort of fell off the wagon with reading the webcomics because there were a lot to keep track of.
Speaker 1: Quite a few of them ended, even though I didn't fit.
Speaker 1: I guess it might have been.
Speaker 1: I can actually time it based on Dr.
Speaker 1: McNinja.
Speaker 1: I left off where they were entering the pyramid.
Speaker 0: I just got.
Speaker 0: Wow.
Speaker 0: Really?
Speaker 1: And then I kept going all the way to the end.
Speaker 1: And then you have no idea.
Speaker 1: That's around the time.
Speaker 1: And then I know Dr.
Speaker 1: McNinja ended soon after.
Speaker 0: You have remember in King Radical when when Dr.
Speaker 0: McNinja asked King Radical to his face, were you up to something?
Speaker 0: And he said, yeah, yeah, I was up to something.
Speaker 1: Yeah, he was.
Speaker 0: You don't know what he was up to.
Speaker 1: No, but anyway, good.
Speaker 1: The point is, is that that's around the time it became sort of inconvenient to read webcomics because you had to check all these sites.
Speaker 0: And, you know, I was sort of a lot of the like RSS feeds kind of stuff working.
Speaker 1: I lost track of where I was.
Speaker 1: This is a website, Comic Rocket, that was trying to help solve the situation.
Speaker 1: But it was kind of janky.
Speaker 1: I don't know if it still exists.
Speaker 1: And it went down all the time.
Speaker 0: We're basically like I can list every webcomic where I go to the website religiously and read them like I read Dr.
Speaker 0: McNinja all the way to the end.
Speaker 0: And now I read what?
Speaker 0: Cucumber Quest, Order of the Stick.
Speaker 1: I read Cucumber Quest on paper.
Speaker 0: I just read the webcomic.
Speaker 1: Anyway, the point is that back in the day, right, people would get mad at webcomics for like not updating on schedule because you had to like manually go to these sites to see the new you to go to all these different websites to see the new comics.
Speaker 0: For my entire adult life, every Monday, Wednesday, Friday, I would go to Penny Arcade in the morning and I'd read a Penny Arcade.
Speaker 1: I had bookmarks of every webcomic and I would open all the bookmarks in tabs and every morning go through each tab to see if there was a new one.
Speaker 0: I had a Monday, Tuesday, Wednesday, Thursday, and Friday bookmark tab.
Speaker 1: Oh, wow.
Speaker 0: Because Penny Arcade was Monday, Wednesday, Friday.
Speaker 1: Yeah, anyway.
Speaker 0: Megatokia was what, Tuesday, Thursday?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: The
Speaker 1: point is, is that that became annoying in an era where you'd go to Twitter or whatever and things would come at you and you didn't have to, you know, you had Google Reader died, you know, and webcomics of that nature were always hesitant to even make RSS feeds or post their comics on Twitter because they depended business wise on the ad revenue of you visiting their website.
Speaker 1: They made a JPEG, which could be easily shared around the whole Internet, and they wanted you to read that to see that JPEG only when it was inside of their HTML that also contained another JPEG that someone paid for.
Speaker 1: They didn't want you to see that JPEG on Imgur or Facebook or somewhere else where they wouldn't get anything from it, or especially not if someone like removed their, you know, name and URL from.
Speaker 1: that was written at the bottom of the JPEG.
Speaker 1: Right?
Speaker 1: And that was the webcomic business model, and because of that, fell off that webcomic bandwagon, not that I didn't want to keep reading them or I didn't like them, it just was inconvenient to read them, and once you fall off a little bit, to catch up is like,
Speaker 0: ugh.
Speaker 0: Yeah, even if it's not, like, even if it's not a serial.
Speaker 1: Like, I really want to read Order of the Stick, but for me to catch up on it is like how much, I have to sit there for like hours and read all the ones I missed.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you have no idea, it's good, it's good stuff.
Speaker 1: I'm sure it is.
Speaker 0: The plot has been revealed.
Speaker 0: Like, the full plot.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: I know what the snarl is.
Speaker 1: I know it, but, you know, I'd have to spend a lot of time and effort to catch up on it, and that's only one of the comics I'd have to catch up on.
Speaker 0: Like, all the people were like, oh my god, you guys should watch Critical Role, like, yeah, that ship sailed, sorry.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so what's happened I've noticed more recently is that even though I haven't been reading the webcomics, on my feeds, on various social networks, Instagrams, Twitters, even, you know, people are just posting full comics.
Speaker 1: And not other people sharing, like, you know, comics that they copied to JPEG and uploaded it, but no.
Speaker 0: Those are out there too.
Speaker 1: They are, but the actual creators, there are people making brand new comics and intentionally creating their JPEG with the knowledge that they, like, might even have a fucking website.
Speaker 1: Like, the primary place for this JPEG to be posted is their social media account.
Speaker 1: Like, the Instagram.com/whatever is the official site for that comic.
Speaker 0: Now, it sort of snuck up on me, like, I just was reading a bunch of comics, like, False Knees was the one where one day I was like, wait a minute, this is a webcomic.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: But I've just been thinking of it as something that appears semi-regularly in my Twitter feed.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: And, like, suddenly we made the connection, like, oh, there's a bunch of these.
Speaker 0: Right, so people- We tried to list them all, and we're going to miss a bunch of them because- But the point is, is that this has become, like, obvious.
Speaker 1: Like, oh, if you want people to read your freaking comic, just post it on Twitter, everyone will follow you.
Speaker 1: Right?
Speaker 1: People will retweet you, you'll get really popular.
Speaker 1: Also- You put your name and URL and your info in the JPEG itself so that people know who the hell it was that made this thing, and you can still make fucking money off, you know, merchandising and the popularity.
Speaker 1: Like, it's working out.
Speaker 1: People who are making good comics and just directly to social media, things are working out for them, just like they worked out for webcomic creators back in the day.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so- They're publishing books of their comics and selling them.
Speaker 0: So the other thing about these comics- Paper kind.
Speaker 0: Is that they tend to not be serial.
Speaker 0: Like, they tend to be stand-alone, like, they're enjoyable stand-alone.
Speaker 1: There are some that are serial, but yes, even the serial ones tend to be enjoyable stand-alone.
Speaker 1: And that's because you don't have that user interface of back and forward that a webcomic website has.
Speaker 1: Right?
Speaker 1: You have the- You know, any individual one might be tweeted or retweeted and must stand alone, you know, to get sort of propagated.
Speaker 1: Some people, like the very popular alien one, which is called- what's it actually called?
Speaker 0: I think Strange Planet?
Speaker 1: It's called Strange Planet.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's the one.
Speaker 1: Right?
Speaker 1: He basically posts them all in, like, a Twitter thread.
Speaker 1: So, like, if you get it shared to one, then you can sort of see,
Speaker 1: "Oh!".
Speaker 1: And if you get back to the original that he posted somehow, you'll see the befores and afters because they're all in the same Twitter thread.
Speaker 1: He keeps replying to it.
Speaker 0: Now, I tried to find some of these I was thinking about because I was also trying to think about, was there an equivalent of this before, like, Twitter?
Speaker 0: And what I remembered was that there was this set of comics- when I was reading webcomics the way we just described, like the traditional old man way of my bookmarks- I got webcomics the old man way.
Speaker 0: Dude, I remember when there weren't that many webcomics.
Speaker 0: Like, the webcomics industry was, like, 30 webcomics.
Speaker 1: I probably could go back and catch up on webcomics, you know, if I had some time, because a lot of the ones I was into ended, so there aren't really that many- Yeah, like, Dr.
Speaker 0: Me Ninja's dumb.
Speaker 1: I can read Dr.
Speaker 1: Me Ninja to the end, I can catch up on Order of the Stick, I think there's some set of Penny Arcades I've missed, but the newer ones, they don't post the comic on Twitter, but they tweet, and in the tweet, they put a link to the comic, so I've-
Speaker 0: I still just go to Penny Arcade every Monday, Wednesday, Friday.
Speaker 1: I have to catch up and then get back in the habit, right?
Speaker 0: I'm still in that habit.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I lost the habit.
Speaker 0: The thing is, the number of comics I read for it with that habit has just slowly shrunk over time as comics I was already doing that way ended.
Speaker 1: Right, you look at someone like Kate Beaton, who basically stopped posting comics on her official comic site and stopped making it, and now, but she still will draw tiny comics and put them on Twitter.
Speaker 0: Yup, but there was an equivalent of this during that era, and I realized that those were the comics, like, there were the webcomics that had their own websites, but there were a handful of comics that would be updated sporadically, they were usually standalone jokes that were in a theme, and they were posted to either Facebook or, like, LiveJournal directly, but because they were there, as opposed to on a website, I either wouldn't see them, or would find one and was unwilling to interact with LiveJournal or Facebook enough to find more of them, because there was no website.
Speaker 1: Right, but you know, if you were, say, there was a comic, say, on Tumblr, or on, you know- Still wasn't willing to, Tumblr comics were the same thing.
Speaker 1: Right, the point is, though, if you were a Tumblr user, that comic would appear in your feed much the way that these other comics appear in your Twitter feed.
Speaker 0: And the one I remembered, the earliest one I could think of, was I, Hearth, Darth.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't remember this.
Speaker 0: Which I'm surprised you don't remember, and I tried to Google for it, and all I found was a Reddit thread from three years ago, where someone asked, "Does anyone remember the I, Hearth, Darth
Speaker 0: series?".
Speaker 0: And two people remembered it, and I ended up finding a link to it.
Speaker 0: It was from 2005, and it was basically this tiny little comic on LiveJournal that was just Darth Vader and a young Luke Skywalker, and it was just funny little comics of, like, "Darth is my
Speaker 0: dad.".
Speaker 1: Right, it's not the same comic as Darth Vader and Son, which is, like, a book- Though it is shockingly similar.
Speaker 0: Like, same jokes.
Speaker 0: I already found strips that are, like, the same strip, basically, but just drawn really cute and tiny.
Speaker 0: So Emily had the idea, and it was a really good idea, that we tried to come up with a list of a lot, as many of these that we read or thought of, that we know of and try to review them all and call them to your attention.
Speaker 1: It's, like, because, like, I just want to increase the consciousness, because the phase I went through was these comics were regularly appearing in my feeds, and I was noticing them and liking them.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: But I wasn't, like, when one would appear, because someone else retweeted it, mostly, I would like it and/or retweet it, but I wasn't taking that extra step of recognizing, "Wait a minute.
Speaker 1: This is a comic that I like.
Speaker 1: Find the original account it's from.
Speaker 1: Follow it.
Speaker 1: Then you can see all of
Speaker 1: them.".
Speaker 1: So that's what I'm trying to do.
Speaker 1: That's the purpose of this.
Speaker 0: False Knees was the one where I realized, "Wait, this is just a
Speaker 0: webcomic.".
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 1: So the purpose of this episode is to spread that consciousness to anyone else who was lacking it.
Speaker 1: You know, you might laugh at us for lacking it, and you're right to do so, but other people might not, you know, grasp, right?
Speaker 1: They might not grok yet.
Speaker 1: It's, like, so we're gonna, like, make you aware so that when you see a funny comic on Twitter, you find the original account and follow it so you can read the whole thing.
Speaker 1: And also, we're gonna tell you a bunch of good ones and some okay ones in case you're looking for ones to follow.
Speaker 0: And you need to come to the Geek Nights Forum and post the ones that we forget to talk about.
Speaker 1: That's right, so I can follow them.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: Let's just go down the list.
Speaker 1: So the first one is the one, it's called Webcomic Name, but everyone else knows it as Ohno.
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 1: The Ohno comic where it follows the same formula of something something.
Speaker 0: It's like dinosaur comics, right?
Speaker 1: Panel one is always something something.
Speaker 1: And then panel two is always butt black dynamite something something.
Speaker 1: And then panel three is Ohno.
Speaker 0: It is never not funny.
Speaker 1: I love Ohno.
Speaker 1: It's caused a meme to infect me in that I now say Ohno way too much.
Speaker 1: I say Ohno all the time.
Speaker 1: In fact, there was an Ohno comic that was like, Ohno, I read this comic.
Speaker 1: It caused me to say Ohno all the time.
Speaker 1: Ohno.
Speaker 1: Butt black dynamite.
Speaker 1: Now I say Ohno all the time.
Speaker 0: It's just Ohno.
Speaker 0: I think what's good about Ohno is that in its core, it is very cutting because we experience like I experience the exact situation like exactly in my brain that happens in these comics on a regular basis.
Speaker 1: They also there was a thing that was there was a tool that would randomly shuffle panels of Ohno comics and also let you create your own your own Ohno comic by combining panels.
Speaker 0: Similar to like Cyanide and Happiness's thing.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: And also today, Dinosaur Comics, the creator of Ohno made the dinosaur comic today.
Speaker 1: It is pretty much Ohno.
Speaker 0: I didn't even see that because I don't follow Dinosaur Comics anymore.
Speaker 1: I saw it on Twitter.
Speaker 1: I didn't see it.
Speaker 0: Oh my God.
Speaker 0: I got to follow them like Stan.
Speaker 1: Let me see if it is what it is.
Speaker 1: Click on it.
Speaker 0: Dinosaur.
Speaker 0: There it is.
Speaker 0: That's too good.
Speaker 1: It's just Dinosaur Comics, except Ohno, Ohno, Ohno, not Ohno, Ohno.
Speaker 0: I just imagine me as William Defoe standing here going, it was a reconstruction.
Speaker 0: Deconstruction.
Speaker 1: So yeah.
Speaker 1: Ohno webcomic name is it's webcomic name dot com.
Speaker 1: But you can you just follow it on Twitter instead.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: And then you'll see all the webcomic names, the Ohnos.
Speaker 0: So Big Brain.
Speaker 1: Oh yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So it's Bird Brain.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: It's basically this pigeon who's got, you know, mental, you know, disabilities of some kind.
Speaker 1: And all the comics involving the pigeon are totally cool.
Speaker 0: I'm scrolling through because there's a regular old.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Because that's the thing is like, this is just someone's Twitter account, right?
Speaker 1: It's an artist's Twitter account.
Speaker 1: And it's like you're getting all the tweets from the artist, but then you're actually getting occasionally the artist will tweet the actual comic.
Speaker 0: Yup.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: So here it's like the, you know, the bird, one bird is depressed and in the bubble on his phone or whatever.
Speaker 1: And then the other bird's like, I know it's hard, but please try to talk about how you're feeling.
Speaker 0: And it's, it's good because again, it's sort of, it's funny, but it's also very true.
Speaker 0: Like that is what it's like to be depressed.
Speaker 0: And it's also well-drawn.
Speaker 0: The Twitter itself is good too.
Speaker 0: Really drawing a lot.
Speaker 1: Because someone who draws a good comic is probably someone who's a good person who's going to tweet good stuff.
Speaker 0: Really into knife movement right now.
Speaker 0: I see a lot of knife movement in this account.
Speaker 1: Love that knife movement.
Speaker 0: This is the best one I've seen.
Speaker 1: It's a, isn't it?
Speaker 1: like Chuck Draws Things, I think is the...
Speaker 0: Charleby, just Chuck and a bird and a snowflake.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but I think that it's called like Chuck Draws.
Speaker 0: Well, what do you, what is the name of a Twitter account?
Speaker 0: Is it the @?
Speaker 0: Is it the name they typed or is it that image there?
Speaker 0: Cause they're all three different things.
Speaker 1: Regardless, Chuck is the person who makes the great pigeon comic Bird Brain.
Speaker 1: I'm sure there might be other comics called Bird Brain.
Speaker 0: It's good stuff.
Speaker 0: So I think Emily introduced me to this one.
Speaker 1: This one is the hottest thing in the world right now.
Speaker 1: Nathan W. Pyle's Strange Planet.
Speaker 1: You'll know it as the Alien comic where basically there's aliens doing normal everyday stuff, but he replaces the dialogue with, how do I describe the dialogue?
Speaker 0: Imagine if aliens were pretending to be humans for funsies and talking about it while they do it.
Speaker 0: I'm trying to find the one that best exemplifies this.
Speaker 0: There's the one where like they come over to the apartment and they're like, oh, people are coming over.
Speaker 0: Let us hide all the shapes that have all the irregular shapes inside of regular shapes.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 1: It's almost like if you're trying, if you were trying to like, you know, basically constantly play a game of taboo all the time to where every single sentence you said, the key subjects and predicates of that sentence were not permitted and you had to instead, you know, work your way around that.
Speaker 0: Aliens are like friends arriving soon and then the ones like, let us store irregular shapes inside shapes with flat surfaces.
Speaker 0: And then other aliens come in and they're like, your home is beautiful.
Speaker 0: Thank you.
Speaker 0: We do own things, but have hidden them.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: That is exactly what you do when someone's about to visit your apartment.
Speaker 1: That's right.
Speaker 1: I hide all my things inside.
Speaker 0: All my things are hidden inside of other flatter things.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's right.
Speaker 1: So it's like you get sort of this double, you know, the reason this comic is so popular and funny is because it does two things at once.
Speaker 1: It exposes a true human thing.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: When people visit my house, I clean up by hiding things.
Speaker 1: That's joke one.
Speaker 1: And joke two is rather than say, you know, just what it is like, yeah, let's quick, let's hide everything because someone's coming over.
Speaker 1: It plays that game of taboo with every sentence to use different words rather than the words that you normally use.
Speaker 0: The surprise party one instead of surprise.
Speaker 0: It's we deceived you.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Exactly.
Speaker 0: It's real funny.
Speaker 1: It's also most of these, not all of them, but most of them are for coma.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: In a square.
Speaker 1: Which is one of my favorite formats, which is a format that not only works super well in general, right?
Speaker 1: As the Japanese have proved, but also works just really well for sharing on social media in a square.
Speaker 1: I thought it's an Instagram or Twitter.
Speaker 1: making JPEG a square just makes it work, you know, on all of these various platforms, right?
Speaker 1: Of social sharing, you know, whereas if you make like a rectangle or something tall, it gets cut off or you can't share it.
Speaker 1: The square is perfect.
Speaker 0: So, so awkward yeti.
Speaker 1: So this is the one where there's like a brain and a heart and it's like these parts of the body and they talk to each other, right?
Speaker 1: It's like the human is doing a thing, right?
Speaker 1: Clearly it's somewhat similar to actually in some ways to the strange planet, right?
Speaker 1: But it's like the characters are the brain, the
Speaker 0: tongue,
Speaker 1: the heart, the parts of the body, and they're sort of describing, you know, what's going on with them in relation to the thing the human who possesses them is actually doing something
Speaker 0: feels wrong and the brain's like quick scroll endlessly through social media.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: Like it's, it's a thing we all do again and they're cute and self-contained.
Speaker 0: And I feel like a lot of these, all the ones we've talked about so far.
Speaker 0: They tend to be very similar in terms of like what it is.
Speaker 0: Like what is the topic they're dancing around?
Speaker 0: What is the topic they're using for their source material?
Speaker 1: So there's War and Peas, which actually was so, War and Peas is so good that I, I became, this one, I became a Patreon patron.
Speaker 1: This is the one that occasionally features the slutty witch who just owns being a slutty witch and is like, yeah, I'm a slutty witch.
Speaker 0: What up?
Speaker 0: It gives me like a slight PBF vibe, but more comicky and less like, PBF is a little bit weird, a little bit different from this, but it gives me a slight hint of that.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: This one, you know, it has that kind of, you know, it's, I think what's funny about this comic is like the edginess of it, right?
Speaker 1: A bit.
Speaker 1: It's not like, you know, edgy, like trying to be cool and edgy, right?
Speaker 1: Like, you know, dark on purpose, like dark Batman edgy or being violent on purpose.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: But it like, it travels into, you know, uh, you know, sort of, you know, sexy and other other topics in ways that are humorous without being crazy.
Speaker 1: Sort of like, I'll go off a little bit without being explicit.
Speaker 0: Like I love it.
Speaker 0: But also like PBF, like sometimes the joke is a callous act or a horrible cruelty occurs in the last or second to last panel.
Speaker 0: But, uh, some like the one, cause I'm just scrolling through here.
Speaker 0: Like you want to talk about a real one is a vampire.
Speaker 0: Just like, can't wait to come home.
Speaker 0: And then he's home.
Speaker 0: Can't wait to watch TV.
Speaker 0: Now he's watching TV.
Speaker 0: He can't wait to go to sleep.
Speaker 0: And then you see the coffin and he's just like, I can't wait to do this again.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: So he's making.
Speaker 1: the one joke that's being made is obviously about, you know, the pointlessness of, of, you know, life, uh, right.
Speaker 1: Just going to work, come home, watch TV, go to bed, the old Simpsons joke, but also it's fun making a vampire do.
Speaker 1: it suddenly makes it right on another level.
Speaker 1: And then the third level is vampires are immortal.
Speaker 1: Oh shit.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: That's the, it's at the three level joke.
Speaker 1: I think there's one where like someone invites, uh, there's like a, a, a slutty witch and he, and it's like, come back to my place.
Speaker 1: The slutty witch is like, I'm not wearing any underwear.
Speaker 1: So he's like, come back to my place.
Speaker 1: So you don't get a cold.
Speaker 1: And then it shows the slutty witch back at his place on the couch with a blanket and he's bringing some tea and she's watching television.
Speaker 1: She watching like be witched on television, just taking care of her being nice.
Speaker 0: Like not being a bad dude.
Speaker 0: It's the wholesome ending where Netflix and chill literally means let's just watch the Netflix.
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 0: I like it.
Speaker 0: It's, it's, uh, I like warm peas a lot, especially because it, uh, appears more readily than a Perry Bible fellowship.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I mean, Perry velvet, he's, he's a little active.
Speaker 0: He's been more active recently.
Speaker 0: Poorly drawn lines.
Speaker 0: I've been laughing at reliably for a while now.
Speaker 0: They're longer form comics usually.
Speaker 1: Usually.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: And they tend to have a more absurdist punchline.
Speaker 0: Like they're much more absurd or indirect than, uh, like some of them are like, some of them just don't end like just nothing happens.
Speaker 0: And that's the joke.
Speaker 1: And it's, they're not poorly.
Speaker 1: It says poorly drawn lines of the name of the comic, but I don't think they're poorly drawn, but they are definitely just not a lot of lines.
Speaker 1: And then sort of the coloring is just bucket tool.
Speaker 0: Yup.
Speaker 1: Right?
Speaker 1: It's like the bird is just blue.
Speaker 1: The koala is just gray.
Speaker 0: Yup.
Speaker 0: They make really good faces despite being so simple.
Speaker 0: Kind of like how XKCD just, even though they're stick figures, they emote like in a subtle way, like.
Speaker 0: that makes it work.
Speaker 0: They make like the bird will sometimes like have this open beak face where he's clearly being dumb about something.
Speaker 1: I've been saving money for three years.
Speaker 1: Here it is.
Speaker 0: I got this money three years ago.
Speaker 1: Money I got three years ago.
Speaker 0: And he's making that slightly open mouth face.
Speaker 0: That reminds me of the Morty face in Rick and Morty.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: Let's just keep, we had a lot.
Speaker 0: Let's just keep going down the line.
Speaker 1: So this extra fabulous comics, this one, I don't know if I can really recommend this one, right?
Speaker 1: So this has like a huge warning on it, right?
Speaker 1: But, but basically I went through my Twitter likes and I noticed that I had like.
Speaker 1: this is the one reason I can't recommend the one.
Speaker 1: So I had liked at least three strips from this same comic, right?
Speaker 1: Scroll down.
Speaker 1: There's like a Jesus one that I really like.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 1: It's like, so this one's hit or miss.
Speaker 1: And it's like, I get a vague feeling the person who makes this comic, it's like, I don't know if they're a bad person, but a lot of the comics sort of go into very uncomfortable territory or make jokes that are not funny.
Speaker 1: Like the newest one is like, literally it's a suicide joke where Ash takes Pikachu in the bathtub.
Speaker 1: It is not funny.
Speaker 1: I found it like really disturbing, not into it at all.
Speaker 0: Then the bonus panel was basically it didn't work.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Sort of.
Speaker 1: But there's another comic made by the same person where it's like, okay, these kids are like, quick, hide the porn.
Speaker 1: Jesus is coming.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: And then Jesus comes and then gives them a spanking and it's like, Jesus is so mad about porn, but he's also into spanking, right?
Speaker 0: Yup.
Speaker 0: Of course.
Speaker 0: The one you just talked about, the thing is, it reminds me of the kind of joke that would be every single parking lot is full.
Speaker 0: Like every parking lot in full was a joke.
Speaker 0: Parking lot is full was a joke like that.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: And that comic was disturbing, but I did also enjoy it.
Speaker 1: So even though some of these are not funny and not disturbing, none of them are offensive.
Speaker 1: They're not Nazi jokes.
Speaker 0: They're not just like racist.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: They're not racist or anything, at least none that I've seen.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So I recommend this one with major qualifications that some are, it's all over the place.
Speaker 0: The Harry Potter one is really gross, but I laughed out loud.
Speaker 0: Oh yeah.
Speaker 0: Because panel one, I laughed out loud and I didn't like, and I was surprised that it got grosser and somehow both grosser and funnier.
Speaker 0: It's a lot of panels in that one.
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 0: A nice long, nope.
Speaker 0: I skipped one.
Speaker 0: No, I didn't.
Speaker 0: A nice long walk.
Speaker 1: I forget.
Speaker 1: See, that's the thing is when you're not going to a website, right?
Speaker 1: For, Oh, so when you're not going to a website and you just see the comic, when it appears in your feed, you might not like know the name of the comic.
Speaker 1: If you're just like, you only see the name of the person or you only saw someone retweeted it.
Speaker 0: So you see your friend's name and I liked a lot of these comics.
Speaker 0: They remind me vaguely of like the kind of joke, like a Natasha Allegory thing would make.
Speaker 1: So this is an exception in that it's, it's sometimes there's episodes, right?
Speaker 1: Sometimes it's just like individual comics, but there is a serial comic, a nice long walk about this girl who lives in a fantasy village and goes on a walk.
Speaker 1: Like, yep, I'm going to go on an adventure now by town and you can read it from the beginning and it's just super wholesome, super cute, you know, leaving town, going on an adventure as wholesome as possible, right?
Speaker 1: And there's all sorts of cute creatures.
Speaker 1: He meets like a little friend on the way, you know, it's like even cuter than cucumber quest, even more wholesome and simple.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: Looks like a lot of the rest of the Twitter is just like pictures of birds, which is also really good.
Speaker 1: That's the thing is you're getting the, you get the artist and the art together.
Speaker 1: You can't, they're not like making a feed just for their comic.
Speaker 0: It's like, this is exactly the kind of reason why I use Twitter, but you just get rid of the Nazis.
Speaker 0: Twitter would be perfect.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: Get rid of the Nazis and charge like a dollar a year to get rid of the spam accounts.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 1: So be everything at once is actually sort of a autobiographical situation.
Speaker 1: There's a person named Demi Lee is Korean American person.
Speaker 1: I actually bought her book on the paper version and read all the comics in it.
Speaker 1: And all the comics are about her real experience.
Speaker 1: You know, as someone who's lived in, you know, New York, I guess New York, but the United States and Korea, right back and forth at various times.
Speaker 1: You know, so there's jokes about like, you know, Oh my God, people like, Whoa, where's your fashion?
Speaker 1: She's like, I bought these clothes in Korea.
Speaker 1: Ooh.
Speaker 1: It's like, you know, stuff like that.
Speaker 1: You know, language jokes.
Speaker 1: If you've ever seen the girl with the, you'll know the comics because she always draws herself wearing a sweatshirt with an egg on it.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: Those are the ones.
Speaker 0: I kind of want that sweatshirt.
Speaker 1: Maybe she sells it.
Speaker 0: I bet she does.
Speaker 0: If she doesn't, someone should sell it.
Speaker 1: Her book, I think, sold well, at least.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So yeah, I'm way, I'm way into it.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: Pigeon Gazette.
Speaker 1: Trying to remember which one.
Speaker 0: I'm trying to remember.
Speaker 1: Oh, this is also.
Speaker 1: a lot of these are this one.
Speaker 0: I think I've liked because I've seen Overwatch jokes in here.
Speaker 0: Kind of this is the Overwatch.
Speaker 0: It's all a little cute.
Speaker 0: Overwatch jokes.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: This person does Genji cat Overwatch jokes and also does again, sort of like, you know, self care, uh, you know, mental health comics as well.
Speaker 0: A lot of these have that because I got one that I only knew it as self care wolf.
Speaker 0: I don't know if there's even a comic, but there's just this one comic someone tweeted once.
Speaker 0: This one is like, this is more just like a cute account to follow.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Which a lot of these are.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: So this is a newspaper comic, but Nancy, the newspaper comic just tweets every comic, at least a lot of the comics.
Speaker 0: And if you're not aware, Nancy, the comic has sort of been reborn, right?
Speaker 1: So way back in the day, it was like an old, it was like, you know, early 20th century, right?
Speaker 1: Uh, Nancy was a thing and Nancy was really funny, right?
Speaker 1: But Nancy, right.
Speaker 1: But the new Nancy is basically the same character design, but completely different content.
Speaker 0: It's modern in a way that actually really confuses baby boomers who encounter it.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: To the point that that is itself part of the humor.
Speaker 0: Cause it's very just like, it's what newspaper comics would be today if newspapers still existed.
Speaker 1: It's like, it's, it's like a museum level, like work of art, what has been done, you know, with this somehow getting a license to the thing and then changing the thing in such a way as like, Oh, it's, you know, there's so many levels going on with Nancy, but yeah.
Speaker 0: Yup.
Speaker 0: The funniest thing about it is that I realized I wasn't actually following the official Twitter account.
Speaker 0: I was following this other Twitter account.
Speaker 0: That's just called Sluggo is lit.
Speaker 0: That's just reposts the Nancy comics as far as I can tell.
Speaker 0: I don't think it's even legit.
Speaker 0: So I just switched to the right one, but no, Nancy is crazy funny.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So false knees.
Speaker 0: This is the one that made me realize that this is a thing, these Twitter comics, it's just really well drawn animals.
Speaker 1: Like, wow.
Speaker 1: Like someone's putting a lot of work into the art on this comic, like damn son.
Speaker 0: And these really well drawn animals.
Speaker 0: Audubon society shit are having the kinds of conversations you would imagine these kinds of animals have.
Speaker 0: If there isn't, if they're as intelligent as us, but otherwise just live like animals.
Speaker 1: So it's like, these are these birds.
Speaker 1: This is the thing that those birds do, but they speak English.
Speaker 0: Yup.
Speaker 0: The humor is really understated and really low key and really, really like, I cannot express to you how much I like this.
Speaker 1: It reminds me, what was that guy's name?
Speaker 1: The comedian who would just, he would say everything super dead pan and even, and then he died.
Speaker 0: Was one of them.
Speaker 1: No, he died.
Speaker 1: He was on, um, was it Mitch Hedberg?
Speaker 0: Is that the guy also did that?
Speaker 1: This is a lot like that kind of humor.
Speaker 1: Only birds that are well drawn.
Speaker 0: Like just read it and you'll see, this is one of my favorite and it's, it's often just wholesome.
Speaker 0: Like my, my favorite strip they ever did is just a bird is like a little, little sparrow looking bird just picking up little flowers.
Speaker 0: And some other birds like, well, someone's a lucky bird and the birds like, Hey, yes, they are.
Speaker 1: I mean, this goes to a larger point in that I heard from someone like way back years and years ago, they were talking about like the cycles of cynicism and sincerity in society.
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 1: And I was like, well, at the time I was like, wow, everything's super cynical.
Speaker 1: right now is sincerity coming.
Speaker 1: And I feel like sincerity is now here.
Speaker 0: I think it's coming.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: You know, it's like, you know, so that's why, you know, the, I think about like, oh, the comics that I was reading before, and I still read web comics were mostly cynical and all these ones on Twitter, they got all the retweets are super sincere and honest.
Speaker 0: So yeah, false knees might so far be my favorite of everything we've talked about.
Speaker 0: I mean, it's not my alley.
Speaker 0: So this one is on the line.
Speaker 0: I don't think it actually counts, but I'll list it because there's a lot of, there's a bunch of Twitter accounts that are taking panels from other people's web comics or even their own web comic in some cases.
Speaker 0: And just tweeting like one panel out of context.
Speaker 1: I think this really all started with that Garfield thing.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Which was really funny.
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 0: And I re I follow this like it's a web comic.
Speaker 0: It's no context.
Speaker 0: Aikwood.
Speaker 0: I've read a bunch of Aikwood.
Speaker 0: I kind of like Aikwood.
Speaker 0: Like it's pretty good comic.
Speaker 1: I read it whenever there's a link to it or somebody ever like read it all on purpose.
Speaker 0: But I like this more than I like Aikwood because in a vacuum, it's just like a couple of panels from one strip that are in and of themselves.
Speaker 0: Really funny, but also kind of fucked up, but in a kind of sincere way based on these characters.
Speaker 0: So it's like on the line of, is it a Twitter comic?
Speaker 0: Cause it's almost a remix of Aikwood, but they're not remixing.
Speaker 0: They're just zooming in on one part of it.
Speaker 0: that ends up being really funny by itself.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: It's super interesting how you can take, you know, a portion of a work of art, not edit it other than to remove the rest of the art and then display it on its own.
Speaker 0: And it completely transformed into something else like Garfield without Garfield is one of the is like is a triumph of artistic expression.
Speaker 1: You could like take Star Wars and cut out like five seconds.
Speaker 1: And what in what if you were watching the movie and got to those five seconds, you would feel one feeling.
Speaker 1: But if I were to just show you out of nowhere, the clip of just those five seconds on their own, you have a complete opposite feeling.
Speaker 0: Yup.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: And that's sort of what happens here.
Speaker 1: And it's like, are you like, how much of an artist are you if you are simply recognizing and, and you know, you're just like an editor, but you're sort of not anyway.
Speaker 0: Well, like the people who will make a very well-crafted animated gif of a tiny part of movie that ends up itself having a life above and beyond the movie itself like that happens kind of often now.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: We only got three more.
Speaker 0: Well, I'm sure there's a lot.
Speaker 0: we've forgotten that we'll remember the second I stop recording.
Speaker 1: So this is rest the shark.
Speaker 0: Oh, my God.
Speaker 1: Rest the shark is pretty much just a ridiculously cute shark.
Speaker 1: That's all there is to it.
Speaker 1: The comic there are a lot of right.
Speaker 1: A lot of the Twitter posts and content are just images.
Speaker 1: And when there are comics, there usually aren't a lot of words on them because it's a shark.
Speaker 1: The shark, for some reason, doesn't need to be in the ocean.
Speaker 1: It can go on land.
Speaker 0: It's basically a shark shaped dog.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: But yeah, it's a, yeah, but it's not shaped exactly like a shark, but it's a shark.
Speaker 0: Yup.
Speaker 1: And it's just literally just like silently watching the cute shark do cute stuff.
Speaker 1: They sell cute merch.
Speaker 1: It's sort of like almost trying to be a Pusheen.
Speaker 1: Only there is a comic with occasional strips.
Speaker 1: Isn't really an official Pusheen comic.
Speaker 1: So this is like a Pusheen competitor.
Speaker 1: You know, rest the shark.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's definitely Pusheen adjacent.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Pockets.
Speaker 0: So Pockets is.
Speaker 1: I've seen this.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So I've seen this comic.
Speaker 0: You'll see this Twitter account because a lot of times you'll see a wolf with a really, really long mouth.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I haven't seen this.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: So it's cute and it has a lot of comics, but the one that really stood out that made me like this account is just this self-care dog comic where there's a dog in bed.
Speaker 0: It's like, you've been laying in bed for 17 hours, man.
Speaker 0: You good?
Speaker 0: And the dog's like, I'm having a self-care day.
Speaker 0: Like bring me 12 pillows and a chocolate croissant.
Speaker 0: And that's the thing people who get depressed do.
Speaker 0: But then the next strip is like dogs out of bed doing shit.
Speaker 0: And the person is like, yo dude, you doing okay?
Speaker 0: I haven't seen you take a self-care day in a while.
Speaker 0: And it's like, yeah, turns out staying in bed for days wasn't actually self-care.
Speaker 0: Turns out I was super depressed, like clinically.
Speaker 0: And it's one of those comics that addresses depression and mental health issues in a funny but real way.
Speaker 1: Why are all the, it seems like a lot of people who, I assume the people making these comics have these issues, which is why they're able to, or they have friends who have these issues, which is why they're able to address them in comic form so well.
Speaker 1: Why are those people so creative and so good right now?
Speaker 1: There's like, it's clearly a sign of the times.
Speaker 0: I think part of it is that a lot of people are way more willing to talk about mental health and a lot of people are sharing things like this.
Speaker 1: It was a topic that was not previously explored in, you know, publicly shared art as much.
Speaker 0: I mean, dude, in public art.
Speaker 1: In this way, there's plenty of art about depression going back to the beginning of time, but like specifically in the modern context of it, right?
Speaker 0: People are just being open about this stuff and you see this as the result.
Speaker 0: I think it's great.
Speaker 0: Do we have any, I think I have one more on the list.
Speaker 0: Nerd and Jock.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: So you may have seen this one.
Speaker 1: It's actually, the account has other comics besides Nerd and Jock.
Speaker 1: It's like, but Nerd and Jock is definitely the best thing on this channel.
Speaker 0: Because it's very wholesome.
Speaker 1: It's again, another example of wholesome sincerity instead of cynicism.
Speaker 1: It's basically a nerd, this little tiny character with big glasses, stereotypical.
Speaker 1: And a jock, this huge muscly dude.
Speaker 1: And they interact with each other, right?
Speaker 1: In a typical high school setting, except the jock does not pick on the nerd in the way you would expect.
Speaker 0: And the nerd does not like look down on or denigrate the jock.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the nerd isn't like, oh, you dumb jock, right?
Speaker 1: It's like, they totally, you know, are cool to each other.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: And it's pretty awesome.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: It's just cute, wholesome.
Speaker 1: Sometimes some of the jokes are like setups making you think someone's about to get picked on or whatever.
Speaker 1: And then not.
Speaker 1: It's like, that's sort of what the funny.
Speaker 0: The end is always like, yo, bro, I will help you with that.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: Instead of, you know, it's like, oh no, this strong jock is going to beat up that weak nerd.
Speaker 1: Oh no, he helped him with his strength.
Speaker 1: You know, awesome.
Speaker 0: Yup.
Speaker 0: So I'm sure there's a million of these we miss.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Send us all your new web comics that are primarily on social media instead of hiding on websites.
Speaker 0: I'm going to post all the ones we talked about in the forum, and then I expect you to post literally all the ones that we're going to remember the second I hit.
Speaker 0: stop on this stream.
Speaker 1: And then we can all go to Twitter, Instagram, wherever it is and follow all of them so that you don't miss any and only see them when someone else retweets them.
Speaker 0: Yup.
Speaker 0: This has been Geek Nights with Rim and Scott.
Speaker 0: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design, and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at frontrowcrew.com for show notes, discussion news, and more.
Speaker 0: Remember, Geek Nights is not one, but four different shows.
Speaker 0: SciTech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays, and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: Geek Nights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: Geek Nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 1: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.
Speaker 0: And the Patreon patrons for this episode of Geek Nights are Finn Daniel Redman, Sean Klein, Chris, Rymer, and Thomas Hahn.
Speaker 0: Now I leave you with... Oh my God, you're moving my mouse.
Speaker 0: It's remote desktop.
Speaker 0: What is your password?
Speaker 0: Uh, it's just the letter A. Just the letter A, alright.
Speaker 1: Like Apple.
Speaker 0: Are you looking at my desktop right now?
Speaker 0: Dude, how many programs do you have running?
Speaker 0: You're totally overloading your box.
Speaker 0: That's probably part of the reason.
Speaker 0: Well, I use all these programs.
Speaker 0: You know, I got a lot of work to do during the day.
Speaker 0: Whoa, whoa!
Speaker 0: Hey, no, no, no!
Speaker 0: Can you save it?
Speaker 0: No, no, I need to save this!
Speaker 0: Shit.
Speaker 1: This is all my work!
Speaker 0: Look, you don't need this stuff.
Speaker 0: I have some research that I'm doing, okay?
Speaker 0: You can't close all my windows, okay?
Speaker 0: I'm closing in on that.
Speaker 0: Don't use AOL.
Speaker 0: It's Dial-Up Networking.
Speaker 0: Well, how am I going to get through the internet without AOL?
Speaker 0: It's broadband.
Speaker 0: But I got like $4,000 for free.
Speaker 0: We have a corporate OC3.
Speaker 0: It costs like $1,000 a month, so don't use AOL.
Speaker 0: Whoa.