Speaker 0: It's Thursday, April 11th, 2019.
Speaker 0: I'm Rem.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott.
Speaker 0: And this is Geek Nights Tonight.
Speaker 0: We have a special guest, Judith, and we're gonna talk about water in the ceiling.
Speaker 1: Should've said "I'm
Speaker 1: Judith.".
Speaker 0: No, we don't let her talk in that part.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: Alright, Judith, you wanna say "I'm Judith"?
Speaker 1: Don't let him silence you.
Speaker 0: No, you can say it.
Speaker 0: You can yell it.
Speaker 0: I don't want to.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: So, uh, my news, I'll get right into it because it's also my opening bit.
Speaker 0: You have all seen, I'm sure, the video of the woman almost getting killed by an axe that she threw.
Speaker 1: I did not see it until you just showed it to me.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So, it was making the rounds, it's a thing, and I realized that Scott is unaware of the fact that white people, particularly tech bro white people, are weirdly obsessed with axe throwing as a fake hobby lately.
Speaker 1: I mean, I knew that axe throwing was a sport.
Speaker 1: in the same way that, you know, all those other crazy sports like that thing where, like, you carry your wife and all, you know, I know a lot of crazy sports.
Speaker 1: Right, I knew that axe throwing was an existing sport, but I did not know that it recently became popular or that anyone was doing it on any scale anywhere other than, of course, you know, the one time a year someone's backyard, they have the axe throwing championship.
Speaker 0: Yup, so like, after over the last year or so, a bunch of businesses sprung up that are, they treated it as like this hardcore cool sport that is also a team building exercise.
Speaker 1: Axe dodging is hardcore, axe throwing is not.
Speaker 0: Well, this woman turned axe throwing into axe dodging.
Speaker 1: Oh, really?
Speaker 0: Because axe throwing sucks, it's not fun, I've done it, it's boring, it's hard, just play darts, and she throws an axe that almost hits her in the face.
Speaker 0: So,
Speaker 1: I was
Speaker 0: already keyed, like, keyed into the fact that axe throwing is this weird white people thing that happens suddenly, but this video went viral, and on my way out of work today, I'm in the elevator, and I got stuck on the local, and the elevator was filled with a bunch of people on some other team who are themselves all going after work to axe throw as a team building exercise, and yes, 100% of them were white and under 30.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I gotta say though, as much as the fault of this is due to doing the stupid sport of axe throwing, I must say, the design of this axe throwing arena is very poor.
Speaker 0: They're all like this.
Speaker 1: Right, underneath the axe target, which is appropriately a giant piece of wood, is a rubberized surface, it appears, of some kind.
Speaker 0: It would not matter what was there.
Speaker 1: No, you could have, say, a foot, like, inch deep pit of, like, bits of stuff, and then that would basically, if any axe landed in that pit, it would just sort of sink into it, like, Right?
Speaker 1: Much like a person jumping into a ball pit.
Speaker 1: You would need smaller bits than ball pit balls, but you could use, like, ground-up astroturf or something.
Speaker 0: I gotta say this, the reason why it looks so shitty and why it seems so close is real simple.
Speaker 0: Most people are not strong, or athletic, or coordinated.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if it was farther, no one would throw an axe that far, they'd be like, "He would never reach the
Speaker 1: target.".
Speaker 1: Yeah, the moral is, axe throwing- Axes are heavy, you need to be strong to throw them.
Speaker 0: If you ever see an establishment that sells axe throwing as its primary thing, it is an establishment to be avoided because it is not fun, just play darts.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean, you know, there is one, there is only one merit I can see to axe throwing above dart throwing, right?
Speaker 1: Is when you throw a dart, you throw it pointy side forward.
Speaker 0: You don't have- I throw it fins forward because I know what the fuck I'm doing.
Speaker 1: The point is, it has fins that keep it straight, so even if your aim is bad, the pointy part is gonna go into the target.
Speaker 0: I mean, we were playing darts at the New Year's party, and only a few people hit the wall.
Speaker 1: But if you hit the wall, the pointy side went into the wall, is the point, right?
Speaker 1: With an axe, when you throw an axe, it rotates head over handle, like whoosh whoosh whoosh whoosh whoosh.
Speaker 1: So even if you're right on target, like dead on bullseye, and you have the strength to get it there, you also, it does have the additional skill challenge of controlling the rotation so that the pointy side is forward when it reaches the target, and that is the, I think, only merit for axe throwing above darts.
Speaker 0: The sad part is that most people I've seen, 'cause I've done, I've thrown axes before, is most people cannot even get the axe to stick into any target because they're just not strong enough.
Speaker 0: Even if they're like five feet away from the target.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you have to put enough power into the axe, or even if the sharp port hits the wood, it still needs to have enough velocity, momentum to get in there, right?
Speaker 0: The thing I'm terrified of is I'm really worried that there are people who will do this, and not realize it's boring, and try to make it their hobby.
Speaker 1: I don't think anyone makes it their hobby, I think it looks to me, based on what I've learned in the past, less than an hour since I discovered that people are doing this.
Speaker 0: I just don't know how you avoid, like, white people, pop culture nonsense.
Speaker 1: It feels like a birthday party situation where you rent the place out, you do it once for fun, and you never do it again.
Speaker 0: Oh, these places will-.
Speaker 1: I don't think it's a rock climbing situation where people, or bowling, where there's like a league.
Speaker 1: There might be a few people in the league, but almost nobody.
Speaker 0: The axe throwing thing will be gone within two years.
Speaker 1: I feel like there's more people in the ski ball league in Brooklyn than in the axe throwing league.
Speaker 0: I think you are correct.
Speaker 0: So what do you have for some news?
Speaker 1: Oh, so the NHL draft was, what, when was it, recently?
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know what, you know what matters?
Speaker 0: Number two!
Speaker 1: And it's the perfect year to get number two, because basically there's two people who are at the top to get to pick, and people are arguing over which one should be one or two, and- A one for you, a one for me.
Speaker 1: So someone else has the difficult task of choosing which one to take.
Speaker 1: It's autochess.
Speaker 0: It's autochess for humans.
Speaker 1: Number two is basically as good as number one, if not better, because someone else makes the decision for you.
Speaker 1: You just take the other guy, and then the quality of draft picks falls off precipitously after number two.
Speaker 1: So, woo woo, that's great.
Speaker 0: So I've watched that part of the draft before, but I never actually looked at what Scott linked me to.
Speaker 1: Right, so if you watch the NHL draft on TV, they try to turn it into a televisable, suspenseful event, where they read off the draft picks, the rankings from lowest to highest, and then at the end they tell you who got the first pick, right?
Speaker 1: But here is a video of the actual draft, the mechanics of it being conducted, which, even if you don't care about sports, if you're a nerd who cares about games, this is fascinating, because it's a camera, it's a video of the entire procedure, and that never cuts away, so you know there's no shenanigans, right?
Speaker 1: And not only can you see the great lengths they have gone through to make sure that is a completely fair lottery, which are fascinating mechanisms, if not the craziest, they're pretty, you could figure them out if you're a nerd, but they're still pretty good, is the great lengths they go through to prove to anyone watching that it's not fixed, right?
Speaker 1: It's like, I could easily make something that no one could cheat at, right?
Speaker 1: But then to prove that no one has cheated is like another level.
Speaker 1: So yeah, it's a pretty cool thing to watch, and I think I'll just be watching this in the future years, even though...
Speaker 0: I'll watch this instead of the televised one.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean, but you won't see this until after they've already announced.
Speaker 0: I could just wait.
Speaker 1: It's gonna be, you know, but it's only if you care about spoilers, right?
Speaker 1: It's like, this is still entertaining to watch regardless of knowing who won.
Speaker 0: So anyway, it's time for... Things of the Day!
Speaker 0: So, you may remember a long time ago, we found this video that was explaining how a differential gear works, and we were oddly obsessed with it.
Speaker 1: Uh, for like a day.
Speaker 0: Well, yeah, but like, we showed it at Kineticon, like when we needed filler content and a panel a couple times.
Speaker 1: Okay, that applies to a lot of things.
Speaker 0: Uh, yeah, so there was, I guess, just a really good video.
Speaker 0: I found a very similar video that has a bonus point of.
Speaker 0: it's got a beautifully rendered animated Archimedes sneering at us in the fashion of a story from North America, and then...
Speaker 1: It looks like the dead from the story of North America.
Speaker 0: He does, but crossed with Poseidon, may he not kill me in a boat someday.
Speaker 1: I mean, pretty much any white dude, white beard, white toga, you could just say, "Oh yeah, it's fucking, I don't know,
Speaker 1: Aristotle.".
Speaker 0: No, no, no, the reason I would say it's Poseidon is the sneer.
Speaker 1: That is a Poseidon-looking sneer.
Speaker 0: Julius Caesar wouldn't sneer like that.
Speaker 1: You could name any Greek or Roman Zeus.
Speaker 0: There are only two beings that can sneer like that.
Speaker 0: The dead from the story of North America.
Speaker 0: The story from North America.
Speaker 0: It's Agamemnon.
Speaker 1: It could be anybody.
Speaker 0: I don't think Agamemnon would sneer like that.
Speaker 0: I think he had more of a haughty look.
Speaker 0: This is a Poseidon sneer.
Speaker 0: Anyway, this video is 9 minutes and 40 seconds of the same thing as that other video that explained how a differential gear works, and it talks about how transmissions work, because really a transmission is just a bunch of circular levers.
Speaker 0: And it's a really, really good video.
Speaker 0: And it's really, really, really old, because the fundamental way a transmission works did not change until electric cars.
Speaker 1: Nope.
Speaker 0: So what do you got?
Speaker 1: So, some people went to McDonald's, or in this case, Macca's, which is what they call it, I guess, wherever they're from.
Speaker 0: Royale with cheese.
Speaker 1: It is a place that I never go, and I haven't eaten there since I can't even remember the last time I ate there.
Speaker 0: Last year.
Speaker 1: The last time I distinctly remember eating there was when I was, in the year 2000, I went to one in Israel and only ate ice cream.
Speaker 1: Because apparently I was told the ice cream there was special, also it was cheap.
Speaker 0: The last time I ate at McDonald's was in January of this year, when I went on a ski trip, and I was in Times Square waiting for the ski bus, and the McDonald's was there, and a part of my brain said, "McDonald's.
Speaker 0: McDonald's.
Speaker 0: McDonald's!".
Speaker 1: My brain never says that.
Speaker 0: So I went and got a McDonald's breakfast.
Speaker 1: My brain sees two golden arches, and it just imagines, like, piss, two people peeing into the central location.
Speaker 0: That was oddly specific.
Speaker 1: So it else is two golden arches.
Speaker 1: It's not good.
Speaker 0: So I had already gotten to the point to where I cannot eat McDonald's regular food without literally getting sick.
Speaker 1: I cannot smell a McDonald's without feeling nauseous.
Speaker 0: But I could still eat the McDonald's breakfast, and in emergencies that was an acceptable option.
Speaker 1: I mean, they have an apple there, I think, right?
Speaker 1: And they had the cookies that come in a bag, and I could get a beverage that's sealed.
Speaker 0: So I ordered a McDonald's, like, McMuffin.
Speaker 1: Maybe I could eat the chicken nuggets.
Speaker 1: Maybe.
Speaker 0: And a hash brown.
Speaker 0: And a coffee.
Speaker 0: The coffee was so hot I could not drink it, and then when it was cold, it tasted like ass, so I didn't drink it, and I threw it away.
Speaker 0: The hash brown was good while it was hot, and the moment it became cold, it tasted like poison.
Speaker 0: And I threw the McMuffin away after two bites, because that shit is disgusting.
Speaker 0: I am now beyond McDonald's.
Speaker 1: Anyway, the point is, these people at this Maccas, there is a digital ordering system, which is pretty cool.
Speaker 0: Which I approve of.
Speaker 0: I don't want to talk to a human.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you just go up, you push some buttons, just like Wawa, or any of those other places.
Speaker 0: Shake Shack has this now, too.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you go up, push the buttons, you wait, then they give you your order, right?
Speaker 0: Oh my, you would not believe how many people, there's a Shake Shack kind of by my office.
Speaker 0: There's always people lined up at this place.
Speaker 0: So many of them are lined up to talk to a person, because they won't use the kiosk.
Speaker 1: So, what these people discovered is a bug in the system, whereby you can get the dollar burger, and you customize the dollar burger to remove the actual beef patty from it, because you can customize your order, right?
Speaker 1: You can be like, no ketchup, yes ketchup, add onion, you know, all those options.
Speaker 0: Give me more pickles, more pickles.
Speaker 1: All that stuff you can customize, you can actually remove the burger itself.
Speaker 1: It is a fully customizable thing, it was programmed well.
Speaker 1: If you remove the burger patty from the dollar burger, you are left with something that costs negative ten cents.
Speaker 0: Because if you get a normal burger that costs more than a dollar, they subtract a dollar twenty, if you're making it garbo-vegetarian, as in just a burger without a button.
Speaker 1: Maybe you want to provide your own burger.
Speaker 0: Maybe.
Speaker 1: You don't know.
Speaker 0: Well, I'm glad that's your example lately for everything, is maybe you want to provide your own.
Speaker 1: They're a legitimate situation.
Speaker 0: BYOB, bring your own beef.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so, what they did is they added, like, ten negative cost burgers to their bag, and then they added a positive cost burger with a patty, and the fine employees of McDonald's, who were not paid enough to give any shits,
Speaker 0: of course, filled up their
Speaker 1: order exactly as specified.
Speaker 1: A whole bunch of buns with almost nothing on them.
Speaker 0: The best part is when they open the bag and they're like, "Oh my god, they made
Speaker 0: it.".
Speaker 1: And then one real actual dollar burger, and they paid no money to this McDonald's.
Speaker 1: They got free food.
Speaker 0: There's something magical, because I'm all very much of the mind that if you pay someone minimum wage, they are obligated to give you minimum effort.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So my hat is off to the McDonald's employees, who chose to not in any way question this, and my hat is off to these kids, who are geniuses.
Speaker 1: It's a lot like the kids who use their phones to video record the dealer no-deal machine.
Speaker 1: Yeah, yep.
Speaker 1: That was a previous thing of the day.
Speaker 0: So now, our guest, Judith.
Speaker 2: Hello.
Speaker 0: You, seeing how we do things of the day, have a thing of the day for us to bring to the table.
Speaker 0: So what do you got?
Speaker 2: Well, playoff hockey begins for the Boston Bruins, my favorite team, today.
Speaker 2: So they posted a video to try and get people pumped.
Speaker 0: Wait, is that blood?
Speaker 2: That is blood.
Speaker 1: They need to get people pumped?
Speaker 1: People aren't pumped enough?
Speaker 0: That's just what their Twitter is for, is to get people pumped.
Speaker 0: Oh, that is literally just blood going down the drain.
Speaker 2: So they posted this inspirational video with the hashtag #InOurBlood, and it has lots of clips of hockey players and people playing hockey, like you would think, but also clips of lions and Dobermans and an occasional bear and some tanks.
Speaker 0: There's a mobile rocket artillery launcher here, and then a hockey fight, and the word
Speaker 0: "fight.".
Speaker 2: And it's awkwardly cut into all this hockey footage, including blood going down a drain, blood going down someone's face, the word
Speaker 2: "bleed.".
Speaker 2: Yeah, you just saw the wolf.
Speaker 0: Oh, that wolf is really mad.
Speaker 2: It's a really mad wolf.
Speaker 1: That looks like a fake wolf.
Speaker 0: That's real.
Speaker 0: That wolf doesn't look mad.
Speaker 0: He looks like he's like, "I'm going to bite this camera,".
Speaker 0: but this other wolf looks mad.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 2: So if you either want to feel ashamed to be a Boston Bruins fan or even more pumped about it, check out this video.
Speaker 1: I'm not sure.
Speaker 1: Is it possible for extreme masculinity to go so overboard that it wraps around to where it's acceptable?
Speaker 1: Well, I mean- It's like it's so toxic that it becomes silly and is no longer toxic.
Speaker 0: Well, it's kind of like how Top Gun was intended to be hyper hetero masculine and ended up being the literally most homoerotic thing humanity's ever created.
Speaker 0: This video is- I want to remix this video.
Speaker 1: It's amazing.
Speaker 2: It's already remixed.
Speaker 0: I don't even know what music it goes to, nor do I care.
Speaker 2: Me neither.
Speaker 2: I just watched it on silent.
Speaker 0: So in the meta moment, the Geek Nights Book Club book, I apologize deeply, but I chose, based on a lot of thought, that we are going to read a book that I read once in high school and thought my high school brain thought it was phenomenal.
Speaker 0: Other adult humans who- That's not saying much.
Speaker 0: Other adult humans whose opinions Scott and I both trust have- Oh, really?
Speaker 0: Alex has also said this book is actually good based on memory.
Speaker 1: Oh, it is high school.
Speaker 1: High school.
Speaker 1: Alex says it was good.
Speaker 0: So I'm really curious to find out if High School Rim had taste because I remember that this Planescape branded Dungeons and Dragons canonical book, Pages of Pain, I remember it being good and I remember it being phenomenal compared to every other branded material.
Speaker 0: I like those nonsense elf books where a bunch of elves do their elf shit in Faerun and I remember this book being a lot- You mean the fanfiction that Rim would have written had it not already existed for him to simply read it?
Speaker 0: Why would I write fanfiction when I just played an elf among elves in my many year running D&D campaign where we went around doing elf shit?
Speaker 0: Our D&D campaign was 90%.
Speaker 0: The elves are having court because they're mad about other elves.
Speaker 0: And then he'd role play dinner.
Speaker 0: That was my high school life.
Speaker 0: Dinner of Sun Chips and Dr.
Speaker 1: Pepper?
Speaker 0: Sun Chips, Dr.
Speaker 0: Pepper.
Speaker 1: What else did elves eat for dinner?
Speaker 0: Pretty much, well, I assume it was only Sun Elves that ate the Sun Chips.
Speaker 0: I was a Moon Elf, fuck those Sun Elves and their bullshit.
Speaker 1: You weren't a medical elf with your Dr.
Speaker 1: Pepper?
Speaker 0: They stole the crown from the Moon Elf and Queen.
Speaker 0: I digress, I'm still mad about that.
Speaker 0: Anyway.
Speaker 1: Toblerone for dinner for the elves?
Speaker 0: So join us for the next Geek Nights book club where instead of reading The Odyssey or The Space Odyssey, we're going to read something about not Odysseus, not Perseus, but potentially about Poseidon and Theseus.
Speaker 0: that is set in Planescape, which technically means it is in the same universe as Kelvin Blackstaff.
Speaker 0: We are reading Troy Denning's Pages of Pain.
Speaker 1: Same universe as every D&D thing ever?
Speaker 0: Yes, except Ravenloft because Ravenloft is actually walled off in its own demiplane that is not accessible from the rest of the universe.
Speaker 1: What?
Speaker 1: I didn't know about that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, Ravenloft is- That sounds not true.
Speaker 0: Ravenloft is walled off from the entire universe and it's its own thing for canonical reasons.
Speaker 0: Because Count von Straad fucked up.
Speaker 0: Uh-huh.
Speaker 0: Wait, you sound like you're curious about the details of how this goes down.
Speaker 1: No, I just do not believe that this is a thing, or I'm pretty sure that someone has probably undone this thing and that it was- No, no, no.
Speaker 0: So you know how every Ravenloft campaign goes?
Speaker 0: It's you got pulled there somehow and because this place is walled off from the rest of the universe- No, no one starts there.
Speaker 0: Why not?
Speaker 0: I guess you could.
Speaker 0: Usually people play in like Forgotten Realms, then oh shit, someone pulled you into Ravenloft, now you're fucked, there's no way back.
Speaker 0: You're living here and when you die, you're just still here because it's the undead garbage place.
Speaker 1: Alright.
Speaker 0: Anyway, we're here to talk about water in the ceiling because as all of us in this room have experienced, if you live in New York City, at some point in your life, water is going- Not even New York City.
Speaker 1: Not even New York State.
Speaker 1: If you live in houses.
Speaker 0: If you live in apartments.
Speaker 1: Shelters.
Speaker 0: Apartments where there are other apartments above you, you have experienced at some point, water coming through your ceiling.
Speaker 0: and if you have not experienced it, you should go check because there might be water coming through your ceiling.
Speaker 1: It is really shocking how many people and how common it is to have water in the ceiling.
Speaker 0: Yup.
Speaker 0: Emily even brought it up at work and everyone was like, "Yup, that has happened to
Speaker 0: me.".
Speaker 0: You get that like bulb in the ceiling dry water.
Speaker 1: So hopefully we can connect with all the listeners with our water in the ceiling episode.
Speaker 0: Let's start with our oldest story and then let's get Judith's story and then I'll tell the most recent set of stories.
Speaker 0: Scott's got his story too.
Speaker 0: that was also recent, but the original story, the reason for all this, and Judith, just interrupt us whenever you want.
Speaker 0: We just keep going unless someone yells at us.
Speaker 2: We were at RIT.
Speaker 0: There I was.
Speaker 0: I was laying in bed.
Speaker 0: Scott was laying in bed.
Speaker 0: We were probably arguing about something.
Speaker 1: We heard noise.
Speaker 0: Yup, we heard noise.
Speaker 1: Dripping noise.
Speaker 0: Drip, drip, drip.
Speaker 0: I'm trying to ignore it, but I vaguely recall Scott was like, "That keeps dripping.
Speaker 0: That doesn't sound
Speaker 0: good.".
Speaker 0: And I didn't want to get up.
Speaker 0: and finally I'm like, "God damn
Speaker 0: it.".
Speaker 0: So I get up and I go into the other room and I hear the drip, drip, drip and I step and the floor is wet.
Speaker 0: Uh-oh.
Speaker 0: I turn on the light and the ceiling is like there is a bubble, like a monster is pushing through the ceiling.
Speaker 0: Like a giant zit.
Speaker 1: I was there so I can confirm.
Speaker 0: It was impressive.
Speaker 0: There is a light fixture there that was entirely full of water.
Speaker 0: So we're like, "Uh, what the fuck do we do with
Speaker 0: this?".
Speaker 0: So I call Campus Safety and a cop comes up basically and he comes in.
Speaker 1: Because they don't let you call a physical plant directly.
Speaker 1: Campus Safety is like the only number you can call for anything.
Speaker 0: I love this cop because he comes in and he's like, "So what's the
Speaker 0: problem?".
Speaker 0: And we point to the ceiling and all he says is, "Oh
Speaker 0: damn.".
Speaker 0: So then he calls physical plant and the gentleman who came to solve this problem had no idea what he was doing.
Speaker 1: Well, you know, fixing the ceiling was problem one but really the question is where the water came from.
Speaker 1: And where the water came from was from our neighbors who lived above us.
Speaker 0: Now you may recall these are the neighbors who hated us.
Speaker 1: Even though we never talked to them ever.
Speaker 0: Didn't even know their names, didn't even know what they looked like.
Speaker 1: I wouldn't recognize them ever.
Speaker 0: Because we had called Campus Safety on them numerous times for having wrestling matches upstairs.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they were basically playing the game known as Pick Up the Bowling Ball.
Speaker 0: At like 4 AM.
Speaker 0: That's the game where you grease your hands up and try to lift a bowling ball above your head.
Speaker 1: So yeah, I guess they just left their sink running and didn't notice or something like that.
Speaker 0: Because they were dumbasses and entirely independent of them being dumbasses.
Speaker 0: They were also deaf.
Speaker 1: And it was a failure of not the plumbing.
Speaker 0: It appears that they had gotten really drunk and turned a tub on.
Speaker 0: And then just forgotten they had done this and flooded their entire apartment.
Speaker 0: Which then flooded the ceiling of our apartment.
Speaker 0: So Campus Safety goes up there to deal with them.
Speaker 0: They came back into our lives later when later that month they called Campus Safety on us.
Speaker 0: And accused us of trying to hack into their computers to get them expelled.
Speaker 0: Remember that was because of the Half-Life networking?
Speaker 0: And their firewall detected our Half-Life landings?
Speaker 1: Oh right, we were playing Half-Life 1.
Speaker 1: And if you try to play Half-Life 1 on the LAN using what's it called?
Speaker 1: IPX.
Speaker 1: IPX, which doesn't really exist anymore.
Speaker 0: Yeah, thanks Satan.
Speaker 1: Then those packets go on the whole subnet, whatever it is, VLAN, whatever.
Speaker 1: And their software firewalls were alerting.
Speaker 1: And then I guess it was our IP address because we were the ones doing...
Speaker 0: And they already hated us because we had ruined their... We fight with each other.
Speaker 1: I don't think they knew it was us.
Speaker 1: I think they just got the alert and didn't know anything about computers.
Speaker 1: So called, you know.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I remember when we talked Campus Safety.
Speaker 0: He was like, "Oh, you have a history with them.
Speaker 0: Why are you antagonizing
Speaker 0: them?".
Speaker 0: I was like, "Uh, what?
Speaker 0: What?
Speaker 1: Who are these people
Speaker 1: again?".
Speaker 1: Anyway.
Speaker 0: So the physical plant guy, they deal with that and he's standing there.
Speaker 0: And I remember he's looking up at it and he gets up on a step ladder.
Speaker 0: And he's trying to take the light fixture off.
Speaker 0: that's completely full of water.
Speaker 0: And I remember this sublime moment because the Campus Safety guy sees that this is going to be a disaster.
Speaker 0: And he kind of elbows me and gives me that look.
Speaker 0: The look I now recognize from New York City as, "Get a load of this guy and what's about to
Speaker 0: happen.".
Speaker 0: And, yeah, water just comes streaming out of the ceiling in like a giant torrent.
Speaker 0: He drops the light fixture.
Speaker 0: It shatters.
Speaker 0: He almost falls off his step ladder.
Speaker 0: The ceiling starts crumbling down.
Speaker 0: Uh, yeah, that sucked.
Speaker 1: I stayed in bed.
Speaker 0: Scott just laid in bed the whole time kind of sniggering and laughing at it while I'm there dealing with Campus Safety.
Speaker 1: You could have just been in bed and let them take care of it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, no.
Speaker 1: Now we had to pay them.
Speaker 0: I was like moving my books out of the way.
Speaker 0: I had like stuff that was going to get wet.
Speaker 1: I didn't put my stuff near the bathroom.
Speaker 0: Yeah, because my little bookshelf was there.
Speaker 1: I don't put my stuff near the bathroom.
Speaker 0: Also, that was not too far away from my computer.
Speaker 0: I had a vested interest in dealing with that shit.
Speaker 0: And, uh, that sucked.
Speaker 2: Now that I think about it, I'm really lucky that never happened to me in college.
Speaker 2: I lived in an ancient building.
Speaker 1: A colony where we lived in college no longer exists.
Speaker 1: They demolished it.
Speaker 2: Rightfully so, it sounds like.
Speaker 1: Long ago.
Speaker 0: I mean, all the floors were asbestos tile.
Speaker 0: That place was old and dank.
Speaker 0: That's why we left the window open.
Speaker 1: We were also in the basement.
Speaker 0: We left the window open all winter and just left the heat on all winter because that was the only way to not die of mold.
Speaker 0: So, Judith, what happened to you?
Speaker 0: Tell us your water story.
Speaker 2: Well, nowadays I still live in an ancient building.
Speaker 2: It was built in 1927.
Speaker 2: And, uh, some pipes are older than others.
Speaker 2: And we originally lived on the first floor.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, with the, like, boarded up, like, sealed garbage chute or coal chute?
Speaker 2: Yeah, we lived right near the garbage chute, which was sometimes boarded up.
Speaker 2: And other times it wasn't.
Speaker 2: It sent mice in.
Speaker 2: It sent roaches.
Speaker 2: It was a great time until we got a cat.
Speaker 0: I remember the first time I visited you, I was like, "What's this scary
Speaker 0: door?".
Speaker 0: And I think Natalie, all she said was, "Don't
Speaker 0: ask.".
Speaker 2: Oh, that one!
Speaker 2: Yeah, they plastered that up and they never told us what it was.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 0: I just assumed that was a coal chute?
Speaker 2: Probably something like that or a dumbwaiter, some ancient relic.
Speaker 2: But, no, we had a bathroom.
Speaker 2: It was a very tiny, awkward bathroom.
Speaker 2: And one day I was taking a shower and I looked up at the ceiling and I noticed this gray stain that hadn't been there.
Speaker 2: Ooh.
Speaker 2: And I ignored it at first.
Speaker 0: That's what you do.
Speaker 1: That's what you do.
Speaker 1: You can't imagine that it's actually a serious problem.
Speaker 1: No.
Speaker 2: No, and as the days went by, it kept getting bigger and bigger and eventually we were like, "Maybe we should tell the super about
Speaker 2: this.".
Speaker 2: So we did.
Speaker 2: And our super back then was the kind of guy who would take your complaint, be like, "Okay, cool," and then disappear forever.
Speaker 2: Seriously, we have a good super now, but nobody goes to tell them anything because they're so used to being brushed off by the old super.
Speaker 1: So I guess at least the old guy was deservedly let go?
Speaker 2: Yeah, he was let go.
Speaker 1: That's good.
Speaker 2: And then the other one after him was let go for hitting on a child.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 2: Live in a fun place.
Speaker 1: Are these live-in supers who are always in the building?
Speaker 2: Yes, these are live-in supers.
Speaker 1: Ooh, I've never had one of those.
Speaker 0: We got one of those.
Speaker 2: Yeah, we don't have a doorman.
Speaker 2: We have a live-in super instead.
Speaker 2: So fancy, yes.
Speaker 0: Ah, queens.
Speaker 2: Yeah, so the stain just keeps on getting bigger.
Speaker 2: Nobody does anything about it.
Speaker 2: And then little gray specks start to fall down from the ceiling.
Speaker 0: See, that's the moment when things start falling from the ceiling where even I would be like, "Uh,
Speaker 0: hmm.".
Speaker 2: No, and I poked him, the super.
Speaker 2: I poked him a few times being like, "Hey, weird stuff is starting to happen in the
Speaker 2: bathroom.".
Speaker 1: Show him a picture or a video or something.
Speaker 2: I didn't have a smartphone back then.
Speaker 1: These were ancient times.
Speaker 0: Oh, I think I still have the email I sent to our management organization for my story where I sent them a video I took with our Geek Nights camcorder of water just streaming down our ceiling.
Speaker 2: Oh, thank God it wasn't that bad for me.
Speaker 0: But no, no.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I digress.
Speaker 2: Eventually this little gray rain one day finally just turned into a giant chunk of plaster falling right on top of my head while I was in the shower.
Speaker 2: Oh, no.
Speaker 1: Why did it have to be that?
Speaker 1: It could have fallen down.
Speaker 1: You're not in the shower the vast majority of the time.
Speaker 2: Maybe I was making it steamy.
Speaker 1: That could have been it.
Speaker 2: Made it release.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but it should have been like you just walk into the bathroom and you see it there.
Speaker 1: The odds of it falling on you at that time is so small.
Speaker 0: Because both situations are unnerving.
Speaker 0: Because if you come into your house and there's a bunch of debris on the floor because you don't look up at your ceiling unless you're prompted to, that's already a very unnerving like, "Wait, what
Speaker 0: happened?".
Speaker 2: The debris became such a fixture because nobody fixed it for so long that we always had to clean it up before we got in the shower.
Speaker 0: Oh, no.
Speaker 0: Was it still like crumbling down?
Speaker 1: What was the cause of it?
Speaker 2: I never found out.
Speaker 2: It was probably a faulty pipe.
Speaker 2: Okay.
Speaker 2: We are full of faulty pipes in that building.
Speaker 2: Like I said, some of the pipes are still there from the '20s and '30s.
Speaker 2: But yeah, the hole in the ceiling finally got somebody to come fix it.
Speaker 2: But that meant no shower for a couple days.
Speaker 1: Uh-oh.
Speaker 0: So you decided to like -- so you were taking showers and there's just a hole in the ceiling for a while.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 2: Yep.
Speaker 0: What was in the ceiling?
Speaker 0: Did you like go up there and look around?
Speaker 2: No, I'm really short and we didn't have a step ladder.
Speaker 0: I would have gone up on a step ladder in a flashlight and been like, "Who is their treasure?
Speaker 0: Should I hide something in the
Speaker 0: ceiling?".
Speaker 2: Well, now that we have a good super, there is a ladder for anyone to borrow in the basement and I guess I'll remember that if there's another hole in my ceiling.
Speaker 1: Old building probably got old treasure.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: My building doesn't have any treasure in it.
Speaker 2: Oh, man, I just checked out some old corridors in the basement.
Speaker 2: That basement is way bigger than I thought.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: That is a thing in New York.
Speaker 1: I've been in situations where I've been in old buildings in Manhattan and the elevator goes down to B2 and it opens up and it's dark and the scary pipes like it's a movie set and then someone comes in and then it closes.
Speaker 0: So at RIT, there was the steam tunnels that we were allowed to use.
Speaker 0: that connected a bunch of buildings together and they were already pretty deep.
Speaker 0: There was another basement under that that connected a bunch of buildings together that we weren't supposed to go into.
Speaker 0: that I broke into a bunch of times and wandered around.
Speaker 0: That was cool.
Speaker 0: But I remember under building one in the sub-basement, there was a locked door that went down from there to a sub-sub-basement.
Speaker 0: And I always kind of wanted to get in there, but I could never quite jimmy the locks.
Speaker 0: I never really tried too hard.
Speaker 0: I assume the statute of limitations is up on me trespassing at RIT at this point.
Speaker 0: But one day the door was unlocked and I was like, "Oh, fuck, I'm going
Speaker 0: in!".
Speaker 0: And I went halfway down the stairs, it was pitch black, it smelled weird, and I heard a lot of machine noises and I just bailed.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's all that's down in those places is machines.
Speaker 0: But it sounded big.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's, you know, boilers, furnaces, HVAC, all that kind of shit.
Speaker 0: Yup, yup, yup.
Speaker 0: Pumps.
Speaker 2: Yeah, I've only seen part of our basement.
Speaker 1: Water filters.
Speaker 2: It's a garbage room, a laundry room, a workshop, and several tiny murder rooms.
Speaker 1: Ooh, tiny murder rooms.
Speaker 0: Our building had two illegal bootleg apartments down there for a couple of years.
Speaker 1: I think there's still bootleg apartments on the roof.
Speaker 0: I think there still are bootleg apartments on the roof, but the ones in the basement are gone because one of those apartments is now our bike room.
Speaker 0: So I put my bike in this place that still has hookups for a stove.
Speaker 0: It's a cool, like, it was obviously an illegal as fuck apartment, but it was kind of a cool space because it has a thing, much like the thing in Peterson 3 in the lounge.
Speaker 0: Remember that thing?
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 0: It was like that.
Speaker 0: There's a thing like that thing.
Speaker 1: Alright.
Speaker 1: Thing.
Speaker 2: We're not allowed on our roof.
Speaker 1: I wonder why.
Speaker 1: Ooh.
Speaker 1: It's probably not suitable for human, you know, presence.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you might have the kind of roof that has, like, a bunch of areas.
Speaker 1: Where someone would just fall off and die.
Speaker 0: Or it has the areas you're not supposed to walk on.
Speaker 1: Yeah, just fall through because the roof is so shitty.
Speaker 1: Or just covered in equipment.
Speaker 1: It doesn't have any nice areas to stand safely.
Speaker 0: Total aside, when I was in high school, the neighbor called my parents once and the police because they thought that I was crazy.
Speaker 1: Because you were on your own roof?
Speaker 0: Because I had a headset, telephone, wireless, and at night I would often climb out my bedroom window onto the roof and hang out up there talking to my friends on the phone.
Speaker 0: That was the thing I would do.
Speaker 0: The neighbor just saw Rim walking back and forth on the roof, gesticulating and ranting into the air every night, and assumed that I was crazy.
Speaker 1: That's not a crime.
Speaker 2: Is it like that scene from Signs?
Speaker 1: So, my building, which is somewhat modern building.
Speaker 0: Your building's new, like ours.
Speaker 1: If it's pre-war, it's only pre-Iraq war.
Speaker 0: Yeah, which Iraq war, though?
Speaker 1: The newest one.
Speaker 1: I don't think it's pre-golf war, anyway.
Speaker 1: But it's a pretty new building, so I never expected, I basically assumed that nothing bad maintenance-wise would ever happen while I lived there because it's so new and everything is so, even my dishwasher's really good.
Speaker 1: I don't know if they really scrape my dishes and it cleans them, right?
Speaker 1: So, what could go wrong in this building?
Speaker 1: Well, I was sleeping in bed and I heard some noises.
Speaker 1: It wasn't a consistent tapping noise and it wasn't obviously a dripping noise.
Speaker 1: It was just sort of like the kind of noises you hear in a house.
Speaker 1: You know, like a little creaky, a little tippetappa.
Speaker 0: But you're not in a house, you're in an apartment, which makes it weird.
Speaker 1: And I've never heard noises like that before.
Speaker 1: It's always been completely silent.
Speaker 1: But I'm like, I look around and I don't see anything from my bed.
Speaker 1: So, you know, I ignored it, actually, for like, it must have been at least two days.
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 0: It seems like the pattern here so far is problem identified, ignored until it causes a bigger problem.
Speaker 2: That's the New York way.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it is.
Speaker 0: That hobo's got a knife, but he is two people away from me, so I'm going to continue playing a game on my phone.
Speaker 1: But eventually it got to the point where I did hear a consistent tapping that was definitely a drip somewhere.
Speaker 1: And then I look and, you know, I still ignored it then.
Speaker 1: It was the next, because I couldn't see anything.
Speaker 1: And then the next morning.
Speaker 0: At least Judith was already like, yo, super.
Speaker 1: Was it that night?
Speaker 1: I think it was that night.
Speaker 1: Anyway, the next time, basically the time after that, I saw in my ceiling, there was clearly a wet spot where I touched it.
Speaker 1: It was a splotch.
Speaker 1: And I'm on the third floor and I'm like, where is this water coming from?
Speaker 1: I'm in my bedroom.
Speaker 1: And the way the building is arranged, all the plumbing is in like one tall stack in the front of the apartments in the middle of the building.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: That was the same way.
Speaker 0: Every bathroom in this building is a bathroom above and below it.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 1: That's all the plumbing is in like this, you know, in vertical shafts.
Speaker 0: That's why the ceiling in this room doesn't really have anything.
Speaker 0: There's no space.
Speaker 1: Now there is a sprinkler system in my building, but that goes down the middle of the apartments right each way.
Speaker 1: This puddle, the small puddle was like in the middle of my bedroom, nowhere near any kind of water.
Speaker 1: I'm like, how the hell is water getting there?
Speaker 1: It makes no sense, but clearly it's happening.
Speaker 1: It's real.
Speaker 1: So there's must be some explanation for it, you know?
Speaker 1: So I called supers and then they get plumbers and then things happen.
Speaker 1: And then they still haven't fixed the ceiling.
Speaker 1: It's just sort of, I guess they just let it dry out and didn't do anything about it.
Speaker 1: So I guess I'll deal with it.
Speaker 1: It's not serious, but apparently everyone living above me has it much more serious problem because there was some sort of valve broken on the sixth floor that had been broken for quite some time.
Speaker 1: And the people, I guess, on floors five and four were much worse off than I was on floor three.
Speaker 1: Or I don't know if anyone on floor two had a problem.
Speaker 0: You know, funnily enough, we had a similar incident in this building unrelated to my bathroom where one day Emily and I just came home and the doorman's like, Whoa, wait, uh, is your apartment okay?
Speaker 0: And we're like, uh, uh, and he's like, yeah, there's this big flood.
Speaker 0: We're like, Oh shit.
Speaker 0: And then we go to our apartment and everything's fine as say, at least I four.
Speaker 0: So I thought, but then I remember that I'd smelled a weird smell in this very room like a couple days before and I couldn't place the smell and it didn't seem to be getting worse.
Speaker 0: I'd just been ignoring it.
Speaker 0: And uh, so I go back down and I'm like, actually there's a weird smell in the inner room and he's like, Oh yeah, it is getting down to you.
Speaker 0: So on the 12th floor, a valve for the radiator system had gone in someone's apartment and fucking flooded it like bad, like the whole.
Speaker 1: Why are valves so shitty?
Speaker 0: Uh, why indeed?
Speaker 1: Have also have insurance.
Speaker 1: Maybe if insurance is, maybe people complain.
Speaker 1: cause like insurance doesn't save you from like tornado or hurricane or flood, but it saves you from incompetence.
Speaker 1: My insurance actually, they told me like they were, they were trying to sell it to me, but I already was buying it, but they were like, these are all the things that covers.
Speaker 1: If I start a fire and the sprinkler goes off and the sprinkler sprays someone else's apartment, it'll pay for their shit.
Speaker 1: If someone else's starts a fire, like a dumb ass sets my sprinkler off and gets all my shit wet, it'll pay for everything.
Speaker 1: So, and it's like if cheapo cheap insurance, it costs less than like a hundred dollars a year.
Speaker 1: It was like nothing.
Speaker 1: So wherever, even if you're poor, no matter where you live, you should get a renter or homeowner insurance that covers all these sorts of things.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: They'll even cover like your bike if it gets stolen.
Speaker 2: Yep.
Speaker 2: Even we did that.
Speaker 0: Yup.
Speaker 0: Pro move.
Speaker 0: So inside of that closet, the wall by the outside of the building was just completely wet, but it was radiator water, which has, uh, some sort of anti-freezing like thing in it.
Speaker 1: Oh, I thought it would just be water.
Speaker 0: Was it not radiated?
Speaker 0: Modern radiators don't use just water usually.
Speaker 1: They have like a closed circuit of like a special water.
Speaker 0: Usually they'll have something like that.
Speaker 1: It's not coming from the water supply.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: And it's not like full on antifreeze, but it basically meant that like mold wouldn't grow from this water as long as it was dealt with.
Speaker 0: I guess that's good.
Speaker 0: I basically just had to leave that closet empty for like a week.
Speaker 1: Go get more special water refill it.
Speaker 0: I don't know what they did, but it completely dried out and it was fine, but that's why it was a weird smell because you couldn't get any heat, but apparently the, the six, seventh, eighth, ninth and 10th floors were like bad water damage.
Speaker 0: Got to replace the walls and floors in like this, this room of every apartment.
Speaker 0: And above that it was like serious damage.
Speaker 0: So living lower actually really helped us out.
Speaker 0: All the other apartments like soaked up all the water.
Speaker 1: I feel like if you're on the top of the top is top floor.
Speaker 1: That's the best case in the penthouse.
Speaker 0: You're the one causing everyone else's problem.
Speaker 1: You're safe except from roof problems.
Speaker 0: Ah, you know what happens in a lot of buildings, the skylights, cause all the penthouses have skylights.
Speaker 0: They go all the way up to the roof.
Speaker 0: Those leak like a motherfucker apparently.
Speaker 1: But other than that though, the modern buildings are going to have a good roof, right?
Speaker 1: Whereas, you know, you have leaky roofs are in old houses very commonly.
Speaker 1: And then you have to replace your roof and it sucks, but we don't have any homeowners on the show to discuss that situation, which is very common.
Speaker 1: But I think that's what most people experience water in the ceiling is from leaky roof in a house.
Speaker 2: I guess it's nice to know that this can happen in these fancy buildings too and not just in our poor ass 1927 building.
Speaker 1: I mean, you go to build a fancy building, right?
Speaker 1: It's like, yeah, it is a fancy building, but the person who built it wants to build it as cheaply as possible.
Speaker 1: They don't actually want to make it, you know, they want to make it look nice to get you to rent it.
Speaker 1: They don't want it to actually be nice.
Speaker 1: Having it be nicer only makes it more expensive to make.
Speaker 1: It doesn't let them get any more rent.
Speaker 0: That's why like all the fixtures in this building, even though it's a quote unquote luxury building, are the bare goddamn minimum.
Speaker 2: They will call anything a luxury building these days.
Speaker 2: I just want to point that out.
Speaker 0: Well, in cities like New York, luxury means the bare minimum to live in.
Speaker 2: It means it's in New York, not New Jersey.
Speaker 1: Luxury means you probably won't see a rat or a cockroach.
Speaker 2: That's a lie.
Speaker 0: Probably.
Speaker 1: I said probably.
Speaker 2: You're going to see a cockroach.
Speaker 1: I haven't seen one.
Speaker 1: You're lucky.
Speaker 1: Mine's not luxury.
Speaker 0: We have thankfully never had cockroaches, but we got some carpet beetles.
Speaker 0: we've been dealing with that.
Speaker 0: I think we finally won the war.
Speaker 0: I have not seen a live one in some time.
Speaker 1: The only kind of bug that gets in my apartment is if I open the balcony and a fly comes in, which every single time I open the balcony, a fly comes in.
Speaker 0: He's waiting out there.
Speaker 1: I swat him and then another one makes sure thing.
Speaker 0: He comes in, he's like, "I will avenge you,
Speaker 0: Father.".
Speaker 1: Father, it's like, how did you even get born?
Speaker 1: I murdered you, Father.
Speaker 0: Dude, did you see there was a story today on like Boeing Boeing and Kotaku and all those places.
Speaker 0: Someone had a sealed fancy DSLR like camera lens.
Speaker 0: They sent it for service because a full-grown adult fly was inside of it.
Speaker 1: That's old news.
Speaker 1: That's a super old thing.
Speaker 0: I saw it come up in my feed today.
Speaker 1: I saw it a long, long time ago because there's a website.
Speaker 2: Maybe it's happened more than once.
Speaker 1: Maybe, but there's a website, LensRentals, I think is what it's called.
Speaker 1: It's a place you can rent camera stuff, but they always post, they have a really good blog where they show repairing lenses and taking them apart and put them together and stuff.
Speaker 1: And they showed how like, yeah, here's a lens we got back.
Speaker 1: There was a fly stuck in front of the front element, but because of the way lenses work, you basically wouldn't notice.
Speaker 1: But yeah, we had to get it out of there.
Speaker 2: Nah, gross.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they're taking the lens on my camera apart right now to replace...
Speaker 1: So it's like, people are worried about a piece of dust on the lens.
Speaker 1: It's like, dude, you got a whole full fly in the lens.
Speaker 1: It won't even show up in your photo.
Speaker 1: You won't notice.
Speaker 0: Even my camera with those giant scratches on the inner element of the lens, unless I zoom all the way out and there's a source of light, you couldn't tell.
Speaker 1: Right, because the camera is focused on a certain distance.
Speaker 1: So if it's focused on five meters away, something that is a centimeter away from the lens is so not in focus, it's invisible.
Speaker 0: Yup, and even the scratch on the lens, it just means there's an area with lower quality and/or lens flare.
Speaker 1: You can set your, let's say you got a macro lens and the minimum focus is like a couple inches.
Speaker 1: You focus it at a couple inches and you aim it at like, you know, the landscape, you'll see like the blade of grass that's in front and then just like a blurry nothing, right?
Speaker 1: If it's not in focus, you can't see it.
Speaker 1: So the fly, even though it was right in the lens, it wasn't in focus.
Speaker 0: So we've had water come through the ceiling of our bathroom like five times.
Speaker 1: Whoa, that's a lot of times.
Speaker 0: Well, it happened three times in a row many years ago.
Speaker 1: That only counts as one time.
Speaker 0: Then, like a few years later, it happened once and then it didn't happen for a long time.
Speaker 0: And then very recently it happened real bad and we finally got it fixed completely as far as I can tell.
Speaker 0: But the story was same deal.
Speaker 0: I mean, I was laying in the bedroom in bed and I hear a little noise like water dripping and I'm like, I'll ignore that.
Speaker 0: And then Emily is like, uh, you probably left your shower drip and go fix that.
Speaker 0: And yeah, you're right.
Speaker 0: And I get up, I go to my bathroom and the floor is just completely wet.
Speaker 0: The light fixture is full of water and there's water everywhere.
Speaker 0: The ceiling is like bowing down.
Speaker 1: Why'd you pee on the floor?
Speaker 1: You got a bad aim?
Speaker 0: So I'm like, uh, and I go down to the doorman.
Speaker 0: He's like, what?
Speaker 0: And then while I'm waiting for him to like get the stuff together, I went upstairs and I banged on the door of the apartment above us and they did not actually speak English and didn't understand me.
Speaker 0: So I couldn't really express.
Speaker 1: What did they speak?
Speaker 0: Korean, I think.
Speaker 1: I don't know the word for water in Korean.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So I couldn't really, I wasn't gonna like barge into their apartment.
Speaker 0: So the doorman, like they dealt with it and dealt with them.
Speaker 0: But basically what had happened is they had like overflowed their sink.
Speaker 2: Well, they just didn't notice.
Speaker 0: Every time we've had a problem, it is that family has fucked up in their bathroom.
Speaker 0: There is no pipe problem.
Speaker 0: There is no, the root cause is those people suck at living in an apartment building or suck at using.
Speaker 1: Even the most recent time?
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So same problem.
Speaker 0: I talked to the doorman in the end.
Speaker 0: He was like, yeah, they just had a problem.
Speaker 0: They let the, they, they let their toilet overflow because they had clogged it, but it overflowed from the top of the toilet with a continuous stream of clean water because they had messed up the inside of their toilet somehow.
Speaker 1: What?
Speaker 2: Do they have kids?
Speaker 2: Is the kids doing it?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I don't think so.
Speaker 0: I think they just suck.
Speaker 1: How do you overflow the top of a toilet?
Speaker 1: That's so hard.
Speaker 1: You'd have to like sit there and hold the thing and open.
Speaker 0: I guess if the thing got stuck open somehow.
Speaker 1: No, but the plunger would have to be closed, but you'd have to keep the water flow.
Speaker 0: It's hard to do.
Speaker 0: They suck at this apparently.
Speaker 0: And that has been the cause of this problem for so many times.
Speaker 0: So this last time they fixed everything.
Speaker 0: But because the door in the bathroom had been damaged by water so many times, after the last time it had warped to the point that the door could not even close anymore.
Speaker 0: So they had to replace the door.
Speaker 0: And then I learned that the way they replace doors in this building is they get a big piece of wood and they fucking custom make a door for that exact door.
Speaker 1: And they just buy a door?
Speaker 0: They, they, I guess the door is different sizes.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: They made me a custom door, painted it and put it up.
Speaker 2: So that's why your door wasn't closing.
Speaker 2: Yeah.
Speaker 2: Now I know.
Speaker 0: Now you know.
Speaker 0: And now it closes.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 0: The only good thing to come out of this.
Speaker 1: Well, that's, you see, on the one hand, that's good.
Speaker 1: Everything was fixed, but it's also, if the problem is like, oh, valve exploded.
Speaker 1: It's like, okay, they replaced it.
Speaker 1: They probably check the rest of the valves to make sure they're not faulty.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: You know, you can have some assurance.
Speaker 1: They're like, okay, not going to have water in the ceiling again for quite a while.
Speaker 1: You know, but if it's people fucking up, it's like, all right, got all new door.
Speaker 1: And then the next day they fuck up again.
Speaker 0: Yup.
Speaker 0: The thing is, I assume either the building will evict them or make them pay for the damage.
Speaker 1: You can make them pay.
Speaker 1: I don't know if you can evict someone for just being dumb.
Speaker 2: It's not easy to evict people here.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: You can eventually, but it takes a long time.
Speaker 1: Not for that.
Speaker 1: That seems like a very weak thing to evict someone for.
Speaker 1: You got to have, like, didn't pay rent ever to evict someone in the city.
Speaker 2: Yeah, they can still get away with it.
Speaker 2: Not paying for months.
Speaker 1: If they tried to make them pay.
Speaker 1: Save some money.
Speaker 0: And they refuse to pay for the damage, I'll bet they could eventually, after like four years, evict them.
Speaker 1: I mean, whoever was across from you had some sort of paper on their door.
Speaker 1: that was some sort of eviction.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 0: The apartment across from us, my best guess, because it was like police stuff going on.
Speaker 1: Or court stuff, at least.
Speaker 0: There was court and police stuff and a search warrant happened.
Speaker 0: Like, I found a bunch of nonsense.
Speaker 0: Pretty sure whoever lived in that apartment left because they were trying to avoid being served a warrant and then got evicted because they weren't paying rent in the time before they left.
Speaker 0: So they abandoned the apartment and eventually, like a judge ordered the apartment to be taken over by the police to get you invested, like evidence gathering.
Speaker 0: They left the door unlocked for like a month while they were doing this.
Speaker 0: I went in there to see what was going on and everything was just like removed at that point.
Speaker 1: Tampered to all the evidence.
Speaker 2: That sounds like how we got our current apartment.
Speaker 2: Yeah, we were looking to move out of the bottom floor one because, you know, there was water in the ceiling and it was tiny and it sucked.
Speaker 2: And we were looking at one on the fourth floor and we got shown it and they said that they would give us priority because we already lived there.
Speaker 2: But then they didn't.
Speaker 2: They sold it.
Speaker 2: But then they contacted us being like, oh, there's another one on the same floor available because the guy who used to live there just disappeared.
Speaker 0: Oh, his furniture is still in there.
Speaker 1: You can take whatever you want.
Speaker 1: I'll take it to the dump.
Speaker 2: I'll take it.
Speaker 2: Well, we kept the hutch, but I'm pretty sure that bed was haunted.
Speaker 1: Maybe that's what happened to him.
Speaker 1: Maybe he's in the bed.
Speaker 0: I love how neighbor just fucking disappeared is also a relatively common story in New York.
Speaker 1: But yeah, I'm sure it's shocking how many people have water in the ceiling.
Speaker 1: And I think the lesson to be learned here is if I hear even the slightest, vaguest drip or noise in any wall, I am now of the mode.
Speaker 1: There is water in the ceiling.
Speaker 1: Get this fixed before there's any sort of droops or bulges or anything and never ignore bad smells.
Speaker 1: No, no.
Speaker 0: If there is a bad smell, you find the source of it, though.
Speaker 0: I remember one time we were sitting in the apartment and we smelled of garbage smell.
Speaker 0: And it was bad.
Speaker 0: And I was like, oh, shit.
Speaker 0: And we like not take out of garbage that we should have taken out the night before.
Speaker 0: But no, there was a clean bag in the garbage.
Speaker 0: And I started hunting around the apartment like, where's the smell coming from?
Speaker 0: And I got to the balcony and it's coming from outside.
Speaker 0: That was three summers, three or four summers ago.
Speaker 0: And the Hudson River was pretty low and the East River is pretty low.
Speaker 0: And the garbage layer had been exposed in the river.
Speaker 0: The whole neighborhood smelled like garbage.
Speaker 0: It was not our apartment.
Speaker 2: Classic New York summer.
Speaker 2: Yep.
Speaker 0: I think we were done here.
Speaker 0: Let's go get some food.
Speaker 0: This has been Geek Nights with Rim and Scott.
Speaker 0: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design, and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at FrontRowCrew.com for show notes, discussion news, and more.
Speaker 0: Remember, Geek Nights is not one, but four different shows.
Speaker 0: Sci-Tech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays, and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: Geek Nights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: Geek Nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 1: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.
Speaker 0: And the Patreon patrons for this episode of Geek Nights in order of how they show up on Patreon.
Speaker 0: Because I'm tired and lazy and I want to end the show real quick and go to bed.
Speaker 0: Meet Mr.
Speaker 0: Archimedes of Ancient Greece.
Speaker 0: Long ago Archis said, "Give me a lever.
Speaker 0: Long enough and I can move the
Speaker 0: world.".
Speaker 0: What Archimedes meant was that the power of a lever is practically unlimited.