Speaker 1: It's Wednesday, July 24th, 2019.
Speaker 1: I'm Rym, and this is Geek Nights.
Speaker 1: Tonight, we are talking about that kappa anime, Sarazanmai.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: There's some kappa and some butt stuff.
Speaker 1: Yeah, not Furikappa, the original, the OG.
Speaker 0: No one knows Furikappa.
Speaker 1: We've talked about Furikappa probably more than any other anime podcast in human history.
Speaker 0: It is my favorite pre-school anime.
Speaker 1: It is also my favorite pre-school anime, and I think it's my second favorite kappa centric anime.
Speaker 0: I don't know if Doraemon is like pre-school.
Speaker 0: I feel it's more kindergarten, right?
Speaker 0: Because you guys sort of have to know more language to talk about Doraemon.
Speaker 1: I think it's my second favorite kappa, because I think Sarazanmai is a better kappa focused anime based on the episodes we've seen.
Speaker 0: Furikappa is even below Sesame Street level.
Speaker 0: In Sesame Street, if you're in elementary school, you're watching Sesame Street, Doraemon, whatever.
Speaker 0: So, I feel like Furikappa is definitely pre-school.
Speaker 1: So, you noticed we didn't do a show Monday, which usually...
Speaker 0: I came.
Speaker 0: I was ready to do a show.
Speaker 0: Even though there was no topic, I was ready to do a show.
Speaker 1: I was pissed.
Speaker 1: It was funny, because for one thing, I had just spent a good chunk of my day arguing with people online about how New York is objectively superior to every other place on Earth and how cars should be banned and the subway, which is all true.
Speaker 0: I mean, in total, if you add up all the things about New York, positive and negative, it is the best place on Earth.
Speaker 0: But at each individual thing, except for maybe things like pizza, bagels, you know, things like that, there are many places that can easily beat New York in individual areas.
Speaker 1: But a place where that is not true is Intra-City Mass Transit.
Speaker 0: There's Tokyo.
Speaker 1: Tokyo actually doesn't go to that many places, and there's all different companies that run it, so you can't have the same card at every subway.
Speaker 0: I'm sure the trains run more on time.
Speaker 1: Not at night.
Speaker 1: They don't run at night, and they don't run that often.
Speaker 0: Aren't people working super late, though?
Speaker 1: Yeah, fuck you.
Speaker 1: It sucks.
Speaker 1: London's the same way.
Speaker 1: London...
Speaker 0: I know it doesn't run that late at night.
Speaker 0: And it doesn't actually go to the... The trains are nicer.
Speaker 0: The underground trains are a lot nicer.
Speaker 1: No, they're not.
Speaker 1: They're not air-conditioned.
Speaker 0: Not at all?
Speaker 0: No!
Speaker 1: The London Underground actually kind of sucks.
Speaker 0: But the trains are a lot newer and nicer.
Speaker 1: Have you ever even been to London?
Speaker 0: I've seen them.
Speaker 0: I look to trains online.
Speaker 1: So the London Underground one does not actually... It has so few stations and covers so little ground and has so little density.
Speaker 1: compared to New York, it's usually not useful to get where you're going.
Speaker 1: And part of that is because a lot of... Like, in New York, people come in to, like, Grand Central, Penn Station.
Speaker 1: There's not that many places.
Speaker 1: They come into the city and then they transfer to the subway.
Speaker 1: In London, there's a lot more light rail, so people will take the equivalent of the LIRR to wherever it is.
Speaker 1: they work in London.
Speaker 0: The Harry Potter place.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and they don't necessarily need to, like, then get on the Underground.
Speaker 1: Also, the London Underground trains don't hold that many people and are really small.
Speaker 1: Like, not that many cars.
Speaker 1: People who have not been to New York do not understand how many fucking people fit into one train of a New York City subway.
Speaker 0: Oh, like thousands.
Speaker 1: Paris is, like, the only place where the trains run at night other than New York.
Speaker 0: I thought they don't run at night.
Speaker 1: No, Paris is, like, the one place where they do.
Speaker 0: I thought they don't.
Speaker 1: Paris they do.
Speaker 0: Are you sure?
Speaker 1: I don't think they run all night.
Speaker 0: I thought New York was the only one where they run all night.
Speaker 1: Paris they run pretty much all night.
Speaker 0: Anyway... I mean, there are places that have better total transportation pictures, like mostly Netherlands, Amsterdam...
Speaker 1: Yeah, partly because they're tiny and have a very low population density.
Speaker 0: Also because they got rid of cars in, like, the '70s and '80s.
Speaker 1: But in terms of a normal human being, 24/7, getting from one part of New York City to another part of New York City, the subway is crazy amazing, considering that it's 100 years old and we spend almost no money maintaining it.
Speaker 0: And always broken.
Speaker 1: Always broken, but the broken subway still gets me there faster than driving would.
Speaker 0: Not really.
Speaker 1: Unless you're going between Brooklyn and Queens.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I was going to say.
Speaker 1: So here's my point.
Speaker 1: It's Monday when we tried to do the show, I couldn't get home because the subways were just fucked by the rain.
Speaker 1: So that was interesting because I just argued that we should ban cars.
Speaker 0: I'm sure if it rains in Tokyo, the trains are working just fine.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but my point was that cars were not getting anyone anywhere faster that night.
Speaker 0: No, I wouldn't...
Speaker 1: There was like a two-hour delay driving out of Manhattan, so the subway still got me home faster.
Speaker 1: But it did not get me home fast enough to do the show.
Speaker 1: There's no way I was expecting Scott to wait here for an hour.
Speaker 1: So yeah, we just didn't do a Monday show, which I think it's notable though, it's the first time we bailed on a Monday show because we were physically prevented from doing the show as opposed to...
Speaker 0: At least on a punctual...
Speaker 1: Yeah, because we just didn't have an idea.
Speaker 0: We also didn't have an idea though.
Speaker 1: But I feel like we could have come up with one.
Speaker 1: We were gonna do a show no matter what.
Speaker 1: I was about to say come hell or high water, but high water actually prevented us from doing the show.
Speaker 0: It wasn't even that high.
Speaker 1: It wasn't that high, but it was high enough.
Speaker 0: Medium water.
Speaker 1: Did you see the video of the person who got out of their car and just like unclogged the drain in the tunnel and then the flood went away?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I shared that video.
Speaker 0: That's why you saw it.
Speaker 1: Everyone shared that video.
Speaker 1: Fark!
Speaker 1: That was on the front page of Fark.
Speaker 0: And I was like, "Hey, they should go up and be friends with our thing of the
Speaker 0: day.".
Speaker 1: The culvert draining guy.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the culvert guy.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Does he got any news?
Speaker 0: No, I don't have any news really.
Speaker 1: Alright, I guess we'll get it out of the way.
Speaker 0: Well, I mean, there was a San Diego Comic-Con.
Speaker 0: And there was... Oh yeah, a ton of stuff got announced.
Speaker 1: MCU, whatever.
Speaker 0: Right, which means there are Eisner Award winners.
Speaker 0: You can look them up yourself.
Speaker 0: I actually haven't read most of them, so that's why.
Speaker 0: I looked at the list and I was like, "Oh, usually on Geek Nights, I talk about the list of Eisner Award winners and like ones that are...".
Speaker 0: But it's like I really have read almost none to none of them, so I can't really say much about them.
Speaker 0: How much I agree or disagree or anything like that.
Speaker 0: And yeah, most of the news from San Diego Comic-Con was not...
Speaker 1: Live action Hollywood movies.
Speaker 0: Right, it's like there wasn't really, you know, too much that was getting really exciting there.
Speaker 0: So, you know, that was in my wheelhouse to discuss.
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 0: It was, you know, it's mostly like, "Oh my God, here's the superhero movies we're gonna make that Scott's not gonna
Speaker 0: watch.".
Speaker 0: And I said,
Speaker 0: "Okay.".
Speaker 1: So I guess we'll get it out of the way.
Speaker 1: We can't avoid talking about the terrifying tragedy that happened to Kyoto Animation.
Speaker 0: I mean, but what is there to say about it other than it was a terrifying, horrifying tragedy.
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 1: Well, it's to the...
Speaker 0: Things like this happen far too often, which is more than zero times is too often.
Speaker 1: As an American, it's easy to be numb to this because we have mass shootings that kill similar numbers of people often enough to where they don't even all make the news.
Speaker 0: Yup, yup, yup.
Speaker 1: But it's also important, like I want to impress on like American anime fans that this is not on the scale of a tragedy that affected the anime industry so much as like a giant national tragedy for the nation of Japan.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think people definitely in the United States don't, you know, like when there's big tragedies, right, it's like they're not really seen as big as big as they are.
Speaker 0: Like I remember, because, you know, K-pop was and such, right, I see a lot of Korean stuffs and years ago there was the seawall fairy.
Speaker 0: It was like a fairy with hundreds of people.
Speaker 0: that was basically that you can look up why, but the fairy went down and a bunch of people drowned.
Speaker 0: Lots of people.
Speaker 0: And the population of Korea is not large.
Speaker 0: There are not a lot of total Korean people on Earth.
Speaker 1: There also aren't mass deaths as often as happened in the United States.
Speaker 0: Right, a significant number of the Korean people on Earth drowned in the fairy to where it was like an enormous, enormous deal for those people, whereas if that same fairy with the same number of people had like, I don't know, sunk in Manhattan, it would be a deal.
Speaker 0: But we would not be talking about it still.
Speaker 1: It would be in the news in the U.S.
Speaker 1: for like two days and then a month later when the follow-up like, "Oh, the driver of the thing has been
Speaker 1: charged.".
Speaker 0: Right, so if this, you know what, like 30-something people.
Speaker 1: 34 because people in the hospital are still dying because burn injuries are horrific.
Speaker 0: Right, so if this had not been anime-related, right, it probably wouldn't even make news in the
Speaker 0: U.S.,
Speaker 0: but it would still, it's probably still, I imagine, the number one news in Japan even now.
Speaker 1: It is because this is the single largest mass murder in Japan since World War II.
Speaker 0: Right, if you probably look, it's probably the front page of every Japanese newspaper every single day.
Speaker 1: Like, you know what this is like?
Speaker 1: Remember when Columbine happened in the U.S.
Speaker 1: This is like 9/11 big.
Speaker 0: When Columbine happened.
Speaker 0: It's like, you know, what, 1000, you know, let's see.
Speaker 1: When the Columbine mass shooting happened in the
Speaker 1: U.S.,
Speaker 1: that was the only thing in the news for months because that was relatively unprecedented and it was a big deal.
Speaker 1: Now they happen so often, they're not even talked about.
Speaker 0: Right, it's like, you know, the actual count of people dying is probably, you know, hundredths of the people that died on 9/11, but in terms of, you know, societal impact to the country, you know.
Speaker 1: But also, this will deeply affect KyoAni because if 34 people, like I work for a giant company, if 34, well we had one person in my department die a while ago.
Speaker 0: Probably a significant person.
Speaker 1: Yeah, one person died out of nowhere.
Speaker 1: It was terribly tragic.
Speaker 1: She died in a plane crash like out of nowhere and that actually really affected obviously psychologically, but it also affected the day-to-day business, like it affected what we're gonna do.
Speaker 0: I had a meeting with that person tomorrow.
Speaker 0: Now they're not there.
Speaker 0: They're never gonna be there.
Speaker 1: It's actually tough.
Speaker 0: Whatever they knew, whatever they had to say, all their knowledge gone.
Speaker 1: What's tough is that some of the things that I had this person design for me aren't done yet, so literally today I was doing an engineering like UX review and I pulled up the screen and I just remembered, oh yeah, she designed that.
Speaker 1: Oof.
Speaker 0: I mean, I've only been at the place I'm working right now a little over a year and I've learned basically a whole shit ton about, you know, our business.
Speaker 0: If I got hit by a bus while I'm biking and I don't work anymore, they have to find a new developer who's as good as me and then teach them everything that it took me six months to learn about the business not to mention any software things.
Speaker 0: Then they have to learn the code that I already wrote and then that project's gonna be delayed for like, you know, right?
Speaker 0: If 34 people, that's more than our whole department.
Speaker 0: Our whole project would be over.
Speaker 0: They would have to start from nothing.
Speaker 1: Yup, or shut, like.
Speaker 1: that's the kind of thing that shuts down a company.
Speaker 0: An insurance policy would pay out to maybe save the company.
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 1: And the only other thing that's notable to say about this, and I'm not gonna say the name of the person who did it because he's just some terrorist shitbag, but it is becoming increasingly apparent that he is another one of these obsessed crazy fan types who are a very real danger to the creative
Speaker 0: endeavors
Speaker 1: in the world today.
Speaker 1: Crazed fans believe that the companies that make the anime titties and the video games that they like owe them something and when they don't get what they expected, they freak out and they're dangerous.
Speaker 0: We've talked about this before, you know, and it's like, what's the root cause is questionable, right?
Speaker 0: Is the toxic masculinity the root cause?
Speaker 1: Is it the sense of entitlement?
Speaker 0: Is it some fungus, you know, like rabies or some disease like rabies that controls your brain?
Speaker 0: 'cause those are real.
Speaker 0: I'm not even joking about that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I doubt it's that in these cases.
Speaker 0: Right, but I'm saying there's like lead poisoning, right, when lead went out of our gas, violence went way down in the
Speaker 0: U.S.,
Speaker 0: right?
Speaker 1: Yup, and we can't say for sure.
Speaker 0: Right, the root cause of why people like this exist is unknown, but people like this have always been around, right?
Speaker 0: But there seems to be a correlation of people who are sad, right?
Speaker 1: Yup, isolated.
Speaker 0: Isolated, toxically, masculine, always men.
Speaker 0: Always men.
Speaker 0: Never women, so there must be some relation to either societal treatment of men or genetically men or both or something like that.
Speaker 1: And then hyper obsessive about a piece of popular culture.
Speaker 0: Well, not just a piece of, obsession with something, right?
Speaker 0: It could be a celebrity that they stalk, it could be a person they know that they stalk, it could be a piece of artwork, right?
Speaker 0: Like they're obsessed with, you know, a catcher in the rye, like the guy who shot John Lennon.
Speaker 0: Right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, people like young kids today don't really know a lot about why John Lennon was shot.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: It was stupid.
Speaker 1: It was just as stupid as this.
Speaker 0: It could be, you know, an anime or a studio or a song or a band.
Speaker 0: or, you know, these people who have all those other problems tend to get obsessed with a thing and then when they, if they, right, but they often do, or I guess we only, confirmation bias, we only hear about them when they do.
Speaker 0: So maybe the ones who- Well, there's another, there's gotta be some other factor on top of all these things.
Speaker 0: There are many people like this who I guess don't end up acting out violently.
Speaker 0: Yup.
Speaker 0: But those who do, target that thing that they're obsessed with with their violence.
Speaker 0: It always, it looks a lot like the serial killers you see in like Hannibal movies.
Speaker 1: Yup, but I think it's like, 'cause you know, the history of- But the history of serial killers, like it was kind of a big deal when the FBI, like in the early days of this kind of research, figured out that there's this one kind of murder that's very different from every other kind of murder we've ever seen.
Speaker 1: And they follow a pattern and the pattern was oddly specific.
Speaker 0: Yup.
Speaker 1: And there is a similar, kind of like how they figured out what a sequence killer was and later they call it a serial killer.
Speaker 1: There is a kind of dangerous person that fits a very narrow profile and the same kind of person did this crime.
Speaker 0: Right, and we see it also happening with like the crazy QAnon dude.
Speaker 0: Yup.
Speaker 1: Yeah, remember the head of the Gambino crime family was murdered by someone who thought that Donald Trump would protect him because of QAnon.
Speaker 1: Like, that is crackpot, batshit, crazy.
Speaker 0: It's definitely crackpot because if anything, Trump and Gambino's are like, "Yeah,
Speaker 0: baby.".
Speaker 0: They're like best bros.
Speaker 0: I guess, or maybe they're not best bros 'cause it could be Russian Mafia versus Italian Mafia.
Speaker 0: Could be.
Speaker 0: Maybe they're not best bros.
Speaker 1: The point is, If you were nefarious and you wanted to hurt people, you would trick the QAnon nut jobs into attacking the person you wanted to take out.
Speaker 1: Just saying.
Speaker 0: Anyway.
Speaker 1: So, there's not much more to say about this except that I hope the studio survives because they're doing really good work.
Speaker 1: Mmm.
Speaker 1: In much more horrifying news 'cause I gotta make a segue out of that, the Cats trailer came out.
Speaker 0: This is much less horrifying.
Speaker 0: In fact, the opposite of horrifying.
Speaker 1: The internet reacted to it pretty strongly.
Speaker 0: it's easy to see why, right?
Speaker 0: Is that A, musicals, regardless of what you personally think of them, is sort of a cultural thing where it's sort of like funny to laugh at them and be against them.
Speaker 1: Now, I love musicals.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: There seems to be this at least some large feeling in the general pop culture, at least in the US, that, you know, you should hate musicals or you should only like them ironically.
Speaker 1: Well, like the anti-disco movement.
Speaker 1: Like, that was a pop culture thing to make fun of disco even if you didn't care that much about disco.
Speaker 0: That was a racist movement, actually.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well, yeah.
Speaker 1: I said pop culture.
Speaker 0: But anyway.
Speaker 0: Was I wrong?
Speaker 0: Maybe the anti-musical movement is anti-gay.
Speaker 0: Who knows?
Speaker 1: But I love musicals and I like the music from Cats but I do not like Cats as a musical.
Speaker 0: I both like musicals and Cats and the music in Cats.
Speaker 1: I like the music in Cats but I don't want to see any part of Cats except the musical pieces themselves separated from Cats the musical.
Speaker 0: Cats is not my favorite musical by any stretch.
Speaker 0: But if you said, "Hey, Scott.
Speaker 1: Cats is playing
Speaker 1: again."
Speaker 1: I don't need to go see Cats again.
Speaker 0: Have some tickets.
Speaker 0: I'd be like,
Speaker 0: "Alright."
Speaker 0: And in fact, I would even pay a number of dollars for those tickets greater than zero.
Speaker 1: I would go see Martin fucking Gair again before I would see Cats again.
Speaker 0: I thought that's your favorite shit, though.
Speaker 1: Martin Gair is not good.
Speaker 0: I thought it was your favorite biz.
Speaker 1: I like Martin Gair in the same way that I like watching a Dark Souls speedrun.
Speaker 1: Attempting to perform Martin Gair is an interesting feat unto itself and I like to watch experts struggle to do difficult things.
Speaker 1: But I do not- Martin Gair is not a good musical.
Speaker 0: I mean, there's a reason it's not really playing, anyway.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it was intended to be Les Mis 2, basically, and it did not succeed.
Speaker 1: But I digress.
Speaker 0: Okay, so there's a trailer for a new Cats movie.
Speaker 0: Now, usually when things are adapted from some other medium to movie, right?
Speaker 0: Which is usually the direction most adaptations go is to movie, right?
Speaker 0: Rarely from movie.
Speaker 0: Usually, they're not so hot.
Speaker 0: We got some notable exceptions like Lord of the Rings, for example.
Speaker 0: But not The Hobbit.
Speaker 0: Which I didn't even see past one and a half- I only watched one and a half Hobbit movies.
Speaker 1: And it depends, because there are 0.75 good Hobbit movies.
Speaker 1: If you don't count the old animated ones.
Speaker 1: Anyway.
Speaker 1: There are 0.75 live-action Hobbit movies.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so, the thing is, the one kind of adaptation to movie that actually has a very long history of being very successful and good is Broadway play, especially musical, but pretty much any Broadway play, even non-musical ones, any stage production, to movie, those actually, historically, tend to be great, and many of the best movies of all time were just originally plays of some kind.
Speaker 0: There's a great Death of the Salesman movie.
Speaker 0: There's a great- Oh, uh, Fiddler on the Roof.
Speaker 0: There's a little- What else can I think?
Speaker 0: Cabaret, one of the best movies.
Speaker 0: Cabaret is a great movie.
Speaker 0: Is it Oklahoma?
Speaker 0: Wasn't that originally?
Speaker 0: That's kind of a good movie.
Speaker 1: Oh, I haven't seen Oklahoma since I was a little kid.
Speaker 0: Kind of a good movie.
Speaker 0: It's not bad.
Speaker 1: Oklahoma where the wind comes running down the ta-.
Speaker 0: The point is, I can go on like this for a while.
Speaker 1: We've done a show about musicals.
Speaker 0: Oh, did we?
Speaker 1: Probably.
Speaker 1: If we didn't, there's an easy Thursday show.
Speaker 0: Anyway, if you go to the theater with a camera, which they won't let you do, and you just record the stage play- Not good usually.
Speaker 0: It's usually, it's rarely, rarely, rarely ever good.
Speaker 0: I actually have seen just recording of Cats on television on cable randomly when I was at my family's house, and it's aight.
Speaker 0: It's nowhere near being there.
Speaker 1: It's like- And it's nowhere near if they adapted it to a movie, like say Moulin Rouge, where there's a camera that can move around and you can do multiple takes and have CG.
Speaker 0: It's worse than being in the cheapest, crappiest, obstructed view seat at the theater than watching just recording of what happened at the theater.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: Right?
Speaker 0: But when you make an actual movie with the same plot, same music, same script basically, just adapt it from a stage play to a screenplay, it tends to turn out great.
Speaker 0: So, a cat's moving, which I already like cats, so I actually think this is gonna be great.
Speaker 1: I guess my- What the internet took issue with, which I do disagree too, is that the faces are way too human and they edge into an uncanny valley as a result.
Speaker 0: Obviously, it would've been better if they didn't do all the CG nonsense and just had to stick people in the cat costumes.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Or if they doubled down on the CG nonsense and just made either actual cats, a la Lion King.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: I would've watched the hell out of that.
Speaker 0: Or, right, the main problem here is if it looks in the trailer like what they've done, it's not as bad as the Sonic the Hedgehog movie trailer was, but it looks like they've made CG furry cat people, right?
Speaker 1: With non-furry human faces.
Speaker 0: That their bodies are controlled by some sort of motion capture, plus a little flair added by animators, right?
Speaker 0: Post, you know, whatever, right?
Speaker 0: Like, you know, whiskers twinkling and stuff you can't really do with your motion capture.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I guess you could attach some whiskers to your face, but you can't control the way a cat does, right?
Speaker 0: Or tails, for example, right?
Speaker 0: And then, they've sort of taken people's faces, and for the face capture, it almost looks... You remember that YouTube with the annoying orange?
Speaker 0: It was like an orange, and there was like a human lip and eyes in the orange that were just like superimposed there on their own.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: It's like that.
Speaker 0: It's like they just put someone's face and just drew a lasso tool around their moving face and just pasted it onto the cat face.
Speaker 0: And drew some whiskers on it.
Speaker 1: It should have either just been actual actors and practical effects or make them have actual fucking cat faces.
Speaker 1: Just go nuts with it.
Speaker 0: But I feel like it's one of those things.
Speaker 0: I didn't actually see it yet, but actually now, I think you can watch it on Discord stream as the more recent Battle Angel movie where people during the trailer were like, "The eyes, I'm
Speaker 0: again!".
Speaker 0: Right?
Speaker 0: I haven't seen it, but I have heard from people that actually, when you watch the movie, it's not really a big problem.
Speaker 0: It just stands out in the trailer.
Speaker 0: So I feel, I'm not saying I guarantee this, but I just feel that when you watch this Cats movie that the weird faces, I think you will possibly get over them.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's hard to say because Cats is kind of long and boring.
Speaker 0: Cats is, I mean, long is a good thing.
Speaker 0: You want more for your money and boring, no.
Speaker 1: You want longer, more for your money, watch the full Jekyll and Hyde.
Speaker 0: Alright.
Speaker 0: Sure.
Speaker 0: Sounds good.
Speaker 0: There's actually, what was that one that's like a, there was a Harry Potter one that was recent.
Speaker 0: I don't know if it's still going.
Speaker 0: Oh yeah.
Speaker 0: You have to go on two different days.
Speaker 0: It's like a two show deal.
Speaker 0: You gotta come on two days.
Speaker 0: Like part one on one day, or part two on another day.
Speaker 1: I think someone on Twitter said it best.
Speaker 0: another play that did the same thing, where it's two part.
Speaker 1: Instead of making the photorealistic Lion King that does not look good.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the Lion King one apparently is awful.
Speaker 0: I don't know why.
Speaker 0: they, you know.
Speaker 1: I think they should have made the Lion King like this, and they should have made Cats Like the Lion King.
Speaker 1: I think those would have made, it would have made two better movies.
Speaker 0: I think they should just go back to hand drawn animation.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I feel like these, it's funny how even mainstream media sites are calling that the live action Lion King.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 1: But I feel like those movies are just aimed at the international generic audience.
Speaker 0: Just about any movie is aimed at the international audience.
Speaker 0: You don't make enough money by putting just a movie in U.S.
Speaker 0: theaters.
Speaker 1: So I got a brief pseudo geek bite, because when we judged anime by its cover most recently, one of the shows we talked about that looked really good, but then when we looked at what it was about, we decided it probably wasn't that good, was Fire Force, which
Speaker 0: was
Speaker 1: Fire Fighters.
Speaker 0: Was the Japanese name of it, because we didn't say Fire Force when we... Anano Shobutai?
Speaker 0: Yeah, we didn't judge it according to the... AnnieChart.net likes to use Japanese names.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: But we knew it was the fireman anime.
Speaker 0: Yeah, because the image we saw had Fire Fighters in it.
Speaker 1: And it looked really aesthetic, but then when we looked at what it was about, it's got a bunch of proper nouns.
Speaker 0: It looks just like a shonen action fight.
Speaker 1: And it's by the Soul Eater.
Speaker 1: It's by the Soul Eater guy.
Speaker 0: It's going to be Soul Eater.
Speaker 0: Fight the supernatural force shonen show, but everyone, it looks like Fire Fighters.
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 1: And my main worry about this show was that it's going to be a dumb shonen fighting show.
Speaker 1: A lot of people are trying to tell me this is not the case, and that is legitimately good.
Speaker 0: Well, do those people like Soul Eater?
Speaker 1: So, here's my new worry about Fire Force.
Speaker 1: Did you watch Fire Force?
Speaker 1: Not yet, no.
Speaker 0: geek biting it?
Speaker 1: No, I said it's a pre-geek bite.
Speaker 0: Pre-geek bite.
Speaker 0: It's the geek.
Speaker 0: He already did that.
Speaker 0: It was called Judge Anime by his cover.
Speaker 1: So here's my thinking on this now.
Speaker 0: Oh my god, this is all rim.
Speaker 0: I got nothing to do with this.
Speaker 1: So all I'm saying is, my worry about this show now...
Speaker 0: Whenever I judge, it still stands.
Speaker 1: My worry about this show, I have a more nuanced judge because I took a bite.
Speaker 0: Uh-huh.
Speaker 1: My worry is that... Remember how Noir felt like it was going to be the greatest anime ever, and then nine or ten episodes in, we realized the music had just tricked us?
Speaker 1: I worry that Fire Force is the same thing.
Speaker 1: The people who are saying it's good have been tricked by the amazing aesthetics, and in eight or nine episodes, they're going to realize it's just Soul Eater.
Speaker 0: Uh-huh.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 1: So what do you got to geek bite?
Speaker 0: So, you know, I've been buying a lot less comic books lately because I've been reading a lot less comic books and waiting for more trades, and there's, you know, there's a lot less... It's like Saga is on hiatus, for example, right?
Speaker 0: You know, and it's... There seemed to be this thing where there was a wave when I started buying comic books in the Beacon days where it's like, aha, I'm out of college and I have a job.
Speaker 0: I can buy comic books now.
Speaker 0: So I bought all the great comic books of history that I had never read.
Speaker 1: And between the two of us, we have a large pile of comics.
Speaker 0: And then over time, great series, I got them all and they were done, or things stopped, right?
Speaker 0: And the number of new things that came out, because I was buying decades worth of great stuff, right?
Speaker 0: The rate at which new stuff came out that I was going to read and also the rate of me reading stuff.
Speaker 0: It was down, right?
Speaker 1: Of all the complete manga I've bought up there, I think Here Is Greenwood is the only one I actually read all of.
Speaker 0: Then there's like a wave where it's like, all right, you got all these American comics.
Speaker 0: Well, now we're going to publish all these great mangas of history that you never had, like all these Tezukas and stuff.
Speaker 0: So I was buying all that.
Speaker 0: And then that wave has now sort of crashed.
Speaker 0: And now there's only like a trickle of new comic books that I have time to read and want to read and I'm willing to pay to read.
Speaker 1: And there's even a worst piece there for me in particular in that other than comics, I do not consume anything else with physical media.
Speaker 1: Like anything.
Speaker 1: Anime, books, nothing.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: I would get digital comics if, A, I could get all the ones that I want, in the format I want, and they weren't meh.
Speaker 1: And B, like the reading experience is still like not quite there.
Speaker 0: It's not there.
Speaker 0: Anyway, there are some things like comics I can read digitally, like if they were meant to, like a webcomic.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Anyway, the point is, I recently went to the beach, I had some reading time.
Speaker 0: I've been trying to read the comics I have because there's quite a few comics I have that are in a pile known as read and then get rid of to clean up shelf space.
Speaker 0: Then there's read and keep forever.
Speaker 0: But anyway, one of the ones I did not read, but is a read and keep forever one, obviously, is Lone Wolf and Cub by Kazuo Koike, because originally, people don't know, it was published by Dark Horse in these tiny weird shaped volumes.
Speaker 1: I remember, I'd always see them.
Speaker 1: I always wanted them, but I didn't have money.
Speaker 0: You can get these at discount bins at like any convention, and there were like tons of them, and in order to get the full set of the manga, you had to buy a lot of these little tiny volumes.
Speaker 0: So I started collecting them at one point, but I didn't want to start reading until I had them all, just in case, right?
Speaker 0: And then before I could get them all, "You know what?
Speaker 0: We're going to reprint it in these big volumes that are not only larger in page
Speaker 0: size.".
Speaker 0: See, the art is better, easier to see.
Speaker 0: Not these little tiny bookies.
Speaker 1: Because you're reading Kazuo Koike, you got to appreciate that art.
Speaker 0: Well, he's not the artist.
Speaker 1: Well, yeah, but his subject matter.
Speaker 0: Anyway, but also each volume was actually like three, I think three smaller ones combined into a single volume, like these omnibus editions.
Speaker 0: So I could buy much fewer total books and get all of it.
Speaker 0: So that was quite a while ago.
Speaker 0: I bought those as they published them.
Speaker 1: And you still got the little ones?
Speaker 0: No, I got rid of the little ones.
Speaker 1: Okay, get rid of them all.
Speaker 0: I have all of Lone Wolf and Cub in larger editions.
Speaker 0: So I finally got around to reading it.
Speaker 0: I've read two and a half large books, which is about, I'd say, seven to eight small books' worth.
Speaker 0: And I mean, everyone says it's like a masterpiece, all time great manga.
Speaker 0: And they ain't lying.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 1: So lay those omnibuses on me.
Speaker 0: If you, you know, if you're the kind of person who watches like samurai movies, you know, like some Akira Kurosawa and such.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And you're like, man, I've seen like every samurai movie, great samurai movie there is.
Speaker 0: You know, I sure would like more samurai tales because they're really great.
Speaker 0: Well, here you go.
Speaker 0: This one is like way better than most.
Speaker 0: I'm sure you can still get it quite easily, maybe even digitally in English.
Speaker 0: Why wouldn't you?
Speaker 0: The only negative thing I can say is that it is still flippid.
Speaker 0: It is left to right.
Speaker 0: And also they leave a lot of words like Romanized, but still the Japanese word, they even warn you about it.
Speaker 0: They intentionally do it.
Speaker 0: And I can see why, because the words they leave are words that have a meaning that is so complicated that you couldn't put enough words in the tiny, tiny bubbles that this comic has.
Speaker 1: All according to Keikaku.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Not like that.
Speaker 0: But, you know, they're usually words, you know, because I imagine that it's an older style of Japanese language from the olden times.
Speaker 0: And also the other thing they do that is slightly meh in the translation, which I guess is a thing that a lot of people have done, which is, you know, when people in the, you know, at least if you know about anime and manga, you're a seasoned anime manga connoisseur.
Speaker 0: That when someone's speaking in like different dialects of Japan, they just translate it to different accents of America.
Speaker 0: So it's like someone's talking in a Southern way.
Speaker 0: Oh, they must be from Osaka or whatever.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Whatever it is.
Speaker 0: So they do that thing a lot as well.
Speaker 0: That stands out.
Speaker 0: But yeah, it's basically, you know, Lone Wolf and Cub.
Speaker 0: If you don't know anything about it, it's about this badass dude.
Speaker 0: His background is mysterious.
Speaker 0: He's like the best god tier swordsman there is.
Speaker 0: He's an assassin.
Speaker 0: You can hire him for 500 Rio, which is a lot of fucking money and he'll kill whoever you want to kill.
Speaker 0: And his only condition is that you tell him the truth, like the whole story, like, you know, I need you to kill this person because X, Y, and Z. And then he does it.
Speaker 0: You better not lie to him.
Speaker 0: No, that would be a bad idea.
Speaker 0: But yeah, he's, he's just god tier.
Speaker 0: And he has a son, a little like, you know, three year old kid.
Speaker 0: He pushes the kid around in a little carriage, which has weapons built into it.
Speaker 1: Spoilers.
Speaker 0: That's not spoilers.
Speaker 0: And yeah, the kid is also a super dangerous badass because his whole life has been going around with his assassin dad watching his assassin dad chop people up.
Speaker 1: I'm just thinking about your crew.
Speaker 1: I'm already now the rabbit in the lion's den.
Speaker 0: That's actually a good, that's actually an example of a word they don't translate.
Speaker 0: is he's always talking about like, I travel the path of Meifumado.
Speaker 0: I don't actually know how to pronounce it or if I'm saying it right.
Speaker 0: But basically it's the word for the Buddhist hell equivalent, right?
Speaker 0: That's the road he travels.
Speaker 0: So you couldn't really, it would be weird if it was like, I travel the road of Buddhist hell all the time.
Speaker 1: And you could translate it as just the road to hell, but in the US that has different connotations.
Speaker 0: It's not, if they could say Jigoku.
Speaker 0: I happen to know the Japanese word for hell is Jigoku because that's one of my favorite Japanese words.
Speaker 0: But Jigoku.
Speaker 1: Plus it comes up a lot in Eccentric Family with the thin golden thread.
Speaker 0: It comes up a lot in anime and manga in general.
Speaker 1: Jipu no Jigoku.
Speaker 0: Japanese word of the day.
Speaker 0: Jigoku.
Speaker 0: J-I-G-O-K-U.
Speaker 0: It means hell.
Speaker 0: Anyway, the point is, if he said I walked the path of Jigoku that would not have the same meaning at all.
Speaker 0: It's completely different, right?
Speaker 0: So there you go.
Speaker 0: This is your, I guess, reminder to read Lone Wolf and Cub.
Speaker 0: If it's, you know, it's a thing you probably know, haven't thought about, maybe you've read it, maybe you haven't.
Speaker 0: If you haven't, correct yourself.
Speaker 1: But anyway, things of the day.
Speaker 1: So I'm a big fan of optical illusions because they're neat.
Speaker 1: Some of them.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but they're neat especially when they illustrate something weird about how the human brain processes visual information.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there are some optical illusions where it's like no one ever explains them really.
Speaker 0: And it's just sort of like, you know, it could be a trick of the light as opposed to it, but the ones that are a trick of the brain that are explained are the best ones.
Speaker 0: Because it's not the illusion, because once you're an adult the illusion itself doesn't really fascinate you anymore unless you're a jaded adult.
Speaker 1: But more like this illusion works because your brain processes simple information faster than it processes complex information.
Speaker 0: Right, stuff like that.
Speaker 1: Like that is the mind-bending stuff.
Speaker 0: Oh my god, it's not red.
Speaker 0: You're seeing green, but it's red.
Speaker 1: Yep, your brain is making shit up because that's what it does.
Speaker 1: And this particular Twitter account just happens to, I'm just going to read the description.
Speaker 1: "I am an experimental psychologist who studies visual illusions as well as makes illusion
Speaker 1: artworks.".
Speaker 0: Nice.
Speaker 1: And the account is just that.
Speaker 1: It's amazing.
Speaker 1: One of these really blew my mind because I was unaware of it and it's one, I'm not going to...
Speaker 0: Is it the one where you stare at the dot?
Speaker 1: No.
Speaker 0: Is that magic eye?
Speaker 1: It's the one about complexity of information where there's this image and if you move your head or move the image, parts of it will move faster than other parts because your brain literally takes longer to process the more complex part of the image.
Speaker 1: So your brain is showing you the simpler information faster.
Speaker 0: Isn't it interesting how video codecs have the same issues with complex parts of the image versus simple parts of the image?
Speaker 1: Yep, like all the contrast of a black gradient gets really messed up and bad if there's complex motion in the foreground for a little bit, stuff like that.
Speaker 1: That's also, you know, fun fact, if you're too young to know, when MP3s came out, the reason why MP3s were a big deal was that they encoded audio in a way that got rid of a ton of information
Speaker 0: that
Speaker 1: the human brain did not need that information to reconstruct the sound for your conscious understanding.
Speaker 1: So what do you got?
Speaker 0: So, a long time ago, I did a thing of the day where there was some, you know, '50s kind of game show or something, right, where they had to guess, like, something about this old man.
Speaker 1: Oh, that was a really good one.
Speaker 0: And it turned out that the old man, you know, this was in the '50s, 1950-something, so when my parents were alive, even though they were just, like, zero, they were less than 10, right?
Speaker 1: The New York City subway had already been around for 50 years.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 0: But there was a man on the game show who had been a child and was in Ford's Theatre when Lincoln was assassinated, right?
Speaker 0: And it was like, damn, that person was alive in 1950-something as an old man.
Speaker 1: That person was alive to be on TV.
Speaker 1: Like, whoa.
Speaker 0: So here is television for 1953, I think?
Speaker 1: October 18th, 1950.
Speaker 0: Oh, they got the exact date.
Speaker 1: I didn't even notice because I didn't watch the whole thing.
Speaker 1: With commercials.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: So this appears to be a TV show, sort of a game show, but not really.
Speaker 0: I guess it is a game show to some extent, called What's My Line?
Speaker 0: You may have heard of it.
Speaker 0: And I've heard of it, but I never actually knew how the show went.
Speaker 0: The way the show goes is there's a panel of -- everyone on the show is white.
Speaker 1: It's the '50s.
Speaker 0: There are women on the show.
Speaker 0: Celebrity comedy guests on the show.
Speaker 0: At least, you know, they weren't major celebrities because I haven't heard of them, but they were celebrities of the time of some nature, right?
Speaker 0: And they were comedian, funny people, writers, that sort of thing, right?
Speaker 0: Colonists, those sorts of people.
Speaker 0: And they would bring someone on the show, just a random person, and they would be trying to guess, sort of like a 20-questions thing, what the person's job was, right?
Speaker 0: And one of the men, for example, who appears on the show, the more questions the people have to ask, I think the more prize and money the contestant, the person with the job gets, right?
Speaker 0: So one of the men was like a bathtub salesman, right?
Speaker 0: So they're asking questions like, "Oh, is this a thing?
Speaker 0: Does your work involve any sort of product?
Speaker 0: Is it something that I would use?
Speaker 0: Is it something I would use in the home?
Speaker 0: Is it something I would use in my
Speaker 0: bathroom?".
Speaker 0: Right?
Speaker 0: It's like, "Yes, you
Speaker 0: might.".
Speaker 0: "Would women use it or men use
Speaker 0: it?".
Speaker 0: They ask these kinds of questions, and he's a bathtub salesman, so he answers truthfully, but the answer ends up being funny, and it's a funny show to watch, right?
Speaker 0: So in this particular episode, well, I think in a lot of the episodes, they have a true celebrity appear.
Speaker 0: They blindfold the panel, and they have the host answer the questions for the celebrity, because otherwise you can guess by voice who it was.
Speaker 1: Like if it was Barack Obama in the modern era, and you heard the voice, you'd be like, "That's Barack
Speaker 1: Obama!".
Speaker 0: Yeah, you'd be like, "Do you work in
Speaker 0: manufacturing?".
Speaker 0: "No.".
Speaker 0: "Oh, you're Obama.
Speaker 0: It's
Speaker 0: Obama.".
Speaker 1: Obama would say, "Welp,".
Speaker 1: and then you'd be like, "Okay, Mr.
Speaker 1: Obama.".
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: But here on this episode, which it's crazy that this is on YouTube, someone managed to save the recording of this, because it seems like it was live television.
Speaker 0: Eleanor Roosevelt was the celebrity person that they had to guess.
Speaker 1: That is amazing.
Speaker 0: That's really amazing, and also, the reason I think it's live television is because they only have one ad.
Speaker 0: It's for Remington Electric Razors.
Speaker 1: Well, because the show is called on the marquee, like while they're doing the show, "Remington Razors
Speaker 1: present.".
Speaker 0: Yeah, pretty much.
Speaker 1: Or "Remington Electric Shavers
Speaker 1: present.".
Speaker 0: Yes, they're constantly, it's the only thing they advertise.
Speaker 0: They talk about it constantly, and I think even there's this little board that shows the prize that he's counting up with, has a picture of an electric razor on it.
Speaker 1: I'd almost rather go back to this kind of advertising.
Speaker 0: I mean, it's honest advertising.
Speaker 0: It's the kind of advertising you guys would do.
Speaker 0: We're like, "Yeah, buy this piece of crap.
Speaker 0: This piece of crap is paying us to make this show.
Speaker 0: Don't buy
Speaker 0: it.".
Speaker 0: In fact, at one point, one of the guests is like, "Oh, you sell electric razors?
Speaker 0: Is that what they're doing?
Speaker 0: You in the razor business, maybe?
Speaker 0: Is Remington making
Speaker 0: it?".
Speaker 0: They incorporate the ad into the, you know, anyway.
Speaker 0: It's a good way to spend 20 to 30 minutes a year, and I think it's live TV because they have to hurry to the end of the show.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: It's not a recording.
Speaker 1: Yeah, also live TV was still relatively in its infancy in terms of how to produce television.
Speaker 0: Well, they invented live TV before recorded TV.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but the trouble was live TV, producing that with the limited time schedules and everything was very difficult, and they didn't have a lot of the modern techniques that we use in production today.
Speaker 1: So, in the moment, the Geek Night's Book Club book is the first, well, not book, but the first novel.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: The Tale of Genji.
Speaker 0: The first novel ever written by human beings that we still have and know about and is in recorded history and such.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: Click on the link to make sure you get the right translation because that's the one we're talking about, and it is the fully unabridged one.
Speaker 1: Geek Nights, if we're about anything, if you had to define a thing that defines Geek Nights, it is that we use the unabridged versions of things.
Speaker 0: Geek Nights is never abridged.
Speaker 1: Except with the original Gundam, maybe we would just talk about the compilation movies.
Speaker 0: Eh, whatever.
Speaker 0: But I am reading a different book right now.
Speaker 1: I am also reading a different book right now.
Speaker 0: This book, The Tale of Genji, is a long book, so...
Speaker 1: It'll take us a little while.
Speaker 0: I mean, this book club will be in a while, but not like the ones in the past.
Speaker 0: We've delayed a long time because we didn't read.
Speaker 1: It'll actually take us a while to read it.
Speaker 0: It'll take us a while to get to it and then read it.
Speaker 0: But yeah, my reading, not playing games on my phone plan continues, and I always open Kindle app.
Speaker 0: I think I might just delete all games from my phone.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: I'm keeping one emergency game on my phone.
Speaker 1: Of course.
Speaker 0: Nuroshima Hex.
Speaker 1: Nuroshima Hex.
Speaker 1: I play that game 100% perfectly, as far as I can tell.
Speaker 1: When?
Speaker 1: How am I not on top of this?
Speaker 0: What do they add?
Speaker 0: I think they added new dudes.
Speaker 1: Are you sure?
Speaker 0: I haven't used it in a while, but I've heard.
Speaker 1: I gotta check right now before we get to the main bit.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: Because I would be surprised if there are new dudes in Nuroshima Hex 3.0.
Speaker 0: Well, that's the board game.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I think they've added new dudes to the digital edition.
Speaker 0: I'm not 100% sure, though.
Speaker 1: Because I know of a lot of factions.
Speaker 0: I'm like 75% sure.
Speaker 1: Alright, I've found some recent things.
Speaker 1: Whoa!
Speaker 1: No, those are unofficial fan armies.
Speaker 1: Those don't count.
Speaker 1: Oh, there's a revised Doomsday Machine.
Speaker 1: There's Mephisto.
Speaker 1: That's new.
Speaker 1: And there's Uranopolis.
Speaker 1: So, piss town?
Speaker 1: Strong robots requiring a power supply.
Speaker 0: Oh, interesting.
Speaker 1: Alright, so they redid Doom Machine because it sucked, I guess.
Speaker 0: It really sucked.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it did suck.
Speaker 0: Wasn't it the reflecting one?
Speaker 1: Mephisto.
Speaker 1: No unit.
Speaker 1: Just modules enhancing an alien HQ.
Speaker 1: And Uranopolis.
Speaker 1: The robots.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: Those are two, two and a half new factions.
Speaker 1: As far as I can tell.
Speaker 1: Alright.
Speaker 1: I did not know that.
Speaker 1: That'll get me like another month's worth of enjoyment out of that game.
Speaker 1: And otherwise, stay tuned.
Speaker 1: We will be live at PEX WEST.
Speaker 1: The mothership.
Speaker 1: The real PEX.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: We will be doing panels on Friday and Saturday.
Speaker 0: Lame panels.
Speaker 0: You can skip.
Speaker 0: But please come to them so I can keep getting free badges.
Speaker 0: But actually I'm not worried about that because they give us two panels at the PEX.
Speaker 0: They must be desperate.
Speaker 1: Well, also notice they're in the Hyatt and it's counter-programming to other big events.
Speaker 1: And based on some other things I've seen about the schedule and based on the worry about the security line situation in the main convention center, they really need to get more people to go over to the Hyatt during peak times.
Speaker 1: And both of our panels are in the Hyatt counter-programmed against other big events.
Speaker 1: So, and the title, these are panels that if you're a Geek Nights listener, you do not need to go to these panels because you know what we're going to say.
Speaker 1: This is the kind of panel where someone will see the 40 games you must play.
Speaker 1: Ooh, I'm excited.
Speaker 1: And then they're going to get tricked and it's going to be Raymond Scott telling them about game design and stuff.
Speaker 1: So, uh, these panels are not for you.
Speaker 1: They're for your friend who doesn't know enough names of games to play.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: So tell your friends to go to this panel.
Speaker 1: You yourself, the listener, you know what we're going to say.
Speaker 1: You do not need to go to these panels and let's get right into it.
Speaker 1: There's an anime that we knew we needed.
Speaker 1: We had to watch, uh, we had like a hundred percent.
Speaker 1: This is the kind of show we judged it.
Speaker 0: We said, Oh shit, that is a show made by Kuni Igu Iguahara.
Speaker 1: We're going to watch it.
Speaker 0: He who directed some episodes of Sailor Moon and then made Utena, made Utena the movie, made, then didn't take anything, then made that bear show.
Speaker 0: Well, there's penguin drum, which we didn't watch.
Speaker 0: I didn't watch the penguin show or the bear show.
Speaker 0: And now he's made the kappa show.
Speaker 1: No, I can't.
Speaker 1: The bear show is so good.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: So there's a lot of things that are so good.
Speaker 0: How much time I got?
Speaker 0: I got to read Telegenji.
Speaker 0: So you know what's better than bear show?
Speaker 0: Lone Wolf and Cup.
Speaker 1: So we're going to talk about Sarazanmai.
Speaker 1: We've only seen a few episodes.
Speaker 1: I know a lot more about it than I think Scott does.
Speaker 1: And I've seen Yurikuma Arashi.
Speaker 1: So there's a lot of parallels I can draw between the two.
Speaker 0: There's a lot of parallels between a lot of things.
Speaker 0: I've only seen two episodes of Sarazanmai.
Speaker 0: Usually we watch three or four, but we didn't have anything else to do the show on.
Speaker 0: And we wanted to do a show.
Speaker 1: We're going to review it to tell you can figure out if you need to watch it or not.
Speaker 1: You should watch it, but you may not be the kind of person who wants to see it.
Speaker 0: Stop listening to Geek Nights.
Speaker 0: I don't know why you even listen to it in the first place.
Speaker 1: But we're not going to spoil anything because I don't want to spoil.
Speaker 0: I've seen two episodes.
Speaker 1: So here's the thing about your.
Speaker 1: I was about to say Yurikuma Arashi, which of Tezuka's poster tenant works.
Speaker 1: I really like Yurikuma Arashi and I think it is definitely worth watching.
Speaker 0: You mean Ikuhara?
Speaker 1: Lesbian bear.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you said Tezuka.
Speaker 1: I did.
Speaker 1: It's a different person.
Speaker 1: Lesbian Bear Storm is another way to translate the name of that show.
Speaker 0: Oh yeah.
Speaker 1: I would say if you have not seen anything that Ikuhara made, you should watch them in the order that they were released.
Speaker 1: Watch the Sailor Moon parts that he had something to do with, like Sailor Moon S, the good Sailor Moon.
Speaker 1: Watch Utena and then just watch them in chronological release order.
Speaker 0: Oh, so you should watch Utena the movie.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you should watch Utena the movie after you watch Utena the show.
Speaker 1: And before you watch Penguin Drum, Yurikuma Arashi or Sarazanmai.
Speaker 0: You want to know something interesting I have on my calendar.
Speaker 0: Uh oh.
Speaker 0: Let me just find it here.
Speaker 1: I'm worried about what this is.
Speaker 0: On August 14th, 2019.
Speaker 1: August 14th, I will still be around.
Speaker 0: Utena the movie will be exactly 20 years old.
Speaker 1: God damn it, I am old.
Speaker 1: God damn, I remember watching trailers to that movie and being crazy excited about it because I didn't know what it was going to be.
Speaker 1: And I thought it would tell me more about Utena the TV show.
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 1: And it didn't, but it taught me a lot about Ikuhara.
Speaker 0: Also, this is the year
Speaker 0: 2019. 1989
Speaker 0: Batman is 30 years old.
Speaker 1: Oh yeah, we can play that game of things are old.
Speaker 0: I'm just saying.
Speaker 1: The 1989 Batman is still my favorite non-BTS Batman.
Speaker 1: Yeah, anyway.
Speaker 1: Not lying, not making a joke.
Speaker 0: So Sarazanmai is a show about Kappa.
Speaker 0: If you don't know Kappa.
Speaker 1: Yeah, this is all real.
Speaker 1: You gotta know this shit.
Speaker 1: If you don't know about Japanese myths around Kappa.
Speaker 0: I know enough about Kappa to be dangerous, but I don't know everything there is to know about Kappa.
Speaker 1: You need to know more about Kappa than you probably do before you watch this show.
Speaker 1: Or you're going to be in the deep end of a pool and you're not going to be able to swear.
Speaker 0: So Kappa are like these mythical Japanese creatures that sort of look frog-like.
Speaker 1: Yep, they wear a dish on their head that makes them look like they have a monk's haircut.
Speaker 0: Right, it makes them look like they shaved a circle at the top of their head, but actually they're wearing a dish on the top of their head.
Speaker 1: They're frog-like, they're mystical creatures.
Speaker 1: The dish is important, like sealing their dish is a big deal.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know, you'll see Kappa a lot in a lot of other animes and mangas, right?
Speaker 0: Like Furakapa.
Speaker 0: Or Fura Fura Kappa.
Speaker 1: Well, you know what?
Speaker 1: If you're going to watch Sarazanmai, I'm going to read two sentences from Wikipedia.
Speaker 1: This is what you need to know that unless you are an advanced anime fan or know about Japanese myth, you will not know.
Speaker 1: Quote, "The Kappa are known to favor cucumbers and love to engage in sumo
Speaker 1: wrestling.".
Speaker 0: Oh yeah, they love cucumbers.
Speaker 0: Yep, they love that too.
Speaker 0: That's sentence number one.
Speaker 1: Sentence number two, "They are often accused of assaulting humans in water and removing a mythical organ called a shirikodama from their victim's
Speaker 1: anus.".
Speaker 0: Yep, so there's this idea that you have this organ in your body called a. what is it?
Speaker 1: Shirikodama.
Speaker 0: Right, which is not a real organ in the body.
Speaker 1: It's a mythological organ that could be analogized to the prostate, maybe.
Speaker 0: There's a made-up bodily organ, so it's sort of like, "I got your
Speaker 0: finger.".
Speaker 1: "I got this thing in your anus.
Speaker 1: that is the seed of your
Speaker 1: desire.".
Speaker 0: Yeah, and Kappa like to steal it from people.
Speaker 0: So a mythical creature, there's a story about it stealing things from people's butts that they don't even have to begin with.
Speaker 1: Yep, some people will translate it or talk about it as a liver, depending on when you... But it is important that you know that Kappa will steal this mythical organ from humans' anuses and that Kappa like cucumbers and sumo.
Speaker 1: And you need to know all the basic stuff about Kappa.
Speaker 0: There's also the area of Japan where the show takes place, which I forget the name of, is a place that is tied to a lot of Kappa lore.
Speaker 0: The same way that when you watch Eccentric Family, that place in Japan is tied to a lot of Tanuki lore.
Speaker 0: Or the way that certain places in the US are tied to Paul Bunyan lore.
Speaker 1: Johnny Appleseed, that kind of thing.
Speaker 0: Right, the same kind of thing, where there's a myth, but the myth has a connection to a real world geography.
Speaker 0: And that's what's going on here, because the show takes place basically in the Kappa area.
Speaker 1: So you need to know all of that because that is what this show is about on the surface in the same way that Utena on the surface is about a bunch of high school kids fighting over who gets to go up into a floating castle and become God.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's the shallow part of the pool.
Speaker 0: Right, so the show, Sara's on my...
Speaker 1: Now take all that and add the Ikuhara factor.
Speaker 0: So you have this kid, he's the main character, and he's just like a high school kid doing high school kid stuff, but he's got secrets.
Speaker 1: Yep, everyone has secrets.
Speaker 0: He's got secrets, right?
Speaker 0: And the show stylizes this.
Speaker 0: And the secrets, they're not extreme, crazy secrets, but they're quite out of the ordinary.
Speaker 0: They're not like ridiculous, totally ridiculous.
Speaker 1: They're not that out of the ordinary in terms of a lot of people got secrets on that level.
Speaker 0: People do have secrets on that level, but this specifically I think would not apply to maybe zero people on Earth.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well, the second secret we learned about him is probably more common of committing that kind of crime because you've got problems.
Speaker 0: Yes, that is true.
Speaker 0: So in the course of him taking care of his secret biz, he bumps into some other kids in town.
Speaker 0: One of them is like a criminal who's trying to jack cars and works for the Yakuza or something.
Speaker 1: The second kid, it's like, okay, the show, you see this kid, you're like, okay, this kid's going to be some kind of delinquent.
Speaker 1: We're going to have main guy who's got a thing, delinquent guy, and then the third kid.
Speaker 0: The third kid you don't learn too much about in two episodes, but he's obviously the nerd kid.
Speaker 1: And like the next scene with the delinquent kid is he is literally fucking waterboarding someone for the mob.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: But anyway, so they all go to the same school.
Speaker 0: They get entwined with each other.
Speaker 0: And what really, really because there's nothing really to bring them together other than circumstance is that they happen to all basically get stuck dealing with this cop.
Speaker 1: This cop, just like this fat, lazy cop is just hanging out and they all meet him.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: They awaken this cop who is dormant and they all get trapped by him into, you know, the same way that it's like, oh, you're up the genie lab.
Speaker 0: Now you're stuck with all this genie biz.
Speaker 0: Well, you're stuck with cop a biz now.
Speaker 1: Or like in Yuri Kuma.
Speaker 0: Welcome to COPPA.
Speaker 1: Your girlfriend got eaten by a bear.
Speaker 1: Bears are lesbians from outer space.
Speaker 0: Now you have to deal with bears now.
Speaker 1: No escaping the bear plot.
Speaker 1: And then the whole show is about a world where bears just randomly attack people.
Speaker 0: So no escape.
Speaker 0: This guy, these kids cannot escape the COPPA plot.
Speaker 0: So what's the COPPA plot?
Speaker 0: The COPPA plot is that there are, I guess, sort of these things they have to fight in similar plot structure, similar episode structure to say in Utena or any sort of one of those anime where, you know, the episode leads up to a battle of some kind.
Speaker 0: You know, it has the same structure, not as much as Tatami Galaxy has the exact same structure every episode.
Speaker 0: But quite some more like Utena, right, where it's like, OK, things happen.
Speaker 0: There's a lead in plot, sort of like a Simpsons episode.
Speaker 1: Then there's a duel with some special music.
Speaker 1: that like is the climax of that little mini plot.
Speaker 0: There's a duel.
Speaker 0: So in the duel, basically the characters had to somehow reveal one of their secrets, you know, and involve that anus organ and COPPA going on into some of this attacking move that allows them to win the battle.
Speaker 0: It's a very allegorical battle and not a true actual battle.
Speaker 0: It's not physical shounen combat.
Speaker 1: If Ikuhara has had a artistic trend over time from Utena onward, it is to have a show that is deeply allegorical and works on multiple levels, even under very careful scrutiny.
Speaker 1: But as his creative works have progressed, he gets more and more heavily focused on the allegory to the point that the surface details barely make sense.
Speaker 0: In Utena they actually show you some sword fighting.
Speaker 0: In Sarazanmai they don't show you any fighting.
Speaker 1: It's singing and butt juices everywhere and monsters flying through the sky and the otter police or literal sexy otter dudes.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: It's not the same style as the witches in Madoka, but it is just as sort of wacky all over the place in terms of like, you know, anyway.
Speaker 0: And yet when they do this and they fight and win the battles to protect whatever the fuck from whatever it is that COPPA wants them to fight, they basically, based on what secrets they revealed, they get a plate.
Speaker 0: And if they get a golden plate, they can literally make a wish with the golden plate.
Speaker 1: I love how the nerd kid fucks that up like right away.
Speaker 1: Here's the wish.
Speaker 1: Oh, you wasted it.
Speaker 1: Good job.
Speaker 0: And if you get silver plates, you need to collect a bunch of silver plates together and then you can get a golden plate or just make a wish, I guess, with a bunch of silver plates, something like that.
Speaker 1: No, clearly the COPPA is manipulating these kids for his own ends.
Speaker 0: Clearly.
Speaker 0: It's not a good situation, but that's what's going on is the kids, all three of them, you're going to follow them.
Speaker 0: They're secret.
Speaker 0: They also transform into COPPA when the shit goes down, by the way.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: The only reason they're doing these fights, it did skip that.
Speaker 1: The COPPA turns them into COPPA and he's like, go steal the anus organ from this zombie.
Speaker 1: We'll get to the zombies because the zombies are created by the Otter police.
Speaker 0: Oh yeah, the Otter police.
Speaker 1: You got to just watch this show.
Speaker 1: It's, it's pretty crazy in a really good way.
Speaker 1: And it escalates rapidly.
Speaker 1: And I think in the end, much like Utena and Yurikuma Arashi, it's really about the little secrets that humans have and hide from each other and the pain of those being revealed and the, like a Evangelion and the Hedgehog's dilemma, the pain of getting close to someone.
Speaker 1: There is always discomfort and pain the more you share with other people, but yet sharing is the only way to grow and change.
Speaker 1: It's, there's a lot of allegories around that kind of thing.
Speaker 0: You know, the human desire, you know, and then the stealing of it by the COPPA.
Speaker 1: But also like you may have a desire, but depending on how you express that desire could be harmful to other people, harmful to yourself.
Speaker 0: Your secret desires.
Speaker 0: You know, it's like things you really love, but you can't show people that you love these things.
Speaker 1: Or things that you love, but if you embrace a hedonistic version of those things, it may end up being harmful in a way that a different kind of expression.
Speaker 1: Those are the kinds of topics this show looks like it's going to be dealing with.
Speaker 1: As opposed to say, Yurikuma Arashi, which is very specifically focused on lesbian issues in Japan and like people navigating those spaces.
Speaker 1: And Utena is about adolescence and feminism and etc.
Speaker 0: It takes the lens of COPPA folklore, applies it to three characters, high school kids, you know, to examine those topics.
Speaker 0: And that's what I've learned from two episodes, who knows what's going to happen.
Speaker 0: And it's not too many episodes, it's only what, eleven, twelve?
Speaker 1: It's not a long show.
Speaker 1: Neither is Yurikuma, Yurikuma is pretty short.
Speaker 0: It's not some twenty-six episode, thirty plus, like Utena is what, thirty-nine?
Speaker 1: Yeah, thirty-nine.
Speaker 0: This is way shorter.
Speaker 1: My advice to you, if you watch this, or any Ikuhara show, treat them all the same way we treat Utena on.
Speaker 1: Geek Nights Presents Utena.
Speaker 1: Meaning, if you watch Saruzanmai, pay attention to the show really closely and look at all the little details and see what you can piece together.
Speaker 1: Like, look for stuff, don't trust what the characters are telling you, don't trust what the show is showing you.
Speaker 1: Just like in Utena, don't just say, "Oh, sword fighting castle in the sky?
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's some anime, that stuff just happens in
Speaker 1: anime.".
Speaker 1: No, there's a literal castle in the sky and literal sword.
Speaker 1: So in the show, there are literal butt juices, literal kappa, literal shirokodama, the butt anus organ.
Speaker 1: Think about those things in a very literal and direct way and then try to figure out the allegories from there.
Speaker 1: And the show will be very enriching to you.
Speaker 1: I like it a lot and I'm going to watch the rest of it and we'll probably do a final...
Speaker 0: I'll watch it eventually.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think we should watch it while the iron's hot because we could do a final thoughts episode on this.
Speaker 0: I just want to go home.
Speaker 1: I'm not saying watch it right now.
Speaker 1: I got to go for a run and eat some food, so I think we're done.
Speaker 1: That image that I just put up on the screen, that is the show.
Speaker 1: This has been Geek Nights with Rim and Scott.
Speaker 1: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design, and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at FrontRowCrew.com for show notes, discussion news, and more.
Speaker 1: Remember, Geek Nights is not one, but four different shows.
Speaker 1: Sci-Tech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays, and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 0: Geek Nights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 0: Geek Nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 0: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.
Speaker 1: And the Patreon patrons for this episode of Geek Nights are... And now I leave you with... We've got to follow.
Speaker 1: We've got to follow.
Speaker 1: Don't find it easy to do.
Speaker 1: Don't find it easy, but we've got to follow along.
Speaker 1: We've always got so much to say.
Speaker 1: We've got to re-love, relax, re-love, relax.
Speaker 0: Everything just gets in the way.
Speaker 0: We've got to re-love, relax, re-love, relax.
Speaker 1: Whoa!
Speaker 1: Re-love, relax, re-love, relax.
Speaker 1: We've got to follow our love.