Speaker 0:
Speaker 1: It's Tuesday April 23rd 2019.
Speaker 1: I'm rim I'm Scott and this is geek nights tonight.
Speaker 1: We've got two tabletop sports for you with catch the moon and volt Faustin.
Speaker 0: Let's do this Alright, so the Roosevelt Island to a two weeks ago.
Speaker 1: Yeah had the shit show.
Speaker 1: they had their annual You know cherry blossom festival And I guess someone wrote an article about it or like advertised.
Speaker 0: if you don't know about Roosevelt Island is not from New York.
Speaker 0: Just go to Google Maps.
Speaker 0: type in Roosevelt Island and see where it is.
Speaker 0: It's weird island in the middle of the East River that it was previously known as welfare island.
Speaker 0: Yeah, people live on it.
Speaker 0: There's it used to be a smallpox hospital there.
Speaker 0: There used to be a tram that went up and down from the bridge now.
Speaker 0: There's a sky car.
Speaker 0: Anyway, they have cherry blossoms there and people go to see them.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: I do I go every year.
Speaker 0: Yeah So there's big festival and it was a shit show.
Speaker 0: So we're like, well, let's avoid that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so the secret of New York is if any Publication of any kind talks about any free event anywhere in the five boroughs is the first year.
Speaker 0: It was a shit show.
Speaker 1: Yeah, because it's never so Years someone talked about it.
Speaker 1: So instead of like a thousand people going tens of thousands of people tried to go.
Speaker 0: Anyway, it's not an easy place to get to even during non festival times.
Speaker 0: We tried to go there.
Speaker 0: we take the bus down and we think all right.
Speaker 0: I normally just bike there.
Speaker 1: I would never.
Speaker 1: I would never go to Roosevelt Island except except on foot or on bicycle.
Speaker 0: Hey, we took the bus down there.
Speaker 0: We're like, alright, let's take on the F train.
Speaker 0: Oh, no, it's a weekend the F trains not going that way.
Speaker 0: We'd have to go backwards and then forwards like alright Let's just walk there.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there's one subway station on Roosevelt.
Speaker 0: There is a bus and it learned while we were walking over the bridge.
Speaker 1: Oh the Roosevelt Island bus.
Speaker 0: No, there actually is a New York bus.
Speaker 0: The Roosevelt Island bus only goes on the island.
Speaker 1: No, that is not true.
Speaker 0: Anyway, I've never seen the red bus go off the island.
Speaker 1: It was like a q1 talking like, you know a lot about Roosevelt Island, but I'm getting the impression You don't know that much about saying I've never seen the red bus.
Speaker 0: leave the island.
Speaker 1: Dude, the red bus is on Crescent Street all the time.
Speaker 0: I never seen it.
Speaker 0: Anyway, I saw the q1 o2 going over the bridge onto the island.
Speaker 0: I'm like, oh we could have used that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I didn't even know where to get on the queue 102 any.
Speaker 1: Oh, wow only 12,000 people live on Roosevelt Island.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's not a lot of people.
Speaker 1: Roosevelt Island.
Speaker 1: Therefore is one of the bigger cities in America.
Speaker 0: Anyway on they building that new school thing there, right?
Speaker 0: So yeah It's kind of creepy because it's like a Cornell Tech School and it's real big.
Speaker 0: It's like a whole university like like a whole college, right?
Speaker 0: And I look at all these buildings that look most of them look done.
Speaker 0: ish One of them is not but the other ones are and I look it in the window and there's like desks in there Yeah, and computers like good to go and I saw no people because it ain't live yet.
Speaker 0: But it's like it's real weird dude if it to see that all that stuff like.
Speaker 0: So we're ready to be used.
Speaker 0: not a student not a nothing.
Speaker 1: You may recall that one of my primary hobbies before I moved to New York City was urban exploration.
Speaker 1: That is 100% the kind of place I would break into for funsies, but in New York City I don't want to get shot as a terrorist or anything.
Speaker 1: So I don't break into buildings anymore.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so The apparently is two different kinds of cherry blossoms and the kind that was open during the festival You know would have still been around but there was some kind of storm action that blew them all off.
Speaker 1: What we went over there the next day and they were all.
Speaker 0: that was the next day.
Speaker 0: This is a week later.
Speaker 0: It was a storm.
Speaker 1: Oh you went this weekend.
Speaker 1: Yes Because this weekend the other cherries were blue, right?
Speaker 0: So the other chair the newer ones they had some action, but actually they weren't a hundred percent ready.
Speaker 0: So I bet if you go like the middle of this week or next weekend, the other kind will be even crazier.
Speaker 0: Anyway, yeah.
Speaker 0: So while we're there we realized oh There was actually a much easier non bike way to get here that we forgot about the ferry and used to go home.
Speaker 1: So for the first time heavily subsidized actually really awesome East River Ferry.
Speaker 0: for the first time I took the ferry and I'm sure it is heavily subsidized.
Speaker 0: who knows what it cost?
Speaker 0: But actually I was very surprised.
Speaker 0: a lot of people are using it.
Speaker 0: Dude, the ferry is really really important now in New York Like if it disappeared there'd be trouble because it's Pete I guess the people online are complaining about the ferry like yeah I want to see ridership data, you know, it's costing a lot of money.
Speaker 1: Dude, I see people on the ferry late at night.
Speaker 0: There's a lot of people on that ferry.
Speaker 0: It was exactly on time.
Speaker 0: It took me directly where I wanted to go.
Speaker 1: The only complaint I have is that it tends to only run every hour.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think it needs to run.
Speaker 1: I think it should run every 10 minutes.
Speaker 1: I don't care how much that costs.
Speaker 0: It was not frequent but It was pretty great.
Speaker 0: So if you cut in New York and you know, you have to go somewhere Consider the ferry.
Speaker 1: I would even say go one step further if you're Touristing in New York.
Speaker 1: The ferry is a great way to see Autana, New York.
Speaker 0: It goes to touristy places, too.
Speaker 1: Yeah You can take the ferry down Like to lower Manhattan and then you can take a different ferry to Staten Island.
Speaker 1: don't get off in Staten Island.
Speaker 1: But if you ride the ferry to Staten Island and you want it it's only like 275 to ride it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, compare that.
Speaker 0: It's like well, I don't know.
Speaker 0: the tourist boat costs like The Circle Line is actually good.
Speaker 0: It's it's a good tourist thing to do.
Speaker 1: But I think sometimes the Staten Island ferry is just free.
Speaker 0: The Staten Island ferry is always free.
Speaker 1: It is free I don't know.
Speaker 0: I wrote the Staten Island ferry once in my life.
Speaker 0: There are scammers who hide out near the Staten Island ferry and pretend to sell tickets.
Speaker 0: They sell like $40 tickets to tourists and then the tourists ride it and they're like, they don't realize That it's just free.
Speaker 0: It's just free all the time always.
Speaker 1: But the secret is if you get on this ferry, it just goes around the Statue of Liberty like right next to it.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: So in the news, what do you got?
Speaker 0: so there's this game coming out what's it called scroll subverse, right?
Speaker 0: So Apparently there's a company called FOW interactive that I never heard of before today and they make porn games of some kind.
Speaker 1: It's like oh, oh not subverse like submarine but subverse like sub First.
Speaker 0: yes, okay All right, so I'd never heard of them, but there are 10,000 comments on this Kickstarter, right?
Speaker 0: But apparently they're kind of popular and people like their porn games, you know They're the.
Speaker 0: I don't know if they're the good porn game.
Speaker 0: I get the feeling they're not the good point.
Speaker 1: two million dollars They're pledged.
Speaker 0: What good what?
Speaker 0: so they have decided.
Speaker 0: I guess they successfully have made games in the past.
Speaker 0: So they're making a game that is basically shitty Mass Effect But porn where you have sex with wife.
Speaker 0: Oh, wow.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's why we made subverse a tactical RPG shmup hybrid With fucking.
Speaker 0: that's right.
Speaker 0: It's it's literally just Mass Effect only probably not as good a piece of software because I mean whether you like the game Mass Effect or not It's a triple-a Quality software that cost a lot of money.
Speaker 1: While at one point it's like your ship is crewed by the sexiest and deadly deadliest waifu's But I don't think it's just waifu's because it looks like there's also a character who is a perpetually stoned imp with six testicles.
Speaker 0: The point is this game on Kickstarter has already got a million plus dollars, you know, which is Shocking.
Speaker 1: there's an old adage In every part of the internet where art is made is that if you are if you really want to make money Just make it the porn version of the thing you wanted to make and you will never need to work again.
Speaker 0: You don't even have to do a great job because the porn covers for your lower quality ness.
Speaker 0: I mean, let's just make porn settlers of good time.
Speaker 0: It'll be a really shitty board game of porn Like porno miniatures that is naked and Scott Sellers is already pornographic.
Speaker 1: Kinda if you got any wood cuz I got a bunch of sheep.
Speaker 0: Yeah, let's just make the literal.
Speaker 0: just go all out like that.
Speaker 0: His is my sheep and these are wood.
Speaker 0: They just fit into each other.
Speaker 1: It is like you would be if you're not aware of like this side of the world like there are people I know Who make a living in New York like a living living?
Speaker 1: Just drawing furry fetish porn.
Speaker 1: That's it.
Speaker 1: That's all they do.
Speaker 1: there are patreon that you can only find if you know the thing like know where to look because they can't search patreon and They make like $40,000 a month and it's just like bad porn updated monthly.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm There's people who just sit at home with a webcam not having any sort of middleman or company.
Speaker 0: Just you know being naked in front of a webcam and people just keep giving them money all day long.
Speaker 0: So as long as they stay there look at it.
Speaker 1: shots from this game.
Speaker 1: It actually looks really bad.
Speaker 1: I dang It looks like an awful game Like these are Naga breasts but not even in the.
Speaker 1: haha funny but in the.
Speaker 1: oh really this is this is what titillates you.
Speaker 0: Yeah, okay Just I couldn't not do it as news because look how much money people are paying for this game We love to entertain.
Speaker 1: so we decided to pack subverse to the brim with waifus of multiple alien species and organic Classifications all of which were created by world-renowned art director and squid girl titty enthusiast Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: Huh?
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: Let's see.
Speaker 1: So we have a sex spot a renegade doctor.
Speaker 0: Yeah, who's next?
Speaker 0: but yeah.
Speaker 1: But I don't think I am worried that you cannot actually date the perpetually stoned amp with six testicles.
Speaker 1: I'm worried.
Speaker 1: you can only date the big-breasted waifus.
Speaker 1: I'm pretty sure that's correct and people are gonna pay one point two million dollars or pledge Rim if you could date.
Speaker 0: see just tell the post a comment one of the comments and say look if you let me date the Six-testicle guy I will play this game.
Speaker 1: I mean cuz that's basically we're gonna say if I could have dated Ventus will I would have played the to the end of rune factory for?
Speaker 1: Anyway, oh there's oh so there is.
Speaker 1: oh no, I think they've unlocked every goal at this point.
Speaker 0: Good lord for a million dollars.
Speaker 0: I sure hope they did.
Speaker 1: We unlocked the cat girl.
Speaker 0: We unlocked we huh?
Speaker 0: We we I miss we oh You and you and the rest of the people who put in the 200,000 pound because I guess it's a UK thing Unlockable was.
Speaker 1: this worries me want to see your waifus.
Speaker 1: Have a good time with your alien companions.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so there's.
Speaker 1: so there's something going on with quadrupeds rim likes to watch.
Speaker 1: I Quoting.
Speaker 1: when I say that I like to watch you know, do you know what I'm actually quoting?
Speaker 0: I do I think I do.
Speaker 1: do you think you do?
Speaker 1: We'll convene on this later.
Speaker 1: So in some other news, this is breaking today.
Speaker 1: But if you weren't aware in the games industry, there's been a really annoying problem for a while because China As you know is a country that does not have free speech and is very like most countries on earth.
Speaker 0: Yeah, free speech is super rare.
Speaker 0: It's like United States.
Speaker 0: end of list.
Speaker 1: Yep, pretty much and even then free speech in the US has a lot of problems.
Speaker 0: I mean other countries sort of have free speech.
Speaker 1: Yeah, not really Germany's a lot better in a lot of ways.
Speaker 0: They still don't have free speech.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but I'd be okay with American free speech except for fascists.
Speaker 0: Sure, but I'm just.
Speaker 0: I'm not saying Yeah, I'm just saying a tech, you know, Mary United States is one of the only countries to have actual free speech on paper For good or ill Guaranteed.
Speaker 1: but China if you want to sell a video game in China You have to submit it to the government.
Speaker 0: if you want to be gonna release any artwork or anything in China You're gonna do anything in China.
Speaker 1: So a while ago the Chinese government stopped approving any new video games.
Speaker 1: Yep, and they started didn't approve any for nine months due to some Like some complicated reason where the government was like restructuring and I didn't really understand it.
Speaker 1: All I know is that it was actually really causing a problem in the game industry Because a lot of publishers were planning on selling games They were developing in China and they put in their applications and they were just ignored.
Speaker 1: Hmm.
Speaker 1: So the freeze has ended The reorganization is done and they've implemented a bunch of new rules and as of today We now know the rules and restrictions and to quote Kotaku.
Speaker 1: It's not to looking so good for Mortal Kombat 11.
Speaker 1: So China has now banned several genres of games.
Speaker 1: So games that involve gambling can no longer be made.
Speaker 0: That's good.
Speaker 0: Belgium got rid of a whole lot of gambling in games, you know, but not no No, but this means you could not.
Speaker 1: this is like this implies that you could not have a game.
Speaker 1: You could not have an RPG where you play poker to fight people.
Speaker 0: Sounds good.
Speaker 1: Yeah, okay You cannot have mahjong or poker or gambling as a focus of the game.
Speaker 1: You cannot in any way represent China's Imperial history so you can't even play destiny warriors.
Speaker 1: I guess not any any part of China's history.
Speaker 1: at least at least it says Imperial history here.
Speaker 1: But there's a note because it's not Exactly clear what they mean by this and all the clarifications are in Chinese.
Speaker 1: like this is breaking news So it hasn't been fully translated for me yet, but it seems that games that deal with much of China's history Regardless of context are banned.
Speaker 1: Okay, corpses cannot be shown nor can blood and Recoloring blood is specifically prohibited.
Speaker 1: You cannot pull the Mortal Kombat of green blood or that sweat coming off of that guy.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so the these rules are actually pretty restrictive because just before the show I tried to go through a list of games I could think of that have come out recently or would be coming out and Most of them run afoul of at least one of these rules.
Speaker 1: no Mario Yeah, overwatch couldn't.
Speaker 1: well Mario does the goomba who is squash count as a corpse?
Speaker 1: No, I mean you killed him.
Speaker 1: He's dead.
Speaker 0: uh-huh Tetris touch.
Speaker 1: Yeah, Tetris does not have corpses.
Speaker 1: Tetris is good.
Speaker 0: There's plenty of games that are just fine.
Speaker 1: But the real interesting thing now is that the rules like based on what I'm reading here The rules have gotten to the point with this recent release that a lot of studios in the u.s.
Speaker 1: Now Aren't sure if they could possibly Make like take games that are already in the pipeline and get them to the point where they would get Chinese regulatory approval.
Speaker 0: There was that recent news that the switch was approved for sale in China.
Speaker 0: Maybe it's because the switch has Nintendo.
Speaker 0: Like I said makes a lot of games that are perfectly.
Speaker 0: Okay Yeah They're not making games.
Speaker 0: or you chop people up and shoot people up with guns or make lots of blood or anything like that.
Speaker 1: I like to shoot and/or slice.
Speaker 0: Well, you're gonna have to shoot slice slice.
Speaker 0: You're gonna have to shoot slice slice on the western hemisphere.
Speaker 1: In a Chinese historical drama while playing Mahjong.
Speaker 0: I'll do it in Europe.
Speaker 0: That's my game.
Speaker 0: Or in the United States cuz you're not doing it in Beijing.
Speaker 1: So I'm sure we'll see some follow-up on this once the fullness of these rules is translated.
Speaker 1: coupled with the first major studios Possibly changing their sales forecast based on whether or not some games they have in their pipeline Can actually be sold in the Chinese market.
Speaker 1: But the good news is it is technically possible now for games to be approved which was not the case for the last nine months Hmm.
Speaker 0: All I gotta say is you know people in the US who cry about free speech, you know Because some company deletes their tweets or whatever, right?
Speaker 0: This is actually.
Speaker 0: this is what actual censorship looks like.
Speaker 0: Yeah Our sentence doesn't look like that.
Speaker 0: I don't want to hear free speech out of your mouth.
Speaker 0: Okay, that if that happens that's when you go on First Amendment.
Speaker 0: right.
Speaker 0: if that's not happening then guess what.
Speaker 1: it's not a First Amendment But anyway things of the day, so I found a cute little documentary here.
Speaker 1: It's a little old but it's got all the info you need.
Speaker 1: You may remember that when I was a kid I had my brother at a Gameboy and I Due to constantly hurrying at my parents was able to get myself a Game Gear.
Speaker 1: That the Game Gear was my main portable console for my entire childhood.
Speaker 1: the battery lasted maybe a half hour.
Speaker 0: So I usually mean the what six double A's.
Speaker 0: well So are the two packed paddle things you shoved in that had connectors that looked like six double A's.
Speaker 1: I had a paddle thing that plugged into the AC port that would last about an hour.
Speaker 1: But so as a side a side point.
Speaker 1: Actually, the reason the batteries died was because there's one battery that powers the backlight and the other batteries power the rest of the console Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: So if you just keep rotating the batteries you can last a lot longer I know.
Speaker 1: or if you hacked it to put multiple batteries in that one spot, which I saw some people doing Or just plug it in while you play it may defeating the purpose of portability.
Speaker 1: No, because my primary use cases were in order in bed in order I am in the car and I'm a kid.
Speaker 1: a 10-minute car ride is an infinite amount of time and I need to entertain myself.
Speaker 1: And we had the cigarette lighter adapters.
Speaker 1: That was fine.
Speaker 0: Is that strong enough to keep it on all the time?
Speaker 1: Yeah Also at grandma's house and I don't want to play the Intellivision or the Atari plug.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like you say a nomad Or I am sitting somewhere without power usually for not that long like in line at Cedar Point and I played it until the batteries Died and then I was just really sad and bored.
Speaker 0: you carried it around cedar point like on roller coasters.
Speaker 1: Yeah, okay I had a little a little tiny backpack that had the game gear the game boy a little battery-powered fan and some water.
Speaker 1: Okay, and some vanilla extract.
Speaker 0: Yeah, why are you carrying that around the amusement park?
Speaker 0: for no reason.
Speaker 1: who are you Inspector Clouseau, what's your thing of the day?
Speaker 0: I think you just say you just mentioned in the middle extract, which is right either Accidentally in there and you're trying to be silly or you're just lying and you just try to be funny.
Speaker 1: So I carried vanilla extract with me because I would get dr Pepper to drink and I would always put a little bit of vanilla in it to make vanilla.
Speaker 1: Dr.
Speaker 0: Pepper Uh-huh.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 1: I did that throughout my entire childhood thing.
Speaker 0: I did Spent a big money on the vanilla.
Speaker 1: Yeah How much?
Speaker 1: how much vanilla do you think I was pouring into my dr.
Speaker 0: Pepper?
Speaker 0: Did you carry a little like half teaspoon with you to measure the?
Speaker 1: no, I actually would measure it in the cap.
Speaker 0: Okay, a cat was a lot 20 ounce dr.
Speaker 1: Pepper smart amount anyway.
Speaker 0: So way back in the PC days like 1997 or 98 If you wanted to play some video games on your computer that you know had some advanced graphics with Windows 95 or 98 You know get some GPU action.
Speaker 0: You didn't have a lot of options.
Speaker 0: It wasn't like there was g-forces in those days, right?
Speaker 0: Pretty much.
Speaker 0: you just had to have a killer CPU like a Pentium something and it would just do all the rendering in software Which is what most people did.
Speaker 1: and I had a 200 megahertz Pentium.
Speaker 1: But if you're in video I could play these goddamn games before I had a video card.
Speaker 0: if you read video game magazines They were like, oh man, you got to buy these graphics cards and some of them weren't even video cards.
Speaker 0: I think you just put them in like a PCI or a VGA slot VGA ISA slot ISA.
Speaker 0: My first network card was ISA as was my first sound card And then they would just sort of do some work and like help out the CPU doing some GPU biz.
Speaker 0: Right, but you know, it wasn't real until we had real 3d game, which is quake the real 3d game.
Speaker 0: Yeah And there was a version of quake that was like called V quake or something that needed like this special card from a company You've never heard of and no one bought that fucking thing.
Speaker 0: But then there was GL quake.
Speaker 0: GL quake was revolutionary because it alright buy any video card you want as long as it uses Open GL.
Speaker 0: So now that started to be in competition where people could make cards that people could afford that supported enough of the OpenGL API So that it would actually make quake run a lot faster.
Speaker 1: The problem was a card that's that pretty fully supported OpenGL not affordable.
Speaker 0: now They had like a min GL which is like a small subset of the OpenGL API that quake would actually, you know, use any disclosure.
Speaker 1: I used to know a lot more about this because in this era it mattered to me a lot.
Speaker 1: the point is nowadays I just don't remember any of the cards.
Speaker 0: at the time was the 3d fx voodoo cup.
Speaker 1: in my Personal opinion when I was a kid.
Speaker 1: I always thought those voodoo cards were garbage pieces of shit because they had bad color.
Speaker 0: There's all these problems.
Speaker 0: by the time that I was buying video cards.
Speaker 1: I bought a TNT - I didn't Got a creative graphics blaster extreme anyway 400 bucks for that thing.
Speaker 0: I paid like 300 pre-ordered the TNT - for like three or four hundred anyway.
Speaker 0: the point is Someone here wrote up.
Speaker 0: What's the person's name?
Speaker 0: Oh, this is real reason.
Speaker 0: This is written like a week ago.
Speaker 1: Fabian sang a lard.
Speaker 0: Fabian sang lard wrote this like a week ago.
Speaker 0: There's amazing published a week ago.
Speaker 0: It's amazing write-up of like every detail of the voodoo card and what the deal with them was.
Speaker 1: it's kind of amazing.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna read this whole thing right for anyone who wasn't there then or was there then and wants to go down memory lane Or fill in the holes in your knowledge of what the deal was then Fabian's got you covered.
Speaker 0: It's also amazing to see quotes from Tom's Hardware in 1997.
Speaker 1: that site is still going as far as I know Dude, I just found on a Nantec a review of the creative graphics blaster extreme.
Speaker 0: From what year?
Speaker 0: 1997. and Nantec is that old and they kept their content up.
Speaker 0: good job in it.
Speaker 1: Oh, they used a Pentium 3 MMX they're eight years older than geek nights with an.
Speaker 1: a open motherboard Was 64 megabytes of RAM which back then was a shit ton of RAM.
Speaker 0: Wow, but yeah, if you're wondering, you know, you think the state of video cards and GPUs nowadays is bad.
Speaker 1: Yeah, dude in the old days.
Speaker 1: You'd buy a video card with like a voodoo card.
Speaker 1: You'd need like the glide wrapper to make a game.
Speaker 1: That was just OpenGL even work.
Speaker 1: So like you had to know a lot about the games you were buying and the individual video cards And you had to do a bunch of fuckery to make them work.
Speaker 1: You couldn't just buy quake and if you had a better video card, it just looked better.
Speaker 0: I just remember every game I would install and it would give me three choices glide which I knew was only for voodoo cards which I didn't have and then OpenGL and DirectX and I knew that I had both.
Speaker 0: well DirectX slash direct 3d and I knew I had both of those because I Windows 98 SE and I had a TNT - I could choose either one of those and I choose whichever one seemed better.
Speaker 0: They I couldn't didn't really notice a difference.
Speaker 0: They're both fine because my computer was so OP at the time.
Speaker 0: Yeah my computer was 99 my computer was not Opie at the time because I was gonna brought the computer to RIT and it became not OP.
Speaker 1: I was still using that 200 megahertz to the as Late as right before I went to RIT And then I bought.
Speaker 1: I sold all my bonds and I used all that money to buy one Computer that I used while I was in college.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so we're gonna review all in the meta moment.
Speaker 1: The geek nice book club book is a painful book.
Speaker 1: It is pages of pain.
Speaker 0: I have read some painful pages.
Speaker 1: I also started reading some painful pages few chapters of pain.
Speaker 0: I am feeling the pain.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the prose is Better than a typical branded.
Speaker 1: our book based on a franchise.
Speaker 0: I will say this they gave the main character two names.
Speaker 0: They named him at the threson Yep, and I assume it's a him and also named him the amnesiac hero.
Speaker 0: and basically every paragraph is Alternating between those two names.
Speaker 0: and it's since it's like this narrator.
Speaker 0: It's the amnesiac hero did xxx the blah blah blah blah blah blah.
Speaker 0: the threson did X blah blah blah.
Speaker 0: the Hero did X blah blah blah.
Speaker 0: the threson did it.
Speaker 0: and just alternating between the two names and every sentence structure is the so-and-so.
Speaker 1: He's gonna get a third name if I recall correctly I'm sure.
Speaker 1: what's the tiefling if you met her yet?
Speaker 1: Yes, she calls him zombie.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right.
Speaker 0: Zoom me I just read that literally.
Speaker 0: just read that zoom on the train just now.
Speaker 0: That was the ding.
Speaker 1: I just read So yeah, we're gonna talk about that book anyway.
Speaker 1: Otherwise bunch of our panels are on YouTube.
Speaker 1: the real harm of games rare game mechanics and The most recent judging of anime all three can be yours.
Speaker 0: I just judged.
Speaker 0: I finished that judge.
Speaker 0: It was all good.
Speaker 1: Yeah, good stuff.
Speaker 0: So it's not a good anime coming this season, by the way.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we got no cons until anime Boston just happened.
Speaker 0: It seemed like it was good, but we weren't there.
Speaker 1: Yeah, maybe I'll go back next year.
Speaker 0: We'll see the security though.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's the problem.
Speaker 1: other than that I think I'm more inclined to just go back to Connecticut because Connecticut is does not have the security problem.
Speaker 0: Maybe they'll have it though.
Speaker 1: I doubt it.
Speaker 0: Anyway, I highly doubt it.
Speaker 0: So we were at PAX East and at PAX East We play a lot of games.
Speaker 0: Yep, and We could talk about a lot of those games.
Speaker 0: But today we're just gonna talk about two that we played back to back.
Speaker 0: Basically, we're sitting there on Sunday We got some time before the Omega thon and I you know in my wanderings of tabletop working in there I had noticed a few games.
Speaker 0: So I went over to the library.
Speaker 0: I grabbed one.
Speaker 0: we played it.
Speaker 0: I went returned it grabbed the other one and we played it because they were quick and they looked like a lot of fun.
Speaker 0: They looked easy to learn and they were dexterity grabby games.
Speaker 0: and we had the circle table Which was great for dexterity grabby games and they were both pretty good.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so the first one It's called catch the moon and basically from 2017.
Speaker 1: It's a recent game.
Speaker 0: Both of these are recent games.
Speaker 0: The other one was 2018.
Speaker 1: It was a nominee for the cardboard republic socializer Laurel.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so if you know our opinion on stacking games like Jenga or via Paletti or the Rhino hero Or any stacking balance games most of the ones that we've played right sort of have the same similar Mechanical problems not in terms of the fun of the stacking or the skill of the stacking that
Speaker 1: parts off that bright
Speaker 0: solid.
Speaker 0: It's really easy to do that.
Speaker 1: It's not via Paletti with the hook.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I love that hook.
Speaker 0: It's super fun and solid.
Speaker 0: the problem is the the victory conditions and the actual rules For winning and losing.
Speaker 0: a lot of these games are very flawed.
Speaker 0: Yeah, a lot of them are.
Speaker 0: you make it fall down you lose everyone else wins, but that's unsatisfied.
Speaker 0: It's very unsatisfying.
Speaker 0: There's a lot of turn order determines who wins.
Speaker 0: it's like a lady right a Jenga tower will become Destabilized on about the X turns.
Speaker 0: you have this many players.
Speaker 0: you want to have turn X To be so.
Speaker 0: that way it'll be the most stable on your turn.
Speaker 1: games like via Paletti that run out It's really just satisfying.
Speaker 0: if turn order is what determines It's like aha it became unstable on the turn before yours.
Speaker 1: So you lose regardless of your actual pulling skills and turn order wouldn't matter that much except Stacking games.
Speaker 1: if people get good at stacking then a turn order is the only thing left to determine who wins.
Speaker 0: and it's also Dissatisfying because most of them involve, you know balancing and shakiness and then a thing collapsing.
Speaker 0: and when the thing collapses It's like well GG.
Speaker 0: This isn't.
Speaker 0: we can't continue.
Speaker 0: We don't have anything left.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so this game we played catch the moon I'm not gonna say it perfectly solves all those problems But it does go a long way towards solving them and it tries to solve them and for that I give it a lot of Credit plus.
Speaker 0: it's still really fun to fiddle with this game because what this game is?
Speaker 0: it is a game of balancing little wooden ladders And they're all shaped slightly differently.
Speaker 0: It's a bunch of little wooden ladders.
Speaker 0: you start the game with two straight ones in this plastic cloud.
Speaker 0: that sort of keeps them erect And there's a lot of different starting positions for the two starting ladders.
Speaker 0: and then you roll some dice or something like.
Speaker 0: that.
Speaker 0: is dice, right?
Speaker 0: Yes, and they tell you how you have to place your ladder.
Speaker 0: It's like your ladder has to be exactly touching one other ladder.
Speaker 0: two other ladders, you know It's like there's a rule about how you have to place your ladder But as long as you follow that rule The other the important thing is one your ladder has to have some part of it higher in Elevation than all the existing ladders.
Speaker 1: in the thing You nominate one of your hands as your grabby hand and you can't ever touch anything with anything But that hand.
Speaker 0: yeah, you gotta use one hand only.
Speaker 1: but here's a difference.
Speaker 0: random ladder You can't choose one.
Speaker 1: most stacking games have rules Like you can't fuck with the structure like you can't fuck with parts of the Jenga.
Speaker 1: You're not actively moving.
Speaker 1: Yep in this game You can do whatever the hell you want to the structure as long as you only use one hand and you only touch it with The ladder you're about to play.
Speaker 0: you can't put your hands on the existing ladders.
Speaker 0: only your ladder you're placing.
Speaker 1: as long as you do not break it or Touch the cloud or the table with the ladder in your hand Drop the ladder in your hand or break the rule of placement like touching too many at the same time.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you can eat the dice.
Speaker 1: Yeah As long as you obey the dice you can fuck with it as much as you want to get it on there and you might think Well, wouldn't we just make a really ugly weird structure?
Speaker 1: Hell, yeah Yeah, that's right.
Speaker 0: And there's a lot of crazy shit.
Speaker 0: You can do.
Speaker 0: the instruction book is actually really good.
Speaker 0: It shows you a lot of different possible ways of placing your ladder and even names them and different techniques with funny names.
Speaker 1: Right the shameful something we use.
Speaker 0: we use the shameful whatever the shameful whatever it is.
Speaker 0: many many times You just lay a ladder flat on top of another ladder.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: We did that frequently.
Speaker 1: Oh my god We had no shame.
Speaker 1: We had a game where there were four like shameful stacks in a row and then like another structure and then another Three higher up on the shameful support the shameful support.
Speaker 0: So he did that a lot anyway.
Speaker 0: But yeah, this game is a ton of fun.
Speaker 0: the one thing that makes it really good is that let's say you fuck up on your turn.
Speaker 0: you go and you try to Put your ladder and you end up knocking over a shit ton of ladders.
Speaker 1: Well the way it works that you can't.
Speaker 1: there's no way to make the entire thing just collapse.
Speaker 0: Let's say I go to place my ladder and a whole bunch of ladders fall off.
Speaker 0: I just I just mess up real bad.
Speaker 0: All right, I scoop up all those ladders and just put them in front of me.
Speaker 0: they're now negative points.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't lose.
Speaker 0: the game doesn't continue term order doesn't determine the victory or anything like that.
Speaker 0: We just keep going and it's like you can still keep having fun.
Speaker 1: The game doesn't end disappointingly, but you also get Hobbs are disappointed in you.
Speaker 0: There is a clear winner at the end and it's more likely that the winner is going to be the person with the best ladder placing skill as opposed to the person with The most luck or seat position or anything like that because I think that makes it a much more satisfying dexterity.
Speaker 1: I'm pretty sure.
Speaker 1: if I recall correctly the rule is When the game ends meaning all the ladders have either been placed or been fucked up in some way Then whoever has the least tears yep wins the game because they fucked up the least yep.
Speaker 1: If multiple people are tied then with tears then whoever has the least ladders wins the game.
Speaker 0: So this game is like and the game also ends when you run out of ladders, I think right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, so it's like you place all the ladders you're gonna have the same number of turns.
Speaker 0: You can also have a ton of players going in this game.
Speaker 0: Why does it go to like eight players on the ridiculous?
Speaker 1: I forget we played with varying numbers of players and it always worked.
Speaker 0: I think six players.
Speaker 0: Yep It goes to six which is best.
Speaker 1: three to four, which I could see right?
Speaker 0: Yeah It's definitely best of three to four.
Speaker 0: but yeah, cuz you're gonna get you know If you play with too many players, it'll still be just fine as a game But there'll be a lot of waiting and as a fewer turns per person which will make it less fun.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but otherwise the game will still be solid even with six players.
Speaker 1: So I feel like this.
Speaker 1: I feel like I want to buy it because it is the best second game for us I've found.
Speaker 0: yet I do like it.
Speaker 0: But I feel like you want to just want to take these advances in stacking game rules And apply them to a even better stacking game.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the trouble is a lot of the stacking games I like the most are such that if someone fucks up the entire thing is likely to collapse.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but you know what if it's via plenty and it's like, okay If you knock something over you take all those cylinder as a place to get a teardrop or something?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: Yeah, just take these innovations and apply them to the to the genre to push it forward From where it is now.
Speaker 1: Yeah props to Fabian Rifard and Juan Rodriguez for advancing the genre of Stacking dexterity tabletop games.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: Like I don't know if you realized you were solving these fundamental problems of the genre.
Speaker 1: You solved like the Primary things we've complained about for more than a decade in the stacking genre.
Speaker 0: It also goes to show you you know Someone like me sits there and looks at like a flaw in a game and like is like I'll make a game that fixes this And I'll think about ideas and I got won't unless I got the perfect solution.
Speaker 0: It's like nope, not good enough where it's like.
Speaker 0: they're just like yeah good enough solution.
Speaker 0: They put it out there and they publish it and they actually make something.
Speaker 0: Yep It's good.
Speaker 0: and if someone talks about it on a podcast Or something to me sits there and still thinking of like it's not perfect.
Speaker 1: So this other game we played Volfasten well, I don't.
Speaker 0: yeah, sorry about the German pronunciation.
Speaker 0: It's vol vo ll pfo sten.
Speaker 0: It's all one word.
Speaker 0: What does it mean in German?
Speaker 0: It means idiot poll.
Speaker 0: Someone said some someone said it means idiot poll.
Speaker 0: They tweeted at us.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so I saw them playing this at PAX.
Speaker 0: They have these turn in tabletop.
Speaker 0: They have these tournaments at night use like like Saturday night showdown stuff like that where you sign up for this tournament And you show
Speaker 1: up not
Speaker 0: knowing what games are about to be played and you just sometimes you're even playing different games other people in the same round of the tournament and you know you play and you play and you try to just it's just who's good at Games, who knows what these games are gonna be?
Speaker 0: only the people who run tabletop know those games are gonna have Time and I saw in a later a very late round possibly a final round of one of these tournaments.
Speaker 0: People are playing this game and I remember what the box looked like.
Speaker 0: So I went and got it from the library and this game is vol Fausten idiot poll or something Whatever, it's basically advanced jungle speed.
Speaker 0: It's advanced.
Speaker 0: It's sort of advanced sort of not advanced.
Speaker 0: Yeah So the way it works is there are five poles or six poles three four or five six.
Speaker 0: There are six sticks and each stick has a lot of different factors.
Speaker 0: They each contain on the top of the stick their square Rectangular like tall sticks like I don't you know, whatever a die face Is a die face from one to six.
Speaker 0: then on the side?
Speaker 0: There is a picture of an animal a letter to the alphabet a number of sticks a number of just sticks like like hash marks Like someone was scratching out the date because they were in prison.
Speaker 0: Yeah a shape and a polygon right a polygon of some kind.
Speaker 0: and then you get a whole bunch of dice and you choose which Dice you're gonna use when you play the game, right?
Speaker 0: so we chose.
Speaker 0: we decided to use the simple dice because of just the situation we were in.
Speaker 0: and You what?
Speaker 0: we roll the dice and the dice tell you which totem to grab What to do depending on which dice you use, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, some dice tell you which totem to grab.
Speaker 0: the white one I think yep.
Speaker 0: Some tell you how to grab it how to grab the totem and some tell you what to do before you grab the totem.
Speaker 0: Right, yeah, so you could end up a situation where it's like, okay, you got a clap then you got to grab a totem You got to grab it in between like your index in your ring.
Speaker 0: You're like your two hands the backs of your two hands.
Speaker 1: that's the worst one.
Speaker 0: and then you win if you get the totem with like the What the biggest animal on it or something?
Speaker 0: So it depends on the animal with the most legs.
Speaker 1: Yeah so the factors are like you're shooting for the highest number of One of the attributes which might be either the Sometimes the row gets reversed.
Speaker 0: You may be going for animal with the least leg.
Speaker 1: So one die says the factor.
Speaker 1: so like you're looking for your by default.
Speaker 1: The factor is the die face.
Speaker 1: You're looking for the highest die face.
Speaker 1: The factor is the polygon.
Speaker 1: You're looking for the polygon with the most sides.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if the factor is the animal you're gonna for the animal with the most legs But the orange die might modify that and say no you're looking for the opposite of that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, now I need the animal the least legs the snake.
Speaker 0: the snake has one leg, right?
Speaker 0: So obviously all the all the sticks are mixed up right zero legs.
Speaker 0: I said like the stick with the letter a on it Which should be the best stick if you had alphabet ranking reversed, right has the number two on top of it.
Speaker 0: So if you were right, so when you're any octopus with the second most legs, yep, so and the hexagon Yep.
Speaker 0: So it's like every third Situations based on the dice that come up where every stick basically has an equal chance of being the best stick for any given die.
Speaker 0: So you don't know until seeing the die which stick you want to grab.
Speaker 0: not only that But you know, you might be too slow.
Speaker 0: You might not have grabbed the best stick because you were a little slower than the person who did grab the best stick.
Speaker 0: And in that case the second best stick is now the best stick.
Speaker 0: There's actually ranking involved.
Speaker 0: It's not just like so whoever grabs it wins and everyone else loses.
Speaker 1: So everybody grabs and then you evaluate did you grab it the right way anyone who grabbed it the wrong way?
Speaker 1: They're just eliminated, right?
Speaker 0: So there are actually a lot of cases where it's like, okay maybe it was, you know clap and grab it with your wrong hand and You grab the worst possible stick But everyone else either forgot to clap or grabbed it with their normal hand.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and you're sitting there with the shittiest stick but in your you did everything else, right you win you get the most points Yeah, so you get first place second place third place, right?
Speaker 0: So the the score keeping is actually pretty clever.
Speaker 0: basically If you win around you get three points.
Speaker 0: if you come in second you get two points.
Speaker 0: if you come in last you get one.
Speaker 0: You can only score points if you actually Successfully grab something right?
Speaker 0: So there could be situations where now Three everyone else get zero way this going works.
Speaker 1: is you get a long stick a medium stick or a short stick, right?
Speaker 1: At the end of the game you make your idiot pole from all the sticks.
Speaker 0: Whoever is really just a really clever score sheet to have these little wooden sticks that are Length one two and three except the gray sticks are about a millimeter.
Speaker 0: Complaining about the manufacturing precision of the stick?
Speaker 1: No, but they were consistently so and if I was losing by a millimeter I would say that I had lost there one two and three.
Speaker 0: Stop being pedantic rules.
Speaker 0: Say you saw the laying that guy's.
Speaker 1: stop making up your own rules for games.
Speaker 0: Stop being that guy complaining about the manufacturing position.
Speaker 1: Who says I complained?
Speaker 1: I said that that is part of the designers.
Speaker 0: No, it is not one two and three - I say it is obvious.
Speaker 1: a second place in the third place is not as long as a first place.
Speaker 1: I would say the first place breaks that tie.
Speaker 0: No, it doesn't.
Speaker 0: by
Speaker 1: the written rules of this game
Speaker 0: You save a lot of time adding up your score with apps or calculators or anything like that Because you can just lay out all your store sticks in a big long line and whoever's score stick total score Stick is the longest is the winner.
Speaker 0: It's a really fun and clever scoring mechanism.
Speaker 0: Mechanically speaking that doesn't involve math And matches the theme of the game of idiot pole because you're grabbing poles and also using an idiot pole to keep score And that's really clever and fun.
Speaker 1: The game is actually very difficult.
Speaker 0: Yes, it is way hard.
Speaker 0: We're like, oh, yeah We're advanced.
Speaker 0: Let's use some advanced dice.
Speaker 1: So if you think you're good at jungle speed and you'll be good at this now.
Speaker 0: So some of them involve like standing up turning around and see.
Speaker 0: so if your environment isn't good It's not really great for this game.
Speaker 0: You want to be in a situation where you're at a table where everyone can reach the whole table without getting up Yep, right with their arms.
Speaker 0: You need a small circular table relatively speaking maybe like a cocktail situation But you want it low so everyone can sit in chairs.
Speaker 0: and plus you need room because to be able to get up and run Around the chairs depending on which dice you use you can always use the simpler dice and avoid those scenarios.
Speaker 0: Either table is suboptimal, which is what we did.
Speaker 0: Yeah But I think if you really want to get the most out of this game You need that perfect environment where everyone's sitting around Equidistant.
Speaker 0: you can all grab this the sticks because you can't arrange the sticks all right in the middle of the table.
Speaker 0: They need some space between them.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so naturally speaking some sticks are gonna be closer to some players that sometimes and sometimes not.
Speaker 0: But if your table small enough and everyone's sitting close enough that won't really matter because all the other stuff is really what's gonna determine The winning and the losing.
Speaker 1: and unlike jungle speed we're very like.
Speaker 1: very often two people grab the totem at the same time and you needed to come up with a like Specific way to resolve that situation.
Speaker 1: that isn't just violence.
Speaker 1: This game has the same problem, but it happens less often because most of the time Someone does just figure out what to grab.
Speaker 0: yes jungle speed has the problem.
Speaker 0: so often it.
Speaker 0: So it puts in a bunch of rules for like okay, whoever's lower on the totem?
Speaker 0: We're just got more fingers on the totem.
Speaker 0: wherever has the totem right by any means necessary right in this one.
Speaker 0: Cut out a lot of those rules because it happens so rarely.
Speaker 0: you don't really need those rules.
Speaker 0: if you're a mature adult It won't happen But you're better off Grabbing a diff.
Speaker 0: right if you're gonna you would better off not fighting with the person for the top stick and is grabbing another stick Before someone else grabs it.
Speaker 1: yeah I would.
Speaker 0: there's no reason that if you're fighting over a stick that is poor strategy.
Speaker 1: Well it does have a. the problem is occasionally three times in our game Which is a small number compared to the number of like throws every single.
Speaker 1: yeah three times Two people grabbed the same stick at the same time, and there's no way to resolve it.
Speaker 1: But if you just come up with a simple rule because the rules do say you cannot pry it out of someone else's hand So I think you could do the jungle speed rule of whoever's holding it lower wins right?
Speaker 0: I give just basically like you can tell like it's in your hand.
Speaker 0: You're trying to pry it therefore.
Speaker 0: You don't get it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's it's sort of obvious.
Speaker 0: in most scenarios.
Speaker 0: There were two the one who's the prior and who's the price twice me and Pat?
Speaker 1: We're both holding it at the same time And we both had a grip on it.
Speaker 0: with the right hand with the right hand the right manner We do we do after doing the right thing yep.
Speaker 1: So that's.
Speaker 1: the only thing I would add is just come up with a very simple rule of if two people hold it Whoever's holding it closer to the bottom gets it like something like that just in case and then you're good.
Speaker 0: I mean you could also if you really want to just put your phone up And then if you set your phone nearby recording you could see who grabbed it first with some instant replay.
Speaker 1: Oh, we should do that.
Speaker 0: for jungle speed you should make an instant replay app.
Speaker 0: It's like oh Add is to replace your whole life.
Speaker 0: Just put this phone on the little tripod and turn this app on.
Speaker 1: that is not a bad idea.
Speaker 0: Keep continuously recording for like you know a minute And then if you ever need an instant replay you can just actually all my cameras like the cameras will do that.
Speaker 1: hmm They have a continuous mode.
Speaker 1: yeah that purpose.
Speaker 0: Yeah, of course.
Speaker 1: Maybe we should start doing that when we play dexterity games, okay?
Speaker 0: We'll see.
Speaker 0: we'll slow it down as fast as the highest frame rate and see who grabbed it first.
Speaker 1: so I would say and Both Faustin is from 2018.
Speaker 1: They're both pretty recent games.
Speaker 0: Sorry German people yep and German speakers Hansa toy tonica.
Speaker 0: anyway.
Speaker 1: anyway these games are both pretty good Both worth getting if you want like dexterity games on the table.
Speaker 1: They are both like way above average for that genre Mm-hmm there.
Speaker 1: neither one of them is great, but they are both very good and very fun.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't know where you're gonna get a copy of all Faustin or or the other.
Speaker 0: Both these games might be hard to find.
Speaker 0: yeah They're the kind of games you're gonna have to either like import or trade someone or something like that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, dude Vol Faustin there are only four pictures of it in board game geek.
Speaker 1: like I have more pictures of this game on my cell phone That are on board game geek.
Speaker 0: yeah So sorry your photos to board game geek.
Speaker 1: I think I should.
Speaker 1: yeah Sorry, we reviewed two games that are great that you probably can't play.
Speaker 0: Imagine the vol Faustin might get an American release or not.
Speaker 1: you couldn't make vol Faustin pretty easily.
Speaker 0: You could just make a vol Faustin.
Speaker 0: You just need a wood shop to make the the wooden sticks, and then you could just wood shop.
Speaker 1: just buy squared squared.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you could buy a square Wouldn't stick?
Speaker 0: and then just chop it.
Speaker 1: you need a dremel and us and one Square.
Speaker 0: go to the hardware store get one piece of wood.
Speaker 0: That's the right shape and just cut it the right lengths.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know six inch five inch four inch three inch whatever.
Speaker 0: I guess I guess I'd do seven six five four three two
Speaker 1: Yeah, something like maybe
Speaker 0: eight seven six five four three one inch in between each and then get a bunch of dice and draw on Them and then you're good, and you're good to go and you get the rulebook from the internet.
Speaker 1: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 0: be sure to visit our website At front row.
Speaker 0: crew comm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 1: remember geek nights is not one But four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows It's actually recorded at night and the patreon patrons for this episode of the geek knives are Craig Oliver Alan Joyce Heidi McNichol just like a dude guy.
Speaker 1: Jartavish and Link Eiji.
Speaker 1: Jennifer Hitchcock Chris midkiff mystating calm j-band scooter lonely Roberto Kingsley Shawn Yeager Nicholas Brando mr Strong distraction for to one creations devourer of chaos champion of the great halls of Tarakas Sure Van Horl Rory Rochelle Monta known as super boy sailor Vista Joe sure Joe star Clinton Walton run from New Zealand Ryan Perrin Drew openlander Finn Daniel Redmond Shawn Klein Chris Reimer Thomas Hahn and now I leave you with.