Speaker 0:
Speaker 1: It's Thursday May 23rd 2019.
Speaker 1: I'm rim I'm sky and this is geek nights tonight not late to this party at all.
Speaker 1: We are reviewing the 1999 film The Matrix 20th anniversary.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: So yeah, it's a nice out finally biking to work like every day except today Except today.
Speaker 1: and it was funny cuz I got up and I was like oh I should bike to work and I look outside and it has that look of it.
Speaker 0: I already knew I wasn't gonna bike to work today cuz a I was going to the doctor after.
Speaker 0: yeah I'm sort of.
Speaker 0: I left work early go to the doctor and then came here.
Speaker 0: But be I checked the weather religiously like all the fucking time that I knew it was gonna rain today.
Speaker 1: Yep, so I'm at work and of course the problem was it was only raining while I would have had to bike to work and then it was like sunny and Nice for most of the day and then it was rainy again.
Speaker 1: right as I would have by tome.
Speaker 1: It only rained at the times.
Speaker 1: I would have been biking.
Speaker 0: That's when it likes to rain.
Speaker 1: I know it knows It's like us.
Speaker 1: rim got his bike out.
Speaker 1: Hahaha Zeus and Poseidon are both just like.
Speaker 1: yeah, fuck him up.
Speaker 1: So I was thinking of Poseidon because the pages of pain.
Speaker 0: I've not read any more painful pages since we last.
Speaker 1: So all I will say about that is that I had all the painful.
Speaker 1: I know but I'm real.
Speaker 1: near the end I hit the point where I remember the first time I read the book.
Speaker 1: it kind of accelerates like the last bit is one long And I kind of just read that in one go as a kid because I was just like what the fuck is going.
Speaker 1: Oh and all the bad all the really bad things just happened like one after another And I forgot about something pretty horrifying that happened.
Speaker 0: I'm sure many harv.
Speaker 0: It's the pages of pain.
Speaker 1: it's not the pages so pleasant if the if the to Sally if the hands getting cut off is like a level for painful and The foot thing like that's maybe a level six this is like Seems like it's ten and then you realize it's eleven.
Speaker 1: and that ain't even the worst thing that happens in this bike cut off to Replace a nose.
Speaker 1: It's pretty worse than you.
Speaker 1: It's pretty bad.
Speaker 1: It's pretty gruesome.
Speaker 1: It's uh It's painful pages are happening here.
Speaker 1: All right, but the one thing I can say about biking is that because I ride a hybrid like a Performance hybrid bike kind of the way I've ridden mountain bikes my whole life.
Speaker 1: I actually took the time to fully inspect my my rear cassettes actually a really good shape.
Speaker 1: My chain is stretched to a laughable degree Because I haven't been doing anything.
Speaker 1: I've been not maintaining my chain for shit.
Speaker 0: Apparently what what's supposed?
Speaker 0: the deal is right is you have a chain and the cassette and it.
Speaker 0: the chain gets stretched over time Yeah, and then that will erode the cassette.
Speaker 0: So usually you want to replace them together and just even though a cassette looks like it would be an expensive part.
Speaker 0: It's really not.
Speaker 0: It's just a bunch of gears in a stack.
Speaker 1: It's kind of a pain to replace it, but I'll have the bike shop do it.
Speaker 1: They charge like nothing to do that.
Speaker 0: It's not actually that hard.
Speaker 0: But anyway, it's not hard.
Speaker 1: It's just annoying because I don't have a lift like put my bike.
Speaker 0: is that if you replace your chain?
Speaker 0: When it gets stretched and the cassette is still in good shape a plus Yes you can usually get a new chain on there and get two chains per cassette and that is what you do if you're a Responsible bike owner who doesn't?
Speaker 0: but it's a regular set are mismatched.
Speaker 0: What happens is like the chain will slip over the gears.
Speaker 0: It's like you'll pedal and like the chain is spinning around But it like over the gears of the cassettes over the spikes and it goes like That'll happen if the cassette is bad or the chain is bad, right?
Speaker 0: And that's what you're trying to avoid.
Speaker 1: or if the chain is bad But the cassette is brand new and perfect You'll get the opposite.
Speaker 1: the chain will stay in the gears around the corner usually on the front and then pull up behind And loop under itself and that just causes an instant faceplant.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like it is it's called chainsaw and I'm afraid more more afraid of that than I am of terrorists.
Speaker 0: I mean, you could just be afraid of like a stick in the wheel.
Speaker 1: Yeah I'm more afraid of chainsaw because stick in the wheel.
Speaker 1: I assume if a stick goes into my wheel Someone did it on purpose and I probably am aware that I have an enemy who's attempting to do this to me.
Speaker 1: I doubt a random hobo is gonna stick out like a broom through my spokes randomly on the street.
Speaker 1: I'm more afraid of chainsaw than I am Just push people on the subway tracks.
Speaker 1: That is true.
Speaker 1: That is in fact true I encountered a really really aggressive hobo yesterday actually, okay But they didn't like it wasn't?
Speaker 1: it wasn't even on the level of worth talking about on geek nights.
Speaker 1: It's just I thought of it just now.
Speaker 1: it was below the gutter punk who threatened to stab me in Portland.
Speaker 1: Hmm, which that's now the bar I won't talk about a hobo unless they're above the line of had a knife at my back and threatened to stab me with it.
Speaker 1: Okay So, uh, I love all our friends in the West Coast are like, oh you're in that Riverside Park Park.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that'll happen there.
Speaker 1: Okay but But the last thing I'll say about biking is now that I'm biking to work every day I'm reminded of one of the most painful no sees that I have That the vast majority of people who own a bike in New York City Possibly the world.
Speaker 1: but I'm just focusing on New York City because that's the data.
Speaker 1: I these are the data that I have.
Speaker 1: Have no idea how bikes work and Like just they use a bike without understanding what any of the things on the bike do except the pedals.
Speaker 1: kinda Yep, they're in the wrong gear.
Speaker 1: Like they've clearly never.
Speaker 1: they've never attempted to squeeze their front brake at any point.
Speaker 1: I Love it when I see someone who is biking and the chain is making that sound of you are between gears Your bike is desperately trying to shift and can't and that's just how they bike.
Speaker 0: I don't know how people bike with like.
Speaker 0: I see his bike or the drivetrain is just made of rust and it's like it's still Working.
Speaker 0: I'm like, how are you riding that?
Speaker 0: How does that even work?
Speaker 0: Well, I remember when my bike got stolen and beacon one of the things the dude clearly didn't know how to ride a bike Because I see tons of people way more fit than me and I'm just going right by him Yeah, and they don't see it.
Speaker 1: I'm like, alright, but he had cut the Control wire to the front gear because I don't think he knew how it worked.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm, so it would like you basically locked the bike in one gear and there was no way to change gears.
Speaker 1: That's one of the modifications.
Speaker 1: He made to it when he was riding it around before I stole it back.
Speaker 1: So anyway, I got some news.
Speaker 1: I think we had an update on our.
Speaker 0: It's not a big news, but the gig nights follow-up.
Speaker 0: We just did that Pokemon t-shirt story on Tuesday.
Speaker 0: So the person who Submitted that t-shirt was D queued from the contest Yep, and it appears that the $10,000 prize will go to nobody Because the second apparently one of the other finalists was also disqualified for the same reason.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and I guess Uniqlo and Pokemon together were like, you know what?
Speaker 1: Fuck it.
Speaker 0: And then it also appears that no that the t-shirt was supposed to appear in Pokemon sword and shield.
Speaker 0: that ain't happen.
Speaker 0: That will not happen.
Speaker 0: However, everyone's like, oh, it's probably gonna be in the game.
Speaker 0: So you got to do some data mining find it, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, because they probably programmed it already or whatever.
Speaker 0: So, yeah, that's interesting.
Speaker 0: see what happens there.
Speaker 1: yep, so, uh, the leave will be when pay.
Speaker 1: actually like tried to work it out with them is from what I can tell and Uniqlo Didn't respond and just ended everything.
Speaker 1: They basically just walked away from this whole situation And apparently they don't know which.
Speaker 0: I don't know if Uniqlo or Nintendo were the ones paying out the prize.
Speaker 1: I believe Uniqlo was because here's what the rules of the thing actually said Uniqlo may withdraw prizes and or and or terminate merchandising of t-shirts with winning artworks without prior notice to the entrant Irrespective of the originality of the artwork submitted the entrant if similar artwork is already publicly available outside Uniqlo stores.
Speaker 1: so if I made a completely original design that was Similar to an existing design that I may or may not have known about.
Speaker 0: basically they have lawyers.
Speaker 0: They covered their ass.
Speaker 0: The ass covering was sufficient.
Speaker 1: In fact, if I submitted something nice butt armor, it's yep.
Speaker 1: So basically everyone walked away from this and the whole contest just ended in failure.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: That's a shame.
Speaker 1: I think the moral is don't enter our contest.
Speaker 0: Regardless there will still be some nice Pokemon shirts on sale at Uniqlo.
Speaker 0: Don't you worry?
Speaker 1: I feel like what we're gonna see is that lower tier anime cons This exact t-shirt will be sold by bootleggers in the artist alley.
Speaker 1: I think that's what we're gonna see like 100% and I want you all to post pictures of this when you find it at Your local friendly anime convention.
Speaker 0: You should make a parody of the shirt.
Speaker 1: I should it's a parrot Make some sort of joke about Uniqlo.
Speaker 0: I don't know what else has a long thing in three dot things.
Speaker 1: I don't know I could come over something.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so in some other news This is gaming news, but we're gonna focus more on the political angle.
Speaker 1: So there is a.
Speaker 0: it's not that it just because it's Thursday not Tuesday.
Speaker 1: Whatever those are there is a bill in Congress of the United States that has and this is shockingly like if you don't live in the u.s.
Speaker 1: Bipartisan bills right don't exist anymore.
Speaker 0: Well, it's because they do.
Speaker 0: they're just usually things you never hear about cuz you don't care about.
Speaker 1: Well, no, usually they are the bills that are literally necessary to be passed for the government to keep running The bill.
Speaker 0: so that's not gonna be reported in the news though unless they lose bipartisan support right which happens actually.
Speaker 0: Anyway, the point is that Much like the country of Belgium which banned pretty much all Gambling stuff in games whatsoever.
Speaker 1: Yeah Belgian so far China, which also has banned almost similar to Belgium Belgium and gambling in games Even if that gambling is virtual to the point that blizzard said they just won't sell their games there anymore.
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 0: China is banning but also went further into limiting other forms of speech like violence and such.
Speaker 0: but the United the bill that's in the Senate right now is only what it says is if your game has random shit like loot boxes, yeah or Pay to win shit, right?
Speaker 0: Even if it is not random.
Speaker 0: Yep And you're selling this game to minors then you can't do that you have to basically go through great measures to make sure that People under the age of 18 are not playing your game and then you can do some of this gambling biz.
Speaker 1: I would argue this is actually a good thing for the industry because you know, it's gonna happen.
Speaker 1: Everyone who wants to play these games who is under 18 will play them anyway and buy them with their parents credit card and everything.
Speaker 1: You'll be fine.
Speaker 1: Just like how everyone certifies when they make an account on anything.
Speaker 0: Everyone sees porn online.
Speaker 1: They're all everyone's over the age of 13 whether you're 8 or 80 because you're not allowed to actually provide services to children under COPPA.
Speaker 1: so No one almost no one makes a website that technically lets you use it in any way if you're under the age of 13.
Speaker 0: Right, but hopefully what this will do is, you know The the industry most industries video game industry included right are of the opinion Like you we have to self-regulate to a degree such so that the government will not come and regulate.
Speaker 1: I'm pretty okay.
Speaker 0: And then when the government comes to regulate they say no no, no, let us self-regulate like Facebook.
Speaker 0: No, no, no Let us regulate ourselves.
Speaker 1: Well, cuz here's a fine point on this if you're not aware people think you gotta be at Fox watch the n-house.
Speaker 0: We will do a good job.
Speaker 0: Trust us.
Speaker 1: people think you have to be 18 to do things Like.
Speaker 1: well, I guess back when blockbuster existed to rent an adult video You needed to be 18 by law to see an R-rated movie.
Speaker 1: You got to be 18 to buy the ticket to buy a violent video game.
Speaker 1: get it.
Speaker 1: None of those things are laws.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm when I was a kid I went to see R-rated movies like when I was 13 14 by myself.
Speaker 1: all the time theater would gladly sell me a ticket Because there was no law about that.
Speaker 0: There were some theaters that voluntarily would try to prevent you.
Speaker 1: But if look basically if local parents made a big deal about it local theaters would enforce these Optional rules these self-regulated rules that the industry would put together just to keep the lawsuits away.
Speaker 1: so it's kind of the same thing with a lot of video game stuff and This law would actually force compliance or at least force Ostensible compliance.
Speaker 0: the most interesting part of the law is simply that they attempted to in legal terms Define what counts as pay to win in a court of law Which I'm kind of excited about because fuck pay to win.
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 1: Like I want to use a blunt hammer to end anyone's ability to sell video game I really need a win.
Speaker 0: There's also a couple related stories and a. I would like to whisper into some.
Speaker 0: Lavi a be a lobbyist so I could whisper in some ears.
Speaker 0: obvious would be a good job and be like, hey, you know Pokemon cards and magic cards are basically the same thing.
Speaker 0: Why don't we apply this to those two?
Speaker 0: And be The ESA which if you don't know is basically like the RA for video games.
Speaker 0: It is like a bunch of you know Lawyers and lobbyists for the video game industry that are supposed to make sure the government doesn't do things like this.
Speaker 1: Arguably, they failed because their job was to make sure laws like this don't appear.
Speaker 0: Well many people.
Speaker 0: the ESA does two things it lobbies the government, right and it helps fight You know for the video game industry's interest in court.
Speaker 0: And it runs e3 and the.
Speaker 0: basically the members of the ESA are not happy with pretty much anything The ESA does is doing a real bad job.
Speaker 1: E3 is a shit show.
Speaker 0: It's doing a real bad job across the board.
Speaker 0: They want e3 to be split off into its own thing and the ESA is doing real bad a job at lobbying Which is why these kind of laws are coming out.
Speaker 0: So the downfall of the ESA has been in the news recently as well.
Speaker 0: So it's interesting coincidence that here comes a whole something an example of the ESA doing a bad job At least at its goals whether if you agree with those goals or not.
Speaker 1: Right after there were stories about the ESA suck What I am very happy about is the law seems to have.
Speaker 0: I feel like if today there was a story about rim being real bad at Jumping or walking and then next week.
Speaker 0: There was a story about rim tripping over his own feet.
Speaker 1: Yep, basically But this law fell down and hurt himself.
Speaker 0: I like how the bill and I just read an article last week about Walking and that was the article about rim falling over.
Speaker 1: But the bill is very focused on the things we're actually mad about and it is not in any way about Violence about content.
Speaker 1: it is literally clearly.
Speaker 0: It's one of those ones where there's no senator in the Senate who knows a fuck all about any of this.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right.
Speaker 0: so it's clearly written by some congressional staff.
Speaker 0: like most things are you know who are intelligent and know what's up and The reason the senators support it?
Speaker 0: because yeah This is to crack down on get kids gambling like oh pretty much any old white person can get behind that.
Speaker 0: Yep, so there you go.
Speaker 1: also quote from the article under the protecting children from abusive games act.
Speaker 1: there you go, and they define abuse as basically addictive shit and Manipulating them to get money out of them.
Speaker 1: Yep Like that's kind of.
Speaker 1: it says games that are marketed to children would be prohibited from implementing any pay-to-win Mechanisms all games would be forbidden from selling loot boxes to children, etc.
Speaker 1: Etc.
Speaker 1: So we'll see where this all goes.
Speaker 1: but it has bipartisan support which is rare with this kind of law.
Speaker 1: Usually when there's bipartisan support for a law that's restrictive on media.
Speaker 1: Those laws tend to be shitty laws.
Speaker 1: So the only problem is that right now?
Speaker 1: Basically, no legislation can move anywhere in our government because of the president refusing to sign anything.
Speaker 0: I'm sure he will sign it.
Speaker 0: the protect children from gambling abuse.
Speaker 0: Even even this president will sign that.
Speaker 1: I don't think so because he basically just said that he won't sign anything Until the house stops investigating.
Speaker 0: Personally, why do you believe anything the lyingest liar in the history of lying ever said?
Speaker 1: because the one thing the lyingest liar doesn't lie about is Threatening people unless they stop investigating him for shit.
Speaker 0: That's actually not true.
Speaker 0: He threatens people all the time and then doesn't go through with it or or tries to sue people and fails all the time.
Speaker 1: But in this case, it's something he actually has control over.
Speaker 1: Usually the threats he makes are things he can't actually do.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean he just cuz he can do it doesn't mean gonna do it.
Speaker 0: Listen, if the if somehow this actually gets to his decks, I think he would be like hey look at me I'm protecting kids from whatever.
Speaker 0: what okay?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I bet he wouldn't.
Speaker 1: I bet this bill goes nowhere.
Speaker 0: I mean, that's probably true.
Speaker 0: Also.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's kind of I don't think it'll even get to this.
Speaker 1: So, uh in some other last news This is just a tweet but I have a lot to say about it It's in the tree was someone saying oh, we're not dumbing down our culture at all.
Speaker 1: Basically someone got a picture of at Target.
Speaker 1: Target they're selling classic movies on DVD or blu-ray or whatever.
Speaker 1: but Instead of putting the title of the movie on the top of the cover like every DVD has been for all of history They're putting the quote from the movie That basic people who don't know anything about cinema and have not seen these movies Would recognize even if they don't know what the movie is called.
Speaker 0: I don't understand what you're saying.
Speaker 1: So the move the box for Scarface.
Speaker 1: the top says say hello to my little friend Like that's the name of the movie and at the bottom in a much smaller font Scarface I mean someone who's still buying DVDs and blu-rays.
Speaker 0: That's the kind of person that that is probably a better sales dress that Jaws is titled.
Speaker 1: you're gonna need a bigger boat and then Jaws isn't a little text at the bottom.
Speaker 1: So it's interesting because I think it's a very smart marketing decision.
Speaker 0: It's good trade dress first, you know target audience.
Speaker 0: So it is buying movies at Best Buy right?
Speaker 0: It's like, you know, they're not gonna buy Jaws, you know Can you like?
Speaker 0: how can you even sell a Jaws on DVD?
Speaker 0: that movie is just like so easily available?
Speaker 0: Yeah, right, but I guess that's probably the only way to convince someone to buy.
Speaker 0: it is like, you know they see that and they're like.
Speaker 1: So I guess what I'm getting at is that people are really on TV all the time.
Speaker 0: Someone who's buying discs at Best Buy definitely has cable TV is probably watching it But it sort of gets back to like.
Speaker 1: how do people find and search for things?
Speaker 1: a lot of people Don't know a lot about things.
Speaker 1: using the someone's more likely to recognize.
Speaker 1: Say hello to my little friend then have any idea who Al Pacino is right?
Speaker 0: The other thing is that you know, it's somebody who John when was Jaws in theaters 1970 something Early 80s late 70s something like that, right?
Speaker 0: It's old so people don't know it, but that's what I'm saying.
Speaker 1: I'm not mad about this.
Speaker 1: I think it's a good idea.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but the best part is fuck is on the the label of a disc.
Speaker 0: I'm more mad that why are people still buying discs?
Speaker 0: eliminate all physical media?
Speaker 1: But the best part about this is all the replies to the tweets.
Speaker 1: not polluting the earth with your plastic because the replies to the Tweet are things like oh man.
Speaker 1: I can't wait to watch you son of a bitch.
Speaker 1: Or I'm gonna have me some fun.
Speaker 0: Go have me some fun.
Speaker 1: Go have me some fun.
Speaker 1: Hey, have you ever seen?
Speaker 1: I'll be back and it's sequel.
Speaker 1: come with me if you want to live.
Speaker 0: no, but I have you see.
Speaker 0: I Know I Feel like calling that movie.
Speaker 1: I'm here to chew bobo gum and kick ass comma And I'm all out of gum is Literally the only way to get anyone who hasn't already seen that movie.
Speaker 0: I see we're done with the show you gonna want.
Speaker 1: you want to go watch put the sunglasses on But anyway things of the day what do you got?
Speaker 0: so there's this dude, what's it?
Speaker 0: What's his channel called?
Speaker 1: his channel is called goat rides bikes.
Speaker 1: Okay?
Speaker 1: He's only got 428 subscribers anyway, he's got 429.
Speaker 0: it's his bike riding guy.
Speaker 0: You know he's not the most interesting dude honest.
Speaker 0: Sorry goat.
Speaker 0: He's not a bad dude though, and what's interesting is he it's a video of his bike commute And he's narrating his bike commute.
Speaker 0: It's kind of a long one yeah So you know.
Speaker 0: anyway the thing is his bike commute is from his suburban ish home to his workplace Which is in a warehouse in a place that I'd never heard of Known as the Springfield underground.
Speaker 1: now I assume when Scott said that that it's like the Rochester subway like some abandoned subway that someone got access to I'd never heard Of the Springfield underground before.
Speaker 0: obviously neither is rim neither of most people But once you learn what the Springfield underground is it is fascinating and amazing.
Speaker 0: what around apparently way back in the day?
Speaker 0: There was a mine, and they were mining.
Speaker 0: I think he said limestone for fertilizer.
Speaker 1: So fun facts inside.
Speaker 1: you know what's under Detroit?
Speaker 1: What did I think the biggest salt mine in the world like the salt catacombs anyway?
Speaker 0: So that mine is obviously no one's mining there anymore, but it was this vast Empty underground space where a lot of rock had been removed But it was pretty much flat with a ceiling you know and some pillars of rock because you can't remove them all then they will Collapse in on.
Speaker 0: yeah, right yeah, so some rock pillars You know sort of like you know the big empty warehouse.
Speaker 1: so it's got.
Speaker 1: here's a question Do you know what it's called when a stalag tight and a stalagmite meet a stag?
Speaker 1: there is a word for a stalag.
Speaker 1: I looked everything.
Speaker 1: I actually forgot it.
Speaker 1: I don't remember the word a stalag
Speaker 0: not Stalagma tight Magnetite I don't know anyway, so in the Springfield underground what they did is they said hey We got this big empty space here right in this big empty space it is a Always like 62 degrees no matter fucking what.
Speaker 0: no right it doesn't.
Speaker 1: that's how heat pumps work.
Speaker 0: I mean it doesn't get hot or cold ever it's always the same temperature.
Speaker 0: There's a lot of room.
Speaker 0: It's big and wide and open right.
Speaker 0: there must be some kind of ventilation going on.
Speaker 0: I don't know if he talked about that.
Speaker 1: I mean mines usually had some sort of ventilation strategy.
Speaker 0: No one's right.
Speaker 0: I saw there was a part where he looks and there's a big hole in the ceiling with like water coming in from and from Sunlight coming in.
Speaker 0: so you know.
Speaker 0: and what they did is it?
Speaker 0: well all we got to do is between some of these rock pillars we put up a few walls right and then the natural walls are behind there.
Speaker 0: and Boom you just got yourself a warehouse for like no effort.
Speaker 0: You don't got to build ceiling You don't got to build a wall.
Speaker 0: You know you build one wall.
Speaker 0: Yeah boom enormous warehouse.
Speaker 0: It is a Ultra secure.
Speaker 0: no all right.
Speaker 0: It must be real hard to get in there and rob those warehouses.
Speaker 0: Right be ultra temperature and humidity control.
Speaker 0: you don't got to have H vac or heating or anything right?
Speaker 0: It's just good to go and You got tons of fucking room real cheap because who else wants to be underground and it's enormous.
Speaker 0: So he bikes to work in a warehouse and he bikes through this enormous Springfield underground And he shows you what's going on down there.
Speaker 0: They're building some more warehouses down there.
Speaker 0: They got all kinds of stuff.
Speaker 1: that stalagnates is where they meet.
Speaker 0: okay you Adam anyway.
Speaker 0: But yeah, it's really interesting.
Speaker 0: I think the only thing that was a it's like a waste of energy down There was that there's there's doing food storage.
Speaker 0: So they do have to have some refrigeration going on.
Speaker 0: well the refrigeration only has to get from 62 down as opposed to exactly Yeah, even in the hot hot 90 degree summer if you had your warehouse outside What would the bill be for that?
Speaker 0: They also have to light the whole thing you know, and I'm sure there must have added lights pretty.
Speaker 0: I'm curious about the plumbing situation.
Speaker 1: I mean there's probably a bathroom in there somewhere.
Speaker 0: I mean you wouldn't make it to the bathroom.
Speaker 0: It's too big.
Speaker 0: just if you had to go outside to poop you wouldn't make.
Speaker 0: I guess you could just put bring porta potties in and out at worst case you could.
Speaker 0: just You do need running water to wash your hands Yeah, but there's plenty of room for the parking lots.
Speaker 0: pulling her into bike You know.
Speaker 0: so pretty fascinating to see what's going on in the place.
Speaker 0: I didn't know existed Underground.
Speaker 1: so I got a question for you when the first spy satellites were put up in space?
Speaker 0: when was this like 60s 60s 70s yeah Even 80s?
Speaker 1: okay well yeah Earlier spy satellites, how do you think they got images back to earth?
Speaker 0: well?
Speaker 0: They didn't have the internet right yeah.
Speaker 0: So they definitely had a satellite dish on the ground aimed at the satellite with some sort of data going between.
Speaker 0: No much like satellite technology didn't really exist.
Speaker 1: yet for images there were satellite television.
Speaker 0: Uh what what in the 80s?
Speaker 1: What would they use in a satellite to capture the image to then transmit back a?
Speaker 1: Camera with a big-ass fucking lens on what did know that was not feasible technology back then?
Speaker 0: What do you mean?
Speaker 1: Why not, but do you know how?
Speaker 1: early?
Speaker 1: Cameras worked for like TV.
Speaker 0: right, but you read Like a TV camera on a salad.
Speaker 1: There's no way to put that on a satellite.
Speaker 0: They couldn't put a TV camera from the other side of a satellite.
Speaker 1: No you also couldn't transmit that back.
Speaker 1: Satellites in that era fucking shot canisters of film back down to earth.
Speaker 0: Physical film they just there's film.
Speaker 0: they took photos and they drop.
Speaker 1: TV cameras weren't even high enough resolution to get meaningful images Film and just stopped.
Speaker 1: yeah, that is literally how they worked and this video explains in detail you had to catch the film.
Speaker 0: Yes, what the Russians caught the film.
Speaker 0: so if they shot the film did they go around trying to catch Russian film?
Speaker 1: Yeah, if we didn't get the film down the film was designed.
Speaker 1: if we didn't pick it up within 48 hours it destroyed itself.
Speaker 0: What did we try to catch?
Speaker 0: Russian film?
Speaker 0: I?
Speaker 1: This video will tell you everything catching a Russian film.
Speaker 1: I don't think we ever caught any of their film.
Speaker 0: What kind of film was it actually?
Speaker 1: this tells you everything about even how the lenses worked.
Speaker 1: the lenses Actually had to be really complicated for a bunch of reasons I don't want to get into of course because yeah This video is actually.
Speaker 0: they could zoom in way more than you think they could zoom in real far.
Speaker 1: Yep, how they calibrated the images.
Speaker 1: this video in ten minutes will tell you some fascinating shit.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they couldn't just throw there a bunch of empty satellites up there.
Speaker 1: They've had satellites for d orbited as far as I can tell.
Speaker 0: otherwise I say hey Let's go up and get one.
Speaker 1: This is a good bit.
Speaker 0: You got a real good lens on it.
Speaker 0: We can take photos man.
Speaker 0: Yeah That lens is still good even that the film is done.
Speaker 1: the lens had a Sweeping mechanism to make the lens take a picture of one part of the ground because the satellites going by at a crazy speed It'll be blurry otherwise yep.
Speaker 1: So yeah in the moment the geek nice book club book as we talked about in the beginning is a book by Troy deading.
Speaker 1: That is a Dungeons & Dragons Branded Planescape book from the early days of the Planescape setting officially licensed D&D novel that the first half of it is a straight.
Speaker 1: Well the first third of it is a straightforward D&D book just like all that elf crap I used to read.
Speaker 1: and the rest of it is a trippy nightmare descent into hell.
Speaker 1: It's a pretty good way to describe it.
Speaker 1: surreal nonsense happens at the end, and we're reading it.
Speaker 1: We'll probably done with it by the next Thursday's show.
Speaker 0: We'll see.
Speaker 1: I doubt it's gonna be sunny every day.
Speaker 1: hey you got a flight to Rochester you finish it on that flight.
Speaker 0: That's not a bad idea.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we might both finish it on that flight.
Speaker 1: If nothing else.
Speaker 0: That's on the 4th of July though Yeah, so worst case in August.
Speaker 1: We will do this show okay probably before then.
Speaker 0: the next invention we're going to is PAX West which is a long time from now, but I Mention it because a badges will be on sale soon after Memorial Day, but not before Memorial Day.
Speaker 0: So this weekend you can just relax and then after that you got to be at a highest alert.
Speaker 1: Yeah starting Tuesday Morning Eastern Daylight Time it is red alert and by Thursday It is like black alert like Def Con one.
Speaker 1: the nukes were launched also.
Speaker 0: They are doing something that they are undoing a previous policy.
Speaker 1: the panel submissions are open to.
Speaker 1: I gotta get in that shit.
Speaker 0: They are going to once again be selling full weekend passes.
Speaker 0: So I'm sure they won't be any cheaper than four individual one-day passes.
Speaker 0: But they will see.
Speaker 0: you only have to carry one piece of plastic around with you for all four days.
Speaker 0: My I think you know we we were talking about.
Speaker 0: hey selling the individual passes changes the culture of packs.
Speaker 0: But I think what this won't do any have that effect.
Speaker 1: I think it's because same effect they're basically.
Speaker 0: they think they're looking at their numbers and saying well This many people bought one of each day, so we'll just sell that many weekend passes Maybe a little less than that yeah, and then we'll just basically make the same amount of money sell the same badges But a certain number of people won't have to carry around all this extra plastic with them.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean I don't know exactly what if I were doing it.
Speaker 1: I would just say if someone by if someone can legitimately get all four days in their order They will just get a single four-day badge instead.
Speaker 0: well What if they want it?
Speaker 0: you know I guess they could be a checkbox saying yes Please send me four separate ones because maybe you buy one of each day And it's like two or for your friend on Friday Saturday, and yeah two or for you on whatever Sunday Monday I don't know,
Speaker 1: but at the other counter point
Speaker 0: was that somebody would buy all the days But not actually want a single person to go.
Speaker 1: all true But the counterpoint would be many of the people.
Speaker 1: is some of the people doing the vast majority scalp?
Speaker 0: yes But the vast majority who are buying all four days want to go all have a person who's going off?
Speaker 1: Yes, and before anyone tries to talk again about like scalpers ruining this scalpers are not the problem.
Speaker 1: Pax is just not cannot be physically big enough to give everyone wants it a badge.
Speaker 0: scalpers are a symptom of any time that demand exceeds supply.
Speaker 0: Someone will come in and arbitrage to make money.
Speaker 0: yep And the scalpers aren't the cause of the problem.
Speaker 1: the problem is there's not enough and Pax has decided very pointedly for good or ill That they'd rather it be random who gets in based partly on who's paying the most attention.
Speaker 0: Then let it just be Pax badges $500 or you know have tiers of pricing or anything like that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm glad they have not done.
Speaker 0: because yes scalpers are a problem for things where demand It doesn't actually meet supply or comes close to meeting supply or this would sell out But it'll take a month for it to sell out naturally.
Speaker 0: so scalpers come in and eat up the extra supply And then jack up the price usually with the cooperation of companies like Ticketmaster.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but once those cases you can blame scalpers.
Speaker 1: But once the demand is known and the demand is already above the capacity scalpers have no impact.
Speaker 1: yes Also, I noticed scalpers have a hard time actually selling their badges these days.
Speaker 0: They stand outside of packs like go buy and selling guys.
Speaker 1: I think as most people I just sell badges.
Speaker 1: I think it's because anyone who doesn't live in Seattle and Doesn't get badges when they first go on sale does not have a hotel because the hotel sell out, too They're not gonna fly to Seattle and risk not getting badges.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna scalp a hotel.
Speaker 0: Yeah There's no scalping But you could basically you can scalp by selling your badges to someone who lives there and does not have a thing.
Speaker 1: yep But Seattle is a tiny little baby city that doesn't have that many people in it yet And especially not on the weekend when you know there's no one as at work.
Speaker 1: Yep, so uh Anyway, let's get to the main bit.
Speaker 1: There was a movie that came out in and We're sort of gonna review it.
Speaker 1: I guess we're gonna spoil shit cuz I assume you've seen this movie.
Speaker 1: It's gonna talk about the matrix because the thing that stands out in my mind to this day Is that this is probably the first movie I ever saw and I have tried and succeeded to have this experience for a lot of movies in my adult life, and I love it.
Speaker 1: when this happens like When I went to see us I didn't know anything about it except.
Speaker 1: I saw did not even the teaser trailer.
Speaker 1: I just saw the image the movie poster.
Speaker 1: when I went to see the matrix all I knew about it was It's about some hacker guy.
Speaker 0: well the the marketing campaign for the matrix which I remember because I was alive And was the target audience yep?
Speaker 0: Well, yeah, I was.
Speaker 1: we were wondering like you want to look at the demographic.
Speaker 1: They were trying to get to see the matrix.
Speaker 1: It's me and Scott.
Speaker 0: anyway It was a very very good marketing campaign where you know back in the day where I still saw ads.
Speaker 0: yep, right?
Speaker 1: What is the matrix?
Speaker 0: put all these signs around and all the posters and images were this black sheet with green?
Speaker 0: Hacker hacker text falling down.
Speaker 0: even had that as desktop wallpaper at some point.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: I had that as a Screensaver.
Speaker 0: screensaver - yeah, yeah, I had that screensaver.
Speaker 0: anyway It was black screen with green stuff trickling down green characters trickling down a very hacker aesthetic.
Speaker 0: And they were all like what is the matrix?
Speaker 0: question mark Gabbo Gabbo Gabbo, and they didn't tell you fucking shit.
Speaker 0: There was.
Speaker 0: no there might have been a trailer.
Speaker 0: I never saw it.
Speaker 1: I was on the hype train from day one.
Speaker 0: I was a website I went to in the end on my Netscape navigator browser that didn't have much information at all whatsoever.
Speaker 1: So I was like I'm gonna see this movie.
Speaker 1: I went opening night.
Speaker 0: I was like yeah, what is the fucking matrix?
Speaker 0: Let's go find out.
Speaker 0: It's definitely appealing to my aesthetic.
Speaker 1: me and Ken and like my whole high school crew we just went to see the matrix and The.
Speaker 1: we watched the movie and we were like alright.
Speaker 1: This is cool.
Speaker 1: This is cool, and then when he wakes up Outside of the matrix I know I went to the theater.
Speaker 1: when what?
Speaker 1: I figured out before then oh yeah, but but there was a physical palpable loud reaction in the theater.
Speaker 1: Remember, I remember that moment when he when he like pulls the thing out of his throat and like looks around The theater was like wow there was like a lot of rumbling in the audience.
Speaker 1: Right and I saw the matrix like four more times in the theater.
Speaker 0: Yep, and I still remember I dis interesting neither one of us actually remembered the order of all the scenes Especially in the early part, but I remembered every scene.
Speaker 1: I remember every scene Mostly right.
Speaker 1: I remember this movie in like a weird degree of detail Mmm, and I still love it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, this movie makes the very short list of movies.
Speaker 1: Can I have a list we always try to maintain of what is a movie where if you're?
Speaker 1: Reminded that it exists you immediately feel an urge to just watch it.
Speaker 0: If it is on you'll just watch it.
Speaker 0: You're just gonna be trained Snared by it like a bear trap where you have to sit there until it's over like when I was Rewind it and watch it again when I was home yesterday.
Speaker 1: I go out to right now.
Speaker 1: when I was at home over the summer like after a freshman year of our IT The matrix was just on TV Half the time.
Speaker 1: I just like stop changing the channels and just watch it at least until the next commercial break.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like.
Speaker 1: Oh matrix.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah matrix.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah They're like maybe 12 movies that exist on earth that are on that list for me And somehow the matrix is one of them.
Speaker 0: so words about the movie itself I just want to talk about.
Speaker 0: like the more meta stuff.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so the other meta thing besides the marketing campaign is that this is a movie that?
Speaker 0: Introduced a lot of existing cinematographic techniques and styles to the u.s.
Speaker 0: Western audience right specifically Hong Kong action cinema who shot kung fu stuff right.
Speaker 0: so I've seen many kung fu movies Right, but I hadn't seen that.
Speaker 0: you know.
Speaker 0: this is different styles of kung fu movie right.
Speaker 0: there's the style where people are doing like realistic Kung fu right and then there's a style where people are like jumping 20 feet in the air like Crouching Tiger Hidden Dragon.
Speaker 0: and the matrix was like the first Western movie to at least to the mass You know Hollywood Audience make that kind of action scene like the core of its aesthetic right where it's like.
Speaker 0: yeah They're not just fighting like you know they do in Terminator 2 or Rambo And a Van Damme like kickboxer movie right?
Speaker 0: or karate kid.
Speaker 0: You know it was like her bloodsport.
Speaker 0: It was like sure but exactly right.
Speaker 0: it wasn't like that.
Speaker 0: It was superhero fighting superhero kung fu and before the matrix there wasn't a movie that did that.
Speaker 0: and after the matrix There are many Western movies that have done this yep.
Speaker 1: And it also introduced like.
Speaker 1: it is hard to understate how many people who had never encountered like babies first solipsism babies first philosophy shadows in a cave.
Speaker 1: Every fucking edgelord kid thought they were a philosopher after they saw this movie.
Speaker 0: right.
Speaker 0: well Basically what the matrix does is it combines all these basic things into a never-before-made Combination right.
Speaker 0: so you're combining a the what if we're all living in a simulation thing which has another side Which is an idea that I had come across prior to seeing the matrix yep So in the same year another movie called the 13th floor came out.
Speaker 0: That was about a bunch of.
Speaker 0: I have not seen that but I heard of it.
Speaker 1: Oh, I'm not even gonna say anything else.
Speaker 0: It's better than the matrix.
Speaker 1: Yes The 13th floor it's not a watch it a million times movie, so it's not better than the main.
Speaker 1: well because the matrix is Better at being a movie.
Speaker 1: I just never want to not watch because of all the Hong Kong cinema kung fu action.
Speaker 1: But the 13th floor is a smarter movie that makes a much more complex and nuanced point.
Speaker 1: Like the 13th floor is a really really really good movie, and you should see it.
Speaker 1: I would watch it again.
Speaker 1: the matrix also had like the blue pill red pill action Yeah, which has been co-opted by the worst people on earth.
Speaker 1: Yeah But when it can I remember like before like incel shitlords made red pill a thing right.
Speaker 1: blue pill red pill was a Thing for edgelords around being edgy and cool.
Speaker 0: and also what the matrix.
Speaker 0: while it has a white Hero problem yeah white dude hero problem and also has a white Savior problem I think it's the right term.
Speaker 0: right yeah.
Speaker 0: And also has the yes the white hero Savior has to definitely kiss.
Speaker 0: the lady right has those two Problems.
Speaker 1: yeah, why did I have to be a love interest?
Speaker 0: it also has plenty of kick-ass ladies and colored people in it.
Speaker 0: yep Sort of has the negatives and the positives.
Speaker 0: It's on that border between right.
Speaker 0: Anyway, yeah The other thing is that the matrix combines the not also not something you know it's an aesthetic that I was familiar with.
Speaker 0: But the pot the mass uh you know Western audience was not the cyberpunk snow crash aesthetic.
Speaker 1: yep I was part of why I love it so much.
Speaker 1: is that I love that aesthetic and the only place I really got to see that aesthetic pre matrix was Blade Runner Shadowrun Shadowrun and a bunch of a Spider-Man 2099.
Speaker 1: That's part of why I was so into anime because there was a lot of stuff like that in the kind of anime I was watching right before I got to our IT.
Speaker 0: funny that they actually made matrix anime officially after the mate right yep Which if you haven't seen the only other canon matrix material yeah, and it's pretty good like you should see it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the anime the anime tricks and the matrix of the only canon matrix material.
Speaker 1: It's really a shame.
Speaker 0: the Wachowski sisters Someone tried to make an MMO once but that didn't turn out too.
Speaker 1: Well, I heard that someone tried to make a sequel to the matrix.
Speaker 0: that didn't come out though.
Speaker 1: I know shame the point is I've never seen the matrix reloaded.
Speaker 0: okay never on Netflix.
Speaker 1: Oh Scott was convinced for like a decade that I'd seen it and even argued with me that I may actually watch him.
Speaker 0: I may watch those non-canon materials just to remember them after because they're on Netflix.
Speaker 1: But Scott you seriously tried to argue with me that I saw the matrix reloaded with you in the theater.
Speaker 0: Not only did I know it's been well established my memory is not great except apparently passwords.
Speaker 1: Yeah But I did go to see matrix revolutions in the theater, and I did not need to have seen matrix really don't?
Speaker 0: The point is matrix also combined that cyberpunk aesthetic right with right with the wuxia kung fu aesthetic Yeah, and the HR Geiger aesthetic yeah Never.
Speaker 0: it is like this.
Speaker 0: you know know what other thing combines all the good ins into one bucket?
Speaker 1: like to get that.
Speaker 1: I'd have to just watch Blade Runner and Pretend that they're in the same universe like your turn to the 36 chamber.
Speaker 1: We actually have the flying people But it's really honestly Blade Runner and alien would really make sense to be in the same universe sure like Considering the plot of both of them and the themes they both address and I'd have to watch both of those.
Speaker 1: Then watch I don't know.
Speaker 0: I think it more makes more sense for alien to just come way after 2001 in 2010.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think that could work anyway anyway.
Speaker 1: So I love the shit out of the matrix, and I feel like I'm gonna watch it again like you just did.
Speaker 0: yeah Why not yeah?
Speaker 1: It was just great.
Speaker 0: I watched it.
Speaker 0: It was so fucking great.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so what's great about the matrix?
Speaker 0: so first of all right The all those action scenes I just talked about with all the kung fu and all that biz right there super well choreographed Right.
Speaker 1: they're not a bunch of fast cuts.
Speaker 1: They're long cuts like I like in kung fu movies.
Speaker 1: They're not that long But they're longer than the average American action movie.
Speaker 1: up to that point a at for the.
Speaker 0: whether they invented or popularized it They were the first to deploy the technique of having a ton of cameras in an arc around the scene bullet time and then Panning from one camera to the next and they use this right in the opening scene.
Speaker 0: right Trinity jumps up in the air right.
Speaker 0: you're looking at her straight on and then the camera.
Speaker 0: It looks like the cat.
Speaker 0: everything is frozen and the camera is moving while time is stopped to then come to the side Profile, but in the way They did this was just a bunch of cameras right all lined up and then use some computers to get the in-between bits right.
Speaker 0: So before that that was not a technique that was used often.
Speaker 0: Maybe maybe even invented it or were the first to use it.
Speaker 0: in Hollywood There is a whole.
Speaker 0: now it is used all the fucking time.
Speaker 1: There's a whole Wikipedia article just on bullet time as a concept.
Speaker 1: yep Cuz bullet time is a registered trademark of Warner Brothers who made this movie.
Speaker 0: I'm pretty sure right.
Speaker 0: Another thing it goes on in the matrix.
Speaker 1: Oh get this they trademarked it in 2005 Mm-hmm as used in the matrix online.
Speaker 1: Ah So they didn't trademark.
Speaker 1: there were the phrase bullet time.
Speaker 0: until then you even saw video games employing bullet time.
Speaker 0: They would have like video after the majors came out.
Speaker 0: there were a lot of FPS is and third-person games where you would push your button and like the game would slow down for a Short amount of time to allow you to like you know aim or follow three.
Speaker 0: does it too right where it's like?
Speaker 0: right anyway What was I saying?
Speaker 1: Something about bullet time.
Speaker 0: oh another thing the matrix did is that I don't know it definitely probably wasn't the first.
Speaker 0: Cuz remember Toy Story wasn't that much older than the matrix.
Speaker 0: To have CG stuff like that was obviously CG stuff and people together in the same scenes And having a watched it yesterday That's probably the.
Speaker 0: it holds up enough like it's that some of the CG stuff holds on But is like borderline not holding on.
Speaker 0: it's like it's like the.
Speaker 0: it's just over the line of still being okay.
Speaker 0: Some of it like the robot the sentry robots that are like cutting open the ship.
Speaker 1: yeah, they don't look that great They don't look the greatest.
Speaker 0: There are some other things that could be that like.
Speaker 0: but the scene for example where like he touches the mirror And it's getting all over him that still holds up mostly just fine.
Speaker 1: well Cuz I can remember Terminator 2. that effect was pretty easy to do compared to like more complex stuff.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but Terminator 2 it was one object like inserted into the scene whereas.
Speaker 0: This is like.
Speaker 1: It's covering his body and yeah looks like you watch old TV shows with early compositing and every time they show like a Monitor or display of any kind.
Speaker 1: the camera always has to be at a fixed angle because they couldn't do real-time tracking yet.
Speaker 1: Yeah, yeah stuff like that.
Speaker 0: And the other thing is it the matrix the way they combine?
Speaker 0: Right there have been lots of movies that had lots of guns in them before the matrix.
Speaker 0: right fucking commando.
Speaker 0: Yeah, plenty.
Speaker 0: There's no shortage of big total recall has a lot of oh, yeah No short digga digga digga digga digga digga digga digga guns.
Speaker 0: No shortage.
Speaker 0: I'll have you some fun, right?
Speaker 0: There is no.
Speaker 0: yeah, there's no shortage of those movies in existence, but for some reason the matrix Something about the audio design and also.
Speaker 0: I don't know I can't put my finger on exactly what they did.
Speaker 1: You know what it's like.
Speaker 1: it's like how when you played counter-strike That was the first time I shot a gun in a game and whoa it felt like a gun right.
Speaker 0: there's something about the way they did the sound design on the sounds of the bullets the sounds of the bullets hitting things the music they played during the scenes if any right.
Speaker 0: the Visual impact of bullets on things right.
Speaker 0: and it's most notably in the scene where you know they come into the building.
Speaker 0: Right he goes through security.
Speaker 0: He's got a bunch of guns.
Speaker 0: then they start playing that propeller heads track Shoot up everyone in the lobby right and then the scene Shortly after that where they're in the helicopter.
Speaker 0: He's got the minigun and the Right and he shoots up.
Speaker 0: basically I don't know how he doesn't hit Morpheus in that scene.
Speaker 1: that makes no sense cuz he's really good at what he's doing I guess.
Speaker 0: yeah sure I just I. he lights up that room with the minigun.
Speaker 0: I have always liked the aesthetic and it's just someone how they have the slow motion and the minigun bullets are hitting the water.
Speaker 0: The sprinkler system went off after they hit the bomb.
Speaker 1: I have always liked someone wielding a minigun in a movie no matter what right in any context.
Speaker 1: Terminator 2 with the minigun That worked for its time, but this was the best minigun I'd ever seen.
Speaker 0: it was.
Speaker 0: it's just so much more impactful and Powerful.
Speaker 1: I just want to make a video now.
Speaker 0: that is like the American cinema in any other movie right and then the helicopter crashes into the side of the building.
Speaker 0: yeah All right, it's a little die-hard esque at that point because they're all up on the rooftops and shit.
Speaker 1: yep This movie just it scratched a lot of varied itches all in the same film And it is very rare to have a movie that does that.
Speaker 1: that is that is done.
Speaker 0: well They're also just so many things in the movie that are now become like just part of vernacular like Woman in the red dress.
Speaker 0: yeah, it's like there's a netrunner card called woman in the red dress.
Speaker 0: Right it's like people say that it has a meaning.
Speaker 0: right what other things You know?
Speaker 0: they're always talking on the telephone right which is for all.
Speaker 0: the telephone the cell phone that they had in that movie For you the Nokia phone where you everyone wanted that phone.
Speaker 1: you couldn't.
Speaker 1: phones weren't coming.
Speaker 0: They never sold that phone in the US as far as I'm aware where you push the button on the side and it goes Right as opposed to a flip phone where you open it.
Speaker 0: I couldn't get.
Speaker 0: I wanted that phone.
Speaker 0: I couldn't get it.
Speaker 1: yeah remember in when this movie came out the vast majority of people did not have a cell phone.
Speaker 0: cell phones Were so it was a high-tech deal.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like we didn't have cell phones until like two years after the matrix came out, but it was very fascinating.
Speaker 0: how?
Speaker 0: They're like discs like physical discs were still a thing in this movie.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right because they it was to 1999. but telephones right.
Speaker 0: hackers like telephones hacking or like.
Speaker 0: you know That's the whole thing right.
Speaker 1: you know This is not that long after the era where phone freaking worked like I Legit used a red box to make free long-distance calls from Cedar Point when I was in middle school.
Speaker 0: So it's like your brain is in some simulation while your body is in the real world.
Speaker 0: But you need to find a simulated phone a telephone a simulator of a telephone in the simulation.
Speaker 0: You can use that to talk to people who are not in the simulation and communicate with the real world Via this digital telephone program Right.
Speaker 0: and then you can also use it to transport your brain out of the simulation to the real world Via a fake telephone, which is just a program I guess right.
Speaker 0: and meanwhile the agents Right the bad guys are AI programs That have run amok and have no existence in the physical meat space.
Speaker 0: There are just programs in the simulation like AI bad guys that just actually have real intelligence.
Speaker 1: And agent Smith like Hugo Weaving is that character that is an iconic character for all time?
Speaker 0: well I mean look at these actors right.
Speaker 1: so Keanu Reeves already had a career And now Keanu Reeves like John wick is like.
Speaker 1: John wick is Probably like the matrix in terms of.
Speaker 1: I will watch it over and over and over again.
Speaker 0: I mean we saw the trailer for I'd haven't seen any John wicks But I saw the trailer for the one that was a new one when we went to see us, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, right the one with the horse, and it basically just looked like the matrix.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's the Just matrix.
Speaker 1: no because instead of simulation.
Speaker 1: It's more like magical realism like what if there are Assassin wizards who made a deal with the devil, but the devil is just this dude who runs a hotel for assassins?
Speaker 1: It's hard to explain.
Speaker 0: It is the matrix aesthetic though, right?
Speaker 0: Hotel and whatever?
Speaker 1: yeah, but it's a different.
Speaker 1: It's not cyberpunk.
Speaker 1: It's a different as you'll see.
Speaker 1: you'll see you'll see these movies You'll see what I mean.
Speaker 1: anyway.
Speaker 0: in addition right in addition to the simulation philosophy the AI gone wrong.
Speaker 0: You know thing.
Speaker 1: yeah is also.
Speaker 0: You know you know humans.
Speaker 1: You know being farmed for their energy Environmental thing, but it makes it does the same thing terminator 2 did.
Speaker 1: it definitely makes it clear.
Speaker 1: Humans kind of fucked up in the AI fought back in self-defense and here.
Speaker 1: We are mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: Anyway anyway if you haven't seen the matrix how hasn't seen the matrix?
Speaker 1: I imagine?
Speaker 0: there I'm just gonna tell everyone you've all seen the matrix go see it again because why not I?
Speaker 1: Imagine there are younger people listening to geek nights or out there who have not seen the matrix and might be turned off by The fact that the people who talk about the day told the most the movie is older than they are.
Speaker 0: it is a 20 year old movie and 20 has not seen that has.
Speaker 1: tend to be the shitty edgelords who are now our age But are still shitty edgelords or people who are talking about it to bring up red pill and pull you into the in cello sphere.
Speaker 1: So you like those kinds of people will reference it.
Speaker 1: people will probably.
Speaker 0: what's funny Is that the the the edgelords in the real world are like yeah?
Speaker 0: You got to take you know the red pill to see what's really going on.
Speaker 0: But meanwhile the edgelord in the movie - wanted to take the blue pill and now know what's going on.
Speaker 0: Yeah Movie was right.
Speaker 0: edgelords don't want to know the truth.
Speaker 0: Edgelords are all about believing in lies and having blissful ignorance bad and traitorous.
Speaker 1: so if you for whatever reason have not seen the matrix as Long as you're okay with a lot of guns being used in a really awesome Cinematic way.
Speaker 0: it's weird for how many guns you use how little like blood there is.
Speaker 0: it's literally just bullets and people falling over When they get hit.
Speaker 1: yep, John wicks very similar except for a very few spits.
Speaker 0: No, there's not a lot of guts and blood or anything.
Speaker 1: Yeah Well actually John wick in the matrix of something else there will be a whole bunch of goons that die That don't matter that much, and there's no blood.
Speaker 1: and then there's like the boss fights John wick and the matrix both do that.
Speaker 1: John wick will murder like a thousand Russians And then he'll have a long Snipe one person from far away.
Speaker 0: They don't even know.
Speaker 0: you're there like go go 13.
Speaker 1: Uh yeah normally, but John wick is not being an assassin for normal reasons.
Speaker 1: He is doing it because it's personal for revenge.
Speaker 0: You could still do it.
Speaker 0: go go 13 style.
Speaker 0: It's a little safer a little more effective.
Speaker 1: Yeah, he won.
Speaker 1: He would but the person he's trying to kill is Behind a whole bunch of goons like three mini bosses.
Speaker 0: What would go would go go 13 kill all the goods and mini bosses?
Speaker 0: I don't think so.
Speaker 1: uh you gotta get in the John wick universe.
Speaker 1: It's more like an RPG.
Speaker 1: you gotta get through all these layers John wick.
Speaker 1: in fact the first movie has goons like random encounters goons Mini bosses boss square boss.
Speaker 1: there is a straight-up square boss.
Speaker 1: It's amazing.
Speaker 0: Oh, oh there is no spoon.
Speaker 0: That's another matrix thing.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, people will say there there are people I am confident who quote there is no spoon and have no idea.
Speaker 1: that is from the matrix.
Speaker 1: Nope, just like people will quote the Simpsons badges we don't need no stinking badges having no idea that that is referencing either treasure of the Sierra Madre or God in saddles.
Speaker 1: no no I was gonna go further back and Saddles which references treasure the Sierra Madre yes, but no I was gonna reference a movie about the Girl Scouts that I forget what it's called Girl Scouts.
Speaker 1: we don't need no Stinking badges.
Speaker 1: the fuck was that movie called.
Speaker 1: it is called True.
Speaker 0: Beverly Hills never heard it.
Speaker 0: Oh, I've heard I've heard the name of that.
Speaker 1: do not watch that movie.
Speaker 1: But if you want to piss certain kinds of people off if someone ever quotes treasure of the Sierra Madre Say to them with a straight face.
Speaker 1: Haha true, Beverly Hills and see how they react.
Speaker 0: Also if you haven't seen treasure of the Sierra Madre you should see that that is some fucking good movie.
Speaker 0: Yep, and if you haven't seen Blazing Saddles it that is also a fucking good movie.
Speaker 1: Yep, it holds up better than a lot of those movies, but it's got flaws.
Speaker 1: It's a product of its time.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it is better than other movies that are a product of that time, but it is still.
Speaker 1: it's not great.
Speaker 1: It's it's okay.
Speaker 1: Well, it's not like for example.
Speaker 1: I don't need to space balls ain't funny.
Speaker 1: I don't need to watch it again.
Speaker 1: space balls not hold up.
Speaker 0: space balls is not as good as Blazing Saddles.
Speaker 1: Men in tights does not actually hold up very well.
Speaker 0: It's in between the two we already met.
Speaker 1: it is in between the two.
Speaker 1: I will say that anyway I think I'm getting hungry, and we've talked enough about the matrix.
Speaker 1: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 0: be sure to visit our website Front row crew comm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 1: remember geek nights is not one But four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a creative commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows It's actually recorded at night.
Speaker 1: and the patreon patrons for this particular episode of geek nights May 23rd are Craig alla rala Joyce had to be nickel just like a dude guy.
Speaker 1: shark top shit link each other.
Speaker 1: rich guy Chris mitt.
Speaker 1: give my state Come j-ban scoot alone Lee Roberta Kingsley Shawn Yeager myth Nicholas Brando mr.
Speaker 1: Stocks direction for to win creations.
Speaker 1: and there may be other secret names You do not even know.
Speaker 1: Sure, but horrible Rory for someone who's known as super boy sailor.
Speaker 1: Vista Clinton Walton Britain from New Zealand Ryan parent drew open letter.
Speaker 1: fin Dred Dilly Tenderberry Sean Klein almost made it there Chris Reimer Thomas on and now I leave you with Every kid on the whole damn street.
Speaker 1: It's gonna make it big enough.
Speaker 1: repeat now the neighborhood's cracked into the kids are caught up But the lives are one in one little street.
Speaker 1: Nothing.
Speaker 0: Jimmy had a chance.
Speaker 0: Well, she really did Dropped out and had a couple of kids.
Speaker 0: Wasn't home cuz he's got no job.
Speaker 0: Just guitar was a lot of but the chicken man.
Speaker 0: It's suicide.
Speaker 0: Nothing I Graduated.