Speaker 1: It's Monday August 5th 2019.
Speaker 1: I'm random Scott and this is geek nights tonight USBC the connector to finally rule them all.
Speaker 0: for now sort of Let's do this.
Speaker 1: You know in geek nights We have a story tradition of.
Speaker 1: you know We have a very regular format over these last 14 or so years of.
Speaker 1: we do an opening bit where we talk about our lives Then we do the news then we do a thing at the day and then I've met a moment in a main bit We have this whole thing.
Speaker 1: So my only question is which one of us should do our opening bit first today?
Speaker 0: It don't matter.
Speaker 1: You don't matter.
Speaker 0: What is it?
Speaker 0: Who cares?
Speaker 1: All right, so I was at work today.
Speaker 1: do my normal thing around 11 Like I do.
Speaker 1: I went to go have my daily poop because I am hyper regular.
Speaker 1: now that I'm in my 30s 11 seems to be the time.
Speaker 0: most dudes poop and dude, I guess you couldn't get a stall cuz everyone's poop.
Speaker 0: I don't know cuz I know the secret because basically you go to a floor no one's poop.
Speaker 1: There are only three stalls in each bathroom like in the bathrooms on each lot one of them you put a pair of shoes Up until the 16th floor is the floor I'm on but 17 18 19 20 21 and 22.
Speaker 1: Daddy, like eight stalls you go up a flight of stairs I go up one flight and I'd like it pretty easy and if I really am desperate I go up to 22.
Speaker 1: No one thinks to go up to 22 22 is an awesome floor.
Speaker 0: No one.
Speaker 1: on 22 There's a small office up there for like certain things like.
Speaker 0: there's like a million stalls and only one desk and there's two.
Speaker 1: it's it Basically, it's the floor with the big conference room for like big outside events.
Speaker 0: So if there isn't an event, there's like no one.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there's no one up there.
Speaker 1: so I can like go out on the balcony.
Speaker 1: It's real.
Speaker 1: I can see the skyline I just hang out up there.
Speaker 1: It's awesome.
Speaker 1: But sometimes I go up there and there's a whole bunch of people and I can't poop.
Speaker 0: Yeah, having a party.
Speaker 1: So I have my poop like I do and I played like for nourishing my hexes during it.
Speaker 0: You trying out those new armies?
Speaker 1: No, they're not in the app yet.
Speaker 1: Oh, okay.
Speaker 1: I was in the app trying to figure out how to buy them and I couldn't figure it out.
Speaker 1: Okay I don't think you can so email and I got a flush but like a good person who's worried about his health and careful.
Speaker 1: I turn around and look before I flush as your poop just like green.
Speaker 1: So my work yellow.
Speaker 1: It was green orange.
Speaker 1: It was the bright.
Speaker 1: it looked like Green neon highlighter and like just taking the inside out and dropped it in like a lie.
Speaker 0: You ate some kind of thing.
Speaker 0: So I thought to myself what vegetable did you eat?
Speaker 1: So I thought to myself I have never seen a color that stark before.
Speaker 0: Let's take a photo of your poop.
Speaker 1: No, I didn't even take a photo.
Speaker 1: So I thought on it for a second because I know that green poop is like a bile thing.
Speaker 1: But I look it wasn't.
Speaker 1: that kind of color was way too bright, but I remembered last night.
Speaker 0: You ate a highlighter.
Speaker 1: We went to Ice and Vice the fancy ice cream place.
Speaker 0: You had some food coloring in your ice cream.
Speaker 1: Their cones Have food coloring in them and I remembered back to not digestible food coloring.
Speaker 1: last time I went there and I had a similar incident and I realized that that is the problem.
Speaker 1: the last time I went there I had a pink cone and the next day when I pooped it looked like I Thought I was bleeding to death for a second.
Speaker 0: You should I remember email them and be like, hey your food coloring Makes me poop the color.
Speaker 1: I should be like, hey, you could put a little less food coloring in these cones.
Speaker 0: You could warn people about it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't know.
Speaker 1: I have an extreme ice cream warning on the door.
Speaker 1: So what do you got?
Speaker 1: is your thing today?
Speaker 1: Hopefully not also poop related.
Speaker 0: No, so Someone posted on the internet about you know, some some science.
Speaker 0: so signed up to do the science.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah Yeah that thing.
Speaker 0: so basically Someone at Columbia is researching the associations between like air pollution biking to work You know cardio Whatever
Speaker 1: makes sense because on one hand you want to do a lot of cardio But on the other hand like especially in a city doing a lot of cardio every day means some days the air is really bad Right,
Speaker 0: so basically
Speaker 1: more pollution.
Speaker 0: So yes.
Speaker 0: Anyway, I signed up to go do this study, you know, help them out Cuz it's of interest to me.
Speaker 0: It's not the kind where they pay you.
Speaker 0: So apparently you only really get paid for Scientific studies and a. they got a lot of grant money and they're having a hard time finding people to do it for free.
Speaker 0: I got paid at RIT once yeah, and B they do it you.
Speaker 0: they usually pay people when you're like you're doing something risky, right?
Speaker 0: It's like take this experimental medicine and it's like we'll give you money.
Speaker 0: All right
Speaker 1: I remember one of my RIT professors talking about how he did a study where they paid him like a hundred bucks Which in the 70s, that's
Speaker 0: a lot of money,
Speaker 1: but the study was Drink a whole bunch of alcohol and then inhale mercury vapor and see how much mercury vapor gets into your blood.
Speaker 0: Yeah Yeah, okay anyway, so I went up there and they gave me a whole bunch of sensors and shit So that they gave me.
Speaker 0: the first thing they gave me are these two.
Speaker 0: I have them over here.
Speaker 0: I had to carry them around so I had to do it six times.
Speaker 0: So basically six 24-hour periods over three weeks, but not consecutively Not on consecutive days.
Speaker 0: So I had to do basically two days a week for three weeks But not two days in a row ever.
Speaker 0: All right, and I got a bike to work on those days.
Speaker 0: Otherwise is you know, what's the point right?
Speaker 0: So they gave me two different kinds of air pollution sensor things They gave me.
Speaker 0: is I got to carry them around and they're just always drinking the air I guess.
Speaker 0: and then they gave me this hexo skin shirt Which is like a undershirt thing and it has a little data recorder.
Speaker 1: Oh, it will it catch your log respiration rate and all that it has.
Speaker 0: basically it's like an easy G situation with three contact points.
Speaker 1: Oh, so it's not doing the chest expansion thing.
Speaker 0: and also it has these two hex Strips that go around my entire body and I guess they can tell when I'm my body is stretching And they use that to measure how much air I've worn.
Speaker 1: I've worn one of those something very similar before right because I guess they do some cut.
Speaker 0: she's like, yeah, you do some volume Right.
Speaker 0: It's like if your chest expands this much that means this much air came out.
Speaker 0: and if the air pollution is this much That means you breathe in this many particles.
Speaker 1: Things I know because I've done a bunch of medical things with those that kind of equipment before and I've been thinking about buying One of those strap sensors, I don't need the EKG nonsense, but I like the respiration sensor
Speaker 0: anyway, so cuz
Speaker 1: I'm trying to train more seriously in the running.
Speaker 0: and then Basically a blood pressure monitor that you can like wear and it checks your blood pressure periodically just on its own.
Speaker 0: And then she's like do you want to take this extra thing?
Speaker 0: It's like you don't have to and it was basically this thing some dude in Belgium made.
Speaker 0: So the dude in Belgium wants it's like a separate study, but it's related.
Speaker 0: So it's like you can do both at once.
Speaker 0: He wants to know about if there's a relation between like noise and air pollution like yeah It's noisier.
Speaker 0: then that means there's more cars and shits is more pollution, right?
Speaker 0: So he basically I'm pretty sure it's an Arduino in a box.
Speaker 0: But yeah as far as I'm concerned It's just a box and I just tie the box to my bike and plug it in when I ride and that's it.
Speaker 0: So I'm just gonna carry this shit around six times and then I don't have to go back to stupid Columbia.
Speaker 0: I they're just gonna come and get the stuff.
Speaker 0: I don't have to go back there.
Speaker 1: I'm glad you're doing this cuz I have a vested interest in the results of this kind of research, right?
Speaker 0: So we're gonna find out.
Speaker 0: it's like well, you know you bike to work.
Speaker 0: Oh so healthy, but you breathe in all this poison.
Speaker 0: if you were in a car that has filters on its air intakes.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I wouldn't breathe the poison.
Speaker 1: you would just poison everyone And it'll probably figure like what's the balance between?
Speaker 1: yes, the pollution is bad for you But the exercise is better for you than the pollution is right.
Speaker 0: It's like my blood pressure like worse when I'm biking in a bad place.
Speaker 1: Well kind of like.
Speaker 0: I also have to use Strava and send her my struggle files.
Speaker 1: Oh, no You saw Strava had a big outage the other day.
Speaker 0: I didn't notice they were.
Speaker 1: basically if you went into the app and had a big banner that was like yo We know we're having problems.
Speaker 1: Stop read.
Speaker 1: Stop restarting the app over and over again.
Speaker 1: It's just making things worse.
Speaker 1: We're gonna fix it.
Speaker 1: Just give us time.
Speaker 1: Seriously, calm down kids.
Speaker 0: You shouldn't tell people just fix it.
Speaker 1: Don't look as if they were trying to fix it.
Speaker 1: But apparently people kept saying oh my runs aren't sinking.
Speaker 1: and they kept like yeah Well, that's tough shit.
Speaker 0: Just make sure that shouldn't affect whether you make it work or not.
Speaker 0: Yeah, just go to your firewall and block everybody until you fix your shit.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean, I agree.
Speaker 0: as a product manager If it's down you might as well just block them having time out.
Speaker 1: Yep Also Strava unlike say a real work thing not that important if it's down for a little while.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's not the end of the world It's not.
Speaker 1: it's not a Sev one at the data center.
Speaker 0: if I was the boss of Strava and they're like Strava is down Oh my god, I'd be like, yeah, well, you know, it's like.
Speaker 0: worst case, you know, don't work on the weekend.
Speaker 0: Worst case all the premium people.
Speaker 0: we can just you know, refund them for the weekends worth of money, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, give them some sort of bonus fake feature.
Speaker 0: Yeah, everyone gets a free month If you're if you're a premium buy whatever pays for that because I it doesn't do any.
Speaker 0: I don't know any feature.
Speaker 0: It's on the premium that I does as I feel I need to pay for.
Speaker 1: it has a safety feature that I don't really need.
Speaker 0: What do you mean?
Speaker 0: safety feature?
Speaker 1: so you can basically list other Strava users and like people as your contacts and you can tell it.
Speaker 1: I'm going for a run and I want my friends to track me and it'll tell all of them where you are.
Speaker 1: the whole time It has like a panic button seems not necessary.
Speaker 1: I could.
Speaker 1: there are use cases for that.
Speaker 0: I have other apps to do that like Google trusted contact.
Speaker 1: Yeah There are there uses for that.
Speaker 1: people who do serious overland hiking people are at risk of assault.
Speaker 1: No, I can see.
Speaker 1: but again it worries me.
Speaker 0: Strava is not the app for that is what I'm saying.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but it's a feature and a whole bunch of this analysis stuff.
Speaker 1: That just seems silly.
Speaker 0: There's some people who are like super like.
Speaker 0: that's.
Speaker 0: their main thing is tracking the data on their body.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I am like they're getting home and they're spread sheeting their body daily.
Speaker 1: I mean, I collect all this data But I don't look at it except in like the most abstract aggregate of like.
Speaker 1: am I getting faster or slower?
Speaker 1: over time How am I?
Speaker 1: how am I doing?
Speaker 1: is my 5k time actually getting worse?
Speaker 0: got faster, but you got older and it evened out.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't need an app to tell me that.
Speaker 1: so in the news this story Escalated rapidly and I think it's worth the time to unpack this because a lot of people don't understand how any of this works.
Speaker 1: So back it all the way up.
Speaker 1: There is a website filled with the most the second most vile people on earth called 8chan.
Speaker 1: 8chan is not 4chan.
Speaker 1: Yeah, because it's twice as shitty.
Speaker 1: That's the best way to think of it.
Speaker 1: the higher the number the shittier the place Like.
Speaker 0: I feel like if you're 8chan would people get banned from 4chan?
Speaker 0: I mean literally.
Speaker 0: 8chan didn't even ban anything.
Speaker 1: 8chan was formed by this gamer Gator dude, basically Who now who is since as vile as that dude is he has actually come out today and said that he disavows 8chan.
Speaker 1: It was a mistake.
Speaker 1: shut it down.
Speaker 1: It is dangerous.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: So even that shitty gamer game That's pretty the only thing that really amazes me these days when someone changes their mind.
Speaker 0: No, they didn't change his mind.
Speaker 0: It's the vile people who somehow have a line.
Speaker 1: Yeah 4chan pretty vile, but they had a line that their line was like this person.
Speaker 0: It's like they.
Speaker 0: they're racist They don't unracist right?
Speaker 0: It's like, you know, they're.
Speaker 0: they're like, they're all these bad things.
Speaker 0: They're misogynist and they don't they don't turn they don't change their ways They still agree with all those bad things, but then somehow at some point they're like that's too far bro, and it's like Well, are you gonna be a good person?
Speaker 0: No, I just draw the line at this much badness.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's the only person that surprises me ever.
Speaker 0: Is that person?
Speaker 0: But does that person exist?
Speaker 0: he's right there a chain guy.
Speaker 1: so basically 4chan Didn't have a lot of rules, but they banned furries for cultural and internet reasons, whatever.
Speaker 1: They banned pedophilia You know porn you don't say and they banned gamer gate.
Speaker 1: Those are the only things that they banned.
Speaker 1: and those people were so affronted that they made a chance.
Speaker 0: Sorry, didn't go to H.
Speaker 1: No the furries Everyone else went to HN.
Speaker 1: the bad people went to HN.
Speaker 1: So HN is there and it's awful.
Speaker 1: and Three of the more recent like mass murderers in the world posted their manifestos to HN.
Speaker 1: And if you actually go to HN Which I do not recommend you do you will find some of the most vile Hate speech and incitement to violence the world has ever seen.
Speaker 1: Yeah, these are bad people.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't know why we just don't go, you know round up everyone on HN.
Speaker 1: The pro move would have been if HN was just a long-running honeypot.
Speaker 0: Just swap them for the immigrants.
Speaker 1: Just The only place worse than HN is gab.
Speaker 0: Gab.
Speaker 0: Gab is just HN reddit, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, Gab is like HN.
Speaker 1: reddit slash Twitter.
Speaker 0: It's a site that's like reddit, but it's you know for bad people that the kind that would go to HN.
Speaker 1: Yeah, imagine the kind of content that even Twitter who won't ban anyone Practically would ban.
Speaker 1: they go to gab and HN.
Speaker 1: So HN only was able to exist because Cloudflare Provided services to them like DDoS protection.
Speaker 0: You don't know right?
Speaker 1: It's all load balance.
Speaker 0: So Cloudflare is a company that's been around for a while and they made their name In the back in the day because what would happen is certain sites good or bad would get DOS or DDoS.
Speaker 0: Yep, and there is a difference a big difference Yeah, but the point is their site would go down and they did not have enough money to say You know do a Google does and run a huge worldwide network of servers.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that are invincible and you know have a huge IT staff, you know, maybe you just got your WordPress blog But you got an awesome article that's getting really popular.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and it's spreading like wildfire.
Speaker 0: Maybe you got slash dotted or something, right?
Speaker 0: And it's not spreading a good message.
Speaker 0: But you you know, you got so much traffic you're down or because you're a good person The hate people are taking you down or you might not even it might.
Speaker 1: you just might have a lot of traffic and it's not Even a DDoS.
Speaker 0: you just you're just one person.
Speaker 0: you can't handle that.
Speaker 0: You can't handle the architecture of that nature for your use case.
Speaker 1: But if you have wizards working for you like between IP table There's a lot of stuff you can do on servers to mitigate that up to a point, but there's a limit, right?
Speaker 0: So Cloudflare what they do is they provide basically a CDN but also other stuff and the way it works.
Speaker 1: CDN is content distribution network.
Speaker 1: in case you have no idea what we're talking about you point your DNS Right you.
Speaker 0: basically Cloudflare becomes your DNS provider.
Speaker 0: Yep, and I'm actually use them.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's free.
Speaker 0: And you go there and you say okay for a front row crew calm The IP address is X and you tell them right.
Speaker 0: and now you tell your registrar where you bought the domain.
Speaker 0: Hey for DNS use Cloudflare and then you're all good.
Speaker 0: And what you do is in the list of DNS the entries on Cloudflare.
Speaker 0: They have these little icons.
Speaker 0: you click and you have two options an arrow going around a cloud or an arrow going through a cloud.
Speaker 0: So an arrow going around the cloud means anyone visiting front row crew calm will go directly.
Speaker 0: their web browser Will send its easy VIP request boom directly to your web server wherever it is.
Speaker 0: line ode Oz.
Speaker 1: very useful for example.
Speaker 1: Front end verse back end like as a content creator.
Speaker 1: I am doing a lot of things.
Speaker 0: I don't need this cloud protection for right and if you click the icon to go through the cloud What what will happen is when their web browser says what's the IP address of front row?
Speaker 0: crew calm?
Speaker 0: It'll actually give you an IP address for some Cloudflare server.
Speaker 0: The HTTP request will go to the Cloudflare server.
Speaker 0: the Cloudflare server will then go to your real server.
Speaker 0: Get the copy of your web page and then cache it and then send it and the next person who comes visiting It's probably gonna see a cached version.
Speaker 0: mostly You've probably seen times where people's like servers go down and you'll get like the Cloudflare error page.
Speaker 0: It's like oh, yeah, we didn't.
Speaker 0: we don't have a recent version of this web page and they went down You know because maybe they stopped paying for their odds or whatever.
Speaker 0: So also in addition to providing that sort of caching CDN kind of stuff They also provide just all this sort of attack protection.
Speaker 0: and way it works is since they have so many Customers and clients and and you know things they see.
Speaker 1: every kind of attack under the Sun and DDoS is hard to stop if you're the target by yourself.
Speaker 1: But if you have the data of all the other attacks around right?
Speaker 0: It's like let's say rims got a website and I got a website and someone attacks rims website with some lame-o attack.
Speaker 0: Yeah, Cloudflare sees that attack.
Speaker 0: They write a you know, some kind of rule to block it usually a simple heuristic rule like from the package themselves.
Speaker 1: You can figure out if they're malicious.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like oh there's an evil server over there and then suddenly every other Cloudflare customer Everyone else using Cloudflare is now protected from that exact same attack.
Speaker 0: So and they save all these over time forever It just if you use Cloudflare, you're protected from like an insane number of attacks.
Speaker 0: It's it actually really works.
Speaker 0: It's super legit.
Speaker 0: the people who work there regardless of your opinion of other decisions they've made which we're gonna discuss right now.
Speaker 0: Yeah, their technology is Excellent and competent.
Speaker 0: I think we've actually they.
Speaker 0: When there's an internet outage.
Speaker 0: recently They wrote the article about why it was out and remember we talked about how they were blaming some provider in Pennsylvania or something.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that was Cloudflare doing that because their internet engineering is good.
Speaker 1: now in terms of ethics The problem with Cloudflare is that they have taken a very extreme free speech position almost extreme.
Speaker 0: They have a line just short of the most extreme free and their line was the Daily Stormer and now 8chan, right?
Speaker 0: So Daily Stormer is the first thing to ever get kicked off.
Speaker 1: Do not Google Daily Stormer.
Speaker 0: It's just a Nazi newspaper Yeah, but it's nothing I know about.
Speaker 1: it's the Nazi newspaper, right?
Speaker 0: That's like I didn't know.
Speaker 0: so they after being on Cloudflare for quite some time Cloudflare kicked it off and after a massive public protest That was and that was our.
Speaker 0: that was a news on geek nights because it was like the CEOs Decision to override their policy and they made a big deal about how reluctant they were to do it.
Speaker 1: Speech right just as aside cuz I don't want to talk about that in this episode, but fuck that.
Speaker 1: Free speech for everyone but Nazis.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's very easy Yeah, sure, but they.
Speaker 0: So now 8chan.
Speaker 0: it took them this long to decide.
Speaker 0: it took no one not two But three mass murders three mass murder manifestos in 8chan and Cloudflare decided that was enough.
Speaker 0: and they're like, yeah They're sort of leaning a little bit more away from the extreme free speech being like, yeah, we're private We don't have to you know, recognize free speech here Yeah, but we try to.
Speaker 0: and there you know what, even though they took down 8chan good job Cloudflare.
Speaker 0: There are still plenty of hate sites that they're that are customers that they have not gotten rid of.
Speaker 0: yep, and I took a sweet long as time to get rid of the two that they have gotten rid of.
Speaker 1: and I generally want Technology providers to be agnostic to content.
Speaker 1: But again, there's that you can make a very clear line on certain kinds of.
Speaker 0: I think it's like people argue the slippery slope Right.
Speaker 0: They're like, oh first the Nazis then the furries then it's like we could just stop it.
Speaker 0: not good It's like.
Speaker 0: it's like yeah, maybe they'll go down the slippery slope But maybe they won't.
Speaker 0: so wait until they ban something that you're actually against before you yell at them.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right It's like yeah, if they ban some perfectly, you know good site tomorrow, then I'll Yeah.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so cloud flare good and bad.
Speaker 1: So cloud flare kick them out Yep, but as everyone expected cloud flare, they even said something.
Speaker 1: the effect of the problem is the problem isn't with 8chan The problem is with America.
Speaker 1: They're gonna find another provider.
Speaker 0: guys daily stormer did find another place to get hosted and so Tor and dark web which we talked about.
Speaker 1: so daily stormer and and now 8chan But only temporarily.
Speaker 1: they found a new service.
Speaker 1: There's a service called bit mitigate.
Speaker 0: Well, why are you sharing the name?
Speaker 1: I'm not gonna link to them because it's gonna be talked about in this article.
Speaker 1: But this is kind of important because bit mitigate is basically Kind of like how 8chan was formed with the people banned from 4chan.
Speaker 1: bit mitigate is formed with the people banned from cloud Similar technology to what cloud flare does and they basically focus on the worst people on earth.
Speaker 0: It's an inferior product, but it's not.
Speaker 0: you know, I guess it works, right and Works well enough.
Speaker 1: So bit mitigate now was hosting daily stormer as far as I can or like doing protection.
Speaker 1: Well, you have to hosting in a second for daily stormer and 8chan was my migrating over there and they were gonna be fine.
Speaker 0: I don't know why the other like hate sites.
Speaker 0: don't just like, you know, go right away.
Speaker 0: It's like they stay with cloud for as long as they can.
Speaker 1: cloud flares free.
Speaker 1: I don't think that mitigate is free.
Speaker 1: I mean think if you it makes like being the IT guy for the mob if you're the DDoS Protector for the Nazis You're gonna charge a premium to be like the arms dealer to these shitty people share any by an AK's on the black marketing.
Speaker 0: So when this?
Speaker 0: so when this happened, it's like well the bit mitigate which I guess is owned by some company.
Speaker 1: Oh the rabbit hole gets deep.
Speaker 1: you gotta read article.
Speaker 0: So, you know It's owned by some other company.
Speaker 0: and I was like and I said when we were discussing that when the news had reached that point Of like yeah, they're going to this company.
Speaker 0: I was like, well that company is still hosting their service somewhere like a data center.
Speaker 0: I doubt they have their own data center.
Speaker 0: so we could call the data center and let them know and the data center could fire them as a customer.
Speaker 0: and even if they Have their own data center.
Speaker 0: We can go to the data center, right?
Speaker 0: You know, you could do something about the town.
Speaker 0: you get them to cut the electricity off.
Speaker 0: It's like, you know, that's the avenue to attack this now, right?
Speaker 0: Especially once all the bad people are in one basket like that, right?
Speaker 0: but as it turns out They weren't using their own data center.
Speaker 0: They were in some data center box.
Speaker 0: ility is Silly.
Speaker 1: they're just an infrastructure as a service provider.
Speaker 1: There's a lot of them.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they're just a data center.
Speaker 1: somewhere turns out.
Speaker 1: bitmitigate Uses them as their outsource infrastructure.
Speaker 0: They don't own their own computers, which I thought would be pretty rare if they did.
Speaker 1: Yeah, very few people own their own and voxility was not in on this game.
Speaker 0: So voxility is just like yeah fire you as a customer get the hell out of here.
Speaker 1: voxility basically said quote.
Speaker 1: We provide services to ISPs and hosting resellers and as a telco we do not have access to websites hosted by Customers of our customers.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: We cannot deal with the websites directly But we are now working on removing this reseller from the network.
Speaker 1: So basically once people figured out that bitmitigate was hosted on voxility Voxility said fuck this and just kicked him out.
Speaker 1: Yeah so right now you can.
Speaker 0: you can always keep figuring out like For them to avoid the only only by using the dark web and like hosting in their houses, but that's fine dark web Not discoverable by the average Nazi.
Speaker 0: It's like how to host yourself.
Speaker 0: You need a ton of money to have your own data center.
Speaker 0: You'd have to get someone to agree to like link your data center to the internet, right?
Speaker 0: It's like at some point you have to do something with someone.
Speaker 0: It's a network.
Speaker 1: You have to get someone to agree to network with you and if you piss everybody else off you're you're not on the internet You're just your own little net.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so that's so.
Speaker 1: Voxility did the right thing and the rabbit.
Speaker 1: so now as of like Dateline right now live doing this show at like 6 45 p.m on August 5th.
Speaker 1: Daily Stormer and a Chan are just down.
Speaker 1: good like they're not.
Speaker 1: I think
Speaker 0: what we need people to do is we need to find Because I don't know how to find them and I want to look at them right the other hate sites that are say on cloud Flare still and be like hey cloud where you ever to they change ever to this - yeah Hey get rid of this -
Speaker 1: we're gonna make a slippery slope for Nazis.
Speaker 0: Yeah, just and just down at the bottom of the slope is Nazis.
Speaker 0: everything else lower on the slope stays.
Speaker 1: So bid mitigate which is already like shitty was sold to epic with a K.
Speaker 0: He pik not the not fortnight.
Speaker 1: Yeah epic with a K is basically the hosting provider for them.
Speaker 1: all the vile speech on earth at this point like they own all the shitty shit and They own gab.
Speaker 1: Gab is the thing we talked about earlier.
Speaker 1: gab is where all the people to vial for Twitter and read it ended up.
Speaker 1: So now we got.
Speaker 1: basically we need to go after.
Speaker 1: epic as a whole like that company needs to be deplatformed Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: So in some related news Where's the other piece here?
Speaker 1: There's.
Speaker 1: there's a related thing we can go after.
Speaker 0: So it turns out that Breitbart which is vile but not a chain vial It's just one step less vile and bright parts been mostly deplatformed.
Speaker 0: It's also a place I would never go never read and if anyone did read it, I would never speak to them again.
Speaker 0: Bright bar, it's still very very very vile.
Speaker 1: and info wars similarly vile.
Speaker 1: very related info wars and bright Bart have been largely deplatformed by a lot of the big providers but a lot of their revenue comes from Advertising.
Speaker 0: I thought it comes from selling bullshit and selling bullshit.
Speaker 1: Okay turns out Amazon provides the storefront to sell the bullshit and Amazon is actually the one of the largest Advertisers on bright part.
Speaker 0: Well, Amazon is one of those people that I don't even know where they're advertising, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, literally just type some code into your site and now Amazon's running.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So same as Google I would recommend all of you to direct your rage at Amazon and get them to stop Letting Breitbart be a part of their ad network.
Speaker 0: go protest at your local Whole Foods.
Speaker 0: So you got some news, yeah, so You know this always sorts of sort of goes down, you know every once in a while where there's the Apple rumors And then they turn out to be true.
Speaker 0: usually, right?
Speaker 0: So If you don't know by now every September used to be when it iPod season because there's back to school and When the iPod died and it became iPhones September is iPhone season.
Speaker 0: they announced new iPhones in September.
Speaker 0: They well, they announced the new Iowa.
Speaker 1: Oh, I gotta back up a little.
Speaker 1: voxility cut service to epic comm is all.
Speaker 1: epic is down.
Speaker 1: Okay, epic bit mitigate.
Speaker 0: Anyway, whatever.
Speaker 0: so the Apple rumors, right.
Speaker 0: so WWDC in the spring ish times is when they announce the new iOS and what features it'll have Which are inevitably gonna be on the new iPhone.
Speaker 0: and then that new iOS comes out.
Speaker 0: when the new iPhone comes out in they announce It September October right.
Speaker 0: and there's usually that's around the time back to school new phones new iOS.
Speaker 0: It has been that way for every year since like two that more than ten years.
Speaker 0: this way.
Speaker 0: It's not a surprise guys every single year as if iPhone one was 2007 It has been September October every year since then.
Speaker 0: do not be surprised by this.
Speaker 0: Don't be like.
Speaker 0: go when a new iPhones coming fucking September Never October you can't mess this one up guys.
Speaker 0: All right, so And there's always rumors and people are like, you never know.
Speaker 0: those rumors can be true But actually as it turns out for the past many years like maybe I don't know 10 fucking years The rumors always turn out to be like 80% true.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and it's usually because of things like Leaks at factories Photos of cases because people have to have to get iPhone cases in the store at the same day as the iPhone.
Speaker 0: So they tell these third-party accessory makers what the iPhones are gonna be shaped like and stuff and they make cases in advance.
Speaker 0: Right all this stuff comes out day one and even if Apple itself and their developers and their engineers are super tight There are leaks.
Speaker 0: I saw a leak.
Speaker 0: someone was taking a picture of a Samsung phone and leaking the Samsung phone.
Speaker 0: They took a picture of the Samsung phone with the new unreleased iPhone XR equivalent like iPhone XR 2 or whatever and you can see a reflection of the back of that phone in the front of the New Samsung phone.
Speaker 0: Ah, perhaps that was intentional.
Speaker 0: Perhaps that was you know, and it's like.
Speaker 0: I mean That was faked.
Speaker 0: But actually in my experience I see things like that every year and it often turns out They're like almost always exactly right.
Speaker 1: Well, plus go all the way back to the famous Teapot for sale, right?
Speaker 0: So the new iPhones.
Speaker 0: the biggest thing people are gonna notice visually about them Is that on the back almost all the leaked pictures show a giant square like three cameras like several camera lenses in it.
Speaker 0: We're not we're beyond daddy to lens now.
Speaker 0: It's like, you know, since they can't have some mock three, right?
Speaker 0: Well, they can't have a mechanical Zoom that's an optical zoom.
Speaker 0: That's actually has a motor that Vertical traversal right that requires moving parts, which they really don't want in a phone, right?
Speaker 0: So as a result, we get on phones several lenses and they're still really amazing cameras, but better than most cameras.
Speaker 0: You'll buy separately.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but still that's the thing.
Speaker 0: But the main thing you got to know about iPhones this year is that Apple bought Intel's modem business?
Speaker 0: There was all this crazy.
Speaker 1: Oh, I forgot about that.
Speaker 0: There's all sorts of crazy shenanigans going on with Apple Qualcomm Modem licensing all these patents for modems right radios and shit, right?
Speaker 0: You can read about that on your own separately.
Speaker 0: Just look for like Apple Qualcomm lawsuit modems radios, whatever.
Speaker 0: But the only real other major company that made you know modem radios for you know, cell phones is Intel making 5g radios and Intel's like getting out of that business.
Speaker 0: So Apple bought part of that business to make their own goddamn radios to try to fuck Qualcomm Putting Qualcomm shit in their phone.
Speaker 0: so they can get away from that nonsense.
Speaker 0: Right because pretty much it's Qualcomm is making the only good radios and it's not that no one else could.
Speaker 0: it's patents.
Speaker 0: Mostly you're locking that one in.
Speaker 0: Yeah so The I thinking was that what was gonna happen?
Speaker 0: was it next year?
Speaker 0: 2021 would be when iPhones all had 5g radios.
Speaker 0: But as it turns out it looks like this year.
Speaker 0: they say they're all gonna have 5g radios in them.
Speaker 0: So if you're hankering from a certain five G's and you live in a 5g place maybe you could buy a new iPhone this year, but The other rumor that's probably true is that the iPhones this year aren't really gonna be a big upgrade from the iPhones last year.
Speaker 0: All right, they're not gonna be that different.
Speaker 0: So the ones in 2021 are gonna be a huge upgrade.
Speaker 0: most notably You might remember a few years ago Apple really wanted to do the fingerprint sensor for unlocking the phone But they didn't want to have that button at the bottom of the screen.
Speaker 0: So what they did is they removed the button and they couldn't get the fingerprint sensor to work when it was behind the actual Screen, so what they did instead is they put the notch up top with the face unlock Right and the face unlock is okay.
Speaker 0: But Apple still really wants the fingerprint sensor behind the screen Because that means they can get rid of the notch and have a phone That is a hundred percent screen on the front and it looks like in 2021.
Speaker 1: Now I'm still fine with phones that just put the fingerprint sensor as a swipe on the side But I guess Apple doesn't want you to swipe.
Speaker 0: They want you to just put your finger there.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like magic that swipe is no good because there's too much user stuff going on.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's not the Apple way.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so it looks like 2021 is gonna be the iPhone that has Not only fingerprint sensor behind the screen a hundred percent screen on the front of the phone and 5g But also most importantly the rumor is that the iPhone from this year 29 not 2021 2020 20 still 2019 Subtracting
Speaker 1: yourself subtract
Speaker 0: a year from all the years.
Speaker 0: I said the 2019 phone will be a minor upgrade.
Speaker 0: 2020 will be a big upgrade.
Speaker 0: the 2019 phone despite being all this other stuff is supposedly gonna have all still lightning cables.
Speaker 0: And supposedly the 2020 phone the major upgrade might finally go to USB C which we're gonna talk about in real soon.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so my plan as of now and there is also some talk that they are gonna make small phone because middle sized phone Doesn't sell.
Speaker 0: well people want big voter small phone.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and I'm and this is something most interesting because small phone might come out this year.
Speaker 0: But I'll probably wait and I'll get the 2020 small iPhone That's a hundred percent screen to finally replace the iPhone 7 and hold on to that phone for ever.
Speaker 1: if they Actually release a small iPhone that's small enough.
Speaker 1: I'll probably switch when the last of my Xperia compacts dies.
Speaker 0: It's not gonna be that small.
Speaker 1: Yeah We'll see how small it actually is.
Speaker 1: Yeah, because right now it's not gonna be iPhone 5 small.
Speaker 1: I don't think I still hold in my hand.
Speaker 1: the Sony xz1 compact is literally the last small Android phone.
Speaker 0: Hey, Amanda, I got the pixel 3a.
Speaker 0: It's way good.
Speaker 0: It's not.
Speaker 0: it's not as small as that but also not waterproof.
Speaker 1: I don't think I think it is.
Speaker 1: Is it fully waterproof?
Speaker 1: like take a picture in the pool?
Speaker 0: I don't fucking know.
Speaker 1: because this is I don't know.
Speaker 0: but the point is If I had to get an Android phone, I would get that phone.
Speaker 1: I've you know what I did.
Speaker 0: I wouldn't get Android, you know, my next Android phone is.
Speaker 1: I actually own another one of this For the next two or three years at least.
Speaker 1: unless they make a small iPhone that'll switch.
Speaker 1: because I Have a smartwatch after the pebble died.
Speaker 1: There really aren't good Android smartwatches like every sound.
Speaker 0: that Apple watch is the only smartwatch worth of shit I have a lot.
Speaker 0: if I was an iOS with Apple watch I would just go back to what I did before of no watch.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I kind of did.
Speaker 1: I stopped were in my LG.
Speaker 0: Apple watch is the only smartwatch worth of shit except since pebble died and the Apple I watch still Wallets great.
Speaker 1: It has still like very deep flaws like what a battery doesn't just last two weeks Last a whole day.
Speaker 0: Yeah More than a day unless you do something stupid like run Strava directly on it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know.
Speaker 0: in which case like for example I use Strava on my watch and I went to summer streets and I biked around for several hours and came home.
Speaker 0: and the what?
Speaker 0: I brought no phone with me.
Speaker 0: The watch was doing all the GPS all the Strava all the upload all and if you're not aware of this out there GPS like to actually do.
Speaker 1: GPS takes a ton of power right?
Speaker 0: my watch has LTE in it So it was a phone at the same.
Speaker 0: it was a phone and when I got home 40% battery left after several hours and a tiny watch.
Speaker 0: that's pretty fucking good with the color screen and all the stuff it does.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: can't complain about the battery life in the Apple.
Speaker 0: I yep, so charge it when you sleep and you.
Speaker 0: I've never had it.
Speaker 0: I've never had it run out ever.
Speaker 1: So supposedly the next round of fossil Android wear watches for their fossil.
Speaker 0: I guess they'll be stylish at least.
Speaker 1: the might also be expensive Yeah, but they will have battery lives that are up to five or six days Depending it's all rumors.
Speaker 0: We don't see how much is it gonna do though?
Speaker 0: One Strava directly on it doesn't have LTE like a phone.
Speaker 0: Is it like it's not doing all the stuff Apple watches do and then you can't really directly compare that battery life, you know It's like pebble lasted battery life forever because it didn't have the kind of you know, oh, you know fancy screen
Speaker 1: Me the most that that the pebble style screen
Speaker 0: didn't have the features that Apple watch I
Speaker 1: think is still the an appropriate screen.
Speaker 1: I agree for for a while.
Speaker 1: buy an Apple watch with that kind of screen and all other features the same because you don't need a watch to Do that much and frankly most of the fancy features people are trying to make watches do.
Speaker 1: They're not that good at because it's not really the right form factor.
Speaker 0: Well, it is Depending on which feet which feature you're talking about?
Speaker 1: Well true, but I I think the most useful features of a watch are just getting notifications Apple wedding timers The Apple watch getting directions while you're traveling somewhere.
Speaker 0: Apple watch does way way way more than the pebble watch does way better than it Ever did.
Speaker 0: so you're you know, it's what you're paying.
Speaker 0: You're paying the money and the battery life in exchange for the power.
Speaker 1: So what I'm waiting to see is of all I've been watching the Android watch space for a while and they're all kind of garbage Right, and this is the first time I've seen an Android that might not be garbage.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think my feeling is if you know if you're not Apple with I with an Apple watch, right?
Speaker 1: Just get a fit and only know it for fitting.
Speaker 0: get either no watch at all.
Speaker 0: I just look at your phone like I did for years.
Speaker 0: It was fine or Get just the cheap, but you know the Casio the regular cat the LG style no fairly works.
Speaker 1: It's like 80 bucks.
Speaker 1: now.
Speaker 0: today just get the regular Casio digital watch.
Speaker 0: That's just a watch and a stopwatch and doesn't?
Speaker 0: it is just no normal ass watch for $5 But there's no doesn't do any smart anything.
Speaker 1: I would never want a watch that tell the telling.
Speaker 1: the time is not what I use a watch for.
Speaker 0: no But the all it saves you though It's like you remember.
Speaker 0: the goal is to not have to take your phone out of your pocket, right?
Speaker 0: So half the time I take my phone in my pocket is to see Notifications and half the time I take it into my pocket is to see what time it is.
Speaker 0: So if I couldn't get a good watch for notifications like an Apple watch at least I could get the cheapo Casio Digital watch and reduce half the time.
Speaker 0: I take my phone out of my pot.
Speaker 0: I've always kind of hate for like $10.
Speaker 1: in the old before there were smartwatches or smartphones or cell phones I hated the idea of wearing a watch.
Speaker 0: I preferred pocket watches for the sole reason that so that you could say so you could be that person who has a pocket.
Speaker 1: No, it was specifically.
Speaker 1: I had this very particular philosophy I need to be able to know what time it is, but I don't want to constantly know what time it is.
Speaker 0: Don't fucking look at your watch.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but it's right there.
Speaker 1: You might just see it.
Speaker 0: My Apple watch is blank unless I look at it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, my watch is also blank until I'd like shake it and look at it or I get a notification.
Speaker 0: the point is anyway, this might be the first like almost usable baby's first Android smartwatch that isn't garbage since the pebble and anyone who like You know has like a Rolex and it wasn't just like the only one you have and it was grandpa's or something.
Speaker 0: Yeah get in line for the guillotine.
Speaker 1: But anyway, it looks like it's time for things of the day.
Speaker 0: What the fuck was my thing of the day?
Speaker 0: Oh, I remember now.
Speaker 0: Yeah So Gen Con just happened and we are not fans of Gen Con.
Speaker 0: Gen
Speaker 1: Con is poorly run and I would never attend it as a guest unless they change a lot of their policies
Speaker 0: despite I mean Gen Con has good policies and bad policies But despite the convention organization itself and the things that they do wrong Good people go to Gen Con and good games happen there and there are Positives to going there that have nothing to do with the con.
Speaker 0: I mean if you get some of the you know There's like really good stuff happening because good people are there playing good games, right?
Speaker 0: And that's not Gen Con's fault nor you know, or nor will I hold it against them anyway, so Because of that there are lots and lots of gaming tweets coming from Gen Con and I was getting a lot of good stuff for Those.
Speaker 1: Lord I have the issue of Dragon magazine where you're thinking of the day was reviewed.
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 0: So One thing I discovered that I did not know existed before thanks to Some you know tweets from Gen Con is I would have saved this for Tuesday, but it's too good.
Speaker 0: The official this is a real thing a hundred percent real thing right Made by published by TSR in 1988.
Speaker 0: So I was six years old now an official RPG.
Speaker 0: That is the Rock Bullwinkle and Rocky role-playing party game.
Speaker 1: Oh, there is officially Officially licensed.
Speaker 0: This is a real.
Speaker 1: you see what it can what it what it entails.
Speaker 1: like you look at this.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, this puppets in there.
Speaker 1: Yeah, ten.
Speaker 1: this comes with nineteen Six spinners two spinners to know she dinners ten hand puppets.
Speaker 0: Yep, they're barely any rules.
Speaker 1: I remember talking to Jared at length years ago, like we should make an RPG that comes with puppets.
Speaker 1: Uh-huh.
Speaker 0: The game was designed Right.
Speaker 0: Oh shit by David Cook Who?
Speaker 0: I don't know who that is.
Speaker 0: and war inspector like Deus Ex system shock thief war inspector Ultima underworld war inspector.
Speaker 0: Right that war inspector worked on this game.
Speaker 0: who the hell is David Cook, let's look them up.
Speaker 1: You don't know who David Cook is.
Speaker 0: some TSR, dude.
Speaker 1: Yep, that's all you need to know.
Speaker 0: He's some TSR dude some TSR dude and war inspector a person who actually know who they are.
Speaker 0: Right, they made this rocky and Bullwinkle RPG.
Speaker 0: Basically, the rules are so loose and sparse.
Speaker 0: It barely qualifies.
Speaker 0: That's what it says in Wikipedia.
Speaker 0: But yeah, apparently it is an amazing awesome card-based tabletop RPG.
Speaker 0: I want to play it because I love Rocky and Bullwinkle.
Speaker 1: I'm scrolling through.
Speaker 1: I have a PDF of that dragon magazine?
Speaker 0: because I you don't have a PDF of the Rocky and Bullwinkle Role-playing party game.
Speaker 1: No, but there's a review of that game in this dragon magazine.
Speaker 0: I mean the dragon magazine is published by TSR.
Speaker 0: Yes, like reading Nintendo Power to get a review of Mario.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 1: Yes Exactly, okay Actually, I'm just scrolling.
Speaker 0: dragon magazine was published by TSR, right?
Speaker 1: Uh Pretty sure was?
Speaker 1: I don't actually know a lot of the history of Dragon.
Speaker 1: amazing.
Speaker 1: All I know is that I had.
Speaker 0: I'm pretty sure it was but let me check just so I don't make it.
Speaker 0: I said so.
Speaker 1: I also yep Company TSR.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I was right.
Speaker 1: I subscribed.
Speaker 1: like my family We subscribed to Nintendo Power from issue one.
Speaker 1: We pre subscribed.
Speaker 1: We got the first Nintendo Power.
Speaker 0: I subscribed to very early game pro up until I was in college.
Speaker 0: Then I cancel game pro like after freshman.
Speaker 1: my mom keeps threatening to send me all my dragon magazines and all my Nintendo Powers.
Speaker 0: Okay, let's take them to like, you know, I mean, I don't know like RPG library.
Speaker 0: But actually they would probably take them that RPG library.
Speaker 0: That's a PAX West.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, I'll take your dragon magazines.
Speaker 1: I think I think I already have a lot of dragon magazines.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but why?
Speaker 0: they'll take a full set you want like Several hundred dragon magazines.
Speaker 0: somebody will.
Speaker 0: there is a good home for them.
Speaker 0: I gave my game pro magazines.
Speaker 0: I looked on Craigslist and when we lived in beacon, I remember that Teacher who lived nearby who wanted to cut him up for arts and crafts class.
Speaker 0: that I said go nuts I can just get PDFs of these online.
Speaker 0: I Don't need the physical ones taking a space in my apartment.
Speaker 1: So my thing today is real brief.
Speaker 1: I didn't want to use a cuz.
Speaker 1: lately a lot of our things that they have been tweets Or very short YouTube videos things of the day are finding are hard to come by in a dark world.
Speaker 1: Yep Also, we've set the bar a little high in the sense that things that might have been like good enough to be a thing of The day back in 2010
Speaker 0: I raised the bar with my good things of the day and then you were embarrassed with your bad things of the day.
Speaker 0: now You're trying to.
Speaker 0: you know, I'd love to see.
Speaker 1: we still need to do the thing of the day off.
Speaker 0: I think they are.
Speaker 1: we just need to.
Speaker 0: you cannot win the thing.
Speaker 1: We need to bring our top ten things of the day of all time and get the listener Things of the day that we've already used as things of the day.
Speaker 1: Yeah You go back and we each bring to the table.
Speaker 1: Well We think our own personal 10 best and we let the listener decide which one of us based on that set of 20 Truly is the king of the things of the day.
Speaker 1: All right, that'll be a fun show to do someday.
Speaker 1: But so this is an article from a blog of going medieval that I read occasionally.
Speaker 1: I bump into it every now and then and it's just like fun explorations of how you don't know shit about the Middle Ages.
Speaker 0: No, cuz it was dark and there wasn't a lot of recorded history.
Speaker 1: No, no, it's actually there's a lot of recorded history.
Speaker 1: But most people just when they imagine the word like medieval times a castle and peasants They imagine shit covered peasants like marching to war against other shit covered peasants.
Speaker 1: Well Knights on horses ride behind them and take a all those castles and crap.
Speaker 1: But a common misconception of the medieval time watery tarts flinging swords And the Middle Ages is that people didn't bathe and this is a pretty direct explanation of it.
Speaker 1: Not only did medieval people bathe, but they fucking loved taking baths.
Speaker 0: Yeah Cuz everything's so fucking filthy.
Speaker 0: you will take in a bath and it goes in if you get all slimy and sweaty After a whole weekend of biking and the shower truck broke down when you get home and shower Baby.
Speaker 0: so you worked in the fields all day.
Speaker 0: Yeah You know harvesting whatever the fuck potatoes for some night.
Speaker 0: who had a castle that protected you?
Speaker 0: No, the night nobleman swerve and you finally get some free time with your family And there's like a is a pond and you can go in that pond and babe.
Speaker 1: It's like the best Peasant coming through like you can even tell yep But not only could meet evil bathe but the point the meta point this article makes is great.
Speaker 0: Rome came first in.
Speaker 0: Rome had bathhouse.
Speaker 0: They had bathing technology.
Speaker 1: But you asked the average person like who is dirtier?
Speaker 1: the Roman like people constantly talk about how medieval people dirty.
Speaker 1: in Rome You had bath houses, but this article points out Romans bathed primarily with oil and did not have modern soap.
Speaker 1: fucking medieval people invented soap.
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 1: So this article is pretty good.
Speaker 0: I mean, I mean a lot of.
Speaker 0: today.
Speaker 0: a lot of people are using oil for soap.
Speaker 0: Yeah, good use soap or soap with oil in it, which is fine do not the?
Speaker 1: Depending on the era of Rome and those times a common way to bathe was to basically Douse yourself in olive oil and then scrape it off with a shell or a stick.
Speaker 0: That is pretty good It's okay feels good though.
Speaker 1: It does not de-stinkify.
Speaker 0: However, but how it makes you smell like olive.
Speaker 1: But oh, I can't find there's a link from this article To tell why I like this blog that gets into the history of nofap November and why it is mostly Promoted by vile people, okay It's surprisingly related to the concept of medieval bathing.
Speaker 0: interesting.
Speaker 1: Yeah In the meta moment the econized book a book is the first novel.
Speaker 0: the tale of Genji the first novel ever Written by humans ever is still available for you to read.
Speaker 0: So why wouldn't you read it before reading any other novel?
Speaker 0: you gonna start with volume one?
Speaker 1: Yep We'll be live at PAX West 2019 with two panels one of which if you've seen it before neither of which got cancelled.
Speaker 1: We we We have our flaws yet.
Speaker 1: We have our flaws.
Speaker 1: We could get kids but we are above the line of being banned from packs for being shitty.
Speaker 0: Thank God.
Speaker 1: So on Friday and Saturday, you can see us.
Speaker 1: live and stay tuned because we're already making our plans.
Speaker 1: Pax south badges went on sale.
Speaker 1: We will definitely be there.
Speaker 1: packs unplugged is coming up.
Speaker 1: We will be there.
Speaker 1: pack season begins as soon as summer ends and we will be there.
Speaker 0: Beach Beach Beach Beach Beach Beach Beach packs.
Speaker 0: That's my life, yep, my life is the same except in the After after bike Beach bike beat by beach starting packs hockey starting.
Speaker 1: after packs You throw a ski in there ski ski ski mixed in with hockey and packs.
Speaker 0: That's that's the life everybody.
Speaker 1: I feel like we need to add one mid like one winter beach.
Speaker 0: Why don't we just add some Civil War in there?
Speaker 1: As in start a civil war.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean finish it As flip as that comment was.
Speaker 1: it is far too important and real and serious and I actually do agree.
Speaker 1: But let's get into the main bit.
Speaker 1: So we are not going to get into the deep technical specifications of USB because we don't fucking know.
Speaker 1: that's why and I'm gonna say I know a lot about all USB both the cabling standards the signaling standards everything up until USB to USB 3.
Speaker 1: I know enough because it matters.
Speaker 1: and now USB is at the point to where you don't need to know unless you work in the hardware.
Speaker 0: We did do an episode before about USB in general, but USB C wasn't a thing then.
Speaker 0: so let me set you straight.
Speaker 0: Just real summary right now.
Speaker 0: There's two different things to got to worry about.
Speaker 0: There's USB ABC letters and there's USB 1 2 3 numbers.
Speaker 0: They are Disconnected.
Speaker 0: you could have USB A and B cable right with a on one and B on the other.
Speaker 0: that's talking about the shape of The cable.
Speaker 1: well that's talking about the shape and the wires.
Speaker 1: answer right and you can have a to a.
Speaker 0: yes Yes, micro a to me doing the summary not the details.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I wouldn't.
Speaker 0: letters are about the cable.
Speaker 0: What does the cable look like?
Speaker 0: where does it plug into?
Speaker 0: what wires are inside?
Speaker 0: right the numbers are about?
Speaker 0: What's going over the cable?
Speaker 0: right if it's a USB 1 cable that ain't doing shit for you in 2019?
Speaker 0: Yeah, a USB 2 cable is carrying USB 2 speeds with USB 2 devices Right USB 3 with the blue inside to let you know that you can plug in.
Speaker 1: you know your high speed devices on that line Even though a fun fact almost every device you use is using USB 2 even if it's on a 3 almost everything is still using 2.
Speaker 0: so USB C is a new cable shape.
Speaker 0: you've probably seen it cuz it's really advancing quite quickly.
Speaker 0: You know most desktop motherboards these days have at least one or two on there.
Speaker 0: Yeah, new MacBooks only have them.
Speaker 0: They just got two on each side.
Speaker 0: That's it.
Speaker 1: Yeah Nintendo my computer which I built a while ago already has one USB C on the back.
Speaker 0: Nintendo Switch has one on the bottom.
Speaker 0: most Newphones that aren't Apple phones with lightning had all this to have them on the bottom.
Speaker 1: I love always does this.
Speaker 0: we're gonna do a cable.
Speaker 0: new iPads have it on the bottom.
Speaker 0: right.
Speaker 0: apples Put it on everything except for iPhones which have lightning.
Speaker 0: everything else.
Speaker 0: everything else at Apple has USB C now.
Speaker 0: So it's a different cable shape.
Speaker 0: It looks like sort of like a hamburger patty.
Speaker 0: It's just flat on the top and bottom and round on the sides.
Speaker 1: I guess I can see that.
Speaker 1: That's not how I would have described.
Speaker 0: you describe it I don't know a cylinder that got hammered from both sides.
Speaker 1: I guess I would just describe it as a pancake.
Speaker 1: Oh, I know a wide oval wide oval.
Speaker 0: It's flat on top and bottom and runs on a blade shape anyway.
Speaker 0: It's the best part about it is it goes in both ways.
Speaker 0: yep swings both ways everybody because no more Four-dimensional USB cables.
Speaker 0: you put it in it doesn't go.
Speaker 1: I don't have to take off my belt anymore to explain Turn it around it doesn't go.
Speaker 0: you turn it around a third time now.
Speaker 0: If it's no you see just goes in.
Speaker 0: it goes in very quite securely.
Speaker 0: like I can put a USB C cable in and like swing My phone around a little bit and be not my phone.
Speaker 0: But you know get.
Speaker 0: you can swing a device around and be kind of confident.
Speaker 0: It's not gonna like become detached and fall off unless you know you it's pretty secure connection there right.
Speaker 1: yep Here's the other very important thing about it Micro USB which up until recently has been the standard.
Speaker 1: like.
Speaker 1: the only things that use mini USB are Old old old thing or cheap things or a full-size USB b-side Shitty old printers and scanners.
Speaker 1: pretty much it yeah.
Speaker 0: But micro USB is what a lot of phones were using before USB C and my old devices.
Speaker 1: extremely good for the time.
Speaker 1: But it had one very and only goes in one way which?
Speaker 0: but it was fine because I was a real cheap and flimsy.
Speaker 1: I would know that actually that's not.
Speaker 1: it was not flimsy nor was it cheap.
Speaker 1: That was the problem because the USB micro connector has moving parts.
Speaker 1: it requires these Springs and these little teeth to make it work and those are great, but that means those cables wear out.
Speaker 0: Yeah They're not great.
Speaker 1: There was a time a few years ago where like a lot of people all at once started randomly complaining about like cables breaking.
Speaker 1: That's just because those cables have a limited number of insertions before they fail.
Speaker 0: And why do we even need micro and mini USB?
Speaker 0: because regular USB was too big.
Speaker 0: think about a regular USB cable for your computer Like that your mouse has.
Speaker 0: hey you have a phone with that kind of pole on.
Speaker 0: it's an enormous fucking phone.
Speaker 1: It was that's the a-side the b-side of full-size USB that goes in your scanner.
Speaker 1: It's a square that is literally thicker than my thick ass.
Speaker 1: Android phone.
Speaker 0: right.
Speaker 0: so the best thing.
Speaker 0: another thing My USB C. Is that it's so small.
Speaker 0: We you can use it on desktop Phone.
Speaker 0: we don't need big and small.
Speaker 0: It's just one size.
Speaker 0: It's small enough.
Speaker 0: already every device whether it's a giant desktop or a TV or a tiny phone or like a headphone that needs to be recharged can All just use normal USB C. We don't need a micro version.
Speaker 1: so here are the other two important things about the physicality Point number one it.
Speaker 1: the two sides the cable are also the same.
Speaker 0: You don't need an a-side and a b-side you can just use either side for a or B. So if you when we have printers and scanners and all these things finally switch to USB C You won't need to get some weird cable.
Speaker 0: That's like as a big one on one side or anything like that.
Speaker 0: You'll just every cable will just be the same USB C thing on both fucking sides.
Speaker 0: end of story.
Speaker 0: No more muss and fuss.
Speaker 1: now there are a side and b-side pin layouts.
Speaker 1: But you don't need to worry about that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the devices will just figure out like oh, I'm on the a-side perp.
Speaker 0: I'm on the b-side perp.
Speaker 1: Yep Because the cables have a bunch of pins.
Speaker 1: The pins are all shielded and wired in such a way to where they can do the things they're intended for.
Speaker 1: I don't want to get into why you twist cables and why you have cable pairs.
Speaker 1: We talked about that in the episode we did about ethernet a long long time.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that USB C has so many wires in it.
Speaker 0: It has so many features on those wires and it can reuse the different wires for different things based on what's going on.
Speaker 1: Here's some examples.
Speaker 1: You can just put DisplayPort like over USB C.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you don't need DisplayPort cables.
Speaker 0: There's no reason you couldn't just make a computer that has only USB C in the back and like nothing else like the.
Speaker 0: instead of a HDMI and DisplayPort output just a USB C and you plug a cable into your monitor.
Speaker 0: There you go, but the video signals going over the USB C cable Thunderbolt fine, whatever.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and a log audio.
Speaker 1: It'll actually just use the USB 2 pairs because it has some pins that are just to be used for USB 2 support.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I actually use that.
Speaker 0: so like my for example, my iPad has USB C on the bottom and this is Apple No headphone jack.
Speaker 0: There's a little adapter you can get from Apple but you can get a third-party one as USB C on one end and headphone hole on the other end and It's not some special thing.
Speaker 0: It doesn't really need a chip.
Speaker 0: the iPad just knows.
Speaker 0: Oh, there's a headphone being plugged in and over those wires It sends ground, you know left audio channel right audio channel And then the microphone one on the.
Speaker 0: you know, cuz TRS right tip ring ring sleeve.
Speaker 0: That's four things Yep, four pins.
Speaker 0: So and then it just it's this analog audio coming out of the digital USB C hole.
Speaker 0: That's normally digital and then it goes right into your normal analog headphones.
Speaker 0: And there you go.
Speaker 0: You're listening to music with a headphone jack, even though it's plugged into USB C hole.
Speaker 0: You could actually have a computer.
Speaker 0: your desktop could go without sound card.
Speaker 0: theoretically, right?
Speaker 0: It would just need a digital analog converter and you could plug headphones into the USB C hole on your computer.
Speaker 0: Theoretically if someone made that work with the right drivers and shit.
Speaker 1: Yep so a step back a little bit.
Speaker 1: USB stands for universal serial bus because in the old days the idea was Get a million different cables like the ps2.
Speaker 0: There was a lot of parallel ones, which is why you need serial ones.
Speaker 0: They refer to our USB episode and skip this entire section of rim reiterating it
Speaker 1: No, no, but the point I want to get at is that While you every time USB could have been the one connector and cable to rule them all there were always these niche use cases.
Speaker 1: like you old USB you couldn't send like Streaming data over it.
Speaker 0: It wasn't fast enough.
Speaker 1: It wasn't fast enough didn't have enough cables and it wasn't real time.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so bit by bit.
Speaker 1: you always needed USB could cover a lot of cases But you still needed firewire.
Speaker 0: It was just for like mice keyboard 56k external motors external USB sticks without a really slow.
Speaker 0: It's like as time went on they made them faster without changing the connector and then more and more use cases came up where it's like Oh, you can have external stuff now doing this.
Speaker 1: yep, but along the way material science got better and we started needing a DC power plug standard because almost every device you use Uses DC and AC is what comes out of the holes.
Speaker 1: Yeah in your house.
Speaker 0: Yep in America Yeah, and most of the world pretty much everywhere.
Speaker 1: No nowhere has just DC to the house.
Speaker 0: I mean, oh, there's some signs and there are some places where like they have DC power lined up.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like in data centers on boss bar.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that kind of stuff.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'd not in your house.
Speaker 0: Someone's house.
Speaker 1: No, someone's house.
Speaker 1: miss some horrible nerd who's probably there's probably a burnt skeleton.
Speaker 0: I'm googling house with DC power.
Speaker 1: I've seen nerds try to make stuff like that.
Speaker 1: It's not a good idea.
Speaker 1: Someone's ass, but We're fine.
Speaker 1: now that USB sort of became the powering standard.
Speaker 1: We're very close to the point with USB C where we literally will have one cable to rule them All.
Speaker 1: the only cable we need to destroy is the lightning cable.
Speaker 1: Yeah, because lightning can just go over USB C cable, right?
Speaker 0: The only thing that's using lightning cables is iPhones And some things and some peripherals that early adopters mistakenly bought.
Speaker 0: Well, there are some iPhone accessories that use lightning like.
Speaker 0: I think there's like beats.
Speaker 0: I had beats headphones once and you had to recharge them with lightning because they they were meant to be used.
Speaker 0: with the iPhones.
Speaker 0: They're like, oh you got an iPhone you got.
Speaker 0: use lightning to charge this headphone to.
Speaker 0: Anyway, yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah USB C is finally one cable one shape.
Speaker 0: You can run anything over the cable you can run, you know your mouse keyboard your phone You're just plug your monitor in high back plug your cam.
Speaker 0: all my can't like cameras.
Speaker 0: now I'll have USB C to transfer a 4k video off the camera.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you could live stream video over it's if you depending on what protocol you're using.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and because the one cable you can use so many protocols even though it's USB C You could use USB 2.0 over USB C USB 3.0 USB 3.2 Thunderbolt.
Speaker 1: second We're not gonna go long on this but a part of the value of the USB C cable is that it supports USB 3.1 which is Really fast.
Speaker 0: There are USB 3.1 that you could use with the old USB 3.0 blue A/B cable
Speaker 1: But
Speaker 0: you can get USB 3.2 like mega speeds over USB C cables like insane speeds like several gigabits at the point and that's actually a huge difference because Up until now the fastest thing you could really plug into your computer.
Speaker 0: That wasn't internal was like something like eSATA.
Speaker 0: maybe right or You know net your network would be one gigabit.
Speaker 1: My last computer had a bunch of eSATA cables and did.
Speaker 1: those were not commonly right?
Speaker 1: He said is killed by USB C because he said like SATA is not a resilient protocol for a long cable to connect to.
Speaker 0: no No, but now it's like well if I got a NAS Why would I plug?
Speaker 0: if I got you know external hard drives right in a NAS in a raid?
Speaker 0: Why would I connect them over the network at one gigabit onto my network?
Speaker 0: When I could just plug them in directly to my computer with USB C yep, that's way faster than one gigabit.
Speaker 0: and then it used the network sharing on my computer if I wanted other computers than the Network to be able to access the.
Speaker 1: we talked about this back when we were doing the NAS job.
Speaker 1: They're due to the NAS and a DAS network tech sort attached storage versus disk attached storage or direct attached storage.
Speaker 1: But if you're like using a workstation to edit like giant 8k videos Yeah You plug a giant sand directly into that computer instead of having hard drives in the computer.
Speaker 0: So the final thing that I want to say about USB C that's so great having this one cable.
Speaker 0: Is that all of the things around the cable are?
Speaker 0: Super super standardized to even right now more than you would realize.
Speaker 0: for example, I bought a little thing yeah, and on one end of it was USB C and on the other end was Female USB C so that you could get some charging power to whatever device you were playing this into right?
Speaker 0: USB 3 B the square shape.
Speaker 0: so that's like a little hub in case you wanted to plug something else in and an HDMI port.
Speaker 0: So what you would use this for would be you would plug the USB C end into your iPad.
Speaker 0: You would then connect another USB C cable to keep your iPad charging.
Speaker 0: You could then maybe plug in like a USB mouse or keyboard into your iPad or something like that on the USB C You know B hole, right?
Speaker 0: and Then you can plug in HDMI cable to get HDMI output from the iPad.
Speaker 0: and now you're using like your iPad Connected to an external monitor or a TV or you're streaming what it's showing on your iPad or something like that.
Speaker 0: Now the
Speaker 1: original USB spec the old one handled this kinda yeah, but it was called USB on the go and because of the direction of the cables and everything the end result was if You weren't extremely careful about what you plugged in and how you plugged it in stuff would just get fried.
Speaker 0: But anyway, I bought this little adapter like about 15 bucks.
Speaker 0: Oh, and it lets me do all that stuff.
Speaker 0: plug into the bottom of the iPad.
Speaker 0: I also have a Nintendo switch and sometimes you don't want to carry your switch dock around with you But I take the same exact adapter.
Speaker 0: I didn't buy another different adapter.
Speaker 0: I plug the USB C into the bottom of the Nintendo switch and then I can plug my you know use actually to charge a Switch pro controller.
Speaker 0: the cable they give you is USB B on one end and C on the other end.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you plug that in and you can now charge your Nintendo A on one ends not B.
Speaker 1: Nothing uses a and it doesn't use this B anymore.
Speaker 0: Anyway, it's the rights of the regular old rectangle.
Speaker 0: That's a that's the a1.
Speaker 0: It was the big one.
Speaker 1: a is the big normal one anyway.
Speaker 0: so Then you plug an HDMI cable to get the video out from your switch to your TV Because you don't want to carry a switch dock, right?
Speaker 0: The only thing is the switch itself is just annoying and that the switches has a special program.
Speaker 0: It's looking specifically for the official legitimate made by Nintendo AC adapter Which is literally just two prongs that go in the wall and USB C on the other end.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so you have to bring your you as your official Nintendo AC adapter with you But you plug that USB C and into this adapter to charge your switch while the HDMI is coming out and lo and behold The switch will.
Speaker 0: now happily doesn't?
Speaker 0: it will think that that thing is basically your Nintendo switch dock.
Speaker 0: Nintendo switch docks cost a fortune.
Speaker 0: this thing costs like 15 20 bucks now and it works with my iPad.
Speaker 0: Also, it's the same standard USB C to HDMI the same exact everything and
Speaker 1: if you're not trying to play video out of it And use it while you're charged like if you just want to charge it any old like the same thing that charges my phone charges The switch.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's.
Speaker 0: you can actually charge other things with the switch.
Speaker 1: I charged my switch from the the anchor battery I carry with myself.
Speaker 0: Yes, it's only when you want your switch to do video out that it demands the official AC adapter.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you.
Speaker 0: otherwise you could just take like your Samsung phone charger That's USB C and plug it into the bottom Nintendo switch and it charges just fine.
Speaker 0: It's like USB C. is that standardized across?
Speaker 0: iPad Samsung phone and tend to switch any other thing USB C. You will be shocked at how compatible and how feature right.
Speaker 0: a MacBook Pro has USB C on the side.
Speaker 0: You can take the charger for that shove it in the bottom Nintendo switch charging.
Speaker 0: It's working
Speaker 1: and it's because that all the people involved have done and all the standards bodies and all the manufacturers have done a lot of work to make USB C Just work without you having to know with all the old USB and all the other cables up at this point.
Speaker 1: You had to know things to make weird stuff happen.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you're gonna be shocked if soon as you get more and more USB C stuff You're gonna want to throw away every key.
Speaker 0: everything you have is not USB C.
Speaker 1: example DisplayPort.
Speaker 1: fuck those cables.
Speaker 1: Remember, those are the cables that will literally ruin your video card or monitor if they're made wrong.
Speaker 1: And most of them are made wrong.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: The cable itself is a danger.
Speaker 1: USB-c you're pretty much good.
Speaker 1: However, only by name-brand USB cables and HDMI.
Speaker 0: It's like one HDMI cable.
Speaker 0: It's like, you know, not great.
Speaker 0: Yeah, actually when you start getting into super high-res Situations USB C. It's like boom.
Speaker 0: Let me see that 4k 8k video wall.
Speaker 0: Let's go Yep.
Speaker 1: Now there is a little nuance to the cables that I don't really want to get into Know.
Speaker 0: it now.
Speaker 0: Someone else can read it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I need to read it for them, but it comes down to the fact that the cables have chips in them.
Speaker 1: now Yep, which if you open up like any converter display stuff, there is a lot of logic in cable.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's thing.
Speaker 0: I was just talking about this.
Speaker 0: like USB C to HDMI probably has a whole computer in it Yep, like a processor and everything and RAM, you know, yep, and even though it's 15 $20 USB-c cables may or may not have support for certain like weird advanced function.
Speaker 0: It's possible that like if you get el cheapo USB C cable that you were using to charge like some.
Speaker 0: I don't know your Bicycle light which my current bicycle lights right now use micro USB C, but I'm micro USB, but I'm sure in the future They'll be USB C.
Speaker 1: But here's where it'll matter some.
Speaker 0: some cable that comes with the light that you use to charge your you know You used to charge your bicycle light is probably not gonna work if you try to send 4k video.
Speaker 1: Here is where it'll matter to you.
Speaker 1: Here's the practical reason why you'll need to know this a little bit.
Speaker 1: USB-c cables can only be about two meters long.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there are many cases where you want a really really long USB cable.
Speaker 1: It's not gonna work, right?
Speaker 1: Usually for video output a really really long USB 3 cable is also not gonna work now Like the one long USB cable I have for that oculus sensor up there.
Speaker 1: That is like the maximum length.
Speaker 1: They're gonna be like the light.
Speaker 0: the length you need is the length to plug it in next to your bed.
Speaker 0: I'm where your night.
Speaker 0: your USB thing is by your night I don't know, but here's why I hold your phone in bed while it charges.
Speaker 0: That's how long you need it to be.
Speaker 1: USB C cables cannot be more than two meters.
Speaker 0: Okay, that's wrong.
Speaker 0: Also two meters is pretty long.
Speaker 1: However, if you you can get USB C cables that are longer.
Speaker 1: There's a. there's a spec accounts for having a really long cable up to four meters.
Speaker 1: He can double the length.
Speaker 0: that is hella long.
Speaker 0: But your if your entertainment system is more than four meters from your TV and your stereo No Whatever it needs to be dams or rearrange your room and all that means is that those?
Speaker 1: USB-c cables will only support USB 2.0 speeds and will not support weird alternate modes.
Speaker 1: So if you use a USB C cable to plug into your des And you use a graph four meter cable.
Speaker 1: It won't work.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's that's really the only cable problem.
Speaker 0: Why is your dad's four meters from your computer?
Speaker 1: Yeah Right, seriously, so I look forward to the death of lightning.
Speaker 0: I look forward to the death of every data cable and Powering small devices that have their own batteries.
Speaker 0: cable.
Speaker 0: Yeah It's not shaped with USB C on both ends because right now Most of the cables I have are actually regularly old USB on one end and USB C on the other because like my anchor Charging hub doesn't have isn't five USB C's it's.
Speaker 1: yeah, I want to get to the point where I just want to start replacing a lot of like I want to put in all My power outlets are on the house.
Speaker 0: Oh, I forgot.
Speaker 0: one more thing you can do is the cave.
Speaker 0: you get a cable that's USB C on both ends.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you'd be shocked what you can do with that.
Speaker 0: I don't cuz I can plug your devices.
Speaker 1: They just they work it.
Speaker 0: I can connect for example my you know micro four-thirds You know Panasonic gh5.
Speaker 0: Plug one end.
Speaker 0: USB C has USB C hole on it.
Speaker 0: other end in the iPad.
Speaker 0: it works.
Speaker 0: It actually shows up and the iPads like Oh import photos.
Speaker 0: do All that crazy shit actually works.
Speaker 0: just connect to devices.
Speaker 0: plug your GoPro into your computer.
Speaker 1: Boom stuff's happening when you connect that USB C game free USB C cameras if they were serious like big cameras tended to have one USB port to be a host and one to be a connector.
Speaker 0: obviously your Experience may vary with different shitty or better devices But yeah for the most part if two devices have USB C And there's some logical reason to connect the two and you do so Something's gonna happen when you plug them in.
Speaker 1: yeah, and unlike the old days was on the go that something will probably not be a fire.
Speaker 1: Yeah, this has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 0: be sure to visit our Front row crew.com for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 1: remember geek nights is not one But four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows It's actually recorded at night.
Speaker 1: and the patreon patreons for this episode of geek nights are Greg Oliver Ellen George, I didn't eagle just like a dude guy.
Speaker 1: kashar tovish and William Isen.
Speaker 1: Rose link Eiji Graham Finch Jennifer Hitchcock Chris midkiff my stady calm J band scooter lonely Sean Yeager Nicholas Brando Mr.
Speaker 1: Strong stretch in four to one.
Speaker 1: creations like Johan Sebastian Bach rock ominous McIntyre cyan man sir Thunder Shervin von Horrell Rory Superboy Clinton Walton run for New Zealand Ryan Perrin drew open letter Finn dread lily tenebrae Sean Klein Chris Reimer Thomas Hahn and a whole bunch of people who are giving a dollar because a dollar is perfectly fine.
Speaker 1: And now don't forget Emily and I have been doing our show of talking about every single Disney animated Theatrical release in chronological order.
Speaker 1: we just uploaded the episode to the patron patreon exclusive about snow white and the seven dwarfs and That will be public sometime this week on patreon.
Speaker 1: You should listen to it.
Speaker 1: and now I leave you with Hopping around Tokyo City like a big playground when suddenly Batman first on the shade and hit Godzilla with a bat grenade.
Speaker 1: Godzilla got pissed and began to attack but didn't expect to be blocked by Shaq who proceeded to open up a can of Shaq.
Speaker 1: When Aaron Carter came out of the blue and he started beating up Shaquille O'Neal Then they both got flattened by the Batmobile.
Speaker 1: before he could make it back to the Batcave Abraham Lincoln popped out of his grave and took a naked 47 up from under his hat and blew Batman away.
Speaker 1: It was right at that time, but he ran out of balls and he ran away because all of this crime came to save the day.
Speaker 1: This is the ultimate showdown.
Speaker 1: Ultimate destiny could grab bad guys and explosions.
Speaker 1: As far as the I can see, there's only one will survive.
Speaker 1: I wonder who it will be.
Speaker 0: This is the ultimate showdown The ultimate destiny.
Speaker 1: Godzilla took a bite out of Optimus Prime like Scruff McGruff took a bite out of crime And then Shaq came back covered in a tire track But Jackie Chan jumped out and landed on his back and Batman was injured and trying to get steady.
Speaker 1: when Abraham Lincoln came back with a machete but suddenly something caught his leg and he tripped in the end and took him out with his whips.
Speaker 1: Then he saw Godzilla sneaking up from behind.
Speaker 1: then he reached for his son Which he just couldn't find.
Speaker 1: cuz Batman stole it and he shot and he missed and Jackie Chan deflected it with his fists And he jumped in the air and he did a somersault while Abraham Lincoln tried to pull a fault onto Optimus Prime But they collided in the air.
Speaker 1: then they both got hit by a Care Bear stare.
Speaker 1: This is the ultimate showdown.
Speaker 1: Ultimate destiny could grab bad guys and explosions.
Speaker 1: As far as the I can see, there's only one will survive.