Speaker 0: It's Wednesday, March 6th, 2019.
Speaker 0: I'm rim Scott and this is geek nights tonight.
Speaker 0: We're reviewing the anime tatami galaxy.
Speaker 1: Let's do this All right.
Speaker 1: So today I'm sitting at my desk like you do and usually, you know, I have headphone problems But that's usually with earbuds because the wire gets all messed up.
Speaker 0: when you got in your pocket on the subway and walk I actually just left a good pair of headphones that are noise isolating On my desk in Japan.
Speaker 0: It's the same ones.
Speaker 0: I got hanging here.
Speaker 0: So I got two pair of these fancy headphones.
Speaker 1: So yeah at work I got some over-ear ones with a replaceable cable and no an active noise cancelling with a triple-a battery.
Speaker 1: So those should not have any problem.
Speaker 1: the wire breaks I can replace it.
Speaker 1: if the battery dies I recharge it, you know, it's all good right there over the ear.
Speaker 1: They shouldn't be fragile and break, you know little You know, there's no fragile bits, right?
Speaker 1: But today I'm sitting there on my desk and like the right ear cuts out and I'm like what the fuck?
Speaker 1: So then I like, you know check it and it's fixed and then it cuts out Huh?
Speaker 1: That is so I was sitting there.
Speaker 1: So first of all, I'm like what is going on with this Caesar analog, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, okay.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean the noise cancelling it.
Speaker 1: I guess yeah, they're analog.
Speaker 1: It doesn't have its own sound card in it, right?
Speaker 1: But anyway, so total the wire I plug it, you know, I'm like wait a minute and I realized what was happening was so strange.
Speaker 1: There's nothing wrong with my headphones.
Speaker 1: So problem number one.
Speaker 1: I was chewing some gum while listening.
Speaker 1: Oh Only on the right side Right.
Speaker 0: I've had something similar happen I think to what you're about to sound like.
Speaker 1: am I messing up my ear?
Speaker 0: cuz my Animotics?
Speaker 0: not not the earbud the earbuds but the actual ear plugs.
Speaker 0: If I put it in my right ear in my left ear a particular way My right ear will do something weird where if it's pushed in slightly too far it like closes My ear entirely and I hear nothing like that.
Speaker 0: ears just dead.
Speaker 1: Well, this is nice is over ear not in ear.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, okay the plot thickens.
Speaker 1: So, you know, I'm like, there's nothing wrong with my right ear.
Speaker 1: So I take them off and I'm listening to stuff doing the Archer thing mop, right?
Speaker 1: It's like you're making noise like I guess my right ear works or I can hear you.
Speaker 1: I'm pretty sure my right ear is working.
Speaker 1: I'm not I'm not going.
Speaker 0: I remember I had faster than expected when I was young.
Speaker 0: I had a small Explosive go off kind of close to me and I remember like sitting there for a while.
Speaker 0: Like is this here?
Speaker 1: Yeah, right ear works.
Speaker 1: Okay, I'm good.
Speaker 1: What was happening?
Speaker 1: I finally solved it.
Speaker 1: Is that problem?
Speaker 1: one?
Speaker 1: Chewing gum.
Speaker 1: All right problem two I'm bald.
Speaker 1: So the the pad Right around my ear like as I was chewing.
Speaker 1: somehow air was Evacuating either into my ear hole or out and then it was creating like a suction.
Speaker 1: So there was no air in.
Speaker 1: it was sealed around my ear and there was no air in there anymore.
Speaker 1: So the speaker was vibrating.
Speaker 1: nothing or almost not enough air molecules.
Speaker 1: So even though the speaker is still vibrating in the headphone It wasn't shaking anything.
Speaker 1: so it couldn't shake anything inside my ear.
Speaker 0: That's plausible.
Speaker 1: so I couldn't hear nothing.
Speaker 1: cuz basically I tested this improved it because every time it happened I just broke the seal and it suddenly it started working again.
Speaker 0: That's uh That's like reverse farting.
Speaker 0: that's right.
Speaker 1: if I had air if I had hair wouldn't have a problem.
Speaker 1: If I wasn't chewing gum wouldn't have a problem because it wouldn't be like squeezing the air out.
Speaker 0: Well depends on what hair.
Speaker 1: because you're talking about hair in the air Any hair that would break the seal of the pad on an over the ear completely surrounding the ear headphones.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right I have no hairs.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and and I guess if I wash the side of my head Even though I just like a shower last night if I just wash the side of my head I guess maybe in the grease wouldn't.
Speaker 0: I'm not gonna to go into details on the thing I'm about to reference but you may remember a thing We read or that based from poop report at RIT about the dangers of shaving certain areas and the suction and resulting suction related issues that can occur Shaving your butt hair that story when he broke the seal.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I know.
Speaker 0: Yeah that one feel like it's an adjacent problem.
Speaker 0: So, what are you gonna do anything about?
Speaker 0: cuz my over-the-air headphones?
Speaker 1: No, it's not gonna chew gum.
Speaker 0: My over-the-air headphones are really good.
Speaker 0: They don't form a complete suction.
Speaker 1: You have hair right above your ear true.
Speaker 0: I do have.
Speaker 0: I have sideburns and such.
Speaker 1: how would how would the headphone form a perfect seal against your?
Speaker 0: The side of your head thing is my headphone even though I put it up against a completely flat surface Does not form a suction.
Speaker 0: I can't just like push it in and stick it to the wall Like it'll deflate it'll let air in.
Speaker 0: it's not perfect like grease it up a little bit.
Speaker 0: Uh, I don't know if I want to grease up my fancy headphones.
Speaker 0: Don't feel like it could happen with these headphones.
Speaker 1: You have it with the ones I had.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't know your pet That's are they like a plunger like?
Speaker 0: could you hurt your ear by like compressing them on your head?
Speaker 1: No, I don't think it's like a perfect vacuum cuz like there was.
Speaker 1: you know It was just.
Speaker 1: I would just break the seal and then it would suddenly work again.
Speaker 1: It might.
Speaker 1: also I don't know if there's any interaction with the active noise cancelling either.
Speaker 0: Maybe that was involved in some way because active noise cancelling could get it if it got into a state where the signal it's using.
Speaker 0: To decide to basically make the noise cancelling signal ended up being the input that's coming into the headphone in the first place.
Speaker 0: It would cancel itself out.
Speaker 0: Yeah That can happen in like regular old podcast audio engineering say.
Speaker 0: I record myself on two microphones And for whatever reason the phase of those is 180 degrees.
Speaker 0: They'll just cancel out to nothing.
Speaker 0: Yep This will commonly happen to people use an OBS to stream who don't know what they're doing and they'll some Stereo inputs to mono and they'll literally end up cancelling out their sound and then they'll see a really tiny volume there and they'll drag the gain up and The road you're on if you're dragging the gate up in that situation.
Speaker 0: Oh, no, it goes somewhere filled with screeching agonizing sounds.
Speaker 0: It goes somewhere.
Speaker 0: it goes to jikoku.
Speaker 0: So you got any anime news?
Speaker 1: Yeah, I got some little anime news.
Speaker 1: It's basically yeah, so first news is that Brian cave on this is the dude who writes saga.
Speaker 1: He wrote.
Speaker 1: why the good comics he wrote?
Speaker 1: why the last man?
Speaker 1: He wrote pride of Baghdad.
Speaker 1: He wrote the original runaways.
Speaker 1: He wrote.
Speaker 0: I kind of just stopped reading saga.
Speaker 0: I feel like I got a pick it back up ex machina.
Speaker 0: He's still going.
Speaker 0: Oh, it's still going.
Speaker 0: Okay I haven't read it in a while.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, I got all the trades Shaky, which I just catch up.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, okay It's probably still the best comic that's currently being published in the United States.
Speaker 1: next time I'm over there you at United States over there to judge anime.
Speaker 0: I'll pick up the trades where I left off and the.
Speaker 1: Anyway, really good comic book writer.
Speaker 1: He's also written other things.
Speaker 1: He worked on some TV shows.
Speaker 1: I think whatever he.
Speaker 1: Apparently, I don't know this hasn't been confirmed or something, but it's being reported.
Speaker 1: But there's gonna be a live-action Gundam movie, which is almost.
Speaker 1: you hear that and you're like well shit show.
Speaker 1: Granted, I mean on one hand every lie every like most Gundam stuff is recent is yeah.
Speaker 1: On one hand my default random that isn't like just a TV series is definitely gonna be chitchat.
Speaker 0: My default reaction to they're making a live-action of an anime is it's bad.
Speaker 0: But then I was surprised because battle angel Alita was good.
Speaker 0: You see it.
Speaker 0: I did not see it.
Speaker 1: How do you know so?
Speaker 0: Everyone I trust who has seen it has said middling to great reviews.
Speaker 0: No one has said it is bad.
Speaker 1: So people said about a lot of things that's but I am that is shocking.
Speaker 1: The problem is it is yeah The point is the problem is that the flaw of the thing a Gundam things that suck right is Usually the bad writing.
Speaker 1: so the fact that they have put an excellent writer on it Means that there is some potential here.
Speaker 1: if this is real and it happened the problem is for this Gundam because it's Gundam.
Speaker 0: how much leash will Brian gave on have?
Speaker 1: how much does Brian cave on know about Gundam?
Speaker 1: Yeah, I imagine he's right watching Gundam right now to get up to speed But what if he'd?
Speaker 0: what if no one told him which got him to watch?
Speaker 0: what if he's just watching like f90?
Speaker 1: Feeling that a dude who has written such comics as ultimate x-men knows what a Gundam is and knows how to watch a gun?
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't think he needs help.
Speaker 1: I don't.
Speaker 1: I think he knows how to internet Yeah, but at the same time he might know he might be like how war in the pocket And I'm sure he can ask them for like you know access to any Gundams He needs to see.
Speaker 1: they'll just give them to him.
Speaker 0: Let's see tentatively titled mobile suit Gundam.
Speaker 1: you see - Right so this would come.
Speaker 1: this is a unicorn - so that already is not.
Speaker 1: it happens in the universal century.
Speaker 0: like you know Original Gundam is a project that would have an quote overseas drama format.
Speaker 0: the hell is an overseas drop.
Speaker 1: Well, that's what.
Speaker 1: no the for the jet.
Speaker 1: the Japanese see it as overseas drama so for them It basically means live-action American thing.
Speaker 0: yeah, right because they take place in the UC 0104.
Speaker 1: okay, so if you think about original Gundam is what 78?
Speaker 1: yeah 104 is like 30.
Speaker 0: I prefer the Gundam seed calendar The cosmic era.
Speaker 0: yeah That was what.
Speaker 0: just gonna see it and gonna see destiny.
Speaker 0: There's nothing else in that one rights.
Speaker 1: It's cosmic era.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there's nothing else in cosmic era.
Speaker 1: Universal Century is real Gundam.
Speaker 1: nothing.
Speaker 0: Nothing happened in that era since what I saw and what I chose it doesn't say seed in the title.
Speaker 1: It didn't happen in the cosmic era.
Speaker 1: I mean there's a probably bunch of mangas that happened in the cosmic era that you were never gonna read.
Speaker 0: all right cosmic.
Speaker 1: I got a Bunch of manga like astray whatever and yeah, it's just.
Speaker 0: it's what I know.
Speaker 1: there's nothing new there, right It's all and everything has the word seed in the title.
Speaker 0: if it's in cosmic era yep Yeah, bunch of manga side stories.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they're all like.
Speaker 0: and a photo novel.
Speaker 1: Okay, sure okay.
Speaker 0: Yeah, anyway.
Speaker 1: Second news is Galaxy Express 3 9. one of the best animes there is right my one of my favorite.
Speaker 1: Maybe my favorite lazy Matsumoto thing.
Speaker 0: Scott likes the slow space drama long shot of someone just walking.
Speaker 1: anyway It's the galaxy.
Speaker 1: sister 9 is a TV series.
Speaker 1: You can still watch it on crunchyroll.
Speaker 1: There's movies.
Speaker 1: they came out discotheque put them out on DVD ways back Right.
Speaker 1: but recently and here's a Twitter thread of the people who did it they worked real hard To basically redo the movies and put out brand new HD bureaus that are like perfect and amazing better subtitles all kinds of extras included in the burei like you can get a Ticket to ride on the galaxy express in the D. It's like an extra in the DVD box like a little piece of paper, right?
Speaker 1: Really cute to do that.
Speaker 1: So that's pretty amazing.
Speaker 1: I you know you read the thread of the people who did it.
Speaker 1: They clearly tried really hard cared a lot did a good job right makes you want to watch them again all redone and stuff.
Speaker 1: But they put it out on burei only.
Speaker 1: so I'm like hey I don't never gonna buy a burei in my life where I want to watch it streaming or downloading.
Speaker 1: I'll even pay.
Speaker 1: I'll pay money for this because you you have done great works.
Speaker 1: And this is out now by the way in the United States in English.
Speaker 1: Where can I watch it like go to Amazon Prime.
Speaker 1: so good Amazon Prime and I see an Amazon Prime.
Speaker 1: I got the DVD that I already own from discotheque.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I see the burei that was just released for 20 bucks, right?
Speaker 1: And it's - it's this two movies this galaxy Express, and then this I do Galaxy Express yep, so it's like two movies anyway I don't know if they did.
Speaker 1: there's like another thing that I've never watched.
Speaker 1: the third thing That's like something destiny something I forget whatever the point is.
Speaker 1: Or is it Endless Odyssey or something like that?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I forget I've never seen it doesn't?
Speaker 1: you don't need to see that these two movies are what's important.
Speaker 1: And then I see like watch the movie.
Speaker 1: There's multiple prime video links.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and one of them Looks like it's clearly based on discotheque because the art is similar to the art.
Speaker 1: That's on the DVD and the burei.
Speaker 1: But is it from the new burei?
Speaker 1: because if it's from the new burei, then I'll watch it But if it's from the DVD then I'm not gonna watch it cuz I already have the DVD.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we've already seen that a long time ago, right, and it just works.
Speaker 1: It's just like an Amazon Prime thing, but then this is other link to watch the movie that has completely different Artwork on Amazon.
Speaker 1: right and if you click on that You can't watch it even if you have Amazon Prime.
Speaker 1: It says get viewster anime Included with viewster for some.
Speaker 1: what $4 a month a month after a seven-day free trial, but it's like What if this is on Amazon Prime?
Speaker 1: Why is it?
Speaker 1: Why is it like this viewster thing going on?
Speaker 0: I never heard of viewster right the head anime.
Speaker 0: Oh wow if I go to viewster calm It's got a fucking broken certificate.
Speaker 1: Yeah, okay, okay, but it's like okay.
Speaker 1: They got rid of that anime.
Speaker 0: Sorry the CN is like not valid.
Speaker 1: they got rid of the anime strike thing.
Speaker 1: so what the hell's up with this viewster thing?
Speaker 1: and how can I tell if you've got a Movie that's on prime viewster might be compromised?
Speaker 0: There's something.
Speaker 0: this actually the certificate here for viewster calm is from viewster calm dot something dot simple helix dot net You don't?
Speaker 1: it sounds like they're really bad at the web.
Speaker 0: They're either really bad, or they got hacked.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I think they're just bad.
Speaker 1: Simple helix is probably their hosting company.
Speaker 1: they prob That's the certificates bright based on the original hostname not in their DNS.
Speaker 1: Yeah, anyway that happens a lot because people are dumb.
Speaker 1: The point is I feel like they need to do a better job of telling you when you go to watch something on You know a streaming site or a download place like hey This is ripped from this bure or this DVD or this film or
Speaker 0: but usually they don't.
Speaker 0: there's no way to know.
Speaker 0: You'll see multiple streaming options multiple physical options and the streaming options are just the movie.
Speaker 0: They might even all be called the exact same thing.
Speaker 1: so it's like.
Speaker 1: I've seen this movie many times.
Speaker 1: I only want to rewatch it if I get to see that great new Remastered redone bure version.
Speaker 0: and if that period is that other one is eternal fantasy, okay?
Speaker 0: You can buy a DVD in English.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I've never seen it.
Speaker 1: It's I wonder I want.
Speaker 1: I don't know if they redid that one also or not, and I don't know what happens in it.
Speaker 0: We get a new one for a hundred and ten dollars.
Speaker 0: Yeah No Based on the original story by L.A.
Speaker 0: Drew Matsumoto picks up one year after the events of ado right.
Speaker 1: so if you don't know if You've never seen any Galaxy Express Right the three movies are sort of separate from like.
Speaker 1: they don't tell exactly the same story as the TV show.
Speaker 1: It's almost like if you had.
Speaker 1: you know this is the original manga, and then it's like all right.
Speaker 1: We'll make it into three movies all right.
Speaker 1: We'll make it into a TV show and they really have like nothing to do.
Speaker 1: It's like it's like two separate adaptations that like that.
Speaker 1: It's not like they're inserted or anything right.
Speaker 0: very their experiences in and of themselves.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like in the TV show.
Speaker 1: Tetsuro is a potato in the movie.
Speaker 1: He is not a potato.
Speaker 0: yep He is such a potato though.
Speaker 0: So and the manga is a potato, but this will remember this question of wait How do I watch this?
Speaker 0: which one of these do I click on?
Speaker 0: because it's gonna come up again in this episode.
Speaker 0: Another interesting news is that Funimation said they're gonna release a Dragon Ball Z blu-ray collector's edition.
Speaker 1: So is that all of the original Dragon Ball Z?
Speaker 0: Yeah the 30th anniversary collector's edition.
Speaker 1: so a full set of blu-rays So you can watch all of Dragon Ball Z. not Dragon Ball not Dragon Ball GT or any other Dragon Ball But just Z every episode.
Speaker 1: I believe so original Japanese unedited original music Titles.
Speaker 0: they're like changing the aspect ratio.
Speaker 0: there was some debate about four by three or sixteen by nine.
Speaker 1: The original last video show is four by three.
Speaker 1: I feel like you shouldn't be stretching was it?
Speaker 0: Are you sure it was on Japanese television?
Speaker 0: Yeah?
Speaker 1: Which is square television.
Speaker 0: Funimation announced they release it.
Speaker 0: the release had planned to keep the four by three aspect ratio.
Speaker 0: Yeah But Funimation only released the first two volumes for suspending production.
Speaker 0: on that They said they had to suspend it due to technical challenges of restoring from the original film frame by frame.
Speaker 0: It was too expensive.
Speaker 0: they gave up.
Speaker 0: they later released it on a nine blu-ray disc thing in 2013 But that changed it to a 16 by 9 aspect ratio.
Speaker 1: So is it like cropping the top and bottom off of everything?
Speaker 0: Hell if I know I don't need to watch Dragon Ball Z again.
Speaker 0: Okay, but the news.
Speaker 1: even watch Dragon Ball Z to begin with I only see.
Speaker 1: I've only seen like a few episodes here and there.
Speaker 0: I watched every episode where Krillin is laying on the ground yelling while someone else is fighting.
Speaker 1: I've watched episodes where people are up in the air glowing yellow and going.
Speaker 0: I saw episodes where Frieza was in them.
Speaker 1: Yeah, those are the ones and I never saw.
Speaker 1: that's like the white lizard II dude, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's like the Mewtwo, yeah, yeah, it's like I'm not gonna lie.
Speaker 1: I haven't seen that.
Speaker 1: I've seen maybe less than 20 Dragon Ball Z's and none of them None of those episodes were adjacent to each other.
Speaker 0: I saw hunks of Dragon Ball Z because it was on like right before Sailor Moon, which I was watching when Dragon Ball Z was on.
Speaker 1: I usually went to a different channel to watch something else.
Speaker 0: Yep, usually I'd catch the end of a Dragon Ball Z episode.
Speaker 1: Yeah, because I wanted to I usually wanted to watch what was before or after Dragon Ball Z. I think I don't remember exactly but I think it was Dragon Ball Z would end it and then I would watch Vitesse.
Speaker 1: I don't remember.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think that was.
Speaker 0: it might have been a different era because I remember it was Dragon Ball Z and then Sailor Moon.
Speaker 1: Yeah, no Sailor Moon was on like our local but anyway Yeah it depends on when you're watching.
Speaker 0: because remember that Sailor Moon R came out and then there was the episodes after the Tree saga that like people hadn't seen in the u.s.
Speaker 1: On Toonami at the beginning of Toonami I would watch the old shows the thundar the barbarian and the Voltron and then I would stop watching when it was the Tenchi Dragon Ball zone in the middle and then I would come back after dinner for B-TAS and other stuff.
Speaker 0: I didn't watch Tenchi because I'd already seen every Tenchi by then Fucking fansubs of Tenchi.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so that was Tenchi was a show.
Speaker 0: I was really into in like high school.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I was even reading that pretty bad manga with like yakage or whatever.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't know what that is.
Speaker 0: It's the villain who's pretty remarkably similar to the villain in the villain in the second OAV.
Speaker 1: I only know what Tenchi looks like and what the girl with the big blue hair looks like and that's it.
Speaker 1: I don't know any other characters.
Speaker 0: Was it the one who seemed kind of evil?
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that was.
Speaker 0: that's the good one.
Speaker 1: That's the only.
Speaker 1: I was the only characters I know from that show.
Speaker 0: There's another girl with big blue hair who was different.
Speaker 0: So if I see those characters, there's a third character with big blue hair who was different still.
Speaker 1: Oh, I know and that's the girl who's technically way too old, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, Sasami That's the other girl with blue hair.
Speaker 1: It was the only.
Speaker 1: and those the only things that I will recognize and say that's Tenchi.
Speaker 1: if I don't see any of those Things I don't know.
Speaker 1: It's ten.
Speaker 0: You'd probably recognize the little cat thing.
Speaker 0: Maybe like the Cabot half rat rabbit.
Speaker 0: That's from that show, but technically she is a spaceship.
Speaker 0: So okay Also, she also tries to bone Tenchi.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 0: Anyway, the news is not.
Speaker 0: I don't get anything to say about Dragon Ball.
Speaker 0: The news is that Funimation said they're only gonna even make This collector's edition if they get 2,500 pre-orders.
Speaker 0: I'm sure they'll get 2,500 pre-orders.
Speaker 0: Yeah I think that's.
Speaker 1: I saw a lot of nerds.
Speaker 1: It makes sense cuz like there's not too much demand for this and clearly it's a pain in the ass for them to make it.
Speaker 1: Dragon Ball Z is a lot of work.
Speaker 1: There's a lot of episodes.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right.
Speaker 1: It's like it seems seems like a lot of work.
Speaker 1: I feel like you wouldn't do it unless you knew for sure you had that enough nerds.
Speaker 1: That's not a very large number.
Speaker 1: I feel like there's definitely enough Dragon Ball fans.
Speaker 1: They'll meet the number.
Speaker 0: Yep so they pointedly said they're not gonna do like a Kickstarter or something because They don't want to just like.
Speaker 0: like that would be asking fans to fund new content.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's through.
Speaker 1: now just do pre-orders.
Speaker 1: Yeah, just like until there's enough pre-orders.
Speaker 0: We won't start working on it Yeah, which I think more companies should do for this kind of thing.
Speaker 0: This is great.
Speaker 1: You don't have to pay a fee to Kickstarter.
Speaker 1: So someone's claiming there's a problem with this.
Speaker 1: They're mad.
Speaker 0: The people I saw who seemed to be mad about this seem to be people who are best ignored in all cases in all things.
Speaker 1: in all cases I mean, I seem to remember the exact same thing happening or a similar thing.
Speaker 1: I could be wrong about this But I remember when I bought the Macross DVDs from anime ego way back in the early 2000s You know, I pre-ordered those for like $300 Of 2000s money when I was pouring in college, but I had to order that anyway, which is I don't regret that I still have those.
Speaker 0: I remember that.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean up until then there was no no way to get that right.
Speaker 0: There wasn't even like YouTube.
Speaker 1: Right?
Speaker 1: That's what I'm saying.
Speaker 1: And I seem to remember them like not having I could be wrong but a vague, you know, 20 year old memory.
Speaker 1: But I seem to remember them like having I got a number and like if they didn't get that many then they wouldn't Wouldn't like, you know do it God What was?
Speaker 0: I don't.
Speaker 1: or maybe that was just the number of that they were gonna make.
Speaker 1: They would sell out.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I can't remember which one it was.
Speaker 0: I have no idea.
Speaker 0: That was so long ago that that was such a different era of reality from today.
Speaker 1: That's what.
Speaker 1: I kept all the discs, but and I ripped I think all the discs to digital.
Speaker 1: But I still have them.
Speaker 1: and but I I kept all the there's like there was like liner notes.
Speaker 1: They came with.
Speaker 1: I kept those.
Speaker 1: they were fancy Yeah, but all the DVD boxes and the the cardboard box that they all went in I got rid of that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I ended up getting rid of too much space.
Speaker 0: I got rid of every cardboard box for every DVD I own and put them in sleeves.
Speaker 0: But now I have a two inch thick binder of sleeves with a shit ton of DVDs That I feel like I should just rip and then throw away.
Speaker 1: I just keep it, you know in a place.
Speaker 0: I keep it in a place.
Speaker 0: But I feel like it might be worth it to just set up a PC and just Script it where I just put a DVD and it just rips it and puts it on the NAS Rip every DVD I own and just get rid of the last of them and
Speaker 1: some of those DVDs I feel like I need like my Windows 95 B CD.
Speaker 0: Yeah I'm only talking about my moon-based commander CD wrong.
Speaker 0: I mean, I have my tribes to see these.
Speaker 0: tell ya have that I In the actual jewel case, I don't have with the code.
Speaker 1: don't have that.
Speaker 1: I got the code.
Speaker 1: I don't have the joke.
Speaker 0: I've also got that too.
Speaker 1: I'm a career to CD room.
Speaker 0: I've got that to CD box set that.
Speaker 0: So an individual who I will not name from the RIT Anime Club gave me when I won that contest our freshman year.
Speaker 0: That was the selection of the 40 best anime music videos of all time Circa 2000 and war and toothaches 2000. okay the year 2000.
Speaker 0: I still have that CD.
Speaker 0: Maybe I should put all those on YouTube if they're not there.
Speaker 0: But first things of the day, what do you got?
Speaker 1: What do I got?
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 1: So if you don't know who Fritz Lang is you got problem.
Speaker 1: Fritz Lang is like one of the best movie directors there ever was Directed such great famous films like metropolis like the original one.
Speaker 1: Yeah M just the letter M that's the name of the movie when the greatest movies there is and a movie I've more recently just.
Speaker 1: I mean Not.
Speaker 1: I mean not saying I personally discovered this movie.
Speaker 1: I'm saying other people knew about this movie.
Speaker 1: clearly I didn't know about it until maybe like a year ago.
Speaker 1: the testament of dr.
Speaker 1: Mabu is a which is like amazing this movie.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, you mentioned that I didn't watch Series.
Speaker 1: of three movies one was made in the late 20s.
Speaker 1: the one that I saw was made in like the early 30s And then there was a third one that was made in like that 60s.
Speaker 1: I only saw the middle one and it was amazing.
Speaker 1: He's also made a lot of other very very famous amazing movies.
Speaker 1: not a lot of them are listed on this page not all of which I've seen because it's hard to see them.
Speaker 1: but Fritz Lang was famous for not being interviewed very often because he said look if your artwork Doesn't speak for itself and you need to give like an interview to explain your work You didn't do a very good job.
Speaker 1: Did you?
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: That was his philosophy, right?
Speaker 0: So he did that philosophy, right?
Speaker 1: He wasn't about trying to make himself famous He was about trying to just make movies.
Speaker 1: So There weren't a lot of interviews with him.
Speaker 1: maybe there was only one and there was this.
Speaker 1: basically there was this one interview with him ever and and I think no one had seen this interview or you know the contents of it until like early 2000s and I Remember seeing it around then and it wasn't.
Speaker 1: it was like.
Speaker 1: it wasn't the whole thing.
Speaker 1: It was like just a portion right and now in 2019 15 years later.
Speaker 1: It's like, all right.
Speaker 1: Here's the whole the transcript of the whole interview the whole thing.
Speaker 1: So this is pretty much all you're gonna get Is long.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna read this.
Speaker 1: it's pretty much like the only time Fritz Lang ever sat down and talked to anyone on the record that it was recorded While skimming these already Comparing him to say Kunihiko Ikuhara.
Speaker 0: He gives the exact opposite kind of answer.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, Ikuhara would be like you'd have to ask Toga.
Speaker 0: There's no way for me to answer that question because I can't speak for Toga Fritz Lang here.
Speaker 0: It's just like if the movie didn't say it like what do you want?
Speaker 0: Hey Yeah, I Don't know what he's got a Monica.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: That's a real good picture.
Speaker 1: Yeah exactly what you expect him to look like.
Speaker 0: yep, so If you like all good sane people read the first do novel possibly because you know, it's a classic of all time.
Speaker 0: I didn't read it until recently both of us.
Speaker 0: We did a book club.
Speaker 1: I tried to read it in middle school and did not like.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm still only you know, it's I.
Speaker 0: I like it a lot but Unlike every other but like many of its ideas every other book club book.
Speaker 1: We're not all.
Speaker 0: yeah, not all the games.
Speaker 1: better.
Speaker 0: yeah, some of the ideas that had were just a product of their time and a Could be done better shall we say.
Speaker 1: but everything I've heard about the other dune books I haven't read has been bad.
Speaker 1: So I'm not gonna read them.
Speaker 0: Yep I think someone did I someone in our forum described the further dune books as a train wreck that you want to look away from But you just can't and you have to.
Speaker 0: yes I can I don't.
Speaker 0: I'm not force yourself to look away and go read a newspaper the next day instead.
Speaker 1: I have not looked at it.
Speaker 1: I haven't had to force myself anything.
Speaker 0: It is telling that There's a trend in the gig nights book club where we read the first book of a series and then I just go on and Read the entire wheel of time after that like just instantly.
Speaker 0: I did not read any more dune books after we did dune.
Speaker 0: I feel like dune ended at a place where I did not need more dune.
Speaker 0: But if you are the kind of person who wants to know what happened in the dune universe But is smart enough to not read all the dune books.
Speaker 0: Here's a 10-minute YouTube video.
Speaker 1: No only 10 minutes.
Speaker 1: When you say I saw you were choosing this is a thing of your day.
Speaker 1: I'm like, I am NOT watching this but now that I know it's only 10 minutes It's like I got 10 minutes.
Speaker 0: and what it does is it doesn't just go through the books It's actually much broader.
Speaker 0: It just takes from all the books.
Speaker 0: What is the entire chronological order of events?
Speaker 0: from the beginning of Anything mentioned in the series beginning of time well to the Roman Empire.
Speaker 0: That's when that's the earliest thing that happens in dune.
Speaker 0: Okay happens in the Roman Empire.
Speaker 1: That's news to me.
Speaker 1: But all right.
Speaker 0: Yep, and this just moves along and covers the 34,000 years of the dune universe.
Speaker 0: the Butlerian Jihad is like right away.
Speaker 1: Okay, so the Roman part isn't a lot of content.
Speaker 0: No, the Rome part is yeah Rome then the Land Strad in space.
Speaker 1: Okay Only because none of the time in between was covered in any of the books.
Speaker 1: So there's nothing to say about.
Speaker 0: yeah It'd be like if I was covering human history and I was like so.
Speaker 0: a monolith fell down then monkeys discovered warfare Then World War two happens moon landing.
Speaker 1: So that brings us to things Met a moment.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: So the meta moment the geek nights book club book is 2001 a space Odyssey.
Speaker 1: I finished reading it for Thursday, but then rim bailed and didn't finish reading it.
Speaker 1: He's bad.
Speaker 0: I will be done with this book because I've been mostly done with it as of now.
Speaker 1: Guess what next Thursday when we do an episode on it.
Speaker 1: We're doing that episode whether you read it or not.
Speaker 0: Yeah, fine.
Speaker 0: The funniest thing about this book so far because I'm near the end is Every time a character talks about it mostly happens only in the first half of the book the price of something Like oh that was it.
Speaker 0: That's a $50,000 person we invested in.
Speaker 0: it's really funny.
Speaker 1: But I mean, it's not funny enough that it's 2001.
Speaker 1: Everything in it still seems futuristic even though it's currently 2019.
Speaker 0: Yeah Well everything in it feels futuristic except information technology and the book is from like the 60s.
Speaker 0: Yeah It's.
Speaker 1: this is another thought cuz I mean if you look at the the rate of space technology Progression that was happening at that time right pre Person on moon time.
Speaker 0: Yep, like before we kind of paused that work, right?
Speaker 1: They saw the space race.
Speaker 1: It's accelerating and they projected forward.
Speaker 1: He's like, well, we keep developing our space technology at the rate We're doing it now, you know that we should be.
Speaker 1: this is what the kind of stuff we'll have by 2001.
Speaker 1: We should be going to Jupiter and Saturn rim only make sense.
Speaker 1: Yeah Typewriters didn't foresee that we would space shuttle and then not even space shuttle.
Speaker 0: We still got casual sexism and typewriters.
Speaker 0: So, yeah Otherwise, we will be in Two weeks three weeks three weeks.
Speaker 0: Well two weeks at zenk icon geek nights will be doing panels.
Speaker 0: I still have to Remember to look up what panels I'm doing So I know to prepare them and to show up for them and I have to repair the panel for PAX East the week after Yeah, but PAX East on Friday.
Speaker 0: We will be doing the real harm of games.
Speaker 0: What harm did people tell us games would do that?
Speaker 0: They may or may not have done.
Speaker 1: and what harm do games do?
Speaker 0: Yep, and The answers may surprise you they may shock and alarm you.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I had what I wanted to say, but then I found that I was wrong.
Speaker 1: It's not changing what I'm gonna say.
Speaker 0: Holy shit geek nights panel that Research.
Speaker 1: usually it's come up with my ten minutes of research.
Speaker 0: Usually our panel structure is come up with an idea.
Speaker 0: Do come up with the thesis that we're going to present then cherry-pick evidence cherry-pick evidence and find all the images We need and all the things to talk about it and then we're good.
Speaker 0: But in this case, it was come up with the thesis then do research then.
Speaker 0: Oh shit.
Speaker 0: Our topic is now.
Speaker 1: Oh, no, I couldn't even find any evidence that I agree with.
Speaker 1: Oh, no.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I guess I'll change my thesis.
Speaker 0: I guess I got.
Speaker 0: I guess I gotta change my world view.
Speaker 1: I can't.
Speaker 0: I can't just say the games don't cause the panels already been accepted.
Speaker 1: Oops, I guess I can't.
Speaker 1: I can't do a different panel.
Speaker 0: short answer.
Speaker 0: games do and have caused harm But it is as far as we can tell not the harm.
Speaker 0: Anyone said it was Pretty much.
Speaker 0: Yeah You'll see it's gonna be a good panel brand new panel.
Speaker 0: So we're excited about it real fan.
Speaker 1: Yep And you know that Grimm's panel do it, you know, clickbait for top 40 list.
Speaker 0: Well top 40 list is a pretty popular panel.
Speaker 0: Clickbait not real because I think what someone impact said that was interesting is the the clickbait title panel.
Speaker 0: That tricks people into a more serious discussion like people come to the panel who wouldn't otherwise come and oh shit It's actually serious or it's actually the real harm of games is click baity enough.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's click baity and it's right.
Speaker 1: You're gonna need you're gonna need someone to save you a click and tell you what the harms were.
Speaker 0: Yeah But our nostalgia first game design panel was very well received and I haven't uploaded all the top 40 lists.
Speaker 0: We've done.
Speaker 0: I gotta edit one of those together.
Speaker 0: The board game one is pretty popular.
Speaker 0: Actually, my co-workers have all been looking at that one because they all want to play better games.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: Here we go.
Speaker 0: Let me close this nonsense about the cosmic era because The more I learn about the cosmic era the less I care about the cosmic era.
Speaker 1: You may know, uh Tomohiko Morimi is someone who we've talked about a lot recently.
Speaker 0: Yep So it's one of those authors where you see a bunch of media and then later you find out there's a creator that is related To all of them and you've like you find a thread and you start tugging on right?
Speaker 1: So there's been a bunch of anime right eccentric family.
Speaker 1: Yep, eccentric family - yep night on Night is young walk on girl.
Speaker 1: Yep Tommy galaxy - Tommy galaxy, which we're gonna talk about now.
Speaker 1: Wasn't there another one penguin highway?
Speaker 1: That's coming soon, right?
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: Anyway, we've seen anime was written in 2010.
Speaker 1: We've seen anime based on all these things and Some of those anime have been animated by the same teams, right?
Speaker 1: So like Masaki Yuasa, he animated what we're gonna talk about today, which is Tommy galaxy on the galaxy, but also he did walk on girl, which is Very related but also not an eccentric family eccentric family - obviously animated by the same studio.
Speaker 0: I just want to point out if you haven't watched eccentric family.
Speaker 0: We reviewed both seasons.
Speaker 0: You should go watch it.
Speaker 0: It's one of the best shows to come out.
Speaker 0: It is one of the best anime there is right now.
Speaker 1: frog in a well anyway But all of these are based on novels written by Tomohiko Morimi and Hopefully these novels will be just translated so I can read them directly and not just have to watch anime adaptations.
Speaker 1: I really want to read the eccentric family novel based on all these anime adaptations of Morimi's work.
Speaker 1: I am a fan of Morimi's work indirectly indirect key.
Speaker 1: so once I found out because we were when we saw Night a short walk on girl in the theater at the end.
Speaker 1: There's the interview with Yuasa.
Speaker 1: He kept bringing up Talking about the time a galaxy and I'm like.
Speaker 1: I've heard of tatami galaxy and I haven't watched it.
Speaker 1: I think I will go home and watch it.
Speaker 1: So I did and I watched like a handful of episodes.
Speaker 0: I've seen like three and a quarter episode.
Speaker 1: I've seen a similar amount.
Speaker 1: I'd have to you know, and I haven't finished it, but I've definitely done enough to talk about right because I mean That's more than we usually talk about anime watching less episodes than yep.
Speaker 0: Basically, it's we.
Speaker 0: either we talk about an anime scene a few episodes or we watch the whole thing as fast as possible And then we talked about it, right?
Speaker 1: The only reason I didn't watch this as fast as possible is because I had so many other things to do.
Speaker 1: It's like it, you know, it was con season.
Speaker 0: We had a lot of conventions.
Speaker 1: It's like there's other things that kept taking up my time So I couldn't just sit down and watch a whole bunch of anime But every time I got a chance I like squeezed in one episode I only just got like four or five chances.
Speaker 1: Yep And now when I want to watch even more of it because I was like, oh, let me go refresh We're gonna do an episode.
Speaker 1: I go in crunchyroll and Rym message me today.
Speaker 1: He's like, yeah, it ain't there.
Speaker 0: Yep, cuz last night I was like, I've only seen like three episodes.
Speaker 0: I should watch a bunch.
Speaker 0: tonight I go to crunchyroll.
Speaker 0: Just couldn't find it and I googled around a little bit and I could not find anywhere to watch it legally.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if I would have known it was gonna go off crunchyroll I would have like bailed on something else to watch it before I got taken off and now I'm gonna have to Resort to like piracy or something to watch the rest of the show.
Speaker 0: Yep, and I really like it's I. There might be a place to watch it legally, but in a cursory search I was not able to find it and in this day and age if you can't find the legal place to watch it by typing The name of it into Google everyone involved has failed and you can pirate it at that point,
Speaker 1: right?
Speaker 0: But so actually it says availability.
Speaker 0: I think it got taken down.
Speaker 1: Sorry due to licensing limitations videos are unavailable in your region All right, so they just I guess the US distribution thing expired maybe whatever.
Speaker 0: Yep So that was a shame because I really like this show and I want to watch the rest of it I feel like I'm gonna have to pirate it right.
Speaker 1: So the thing is like I said when we were talking about Even though I hadn't watched all this and still haven't watched all of it Like I said, we were talking about walk on girl.
Speaker 1: I've said man, you know because I watched a couple episodes of this before we did our walk on girl episode I was like man, you got you it's hard to talk about walk on girl the anime if you haven't seen the time.
Speaker 1: the galaxy the anime because Both by you also both based on works from the same author but what you also does here the most notable thing is Similar to Tezuka manga where he'll have the same Characters playing the same quote actors playing different act characters in different things The same exact character designs and maybe even voices.
Speaker 1: I have to go verify that.
Speaker 0: I didn't verify.
Speaker 1: I didn't verify the voices But there was no disjointedness.
Speaker 1: So I feel like it's the same voices.
Speaker 1: It's 100% the same character design.
Speaker 0: yep, so in walk on girl in both right in walk on girl, there's a dude who is 0.1 steps above being a bum.
Speaker 0: Yep, who may or may not Be a magical creature may not.
Speaker 1: he's Tengu adjacent.
Speaker 1: Yeah, he's got like a big old chin.
Speaker 0: Yep, he might just be a bum who through who acts like he's a Tengu, right?
Speaker 0: He might actually be a Tengu.
Speaker 0: But anyway, there's a tatami galaxy.
Speaker 1: there.
Speaker 0: that person plays someone who's 0.2 steps above being a bum right?
Speaker 0: It's a very similar character who is probably a god.
Speaker 1: Yeah You can imagine an eccentric family that you could tell eccentric family with that same character being the Tengu grandpa guy.
Speaker 0: Oh my god that character could you only older.
Speaker 0: if you saw any character from eccentric family or tatami galaxy or walk-on girl In the background of the other shows, it just makes sense.
Speaker 0: They're all in the same universe.
Speaker 1: for example eccentric family There's the girl who's always like turning into objects.
Speaker 1: You never see her.
Speaker 1: yeah, that could be.
Speaker 1: you could use the character design for the girl from walk-on girl or The girl in tatami galaxy for that character.
Speaker 1: Yep, right You know main guy in eccentric family main tanuki guy could be main college dude from right, right?
Speaker 1: It's like you can see that the author sort of has you know characters that feel similar adjacent ish personalities and roles in their stories.
Speaker 1: and Because the same animation team did you know these two anime the time of galaxy and walk-on girl?
Speaker 1: They use the same character designs, right?
Speaker 1: There's like devil II guy You know, yeah definitely guy bum buff, dude Buff jock dude earnest male protagonist.
Speaker 1: Yep There's a lot of reused character designs from both and the characters that share the designs share personalities quite a bit.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so what's the time in galaxy actually freaking about?
Speaker 1: so there's this dude and he is looking to have like the perfect Most wonderful college existed.
Speaker 0: Yeah, what does he say?
Speaker 0: He wants to go to college and find a raven-haired girlfriend, right?
Speaker 1: So he's got these ideas about college.
Speaker 1: He wants college to be like amazing.
Speaker 1: He's he goes to college.
Speaker 1: He's trying to fulfill his dream of you know, what's gonna happen in college.
Speaker 1: So each episode it's an episodic show.
Speaker 1: surprisingly Yeah, I'm sure it's not episodic at the end, but it's episodic at least most of the way.
Speaker 1: I've read some like episode descriptions.
Speaker 1: each episode He joins a club at the college.
Speaker 1: So this is my favorite so far.
Speaker 1: is the bicycling club?
Speaker 1: Yeah, the bike one's good because of how badly it goes Right, but there's other clubs.
Speaker 1: He joins like a drama club, right was one of them.
Speaker 0: I think the first three episodes are tennis club a film club film club.
Speaker 0: Remember with the pervert guy, right?
Speaker 1: Right, right yeah, anyway, each episode he joins a different club and Crazy stuff happens
Speaker 0: but all in like the same circle like but
Speaker 1: the girl
Speaker 0: he likes that he Can't talk to is like in the club or right here by
Speaker 1: the same Each even though each episode is different in terms of the club he joins and the exact drama that happens.
Speaker 1: There's the same format of how the episode breaks down right early and he makes a promise to this girl right and then he's got her like little thing hanging from the from the Pole string on.
Speaker 1: his land is low and is thick right and he can't remember to give it back to her.
Speaker 1: You know even though she has the rest of the set he has the.
Speaker 1: he is the one that she's missing.
Speaker 1: and Then there's the evil dude comes and makes mischief which looks like a demon.
Speaker 1: Yeah, he mess up the clean messes up the club's business right the crazy old Tengu adjacent guy Gets in the who is the best and my favorite character.
Speaker 1: Yeah the most rim like character.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's a very rim adjacent I love.
Speaker 0: so the description of him in the in this Wikipedia is And it is similar how he's described in the show an eighth-year super senior Mm-hmm, very similar to some people we knew in college ourselves who were still around.
Speaker 1: Maybe what point one steps above being a homeless bum somehow still in the school Yeah, but anyway, and I guess you know that character that Tengu ish character is sort of like the mentor master Ish in a way like he's learning from him sort of.
Speaker 1: anyway.
Speaker 0: I mean the vague gist of it is he sort of gives this ultimatum to the main guy of yo, I'm a god, right?
Speaker 0: You're either I'm gonna have you date this girl or that shithead, you know And don't like.
Speaker 0: but you're also best friends with dater, right?
Speaker 1: So the episode, you know as he joins the club He's you know, he's trying to do stuff in the club.
Speaker 1: He's usually bad at whatever the club is.
Speaker 1: He's bad at biking He's bad at filming.
Speaker 1: He's not helping much, right?
Speaker 1: He's sort of failing.
Speaker 1: and then you know as things are sort of collapsing because of his failure despite his attempts to succeed in his You know devolving into making mischief instead of participating and being nice and doing a job like the first episode He bumps into the fortune-teller.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: I think the first every time I'm pretty sure the fortune-teller Raised her price every episode.
Speaker 1: I didn't notice the fortune-telling part is like usually identical every episode.
Speaker 1: She says basically the same thing right, yeah every time He feels like he remembers this fortune-teller, but he doesn't do what she says.
Speaker 1: He doesn't do what the fortune-teller says does what else.
Speaker 0: who says instead?
Speaker 1: then the whole thing Collapses in a giant climax clusterfuck.
Speaker 1: That's amazing Yep.
Speaker 1: and then There's the end of the show.
Speaker 1: at the end of the episode happens and the end of the episode is this animation of like time Rewinding and then the next episode it's like he's back at the beginning of college again.
Speaker 1: So he's replaying sort of a Groundhog Day situation Trying to live this perfect college life.
Speaker 1: and even though it's each episode He's joining a different club and things are a little different getting a little crazier a little more Twisted a little more advanced.
Speaker 1: each time you feel like with each episode He's getting closer to not fucking up.
Speaker 1: Yep, so far at least in the for, you know I imagine he's not gonna figure it out to the last episode, but You know for the four or five episodes I've seen it's pretty the same structure just different clubs every time.
Speaker 1: But it's it's still Fascinating and I can imagine you can just imagine that at the end.
Speaker 1: He's finally gonna get it, right Yep, but what is right?
Speaker 0: What is a perfect college experience?
Speaker 1: Remembering the thing he's forgetting you're doing with the fortune teller says to do because
Speaker 0: not to spoil walk-on girl Which has a similar story in some ways
Speaker 1: It
Speaker 0: sort of has this moral of like your rose-colored glasses of what you wanted versus what you actually wanted versus the complexities of a real world and what actually happens all set to the backdrop of All the kinds of crazy people and crap that happens in college.
Speaker 1: Yep So the structure of you know, like walk-on girl isn't doing the time rewinding thing It's the.
Speaker 1: it's it's this four seasons thing.
Speaker 1: this four seasons that play out in one night is the structure.
Speaker 1: so here it's a similar thing where there is a time based structure of College playing out and rewinding Right.
Speaker 1: So I you know, I guess eccentric family doesn't have this structure.
Speaker 0: But the two novels that Yuasa Adapted have some sort of you know time based thing going on, but I guess this and walk-on girl both Really really capture this vague nostalgic feeling I have for my own college life.
Speaker 0: and like RIT anime and like that Kind of environment where everything feels bigger and more important than a walk-on girl Also did have a college with a club that was significant, right?
Speaker 0: In the sense of like you see people in clubs who were treating it like it's way more important than it really is.
Speaker 1: Which also makes you think of you know, Utena.
Speaker 0: Yep, but then you see the people post-college.
Speaker 0: Reminiscing on that makes you think of Mahotsukaita.
Speaker 1: Yep, or any of the other anime with clubs.
Speaker 1: Yeah El Hazzard?
Speaker 0: Nah, El Hazzard just turns into Escaflowne.
Speaker 1: El Hazzard was just a weird thing in the basement, right?
Speaker 0: Yep, El Hazzard doesn't really get back.
Speaker 0: El Hazzard, the good ol' EV, not the TV show.
Speaker 0: that's bad.
Speaker 1: I'm just trying to remember animes that have school clubs.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but the one The one I didn't watch all of Haruhi.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, Haruhi.
Speaker 0: Haruhi does some stuff.
Speaker 1: Anyway, also a time-based situation, right?
Speaker 0: Where this one fits more with Utena Is these more ideas of the thing?
Speaker 0: the way you see the world when you're in college Is very different from the way you see it outside of college and you overestimate the importance and the grandeur and scale of the things you're doing and the people around you like.
Speaker 1: You see these legends when your world is small, right?
Speaker 1: Your pond is small that lily pad seems huge and then when you know You don't see the whole world until you leave college.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 1: No one cares about that.
Speaker 1: Yep, like the world is big only big things are big.
Speaker 0: like when you're in college.
Speaker 0: This the eight-year super senior is like this legendary figure in the local community.
Speaker 0: Right when you're an adult the eight-year super senior is a bum.
Speaker 0: fuck is wrong with that guy.
Speaker 1: It's just a bum walking around the street.
Speaker 1: What the hell is that?
Speaker 0: You still taking one credit hour a year?
Speaker 0: Like what are you doing?
Speaker 1: What are you doing, man?
Speaker 1: Yeah, if you like other things based on the works of Morimi, you never get the name, right?
Speaker 0: If you have If you like other lots of things if you saw walk-on girl, the night is young and liked it Just watch this.
Speaker 1: Yeah, this one actually came first.
Speaker 1: This was on the noetomena block, which is it's sort of like it back in like 2010.
Speaker 0: Wow, okay.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So if you don't know noetomena is the word animation spelled backwards and it's a. it's a programming block on a Japanese TV channel.
Speaker 1: I forget which one.
Speaker 1: Fuji TV Fuji TV.
Speaker 1: So on Fuji TV at some time.
Speaker 1: I think it might be late at night.
Speaker 1: I'm guessing They they're like, alright, it's.
Speaker 1: no it's a minute time.
Speaker 1: It's sort of like how you know This tsunami or adult swim don't swim.
Speaker 1: and they show a bunch of anime and those anime are usually the good anime.
Speaker 1: It's usually right if something's a noetomena anime odds are it's probably good.
Speaker 1: It's probably something about.
Speaker 1: it's not gonna be some some garbage kids show.
Speaker 1: It's not gonna be you know, some some like Shonen trashy show like your panel.
Speaker 1: Oh, right It's gonna be actually a show with some sort of artistic merit to it And this is one of those.
Speaker 0: Yep, so it's worth watching.
Speaker 0: I wish it was still on crunchyroll.
Speaker 0: So if you can't get a hold of it figure out how to get it.
Speaker 1: somehow this.
Speaker 1: you have an internet.
Speaker 1: You can find out how to get the show.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna figure it out when I get home.
Speaker 0: Yep Cuz I'm gonna watch the rest of it and maybe we'll do a final thoughts on it at some point cuz it's only like 13 Episode right 11 11.
Speaker 1: So I meant I was like almost halfway done.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I could have made it.
Speaker 0: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Speaker 1: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 0: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 1: But unlike those other late shows it's actually recorded at night.
Speaker 0: And the patreon patrons for this episode of geek nuts are Craig Oliver Allen Joyce hiding McNichola Just like a dude guy chartovitch and Linky G Jennifer Hitchcock Chris midkiff mystady.com Jay bench scooter lonely Roberto Kingsley Sean Yeager, Matthew Smith Nicholas Brando Mr.
Speaker 0: Strong's traction for to win creations Chris Reimer and Thomas Hunch Horrell Rory Rochelle, Montana super boy sailor Vista Joe show Joe star Clinton Walter and read from New Zealand Ryan parent.
Speaker 0: You're open letter.
Speaker 0: Finn Daniel Redmond Sean Klein Chris Reimer and Thomas, huh?
Speaker 0: Now I leave you with a song that I actually know all the words to buy hearts.
Speaker 1: Hi, my name is You can take.