Speaker 1: It's Tuesday, December 3rd, 2019.
Speaker 1: I'm Rym.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott.
Speaker 1: And this is Geek Nights Tonight, back from a long hiatus.
Speaker 1: We are talking about the remake of The Legend of Zelda, Link's Awakening.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: So in true fashion, we always have hiatus around this time of year.
Speaker 1: But we had a longer hiatus than usual because I had that two week trip to Asia that I hadn't actually planned for.
Speaker 1: Usually when I had the old job way back, I flew around a lot, but I kind of picked when I traveled.
Speaker 1: So I tended to avoid doing those kinds of trips at the same time as our usual Geek Nights holiday hiatus.
Speaker 1: So I basically disappeared for two weeks, and then we've got a bunch of conventions.
Speaker 1: We're not going to do a show on Thursday because we're going to be at PAX.
Speaker 0: Save it for the meta moment.
Speaker 1: No, meta moment.
Speaker 1: We'll talk about what we're doing at PAX.
Speaker 1: But we're back after almost, but not quite a month.
Speaker 1: So we're going to blow all our opening bits and all the anecdotes and forget everything after that.
Speaker 0: I mean, we've already forgotten all the ones because we had another PAX time hiatus.
Speaker 0: And we came back from it.
Speaker 0: We're like, "Yeah, I haven't done a show in a
Speaker 0: while.".
Speaker 0: We forgot all this stuff.
Speaker 0: We're going to blow our load and forget everything, and all that stuff has already been forgotten.
Speaker 1: If I eat a good sandwich over the weekend, that's what I talk about on the next Monday's show.
Speaker 1: But if I take a month off, I might fall in a volcano.
Speaker 0: I don't remember that sandwich.
Speaker 1: Escape some terrorists, and then eat a sandwich.
Speaker 1: that's pretty good.
Speaker 1: And then when I do the show, the sandwich is the last thing I did.
Speaker 1: So that's what I'm going to remember.
Speaker 1: But yeah, it's good to be back.
Speaker 1: I miss doing this.
Speaker 1: And I was way too tired and lazy to do it on the trip.
Speaker 1: So I guess the only notable anecdote from my trip is I actually went to two places I've never been before.
Speaker 0: Shocking.
Speaker 0: This is a giant world.
Speaker 0: I feel like it's pretty easy to go to two places you haven't been before.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but when it's work sending you to places, especially in global finance, there's a short list of places that someone like me needs to go on a regular basis.
Speaker 0: Yeah, mostly cities.
Speaker 0: You're not going to be going to the woods.
Speaker 0: There's not a lot of finance in the woods.
Speaker 1: I've been to London.
Speaker 0: You're only going to go to cities, and not every major city even has a stock market.
Speaker 0: So you're only going to go to places with markets and financial companies.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there are only 88 exchanges in all of Asia.
Speaker 1: There aren't that many exchanges.
Speaker 0: Right, so you look around the world, even if you go to some place that has a ton of countries and a ton of big cities, the big exchanges are all here, here, and here.
Speaker 0: All the financial companies put themselves in these few cities, and all those other big cities might be focusing on other industries, and I don't need to go there.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but also when I used to go to Australia all the time, I'd mostly go to Sydney.
Speaker 1: I had no excuse to go to Melbourne, but this time I got to go to Melbourne too, which was nostalgic, because I ate dinner where I could actually see the PAX building, and I was thinking back to those old...
Speaker 0: It's the PAX building?
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: It's the Melbourne Convention Center.
Speaker 1: I've never been in that building except for PAX, and I will never go to that building except for PAX, I suspect.
Speaker 1: But I got to go to the Philippines, where I've never been to before, and I had a few days to just fuck around in Manila.
Speaker 0: Which Philippines was it?
Speaker 1: Manila.
Speaker 0: The main one.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the one.
Speaker 1: But Manila was pretty interesting.
Speaker 0: It was a thriller.
Speaker 1: There's a thing there.
Speaker 1: The problem with Manila is it's so dense, like denser than New York.
Speaker 1: So many people live there.
Speaker 1: The downtown is really like a normal city, but the commute... Take the LA commute in terms of just cars and traffic in Nightmareland.
Speaker 1: Make it literally four to ten times worse.
Speaker 0: Why aren't people just walking?
Speaker 0: if it's so small?
Speaker 1: Because it's not.
Speaker 1: It's actually huge.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 1: It's dense and sprawling.
Speaker 1: It's a huge city.
Speaker 0: Doesn't sound like if it's dense, I should be really close to work.
Speaker 1: No, imagine if Manhattan were like ten times bigger space-wise, but just as dense as Manhattan.
Speaker 1: It's nuts.
Speaker 1: So my hotel was like four miles away out of like Makata or Makati.
Speaker 1: I have terrible Filipino pronunciation.
Speaker 0: You mean Tagalog?
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Isn't that the language?
Speaker 1: Yeah, it would take me maybe like 15 minutes to like ride in a cab or like take a jeepney or something.
Speaker 1: Except during rush hour when it took like an hour or two, maybe three.
Speaker 1: So I literally like one day after work, I was like fuck this.
Speaker 1: So I just went to a restaurant for like two hours and I came out and traffic had not changed at all.
Speaker 1: And Bangkok is the other place I've never been to Thailand.
Speaker 1: I avoided insulting the king.
Speaker 1: Looks like they have a new king.
Speaker 1: I don't know a lot about Thailand, but the one thing I can say is...
Speaker 0: The things I know about Thailand are a mixed bag.
Speaker 0: I know some really positive things about Thailand and some really negative things.
Speaker 1: There's also, depending on where you go in Thailand, there are very...
Speaker 0: A lot of unknown things.
Speaker 1: Very different situations going on.
Speaker 0: I'm sure there are.
Speaker 1: But I only got a couple days in Bangkok and unfortunately I was with some coworkers who basically hate food as far as I can tell.
Speaker 0: But isn't Thailand like?
Speaker 0: the number one thing that I would go there for is the street food?
Speaker 0: Yeah, all I wanted was the food.
Speaker 0: The street food in Thailand is famous.
Speaker 1: Yeah, all I wanted was that food.
Speaker 1: Now on one hand, I was told by all the security people and everyone that that street food is great, but you better be up to date on all the hepatitis shots or you will get hepatitis.
Speaker 0: I got 'em.
Speaker 1: Yep, I got 'em too.
Speaker 0: Are people in Thailand getting hepatitis?
Speaker 1: Yeah, hepatitis is like crazy endemic and it's mostly food.
Speaker 0: You ship them some hepatitis vaccines.
Speaker 1: Well, not all hepatitis have vaccines.
Speaker 0: Oh.
Speaker 1: And it's a real danger in Bangkok.
Speaker 0: Alright, I'll stick to the hot foods.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: Also, even though it's a really modern, normal city, you can't drink the water there either.
Speaker 0: There's not a lot of places you can drink the water.
Speaker 0: I know.
Speaker 0: That's why I live in New York.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: I mean, I'm not even super much a fan of the water too far upstate New York.
Speaker 0: I mean, even New Jersey, you can't drink that shit.
Speaker 1: Yep, but the other thing was I was in Singapore, but I've been to Singapore a ton of times, like eight or nine times, but I'd never been there over a weekend where I could just fuck around, and I was just there.
Speaker 0: Well, you don't want to fuck around too much.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well, fuck around in the fun way.
Speaker 1: I wasn't spitting gum or smuggling drugs or anything.
Speaker 1: But I went to a whole bunch of cool places.
Speaker 1: I'd never been, and I even went to Universal Studios there because it was near- They even have one?
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's really small.
Speaker 0: Oh, okay.
Speaker 0: I was like, "How many of those are
Speaker 0: there?".
Speaker 1: So the best part about Universal Studios- No one's there.
Speaker 0: In Singapore- You're all alone.
Speaker 1: You can just enjoy- Is that they have a New Yorkland.
Speaker 0: Holy shit.
Speaker 0: What was the New Yorkland like?
Speaker 1: Oh my God.
Speaker 1: I've got to even pull up these photos.
Speaker 1: I'll make this my thing of the day instead.
Speaker 1: It is like a grimy New York.
Speaker 1: They've got a fake New York Public Library.
Speaker 1: They've got a fake Empire State Building.
Speaker 0: Holy shit.
Speaker 0: We should make a fake Singapore.
Speaker 1: It's got all these really complicated no parking signs everywhere.
Speaker 1: It is absolutely amazing to see this place.
Speaker 0: How accurate was it?
Speaker 1: Actually, really accurate for my sensibilities.
Speaker 0: Was it made by someone who saw a movie of New York, or was it made by someone who had been in New York?
Speaker 1: So they got just all over, there's just these grubby- That looks like old New York.
Speaker 1: It is old New York.
Speaker 1: Grubby parking signs.
Speaker 1: They got the New York Public Library and the Lions.
Speaker 1: It's a smaller scale, but it's pretty accurate.
Speaker 1: Empire State Building facade, signs and stuff.
Speaker 0: There's a roof on it, but- Yeah.
Speaker 1: Well, the roof is not a real roof.
Speaker 1: That's just a sunshade because you'll die otherwise.
Speaker 1: It was like 100 degrees.
Speaker 1: The only weird thing was the entertainment in New York land is like mid-80s hip hop and breakdancing.
Speaker 1: So that is the musical act in New York land, but otherwise the setting is just very New York.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 1: So that was interesting.
Speaker 1: And of course I went mountain biking again and I only injured myself minorly.
Speaker 0: Only minorly.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well I took two- My coworkers today were like, "Let's go on a ski
Speaker 0: trip.".
Speaker 0: I'm like,
Speaker 0: "Nope.".
Speaker 1: Why?
Speaker 1: Skiing's way safe.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I know.
Speaker 1: Compared to mountain biking.
Speaker 0: It's also, not only is it unsafe, it is cold and wet, which is even worse than being unsafe.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so for the first time in my life I was defeated by heat.
Speaker 1: It was 99 degrees when I was mountain biking.
Speaker 0: That sounds good.
Speaker 1: So I was biking hard uphill significantly over a very rough terrain.
Speaker 1: It was like 100% humidity.
Speaker 1: My body ran out of water despite drinking infinite amounts of water and- You need some salt.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I had all my kit.
Speaker 1: I was good on that front, but I was unable to complete the second half of the course at speed because it was too hot for me to continue exerting myself without taking long breaks.
Speaker 0: Your problem is exerting yourself instead of chilling.
Speaker 1: You can't chill on a mountain bike trail.
Speaker 1: Chilling on a mountain bike trail is a recipe for flipping over your handlebars.
Speaker 0: Just go nice and slow.
Speaker 0: Nope.
Speaker 1: You've got to get above a certain minimum speed over rough terrain or you're going to have a bad time.
Speaker 0: Alright, well then don't do that.
Speaker 1: Or do it because it's awesome.
Speaker 0: Stay on roads.
Speaker 0: Nice and safe.
Speaker 1: Yeah?
Speaker 1: So yeah, I'm back.
Speaker 0: Go back to New York land.
Speaker 1: The worst thing though was I was in this whole trip all over the world.
Speaker 1: There was like 100 degrees everywhere.
Speaker 1: I finally fly back home and I get to JFK and- Yeah, I didn't bring a coat or anything.
Speaker 1: And when I left New York, I wasn't that cold yet.
Speaker 1: So I get off the plane, carry on the whole way.
Speaker 1: I'm like right through customs.
Speaker 1: I walk straight for that taxi line because it's way early in the morning and the air train would have taken like almost two hours.
Speaker 1: And I walk outside and it's cold.
Speaker 1: And I instinctually said, "Oh
Speaker 1: fuck!"
Speaker 1: Like flinched a little bit.
Speaker 1: And this dude was standing there.
Speaker 1: I think he was a cabbie or something just like hanging out.
Speaker 1: And he looks at me and he just starts laughing.
Speaker 0: I forget who it was.
Speaker 0: There was a famous story of a basketball player.
Speaker 0: I think they were from... What country were they from?
Speaker 0: I forget.
Speaker 0: But they came to play in the U.S.
Speaker 0: Right?
Speaker 0: You know they did from some country.
Speaker 0: So I think it was Africa.
Speaker 0: They came over and they were like, "Oh yeah, there's a few
Speaker 0: colleges.".
Speaker 0: Because they were coming over to play college basketball.
Speaker 0: They were like, "Here's a few colleges to choose from.
Speaker 0: You can go to St.
Speaker 0: John's.
Speaker 0: We'll take you to somewhere maybe... I forget.
Speaker 0: I think it might have been Kentucky or something.
Speaker 0: And
Speaker 0: Houston.".
Speaker 0: And the guy was like, "I think you'll like Houston,
Speaker 0: right?".
Speaker 0: Alright.
Speaker 0: Guy gets off.
Speaker 0: You know, this kid is going to go to play college basketball.
Speaker 0: Gets off the plane in New York.
Speaker 0: Feels a cold breeze.
Speaker 0: Turns right around and says, "I want to change my flight.
Speaker 0: Take me to
Speaker 0: Houston.".
Speaker 1: So there is a ton of gaming news and we skipped most of it.
Speaker 1: I'm sure some of the things that we're not going to talk about will come back when there's further news.
Speaker 0: Seems like most of the stuff that happened since we podcasted was like Pokemon related.
Speaker 0: Which I'm playing somewhat.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that might be just the over-representation of Pokemon on my social media feeds though.
Speaker 1: And among our friend groups.
Speaker 0: It's pretty much the game right now.
Speaker 0: I think also like Shenmue 3 came out.
Speaker 0: Don't care.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: And what other games are hot right now?
Speaker 0: There was a Half-Life prequel VR whatever.
Speaker 1: I'm pretty into that.
Speaker 1: I'm excited about that.
Speaker 0: I don't know any other games that came out.
Speaker 1: Because we're planning to do some VR development.
Speaker 0: Someone screaming and yelling some important game.
Speaker 0: Yeah, whatever kid.
Speaker 1: We picked up, we have an Oculus Quest now.
Speaker 1: The one that's completely wireless.
Speaker 0: How many do you need?
Speaker 0: Like every model?
Speaker 1: Well, because that one's way easier to use.
Speaker 1: And now they added the thing where you can plug it with a long USB-C cable into a gaming computer.
Speaker 1: And it'll just look better and work better.
Speaker 1: But you can run it completely independently.
Speaker 1: Like run it outside, do whatever you want.
Speaker 1: And because that's the actual consumer tech, that's what we want to use to gear experiences and experiment toward.
Speaker 1: And I might sell my Rift or I might just use the Rift as the second headset for more advanced sideloading nonsense.
Speaker 1: But I'm not going to upgrade the Rift to the S. There's really no reason to do that.
Speaker 1: And I think it'll be a few years before there's a real upgrade that is actually expanded or extended market friendly.
Speaker 1: Because the Valve VR is way too expensive.
Speaker 1: And even though it's very high quality, that is not something normal people will have at any point.
Speaker 1: So you got some news?
Speaker 0: We do have some news.
Speaker 0: So on Steam, they've had for a while, Steam Stream.
Speaker 0: I forget what it's actually, the real name of it is called.
Speaker 0: Steam Remote Play maybe?
Speaker 1: That's where like, I have a computer in this room.
Speaker 0: Right, you have your computer, your desktop computer that is very powerful.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: Right?
Speaker 0: And you install games on it.
Speaker 0: And it has a GPU and it can run games at high resolution in full frames and everything.
Speaker 0: But you want to play your game somewhere else.
Speaker 0: Maybe you want to play your game on your phone or your tablet or some, you know, your friend's house.
Speaker 1: Or just your HTPC in the other room that you didn't spend $3,000 on.
Speaker 0: Right, you want to play the game in a different location, but you don't want to buy another GPU.
Speaker 0: Or you want to play it on a device that doesn't run the game, right?
Speaker 0: So the way it works is a lot like the way Google Stadia works.
Speaker 0: The game will open on your computer.
Speaker 0: It will run in a window.
Speaker 0: The get.
Speaker 0: your computer will then capture the video from that window.
Speaker 0: Stream that video to your location or your other device, wherever it is, on the network.
Speaker 0: And then it will stream your computer inputs back to your computer and send them into the game.
Speaker 0: There will be some latencies.
Speaker 0: You don't want to play a fighting game this way.
Speaker 1: Yeah, what's funny is I'm looking at this screen right now about Remote Play.
Speaker 1: And they actually show Towerfall Ascension as one of the games.
Speaker 1: But yet, in my experience, Towerfall Ascension, when we tried to use Teamstream to play it at multiple parties, the lag prevented skill from being a factor.
Speaker 0: Well, it depends if you're on a LAN or if you're going over the internet.
Speaker 1: That might have just been Scott's terrible network.
Speaker 1: Not this Scott, other Scott.
Speaker 0: It also depends on the players, right?
Speaker 0: I think most people playing, you're going to notice latency, right?
Speaker 0: Being all pro, but I think most people won't notice or care, right?
Speaker 0: But yeah, so that's a thing.
Speaker 0: They added a new feature.
Speaker 0: that's kind of a big deal, but I wonder how many people will use it, which is called Remote Play Together.
Speaker 0: And what this does is, let's say I'm sitting on my computer and I want to play a game, and that game has local co-op, right?
Speaker 0: It doesn't have any internet play.
Speaker 0: It only has local co-op play, like couch co-op.
Speaker 0: Or couch competitive, right?
Speaker 0: It could be like a dive kick.
Speaker 0: I want to play some dive kick.
Speaker 0: Does dive kick even have internet play?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: Pretend it doesn't.
Speaker 0: In case it does.
Speaker 0: And my friend, though, lives somewhere else, right?
Speaker 0: And we want to play this dive kick.
Speaker 0: So now what a way it works is.
Speaker 0: I play the game, looking at my screen with my controller, but it also captures my screen, streams the screen to my friend, and streams my friend's inputs back, so my friend is doing the stream remote play, but I'm doing the local play at the same time.
Speaker 0: And it's only running on my computer or my friend's computer, right?
Speaker 0: So you're doing a local co-op, but you're doing it over the internet using that same exact remote play mechanism.
Speaker 0: So this is a great feature, and I'm sure it works, right?
Speaker 0: The problem is I've been on the lookout for couch co-op games.
Speaker 1: They're in shorter supply than they used to be.
Speaker 0: There are not a lot of couch co-op games.
Speaker 1: Well, I would say most of the couch co-op games...
Speaker 0: There aren't even a lot of couch competitive games.
Speaker 1: Or couch competitive games I want to play like this are actually just NES and SNES ROMs.
Speaker 0: Right, because the NES, SNES, Genesis, GameCube especially, they had several controller ports, and developers made lots of games to use several controller ports.
Speaker 0: You turn on Mario Brothers.
Speaker 0: This is one player, two player.
Speaker 0: Even though you're taking turns, it's still a two controller deal.
Speaker 0: Even Duck Hunt is a two controller deal, right?
Speaker 0: People felt like when they made a Nintendo game, they had to have one player, two player.
Speaker 0: But now, people mostly just make a one player game or an internet multiplayer game.
Speaker 0: There's not a lot of local multiplayer games that you need this feature for.
Speaker 1: I feel like in the Steam library, it's games that came out between 2006 and 2012-ish.
Speaker 1: That was when there were a lot more of these kinds of games, because that's just what people were making.
Speaker 0: At least now, if you have one of those games you want to play and you don't have friends, like maybe Trine or something, there's a few Trines, right?
Speaker 0: Now you can play it over the internet, which is also good, because now you can do a stream.
Speaker 0: You can do this plus a Twitch stream at the same time.
Speaker 0: Watch me, the Twitch streamer, and my friend, the Twitch streamer, play this local co-op game, but my Twitch streamer friend lives far away.
Speaker 0: You can do that setup now, which is great, but there's just not enough games, I think, that need the setup.
Speaker 0: Please develop more games with local co-op.
Speaker 1: We've talked about this at length over the 15 or so years of doing Geek Nights, about those heady days of the GameCube era coupled with us happening to be in college during the GameCube era.
Speaker 0: But also, I think, from the perspective of a game developer, developing network shit is hard, and takes a lot of development time and effort, and sucks ass, which is why if you are going to make a game with some local multiplayer...
Speaker 1: Yeah, skip making your...
Speaker 0: Local multiplayer is much easier to develop, much less resource-intensive, much less difficult for developers.
Speaker 0: So if you've got a game, I think this might encourage developers, please add local multiplayer.
Speaker 0: You will get the internet multiplayer for free.
Speaker 1: Well, only for people using Steam for your game.
Speaker 1: If you release this game on multiple platforms, or you've got, like, Switch players...
Speaker 0: Right, so release your game on fucking Steam, right?
Speaker 0: I know.
Speaker 0: Come on.
Speaker 0: Do it.
Speaker 1: So in some other news, Baba Is You actually has always had a level editor, but it's something that, like, Mega Nerds, it's not a hard hack, but you had to, like, fuck with some Lua files and, like, make things happen to get access to the level editor.
Speaker 1: And that's how people were making a lot of crazy.
Speaker 1: Baba Is You mods, but Baba Is You, much like Mario Maker, is getting an official level editor.
Speaker 1: There's no date given yet, but it's going to come out in 2020.
Speaker 1: On one hand, I think this is going to be amazing, because I think we're going to see some amazing, crazy crap.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 1: But on the other hand, like with Mario Maker, I'm not going to try to make anything, because nothing I make would even come close to what we're going to see on the internet within a week.
Speaker 0: Well, I think it's one of those things where there are people who dedicate their time to it as, like, it's their thing.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Right?
Speaker 0: And I'm only shallow into it.
Speaker 0: I didn't even beat all the puzzles in the default game.
Speaker 1: Well, it's tricky, too, because as soon as I think I have a clever with Mario Maker, like, you think you have a clever idea, you go online, a thousand people have done that idea to a level of polish you could never approach.
Speaker 0: There's nothing wrong with doing a thing just because someone else has already done it, even if they've already done it better.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that is true.
Speaker 0: You can do it anyway.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but it might not feel like it's worth the effort to polish.
Speaker 0: I mean, if that's your line, because if that's your rule, I'm not going to do anything if someone else has already done it and better, you're not going to do anything ever.
Speaker 1: Well, no, it's more-.
Speaker 0: Why are we making this podcast, this better podcast?
Speaker 1: Now, there's a difference between if you want to do something as, like, you want to experience the craft of doing it, but usually when it came to level editors, like, before the internet, if you told me as a kid, like, I could make Mario levels or something,
Speaker 0: the only
Speaker 1: reason I wanted level editors was because I wanted to make cool, interesting things that didn't exist so me and other people could play them.
Speaker 1: I wasn't actually interested in the mechanics of level design, but now someone else will have already made the experience and I can just go play that experience.
Speaker 0: You can still be the guy who plays and beats all the custom levels.
Speaker 1: Oh yeah, and that I'm into.
Speaker 0: It's still a thing.
Speaker 1: I play way more Mario Maker than I make.
Speaker 1: Oh yeah.
Speaker 1: I'm still, like, I'm working on one that has the feel of a certain level from Mario 2, but it's taken me a while because level design in that type of space that feels right and good and tight is not easy.
Speaker 0: No, it's not.
Speaker 0: I think that's the reason they made these games.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: So I really look forward to seeing what people do with the Baba.
Speaker 1: Is You Baba Maker.
Speaker 1: And in some last funny news, you might remember a long time ago, there was a humble little controller called the Valve Steam Controller.
Speaker 0: So much Valve news today.
Speaker 1: The news is that Valve ran out of Steam Controllers.
Speaker 0: Finally.
Speaker 1: I guess they discounted the price.
Speaker 0: Well, I think what happened is they made a bunch of them and then...
Speaker 1: People like us bought them to try them out.
Speaker 0: It was pretty cheap.
Speaker 0: I bought one to try it out.
Speaker 1: It was kind of bad.
Speaker 0: It had some good parts and some bad parts, but in the end of the day, it wasn't really good enough to use.
Speaker 0: I ended up getting rid of it.
Speaker 1: The only game I used it for, like, I wanted to... Yeah, I was about to say, I used it for Rocket League and nothing else.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: Because it had, the only innovation it had that was good, for me, were those two little pedal buttons on the left and right on the inside.
Speaker 1: I used those to juke left and right in Rocket League.
Speaker 1: It felt great.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: Anyway.
Speaker 1: But, like, the buttons weren't comfortable, the stick was in a weird place, the pad didn't work that well.
Speaker 1: There was no D-pad, really.
Speaker 1: Like, it was a problem controller that didn't actually work very well.
Speaker 0: I mean, it wasn't a problem.
Speaker 0: It just wasn't good enough.
Speaker 0: It wasn't better than any other controller.
Speaker 1: It was not better than the four Xbox controllers I already had.
Speaker 0: But it was super inexpensive, and I guess if you didn't have any controller, right?
Speaker 0: It's like, I guess it's slightly less than trivial to use another kind of controller on a PC.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: Anyway.
Speaker 1: I also, in the early days, ran into problems.
Speaker 0: But the price was, they kept lowering the price so much and they stopped making them, right?
Speaker 0: They just kept lowering the price and lowering the price until it's like, well, might as well get one even if I don't need it.
Speaker 0: Five bucks, whatever, for a whole game controller.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: And they finally sold out and there aren't any more and they're not going to make any more because they're not any good.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: Even better, a lot of people tried to buy them and apparently they messed up their stock and they actually had way less than they thought.
Speaker 1: So a whole bunch of people just got their orders cancelled.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so I can tell you that actually I recently had too many controllers of different kinds and I tried to consult.
Speaker 1: I have two Oculus controllers, I have four Xbox wireless controllers, the old ones that were actually made for the PC.
Speaker 1: Connected to an official dongle that they don't sell anymore.
Speaker 0: I consolidated all my controllers and what I got was I kept all legacy controllers that I need for old things, like NES controller, SN8, right?
Speaker 0: Those.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like you do.
Speaker 0: But in terms of controllers for PC and Switch and modern things, I bought the 8BitDo SN30 Plus Pro, which is basically the ultimate controller of ultimateness.
Speaker 0: It has every single feature except HD rumble.
Speaker 0: It's regular rumble, but not HD rumble.
Speaker 0: And you can use it with the Switch, the PC.
Speaker 1: But Scott, my HD rumble.
Speaker 0: You can use it with literally everything.
Speaker 1: The only other- How will I know if Luigi is nervous versus pensive when I'm playing Luigi's Mansion?
Speaker 0: The only other negative aspect of this controller besides that is that you cannot turn on, it's actually a problem not with this controller specifically, but with any third party controller whatsoever, is that you cannot wake the Switch from sleep mode with it.
Speaker 0: So you have to go over to your Switch, push power.
Speaker 0: Ooh.
Speaker 0: There is no third party controller that can wake the Switch.
Speaker 0: Only official Joy-Cons and Switch controllers can do it for some reason.
Speaker 1: I don't like that because- That's a Nintendo thing.
Speaker 1: The way I use my Switch when it's in the dock is I'm sitting on the couch- You sit on the couch and you push the button.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I push the button, that wakes up the Switch.
Speaker 1: The Switch, because my TV is not that old, automatically wakes up the TV and sets it to the Switch input.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's a thing.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so uh- But yeah, so if you want to use this controller, the only thing is you have to go and push the power button on the Switch, or never make your Switch go to sleep, if they can do that.
Speaker 0: And then go sit down and turn the controller on.
Speaker 1: I guess the other thing is I have two Pro controllers, and the Pro controller is really good.
Speaker 0: But yeah, this controller will work with like iOS, Android, PCs, PS4s, Switches, literally every fucking thing.
Speaker 1: I feel like I'll get that controller for like, my uh, HDPC.
Speaker 0: I have two of them, and I got rid of every other controller I could because they replaced almost every other controller possible.
Speaker 1: Not bad.
Speaker 0: Uh, so there you go.
Speaker 1: But anyway, things of the day, what do you got?
Speaker 0: So, uh, let's say you live in Canada, and you gotta, you live in Canada, you gotta play hockey.
Speaker 0: It's hockey time.
Speaker 1: Like, I think there's a law.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there is a law.
Speaker 0: If you're not playing ice hockey, you at least gotta skate.
Speaker 0: But what if you live in Canada in a place, and that place doesn't have a pond?
Speaker 0: Or if there's a rink, but the rink is like, you know, you gotta buy ice time there, there's other Canadians playing hockey there, you can't get in the rink, right?
Speaker 0: You just want to go outside and skate, you know, a little quick skate right outside the house.
Speaker 1: Yep, we'd go skate at uh, ponds, or we'd go to rinks.
Speaker 0: Right, so apparently they have a thing called Puddle Rink, which is literally just, they shovel the snow out of an area that's- I've never seen one of these!
Speaker 0: They just shovel the snow out of an area, spray water, and it's, you know, take care of it, you know, do sort of like a handheld manual Zamboni-ing.
Speaker 1: It's not a great service, it looks kind of mushy, but I'd take it.
Speaker 0: It's not like amazing, but it's like, yeah, it's like they make a little tiny rink.
Speaker 0: so people can, who live in the neighborhood, can walk over, do a little skate, do a little whatever, you know, people with old hockey equipment, which there's tons of, you know, leave it out there and like a little thing.
Speaker 0: so, you know, grab a stick, you know, skate around a little circle, you know, shuffle puck, whatever, go back inside.
Speaker 0: And there's usually an old man in the neighborhood who wakes up at the crack acid dawn, sprays water on it, shovels it, you know, takes care of the old, yeah, tries to make it level because the land isn't going to be level.
Speaker 0: They're going to level it off over time, you know, just take care of it.
Speaker 0: Otherwise, you know, it's not the kind of thing that works if there's no maintenance, right?
Speaker 0: It's not like you, if you had a real Zamboni, you would take up half the rink.
Speaker 0: That's not going to work either.
Speaker 1: It looks like it's very soothing to make too.
Speaker 1: Like it looks like it would be fun to be the person to make it.
Speaker 0: Here's a video about a dude who maintains a little puddle rink.
Speaker 0: He shows you how to do it.
Speaker 0: He tells you the story of how it works.
Speaker 0: There's tons of these things apparently around Canada.
Speaker 0: And if you live in a neighborhood somewhere that's got a little room and it's cold enough, maybe like Minnesota or something.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Maybe, you know, talk to the neighbors.
Speaker 0: Maybe you can be that guy who wakes up at 5 a.m.
Speaker 0: every day and sprays the puddle rink.
Speaker 1: Top YouTube comment.
Speaker 1: Me, never goes outside.
Speaker 1: Also me, goes outside to make a hockey rink.
Speaker 1: So I saw a video the other day.
Speaker 1: I tweeted about it.
Speaker 1: People commiserated.
Speaker 0: Title of video.
Speaker 0: You are old.
Speaker 0: Haha.
Speaker 0: The end.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: But I never had one hit me like right in the mean bean machine like this one did.
Speaker 0: I mean, it's about the same as all the other ones.
Speaker 1: This one hit me right in the old.
Speaker 0: It's about the same as the ones that are like, "Oh yeah, Pokémon.
Speaker 0: It's like 20 years old,
Speaker 0: bitch.".
Speaker 1: No, I guess the difference is that the, "Oh hey, X is Y years old," is a much more like, "Yes, because of the progression of time
Speaker 1: thing.".
Speaker 1: But when it's framed more as, "What did people do before
Speaker 1: X?"
Speaker 1: That feels like there's more of a mystery and it reminds me of the fact that younger people actually don't know.
Speaker 1: They look at this shit.
Speaker 1: the way I look at, I'm trying to think of what's old enough, the way I look at 10 base 2 internet.
Speaker 1: Like, "Wow, you live with that?
Speaker 1: Ooh.".
Speaker 1: So the video was called, "What did we use before
Speaker 1: USB?".
Speaker 1: And the thumbnail was like a serial port, a parallel port, and a joystick port, and some PS2 ports.
Speaker 0: Well, that was what we used immediately before USB.
Speaker 0: That wasn't what we used before then, and before then, and before then.
Speaker 0: But yeah, if you had an IBM, if you had a PC and not a Mac.
Speaker 1: Oh, look at that.
Speaker 1: Look at those ISA ports right there.
Speaker 0: If you had a PC, not a Mac, right?
Speaker 0: Macs used other things.
Speaker 0: And it was the late 90s and USB had just been invented around like '98 or something.
Speaker 1: Yeah, Windows 95 did not work with USB.
Speaker 0: No, you had to.
Speaker 0: actually, there was Windows 98.
Speaker 0: Oh, no, it was Windows, no, actually Windows 95 did not have support for USB.
Speaker 0: But then, Windows 98, and there was a second release of Windows 95 that was like Windows 95B.
Speaker 1: Which I never got.
Speaker 0: I had it.
Speaker 0: I actually have the CD-ROM for it.
Speaker 1: Because I never got 98.
Speaker 1: I skipped to 2000 on a brand new computer.
Speaker 0: I have both, I have 95B and 98 and 2000.
Speaker 0: Anyway.
Speaker 1: I went, I had Windows 311.
Speaker 0: So the point is, is that not until Windows 95B, so I assume 96 or 97 is when consumer computers started having USB.
Speaker 0: And that was USB 1.0.
Speaker 1: I don't think you understand how, like USB 1.0 was so slow.
Speaker 0: I had a USB 1.0 three button mouse bitches.
Speaker 0: But that computer still had PS2 port, serial port, games port, parallel port.
Speaker 1: Yup, my scanner plugged into the SCSI port because I had a SCSI card.
Speaker 0: SCSI was like the special elite connector.
Speaker 1: Yup, but the SCSI card was plugged into an ISA slot.
Speaker 0: Oh yeah.
Speaker 0: I had PCI slots.
Speaker 1: I mean, I had two PCI.
Speaker 0: The point is, if you had a computer in the early to mid 90s that was an IBM computer, you had these, it was a PC.
Speaker 0: It could have been, it might have been IBM, but in Compaq or HP or Gateway or whatever the hell.
Speaker 0: These are the connectors it had before USB was a thing.
Speaker 0: And even when USB was a thing, they still had these connectors.
Speaker 0: Computers with exclusive USB.
Speaker 0: Do they even still, I don't even think there are computers with exclusive USB.
Speaker 0: My newest computer I think has all USBs and a PS2 port still, a combo one.
Speaker 0: Yup, mine has two PS2 ports.
Speaker 0: And some HDMI's and like an external SATA and some other connectors.
Speaker 1: Ah, eSATA, that didn't really take off.
Speaker 0: No.
Speaker 1: Cables couldn't be long enough.
Speaker 0: But yeah, these are the connectors that existed then.
Speaker 1: So this video will explain what the world of computing was like during the formative years of us using computers.
Speaker 0: Yup.
Speaker 1: In the meta moment, we will not do any more shows this week because we will be at PAX Unplugged in Philadelphia, Pennsylvania.
Speaker 1: Friday, Saturday, and Sunday.
Speaker 1: I'm pretty excited about this.
Speaker 1: Thus starting the era of the PAX's because we're going to go right from PAX Unplugged to MAGFest.
Speaker 1: And then right from MAGFest, very little gap at any point along the way, to PAX South.
Speaker 1: And then PAX East is actually really early this year.
Speaker 1: So PAX East is right on the tails of PAX South.
Speaker 0: Yup, we're going to Unplugged, MAGFest South, wait, wait, East, ah.
Speaker 1: Yup, ah.
Speaker 0: Once we get past East, it's going to be like ah.
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 1: I do know what panels we're doing at PAX South, but we got to talk about PAX Unplugged first.
Speaker 0: So PAX Unplugged is literally a few days from the release of this podcast.
Speaker 0: What are the actual dates?
Speaker 1: It is Friday the 6th through Sunday the 8th.
Speaker 0: It is in the shithole city of Philadelphia.
Speaker 0: But at least it's a PAX.
Speaker 0: You'll survive, I guess.
Speaker 0: Come down and play some games.
Speaker 0: Watch out for Eagles fans.
Speaker 1: It is, I think PAX Unplugged is my second favorite PAX.
Speaker 1: I like West the most for just a lot of reasons.
Speaker 0: Unplugged feels a lot like South, only without video games.
Speaker 1: But the best part about Unplugged is that 95% of what I do at PAX is at PAX Unplugged.
Speaker 0: Yup.
Speaker 0: I think for a lot of video game people, PAX Unplugged would feel like a lesser PAX.
Speaker 0: But for someone who mostly tabletops at PAX, it feels like a full PAX.
Speaker 0: I'm like, what's missing?
Speaker 0: Nothing?
Speaker 1: I do often want to get a group of us to go into the console free play room to play like Old Smash or something.
Speaker 1: But no one's ever up for it.
Speaker 0: We could just do that at our house.
Speaker 1: Can we?
Speaker 1: Will that happen?
Speaker 0: It's easier to do than play board games at our house.
Speaker 1: True, true.
Speaker 1: But we don't have that crew.
Speaker 1: Anyway, we will be doing on Friday, Learn and Play, three short but essential games.
Speaker 0: Alright, and we're going to teach you how to play, hopefully we'll have as long as the panel.
Speaker 0: Two hours.
Speaker 0: I hope we fit it in two hours.
Speaker 1: I think we'll fit it in two hours.
Speaker 0: We're going to teach you how to play Cockroach Poker, Wizard, and I'm going to pronounce it incorrectly.
Speaker 1: Gon-Shane Clever, Gon-Shone Clever.
Speaker 0: Gon-Shane Clever, Gon-Shone, German people, help me out.
Speaker 0: How do I spell the O with two dots on top?
Speaker 1: That's very clever.
Speaker 0: Yes, that's very clever.
Speaker 0: The roll and write dice game is basically super Yahtzee.
Speaker 0: Yahtzee on crack.
Speaker 0: We're going to teach you how to play all three games, one at a time.
Speaker 0: So it's going to be learn, play, learn, play, learn, play.
Speaker 1: It's going to be a really good time.
Speaker 0: So you can even show up late and just learn one of the later games.
Speaker 1: And because these are not games that PAX has in the library, we're bringing the games ourselves to run this thing.
Speaker 1: So that means we can just take this to other conventions that may want to have a learn and play room, but don't have the logistics of PAX.
Speaker 1: And we can just run this at any con that will give us a room of tables.
Speaker 1: I feel like we should bust this out at a future magfest.
Speaker 0: I mean, South did a little bit of learn and play, right?
Speaker 0: But no one came.
Speaker 0: I don't know if they're continuing with that.
Speaker 1: I hope they continue with it.
Speaker 0: I do hope they are, but we'll see.
Speaker 1: And then on Sunday at 3 p.m.
Speaker 1: in the Leviathan Theater, we are doing a panel affectionately titled Take Your Fucking Turn.
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 1: I'm pretty excited about this one because I had an idea.
Speaker 1: When Scott and I came over to the panel, usually we'd have a concept.
Speaker 1: Scott was like, "I want to talk about how games hurt
Speaker 1: people.".
Speaker 1: And then we have a pretty good idea of what we're going to talk about and what the flow would be and what are the important points.
Speaker 1: Loot boxes are evil.
Speaker 1: Games don't make people serial killers, but they do make them gambling.
Speaker 1: That kind of thing.
Speaker 1: And then we do the research and usually we find out we were pretty right.
Speaker 1: We learn a few things along the way.
Speaker 1: Some of the ideas we had about some of our panels, like the Real Armor Games panel, were updated by the data that Scott gathered.
Speaker 1: But with this one, it's basically part one, why do games take so long, and fun economy.
Speaker 1: Part two, the mechanics of that.
Speaker 1: Part three, how to be like us and play a four-hour game in 40 minutes.
Speaker 1: And the panel wrote itself.
Speaker 1: The slides just spewed out because it was exactly something.
Speaker 1: We've talked about this so much.
Speaker 0: Well, you also took, it didn't help that a good chunk of the slides you have ripped off from our other panel about how to win at games.
Speaker 0: Because it just so happens that a lot of the ways to win are also the ways to play fast.
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 1: Heuristics.
Speaker 0: Coincidence.
Speaker 1: But here's the difference.
Speaker 1: Instead of getting deep into heuristic, heuristic, heuristic.
Speaker 0: I think you should shorten some of those slides.
Speaker 0: We don't need them all.
Speaker 1: I think some of those slides are like 10 seconds.
Speaker 1: Because the message there is just don't be our friend Scott and calculate everything in acquire.
Speaker 1: Just do a soft calculation like that one A is bigger than B, not.
Speaker 1: A is 17 cubes and B is 15 cubes.
Speaker 1: Like it's that kind of advice.
Speaker 1: But I'm really excited about this one.
Speaker 1: And I'm going to post a thing announcing our panel for PacSouth.
Speaker 1: And all that stuff is coming.
Speaker 1: The book club book is The Tale of Genji.
Speaker 1: I feel like we're going to read enough of it over the holidays to at least do a part one.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think that's how it's got to be.
Speaker 0: It was, you know, I knew quite a bit about it when I chose it, but I did not understand its length.
Speaker 1: Well, I did.
Speaker 1: And I could have warned you.
Speaker 1: But instead of reading The Tale of Genji a lot on my trip when I had a lot of downtime.
Speaker 0: Like you said you would.
Speaker 1: I ended up mostly beating Link's Awakening.
Speaker 0: Oh, okay.
Speaker 0: Well, that's good because we'll talk about that right now.
Speaker 1: So Link's Awakening.
Speaker 1: Let's go back.
Speaker 1: Let's go back to a heady year.
Speaker 1: 1993.
Speaker 0: Well, the Super Nintendo was already out for a while.
Speaker 0: And so I actually didn't learn the history of Link's Awakening until recently, even though I played Link's Awakening in 1993.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I did not.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I know you didn't.
Speaker 0: So what happened was is Link to the Past had come out.
Speaker 1: In 1991.
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 1: We got it on release day.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the developers on that game, I think one of, there's a YouTube video about this.
Speaker 0: Maybe you can find it and link it.
Speaker 0: I've seen it.
Speaker 1: I've seen, I haven't watched it, but I saw.
Speaker 0: I watched it.
Speaker 0: maybe like, I think someone posted the video maybe a few months ago.
Speaker 0: And that's when I learned the story of, the backstory of Link's Awakening.
Speaker 1: But it began as a port.
Speaker 0: Right, one of the developers on Link's to the Past was like trying to make, you know, Link's Awakening for the Game Boy.
Speaker 1: Now, you have to step back.
Speaker 0: The black and white, or the green and white Game Boy, from Super Nintendo to Game Boy.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you have to step back and think about how utterly insane that is.
Speaker 0: People don't realize that, like, you think Super Nintendo, like whoa, yeah, the Game Boy was contemporary to the Super Nintendo.
Speaker 0: That's the technology level you had in the early 90s.
Speaker 1: Yup, and the Game Boy was pushing it.
Speaker 0: Yup.
Speaker 0: Like, I would go to the doctor's office, the dentist's office, or orthodontist, and they'd have a Sega Genesis, Super Nintendo.
Speaker 0: But then when you sat down to get worked on, they gave you Game Boy.
Speaker 1: What kind of bougie orthodontist did you go to?
Speaker 1: I had nothing.
Speaker 0: Oh, that sucks.
Speaker 0: Our orthodontist even had like a fancy, he lived in like a mansion, and had fancy parties at his house that like all the patients, like literally every patient would come and it was like a field day.
Speaker 1: I can say that I've never been to the house of my orthodontists.
Speaker 1: Either of them.
Speaker 0: We did an egg toss, and I threw an egg, and it broke, and Ricky Cohen got hives because he was allergic to egg.
Speaker 1: Fuck you, Ricky Cohen.
Speaker 0: Even though we came close to winning that egg toss.
Speaker 0: Anyway.
Speaker 0: So, they were secretly working on this game, right, for the Game Boy, and the game, you know, was kind of off the rails and quirky and nutso, but eventually, you know, this one guy was working on it, the other Nintendo developers saw what they were doing, and he was like, "Whoa, what's
Speaker 0: that?".
Speaker 0: And they kept, they were basically, it was like their secret project at night to make fancy Zelda for Game Boy.
Speaker 0: Yup.
Speaker 0: And then eventually, the wind broke, and they were like, "Alright, we'll let you do
Speaker 0: it.".
Speaker 0: And this completely nut job, like, you know, sort of bottom-up grassroots Zelda game was released for the Game Boy.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and I gotta, 'cause I'm gonna read a line from Wikipedia, I'd heard this before, but uh, so the director of the game was Takashi Tezuka.
Speaker 0: That's the guy.
Speaker 1: And I'm gonna read this from Wikipedia, the majority of the Link to the Past team reassembled for Link's Awakening, comma, and Tezuka wanted the game world to feel like the television series Twin Peaks.
Speaker 0: Yup.
Speaker 1: So they set it in a dream.
Speaker 1: And they made it weird.
Speaker 0: That's why it's called Link's Awakening.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the game is literally, Link is asleep in a dream world, and there's like, there's a lot of kami, like Mario's in it, Chain Chomps are in it, there's all this like- There's Goombas, there's Boo the Ghost, there's all this like- There's side-scrolling sections.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there's all sorts of completely nutty, batshit stuff in this game.
Speaker 1: You're gonna find an animal village, it's just animals.
Speaker 1: Right, it's like- You talk to this one rabbit, it's like, you might wonder, like, if there's some magic, like, why can rabbits talk?
Speaker 0: The plot- Don't ask me.
Speaker 0: This game is in this giant egg in the middle of the island that you're trapped on, and you wanna wake, you know, your goal is to wake, to crack the egg and wake the Wind Fish who lives in the egg.
Speaker 1: Break the world's shell.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 1: For the sake of revolution.
Speaker 0: Because you're in the Wind Fish's dream right now.
Speaker 0: Yeah, remember, this takes place- And everyone in the dream is telling you you're in the dream, and the bosses in the dungeons don't want you to get the instruments, they're all guarding instruments.
Speaker 0: Because if you get all the instruments, you can play music that's loud enough, I guess, to wake the Wind Fish up, and which means- They'll all die.
Speaker 0: They'll all cease to exist, because this whole world is just the dream of the Wind Fish that you're in.
Speaker 0: But you go ahead and wake the Wind Fish, which sends Link back to the real world of Hyrule, where he's stranded, floating in the ocean, because his boat crashed.
Speaker 1: It basically takes place, like, right after other Zelda games, like, you beat Ganon- But yeah, basically, someone- After Ocarina of Time and A Link to the Past.
Speaker 0: Okay, but yeah, Link is on a boat, he fucking crashes, he has some sort of fever dream, and then he wakes up.
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 0: Still crashed on a boat.
Speaker 1: In a weary world, but it has none of the- like, it has a lot of item tropes, but the story does not have a, like, Zelda trope.
Speaker 1: There's no Master Sword.
Speaker 0: No, but it's cool how the story matches what's going on in the game, right?
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 0: It's not, you know, it's the same way that Mario 2 does, even though Mario 2 is, like, a different reason.
Speaker 1: Whoa, look, Link to the Past and Mario 2, also just dreams.
Speaker 0: Right, it's like Mario 2, it's sort of like, okay, this is completely nothing like Mario, how do we explain it?
Speaker 0: Ah, Mario is having a dream.
Speaker 0: Well, here, it's like intent- it wasn't like.
Speaker 0: they took another game and put, you know, Mario on it, right?
Speaker 0: It was like, ah, we'll actually make this game, it's completely nutjob, it's nothing like Zelda, look at all this crazy stuff in it.
Speaker 0: Right, but the story is that it's a dream on purpose, right?
Speaker 0: It's like an integrated, not a deus ex machina dream at the end.
Speaker 1: Now, sort of an interesting aside, as Scott alluded to before, and I mentioned repeatedly- You didn't play this game.
Speaker 1: Until the remake, I had never actually played Link's Awakening.
Speaker 0: No, I was like, every time, it was like, "Ray, you haven't played Link's Awakening, what the fuck?
Speaker 0: What the fuck,
Speaker 0: seriously?".
Speaker 1: Part of the reason for that was that I had the game Gear, primarily, and my brother had the Game Boy.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: We had the Game Boy, like- I played it on the Game Boy, I played it on the Game Boy Color.
Speaker 1: Yep, I never had a Game Boy Color, because around- I played it on the Game Boy Color, and it came out.
Speaker 0: So,
Speaker 1: when
Speaker 0: I was a kid,
Speaker 1: I had stupid kid brain, so I played a bunch of Super Nintendo games, I'd played Link to the Past, I saw Link's Awakening was coming out, I saw screens from it, I read about it in Nintendo Power, and I saw it just looked like a knockoff of Link to the Past, which I had already played, and because it was on the Game Boy, I assumed it was just gonna be worse than Link to the Past.
Speaker 0: Very wrong.
Speaker 1: But also, it was 1993.
Speaker 1: That was when I took a hard pivot away from console gaming into PC gaming.
Speaker 1: So, that was basically the era when I stopped playing console games, and I didn't pick up a portable Nintendo console again until the Game Boy advanced.
Speaker 0: When I was doing the hard PC games, I was simultaneously doing the hard handheld games, because, you know, the console games were a lot of monies.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Right?
Speaker 1: And I could pirate PC games.
Speaker 0: Right, exactly.
Speaker 0: But it's like, you know, the job I had, I could go to GameStop and buy plenty of Game Boy games, right?
Speaker 0: Yup.
Speaker 0: And I could bring my Game Boy to school, I'd play those games a lot.
Speaker 0: Anyway.
Speaker 1: So, fast forward.
Speaker 1: Well, what happened was, when Game Boy Color came out- Oh, yeah, yeah, that's some good context.
Speaker 0: They re-released this game as Link's Awakening DX, and what they did is, people don't know, the Game Boy Color was a Game Boy that could play original Game Boy games, and then it would sort of color them the same way the Super Game Boy did.
Speaker 0: If you don't know about the Super Game Boy, that was a Super Nintendo cartridge that you would put a Game Boy game in, and it would play the Game Boy game on your Super Nintendo on the TV, and add some color to it.
Speaker 1: I rented that from Blockbuster a few times, but I never owned one.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so I knew someone who owned one.
Speaker 1: 'Cause I had a lot of Game Boy games.
Speaker 0: So, you, the Game Boy, so Link's Awakening DX was a cartridge that you could play, a DX cartridge was a cartridge you could play in an old school Game Boy or Game Boy Pocket, and it would be black and white.
Speaker 1: Now give 'em a, this is 1998.
Speaker 1: This is much later.
Speaker 0: But if you play it in a Game Boy Color, it would be quite colorized more than a Super Game Boy would colorize it.
Speaker 0: And then they had other games that were Game Boy Color games.
Speaker 0: You could only play them in a Game Boy Color.
Speaker 1: And they just had color.
Speaker 0: You could not play them in a Game Boy or Game Boy Pocket.
Speaker 0: They just had color.
Speaker 0: Not as good as GBA, but pretty good color for the time, right?
Speaker 0: So this, they re-released a lot of the classic Game Boy games on DX cartridges for people with Game Boy Colors to encourage them to go and buy those.
Speaker 0: I actually didn't buy it because I had played it already, but I knew the deal, and I think I played someone else's maybe.
Speaker 0: They basically not only colorized the game, they added a dungeon to the game called the Color Dungeon.
Speaker 1: You had to be able to see color to beat that dungeon.
Speaker 0: And if you couldn't see color, you couldn't really do that dungeon.
Speaker 0: It was like they made color a game mechanic.
Speaker 1: Like those skeletons wouldn't even let you in if you were on a regular Game Boy.
Speaker 1: They'd just be like, "This isn't for
Speaker 1: you.".
Speaker 0: Right, exactly.
Speaker 0: They made a special thing for that.
Speaker 0: And that was pretty cool.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so what happened these times is people who didn't have Game Boys back in the day have not played this game.
Speaker 0: It's been out of print inaccessible to only nerds for quite a long time.
Speaker 1: But in the day, what I didn't notice, because Nintendo powers that every game is 11 out of 10 perfect must-buy.
Speaker 1: But the rest of the world also said that about Link's Awakening.
Speaker 1: I'm not going to say it's better than Link to the Past, but it's on the same level as Link to the Past.
Speaker 0: It's basically amazing.
Speaker 0: They fit.
Speaker 0: You think, "Oh, it's a little Game Boy Zelda game.
Speaker 0: It'd be
Speaker 0: tiny.".
Speaker 0: It's like, "No, it's a full seven, eight dungeon Zelda
Speaker 0: game.".
Speaker 1: The world is huge.
Speaker 1: There's a lot of puzzles.
Speaker 1: There's a lot of things to find.
Speaker 0: Well, the world is sort of huge, but a lot of space is taken up by the raft game and the overworld.
Speaker 1: Well, I guess I'll put it this way.
Speaker 1: The world feels huge because there are a lot of tunnels and caves and dungeons and things.
Speaker 1: So that even though the world is actually physically smaller than another Zelda game, it is very dense.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and also the dungeons got a lot going on.
Speaker 0: They're not like baby nothing dungeons.
Speaker 1: Yeah, some of the dungeons are actually pretty hard.
Speaker 1: The one where you got to walk on top of the orange-blue blocks, that's probably the hardest dungeon in the game.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so they re-released this game on the Switch, but they don't just re-release it so everyone can play it.
Speaker 0: They do a badass HD remake.
Speaker 1: It is so beautiful.
Speaker 0: The HD remake, they basically kept all the original character of the game, all the quirkiness and the puzzles and the items.
Speaker 0: The art style exactly matches the mood of the original, but the only real change from the original game that's meaningful is that the aspect ratio is 16 by 9.
Speaker 0: It's basically the exact same game, almost like 99%.
Speaker 0: Square by square, enemy by enemy.
Speaker 0: The enemies behave the same.
Speaker 0: The weapons are in the same place.
Speaker 0: The controls are almost identical, right?
Speaker 0: The trading puzzle is exactly the same.
Speaker 0: The bosses are the same.
Speaker 1: Because you have more buttons, you can actually have more things equipped at the same time effectively.
Speaker 0: That was actually a unique thing about Link's Awakening.
Speaker 0: You could unequip sword and shield and put whatever you wanted on A and B on the Game Boy.
Speaker 1: I got feather and wizard staff.
Speaker 0: But now you got more buttons, so you pretty much always have sword and shield and you can add more.
Speaker 0: It's a little better.
Speaker 1: Didn't have to equip the pegasus boots.
Speaker 0: But other than that, it is the same game.
Speaker 0: There is no reason to play another version of Link's Awakening now that this just better version exists with just better graphics and sound because it is still the same thing.
Speaker 1: I do like how when you beat the game, it plays the full song at the end, but then it segues into the original Game Boy music a couple times.
Speaker 0: But yeah.
Speaker 0: Really, it just stopped on the back story.
Speaker 1: There's a lot going on here.
Speaker 0: It's almost like Mario All-Stars where it's the same game, right?
Speaker 0: Mario All-Stars versus Mario 1, 2, and 3 wasn't a lot of time, so it wasn't as much of an improvement.
Speaker 0: To go from a Game Boy game to a Switch game is such a dramatic improvement in terms of technology.
Speaker 0: But then to make the same exact game...
Speaker 1: It shows the strength of the core game design of Link's Awakening.
Speaker 0: It shows how good a game the original was that you can literally not change a damn thing and get away with selling it as a $60 Switch game.
Speaker 1: Well, there are some ways where I think it is better than A Link to the Past in the sense that A Link to the Past has many areas that are just difficult to get through because you'll take a lot of damage and you have to fight well to get through them.
Speaker 1: There's a lot less of that in this game.
Speaker 1: This game is more about solving fairly complex puzzles.
Speaker 0: There's definitely a little more puzzle action.
Speaker 1: I'm not saying A Link to the Past doesn't have that.
Speaker 1: I'm saying this is more focused on that and the combat kind of takes a back burner.
Speaker 1: The other thing is that A Link to the Past does have a lot of places in the game where there really isn't anything going on.
Speaker 1: Like there's between other places or journeys.
Speaker 1: But in Link's Awakening, it almost does what Breath of the Wild did where there's some secret on every fucking square of the game.
Speaker 1: There's some secret there.
Speaker 0: Like I said, it was the Game Boy, so the overworld is smaller, right?
Speaker 0: So they really had to cram everything in real tight but still fit a lot of stuff.
Speaker 0: So the secret seashells, those are in the original game, but I think they added... Dampy's Dungeon is the only new thing on the Switch version.
Speaker 1: I did not interact with that at all.
Speaker 0: I did a little bit.
Speaker 0: What it does is basically you go there and you can make your own dungeons by taking rooms.
Speaker 0: You basically acquire rooms, like an inventory of rooms.
Speaker 0: And then you can design dungeons by piecing whatever rooms together as long as they fit.
Speaker 0: And you can design your own dungeons by combining rooms.
Speaker 0: And it's kind of cute and fun, but it's not good enough to be... Like if they made Zelda Maker where you make a Zelda dungeon square by square.
Speaker 1: I would fuck with that a lot.
Speaker 0: Right, that would be the shit.
Speaker 0: But making a Zelda dungeon room by room is not as exciting.
Speaker 1: In fact, I immediately think I would use the Link to the Past rules... Not Link to the Past, I would use the Link's Awakening rules with the feather.
Speaker 1: And I would make a dungeon that was basically StarTropics.
Speaker 0: Yeah, go for it.
Speaker 1: Well, I can't.
Speaker 1: It doesn't exist.
Speaker 0: I mean, you could use actual programming and just make a Zelda-like game.
Speaker 1: I mean, I guess I could.
Speaker 1: I don't care that much.
Speaker 0: You could make a StarTropics mod.
Speaker 1: But I guess it's interesting that this game is so good and in a lot of ways was ahead of its time.
Speaker 1: And in a lot of ways, because I used to always have this feeling that a Link to the Past after that... Like Ocarina of Time is also an important pivotal Zelda game.
Speaker 1: But a lot of the other Zelda games I didn't enjoy that much.
Speaker 1: And it felt like there was a... While there were a lot of high points, there was a downward slope until Breath of the Wild.
Speaker 0: Well, in terms of 2D Zelda games, I think they sort of lost... You could see Minish Cap trying... Minish Cap had nothing going on, though.
Speaker 0: It was trying to be... I guess after this came Ages and Seasons, but those were made by Capcom.
Speaker 0: And those are good, but they...
Speaker 1: They're not great.
Speaker 0: They're great.
Speaker 1: I only played... Seasons was the one that was mostly puzzly.
Speaker 0: No, Ages was puzzly.
Speaker 0: Seasons was more fighty.
Speaker 1: I didn't play Seasons.
Speaker 0: They still both had puzzly and fighty in them, but... Anyway.
Speaker 0: But yeah, I wish someone would remake those and make them easier to play.
Speaker 0: Because who the hell can connect the two Game Boys together these days, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, but this showed that after Link to the Past, they could still make different enough to be fun 2D Zeldas without turning them all into Minish Cap.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like the 2D Zeldas that came later that weren't made by Capcom, where your Minish Cap, that train one that was garbage...
Speaker 1: Oh god, I did not even finish the train one.
Speaker 0: I gave up on it about a third of the way through.
Speaker 0: There was one, a DS one that was okay.
Speaker 1: I'm losing track of which one's which.
Speaker 0: The one that was Wind Waker-y on the DS.
Speaker 1: Oh yeah, that was okay.
Speaker 1: The train one was just so bad.
Speaker 0: The train was the worst one.
Speaker 0: That might be the worst Zelda there is.
Speaker 1: Like, I think it was worse than Minish Cap.
Speaker 0: I didn't finish it.
Speaker 0: Oh, definitely worse than Minish Cap.
Speaker 1: Because while Minish Cap was bad, it was also so easy that it was pretty short.
Speaker 0: Oh yeah, no, the train one was definitely worse than Minish Cap, no question.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Um, you know.
Speaker 1: But, uh, if you were like me, and... Or you're just young enough to where, like, you never encountered a Game Boy.
Speaker 1: Like, this is a must-buy game.
Speaker 1: Just treat it like a brand new Zelda game.
Speaker 1: Just treat it like...
Speaker 0: It's like, you think all that money.
Speaker 0: It's like, actually...
Speaker 1: It is a triple-A.
Speaker 1: I would treat this as a triple-A game today.
Speaker 1: Just like any other triple-A.
Speaker 1: And, uh, I enjoyed the shit out of it.
Speaker 0: And the best thing is that, especially as an older person, right, this is the kind of game where you can play once and be done with it.
Speaker 0: And you don't need to keep going and do anything else.
Speaker 1: I did not get all the seashells.
Speaker 1: I got the 40 necessary.
Speaker 0: You just want to get 40 secret seashells to upgrade your sword.
Speaker 1: But I'm very proud of myself.
Speaker 1: I found them all entirely within the context of the game.
Speaker 1: I didn't read any guide, any fact, anything.
Speaker 1: I treated it like an old NES or Game Boy game back when I was a kid.
Speaker 1: I didn't look up shit.
Speaker 0: I mean, I got a lot of them by memory, you know.
Speaker 0: But, yeah, I just, you know.
Speaker 0: I don't got time for that.
Speaker 1: Well, I figured, because a good design mechanic is, early on, seashells are just a mystery.
Speaker 1: You've got to be like, "Well, that looks like a weird bush that's by itself and surrounded by a circle of things.
Speaker 1: I will cut it.
Speaker 1: Oh, look, a
Speaker 1: seashell.".
Speaker 1: But then when you get the bow-wow, if you have bow-wow with you, he'll run and show you where to dig.
Speaker 1: But once you give him up, you don't have him anymore.
Speaker 0: You can get him with your back.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I never tried.
Speaker 1: Because then they give you this tuning fork that will just ding whenever there's one on the screen.
Speaker 1: And that is great, because then it's more of a puzzle of, "All right, what on this screen could possibly be the
Speaker 1: seashell?".
Speaker 1: Yeah, jump in that hole.
Speaker 1: Yep, throw a bomb in that hole.
Speaker 0: Oh, it's up on that roof?
Speaker 0: How the hell do I get up there?
Speaker 0: I guess I've got to go in every cave in the area.
Speaker 1: There doesn't seem like there's anything on the screen.
Speaker 1: Maybe there's an item I don't have yet, like the shovel.
Speaker 1: But I had a lot of fun with it.
Speaker 1: I only died two or three times.
Speaker 0: I only died early.
Speaker 0: Once you get some hearts, you're good.
Speaker 1: But I died early because I kept trying to damage boost past shit.
Speaker 1: I should have just waited for.
Speaker 1: And I succeeded about half the time.
Speaker 1: Like the Dreaming Shrine.
Speaker 0: Once you get some hearts, and especially if you get the defense armor.
Speaker 1: Which I did not.
Speaker 1: I got the attack armor.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 1: Because I figured, I never get hit by anything anyway.
Speaker 0: Defense, because I figured the enemies don't have a lot of HP.
Speaker 0: So the extra sword doesn't help you.
Speaker 0: Plus, you can get upgraded sword from seashells.
Speaker 1: They do stack though, so the final fight if you have both.
Speaker 0: Is like two hits.
Speaker 1: Yeah, every phase of the thing that the sword can use the sword on is basically like a 2/8 kill.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I mean it's not that much of a kill if you just do a spin attack.
Speaker 1: Yeah, especially if you got two bottles.
Speaker 0: And if you got the shield, you can't really.
Speaker 1: And Crazy Tracy's rubbed your secret medicine all over your naked body.
Speaker 0: Oh yeah, you definitely do not need bottles if you got the armor.
Speaker 1: Are there three bottles?
Speaker 1: I only found two.
Speaker 1: And there was an empty spot in my inventory.
Speaker 0: I think there might be, but I also only had two.
Speaker 1: Because, well part of it, I did get the one at the bottom fishing.
Speaker 1: But I otherwise was not willing to engage with the fishing beyond the bare minimum.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there's a mini, the fishing minigame and the crane game minigame.
Speaker 0: I only did the minimum necessary.
Speaker 0: Yup.
Speaker 0: When I was a kid, I think I did like the maximum on both of them.
Speaker 1: When I was a kid, I think, is that fishing game is actually pretty sophisticated?
Speaker 0: Yeah, no, it's got something on it.
Speaker 0: The Game Boy game?
Speaker 1: You could have sold that as its own game and people would have paid for it.
Speaker 1: Probably.
Speaker 1: That is the state of Game Boy games in the early 90s.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I mean, you know, this is like a passion project made at night.
Speaker 0: They went all in, that's why it's so awesome.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean, the sheer variety.
Speaker 0: It only took 20, 25 plus years to get around to.
Speaker 1: The other thing is like the Minish Cap tried to be funny, but like it wasn't.
Speaker 1: Link's Awakening, honestly, there are many, like it is legitimately funny.
Speaker 0: And also, those jokes that you're laughing at are unchanged.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's the crazy thing.
Speaker 0: Those aren't like updated jokes for the times.
Speaker 0: Those are the same exact dialogues.
Speaker 1: I think my favorite part is the dude who's like, "Man, they don't fucking make roosters like they used
Speaker 1: to.".
Speaker 1: And then you give him a rooster and what he does with that rooster is just A plus.
Speaker 1: Or the dude who's like, "Yeah, just so you know, later on, I'm going to be lost in the mountains.
Speaker 1: Be ready for
Speaker 1: that.".
Speaker 1: And sure enough, like hours and hours later, you're in the mountains and you see this dude and he's just like lost out there.
Speaker 1: So yeah, seriously, like this is a must play game of 2019.
Speaker 1: Like this is one of the best games to come out in 2019, even though it also came out in 1993 and 1998.
Speaker 0: '93 or '98, different time units.
Speaker 1: This has been Geek Nights with Rim and Scott.
Speaker 1: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design, and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at FrontRowCrew.com for show notes, discussion news, and more.
Speaker 1: Remember, Geek Nights is not one, but four different shows.
Speaker 1: Sci-Tech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays, and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 0: Geek Nights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 0: Geek Nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 0: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.
Speaker 1: And the Patreon patrons for this episode of Geek Nights, now that we are back from our nearly month-long hiatus, are still loading as I try to navigate and log back into Patreon.
Speaker 1: This is taking longer than expected.
Speaker 1: Here we go!
Speaker 1: (Reading).
Speaker 1: I give it a 50/50 shot, and if we do a show on Monday, since we're coming back from PAX Sunday night pretty late, and we might be a little bit wrecked, and there is another PAX coming up pretty soon afterward.
Speaker 1: But we'll see.
Speaker 1: Expect still continuing hiatus and delays on shows and skipped content, but we will resume by mid-January at the latest with our usual gusto.
Speaker 1: You'll also see some YouTube videos coming out along the way, but for now, I leave you with... (Singing) (Singing) (Singing) (Singing) (Singing) (Singing) (Singing).