Speaker 0: It's Wednesday October 2nd 2019.
Speaker 0: I'm rim.
Speaker 0: that's good.
Speaker 0: And this is geek nights tonight.
Speaker 0: Promare studio triggers first feature film.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: Okay, so as we have said in our previous few shows we had a huge huge huge pile of opening bits and newses and things of the day and Within one episode we completely forgot all of them.
Speaker 0: I remember like over the two weeks.
Speaker 0: We weren't doing shows like every day.
Speaker 0: I was like, oh if we were doing geek nights tonight, I would talk about this.
Speaker 1: I got like 20 opening bits and then up there all escaped my mind and I thought to myself the same thing.
Speaker 0: I always think I thought the exact words in my own brain.
Speaker 0: There is no way I will forget to talk about this when we resume geek nights.
Speaker 0: It's too good.
Speaker 0: There's no way I could possibly gone.
Speaker 0: It's literally and it's gone my life.
Speaker 0: at this point I'm just like a fish like what happened to me in the last.
Speaker 1: so you can sit.
Speaker 1: If anyone's actually unwisely listening to this.
Speaker 1: Well now you can sit there wondering what all those opening bits that you will never hear were.
Speaker 1: Yeah, because we forgot the only one I didn't lose.
Speaker 1: Let's talk about things that went down just recently that I still remember.
Speaker 0: All I'll say is I when I t-bone that lady on my bike with her bike.
Speaker 0: I talked about that in the forum.
Speaker 1: okay, so first thing It's early October.
Speaker 0: So right.
Speaker 0: I got to make my Twitter Twitter avatar spooky.
Speaker 1: Oh, that's also true.
Speaker 0: I'll do that tonight.
Speaker 1: It's spooky season but also the spooky season is the time to go.
Speaker 1: get a flu jab season.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah Get your flu shot.
Speaker 0: anyone who tells you you shouldn't get your flu shot except a doctor is wrong and anyone not doctor.
Speaker 0: No, I'm gonna be a real doctor.
Speaker 1: if you know anyone who?
Speaker 1: Didn't get a flu shot or his anti-vaxx or something and you know isn't.
Speaker 1: have a real reason like, you know weak immune system.
Speaker 1: Yeah, get a flu shot sneak up on him.
Speaker 1: Yeah, give him the gym.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like if you show up at PAX and you didn't get your flu shot do not fucking come near me.
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 1: In fact, you're lucky I'm not in charge because we would just hold you down and jab you back when we do our and if you or exile you Know we should do the panel.
Speaker 0: We should start, you know, we do that like opening like hey everybody before we actually start the panel We should be like, hey Did anyone here not get their flu shot and then ask anyone who raises their hand to be removed from the room for our safety?
Speaker 0: Uh-huh You know, I'll bet they would but I feel like there would be consequences for us.
Speaker 1: something interesting would happen.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that would be that would be.
Speaker 0: something interesting would happen.
Speaker 0: That is the best way to put that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so what happened to you in the last?
Speaker 0: like 12 to 16 hours?
Speaker 1: so my you know Not only did I move to a new apartment but shortly before that which I have not even been to yet immediately at well It's not it's not in great shape.
Speaker 1: Yeah Immediately before that like as soon as I got back from packs I moved like, you know, like three or four weeks after that.
Speaker 1: right basically three weeks after packs, but Immediately after packs over Labor Day weekend my company moved to a different office where we had Like this crappy old office and then we our team was in like a separate temporary Bree.
Speaker 1: not we work but similar sort of thing.
Speaker 0: ish Right speaking of which you saw we weren't gave up on their IPO for now.
Speaker 0: good Broken up.
Speaker 1: I mean there's better candidates breaking up, but why not them too?
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah Many companies could be broken up anyway.
Speaker 1: So we finally combined the whole New York company at least into one office new office redone.
Speaker 1: Everything's nice You know and since it's a rather progressively minded company, they're doing lots of you know Improvements, you know related to like, you know being environmentally friendly and whatnot, right all that sort of thing, right?
Speaker 1: So one of the things really I work for the place that's like obsessed with that really small common thing is you know Some of the rooms have lights on motion detectors and lights turn off.
Speaker 0: Yeah Oh, there's one conference or my book kind of often but if I if there's only like a few people in it and we sit at the front after about 20 minutes the lights all turn Off and someone has to walk all the way to the back of the room to make the lights turn on again.
Speaker 1: So today I was sitting on the shitter.
Speaker 1: I Happened to me and the lights just turn off.
Speaker 1: Nobody came in to use the bathroom the whole time.
Speaker 0: I was sitting there playing reason the galaxy Yeah, and there's no sensor in the stall with you Wave your hand.
Speaker 1: So the way was pitch black.
Speaker 0: the words that wait, how do you wipe?
Speaker 1: Well, I mean I could.
Speaker 1: I felt around for the teepee?
Speaker 0: Yeah, but you can't until you visually confirm like there is always risk.
Speaker 0: Yeah, basically But yeah, it's the least gross way to describe that problem.
Speaker 1: yeah I managed to you know, open the door wave my hand around.
Speaker 0: actually You know the worst thing about that would be if someone does come in.
Speaker 0: They come in like they used to open the door.
Speaker 0: It's pitch black.
Speaker 0: The lights turn on while they're in there.
Speaker 0: you come out of the stall and they won't have the context of the lights turned out On you.
Speaker 0: all they'll think is why was Scott alone in the dark in the bathroom?
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm Anyway, so that happened.
Speaker 0: At least I can say that that is.
Speaker 0: that is literally happened to me Multiple times in my life at multiple employers.
Speaker 1: a first for me.
Speaker 0: This is why I don't want AI driven facial recognition technology to do a lot of stuff.
Speaker 1: yet I feel like if you're just gonna have the lights turn off in a bathroom You should make it a little smarter right?
Speaker 1: It's like it should also have detectors on the stall doors.
Speaker 1: The light should you know.
Speaker 0: I feel like this is like it's the same problem Microsoft had with the original Xbox because I assume the person they hired to design the controllers had gigantic monster hands.
Speaker 0: I feel like the person that designed all these sensors for bathrooms only has never had a poop that takes more than 20 seconds to complete.
Speaker 0: They've never played for race for the galaxies in the course of one poop Or would be a little much for means the poops a problem.
Speaker 1: so, you know, you got that the phone flashlight is Helpful.
Speaker 0: that is the good backup.
Speaker 0: So someone pointed out that there is an opening bit.
Speaker 0: We should have talked about and this was like of all days.
Speaker 0: today was the day to say this.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm warm today.
Speaker 1: All right, it's like 90 degrees in October.
Speaker 1: It's actually a problem.
Speaker 1: It was Scott.
Speaker 0: the high today was 88.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: What do you mean?
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm?
Speaker 0: I'd looked at a thermometer.
Speaker 0: It was 88 today.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I wasn't that hot.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it was 88.
Speaker 1: Didn't feel that in October is warm, but it wasn't.
Speaker 0: and New York City is having a problem where people.
Speaker 0: It's summer.
Speaker 0: So people are still going to the beach.
Speaker 0: But New York doesn't have like lifeguards at the beach.
Speaker 0: in October beaches closed Labor Day or shortly thereafter Yep, but it's so nice out.
Speaker 0: people are still going to the beach.
Speaker 0: They're just ain't lifeguards or like parking attendants.
Speaker 1: I mean you're allowed to go there.
Speaker 1: You just you know, you go into the water sort of like no one's gonna physically stop you from going in the water But you're not supposed to.
Speaker 1: yeah, but surfer is usually go in the water.
Speaker 0: I feel like it this weekend.
Speaker 0: Maybe I should go to the beach go swim.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: You only the water will start to get cold.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so there's actually I learned from surfers There's a website called like magical seaweed and that website tells you basically where and when to surf like.
Speaker 1: this is like.
Speaker 1: You know like oh, it's sort of like how you're always checking that the snow on the ski mountains.
Speaker 0: Yeah, no Who's got the good snow today?
Speaker 1: magical seaweed is like good waves here bad waves there.
Speaker 1: go to this beach go, you know.
Speaker 0: Yep, that is I assume that exists.
Speaker 0: I assume there's a mountain bike one.
Speaker 0: Like oh, yeah Here's where they go.
Speaker 0: I guess mountain biking doesn't matter as much just is a sunny go.
Speaker 1: No, it's not a sport where you need conditions.
Speaker 0: true Yeah, surfing and skiing are the ones you really need very specific conditions for.
Speaker 0: it can't eat like skiing It's not even just is it cold?
Speaker 0: It's like is there enough of the right kind of snow in this one place right now?
Speaker 0: Surfing are there waves like this and is the temperature like this right here right now?
Speaker 0: I Don't know how it works.
Speaker 1: It's magical seaweed.
Speaker 0: If I lived somewhere else, I would probably take up surfing instead of skiing.
Speaker 1: I mean, I'm okay I'm totally down to surf cuz it's not doesn't seem dangerous or too dangerous in any way.
Speaker 0: It's more dangerous than skiing.
Speaker 1: I mean, I know I don't think so.
Speaker 1: The thing is is that you know, the the cartoon image of surfing which actually is real people do surf.
Speaker 1: I'm like enormous enormous waves.
Speaker 0: Why would you surf unless that's your end goal?
Speaker 1: But be able to do the vast majority of surfing is on waves way smaller and not dangerous at all.
Speaker 0: I mean case in point, you know There are a lot of the surfing happens in the US in fucking Wildwood with those tiny little two-foot waves.
Speaker 1: the super giant wave surfing that you know You imagine is like the stereotypical surfing is pretty rare and only in a few places And only with expert be I get the impression people are actually more likely to die like hiking.
Speaker 0: I Think skiing is safer than surfing, but I can't find like enough evidence to make that case Specifically.
Speaker 0: Mmm.
Speaker 0: I think skiing is less dangerous than surfing though I mean depends cuz drowning is way more likely to happen.
Speaker 0: then like skiing dying is pretty rare.
Speaker 1: I'm just gonna say how many stories of professional surfers do you hear dying?
Speaker 1: and there's more than zero.
Speaker 1: I've heard some.
Speaker 1: I've heard a lot actually But I've heard a lot more stories about professional skiers Like even in the early during the Olympics like crashing into some trees breaking all the bones in their body.
Speaker 0: Yeah, pretty uncommon though.
Speaker 1: I See it happen.
Speaker 0: Yeah, not that often.
Speaker 0: Anyway, anyway, you got any anime news on this anime Wednesday?
Speaker 1: I just got too small anime new.
Speaker 0: I too have small anime news's of two.
Speaker 1: Okay, so the first small anime news is that they're making a Lupin the third Computer-generated animation movie which is actually really old news, right?
Speaker 1: But there's now trailers for it and the cast and the plot.
Speaker 0: Oh, it looks good.
Speaker 1: It actually looks pretty damn good.
Speaker 0: It looks really like I'm feeling this.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's a. so this trailer is way hot The music is hot the the plot seems to be a typical Lupin plot where he's trying to steal something that has some sort of semi-supernatural.
Speaker 0: You know DaVinci Code powers Lupin as a franchise for a while basically up until The Fujiko mean anything that sort of reset it again a lot of Lupin things that were coming out.
Speaker 0: We're not actually that good for a while.
Speaker 1: This appears at face value to follow the Lupin movie formula Of you know, the great upon the third movies.
Speaker 0: Well, I mean look at your normal cast but it's us plus the girl who's only in this movie the plot girl And the one movie villain.
Speaker 1: and you know, it's like.
Speaker 1: it's like.
Speaker 1: yeah, it's cookie cutter, but it is all new But it's a good cookie.
Speaker 0: Yeah Shit out of me a good bunch of sugar cookies.
Speaker 1: the CG looks actually pretty great.
Speaker 1: Yeah So I'll wait to see this when it's all subtitled.
Speaker 1: and all that biz.
Speaker 0: Did you ever actually finish Fujiko mean a no Really?
Speaker 0: It's a real good.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Well, I got there's a lot of things that are real good.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna watch one day.
Speaker 1: How am I watching so much more anime than you?
Speaker 1: cuz maybe I do things besides.
Speaker 1: sit around watching TV.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I do a lot.
Speaker 0: Uh-huh Speaking of what I've been doing I don't spend very I don't.
Speaker 1: I spend very little time in front of the the screen watching shit.
Speaker 0: So speaking of what I've been doing This is a geek bite because I have finished all of Carolyn Tuesday the hot new Watanabe like bones anime music oriented.
Speaker 0: It's not covered.
Speaker 1: You only watched half of it.
Speaker 0: Well, so The first half of it is on Netflix completely.
Speaker 0: They just released the whole thing and it ends at a very good like stopping point because the story is sort of a. The first half of the show is how did these two people become famous?
Speaker 0: Like how did this happen?
Speaker 0: And then the second half of the show is what do they do now in this world?
Speaker 0: That it's basic like ice like American ice?
Speaker 0: are Gestapo Like?
Speaker 0: is it basically a plot point around immigrants and refugees and all they like?
Speaker 0: there's a real serious plot.
Speaker 1: What about this other anime we're gonna review in our main?
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah There are two anti ice movies or shows that have come out and read like around the same time with Actually kind of the same message.
Speaker 0: at least that message interleaves with all the other messages.
Speaker 0: We'll get to that in Carolyn Tuesday.
Speaker 0: It's mice.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they're not even pretending Literally like refugees from Earth like moving to Mars and an anti refugee politician like it's.
Speaker 0: it's really direct.
Speaker 0: They're not fucking around here.
Speaker 0: but so the second the show is still like being finished and The second half of it will drop on Netflix sometime soon.
Speaker 0: I forget what day it's gonna come But basically you can watch the first half of it on Netflix now and it ends at a pretty good point.
Speaker 0: Having watched it all I'm gonna say like I'm gonna spoil anything.
Speaker 0: This is a geek bite one.
Speaker 0: I think it's gonna be one of the great anime.
Speaker 0: Like I get the feels why having watched the first half of this that I got the first time I watch shows like cowboy bebop.
Speaker 0: It just feels real good.
Speaker 0: I find myself rewatching certain scenes a bunch of times on YouTube, which I also find myself doing with things like cowboy bebop.
Speaker 0: The music in it because it's a show about musicians is great.
Speaker 0: There's a lot of songs that are done very well, which is where music anime tend to fuck up and fail.
Speaker 0: It's big-budget like everything about.
Speaker 0: it is great and If you wanted kids on the slope to be good, but you thought it was boring because it was boring It wasn't going anywhere.
Speaker 0: This is actually good and you should 100% watch the show as soon as you can.
Speaker 0: That's all I'm gonna say.
Speaker 1: So when we judged anime, we were correct.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we were a hundred percent correct.
Speaker 0: In fact, I think it's better than we thought it was gonna be because I didn't know Where it was going and where it's going, I don't know what it does.
Speaker 0: with that I mean the second half could fuck it up.
Speaker 0: Don't feel like it's gonna fuck it up.
Speaker 0: I feel like they know what they're doing.
Speaker 0: Hmm.
Speaker 1: Also, uh dubstep grandma Whatever that is is good.
Speaker 0: Oh the tooth it.
Speaker 0: You know how a lot of anime are funny and that they have jokes But you don't actually laugh out loud at any point cuz they're not that funny.
Speaker 0: I laughed out loud a lot at this show kind of like when I watch cowboy bebop.
Speaker 0: But the points I think you specifically Scott will laugh out loud are the dubstep grandma and the mermaid sisters.
Speaker 1: The mermaid sisters, when are they coming over?
Speaker 0: I Would go if the mermaid sisters were a real band.
Speaker 0: I would fucking go to their concert like no, I would stand in line to get tickets to see them perform live.
Speaker 1: No one sells tickets and lines anymore.
Speaker 0: I'm did obviously a digital line obviously.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so what's your other anime news?
Speaker 1: Oh, well You know There's this convention in New York called anime NYC that we've talked about every year since it came into existence And we've been to it zero time.
Speaker 0: We never go because either it overlaps with some of like some geek nights thing We got to do or some travel or something.
Speaker 0: It doesn't overlap with shit.
Speaker 1: we can totally go to it.
Speaker 0: a few times that overlapped.
Speaker 0: or As the producer of geek nights or I'd like I arrange all of our convention appearances.
Speaker 0: I keep fucking forgetting to talk to them and sort stuff out until it's way too late.
Speaker 0: Cuz there's way too many taxes for me to deal with like I'm I've.
Speaker 0: you know how many packs is.
Speaker 0: I've had to schedule for us in the last like two weeks.
Speaker 1: Anyway, it's at the Javits Center for November 15th to 17th.
Speaker 0: It is the facts of anime conventions like.
Speaker 1: it's real big It's not you know, just based on you know on paper.
Speaker 1: It does have some issues.
Speaker 1: I think they do some VIP biz, but you're not a big fan of Right, but in general it seems to be a great giant anime con in New York City, you know.
Speaker 1: It's not run by read, right?
Speaker 1: You know, it sort of broke away from.
Speaker 1: you know It's a lot of those people who were involved in that New York anime festival.
Speaker 1: They busted away.
Speaker 0: I think we talked about this way back when this first came out, but yeah It's like an a-team of the kinds of people who worked for the companies that made anime conventions or volunteered for Anime conventions right who wanted to do the right thing and the conventions were stupid and basically they formed the power team of all Those people
Speaker 1: anyway, so there are already been a lot of huge guests announced for this year's but it's November 15th to 17th For this year's anime NYC.
Speaker 1: They've already announced a ton of huge guests including Kill Em All to me know creators of the Dr.
Speaker 1: Stone manga the illustrator of Monogatari A voice actress named Miku Ito, I don't know You know, but as I get older, I honestly pay less attention to the voice actors.
Speaker 1: You know a jam project and a bunch of other musical guests are gonna be there Right, but they just announced a big-time Japanese voice acting guest who has never ever even once appeared at a US convention.
Speaker 1: So only the weebs are gonna know.
Speaker 1: Yeah about Rie Kukimiya.
Speaker 0: Yeah, let's see Alphonse from Fullmetal Alchemist, Happy from Fairy Tail.
Speaker 1: Have you seen any of these other anime that this person has voice acted in?
Speaker 0: No, I know they're popular, but these are not my anime, right?
Speaker 1: It's like this is a very other than Fullmetal Alchemist and Gintama.
Speaker 1: I've never seen an anime this person voice acted in but I can still recognize like this person is way big deal.
Speaker 0: Oh, they also do Oda Nobunaga in Fate Grand Order.
Speaker 0: Okay If you do not know What that is, it's not the Oda Nobunaga you're thinking of.
Speaker 1: No, it is not.
Speaker 0: But it actually technically is it's.
Speaker 0: uh anyway There are many Oda Nobunagas.
Speaker 1: Right, the point is this is like a big-time Guest announcement right never before and I wish they would have gotten the person to
Speaker 0: do
Speaker 1: The Japanese voice of Edward Elric, whoever that is Because I misread this post at first and was about to be like
Speaker 0: Yep, yep, actually that that segues nicely into my news.
Speaker 1: I was about to make a funny tweet, but I couldn't.
Speaker 0: yeah, so People have been asking me to summarize this.
Speaker 0: you can just read it.
Speaker 0: The bad talked about it a little bit on gig nights But basically Vic Mignona the guy who voice-acted Edward Elric and a whole bunch of other characters across a bunch of popular anime in America Terrorized many anime cons.
Speaker 0: Yeah, uh kind of in my personal opinion based on my interactions with him and my Discussions of him with other people who have had first-hand interactions with him.
Speaker 0: He's kind of a piece of shit like he's an annoying demanding kind of shitty dude who always gave off bad vibes and as you all know It looks like he was also a creepy person and did a bunch of creepy stuff and you can read all about it here.
Speaker 0: I don't want him to sue me because seems like I keep suing people but he sued a bunch of people in the industry because His complaint was they fired him because he's a creep and that is defamation and slander and all that kind of crap He lost.
Speaker 0: like that lawsuit went nowhere because it was ridiculous.
Speaker 0: he hired a lawyer who is Basically the Lionel huts of this kind of thing.
Speaker 0: Like the guy fucked up real bad.
Speaker 0: the whole situation was disaster.
Speaker 0: the lawsuit was a mistake.
Speaker 0: But the thing that happened that you should all know from the anime industry perspective and anime news perspective Is that the lawsuits basically over.
Speaker 0: he did lose.
Speaker 0: there's like one last thing that's gonna happen where he's gonna fail in this mediation thing and then it's done, but the mob of Weeb's who are weirdly obsessed with him is a real fucking problem.
Speaker 0: now in anime There's more of them than you think.
Speaker 0: they're basically doing a hundred percent the gamer gate thing.
Speaker 0: They've been harassing the judge in the case Like directly like vandalizing his Facebook wall and stuff.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like judges looking at his Facebook wall often.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, but think about this.
Speaker 0: the weebs are organized the judge even knows.
Speaker 0: uh So we'll see what comes of that.
Speaker 0: because they're.
Speaker 0: they're sending death threats all over the place.
Speaker 0: They're using hashtags just like gamergate did.
Speaker 0: they're doing mass like reporting antics on Twitter.
Speaker 0: They're going after people on Facebook.
Speaker 0: They're doxxing.
Speaker 0: It is literally just another gamer gate mmm, and it's growing.
Speaker 1: I'm sure there's like 20 of those happening that you don't even know about.
Speaker 1: Oh, there aren't that many in circles that you don't even know.
Speaker 0: they tend to focus the.
Speaker 0: those things tend to focus on nerd franchises and Partly because there are a lot of aggrieved shitty incel type white dudes who are really easy to trick with this stuff.
Speaker 0: so It's basically all over.
Speaker 0: But what you got to watch out for is that this mob is going around like attacking and harassing people and I think they're gonna Get a little more potentially violent and angry when the final verdict happens.
Speaker 0: If you run an anime convention all I'm saying is anyone that you are booking to do panels Anyone that you are interacting with in the industry Just check their social media tags and make sure they're not interacting with the I stand with Vic hashtag.
Speaker 0: That is literally just gamer gate for anime.
Speaker 0: if they even are adjacent to that just hard pass block them and move on.
Speaker 0: And if you want to know more about like the full details of this ridiculous clown circus that happened.
Speaker 0: I will link to this CBR article that talks in depth about all the ridiculous crap that happened.
Speaker 0: It would be funny if it wasn't so sad.
Speaker 1: hmm and one final news that is unrelated to any anime manga or comics.
Speaker 1: Whoa, but today is October 2nd, which is the first day of hockey.
Speaker 1: Oh shit In 2019, I'm a 20/20 season.
Speaker 0: I feel like here we go.
Speaker 0: Should we do our next Tuesday show on The preview of the upcoming hockey season or something.
Speaker 1: What do you?
Speaker 1: what the fuck?
Speaker 1: Do you know fucking nothing?
Speaker 0: I got you know, I've got I have nothing to do shit.
Speaker 0: Oh, wait.
Speaker 0: Wait, here's what I got.
Speaker 0: I have uninformed conjecture Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: I have.
Speaker 1: can you even name players on other teams besides the Red Wings or the Rangers?
Speaker 1: No, really name for me one player on the Nashville Predators predators.
Speaker 0: Oh Did they trade him?
Speaker 0: I'm worried that the people anyone I would mention has been traded.
Speaker 0: I'm just gonna say now.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so you have no place.
Speaker 1: season preview Scott.
Speaker 0: I'm doing a Rangers preview.
Speaker 1: if you need any sort of preview or any sort of hockey info You should go to respected sports journalists who are full-time paid sports journalists.
Speaker 1: Yeah doing this all day and not to rim who knows next to nothing.
Speaker 0: No, I'm saying if you want unfounded and uninformed conjecture, let's do a different show.
Speaker 1: You want someone who talks 90% about the Rangers who just make stuff up because you don't know nothing.
Speaker 1: And what you're gonna do is read something and repeat what you read.
Speaker 1: I probably could have just read that to begin.
Speaker 0: I think the other thing I would actually talk about for the entire time is the rules changes.
Speaker 1: We can talk about the rules.
Speaker 0: actually that would be a good Tuesday show.
Speaker 1: That is the thing that we can talk.
Speaker 0: that would be a really good Tuesday show.
Speaker 0: Yes, remind us on Monday because I've already forgotten what we were gonna do this show on.
Speaker 1: You can do a show about all sorts of sports rule changes.
Speaker 0: Oh, that would be a good.
Speaker 0: that would be a good panel.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like in a PAX.
Speaker 0: Anyway, I'm gonna put that in for PAX East.
Speaker 0: But anyway things of the day what he got.
Speaker 1: so here's a bunch of baby alligators right already cute I guess Scott the fuck.
Speaker 1: Hmm.
Speaker 1: These are not alligators crocodiles, whatever all same shit.
Speaker 0: There's a big difference between an alligator and a crocodile.
Speaker 1: Fuck you alligators crocodiles.
Speaker 1: I'm putting you together.
Speaker 0: Fuck alligators crocodiles are where it's at.
Speaker 0: Anyway, the point is you picked the right one.
Speaker 1: There's a bunch of babies Scott.
Speaker 0: Do we need to play?
Speaker 0: is it Ireland or is it Scotland again?
Speaker 1: No, I don't care.
Speaker 1: They're all the same.
Speaker 1: now deal with it.
Speaker 1: Now golf and Barney stones and deal with it.
Speaker 0: Oh god, I'm glad you at least got one of each there.
Speaker 1: Difference between the United Britain and Great Britain, so these baby Floridians here Make albion ease they make a bunch of cute noises and it just so happens that in this video They're making these cute noises and they sound Incredibly like a Galaga machine.
Speaker 1: I love shockingly like a Galaga machine.
Speaker 0: I love it when cuz you know There's animals that people encounter a lot of their lives like doggos.
Speaker 1: I feel like I should have just taken a Galaga machine and dubbed it over.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that would have been.
Speaker 0: we could do that Galaxian doo-doo-doo-doo.
Speaker 0: But I love it when animals that Normal people don't encounter on a regular basis make a noise that normal people would not expect them to make.
Speaker 1: Well, I think it's you know, people learn the cow goes moo.
Speaker 1: The duck goes quack.
Speaker 1: They don't realize that the Fox the Fox goes right, sometimes There's a bunch of animals and no one ever fucking teaches you what sound they make, you know, the whale goes.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but it's like, you know, what the fuck noise does?
Speaker 1: uh, I don't know.
Speaker 1: Fucking Rhino make mmm.
Speaker 1: Yeah, pretty much right?
Speaker 1: That's you.
Speaker 1: That's a good guess.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's probably right, but you don't fucking know that That would be.
Speaker 0: there's a game.
Speaker 0: There's an interview question.
Speaker 0: Just get someone to make all the noises of every animal in alphabetical order.
Speaker 1: Yeah, weird-ass animals and I bet the thing is it's probably a bunch of animals that do make a noise.
Speaker 1: We just don't know what fucking noise they make because it's too small, right?
Speaker 1: I bet if I was spider size, I would be like, oh spider goes.
Speaker 0: so Rabbits you think they don't make noise right like that like they don't yell or anything.
Speaker 0: They don't have like a barking noise.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they make noise.
Speaker 0: Like what?
Speaker 0: What do you?
Speaker 0: what noise do you think they make?
Speaker 1: Oh, they got little.
Speaker 1: they go teethy noises.
Speaker 0: Yeah, when they're biting stuff.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they'll thump when they're mad where they want attention.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they can vocalize.
Speaker 0: usually they only do it when they're extreme pain or distress of some kind.
Speaker 0: Some weird rabbits just yell because they're weird not common.
Speaker 1: I was actually reading something recently that was like yeah cats didn't vocalize They meowed because of humans.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't know if that's true or not.
Speaker 1: I read a thing that is recent.
Speaker 0: claim that that is recent very like very fascinating research actually.
Speaker 0: so My thing of the day is actually related to this because rabbits do make these tiny little vocalizations That you wouldn't hear.
Speaker 0: unless you're like really up close and really paying attention Like Moogie when he's eating stuff and he's excited you'll hear these tiny little like Mmm, like he gets excited.
Speaker 0: So this channel Basically mics.
Speaker 0: they mic up their rabbit with a really sensitive microphone and it's basically rabbit ASMR.
Speaker 0: Like here's the rabbit eating a watermelon and you just get like the sounds of a rabbit eating a water.
Speaker 1: We got two animal noise things of the day.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you're telling me remember the old days We used to do like week-long themes of things of the day.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we don't have that many spare things of the day.
Speaker 0: I remember when we did hockey fights for a week.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well the internet now has you know, a lot less cool things of the day and a lot more bad news Yeah, or a lot more.
Speaker 0: This is a cool thing of the day But it's literally just the next video from the guy who I've already used for like eight things of the day.
Speaker 0: Yep Like the Tecmoan guy.
Speaker 0: I'm trying to avoid linking to him.
Speaker 1: Product testing guy.
Speaker 0: Yep There's I feel like maybe we should do a show on that like where do we get our long-form cut like the like?
Speaker 0: what?
Speaker 0: Are there really are reliable go-to?
Speaker 0: show me something.
Speaker 1: interesting channels every kpop music show.
Speaker 1: Yeah Be hey test kitchen.
Speaker 0: In the meta moment the geek nice book club book is still the tale of Genji.
Speaker 0: not just a novel but The first novel.
Speaker 1: yeah, I haven't.
Speaker 1: I've started reading it and I was making some moves and then I moved and I haven't started reading it again, so once Everything in my apartment is settled.
Speaker 1: I'll probably be able to like, you know get in bed and start reading again.
Speaker 0: Yep, so, uh still be a long one before we get into the.
Speaker 0: it's also a long book Yeah, because we're going full hardcore on a bridge.
Speaker 0: But I know Bridgman having read a bit of it when you said you were reading it.
Speaker 0: I've paused now because you paused but I Get the same feeling I got when I was reading the long on a bridge count of Monte Cristo in the sense that yeah It's long but stuff just keeps happening and I'm always just like all right.
Speaker 1: All right All right.
Speaker 1: Well, you have to remember this thing was originally released as like several separate chapters.
Speaker 0: Well, I mean the count of Monte Cristo was like here's a chapter in the newspaper every week exactly.
Speaker 1: So this was you know, and this was only like for rich people, right?
Speaker 1: Because I guess other people even how to read yeah, or you couldn't get definitely couldn't get books and paper.
Speaker 1: It's not like that a pretty press or whatever, right?
Speaker 0: So Yeah Yep, the other about big metabit because we do know there's a lot of stuff going on.
Speaker 0: But the thing I really want to point out because it's Wednesday is that many of you in fact someone is in the live stream agitating right now asking us what we think of pro mayor because if you've noticed the format of geek nights is we talk for like 20 ish minutes about
Speaker 1: Bullshit.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Well stuff that is either bullshit or That's really only relevant now and like you don't care about this if you listen to this episode Ten years from now right when this someone is listening to this in some year.
Speaker 1: well, well into the future from 2019 if the world still exists.
Speaker 1: and They're listening all this pre-promare stuff like what the fuck?
Speaker 1: but really they're just wondering if they should watch this movie promare Which is now readily available on the.
Speaker 1: you know, I guess one dollar a month every old anime ever.
Speaker 0: Well, I case in point.
Speaker 0: on December 28th 2005 on geek nights we reviewed samurai Champloo like we talked me to review.
Speaker 0: We also talked about some windows exploit from 2005 and how it looks like blu-ray might win the fight against HD DVD.
Speaker 1: You're right Blu-ray did win the fight and then it lost.
Speaker 0: you don't?
Speaker 0: you do not want to hear us talk about the blu-ray news You just want samurai Champloo.
Speaker 1: That's right.
Speaker 0: So what I'm doing and I posted a bunch of these already and I'm gonna like put one of these out like once a week for a long time because We've reviewed a crazy amount of anime over the last 15 years of doing geek nights.
Speaker 0: So I'm taking just the main bits from those episodes just the reviews I'm pulling them out and I'm uploading them both to YouTube and to the patreon.
Speaker 0: So well, you don't have to any money It's free.
Speaker 0: I'm not making these like hidden behind the paywall.
Speaker 0: so you can subscribe to the main bits patreon RSS feed and you'll get Just the anime reviews that we do and have done for the last 15 years About once a week without having to listen to any of our old news Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: So I've already uploaded four of these and I'm gonna try to do one once a week.
Speaker 0: So I did our Evangelion review our Evangelion final thoughts our big o final thoughts and a movie that neither of us remember at all that we reviewed Called the boy who saw the wind Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: So I think next what I'm gonna put up is uh, actually, I'm not gonna spoil it They'll just appear in the feed as they appear.
Speaker 1: So promare we finally get to it.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: Well, here's the deal.
Speaker 1: right studio trigger the makers of such fine anime as Kill-la-kill little witch academia Etc.
Speaker 1: Etc.
Speaker 0: The studio that saved anime.
Speaker 1: Yes They've made a move a full-length Animated motion picture.
Speaker 1: now This is our first one and as we say if there's an anime movie in the theater That's not a sequel even if it's just like brooms.
Speaker 1: You should go sooms.
Speaker 0: Yeah There aren't that many anime movies that are feature length full of production value Released in theaters and are not a sequel to like Pokemon or Yu-Gi-Oh or not like one piece movie 12 or some shit like that.
Speaker 1: The second, you know compilation movie of existing anime TV series Yeah, ones that are original stories, you know things like that.
Speaker 1: They're pretty rare.
Speaker 1: So if you're if you're an anime fan, you know It might be hard to go back in time and watch all of them.
Speaker 1: But you should go back in time and watch all the great ones.
Speaker 1: It won't take that long.
Speaker 1: There's not too many.
Speaker 0: and if you live in a major city in America in the u.s.
Speaker 0: They're all in the theater, right?
Speaker 1: It used to be that you know back in the day You could only see them really at like.
Speaker 1: in New York at like we used to go to like IFC or stuff like that.
Speaker 1: Right, but now thanks to what it called the fathom events and whatnot You know a small company a small distributor like G kids or Funimation can now through that fathom events Put their movie on the screens in theaters around the country for like one or two nights only.
Speaker 0: So it's not even like oh go to Manhattan to the weird theater one night only.
Speaker 0: it's like go to the movie theater We normally go to in Queens.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we went to just a normal old multiplex that shows all the you know But it's like are they showing the dub on one night and the sub two nights later, and that's it.
Speaker 0: They got you back.
Speaker 0: They know what's up.
Speaker 0: They know.
Speaker 0: Yep, so you can go see this.
Speaker 1: the sub which is the May or may not have missed your chance to see it in the theater in the.
Speaker 0: I saw some.
Speaker 1: There are still some screenings out there.
Speaker 0: I believe in some markets.
Speaker 1: They extended promirs Theatrical release because I think it's made like a million dollars.
Speaker 1: the US box office It's doing well as far as doing well for a extremely limited run and non-english anime movie in the u.s.
Speaker 0: Yep, so before we get into the like the full review the TLDR version is just go see it Of course, like just automatically just go see it.
Speaker 1: even before I saw it I would tell you that because we said it's an anime, but now that I've seen it go see it Seriously like.
Speaker 1: so all I knew is that this is a movie by studio trigger.
Speaker 1: So I know expectations based on what I know about studio trigger.
Speaker 1: But this basically is even be like.
Speaker 1: not only did it meet the expectation It basically was too on target.
Speaker 1: It is literally studio trigger the movie.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like the way it put it They just went in they went all in on what they are good at and who they are.
Speaker 1: They didn't try to do anything new.
Speaker 1: They just did what studio trigger does as hard as they possibly could.
Speaker 0: it's like the opposite of what happened with Mary and the witch's Flower.
Speaker 0: it's like hey, we're gonna make a Ghibli movie but not be Ghibli.
Speaker 0: and they made a not that good Ghibli esque movie.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but this is literally like Scott said it best.
Speaker 0: This is studio trigger the movie and if they made a premiere - I would go see it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's the way I would describe it before we even get into details.
Speaker 0: Is that is you know like an anime movie has like the of the first act the twist the second act the big Climaxi scene and then the denim on.
Speaker 0: Take that big climax II seen and literally make that the entire movie and never fucking stop.
Speaker 0: pretty much There's like a few scenes where it slows down a little and they're not even that long.
Speaker 0: This movie just it.
Speaker 0: it just shoves Anime into your face as hard as possible.
Speaker 0: take the biggest action scene in giant Robo and make that an entire movie Mm-hmm, and I loved every second of it.
Speaker 0: The other thing is it's the plot is there are firefighters What is nothing.
Speaker 0: the plot is there are firefighters and there are fire terrorists?
Speaker 1: Yep Well the whole world the plot is actually something weird happened that we don't can't explain.
Speaker 1: Yeah, where some people were suddenly on fire The war the entire world the entire world got set on fire literally and the post-apocalyptic You know reborn society firefighting is really there are still some fire people around.
Speaker 1: So there are.
Speaker 1: but you know The societal structure has basically firefighters who go out and deal with the fire-causing people as well as a Gestapo a separate Gestapo like police force that arrests the fire people and prisons them and then that Gestapo Literally starts arresting people who are obviously Immigrants effectively.
Speaker 1: Yes, they have like it.
Speaker 1: Yeah They use ice weapons Literally, yep, and and if you're a non-white worker in a restaurant making pizza He's making the best pizza and all he wants to do with his firepower is make the best pizzas.
Speaker 1: And then they find out that he is a you know fire person and they come and arrest him.
Speaker 1: He's working there making pizzas like if you know all the racist people in the restaurant are like Oh, I don't like this pizza anymore and leave.
Speaker 1: there is firefighters who aren't races.
Speaker 0: There is zero Ambiguity that it is ice ice.
Speaker 1: No, but yeah, it's.
Speaker 1: uh The plot is not much of a plot.
Speaker 1: Well the plot so it's basically the plot.
Speaker 1: in a mood to set things on fire and have giant robot.
Speaker 0: yep, but the plot in terms of like forget the anime something like What the major characters are doing and why.
Speaker 0: I'm not saying it's complex But it's more than you would expect.
Speaker 0: like the villain has fairly complex and interesting motivations.
Speaker 0: Like more so than I expected Scott did you ever actually see all of giant robo?
Speaker 0: Yeah, said.
Speaker 0: all I'll say if you have seen giant robo the end and like what the real plot is and like the final moments of this movie are so so parallel Directly to the end of giant.
Speaker 1: I don't think it's.
Speaker 1: actually I don't think it comes from giant robo.
Speaker 1: I think it just comes from the same source material as giant robo, which is old giant robot animes Yeah, but more the like.
Speaker 0: what did you?
Speaker 0: it's that?
Speaker 0: What did you expect me to do with this moment from giant robo?
Speaker 0: Similar sort of situation in from air.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean this.
Speaker 1: similar sort of situations in like, you know, Gigantor and messenger and whatever From the same cloth.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but giant robo really crystallized it.
Speaker 0: Uh-huh.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so Yeah, not this is not a spoiler even though it is a thing that happens near the end of the movie.
Speaker 1: This is a movie where a robot that is so enormous It the entire earth is on fire.
Speaker 1: This robot punches the on fire earth and the entire solar system sets on fire.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that is a thing that happens in this movie.
Speaker 1: It's not a spoiler because what the fuck can you make of that?
Speaker 1: Yeah, but that's the kind of movie you're going into, you know.
Speaker 0: So, you know in the gun drill through the earth insanity or you know Like the open like giant robo starts in media res it literally just starts with this crazy train and a giant action.
Speaker 1: Yeah, this starts with after they explain the history of the world briefly.
Speaker 1: Yeah, this building on fire the firefighters are going with their robots to fight the fire.
Speaker 1: Yep, and all the fire like hydrants on the street are actually like little mecha City is very Evangelion nerve city where the whole construction of the city is designed to help fight fires Every same way that you know the nerve city or whatever.
Speaker 1: It's called Tokyo seven random fucking.
Speaker 1: remember.
Speaker 0: Every character is a ridiculous over-the-top Character of something like they're.
Speaker 0: they're as ridiculous as you could possibly imagine and a lot of them use.
Speaker 1: they're basically Transplanted characters from other trigger anime which I like is like there's like the big dude.
Speaker 1: Yeah Gamagori is gamagori and then you know the sciency girl who handles all the tech stuff.
Speaker 1: It's obviously just the hat girl from kill la kill all those characters in the firefighting team.
Speaker 0: I was getting these vague like bubblegum crisis vibes a little bit Like it almost made me want to go watch bubblegum crisis again.
Speaker 1: Well the also the the chief guy with the mustache Yeah, you know plus all the vehicles gave me a lot of tank police vibe.
Speaker 0: Especially there is literally a scene where a fire truck starts rolling through a hallway that is narrower than the truck.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that is like the iconic scene in tank police.
Speaker 0: well the second most iconic scene the most iconic scene is all the penises.
Speaker 0: but This movie is Just ridiculous and over-the-top to the point that I am hesitant to try to describe anything about it beyond that.
Speaker 1: Well, I also got to point out, you know, this is for all the the people's out there.
Speaker 1: this movie is pretty gay Yes, but it.
Speaker 0: but here's the important point.
Speaker 0: There is no romantic subplot No, which I'm very.
Speaker 0: that is refreshing.
Speaker 0: There is a female love interest and a male love interest.
Speaker 1: There is a brief scene where they obviously The camerawork is done in such a way to make you think up.
Speaker 1: main character, dude Who's gonna kiss, you know, the hot girl that is also a firefighter and like she likes him Basically just gets on his motorcycle and drives away.
Speaker 1: and then there is another scene where it's like, oh he's good Oh, he's gonna give you know, it's.
Speaker 1: it's that old mouth-to-mouth resuscitation situation You know, but there's basically it's.
Speaker 1: it is inferred in such a way as like yes There's something there and they don't make it explicit with the main character.
Speaker 0: is that either gay or bisexual?
Speaker 0: It's openly right.
Speaker 1: it's a shame that they don't make it more explicit But they clearly though, you know via the it is unspoken that like yeah He is not interested in that girl.
Speaker 1: He's yeah, I stayed in.
Speaker 0: you know, I guess what I what is refreshing.
Speaker 0: I'm glad it wasn't
Speaker 1: darling in the franks Yeah, which I haven't even watched but I know that like yeah There's a dude and the girls all bent over in front of him here the two dudes combined in the robot Not that the girl doesn't combine in the robot with the other dude, yeah, okay the two dudes combined in the robot.
Speaker 0: But I'm glad there's no romantic subplot only in the sense that I hate that.
Speaker 0: that just is in everything.
Speaker 0: Always the fact that it's not actually a subplot and it's just about these people.
Speaker 0: But at the same time their attraction to each other is not in any way hidden.
Speaker 0: It's just there.
Speaker 0: It's also a movie like I almost want to just send this to my dad and be like, hey, it's a movie about firemen.
Speaker 1: No, it's not.
Speaker 0: It technically is.
Speaker 1: but no this is it just.
Speaker 1: Firefighting is merely the you know facade for which it is a you know Tactical.
Speaker 0: they literally fight fires superhero team.
Speaker 0: They fight fires with.
Speaker 1: It's like it's like if you just repainted gatekeepers and put like a fire Emblem FDNY on the side of the gatekeepers vehicles.
Speaker 1: that doesn't make them firefighters.
Speaker 0: The other thing I really appreciated was that it's such crazy over-the-top action.
Speaker 1: the colors are Amazing like the colors the lines like everything about those aesthetic and how they managed to combine the CG Right and the you know, the the regular non CG animation in such a way, right?
Speaker 1: That is it not the way that Spider-man spider-verse does it?
Speaker 1: Yeah, right like a new and different way.
Speaker 1: It's pretty you know, it just has.
Speaker 1: there's like tons of energy in it.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: the one thing is What was I gonna say in the early part of the movie?
Speaker 0: the city itself looks very CG and sterile And I fed to the point that I thought that was on purpose and there was gonna be a plot around that which there wasn't.
Speaker 0: No, but otherwise like it just looks so good and in the midst of all this chaos That what is actually happening on screen still like makes sense.
Speaker 0: Which a lot of thing.
Speaker 0: a lot of anime and even live-action movies that try to go crazy like that Tend to lose this like Transformers movies.
Speaker 0: the perfect example.
Speaker 0: It doesn't actually make sense.
Speaker 0: What's happening?
Speaker 1: I mean if you will go on Twitter, right, you know an anti Twitter people often post like these gifts of Like a brief cut from an anime to show you like the insane Animation in that sequence that somebody did by hand way back in the day, right?
Speaker 1: You'll always feel like the one from Matt cross where it's like, all right the plane They're fighting outside the macros and then they're in the city and then they transform and then they chase and then right and then You know There's also the scene where like they're falling and the cockpit opens up and they fall out and then they come back in and he grabs And closes it right.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like these, you know, if you watch those old anime that have these scenes in them It's like most of that show will be the cheapest barely moving Cut, you know low-budget animation Yeah, just talking heads and stuff like that.
Speaker 1: And then during the action scene, they'll have this one Sequence.
Speaker 1: they put tons of effort into that.
Speaker 1: You can then clip and make an animated gif for Twitter.
Speaker 1: That will be amazing.
Speaker 1: Wow, look at that incredible animation this entire movie.
Speaker 1: You could basically pick any Starting and stopping point and the whole thing will be You know Twitter gif worthy.
Speaker 1: it's just non-stop anime Twitter gif of amazing animated action sequence.
Speaker 1: also, I cannot stress enough the Absolutely bumping soundtrack and if it ever pauses for a moment and there's no action instead you get like breathtaking Beautiful still background kind of every frame of this movie would be a fine desktop background.
Speaker 0: Yes, every single frame.
Speaker 0: Yeah But the music is fantastic.
Speaker 1: It's the same composer that you heard, you know and kill la kill and all the others Yeah trigger things with that same kind of energy.
Speaker 0: But the animation is like really set against the music very well and the music is varied Within the confines of the movie.
Speaker 0: Yes, wait, like to the point that I've just been listening to the soundtrack at work So it's on YouTube.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the other thing along all those lines is that despite all this nonsense and like all this crazy crazy There's a ton of humor and like little jokes and like Little bits that would be easy to miss.
Speaker 0: and the movie and I really really appreciate this because it's so rare They trust you to just notice this shit It's so fast.
Speaker 1: If you you have you don't notice it, you're gonna miss it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but like the movie trusts you to notice all these really little jokes without going back like hey Did you get the joke?
Speaker 0: Did you?
Speaker 0: did you get it?
Speaker 1: Yeah, and I mean that's the thing is like it moves crazy fast But it's not crazy fast like Excel saga, or what was that other one?
Speaker 1: That was crazy fast.
Speaker 0: Oh the one that the one we're god, this is so long ago the elf princess rain.
Speaker 0: Yeah, something like that right where it's not just like who the fuck listening to geek nights remembers elf princess rain.
Speaker 1: Is that I'm so calm so smart.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: That's the one.
Speaker 1: Yeah Yeah, it's crazy fat.
Speaker 0: There's another one.
Speaker 1: We forgot that has a similar thing, but it's not like this ridiculous Breakneck speed that it's like, you know, you're listening to a record and it's spinning too fast.
Speaker 1: You can't tell what any what the lyrics are.
Speaker 1: It's like it's going.
Speaker 1: it's like a podcast on 2x where you can get all the words in.
Speaker 1: Yep, and it's still fast, but you 100% can tell everything that was said and it's perfectly clear.
Speaker 1: You don't you know you and I guess you might miss some things if you don't pay enough attention or you slip.
Speaker 1: You know you doze off or get distracted But otherwise is Totally good.
Speaker 1: and they managed because of that speed to cram in a ton of stuff, right?
Speaker 1: I didn't feel like there was anything that was like that they introduced.
Speaker 1: that was lacking screen.
Speaker 1: It's not like.
Speaker 1: it's not like oh not too many characters.
Speaker 1: not not enough characters.
Speaker 1: Just right number of characters Just right number of you know scenes and twists and things like that.
Speaker 0: I'm like every side character as crazy as they are has just enough screen time for you to enjoy that character.
Speaker 0: yep, even like really minor characters like they get enough and Everyone's like rotten tomatoes like this movie is making money.
Speaker 0: It's like.
Speaker 0: the reviews are all great for the most part.
Speaker 0: What did anime news network say?
Speaker 0: Promare is a refinement of the trigger formula to the point where I honestly believe it has outdone the classics that inspired it.
Speaker 1: Yeah problem.
Speaker 1: The only thing I can say about this movie that would be negative besides the fact that the plot is basically nothing.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's just anime.
Speaker 1: plot the anime, right?
Speaker 1: I love anime plot the anime, but relatedly I think if you're just like I like Guy Ritchie movie the movie, right?
Speaker 1: I think if you are not anime fan the weeb this movie will just be like what the fuck.
Speaker 1: Yeah, cuz just movie will just just blast right?
Speaker 0: It might blow you away right Yeah, but then I don't think you're going to be like if you did a non anime person.
Speaker 0: It'd be like a hurricane rolled through and you're like just throwing around.
Speaker 0: You know, what was that?
Speaker 0: Yeah, then it ends.
Speaker 1: You're just like what right whereas an anime fan would be.
Speaker 1: it's like well It's.
Speaker 1: imagine two people riding a roller coaster and one person's like, whoa roller coaster And the other person's like, oh my god, what the fuck is this?
Speaker 1: Compare this to red line and then one person gets off and it's like that was awesome.
Speaker 1: Another person gets off and it's like what the hell was that?
Speaker 1: Compared to red line, which is a pretty I was also thinking about red line But I think red line red line is a more actually sit like a normal movie.
Speaker 1: right red line is crazy is more Speed up and slowed out right?
Speaker 1: It's not full speed the whole movie.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right It's like they're the scenes where the racing and crazy erasing act.
Speaker 0: But then there's the scenes were like the characters are developing and having a quiet night, right?
Speaker 1: And then there's talking in between right and there's a whole lot of setup before the race and stuff like that.
Speaker 1: Yeah It's just not to be fair.
Speaker 0: red line to red line actually has a pretty nuanced like Set of character arcs and the plot is actually pretty complete more complex.
Speaker 1: And red line has a plot that is way more advanced than the plot of pro hair, which is which is just nothing.
Speaker 0: Yep But if I takes if I take like random person and show them red line, they'll understand it as a movie.
Speaker 1: Yes, a normal person can watch red line.
Speaker 1: Yeah, only a weeb can watch pro mayor.
Speaker 1: I would be very surprised.
Speaker 1: I would love.
Speaker 0: this is why I want to send this to my dad and be like, hey dad It's a movie about firefighters Japan.
Speaker 1: They might hate you though But I would love to just do like a test with like a room of non weebs of Various sorts of people but non weebs and have them all watch pro mayors.
Speaker 1: Maybe their first anime ever See what the fuck they think Like kids might be like woo, but I think adults who have closed or well, you know mines might be like what the hell I mean.
Speaker 0: the first anime I ever saw was vampire hunter D And all I remember is that I'd never encountered anything like that in my life.
Speaker 0: No vampire story Yeah, but it was crazy Ultra gory event like it was way gorier than anything.
Speaker 0: I'd really seen up to that point.
Speaker 1: Yes true It's Halloween time.
Speaker 1: Watch yourself a vampire hunter D.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if you haven't, uh We have a review.
Speaker 1: the original vampire hunter D. I haven't watched it in forever.
Speaker 1: I remember like all I remember was there was like a oh Nothing.
Speaker 0: usually every year around this time Nighthawk cinema will do a midnight screening with food.
Speaker 0: Midnight though on a weekend.
Speaker 0: Yeah bike there a midnight.
Speaker 0: That'll be fun.
Speaker 0: I'll do that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so yeah If you are listening to this episode of gig nights, that means you can probably go watch pro mares Opportunity.
Speaker 0: if you are hearing these words Just stop listening and go find out how you Right now can watch program.
Speaker 1: I have to wait for it to come out and stream to you or something like that.
Speaker 0: Bye Almost just want to watch it right now.
Speaker 1: We can't easily.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I'm sure I could find it somewhere.
Speaker 1: It's possible It's but difficult.
Speaker 0: It might still even be in theaters in New York.
Speaker 0: I'll have to go check on that.
Speaker 0: Maybe yeah, this You know, this movie does have more of a plot than the original vampire hunter D Maybe but I'm still saying it really does not have you know a stone.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but there's already.
Speaker 0: like world was on fire Why like that's the plot and at the end you will know why the world burned down, right?
Speaker 0: And it's actually a pretty interesting plot.
Speaker 0: That was more than I expected it to be.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but it's not.
Speaker 1: you know, you're not getting any meaning or no you could.
Speaker 0: It's one of the aspects of this movie is actually very relevant.
Speaker 0: Well, two of the aspects are very relevant to current-day Like real-world problems.
Speaker 0: the two things I'm thinking of are one Anti-immigrant anti-refugee like bullshit.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and number two rich people wanting to give up and start over and leave all the pores behind Instead of using those resources to fix the world.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: Those are two very core very real themes in this movie But they are just they're.
Speaker 1: they're just like put right out there.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the plot is just Anti-immigrant people are bad.
Speaker 1: There is no Jeff Bezos bad.
Speaker 1: There is no subtlety whatsoever.
Speaker 1: There is no Right.
Speaker 1: It's literally just.
Speaker 0: but that is still more.
Speaker 1: I think they thought when they made this movie I think there was like an interview with them at the end, but they didn't say too much but what it did come across like.
Speaker 1: We decided we wanted to make a studio trigger movie
Speaker 0: about fire
Speaker 1: about fire And then they pretty much has made
Speaker 0: up a plot
Speaker 1: in order to support the scenes that they wanted including like I said Robot so big it punches the earth that is entirely on fire and solar system
Speaker 0: Because they were like with kill la kill.
Speaker 0: We wanted to make a movie about clothes Yeah, and then they even correct the show about clothes Yeah, but what then they correct themselves like.
Speaker 0: well actually about fabric, yeah specifically fabric Yeah, so this is the fire movie Yeah, and it's great and you should go see it and we truly live in a golden age of animation.
Speaker 0: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Speaker 1: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 0: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows It's actually recorded at night.
Speaker 0: and the patreon patrons for this pro mayor episode of geek nights?
Speaker 0: Because as you may know I read this list every single time we do a show.
Speaker 0: So if you give us money, you're basically forcing me to say whatever it is.
Speaker 0: You typed into that field every single episode a new and a new and a new.
Speaker 0: I will never cheat on this.
Speaker 0: I will never rerecord this always done in one take.
Speaker 0: Sometimes I've had some beer or several beers between when we finish recording the show and when we do this.
Speaker 0: So, uh, you never know.
Speaker 0: Sometimes it's a garden of delights in this bit.
Speaker 0: Here we go.
Speaker 0: Craig Oliver L enjoys hiding my nickel just like a dude.
Speaker 0: guys are toppishing William Eisner's link Gg.
Speaker 0: Hydrated Ganon Boogaloo, Graham Finch, Jennifer Hitchcock, Chris Minkiff, MyStady.com, Jay Bentz, Shawn Yeager, Nicholas Brandow.
Speaker 0: Let's see if rim says Toronto properly for two.
Speaker 0: one creations down and I'd like to take a minute.
Speaker 0: Just sit right there.
Speaker 0: I'll tell Son of I see what you're doing.
Speaker 0: Anyway, Sherman Horrell, Rory, Superboy, Clinton Walton, Ren from New Zealand, Ryan Perrin, Drew Openlander, Finn, Dread, Lily, Tenebrae, Sean Klein, Chris Reimer, Thomas Hahn.
Speaker 0: None of you have figured out what the stinger was from the previous episode of Geek Nights.
Speaker 0: So, uh, I really want to know if someone recognizes that song.
Speaker 0: but now I leave you with something completely different About the raising of the ribs.
Speaker 0: Socrates himself was permanently pissed.
Speaker 1: John Skirrett built on his own free will on half a life of shame, he was particularly ill.
Speaker 1: But later they say he could stick it away, have a grain of whiskey every day.
Speaker 0: How his bottle, how his bottle was a bag of for the bottle, on to a spond of his drem And when he'd take off as a drunken fart I'd drink, therefore I am.
Speaker 0: Yes, Socrates himself is particularly missed A lovely little thinker but a bag of what he's pissed.