Speaker 0: It's Wednesday, June 12th, 2019.
Speaker 0: I'm Rem.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott.
Speaker 0: And this is Geek Nights.
Speaker 0: Tonight, we are talking about Gunsmith Cats, the OAV from the mid 90s.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: So my office is right by a place in New York that most people know, like, if they live here or come here often, they know what this place is, but they don't know that it's called something.
Speaker 0: Pershing Square.
Speaker 0: Mm hmm.
Speaker 0: That it's basically in the front of Grand Central Terminal or Grand Central Station and Terminal together, there's a little viaduct that has a road on it because they made a road split around Grand Central.
Speaker 1: Well, it's Park Avenue, right?
Speaker 1: Because basically you go down Park Avenue and to the left is, you know, Madison Avenue and to the right is Lexington Avenue.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: But Park Avenue can't go right through the middle of the train station.
Speaker 1: So it goes up and then it goes splits in half and goes around Grand Central, right?
Speaker 1: And then in the back of Grand Central, there's these two like ramps that turn and go down and then it becomes Park Avenue again.
Speaker 1: And then that Park Avenue is like a road.
Speaker 1: that's like has a big median in it to begin with, right?
Speaker 1: So it still has that big ass median on the other side.
Speaker 0: Yep, but under that little bridge, there's a restaurant.
Speaker 1: We went to it a long time ago.
Speaker 0: Yep, and I remember they had a really good chicken pot pie and their breakfast is pathetic.
Speaker 1: It was really interesting because I would see the restaurant constantly because I went when the days when I went to Grand Central constantly.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if I was like really just like, oh, I don't want to eat dinner there.
Speaker 1: It always had this sign in the front that was like best breakfast.
Speaker 1: Oh, my God.
Speaker 1: And I ate the breakfast once and I was not impressed.
Speaker 1: It was like, you know, diner or less and it was more money than diner.
Speaker 0: But I would rather eat it at Denny's than eat there for breakfast.
Speaker 1: But the dinner that I've had there a few times, but not in many, many years, who knows what's changed.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but I had dinner there maybe a handful of times many years ago just because convenience.
Speaker 1: And the dinner, while not like interesting, it was like perfectly normal dishes of, you know, just like restaurant, whatever.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but they were quite good.
Speaker 1: Like it was very flavorful chicken and a nice potato.
Speaker 1: And, you know, it was like boring food, but high quality, boring food at not too much overpriced, considering it's right there in front of Grand Central.
Speaker 0: But at a restaurant like to picture this, it's basically built into the bottom of this bridge.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So like on top of the restaurant is a road.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: And on the left and right sides are roads that you can't really drive on because they're like they turn them into pedestrian only zone, kind of.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So that's what I'm getting at.
Speaker 1: And right in front of the restaurant is 42nd Street.
Speaker 1: And right.
Speaker 1: If you just go out of the restaurant and just cross the road, there's entrance to Grand Central.
Speaker 1: So for a long time, Pershing Square is the name of like the square.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: But it's also the name of the restaurant.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: And there's a little old sign there.
Speaker 0: But basically, this area was really kind of like run down, like the bridge and the sidewalk and like the streets that weren't on top of the bridge were all just really run down and beat up.
Speaker 1: Well, they've been.
Speaker 1: they've been polishing it slowly over the years.
Speaker 1: Well, that's it.
Speaker 0: So a while ago, like over a year ago, they blocked it all off and they started doing a big reconstruction project and they actually only recently removed all those fences.
Speaker 0: Now it's just open again and there's a big pedestrian plaza there.
Speaker 0: And now there's kind of like in Times Square, they got all those tables in those in what used to be the street.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: They got that same thing going on here.
Speaker 0: And now there's outdoor seating for that restaurant in that area and public seating that's not tied to the restaurant also there.
Speaker 0: So I've been eating lunch like outside of these tables is real nice.
Speaker 0: But something interesting happened.
Speaker 1: The restaurant harassed you?
Speaker 0: Oh, no, restaurant doesn't care.
Speaker 0: It's a public land.
Speaker 1: because I was going to say.
Speaker 1: But, you know, restaurants do that, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, but they don't.
Speaker 0: They're there.
Speaker 0: They know better.
Speaker 0: OK.
Speaker 0: And also right next to that in 120 Park, the whole lobby of that building is technically public space.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: So like you'll see people playing board games in there.
Speaker 0: I know that one.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: Like so there's a whole bunch of public spaces there now and it's a pretty good place to hang out.
Speaker 0: But when they open this area, it is technically designated as a park.
Speaker 0: And what that means is that in New York City, you cannot smoke in any park.
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 0: No exceptions.
Speaker 0: Like the cops will bother you if you can.
Speaker 1: Smoke on the sidewalk.
Speaker 1: You can smoke in your own car that you own.
Speaker 1: You can smoke in your place of residence if you own it.
Speaker 1: And but like in my apartment building is no smoking rule.
Speaker 1: You can't.
Speaker 1: But, you know, if you own a house, no one's going to start smoking in your own house.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Unless you own a house that's too close to someone else's house and you smoke too much.
Speaker 0: Maybe the point is over nuisance.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: You can also smoke in certain like cigar shops have like smoking zones.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Stuff like that.
Speaker 1: But you can't smoke in a place of business.
Speaker 1: You can't smoke in a park.
Speaker 1: You can't smoke in like, you know, your apartment that you rent that has a no smoking rule.
Speaker 1: You can, you know, you can't smoke at work.
Speaker 1: And it's worked in the sense that I encountered within a certain number of feet of an entrance to a building.
Speaker 1: You sort of have to walk away from the building entrance to somewhere else that's not near any building entrances.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: And it's to the point that in New York City, like the rare times I run into someone smoke it, it's so obvious.
Speaker 1: Like I 99 percent of the time it's somebody walking on the sidewalk while smoking, which is pretty much the only place you can.
Speaker 1: So behind him and have to run past him.
Speaker 0: So something interesting happened because Pershing Square, the two sides of the bridge, the restaurant and the bridge are in the middle.
Speaker 0: One side now is a big park with tables, meaning no one can smoke there.
Speaker 0: And the other side of it is the city bike dock.
Speaker 0: The other side of it is not actually a park.
Speaker 0: It's just a pedestrian throughway.
Speaker 0: Everyone who smokes anywhere in that area, the area with the city bike docks is the only place that you can actually legally smoke.
Speaker 0: So there are a ton of really sad looking people smoking there, sitting on the city bikes every day.
Speaker 0: They're just sitting on the city bike smoking.
Speaker 0: And there's one dude and I see him every day and I know which dude it is.
Speaker 0: He's smoking weed there every day.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 0: We just don't smoke cigarettes, smoke weed every day.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I was going to make the show and then I got high.
Speaker 1: So you got any news?
Speaker 1: I do have a news.
Speaker 1: So, you know, there have been various attempts over the years to make more, you know, Warner Brothers, Looney Tunes, you know, Forky Pig Bugs Bunny cartoons.
Speaker 0: Make success.
Speaker 0: Like there was a recent one that was basically just.
Speaker 1: you could even count things like, you know, Tiny Toons.
Speaker 1: Like big success.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: You know, and other ones, not so much like the Seinfeld one.
Speaker 1: But now there is a much more recent one, like literally just now.
Speaker 1: And it seems like they're going to make a ton of them.
Speaker 1: And they're going to basically allow the animators to sort of go like full controls.
Speaker 1: Like the team that works on one is going to like write it, direct it, animate it like, you know, so you'll get a lot of, you know, Similar to when Adventure Time would have guest animators, they'd be like, yeah, do whatever the hell you want.
Speaker 0: Make it awesome.
Speaker 1: So they're apparently have already made a bunch and are going to make a bunch more and distribute them like on all the places that they can distribute them.
Speaker 1: And there is one on YouTube already.
Speaker 1: I didn't watch the whole thing.
Speaker 0: It was pretty good.
Speaker 1: But what I've seen of it, it's like it's basically old school.
Speaker 1: Like it's the real deal.
Speaker 1: Like, yeah, they just made more of those from the olden days.
Speaker 1: But it's the new days.
Speaker 0: I've said this repeatedly because we've talked about all these shows like She-Ra, which is OK.
Speaker 0: It's a children's show or BoJack, all these different, like there's a lot of animation happening right now.
Speaker 0: Dragon Prince.
Speaker 0: And we're entering like this new golden era of animation.
Speaker 0: We're already in it.
Speaker 0: And I think it's just still continuing to grow.
Speaker 0: But right now we're in an era where there are new good Mickey Mouse shorts and now new good Bugs Bunny shorts.
Speaker 1: I mean, I think, you know, on the one hand, it's nice to see people doing something, you know, new and different.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: We don't need to just repeat the same thing over and over again forever.
Speaker 1: We like to see new things, original works.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: And, you know, when people do retread a lot of old things, though, you know, they try to put a spin on it.
Speaker 1: And that can be hit or miss.
Speaker 1: And the thing is, oftentimes I think usually it's miss.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: And there are a lot of times and, you know, where it's like, hey, there was a thing that was good and we don't want to just repeat that good thing forever because that's tired and boring.
Speaker 0: But if you change it, you change the thing that was good about it.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: But we didn't get enough of that good thing.
Speaker 1: Like I always say, Metroidvanias, just make another fucking Super Metroid.
Speaker 1: The same exact fucking kind of thing can be Super Nintendo quality.
Speaker 1: Just bigger.
Speaker 1: Just how hard is this?
Speaker 0: Take Symphony of the Night as is.
Speaker 0: And now after you beat the Upside Down Castle, Sideways Castle.
Speaker 1: 4D Castle.
Speaker 0: Just more castle.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: It's like you can just do the same.
Speaker 1: You know, it's like, yeah, that was great.
Speaker 1: And I see that you're doing something else, which could also be great.
Speaker 1: But we didn't get enough of that great thing you did.
Speaker 1: Just do it like one or two more times.
Speaker 1: Don't go nuts.
Speaker 1: Don't make like 10 Super Metroids.
Speaker 1: Then we're going to go to sleep, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Like Mega Man, eight, nine, 10, 11.
Speaker 1: It's like Mega Man 10.
Speaker 1: Good job.
Speaker 1: Eleven.
Speaker 1: It's like, all right.
Speaker 1: You know, it's like, come on.
Speaker 0: I feel like 11 was better than 10.
Speaker 1: The point is, we don't need that many more NES style Mega Mans.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: We got, you know, one or two was fine.
Speaker 1: You're right.
Speaker 1: They're starting to go overboard making too many.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: But we do need another Super Metroid and we do need some more Looney Tunes, especially because a lot of the old Looney Tunes are racist, sexist, inappropriate or whatever, and probably shouldn't be watched anymore.
Speaker 1: There's only a handful of them that are, you know, still worthy and hold the test.
Speaker 0: I can tell just based on watching a few again recently, the Yosemite Sam ones are by and large fine.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: Partly because it's just it's just a pirate dude.
Speaker 0: Pirate dude.
Speaker 0: Yosemite Sam is a very accurate representation of rural America.
Speaker 1: Just an angry pirate dude.
Speaker 0: Angry gun toting dude.
Speaker 1: Whatever he is in the episode cowboy or whatever.
Speaker 0: He'd be on Twitter with his two way hashtag.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: But no, I think these are really good.
Speaker 0: And I look forward to watching them.
Speaker 0: And if if they're as good as the one I just saw, but they're not all just the same as the one I just saw, I feel like we're going to be really good shape.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So in some other news, Utena, there's got to be no more Utena like we don't say.
Speaker 1: I mean, I thought it was going to be more Utena manga.
Speaker 0: There is going to be more Utena manga.
Speaker 0: But the manga is not why people care about Utena.
Speaker 0: Let's not pretend otherwise.
Speaker 0: That show is a triumph and it stands alone and apart.
Speaker 0: But the musicals perennially come and go and the musicals have started to up their game and escalate a little bit.
Speaker 0: So the current state of that is one.
Speaker 0: If you don't know that there are Utena musicals, go to YouTube.
Speaker 1: Well, there's musicals for like all kinds of anime.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: We've talked about this on Geek Nights before, like it's a thing.
Speaker 1: Tons of them.
Speaker 0: But the Utena ones are pretty interesting.
Speaker 1: And they had like a resurgence lately, or at least if it's not an actual resurgence, it's a resurgence of Americans, you know, like getting reporting about which ones are happening.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: Because like hardcore Utena fans were like obsessed with the old Utena.
Speaker 1: While we were at PAX, the Sailor Moon musical was like sold out in New York City.
Speaker 1: I would have gone to see it otherwise.
Speaker 0: I remember as a kid, I pirated all of the Sailor Moon music, including all the songs from the musicals.
Speaker 0: And I remember being really excited about that because I couldn't actually get video of the musicals like.
Speaker 0: that was really hard to pirate back in the 90s.
Speaker 1: I have seen it being played at anime cons in the 2000s.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: You know, like you go into a showing room and you're like, oh, they're showing the musicals.
Speaker 0: But I think to your point, what's happening now partly is that American anime fans are starting to find out that these exist.
Speaker 0: And I feel like the fandom of them is starting to grow, but it's still very niche.
Speaker 0: So if you're a fan of Utena, the big news is that they are bringing it now because the Utena musicals tended to only cover basically season one.
Speaker 0: They're doing Black Rose.
Speaker 0: And they're right now they're releasing like the teasers and what the character is going to look like.
Speaker 0: And I'll admit, I don't actually particularly like the Utena musicals.
Speaker 1: I haven't actually seen any.
Speaker 1: I haven't seen too much of any anime musical because I haven't had access or like put the effort in to get translated.
Speaker 0: The problem is generally watching a musical on a screen tends to not be a great experience for a lot of reasons.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: But I hope that, you know, we can get some translated ones.
Speaker 1: But yeah, none of the ones that I have seen have been like things that I want to spend a lot of time on.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: So the Black Rose Arc Utena musical will be in Tokyo early July, and they've announced some of the cast members and there's a bunch of stuff going on.
Speaker 0: So we'll see.
Speaker 0: I'm just going to keep an eye on this.
Speaker 0: And at some point, maybe I will watch a not great quality video of this musical and talk about it and some news that is only adjacent to the anime world.
Speaker 0: But I think we need to talk about a little bit, as you are probably aware, that guy, Vic, who is a voice actor for a bunch of stuff.
Speaker 1: Why do we keep talking about it?
Speaker 0: We're talking about good people because they're all just continuing to do good stuff like Monica is just like she's casting, being cast for more anime and doing stuff.
Speaker 1: But the news is basically interesting to say about good people.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's not just that.
Speaker 0: Vic is probably a creep, a large number of people have made allegations about his creepy harassing every interaction and, you know, time that I have seen him in my life.
Speaker 1: I got a, you know, negative aura feeling.
Speaker 0: I cannot say that I have witnessed him harass anyone, but I can say I've not witnessed him or have any specific memory of witnessing him doing something specifically bad.
Speaker 1: I can say he was just a distasteful person to be around.
Speaker 1: I did not.
Speaker 0: I can say that while he was very nice to me directly and all the times I interacted with him, he was an absolute prick to the rest of my staff.
Speaker 0: And I will leave it at that.
Speaker 0: So the news was not just that this whole nonsense is going on, but that there's a huge brigade of Internet shitlords who have decided that he is their Elon Musk and they are going around harassing people.
Speaker 1: Why can't I be someone's Elon Musk?
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Do you want an army of shitlords on the Internet to do your bidding?
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I'd send them to attack the other armies of shitlords.
Speaker 0: That's like the toner wars.
Speaker 1: I'd be like, I'd be like, all right, guys, here's what we're going to do.
Speaker 1: You're going to find every single person who's, you know, doxxing people, you know, well, in order to defend Vic.
Speaker 0: But Scott, who doxxes the doxxers?
Speaker 1: That's right.
Speaker 1: And doxx each and every one of them and send 10 pizzas to all the houses.
Speaker 0: So the crazy part of this is that either Vic is stupid or gullible because he actually did sue like the people who are making allegations against him and funimation because his career is basically over.
Speaker 1: The only conventions that are inviting him to do something else is not like he's going.
Speaker 1: He's not criminally charged with anything.
Speaker 1: He's not going to jail.
Speaker 1: He just lost his job.
Speaker 1: So go get a different job, bro.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Like being an anime voice actor.
Speaker 1: Like if for some reason I was kicked out of the tech industry because I don't know, everyone stopped using the technology that I know and I didn't want to learn anything.
Speaker 1: I just go do something else.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I think the problem is his career jobs left to do.
Speaker 1: I would do them even if I had to work like, you know, some shitty job.
Speaker 0: His career seems to be based primarily on the like the shakings you can get from the pockets of the nerds who adore him at conventions.
Speaker 1: Also, there are plenty of industries where like, you know, things are still really bad and no one gives a shit about sexual harassment.
Speaker 1: And if you're a sexual harasser, you can just go work in one of those really old school industries where everyone's still a scumbag until we've weeded out those scumbags as well.
Speaker 0: But in the voice acting world, not like what you're going to be a video game voice actor or an anime voice actor, because that's basically the horizon you've got if you're a voice acting B-lister.
Speaker 0: Like what other industry needs voice acting?
Speaker 0: You could do bit like jobber jobs for like an ad agency that does not pay a lot like that pays a per diem like here's four hundred bucks.
Speaker 0: Read these lines.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Crusty the Clown style.
Speaker 1: I'm sure Vic opened up a thing that was like, send me money and I'll do whatever you write, like the other people do.
Speaker 0: Like John St.
Speaker 0: John.
Speaker 0: John St.
Speaker 0: John was like the king of taking advantage of that in the correct way.
Speaker 1: But the point is, I'm sure he would make a lot of money if he did that.
Speaker 0: So basically, dude sued Funimation over all this.
Speaker 1: With Funimation, which is now owned by Sony and has deep pockets.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if I'm if I remember correctly, also sued a bunch of individual people.
Speaker 0: And it's pretty crazy that this is happening.
Speaker 1: You probably got some cuckoo bananas lawyer just like, you know, it was like a go fun me and all this nonsense.
Speaker 0: So the best Twitter thread I saw was someone who said to to paraphrase as a lawyer, I believe that what's about to happen is that Vic is going to learn what happens during discovery.
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 0: So Funimation, the news is that they actually finally reacted to this and they basically said this ain't happening.
Speaker 0: You can write me a link to it.
Speaker 0: That's the news.
Speaker 0: So if you are in the anime world and you encounter this like mob of shitlords that are harassing people on Twitter because of it, I'm just going to point out that I found a list of the Twitter accounts that are doing
Speaker 1: this
Speaker 0: and I added them to my Twitter block list.
Speaker 0: So if you happen to subscribe to my Twitter block list, some sixty five hundred people will be blocked, including most of the people who are in this weird harassment brigade.
Speaker 1: It's so weird.
Speaker 0: It's like that's the crazy thing.
Speaker 1: I was not but I would subscribe to your Twitter block list.
Speaker 1: But for some reason, the way I use Twitter, I never see despite blocking basically almost nobody.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I never see a almost I almost never see a tweet from anyone that I would block unless the only way is if I go looking for them.
Speaker 1: Oh, I see.
Speaker 1: But unless I do something like click on one of the president's tweets and look at the replies.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: So I basically see no bad tweets to block because I don't follow anyone shitty or reply to anyone shitty.
Speaker 1: And because I'm a white dude, no one should he replies to me.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: But occasionally I will click on a tweet from like Planned Parenthood and I don't do that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but then I see those responses.
Speaker 0: But also me and our good friend Adam have a friendly game going on.
Speaker 0: of how many shitty people can we get banned from Twitter?
Speaker 0: So every now and then, if I get bored, I'll click on like an AOC tweet and I'll just block and report everyone who replies.
Speaker 1: See, when I see a good tweet like that from a person I know who has haters, I do not click to see the replies of the tweet because I know that there will be nothing useful.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: I basically only do it as a public service to the people who do encounter these harassment brigades.
Speaker 0: And also because I have gotten a lot more people banned from Twitter than Adam and I'm winning that race and I want to stay ahead.
Speaker 1: Well, I think you spend a lot more time on the Internet.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I do.
Speaker 0: So one last little, little news.
Speaker 0: I love going to TCAF.
Speaker 0: Emily used to go every year.
Speaker 0: We didn't go this year because we're saving those vacation days to do a big Japan trip in the fall.
Speaker 0: But I have a little more regret that I didn't go to TCAF this year because Junji Ito was there.
Speaker 1: We, you know, we know we did some episodes about some Junji Ito works.
Speaker 0: Junji Ito did a panel recently, like a normal panel.
Speaker 0: He also did a panel where he live drew his horrifying art and talked about it.
Speaker 1: It was basically like everyone who wants to draw horrifying Junji Ito art, you know, have a how to, which is pretty unavailable.
Speaker 0: Luckily, this whole both of these panels are just on YouTube on.
Speaker 1: this is why you regret not being there, because you can just fucking see it on YouTube.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it would have been neat to see this in person because TCAF is a fun event.
Speaker 1: And I'm glad that sharks with legs stay as far away from them as possible.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I guess I'll put it this way.
Speaker 0: I really like the Penny Arcade Q&A.
Speaker 0: Like that's one of the highlights of the packs for me.
Speaker 0: Probably wouldn't watch it on YouTube.
Speaker 0: No, there's something about Q&A's.
Speaker 1: we were not at that.
Speaker 1: we could easily watch on Twitch.
Speaker 1: that we just don't.
Speaker 0: It's kind of like.
Speaker 0: there are certain sporting events like.
Speaker 0: I like hockey.
Speaker 0: I don't watch every hockey game, but if I'm like if it's two teams I don't care about, I'm not going to watch it on TV.
Speaker 0: But if I happen to get tickets to see two teams I don't care about, I will gladly go live and watch that hockey game like Sabres versus I don't know, the St.
Speaker 0: Louis Blues, like, yeah, whatever.
Speaker 0: I'll see that in person, but not Bill's Jets football.
Speaker 0: That was the only sporting event I have ever just said fuck it and walked out of.
Speaker 0: We left before halftime and we just drove.
Speaker 1: I don't know if it was before halftime, but it was early.
Speaker 1: I think maybe it was halftime.
Speaker 0: I think we might have left like right around halftime.
Speaker 1: We definitely just left.
Speaker 0: Because I remember the moment because I remember like P was sitting there and even he was cold and I looked at you and I was like, should we should we really need?
Speaker 0: do we really need to stay for this game?
Speaker 0: And we all were like, no, we could just leave.
Speaker 0: Fuck it.
Speaker 0: But anyway, it's time for things of the day.
Speaker 0: So our good friend Luke Burrage is a juggler.
Speaker 0: He is a professional juggler.
Speaker 0: He is in our forum arguing with all of you.
Speaker 0: And you should go and argue with him because that's always a good time.
Speaker 0: But there's been a genre of YouTube video lately that I'm a big fan of where you get an expert in a thing and have them tear apart movie depictions of the thing they're an expert in.
Speaker 0: I like that genre video.
Speaker 0: Like last night, I watched a really, really good one.
Speaker 0: It was a CIA agent who is the head of disguise for the CIA for a long time.
Speaker 0: And she broke down disguise shit in spy movies.
Speaker 1: I saw a video yesterday where there was a former Navy SEAL who was doing.
Speaker 1: he did a video about situational awareness.
Speaker 1: But as a only a small portion of the video, he was reacting to stuff in the Bourne identity.
Speaker 1: Oh, it wasn't that the whole video wasn't like react to movie.
Speaker 1: It was just a small portion of the video.
Speaker 0: Actually, I saw a similar one.
Speaker 0: It was these FBI agents and they were like, here's the reality of trying to read someone's body language.
Speaker 0: And it was really in depth because he was most of the things you think of, like, oh, people tend to touch their like.
Speaker 0: none of that.
Speaker 0: It's all bullshit.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: But he talked about very specific things and what they mean and how you can use them to like tell a story.
Speaker 1: I rubbed his hands together.
Speaker 1: His hands must be cold.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: But there's one specific example of people who are confident in what they're saying or unafraid of answering a question if they bring their hands together, tend to do the Mr.
Speaker 0: Burns thing or just like clasp their hands.
Speaker 0: People who are nervous tend to interlock their fingers and rub them.
Speaker 0: And there is some evidence about that's like a self soothing thing that that humans and monkeys both do.
Speaker 0: And that was very specific.
Speaker 1: Do they know knowing this?
Speaker 1: Then do they play the poison cup game of clasping fingers and confidently saying lies?
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: He only talked about how to spot other people and like and and also we talked a lot about how that information is not 100 percent and how it's just one tool in your toolkit to figure out if someone's lying to you.
Speaker 1: But I think I can tell if someone's lying.
Speaker 1: Is there an AMRIM?
Speaker 0: I rarely lie.
Speaker 0: There's a lie right there.
Speaker 0: First one.
Speaker 0: So our friend Luke does this for juggling in movies.
Speaker 0: And I learned a lot watching this video.
Speaker 0: This is actually really good.
Speaker 0: The only thing I will warn you about is that he pronounces David Bowie's name in a very brightish way.
Speaker 0: That's all I'm going to say about that.
Speaker 0: So what do you got?
Speaker 1: So, you know, there is this cat.
Speaker 1: It is a fictional cat, but it is a cute cat.
Speaker 1: It is named Pusheen and Pusheen is doing a lot more action lately, like you think it's like, you know, Pusheen sort of had their day.
Speaker 1: But no, Pusheen's popularity seems to only be increasing the activities of the Pusheen Corporation, as opposed to which I believe is in Chicago, as opposed to a viral video that suddenly gets famous.
Speaker 0: Pusheen is this long, slow and steady smolder that just grows and grows and grows like.
Speaker 1: a website was recently completely redone by our friends, Joe and Conrad, who have been on this podcast.
Speaker 1: I believe that they made the official new official Pusheen website, but that was like a month, some months ago already, just like yesterday or the day before Pusheen the cat opened its official YouTube channel.
Speaker 1: And it is not just like new YouTube channel one video.
Speaker 1: It's new YouTube channel, a lot of videos with more coming.
Speaker 1: So if you don't want to follow Pusheen on like Instagram or Twitter or whatever, you can follow Pusheen on YouTube.
Speaker 1: And there's the stuff that Pusheen has on YouTube is basically YouTube version, right, which is, I guess, better in some ways.
Speaker 1: It has audio and more animation.
Speaker 0: So in the moment, the Book Club book that we are going to talk about for the next Thursday show, Troy Dennings Pages of Pain, an officially licensed Dungeons and Dragons Planescape novel.
Speaker 1: I from nineteen nineties something I'm actually something I'm really interested to.
Speaker 0: This is the 90s.
Speaker 0: It's like ninety six.
Speaker 1: It feels like 90s.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I'm really interested to do this show because the difference between you and I, because we both went into it knowing, yeah, this is a D&D book.
Speaker 0: I had read it once before, but my memory was it's the best.
Speaker 1: I think it's the only maybe the only I think the only one.
Speaker 0: it's only one you should even consider reading.
Speaker 1: Well, I think I would say it's the only D&D book I ever read, but that's actually not true.
Speaker 1: I had a. I don't know if it was D&D, but it was TSR.
Speaker 1: It was a TSR.
Speaker 1: choose your own adventure book, which gets into a mech suit and is the president.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I don't know which one that might still have it.
Speaker 0: I don't know because there's a bunch of those kinds of things anyway.
Speaker 0: But I'm really curious because the the only difference between you and I reading this book is that I know a lot about the Planescape setting, or at least I knew a lot about the Planescape setting as it existed in the 90s.
Speaker 1: I know about Planescape from playing Planescape torment once, but sort of cheating and not paying too much attention now and also absorbing being around nerds.
Speaker 1: You talked about Planescape a lot.
Speaker 1: Yup, but that's I never read a Planescape.
Speaker 0: You knew the lady of pain was the sword head lady.
Speaker 1: Yes, I never read a Planescape source book or anything like that.
Speaker 0: Yup.
Speaker 1: So the cool thing is, you know, actually we played one of the forum games he played was technically a Planescape game.
Speaker 0: Yeah, maybe that was the one where I was the little dragon guy, the Mind Flayer.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you were the Mind Flayer.
Speaker 0: OK, that was a Planescape game.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: There you go.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that was that was my Planescape experience.
Speaker 0: Yeah, Planescape.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: I've always wanted to play Planescape games, but my group in high school was much more invested.
Speaker 1: Forgot 10 Realms.
Speaker 1: Forgot 10 Realms is just one realm.
Speaker 0: Yeah, Forgot Realms is just one realm.
Speaker 1: You're also in Planescape, right?
Speaker 0: Well, yes, everything is in Planescape.
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 0: Except Ravenloft is sharted off at its own thing.
Speaker 0: And Dark Sun is also cut off from the multiverse for its own reasons.
Speaker 1: Uh huh.
Speaker 1: And let's just make a heretical D&D game where you go there anyway.
Speaker 0: No, you're not allowed to.
Speaker 1: Stop me.
Speaker 0: Gary Gygax will come back from the dead and get you.
Speaker 1: Let's do it.
Speaker 1: We want to resurrect him.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we could use it.
Speaker 1: We'd be like, dudes, we just played a D&D game and we opened a portal from Sigil to It's pronounced Sigil.
Speaker 1: Whatever, to Ravenloft.
Speaker 1: And we mispronounced Sigil.
Speaker 1: And that got Gary Gygax so mad that he came back from the dead.
Speaker 1: Check out the zombie Gary Gygax.
Speaker 1: He's running our game now to prevent us from doing these heretical things and making sure our pronunciation is correct.
Speaker 0: Oh, what are the not-hobbits, the Dragonlance ones?
Speaker 1: Halflings?
Speaker 1: No, I don't know.
Speaker 0: Kender, Kender.
Speaker 1: It's the we'll have a game.
Speaker 1: I have heard that word before.
Speaker 0: So Kender are basically, they're only a dragon.
Speaker 1: That is a word I have heard.
Speaker 0: So Dragonlance are also technically a D&D setting, but that's even worse.
Speaker 0: But I don't think that's in the modern cosmology of Planescape anyway.
Speaker 0: But they had their own version of halflings that were a hundred times more annoying.
Speaker 0: And they're best not spoken of.
Speaker 0: We'll have both Kender and halflings.
Speaker 0: You know what?
Speaker 0: We'll even have some gnomes and some quarterlings in this game.
Speaker 1: And hobbits.
Speaker 0: Hobbitses.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: You want to get into this?
Speaker 0: We got any other meta?
Speaker 0: We got no cons.
Speaker 0: So PAX.
Speaker 0: PAX ain't sold out yet, but Friday is going to sell out pretty soon, I think.
Speaker 1: Well Saturday's sold out.
Speaker 1: Sunday's almost sold out.
Speaker 1: The full day, a full weekend passes.
Speaker 1: This is PAX West in Seattle, by the way, on Labor Day weekend.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: The problem is with PAX is that they keep moving and moving to the point that they're all clustered like one after the other.
Speaker 1: So basically we don't have... Well, basically not in the summer, right?
Speaker 1: So as soon as you get through with summer, it's like Labor Day, PAX, then you got Unplugged in Australia.
Speaker 0: October, October, PAX OSS, November, PAX Unplugged, early January, PAX South.
Speaker 0: And then right away, like late February, early March, maybe April, PAX East.
Speaker 1: And then summer.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: It's annoying in one sense in that we used to have this cycle of like write a bunch of panels and then do a PAX, and we have some time to be like, "Okay, what was good?
Speaker 0: Let's shift it
Speaker 0: up.".
Speaker 0: Now I get to write all the panels for all the PAXes in one go and submit them all at the same time.
Speaker 0: It's getting... It's moderate.
Speaker 0: It's not stressful, but it is annoying.
Speaker 0: But I don't know if I want more PAXes or I just want the existing PAXes to spread out.
Speaker 1: If there's enough PAXes, I can get them to pay me an equipment job.
Speaker 0: If there was one PAX a month, I think I could turn that into a living.
Speaker 0: So, gunsmith cats.
Speaker 1: So way back at the RIT Anime Club, right, in like one of the first... No, this is the first, but one of the first showings we went to was this anime.
Speaker 1: This was before we ran the RIT Anime Club.
Speaker 1: That was the last time I saw this before yesterday.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: And so that was like, what, 20 years ago.
Speaker 0: This OAV came out in like '96, so I was a freshman in high school.
Speaker 0: So I didn't see it until the year 2000 when we went to RIT.
Speaker 1: And all I remember watching it was, there was the girl with guns, the car, the girl with a bunch of grenades, and it was just sort of crazy and ridiculous.
Speaker 1: And watching it in a big group, it was a lot of fun and people got real excited.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: The crowd went crazy.
Speaker 0: It was only three episodes.
Speaker 1: Everyone, people were laughing hysterically at certain parts.
Speaker 0: Yep, it was only three episodes.
Speaker 0: It's pretty well animated, like it had a pretty high production value for like the era.
Speaker 0: Like it looks good.
Speaker 0: Like a lot of that...
Speaker 1: So much more recently, Dark Horse released all of the manga, Gunsmith Cats and Gunsmith Cats Burst, and I bought it all and read it all.
Speaker 1: I don't know if I kept any of it, I may or may not.
Speaker 1: If I do have it, it's on one of my back shelves hiding behind other manga.
Speaker 0: Yep, I never actually read the manga, but... And you know what?
Speaker 1: Even though I read absolutely all of it, I remember almost none of it, basically.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: It was not memorable.
Speaker 1: And anyway, there's also...
Speaker 0: I remember the OAV more of it than I expected, because what I remembered before we watched it again was in the first episode, she does a cool ricochet thing with a shotgun.
Speaker 0: In the second episode, that Russian Spetsnaz lady fucking murders everybody, and she has a gun knife, which is a real thing.
Speaker 0: And the third episode is a little spooky, and it gets a little dire toward the end, and people die.
Speaker 1: And then...
Speaker 0: I also remembered she had the Shelby Cobra.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: So there's this related thing called, like, Bean Bandit.
Speaker 1: Riding Bean.
Speaker 1: Which is a character, Bean Bandit, who is in the manga and is not in this anime, but he has his own spin-off anime, which is just a movie, called Riding Bean.
Speaker 0: I have not seen Riding Bean since I was in high school.
Speaker 1: I watched the Riding Bean anime VHS from the RIT Anime Club.
Speaker 1: I took it out of the library, and I watched it once, and then I returned it.
Speaker 0: I want to say I rented it from Blockbuster.
Speaker 1: I don't remember much of it.
Speaker 0: Pretty sure I got it from Blockbuster Video.
Speaker 1: All of these things were made by a man named Kinichi Tsunoda, so what you have to know about this guy, is this is a guy, this is a Japanese dude, right, who I don't know how significant he is in Japan, right?
Speaker 1: It seems like... It seems like he had his day in Japan, where he was big, and like, his manga was big enough to be animated, right, into movies and OAVs, but it seems like he was bigger in America, at least compared to other manga artists.
Speaker 0: Which I think partly because Riding Bean and Gunsmith Cats came out at two, like, big inflection points for American anime fandom, and got, for the time, pretty wide releases.
Speaker 1: Well, I think it's also, I know he definitely came to conventions here and made appearances and stuff.
Speaker 1: I don't know how much...
Speaker 0: People cosplaying as Riley Vincent at early Otakobs.
Speaker 1: But also, this dude, maybe he's part of the reason he was coming to America and doing, you know, and stuff like this, is because this guy's America fanboy.
Speaker 1: He loves cars, he loves guns, he loves American cars, yes, he loves boobs, and butts, and naked ladies, right?
Speaker 1: That's the kind of guy he is.
Speaker 0: And weird, technically, she's 30 years old nonsense, he's a problematic figure.
Speaker 1: So, if you look at the manga and the anime, like, you know, the guns are so perfectly illustrated down to the tiniest detail modeled after real guns, the Shelby Cobra is drawn in, like, ridiculously higher resolution infidelity, but unlike Initial D, the characters are also drawn well.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: The characters are drawn well, but still much less than the car, and it seems like most of the work he's had in the anime industry, other than the things he's worked on that were his original works, were basically character design for other things.
Speaker 1: He hasn't, you know, done a lot of original stuff.
Speaker 1: Also, it seems like he hasn't done anything at all in a large number of years.
Speaker 0: So, I know what he's up to.
Speaker 1: And according to Wikipedia, he's working at his family's candy store.
Speaker 0: Yup, by adding lemon peels to his family's existing candies, and providing his own bishoujo illustrations for the packaging, he's up to his same bullshit.
Speaker 1: Right, but it's like, the point is, he, you know, it was a guy who had his moment in the sun, and went away.
Speaker 0: What a Wikipedia article.
Speaker 0: His personal life section says, and I quote, Sonora is a self-confessed gun fanatic, owning several replica guns.
Speaker 1: Right, because he can't have real ones in Japan, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, but that is a sentence for a Wikipedia article.
Speaker 1: I think he's also done-
Speaker 0: He worked on, like, Doll Force, and Bubble Gum stuff-
Speaker 1: I don't know if this is true, but I get the- because there was also another guy who did this, I forget his name, but I think he's also done, like, American comic stuff a little bit, maybe.
Speaker 1: Anyway.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: But yeah, there are other people who know a lot more about this guy, and can probably talk for hours about, you know, what the deal with him is, but you have to know about this dude to understand this work, right?
Speaker 0: Now, one thing I would say is, we're going to focus on the OAV, because- That's what I watched yesterday.
Speaker 0: Yes, you do not need to know anything about the Gunsmith Cats universe to watch that OAV.
Speaker 1: Right, if you read the Gunsmith Cats manga, you will get the full story of Gunsmith Cats.
Speaker 0: Because it was originally just the Gunsmith Cat.
Speaker 1: Who are these people, how did they get together, how did they get in this business, what their deal is.
Speaker 0: That is less interesting than the OAV.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 1: You'll also, in the manga, get some really bad stuff, right?
Speaker 1: So if you don't know the girl, Minnie May, right?
Speaker 1: She is, in the manga, you will learn, she is actually like a teenager, basically.
Speaker 1: And in the anime, in the first episode, there's a very short scene where she looks at a photo of a dude longingly, and they don't mention that dude again.
Speaker 1: In the manga, that dude is her boyfriend, he's there, he's way old, and she's a teenager, and it's totally fucked up.
Speaker 0: Doesn't she like take drugs to keep herself young?
Speaker 0: I don't know about that, I don't remember, but- There's weird shit with her.
Speaker 1: It is interesting that the boyfriend's name is Ken, and the guy we just talked about who's.
Speaker 1: the creator is Ken "Ichi" Sonoda.
Speaker 0: Oh my god, yes, May is tiny and young, appearing for her age, having taken growth-stunting drugs in an effort to stay attractive to Ken, the aforementioned guy.
Speaker 0: She can pass for a child of ten or tw-.
Speaker 0: Don't read the manga.
Speaker 1: I read it.
Speaker 0: Do not read the manga.
Speaker 1: I don't know if I still have it, though.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Uh, but yeah, other than like the creepy facts like that, though the manga is basically just a lot like these OAVs, only just more of it.
Speaker 0: But the beauty of the OAV is that
Speaker 1: a lot
Speaker 0: of 90s anime have this dynamic of there's a bunch of characters, and you kind of figure out their deal insofar as it matters instantly, and you just have this story with a whole bunch of characters that all play their part, and watching Gunsmith Cats again really reminded me, it's not the best anime, it's got a lot of flaws, but it reminded me of all the things I really liked about these 90s OAVs.
Speaker 1: I mean, this OAV, even though it's three episodes, it's actually just a movie.
Speaker 1: It's not a movie like top-tier movie when you think of anime movies, but it is 90 minutes of animation with one contiguous story that just happens to be chopped up into three acts with an opener and a closer between separating the acts.
Speaker 0: The opener is basically the Cowboy Bebop opener.
Speaker 1: Or the Cowboy Bebop opener is the Guns for the Cats opener.
Speaker 1: It's jazz music with colors and panning and, you know, three dramatic guns.
Speaker 1: If you cut out the opener's enclosures and pasted all three of these together, it would be a movie.
Speaker 0: Yup.
Speaker 1: Like a made-for-TV-movie quality level, right?
Speaker 1: Not like a, you know, movie, cinema movie quality movie.
Speaker 0: So what is this movie?
Speaker 0: It is basically, we're in the city of Chicago, and there are these two women who run a gun shop.
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 1: They're also bounty hunters.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: They are bounty hunters.
Speaker 0: They run a gun shop.
Speaker 0: The gun shop is perfectly legal and like regulated gun stuff.
Speaker 0: Like their customers are cops because that's just how it is.
Speaker 0: But they also have a large collection of extremely illegal firearms to support their bounty hunting.
Speaker 1: Well, also because, you know, she's a gun nut because the author is a gun nut.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: The main character is a hyper competent gun nut who knows her shit.
Speaker 0: Also a car nut.
Speaker 0: Yup.
Speaker 0: Private investigator drives a Shelby Cobra.
Speaker 0: If you don't know what a Shelby Cobra is, it's a very rare and special car.
Speaker 1: It's a very American muscle car.
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 0: There aren't many of them.
Speaker 1: There's enough.
Speaker 1: It's not ultra rare.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: But it's pretty rare.
Speaker 0: If you got money, you can get one.
Speaker 0: There are a lot of adjacent cars, but the Cobra was a rare one.
Speaker 0: Anyway, her partner is basically an explosives expert in the same vein as movies like Predator.
Speaker 0: You have the team and there's always the one on the team.
Speaker 1: Well, it's like Team Fortress.
Speaker 1: You got Gunperson and Demoman.
Speaker 0: Yup.
Speaker 1: You see a gun and Demoman.
Speaker 0: So like the running gag will be, there'll be a tense scene and Riley has a pistol or something and like gunfights and Mini May will just fucking blow up the building.
Speaker 1: She usually uses flash bangs and smoke grenades and is super clumsy with them and only uses Not clumsy, careless.
Speaker 1: Yes, but the explosives are usually reserved for traps when they're far away from them.
Speaker 1: She's throwing usually flash bangs and smoke.
Speaker 0: A lot of the jokes, like the throwaway games come down to.
Speaker 0: Riley's got a gun and she's like looking down a stairway and then Mini May kind of slides up behind her just holding a fist full of grenades.
Speaker 1: That's when the anime club got excited.
Speaker 0: Yup.
Speaker 0: And then you get the long distance shot.
Speaker 0: You see the house like way in the background, you just hear a pop and then smoke comes out the window.
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 0: That kind of stuff.
Speaker 1: So the movie, these three episodes are, you know, they're not telling you any of the plot of the characters.
Speaker 1: There's no real character development or anything that happens here.
Speaker 1: They're assuming that you already read the manga or you don't have to have, right?
Speaker 1: But they don't bother introducing the characters very much, although you'll get it right away.
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 1: It's just a side story.
Speaker 1: I don't believe this story was in the manga at all.
Speaker 1: It's like a complete side story, the same sort of like a cowboy bebop movie, right?
Speaker 1: It's just like a side story doesn't interfere, right?
Speaker 1: You could insert it pretty much anywhere into the into the main plot.
Speaker 1: You know, it's like is a bad guy is the story of them, you know, dealing with the bad guy, the ATF agent, the cops, you know, the Russian, the whole situation, right?
Speaker 1: And then resolving it over the course of, you know, 90 minutes, then the end back to status quo.
Speaker 0: And it has a pretty good progression.
Speaker 0: Like the three acts work pretty well.
Speaker 0: Like act one is basically the somewhat silly plot where they get roped into some hijinks and the cops sort of extort them into helping the cops with this dangerous investigation.
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 0: And it's mostly funny.
Speaker 0: And then act two is like, oh, there's something bigger going on.
Speaker 0: This Russian like former Spetsnaz person.
Speaker 1: They thought they took care of it in episode one, but no episode two, actually, this is a much bigger deal and you don't want to be involved.
Speaker 1: But now you sort of are being forced to and a big shootout thing happens.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: It's a big shootout and a little bit of a. I'm too old for this shit.
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 0: And then act three is no, this is dire and people are going to die.
Speaker 1: That crazy Russian person who you shot at and is upset and is now coming after you.
Speaker 1: And also the big boss has been revealed.
Speaker 1: The end episode three.
Speaker 0: And it holds up pretty well.
Speaker 0: Like if you're an anime fan, it's worth watching.
Speaker 0: It's just on YouTube.
Speaker 0: You could just go watch it right now.
Speaker 1: Well, it's on YouTube illegally.
Speaker 1: But yeah, the things, you know, that are positive about it, if you really like illustrations of guns and cars.
Speaker 0: Yup.
Speaker 1: But, you know, there's also parts of the gun.
Speaker 1: There are also lots of scenes where there are just excuses for characters to have a lot less clothes on than otherwise.
Speaker 0: But what's funny and Dave Riley said this a bunch of times in the past, but it's almost wholesome compared to what that kind of fan service is in the modern era.
Speaker 0: That's true.
Speaker 1: Also, some of the scenes.
Speaker 1: For example, it's like these two girls living together in a house.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: So for them to be like sitting in the kitchen table wearing only their underwear talking is like I feel like normal.
Speaker 1: That's like.
Speaker 1: that's how I live my life.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: It's like that seems normal.
Speaker 1: And they're just illustrating it.
Speaker 1: You know, they're just happen to be have, you know, stereotypically sexy bodies or whatever, wearing sexy underwear.
Speaker 1: But like every scene that's most egregious is an episode two where the bad guy attacks by using the warehouse crane hook.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I was going to bring that up.
Speaker 1: And it happens.
Speaker 1: A giant hook is being is swinging at this woman and it just so just so happens to tear her shirt open right down the middle and tear her bra open right down the middle.
Speaker 0: Nineties anime, ladies and gentlemen, it's a giant hook.
Speaker 1: It's not like some, you know, it's like really.
Speaker 1: it's not like a sword slash cutting the open.
Speaker 0: But the other like the good.
Speaker 0: positive aspect of the thing about it is that it's set in Chicago and they did their research.
Speaker 1: It is like, well, because he's and you know, this guy is a fanboy of guns, cars, America, boobs.
Speaker 1: Well, crime is like, yeah, Chicago.
Speaker 0: So the anime was adapted by Takeshi Mori, who, according to this article, didn't know anything about guns at all, but knew a lot about cars.
Speaker 0: So they actually took some of the production crew to go to Chicago to scout locations, to get backgrounds, to do research.
Speaker 0: They actually visited gun shops and they went to a police academy and got firearms training.
Speaker 0: And then they use that to make the anime.
Speaker 1: Trying hard.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: And they actually went so far as to get a Shelby Cobra GT500 and record the sound effects for the anime.
Speaker 1: They didn't buy the car.
Speaker 1: They just found someone who let them listen to it.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: And they got the sound effects and made it legit.
Speaker 1: I was going to say.
Speaker 0: And it's funny because half the gunplay is very noir.
Speaker 0: Like goons just fall over instantly dead.
Speaker 0: You don't see a lot of blood or any blood.
Speaker 0: But then a few moments are much more realistic about the guns.
Speaker 0: Like it's a weird thing to point out, but ricochets are hyper realistic for some reason.
Speaker 0: But the noir stuff is just John Wick style.
Speaker 0: A hundred Russians die.
Speaker 0: The gunfights are really fun though.
Speaker 0: They're more interesting than most of the noir gunfights, I would say after episode four of noir.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: If you want a nostalgia trip back to 90s anime, if you don't mind some of the negative parts of 90s anime.
Speaker 0: If you want to see like in a really tight example of what popular 90s anime was like, this is like, this is the shortest path to experiencing that.
Speaker 1: You can also learn about this Kinichi Tsunoda guy who was important/infamous in a time and a place in this really narrow.
Speaker 1: It's like a really big fish in this tiny pond for a period of time.
Speaker 1: You know, I guess we'll be remembered by some anime nerds and then, you know, it feels like we'll be forgotten at some point.
Speaker 0: Every now and then some nerds like us will do a panel at a random anime convention talking about, so you ever heard of this guy?
Speaker 0: Let's talk about this guy.
Speaker 0: none of you have heard of.
Speaker 0: But I now kind of have this itch I need to scratch.
Speaker 0: I kind of want to watch like Bubblegum Crisis again.
Speaker 1: But you did character design for that, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: But like that 90s anime, like I'm starting to feel it again.
Speaker 1: Bubblegum Crisis I think is much better than this.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but Bubblegum Crisis is also not great.
Speaker 1: No, it just is better than this.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: This means great.
Speaker 0: The only real important part of Bubblegum Crisis is that the 80 police suck.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: This has been Geek Nights with Rim and Scott.
Speaker 0: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design, and Brando Kay for the logos.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at FrontRowCrew.com for show notes, discussion news, and more.
Speaker 0: Remember, Geek Nights is not one, but four different shows.
Speaker 0: Sci-Tech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays, and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: Geek Nights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: Geek Nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 1: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.
Speaker 0: And the Patreon Patrons for this Gunsmith Cats episode of Geek Nights.
Speaker 0: Let me go into my Patreon manager here, because as you know, I record this all in one go.
Speaker 0: No edits.
Speaker 0: No, once I record, it just happens.
Speaker 0: And the Patreon website is actually being really slow right now, which is annoying.
Speaker 0: Here we go.
Speaker 0: The Patrons are.
Speaker 0: Really?
Speaker 0: You haven't loaded yet?
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: Craig Oliver, Alan Joyce, Hunter McNeagle, JustLikeADudeGag, Jared Thompson, Link Iggi, Jennifer Hitchcock, Chris Midgiff, MyStakeTheAcom, Jay Bandz, Scootalonely, Roberto Kingsley, Sean Yeager, Nicholas Brandow, Mr.
Speaker 0: Strong Strachan, 421 Creations, and there may be other secret names you do not even know, Shervin Von Horl, Rory, Rochelle Montano, SuperBoySailor, Vista Clinton, Walton, Rem from New Zealand, Ryan Perrin, Dropenlander, Finn, Dready Lily, Tenebrae, Sean Klein, Chris Reimer, Thomas Hahn, and I've got something that is going to awaken ancient memories and get stuck in your head.