Speaker 1: It's Tuesday, July 30th, 2019.
Speaker 1: I'm Rym.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott.
Speaker 1: And this is Geek Nights Tonight, The Wizard's Grimoire, an RPG.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: And to be clear, we are not talking about one that I had never heard of until I Googled for this, and I found this old, not great looking RPG that's also called The Wizard's Grimoire.
Speaker 1: That apparently has at least four editions and it does not look great based on bicursory.
Speaker 0: Someone published it and people played it, right?
Speaker 1: I mean, the same could be said of Palladium Books.
Speaker 0: True.
Speaker 1: Did anyone actually use Palladium Books to play games, though?
Speaker 0: Yeah, but apparently not enough to keep them in business.
Speaker 1: But like, who?
Speaker 1: Like, who was the person who played RPGs using Palladium Books for that purpose?
Speaker 0: Right, it's like we see people who, like, I saw plenty of people like mourning their loss.
Speaker 1: Like, at least Gamma World, like, I knew people who played Gamma World.
Speaker 1: I had heard of Gamma World.
Speaker 0: But, like, I never met someone who, like, had a story of a session they played of a Palladium game.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I remember every time I went to Millennium I would see this giant bookshelf of Palladium Books and every time I'd kind of laugh at them.
Speaker 0: No one, nobody bought them.
Speaker 1: They were next to all those Besom supplements.
Speaker 0: Everyone knew them, no one bought them, never met anyone who played one, but when they went away people were sad and were like, "No, I think a lot of RPGs are really just things people buy and read and don't
Speaker 0: play.".
Speaker 1: Well, like, Hall, the RPG that was designed to just be read and not actually played.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: So, uh, yeah, we will link to the correct one.
Speaker 1: We were talking about Vincent Baker's Wizard's Grimoire.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we haven't done a Geek Nights in a while, have we?
Speaker 1: Uh, no, we've been out of town, we've been busy, and we haven't talked about RPGs in a while either.
Speaker 1: It's an exciting show.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I have a lot of RPGs I haven't played.
Speaker 1: But we played the Wizard's, all I gotta say is, we played the Wizard's Grimoire three times.
Speaker 0: I played it three times.
Speaker 1: I played it one time, and the second time when I was sitting next to a game, it was really hard to not jump in.
Speaker 1: You weren't actually playing.
Speaker 1: Uh, the second game I wasn't supposed to play.
Speaker 0: No, you weren't playing, you played it zero times.
Speaker 1: I played it the first game.
Speaker 0: You volunteered to assist in me playing.
Speaker 1: True, I was the assistant the first game, but the key fact is the second game.
Speaker 0: You have never played this game.
Speaker 1: The second game.
Speaker 1: I was sitting next to the game, playing my Switch, and it was really, Scott Ed kept telling me to shut up because I was not technically one of the assistants.
Speaker 0: You were just sitting around while someone else played.
Speaker 1: But I felt I wanted to be an assistant.
Speaker 1: This game is real good.
Speaker 0: Go read your own grimoire.
Speaker 0: Maybe you'll go on a barbarian bloody quest.
Speaker 1: I feel like, and this will save this for the end of the show, but I feel like we should do live sessions of this game on Geek Nights.
Speaker 0: Why don't you, you can go on a barbarian bloody quest.
Speaker 1: Maybe I should, or I'm more invested in The Last Adventure.
Speaker 1: Because you're dead.
Speaker 1: So there's a bunch of gaming news, so we're gonna be real selective about which ones we cover, because there's just so much.
Speaker 0: Because you haven't done a show in so long.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and also there's been a lot of gaming news lately.
Speaker 1: that's notable, and we can't cover it all twice a month.
Speaker 1: If you want to see gaming news as it happens, Geek Nights is not the place.
Speaker 0: Well anyway, the biggest gaming news, and obviously we don't play or give a shit about Fortnite, but the Fortnite World Cup happened, which I guess may have been the biggest esports event in history, so it's extremely notable.
Speaker 0: I guess it was bigger than the LUL, right?
Speaker 0: It was enormous, right?
Speaker 0: It was actually in New York, but we were out of town, so it's not like we could go.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you cannot underestimate the like, latent popularity of Fortnite.
Speaker 1: This is possibly the most played game in human history.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so at the event, I don't even know who won, but there were two major things that happened at the event that are notable to people who don't even care about Fortnite.
Speaker 0: You simply care about games.
Speaker 0: The first thing that happened was there was a player who had been, I guess, caught or widely believed to have cheated.
Speaker 0: We might have done a story about this person earlier.
Speaker 0: We did.
Speaker 1: We talked about this at length.
Speaker 0: It was a Fortnite cheater we've talked about on Geek Nights in the past that somehow is still allowed to go to the World Cup despite cheating.
Speaker 1: Because the professionalized Fortnite is kind of amateur hour.
Speaker 0: Right, and this person at the Fortnite World Championship was eliminated.
Speaker 0: I guess they still got some amount of money for, you know, whatever, right?
Speaker 0: But they were eliminated.
Speaker 0: They did not become the Fortnite World Champion.
Speaker 0: And when they were eliminated, the arena erupted in cheering.
Speaker 0: People were so happy to see the evil cheater defeated.
Speaker 0: It was a good time.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: Alright, the second news, somebody who is significantly less evil, another Fortnite player, because I don't know they're, you know, whatever.
Speaker 0: For some reason.
Speaker 0: Let W1K3.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: This player, while playing, they're playing, you know, it wasn't team based.
Speaker 0: It was just solo rounds or whatever.
Speaker 1: Fourteen year old representing Russia.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: No, representing Canvid Esports.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: While they were playing, they happened to look over their monitor and were they were able to see these big giant screens for the spectators.
Speaker 0: And you're not supposed to look at those because there's information on those screens that you can't get.
Speaker 0: Like, you might be able to see where another player is hiding, right?
Speaker 1: Now, you may already, having listened to this, already be mad about that because that's ridiculous.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Why are those screens visible from where the players are?
Speaker 1: That's just stupid.
Speaker 1: It would be like if in Major League Baseball the jumbotron was in front of the batter so he could see it and it was zoomed in on the catcher's hands.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Like that's that's amateur hour crap.
Speaker 0: Like if they showed all the signals from all the managers up on the big screen and everyone could see him.
Speaker 0: Like look, Bridge.
Speaker 1: If you play contact bridge, they put up these shields to make sure you can't look at your partner.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: So they met.
Speaker 0: this player was.
Speaker 0: I don't think they were disqualified or fined.
Speaker 1: But after quote after multiple warnings to the player, a penalty was assessed and he was removed from the match.
Speaker 1: He was not disqualified and will not be fined.
Speaker 0: And he still took home like a pile of money, but not a win.
Speaker 0: He could have won.
Speaker 0: Who knows?
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: You never know what could happen.
Speaker 0: You're still playing.
Speaker 0: You still got a chance to win.
Speaker 1: It's one thing if you cheat by doing something like, I don't know, hacking your monitor to be able to see someone else's screen picture.
Speaker 0: I guess complain that they weren't given the right keyboard or something.
Speaker 0: But that's irrelevant.
Speaker 0: The point is, I think if I was this player, I would be like, hey, why the fuck was that even visible?
Speaker 1: Oh, Lord, look at these screenshots.
Speaker 1: The jumbotron is like, you can't not look at this thing.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 0: But yeah, this is not only was this maybe the biggest e-sport event in history is probably the highest production value e-sport event in history.
Speaker 0: And to have a fuck up so basic is really, really, I think, casts a further shade of, you know, over the whole legit competitive e-sport counterpoint.
Speaker 1: It may not matter because in the early days of American professional sports like hockey, the officiating was just corrupt, made up nonsense half the time.
Speaker 1: Like games would get canceled because the power went out or the ice melted.
Speaker 1: Like professional sports was amateur hour for like 50 years.
Speaker 0: It's been amateur hour.
Speaker 0: It's like when you were watching it as kids in the 80s and 90s, didn't feel like amateur hour.
Speaker 0: But now you look at what we have, how far we've come.
Speaker 0: If you look back just like the 90s, it's like, wow, what?
Speaker 1: Dude, I was we were watching.
Speaker 1: we saw that documentary about the Red Wings in the Russian five.
Speaker 1: So we saw like long under under erupted segments of play from like a hockey game in 1996.
Speaker 1: That shit is barely officiated.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So in some other news, Bethesda, Bethesda, I feel like Bethesda is a verb at this point.
Speaker 1: But if you're not aware, you're probably you might not actually be aware of why these means were happening.
Speaker 1: But there was a huge amount of memes around someone's trying to do something.
Speaker 1: And then the next panel was just sorry.
Speaker 1: A Bethesda dot net account is required to play this title, right?
Speaker 0: So what happened was to continue complete surprise to everyone.
Speaker 0: No one knew this wasn't announced in advance, which I think is good.
Speaker 0: They just put Doom, Doom two, Doom three on switch.
Speaker 0: And I think some other platforms, maybe they just put it out there.
Speaker 0: And now I don't think what do I need?
Speaker 0: Doom on my switch, right?
Speaker 1: Because on one hand, you might think like, oh, a first person shooter without a mouse and keyboard.
Speaker 1: What bullshit is this?
Speaker 1: However, imagine this scenario.
Speaker 1: You go to a con with your friends.
Speaker 1: You're hanging out in a hotel room.
Speaker 1: You'll have switches and you just play multiplayer Doom together, right?
Speaker 0: Then they have somehow not only it's like, oh, do my switch, whatever.
Speaker 0: I wouldn't pay even a dollar for that.
Speaker 0: I got every doom, everything ever and quake, everything ever on my PC.
Speaker 0: But no, they added co-op and multiplayer that just works without having to fuck around.
Speaker 1: One in Doom two are not actually 3D.
Speaker 1: You don't need to aim up and down.
Speaker 1: And yes, while even in a game like that, a controller is objectively, ridiculously inferior to a mouse and keyboard.
Speaker 0: Good enough.
Speaker 1: If you've all got the same controllers and you're in the same room together, that shit is lit.
Speaker 0: Better than GoldenEye.
Speaker 1: The only thing, the only thing that had to get right is that it has to just work.
Speaker 1: And that is what Bethesda fucked up.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 0: So apparently to make this work, you need to Bethesda login.
Speaker 0: And it's like, what the fuck?
Speaker 1: I feel like most people, their first thought was, what the fuck is Bethesda.net?
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 1: No one knows what Bethesda is.
Speaker 0: Imagine some little kid who buys doom on his switch.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Or some, you know, it's like they turn it on and it's like, you must log in.
Speaker 0: It's like, what the fuck?
Speaker 0: I feel like Bethesda on that account is required to go to his computer, go to Bethesda.net, making it who knows what the fuck.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: And anyway, so they're changed.
Speaker 0: They're like, they're claiming it was a mistake, which is bullshit.
Speaker 0: And they're going to change it.
Speaker 0: So it's optional.
Speaker 1: There is no way this was an accident.
Speaker 1: It was a mistake.
Speaker 1: No, I mean, it should at least admit it was just a mistake that no one cares about you and just take your money from the fact that this is a brilliant idea.
Speaker 1: The only thing that could have been better than this, if someone had thought to just make a good FPS that was designed for controllers that just worked and sell it on the switch as an indie game.
Speaker 0: I mean, they did, but it wasn't on the switch.
Speaker 0: It was called halo.
Speaker 1: It was called golden high.
Speaker 0: It was better than gold.
Speaker 1: Kalo is a lot better than golden high, but doom is like this perfect storm because the fact that it's this two point five D at least do one in Doom two.
Speaker 0: It's not really two point five D.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it is.
Speaker 0: Two point five D is usually referred to like, you know, like Smash Brothers.
Speaker 1: So here's the deal.
Speaker 1: Doom.
Speaker 1: I know a lot about the Doom engine because I was, do you have a three D game, but your camera is fixed, right?
Speaker 0: It's a flat.
Speaker 0: So I was, everything moves on a flat plane.
Speaker 1: So I was deep into the Doom modding community when I was younger, but basically the way the Doom engine works is fascinating.
Speaker 1: I'm not going to get into all the details.
Speaker 1: That'd be a whole show, but basically the game is two D in that no Sprite, like no object can ever be on top of or underneath another object that cannot overlap on the top down two D plane.
Speaker 1: However, every object, every missile, every enemy, everything other than the floor, because I don't want to get into explaining like sectors.
Speaker 1: Now that works has a Z coordinate and the game uses that to render how high it looks like it is.
Speaker 1: But if you aim at something, uh, say I aim at an imp that's way above me, I'm still looking straight ahead.
Speaker 1: If I have an aim at the, at the two D coordinate, that thing is my bullet will just go up as far as I can see it and hit that guy because the Z component is purely for rendering and display.
Speaker 1: It doesn't do anything else.
Speaker 1: That's how you can like fall off of stuff.
Speaker 1: Uh, but yeah, Doom is basically the perfect storm for this kind of thing.
Speaker 0: Bringing it out on the switch with multiplayers, the brilliant idea and Bethesda just expose a generation of younger non PC gamers to do maybe, yeah, do just be nice on its own.
Speaker 1: Doom co-op is legitimately fun.
Speaker 0: I see so many people on like switch discussion places on the internet who are like, bring this to switch, bring this to switch, please remake this thing on switch.
Speaker 0: And it's like, people is the switch literally the other, like, please bring Netflix to switch.
Speaker 0: It's like, is this the only fucking computing device you own?
Speaker 0: So it's like I, you only need a switch to play rather the wild Mario maker.
Speaker 1: So Jesus Christ, actually, so I didn't, I wasn't gonna make this my news cause I was gonna wait for later numbers, but projections are that the switch may soon have outsold the fucking Super Nintendo.
Speaker 0: Yeah, no, the switches are, nothing's the outsell.
Speaker 0: the we though, but the point is a or a DS maybe, but the point is the switch is selling a lot, but it's like, kids do not have laptops.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I can't imagine having a switch and not having like a phone or a computer or literally any other thing ever.
Speaker 1: You don't interact with regular people that often.
Speaker 0: It's like the switch is the only thing you own.
Speaker 0: You need every piece of software that everyone else has and all their other things.
Speaker 0: You know what it is?
Speaker 1: They don't own a tablet.
Speaker 1: They don't have a laptop.
Speaker 1: They have a phone, but the switch is a way better screen and they don't know anything about it.
Speaker 1: Technology works.
Speaker 0: You don't have a TV with like some sort of some box connected to it, even if it's not a real HD, VC, you don't have a computer, not one they can carry with them.
Speaker 1: They don't have an iPad.
Speaker 1: Those are expensive.
Speaker 0: It's like you get a Kindle fire or whatever.
Speaker 1: Yeah, those cost 20 bucks.
Speaker 0: I'm making is that if you don't have any of those things, why are you buying?
Speaker 1: the chat is even like room is right on this.
Speaker 0: If you don't have any of those things, why are you buying switch?
Speaker 0: You should buy iPad first.
Speaker 0: You know what?
Speaker 1: Second, I would buy switch first.
Speaker 0: Well, you have, cause I, I would buy a switch for you to get rid of all your computers and all your everything else and have just a switch.
Speaker 0: That would be the last device you would get rid of.
Speaker 1: No, no, no.
Speaker 1: I would buy switch first because I already have a phone because you have a phone and I would just learn a phone.
Speaker 0: Then why do you fucking need all this other shit on the switch?
Speaker 1: One because they don't want to use their phone to phone doesn't have a good controller or games on it.
Speaker 1: Really.
Speaker 0: This isn't, I'm not talking about just games like others.
Speaker 1: I don't know people that you, we are already in a rarefied class of people who know a lot about this stuff.
Speaker 1: Most people buy more shit.
Speaker 0: If you got enough money to buy a switch, you can buy more shit.
Speaker 0: Oh, I got a good shooter.
Speaker 1: Good quote in the stream.
Speaker 1: If my Brazilian ass gets enough money, I'll get a switch first.
Speaker 0: You'd have a switch and not have a phone or a tablet or a computer.
Speaker 1: You know what?
Speaker 0: You'd go only switch.
Speaker 0: If you had to go down to one device, that would be the last one you get rid of.
Speaker 0: You know what?
Speaker 1: I've had more fun on my switch than I have on my phone.
Speaker 1: My phone is not a fun device.
Speaker 1: My phone is a necessary device.
Speaker 0: Anyway.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so I talked about this briefly last time, but Overwatch had a ton of changes, but now that I've actually like really looked into them, analyzed them, thought about them a lot, there's good stuff going on here.
Speaker 1: This is really interesting what's happening.
Speaker 0: Well, the only thing that I read actually is, A, people are, there's some role cues.
Speaker 0: You can always be what you want to be.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but there's a lot more to it than that.
Speaker 0: Alright, I'm sure we'll hear about it, but the other thing I read was actually Take This wrote an article today about the new character.
Speaker 1: I saw that.
Speaker 1: I wasn't going to talk about that, but I did read that article.
Speaker 0: And how the new character is like a bad trope and stereotype of people with mental illness.
Speaker 1: Well, it's, it's complicated.
Speaker 0: I don't know anything about the new character.
Speaker 1: So the new character is basically someone who did a Dr.
Speaker 1: Manhattan type experiment and it like broke his brain.
Speaker 0: Instead of becoming Dr.
Speaker 0: Manhattan, he just sort of messed up.
Speaker 1: He's messed up and he has like power over time and gravity.
Speaker 0: Oh, okay.
Speaker 1: And he can't remember who he, like he lost himself.
Speaker 0: Like he's, it's creepy.
Speaker 0: Dr.
Speaker 0: Manhattan had the opposite of the thing though.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: His brain went, got better.
Speaker 0: From a certain point of view.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but from another point of view, he lost the concept of what humans are.
Speaker 0: Yes, indeed.
Speaker 1: It's one of those kinds of things, which is complicated because it's a, it is a negative.
Speaker 1: It is a potentially negative depiction of mental illness, but simultaneously there are other characters in Overwatch who are more positive representations of, I will not say mental illness, but of a neuro-typical people.
Speaker 1: And I have not looked into this enough to comment on that issue.
Speaker 0: No, I'll just say, read this.
Speaker 0: I did.
Speaker 0: I read the article, but other people read that article.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'll take any R word for it because I don't have a word.
Speaker 1: I'll link to it in the show notes because it is a, it's a, it's a good article.
Speaker 1: to read it.
Speaker 1: You should think about this kind of thing, but, uh, talk about the do the role cue thing.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So Overwatch in general is doing pretty much everything right when it comes to e-sports.
Speaker 1: They're trying the hardest, like they're trying the hardest to make it real and professional and modern.
Speaker 1: They're not having the amateur hour kind of crap.
Speaker 0: They care about legitimacy.
Speaker 1: They're trying, they're trying like, you know, home games and like league, like leagues that are based on like home and away schedules and teams that are based in city, like they're doing everything right.
Speaker 1: But there was this, but there were two things that happened in Overwatch that were a problem.
Speaker 1: And viewership of Overwatch league was going down and players of Overwatch were less engaged.
Speaker 1: Like people were giving up on the game or at least weren't playing it as much.
Speaker 1: On one hand in league, there was a particular meta that it involved that it mean Overwatch league, not league.
Speaker 0: Usually when people just say league, they mean league of legends.
Speaker 0: Yup.
Speaker 1: Overwatch people, when they say league, they mean Overwatch league.
Speaker 0: Usually you say owl or something.
Speaker 1: Well, like if you live in New York, when you say the city, you mean New York city.
Speaker 0: No.
Speaker 0: If you live on earth and you say the city, you mean New York city.
Speaker 1: If you live in Europe, you might mean London because London is a, I will argue that London is a peer to New York.
Speaker 1: It is the only pair to New York, but it is a peer to New York.
Speaker 1: So in league, a meta involved that is incredibly boring to watch.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 1: Unless you are a professional or a serious player.
Speaker 0: But that's true of all sports.
Speaker 0: Is that the most conservative strategy?
Speaker 0: is the strongest strategy.
Speaker 1: For example, the New Jersey devils, the New England Patriots are boring, but they win.
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 1: Me as an enlightened enjoyer of games, I appreciate what they do, even though I hate them.
Speaker 0: Yup.
Speaker 1: But I appreciate the craft and I appreciate someone who plays.
Speaker 0: It's funny to say that when the owner's name is Robert Kraft.
Speaker 1: He's a bad person.
Speaker 1: Yeah, he is.
Speaker 1: But, or for example, like as someone who plays a lot of Overwatch, I'm fine with that meta.
Speaker 1: I love watching the triple tank, triple, triple healer.
Speaker 0: Like, is that the strategy?
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Basically you get three tanks, three healers, no, no snipers, no DPS, no nothing.
Speaker 0: DPS doesn't matter.
Speaker 1: It's just a game of attrition.
Speaker 1: It's just, it's basically two teams, posturing.
Speaker 0: So if you have three tanks and three healers who make this unkillable blob.
Speaker 0: Two unkillable blobs.
Speaker 0: And what if the other team has like DPS?
Speaker 0: Couldn't they do enough DPS?
Speaker 1: You can't bring them down.
Speaker 0: So why don't they decrease the rates of healing and HP on the tanks?
Speaker 1: I don't think so.
Speaker 0: So that a DPS concentrating on a tank could take it down, even if it's being healed.
Speaker 1: I will get back to that actually.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 1: So, cause I have another news I want to link to briefly that's related to this.
Speaker 0: Like sniper shot, kiss you in the head.
Speaker 0: You should be dead.
Speaker 0: It doesn't matter.
Speaker 0: Right?
Speaker 1: So this meta is fun for professionals to watch and play and boring for everyone else.
Speaker 1: See also American baseball for many people.
Speaker 0: The battery, especially now.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Like the battery is still interesting to people who care a lot about it and know a lot about it and is completely boring to anyone else.
Speaker 1: And if you don't know what the battery is, then you were probably bored by baseball.
Speaker 1: So, uh, when Overwatch announced that they were going to have this role lock, meaning your team must consist of two DPS, two tank, two support, like a lot of people assumed that that was to prevent this meta from ruining the professional spectator aspect of Overwatch.
Speaker 1: But that's not entirely true because they applied this to all Overwatch, even quick play, even like regular old bronze tier competitive.
Speaker 0: So no matter what mode you can't just change.
Speaker 0: So they took strategy out of the game.
Speaker 0: You can no longer decide your team composition.
Speaker 0: The number of possible team compositions was decreased dramatically.
Speaker 1: Well, so in the arcade you can still do like.
Speaker 1: there's a million modes and custom servers.
Speaker 1: You can do normal mode, but even like capture the flag is still, there are a lot of DPS, like there are a lot of options in these three.
Speaker 0: There is still, I'm sure, I'm sure there are still a large number, but it was a vast decrease from an even more crazy large number.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 1: But I would analogize this to the rules of who you put on the field and where you put them in football.
Speaker 1: If football did not have like the role of wide receiver or the concept of eligible receivers, the game would break down into a really boring meta.
Speaker 0: Baseball, you can do other things in football.
Speaker 0: Like you could just put like a huge dude out there as your quarterback if you really want, but there's no, you know, it's like you can't like.
Speaker 1: there's rules on like eligible receivers.
Speaker 1: Like there's rules to limit what role a player can play in a given like play, uh, other professionals like hockey.
Speaker 1: You can't just say I'm at two goalies and four people on the ice.
Speaker 1: Can't do that.
Speaker 1: You can't just be like, yeah, four of my players are wearing goalie pads.
Speaker 0: You could have one person in goalie pad and someone else just hang out with them.
Speaker 0: You could wear normal gear.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: And the same thing in Overwatch.
Speaker 1: The DPS could like do a tanky, like try to act like a tank.
Speaker 0: You could get some, you could get say your backup goalie in non goalie gear, hang out near the goal in front of your real goalie or maybe to the side.
Speaker 0: And they have, you know, they do some Evangelion episode whatever DDR episode trading to where they're in sync, right?
Speaker 1: So in Overwatch now you can have one of your two tanks.
Speaker 1: So you wanted to play a more DPS focused game.
Speaker 1: You can have one of your two tanks pick a more DPS focused tank.
Speaker 1: So there are still a lot, there's a lot of fungibility there, but it forces a certain level of structure.
Speaker 1: And I really analogize it to football because it does just so happens that the meta of the game is extremely boring to spectators unless you do things like that.
Speaker 1: And, uh, what do we always say on geek nights?
Speaker 1: Professional sports.
Speaker 1: The only people that matter are the spectators.
Speaker 1: Nothing else matters except for health and safety.
Speaker 0: Well, there's, you know, there's legitimacy and then spectators, right?
Speaker 1: Well, I would argue that legitimate, they don't always go together.
Speaker 0: Cause if you see the incredibly illegitimate FIFA soccer as the most spectators on earth.
Speaker 1: True.
Speaker 0: And the extremely, you know, the other thing, you know, I guess the most legitimate sport would be basketball probably, even though it's got some issues, but you know, actually more exciting.
Speaker 0: I would almost basketball has more spectator.
Speaker 1: I would almost analogize soccer to Fortnite in the sense that soccer has terrible governance and re and terrible officiating.
Speaker 0: There are, there are things though that have worse governance in Fortnite.
Speaker 1: Oh yeah.
Speaker 1: But I'm saying that Fortnite is similar in that people are invested in Fortnite as a concept to the point that all those other mistakes don't actually matter to the fan base.
Speaker 1: Maybe soccer is very similar.
Speaker 0: Boo that cheating guy or cheer when he lost or, you know, whatever they ate a cheating guy.
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 0: So they cared about the legitimacy to quite an extent.
Speaker 1: So here's the thing, cause I don't, I can't turn this, I can't turn this into rim talking about overwatch for an hour cause we have an RPG to talk about.
Speaker 1: So they applied these changes everywhere, not just in the pro modes because the, it wasn't that the meadow was the problem with everyone else.
Speaker 1: It was that people like players of games in general, the average person are incapable of talking to each other and are incapable of forming a valid team composition.
Speaker 1: So by forcing the same role lock in the regular modes that they force in the professional modes, even if the people who happen to be matched up with you on a random game that you play in just a regular old mode might be utter pieces of shit or incapable of talking to each other, they cannot ruin the team composition, which matters a lot.
Speaker 1: Imagine if football like American football, we're an online game where everyone plays a role and you join a team and it's 12 people.
Speaker 1: Let's say they just say you get 12 people and eight of them just say, I'm playing a wide receiver.
Speaker 1: Fuck you.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I think the main thing is though is that, you know, when you look at a lot of the e-sports, especially the FPSs, there are games in which there's no stoppage.
Speaker 0: There's no plays really to usually, right?
Speaker 0: Everyone can go everywhere and do everything.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: And it's like, okay, you know, I think what we need to do, you know, the, the role lock is, is, is a fine solution for a game like overwatch, assuming you don't need to want to fundamentally change the game.
Speaker 1: Also because overwatch is a limited number of players and it has set matches.
Speaker 0: There's a lot of reasons you know, and you look at say rocket league, it's like usually in rocket league, you'll self-organize, you know, someone will hang back and be the goalie, but nothing's stopped.
Speaker 0: Everyone's just in a car.
Speaker 0: Everyone's equal.
Speaker 0: You can all do whatever.
Speaker 0: I'll go all over the field.
Speaker 0: I think there really needs to be a development of some sort of game where it's like, you know, in the MOBAs, someone has to be the carry.
Speaker 0: Someone sorta has to, if you don't have, you know, but sort of the right, you can, everyone can go everywhere and do everything.
Speaker 0: The support in a MOBA can go away and destroy the base.
Speaker 0: theoretically, right?
Speaker 1: Theoretically, like I have killed a lot of people as mercy in overwatch.
Speaker 0: Sure, sure.
Speaker 0: But what we need is we need someone to make some kind of game.
Speaker 0: I can't imagine what the game will be like where you literally must have, like we just talked about goalie.
Speaker 0: Imagine some sort of FPS where it's a capture the flag game.
Speaker 0: I'm just, I'm just kind of with whatever right now.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And not everyone can touch the flag.
Speaker 0: There's only one person has to be a flag carrier and all they can do is carry the flag.
Speaker 0: They can't even shoot.
Speaker 0: That's obviously not going to be that fun a game, but you get the idea of like the route.
Speaker 0: Now the game itself is such that you must have a person in these roles.
Speaker 0: Well, right.
Speaker 0: When you sign into the game, there's going to be like a, um, you know, you know, you can, you're the, you can't go in that area if you're not the goalie.
Speaker 0: You can't look at literally cannot do this thing and let.
Speaker 0: your only one kind of role has guns.
Speaker 0: No one else has them.
Speaker 1: Let's look at like ice hockey.
Speaker 1: You could just have two left wings.
Speaker 0: Sure.
Speaker 1: If you wanted to.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: Because the probably because the human being that's playing left wing versus right wing versus center has a different set of skills and abilities.
Speaker 0: It's usually about their handedness.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Handed your left handed.
Speaker 1: Also handedness is kind of messed up in the U S like I, I learned this from while I don't want to get into it now, but basically American street handedness and hockey differently from the rest of the world for weird reasons.
Speaker 1: And I feel like that's a topic I want to bring up.
Speaker 1: I got to find a video on it and make it a thing of the day in the future.
Speaker 1: Cause I read about that.
Speaker 0: I know about that as well.
Speaker 1: Uh, fun fact, I'm, I'm like hyper right-handed like I am right-handed to an extreme.
Speaker 0: All you gotta know is that if an American is right handed, they keep their right hand near the bottom of the hockey stick.
Speaker 0: Whereas if say a Canadian was right handed, they got their right hand at the top of the hockey stick and their left hand near the blade.
Speaker 1: So I was taught hockey left-handed because my, the people I played hockey with knew better.
Speaker 1: So I am right handed.
Speaker 1: So when I was first handed a hockey stick as a kid, I was handed it and told to play left-handed and it made me way better.
Speaker 1: I put my right hand, my right hands at the top, my left hands at the bottom.
Speaker 0: My right hand is near the blade.
Speaker 0: I guess American style.
Speaker 1: My left hand is near the blade and I'm right-handed anyway.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so the, the roll lock thing that they did is going to make the sport more professional and probably save it.
Speaker 1: In my opinion, I may be wrong.
Speaker 1: I mean, it's hard to tell if it can be saved.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: It's not going to hurt.
Speaker 1: I think it can be saved.
Speaker 1: If any e-sport is going to be the most like legitimate and serious, I feel like the blizzard ones, blizzard is trying the hardest.
Speaker 0: Even if it fails, it probably isn't because of the e-sports things they're doing.
Speaker 0: It's just, you know, you got to have interest in your game.
Speaker 0: Exactly.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: It's like, yeah, even if you run your league a hundred percent correctly, it's like, well, people aren't interested in your game.
Speaker 1: It's going to make regular play way better and bring people back into the game.
Speaker 1: because the way regular competitive play now works, if you do a roll lock, you'll have three different rankings for each of the roles.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: So if I join a game and I say, I'm a tank, I'll get a tank rating.
Speaker 1: Now the game's algorithms when they decide how good I actually am and how much I contribute to the team.
Speaker 0: It could be world champion tank rating and like nub.
Speaker 1: But it means I could play competitive and decide I want to try being DPS and try to get better at DPS and it won't hurt my other ranks.
Speaker 0: That's real good.
Speaker 1: And if I suck at DPS, it'll put me in wood tier where I belong and I won't ruin anyone else's game.
Speaker 0: Also good.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: But also the only thing I can imagine this being a problem with is let's say everyone wants to be tanks and now you chose tank and you wait like an hour to get in a game because not enough.
Speaker 0: And meanwhile games aren't launching because no one wants to be, not a factor.
Speaker 1: The player base is broad enough.
Speaker 0: It is, but there could be, there's going to be a longer line in one of the categories.
Speaker 1: You know what?
Speaker 1: The categories have the longest line is DPS and those are the shittiest people.
Speaker 1: So problem is going to self correct.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 1: But the separate ranking also means this is the important part.
Speaker 1: They haven't said much about this, the algorithm, because it's still a team game.
Speaker 1: Like I've been rated between low silver and like upper gold, low platinum, depending solely on who I happen to be matched with when I play games.
Speaker 1: Because sometimes I get good teammates.
Speaker 1: Sometimes I get shitty teammates.
Speaker 1: Sometimes I get good comp.
Speaker 1: Sometimes I get bad comp.
Speaker 1: But with this, the algorithms that determine your rank can take very specific factors into account.
Speaker 1: Like if you're playing tanks, it can look at how much damage you prevented being done to your team and use that to have a more nuanced approach to your skill ranking in terms of the team, even if the rest of your team sucks.
Speaker 1: There's no way to do that today.
Speaker 1: And that's enough Overwatch talk because it's time for...
Speaker 0: I just want to briefly talk about this one thing.
Speaker 0: Oh, what one thing?
Speaker 0: So we talked about 8BitDo a while ago.
Speaker 0: It's a company that makes third party game controllers that don't suck.
Speaker 0: Oh yeah.
Speaker 0: I forgot about this.
Speaker 0: They made a thing, the adapter that lets you basically plug in the GameCube controllers wire into it, and it will wirelessly connect to a switch.
Speaker 0: So you can play Smash with a GameCube controller.
Speaker 0: That's a wired controller, but you'll be wireless.
Speaker 0: I got one.
Speaker 0: I used it for Smash.
Speaker 0: It's great.
Speaker 0: I still use it if I smash, which is rarely, but I have it.
Speaker 0: It's good.
Speaker 0: So 8BitDo had this other controller called the SN30 Pro, and basically it was a Super Nintendo looking controller, but it had two analog sticks like PlayStation.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: People know controller is pretty good, but people had some issues with it.
Speaker 0: I think there was a Kickstarter or whatever, but now there is an Amazon pre-order for this new controller, the 8BitDo SN30 Pro Plus.
Speaker 0: It's a Super Nintendo controller that also has two analog joysticks, two analog sticks where the PlayStation original PS one has them.
Speaker 0: It has, you know, the extra has two triggers on each side, not just one.
Speaker 0: And it has wing-a-lings like a PlayStation controller.
Speaker 0: And you can use this to connect to a switch, a PC, right?
Speaker 0: A Raspberry Pi.
Speaker 1: This might be the one controller.
Speaker 0: Windows, OS X, or Android.
Speaker 0: It doesn't connect to iOS.
Speaker 0: It connects to literally everything else except iOS and PlayStations and Xboxes.
Speaker 0: But yeah, Windows, Android, OS X, Steam, Switch, Raspberry Pi.
Speaker 0: It's like the be all end all controller.
Speaker 0: It seems to be.
Speaker 0: I'm going to wait for some more reviews of people actually got one in their hands.
Speaker 0: Some people did get them already before I decide, but I think if this controller is legit, it's only $50 per controller.
Speaker 0: The Switch Pro Controller costs a fortune.
Speaker 0: The new Xbox controller is a mega fortune, right?
Speaker 0: PlayStation controllers, I think, are more or at least as expensive.
Speaker 0: So since I don't have an Xbox or a PlayStation, I think I might get rid of if this is a legit controller.
Speaker 1: I've already got four Xbox controllers that I used on the HDPC.
Speaker 0: I'm going to get one of these, and if it's legit, I'm going to dump my Xbox controllers.
Speaker 0: I'll even dump, I have real SNES and NES controllers like adapters.
Speaker 1: I have the same.
Speaker 0: I'll dump those.
Speaker 0: I won't even really need GameCube controllers.
Speaker 0: It's not like...
Speaker 1: I'm definitely getting rid of that garbage.
Speaker 1: Steam controller.
Speaker 0: Right, Steam controller gone.
Speaker 0: I'm going to get rid of every controller and just replace it with like two or three of these.
Speaker 0: The end.
Speaker 0: Forever.
Speaker 0: The perfect controller.
Speaker 0: So I'm hoping that it turns out to be true.
Speaker 0: I'm super glad that it's no longer the case as it was for my whole life that only first party controllers are worth a shit.
Speaker 0: And all third party was trash except for like the occasional fight stick.
Speaker 0: Finally, 8BitDo coming through with the third party controllers that don't suck.
Speaker 0: Hopefully, the verdict is not in yet, but it's looking promising.
Speaker 1: What a time to be alive.
Speaker 1: That's right.
Speaker 1: But anyway, it is time for Things of the Day.
Speaker 1: What do you got?
Speaker 0: So, Bruno Faidutti, I think that's how you pronounce his name, is the game designer who made the game, Citadels, among many other great games.
Speaker 1: Ooh, I've been thinking about Citadels because of some stuff we might do at PAX Unplugged.
Speaker 0: Anyway, Bruno Faidutti went to Tehran in Iran and checked out the board game scene in Iran.
Speaker 1: And it is lit.
Speaker 0: Well, it's not 100% lit, but there's a lot going on there.
Speaker 0: It's kind of exciting.
Speaker 0: And he wrote a big ass article about it.
Speaker 0: And if you go look at the article, you'll say, "Hey, this isn't in English,
Speaker 0: goddammit.".
Speaker 0: Especially if you can't read it, I think it's French.
Speaker 1: It looks like French.
Speaker 0: But if you scroll all the fucking way down, he wrote the whole article again in English.
Speaker 0: Thank Satan.
Speaker 0: The article's written twice on his blog, once in French, once in English.
Speaker 0: You can read all about what's going on in the board game scene in Tehran.
Speaker 0: And it is fascinating, excellent read.
Speaker 0: If you care anything about board games or the country of Iran or both, read this shit.
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 1: So my thing of the day, Hank Green, you know, the guy who does a lot of YouTube videos with his brother.
Speaker 0: Your favorite YouTube guy.
Speaker 1: Yeah, he's a pretty good guy.
Speaker 1: I used to be more a fan of John Green, but Hank Green has grown on me over time.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: But this is special.
Speaker 1: He did this spinoff show called Journey Into the Microcosmos.
Speaker 1: And holy shit.
Speaker 1: So basically, this is like the thing you should watch before you go to bed every night.
Speaker 1: It's basically really, really good microscopic video of tiny organisms and him very softly talking to you and explaining what the deal is with protozoa and like really excruciating detail.
Speaker 1: And it is terrifying and fascinating.
Speaker 1: I've learned a ton.
Speaker 0: Is this why you're scared of amoebas at the lake?
Speaker 1: No, I mentioned the amoebas at the lake because amoeba deaths have actually been on the rise due to global warming.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but there are no amoeba deaths in New York yet.
Speaker 1: Not yet, but they're coming north.
Speaker 0: I'm sure they are.
Speaker 1: They're coming north rapidly.
Speaker 1: Basically, don't swim in freshwater lakes in the south without nose plugs.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: And don't go to water parks in the south.
Speaker 0: I mean, the amoebas can't live in the ocean, though, right?
Speaker 0: Nope.
Speaker 0: And they can't live in a swimming pool.
Speaker 1: Not really good enough.
Speaker 1: Chlorine just kills them.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So it's basically fresh places.
Speaker 1: I swim shallow, warm, fresh water, mostly in the south.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 1: But it is weird to watch a video that's just like this tiny little single celled organism, like having a fight with another single celled organism in semi real time.
Speaker 1: And you just get to watch it while Hank Green in a very soft voice just explains, like, what's going on?
Speaker 1: This stuff.
Speaker 1: This is my jam.
Speaker 1: You just have to watch this.
Speaker 1: And the one I'm going to link to is the one he waited to do until long after the show started.
Speaker 1: The best tiny organism, the smallest actual animal, the tardigrade, the snoot.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the water bears, the snoot, the tiny little bear looking guys.
Speaker 0: I know that guy.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that guy.
Speaker 1: I learned I learned some crazy shit about this guy from this video.
Speaker 0: The thing is, I keep seeing pictures of that guy all over the place, but like a little guy.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: But where does it even like live everywhere?
Speaker 0: Like is it went on me right now?
Speaker 1: They live in like tiny bits, like tiny films of water that are like just drops of water on plants.
Speaker 1: They're just there.
Speaker 1: They're all over the world.
Speaker 0: They're everywhere on the whole earth.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: And they're basically invincible.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 0: Are they like?
Speaker 1: NASA sent a whole bunch of them into space on the outside of a research thing and they were fine when they came back.
Speaker 0: But it's like, are they on me right now?
Speaker 1: Uh, on you?
Speaker 1: Probably not.
Speaker 0: Are they the most, are there more of these than any other living organism on earth?
Speaker 0: Hell no.
Speaker 0: Are they like actually the number one guy?
Speaker 0: Who's the number one guy?
Speaker 0: Some kind of fungus?
Speaker 1: No, probably some sort of archivacteria, I guess.
Speaker 1: I am might remember when we were not, when we were learning biology, there were still five kingdoms and everything was way different.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Uh, some kid who lives in a rich school district and is in high school probably knows more about this than we do.
Speaker 0: Yeah, probably.
Speaker 1: But these videos are really, really fascinating to watch in the meta moment.
Speaker 1: The geek nights book club book is the first novel, not the first book, but arguably the first novel.
Speaker 0: Actually the first novel ever written the tale of Genji.
Speaker 0: It's long.
Speaker 0: I'm not going to get to it soon.
Speaker 0: When I do get to it, it'll take a while.
Speaker 0: That's okay.
Speaker 0: Cause we actually read the last book club book in a decent amount of time.
Speaker 1: I'm currently reading a nonfiction book that's mostly focused so far on baseball teams a long time ago using particular kinds of grass to try to cheat.
Speaker 1: So it's good stuff.
Speaker 0: Relevant to our interests.
Speaker 1: Uh, we will be live in a month at the penny arcade expo.
Speaker 1: Oh my God.
Speaker 0: I booked my flight, but also summer is coming to a close.
Speaker 1: Basically convention season starts.
Speaker 1: We're going to be at PAX west.
Speaker 1: Then not too long after that packs unplugged.
Speaker 1: Not too long after that magfest.
Speaker 1: Then right after that we got packs south and then pecs east is not that long after that.
Speaker 1: Cause it looks like pecs east is going to be early in 2020.
Speaker 0: Thank God it will be summer again.
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 1: So there's going to be a whirlwind convention season.
Speaker 1: You can see us on Friday or Saturday.
Speaker 0: It's like packs is coming up and I'm like, Oh no, no pegs do not come.
Speaker 0: It will be the end of summer and beaches, but then I'll have paxes and hockey just until the next summer.
Speaker 0: Yup.
Speaker 1: And we upgraded the, uh, we had a lot more hockey games than we used to.
Speaker 0: We got more people.
Speaker 1: So you got the same amount of hockey, but worst case scenario, I got all those games.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 1: I'll pay for them all.
Speaker 0: Go ahead.
Speaker 0: Uh, so yeah, let's get right into it.
Speaker 1: Uh, we talk a lot about RPGs.
Speaker 1: Like the first panel we ever did at a PAX was called beyond dungeons and dragons back in 2008.
Speaker 1: And the whole gist of that panel was guys, there are RPGs that are not dungeons and dragons or like dungeons and dragons in a different skin, like pathfinder or 20 star wars or whatever, or those garbage games like shadow run, which has never actually been a good game.
Speaker 0: Anyway, the point is we had a period of time where you played a lot of RPGs in college and shortly after college.
Speaker 0: And we still have a lot of people who are good to play with.
Speaker 0: You don't have that problem.
Speaker 0: The problem we have is all the people are adults and you can't get time together.
Speaker 0: And RPGs usually take a significant time to play.
Speaker 0: They take the good ones often have a lot of rules to learn and investment and that those are our hurdles.
Speaker 0: And this is, I think why people don't play tabletop RPGs in general and we'll even pay GMs to run games with them is because it's just such a to do to play an RPG.
Speaker 1: So, uh, actually there's another point there I want to make.
Speaker 1: before we get in as a, as a reviewer, I can read the rules to a board game and review it.
Speaker 1: But with RPGs, it's very hard to review an RPG without playing it a lot with a varied audience of people.
Speaker 1: So it's very hard to get to the point, even if I played a bunch of RPGs where I am comfortable passing some sort of judgment or reviewing it.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: I've got some RPGs on my shelf.
Speaker 0: I've never played a lot of them, quite a few.
Speaker 0: And it's like, I would have to play one of those several times with several different groups because I might have a good review, but like, Oh no, that was the group or we played it wrong.
Speaker 0: Or, you know, I'd have to see like, what is this game really all about?
Speaker 0: It's such a thing.
Speaker 1: When you review a game, you gotta be able to say, who is this for?
Speaker 1: Who is this not for?
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 0: You gotta get, you know, it's like, Oh, well that time that people didn't really learn the game when we played it.
Speaker 0: That time I played it with the experts.
Speaker 1: We played the wizard's grimoire enough to give a real review of it.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: So, uh, the wizard's grimoire is a game that I saw and it was like, Hey, get it on like itch IO for like a few dollar and you get all these other games in a big bundle that are all just PDFs.
Speaker 0: And I said, that sounds good to me.
Speaker 0: Just a bunch of PDFs not going on my shelf.
Speaker 0: Won't feel guilty if I don't play them.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: So paid the few dollars in itch IO.
Speaker 0: I downloaded a bundle of PDFs.
Speaker 0: I read the wizard's grimoire, the first one.
Speaker 0: Uh, I didn't read the other ones, but they're the similar, from what I can tell, uh, the barbarians bloody quest and all the other ones are basically the same mechanics, just with different, uh, you know, different setting, different character.
Speaker 1: Uh, and basically it's by Vincent Baker, who you may know from apocalypse world, kill puppies for Satan dogs in the vineyard.
Speaker 1: in a wicked age.
Speaker 1: apocalypse world is what most people would know.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 0: So, uh, puts out this game.
Speaker 0: It's a really brief game.
Speaker 0: The PDF is like a handful of pages.
Speaker 0: Most of the pages you don't even have to read to play.
Speaker 0: You only have to read like two pages to play.
Speaker 1: In fact, you need to exercise the cell, the, like the force of will to not read everything.
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 0: So the way it works is one per.
Speaker 0: it's a solo RPG.
Speaker 0: One person is the player.
Speaker 0: And what you do in order to play the game is you need to find two, not one, not three, exactly two volunteers to play the game.
Speaker 0: Those players need those volunteers.
Speaker 0: They're not players.
Speaker 0: Those two volunteers need a no prior knowledge of the game whatsoever.
Speaker 0: Be no time commitment whatsoever.
Speaker 0: You can play for one minute or forever.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: Like basically any player can say, Nope, we're done.
Speaker 0: Any player, the player or any volunteer can just be like, that's it or done with this session and you can end it.
Speaker 0: I hit myself with the mic.
Speaker 1: I didn't even cause it this time.
Speaker 0: You can end the game as abruptly as necessary at any time, whenever you want or have to or any doesn't matter.
Speaker 0: Right?
Speaker 0: It is the least investment imaginable.
Speaker 0: You can, if you're the player solo game, remember, you can just carry the game around with you.
Speaker 0: And literally any brief moment that you have found two volunteers, you can play like you're on a train.
Speaker 0: You happen to two nerds having to sit near you or a better a nerd and like a random non nerd, right?
Speaker 0: You convince them to volunteer.
Speaker 0: They volunteer.
Speaker 0: After five minutes, they're bored.
Speaker 0: You're done.
Speaker 0: All right, you did it.
Speaker 0: Good.
Speaker 0: It's like now.
Speaker 0: literally is that easy to play this game.
Speaker 1: I would be shocked if you ran into people who after five minutes were bored because what was fascinating about this both playing as a volunteer and by watching other people like play it and other people be volunteers is that it's real easy to get invested.
Speaker 1: Like the game, the simple bare minimum mechanics and the rules of how the story progresses really get people to be creative.
Speaker 1: And the fact that there are two volunteers is crucial to this.
Speaker 0: So here's how it works.
Speaker 0: The player reads their little document and it tells a story.
Speaker 0: You are some kind of wizard.
Speaker 0: You build your stats with this system.
Speaker 0: You can change your stats every session if you want to go nuts.
Speaker 0: Who cares?
Speaker 0: They don't progress or anything, right?
Speaker 1: So it was that the best of the two courts compiled her notes into a signature, right?
Speaker 1: Herself for travel, right?
Speaker 0: There's a story where somehow there was a magic book and you've got it and you don't understand shit in this magic book.
Speaker 0: So you are going to try to learn what's in the magic book.
Speaker 0: And the magic book is the several last pages of the PDF and you only read sections of that book.
Speaker 0: that is literally given to you when you have achieved enough understanding via in-game mechanics.
Speaker 0: And then with your self adult restraint, you only read one section of the book at a time when you're allowed to do so.
Speaker 0: So I have only unlocked so far one section of the book.
Speaker 0: I haven't read sections two through X. I don't know how many sections there are.
Speaker 0: I only know what's in that first section.
Speaker 0: And the goal as the solo player is to play enough to have enough sessions that you can read the whole book.
Speaker 0: But that's not actually your goal.
Speaker 0: Your actual goal, according to the rules, it says your goal as a player is to get in trouble and then get out of trouble, hopefully.
Speaker 1: And that happened reliably.
Speaker 0: Every single time I played, I got in trouble and got out of trouble, right?
Speaker 0: Now the volunteers, what are they all about?
Speaker 0: Well, here's how this game works.
Speaker 0: Ninety percent of the game does involves no dice.
Speaker 0: When it does involve dice, it's a D6.
Speaker 0: But don't worry about that D6 right now.
Speaker 0: The way the game works is you are the player.
Speaker 0: You find two volunteers who are willing to volunteer.
Speaker 0: They read some little tiny pieces of paper, which is like a whole page of the PDF, and it doesn't tell it in half.
Speaker 0: It doesn't tell much.
Speaker 0: Just tells them.
Speaker 0: the player is going to ask you questions.
Speaker 0: You answer them.
Speaker 0: Your goal as volunteers is to just answer the questions in the way that pleases you most.
Speaker 0: Entertain yourself with your answers to the questions.
Speaker 0: However, your answers to the questions only count and become real if both volunteers agree.
Speaker 0: Yes, that is the answer.
Speaker 1: That is the magic.
Speaker 1: That's the secret sauce.
Speaker 0: That's the whole game, basically.
Speaker 1: Because if there's just one volunteer.
Speaker 0: It's stupid.
Speaker 1: It's boring.
Speaker 1: It doesn't go anywhere.
Speaker 0: You don't have enough creative juice from one person and it can get stale.
Speaker 1: But two people, when I was playing with the other, I was one of the volunteers and we had another friend as a volunteer.
Speaker 1: He'd say something, I'd be like, "No, but what about...".
Speaker 1: And we really started bouncing off of each other in a hurry when we could veto each other.
Speaker 1: It must be unanimous.
Speaker 0: You need two votes for anything to become a correct, true answer in the game.
Speaker 1: But the other magic sauce is that we can't just, we're constrained heavily by all we can actually do is answer questions that Scott asks us.
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 0: These volunteers, if they have any...
Speaker 1: I can't just be like, "You are sitting in a cottage by the
Speaker 1: woods.".
Speaker 0: If these volunteers have any concept of normal, typical D&D-style RPGs with a GM, they feel like they're a team of GMs, right?
Speaker 0: Where they decide everything in the world.
Speaker 0: It's like, "No, no, no.
Speaker 0: That's not what you
Speaker 0: are.".
Speaker 0: All you are is procedural generators of answers.
Speaker 1: It edges almost more into like, "Sleep is
Speaker 1: death."
Speaker 1: Except there's two people who have to agree on what happens.
Speaker 0: So the player, right?
Speaker 0: They're really in control by asking the questions.
Speaker 0: They'll be like, you know, and sort of, you know, mostly in control, right?
Speaker 0: They'll be like, "What's the weather
Speaker 0: like?"
Speaker 0: Right?
Speaker 0: "What time is
Speaker 0: it?".
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 0: "Who knocked on my
Speaker 0: door?".
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: "I go into a town.
Speaker 0: What building do I
Speaker 0: see?".
Speaker 0: The volunteers might be like, "You don't see a
Speaker 0: building.".
Speaker 0: Right?
Speaker 0: "There are no buildings
Speaker 0: here.".
Speaker 0: It's like, "All right,
Speaker 0: fine.".
Speaker 0: "I go into a tavern.
Speaker 0: What does it smell like?
Speaker 0: Who's here?
Speaker 0: Who's sitting at the table in the back
Speaker 0: corner?".
Speaker 0: You can ask all kinds of leading questions, non-leading questions, and those volunteers have to answer all these questions or end the session, right?
Speaker 0: And that is what makes the things happen.
Speaker 0: Now, the dice, right?
Speaker 0: So, sometimes you want to do something, right?
Speaker 0: And you know, that you can't necessarily get done via asking questions, or there are questions that you can't really ask, right?
Speaker 0: Like, if I'm just asking the questions, like, "What does the grimoire
Speaker 0: mean?".
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's, "Ha, ha,
Speaker 0: ha."
Speaker 0: Right?
Speaker 0: "Oh, you met a large, mysterious man.
Speaker 0: Is this man planning to kill
Speaker 0: me?"
Speaker 0: Right?
Speaker 0: It's like, that's not something that you would be able to tell, like, how warm is it, right?
Speaker 1: Because if I got asked that question as a volunteer, you don't know.
Speaker 1: You can't read his face.
Speaker 1: Now what?
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: So, what you do in those cases is you have your stats, and you roll one d6, and the way the system works is you pick the relevant stat, and if the d6 goes over the number, or that's sort of like equal or over, that's a failure.
Speaker 0: You want to be as high as possible while being under.
Speaker 0: So if my stat is 4, I think maybe equal, oh, I forget, it doesn't matter, right?
Speaker 0: You over is bad, I forget if equal is bad, but under is definitely a success, and you still want the number to be higher, right?
Speaker 0: So, if I'm doing, like, a, you know, test for stealthiness or whatever, subtlety, I forget what it's actually called, not looking at the PDF right now, you know, then I would roll, and if I got, like, a 3, and my stat was 4, it's like, all right, well, I can, you know, I, it was really good, I got, like, 3 opportunities to be stealthy or whatever, and it's probably going to be a successful endeavor, right?
Speaker 0: The other thing that's really interesting is that there is an option to submit to circumstance, right?
Speaker 0: So, for example, in the third session where you weren't there, and I played, at one point, it's like, oh, you stumble into a bunch of cultists, and you weren't stealthy, and they saw you, and they caught you.
Speaker 0: It's like, I submit to circumstance, right?
Speaker 0: So I submit, and when you submit, it's the same system, but all the, as high as you get is the number of things you can keep.
Speaker 0: So you can choose, like,
Speaker 1: I keep my dignity,
Speaker 0: I keep my life, I keep my bearings, and it's like, all right, well, you lose, you lose, you
Speaker 1: lose your clothes,
Speaker 0: you lose your
Speaker 1: stuff, and that sword,
Speaker 0: and you're right, it's like, you know, it's like that, basically, to prevent the volunteers, it's like, okay, you choose what you keep, you choose what you live, and then the book says, all right, the volunteers now tell you, you know, what happens next, right?
Speaker 0: It's like, there are instructions on each dice roll for the different, so, like, 6 or 7 different ways you can roll the dice on exactly what to do and exactly what the volunteers do.
Speaker 0: So it's like, if you fail a certain thing, it's like, okay, you are unconscious, you are, you know, surprised or shocked, you're unconscious, you are then, you're snapped out of it by something the volunteers have to say what snaps you, you ask the volunteers, what snaps me out of it, right?
Speaker 0: And now they have to answer that question.
Speaker 1: And this leads to really fun interactions, like, at one point, Scott, I mean, one of the games we played, you basically did a thing that lets you know the mind of one of our NPCs.
Speaker 0: Right, right, right.
Speaker 0: It's like, when you roll the dice, it basically either allows you to ask questions, or forces you to ask certain questions, or it's always relating to the questions, right?
Speaker 0: It's like, well, now you have to ask this question, or you may now ask these three up to X questions you normally couldn't ask.
Speaker 1: Like, do these bandits actually plan to harm me?
Speaker 1: And then, as a volunteer, I gotta decide what the truth is there, and be truthful about it.
Speaker 0: You could say yes or no, but you just, you have to answer my question, or stop the game.
Speaker 1: And there's some magic here, like, this concept is very powerful, and I was incredibly surprised at how easily, even, because, you know, when you try to get someone to play an RPG, even, like, what seems like a short, low investment one, like Ghost Court, sometimes people, like, aren't super enthusiastic, or, like, they're really hesitant.
Speaker 1: People who are even hesitant in this game.
Speaker 0: All you gotta do is answer questions.
Speaker 0: It's like, even someone who knows nothing about RPGs, it's like, all right, you know, it's like, every session starts with a sort of, like, a hook, right?
Speaker 0: There's these little, like, tiny single paragraph, or even smaller hooks in the PDF.
Speaker 0: That's, like, a whole page, actually.
Speaker 0: Just hooks.
Speaker 0: I've just been picking one and starting, but I guess you can make up your own hooks also.
Speaker 0: But you just pick a hook, and then start asking questions.
Speaker 0: You read the hook, and start asking.
Speaker 0: And all the volunteers gotta do is answer.
Speaker 0: They don't gotta do nothing.
Speaker 0: Right?
Speaker 0: The player is the one who has to know at least a little bit about RPGs, but you don't gotta teach a volunteer shit.
Speaker 0: All they gotta do is answer questions.
Speaker 0: You know, all right, what does the town look like?
Speaker 0: What time is it?
Speaker 0: What color is the bartender's skin?
Speaker 0: What are they selling in the shop?
Speaker 0: What's the price?
Speaker 0: And the thing is, you can't do anything but ask questions.
Speaker 0: So it's like, how much does the beer cost?
Speaker 0: A gold piece.
Speaker 0: How many gold do I have?
Speaker 0: Five gold pieces.
Speaker 1: I drink five beers.
Speaker 0: I offer the man a gold.
Speaker 0: How many gold do I have?
Speaker 0: None.
Speaker 0: You don't have an inventory.
Speaker 0: You just ask questions.
Speaker 1: The highest praise I can give is that in the game I was an assistant in, and then a game I watched, were radically different, and both really fun.
Speaker 0: Every game I played was radically different.
Speaker 0: The volunteers basically, and it's who is playing, and the questions they ask, and who the volunteers are, and their mental state drives the game in a crazy different direction.
Speaker 1: The first one was like, "Oh, these bandits actually aren't that
Speaker 1: bad.".
Speaker 1: And the second one was like, "Scott's erotic
Speaker 1: journey.".
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: And the third one I played, the two volunteers were seasoned D&D GMs who had, I imagine, little experience with other RPGs.
Speaker 0: And sure enough, it was a dungeon full of cultists.
Speaker 0: And it's like, I guess that's the story you know how to tell.
Speaker 1: The most high praise I can give is that sitting next to a game of this, you really want to be able to answer questions.
Speaker 1: You want to be a volunteer, like badly.
Speaker 1: It was really hard to not shut up when Scott and Kate were being your volunteer.
Speaker 1: I kept jumping in, and you were like,
Speaker 1: "Shh.".
Speaker 0: Yeah, I didn't ask you.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but I really wanted to answer.
Speaker 1: I had good ideas.
Speaker 0: Too bad.
Speaker 1: This game, the risk to you as a person who could play an RPG is so low, you should just get this game and make random people play it with you.
Speaker 0: Also, the stuff you need to play this game is you need the PDF, which you could put on a few pieces of paper, or just like your iPad or your phone, right?
Speaker 0: You need a single D6.
Speaker 0: You need nothing else.
Speaker 0: I have been having a book and writing down everything that happens.
Speaker 0: That is not necessary or dictated or whatever.
Speaker 1: That's just fun.
Speaker 0: You guess you could actually do an audio recording might be easier.
Speaker 1: I think we're going to try to play this game a few times and record it and see how that goes, maybe live stream it.
Speaker 1: Right,
Speaker 0: but the point is you need nothing, so you just bring a D6 with you everywhere you go and either a digital or physical copy of the PDF, and any time you're in a situation where you've got nothing to do for some minutes, even a few minutes, you know, maybe at least 10 minimum, right?
Speaker 0: Maximum hours.
Speaker 0: You got two people.
Speaker 0: They're ready, willing, and able.
Speaker 0: You play.
Speaker 0: It's your game.
Speaker 0: You carry it around with you.
Speaker 0: You're the player.
Speaker 0: It's not like you have other, right?
Speaker 0: If other people want to play, they get their own PDF and start their own deal, right?
Speaker 0: Maybe you can volunteer for them too, but you know, it's your game.
Speaker 0: You're playing solo.
Speaker 0: You just need volunteers to help you unlock the wizard's grimoire, and the other ones in the series appear to follow the same mechanics.
Speaker 1: I think I'm going to say Bloody Quest is the one I might just start playing.
Speaker 0: I looked at the PDF of the Barbarian's Bloody Quest briefly.
Speaker 0: It is basically the same game, only obviously you're unlocking not a wizard's grimoire, but something else.
Speaker 1: You're Conan figuring out why the wizard killed everyone you've ever known.
Speaker 0: Right, and you know, you unlock pages in the PDF that you don't read at the start with your adult abilities.
Speaker 0: You have similar, you know, just different themes, but you still find two volunteers and ask them questions.
Speaker 0: That's the mechanic of the game, and you can make, I guess if you wanted to, there would be nothing stopping you from making more games using the two volunteer ask questions system, the wizard grimoire system.
Speaker 0: Just write up a new character, a new scenario, a new thing to unlock, right?
Speaker 0: A new set of stats, a new character generation system for those stats, and a bunch of hooks, and that's all you need.
Speaker 0: You can copy the volunteer page verbatim basically.
Speaker 1: So if you can, if there is anyone you want to be a celebrity guest on a live stream where Scott or I play these games, let us know.
Speaker 1: Like, I want to stream this game.
Speaker 1: This game, of all the RPGs we could stream, this is the one that has the most potential to not be boring or procedural.
Speaker 0: It needs nothing, right?
Speaker 0: And also, if you don't have friends in person, like if you go on the internet.
Speaker 1: Joe, you can play this on Discord with zero problems.
Speaker 0: Go on a Discord and just find two freaking people who are on the Discord at that moment, who have it for a minute, send them a digital copy of the thing to read, the volunteer page, not the other pages.
Speaker 1: You don't even need voice chat, you could do this over text, it would work fine.
Speaker 0: You could just chat your questions, but voice chat is probably easier if you have speaking and hearing abilities, but if not, texting, texting, just fine.
Speaker 0: You could even play this game slow rolling over email, email a question, then they email it back and forth.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you could play this game by mail.
Speaker 0: You could do this, whatever.
Speaker 0: This is the most flexible, least investment, highest payout RPG in maybe history.
Speaker 0: A+ for this game.
Speaker 1: Yep, Vincent Baker is always standout, but this one, I feel like, this one has given me ideas I hadn't thought about.
Speaker 1: Like, it pushed new ground that I had not considered in RPGs and is making me think about a later future of RPGs.
Speaker 0: It's like, please be a computer for me in this game I am play.
Speaker 0: That's why they're volunteers, they're just helping you play, you thank them profusely for their time and efforts.
Speaker 0: Computers can do a lot in terms of... Doing what a computer should and possibly will do in the future.
Speaker 1: But computers can do a lot in terms of procedural generation, but one thing they are not good at procedurally generating is stories.
Speaker 0: I've seen some.
Speaker 1: Not good ones.
Speaker 0: I've seen some machine learning pretty good stories.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I have, but they're not interactive like this.
Speaker 0: Anyway.
Speaker 1: This game is 100% worth playing.
Speaker 0: Get this game.
Speaker 1: This has been Geek Nights with Rim and Scott.
Speaker 1: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design, and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at FrontRowCrew.com for show notes, discussion news, and more.
Speaker 1: Remember, Geek Nights is not one, but four different shows.
Speaker 1: Sci-Tech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays, and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 0: Geek Nights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 0: Geek Nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 0: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.
Speaker 1: And the Patreon patrons for this episode of Geek Nights are... This is taking longer to load than usual.
Speaker 1: Craig Oliver, Alan Joyce, Heady McNichol, JustLikeADudeGuy, Kjartavishan, Link Iji, Graham Finch, Jennifer Hitchcock, Chris Midcave, MyStacy.com, Jay Bants, Scootalonely, Shawn Yeager, Nicholas Brando, Mr.
Speaker 1: Strong Stretch, and 421 Creations.
Speaker 1: Like Johann Sebastian, Bacharach, Ominous MacIntyre, Cyan Mancer, Thunder, Sheraton Von Harl, Rory, Superboy, Clinton Walton, Wren from New Zealand, Ryan Perrott, Dropenlander, Finn, Dread Lily Tanebrae, Sean Klein, Chris Reimer, Thomas Hahn.
Speaker 1: And now I leave you with something that I suspect you've forgotten if you've ever even encountered it.
Speaker 0: And I say, "Hey, yay, yay, yay, yay, hey, yay,
Speaker 0: yay.".
Speaker 0: I say, "Hey, what's it doing
Speaker 0: now?".
Speaker 0: And he tries.
Speaker 0: "Oh my God, no, I try.
Speaker 0: I try all the time in this
Speaker 0: institution.".
Speaker 0: And he tries.
Speaker 0: "Oh my God, no, I
Speaker 0: try.".
Speaker 0: And I say, "Hey, yay, yay, yay, yay, hey, yay, yay, yay, yay, yay, yay, hey, yay, yay, yay, hey, yay, yay, yay, yay, yay, yay, yay, yay, yay,
Speaker 0: yay.".