Speaker 0: It's Tuesday, May 21st, 2019.
Speaker 0: I'm rim.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott and this is geek nights tonight.
Speaker 0: 2p 2c.
Speaker 0: We're talking about two-player games.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: So I got to play like risk of rain some other games so we can do some new game reviews.
Speaker 1: But I've been mostly a lot of video games and up until like a week or two ago and remember in planning He just was playing one game.
Speaker 0: Well, I keep playing two-player board games Overwatch and some autochess.
Speaker 0: I'm basically just playing those games Over.
Speaker 0: I kind of got back into overwatch in a big way.
Speaker 0: I stopped a while ago.
Speaker 0: Remember I said fuck it.
Speaker 0: I'm not gonna worry about my rank.
Speaker 0: I'm just gonna always play competitive no matter what.
Speaker 0: I'm just gonna play competitive solo queue.
Speaker 0: Let's see what happens.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't care about my rank in autochess.
Speaker 0: I just play and now that I've been doing that Kind of in that mode.
Speaker 0: I was in at RIT when we just played tribes 2 and literally nothing.
Speaker 1: There's no rank in tribes 2.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but was there?
Speaker 0: No, we just joined a server.
Speaker 1: I forget it.
Speaker 1: There might have been some kind of ranking.
Speaker 0: There was the clan ranking system.
Speaker 1: It was something but we didn't.
Speaker 0: we formed that clan and then you and I were the only ones who kept playing the game Seriously, so we didn't actually bother using any of it.
Speaker 0: Anyway, god that game.
Speaker 0: we used to use it as almost a social network anyway.
Speaker 0: So yeah, I've played a lot of overwatch and I'm consistently surprised actually how Like non-toxic and chill almost everyone I play with in the range.
Speaker 1: Everyone else has already been kicked out or banned or went through a different game.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they're pretty aggressively banning the shitty people.
Speaker 0: I also found that all the really salty shitty people are in the low silvers and if you don't get whenever you're not down there anymore Everyone's just way nicer Like everyone's just more chill.
Speaker 0: It's kind of like when you go hiking like if you're an angry person.
Speaker 0: You know, this is a correlation between like, you know being angry because I'm bad at over chat overwatch Right, I'm bad at overwatch because I'm angry.
Speaker 1: if you have like this, you know angry piece of shit I'll give you look.
Speaker 1: say like professional sports that you know where the people are more visible, right?
Speaker 1: It's like the number of people who are like at the top of their game.
Speaker 1: Who are angry mean?
Speaker 1: bastard Like disgusting people.
Speaker 1: it's like there are there's more than zero But it's like they're infamous and they know.
Speaker 1: everyone knows who they are.
Speaker 1: It's like a handful at any given time and they're everyone else in the whole rest of whatever League is like great person Yep.
Speaker 0: And then the bastard people tend to be like the shitty enforcer Like the fourth line grinder who sucks and is about to retire and hates his life.
Speaker 1: I mean, you know, it's like people who are bad or like famous for being bad and everyone else is not bad.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So, uh, also we're playing some auto chess But I have not played with that new update that lets you actually Just lets you click on a dude then click on the board and not have to do any weird bullshit.
Speaker 0: Thanks Satan I do not need the skin of a MOBA around this game.
Speaker 0: I want the game to just be auto chess.
Speaker 1: They're trying hard with the quality of life improvements.
Speaker 1: Actually, I learned you know, cuz I play about like what one or two auto chess a day or whatever, right?
Speaker 1: No, I learned a bunch of info like game, you know Cuz I hate.
Speaker 1: it's something I still hate even about auto chess and every other game ever is Knowledge games meaning you're better at the game because you know stuff, right?
Speaker 1: I feel like if you read the rules and the rules should be public and in English for anyone to read for any game No matter how.
Speaker 1: come you know, even civilization is civil opedia, right?
Speaker 1: But even civilization even though you can just read the rules there.
Speaker 1: They are there's too much.
Speaker 0: No, there isn't.
Speaker 0: they're all really simple I don't know.
Speaker 1: Why can you tell me what every single building does?
Speaker 0: exact numbers show me the exact that you so one.
Speaker 0: I'm curious.
Speaker 0: What are you gonna do with that information?
Speaker 0: I'm just saying but I can tell you most of them all the ones that matter.
Speaker 1: I know exactly what I just say and that's like, you know in in overall Tells you an auto chat.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you got hurt, but it's like what if I don't have the guy on my screen right now and I'm like Oh, what is the what is enigma's power do?
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's the problem.
Speaker 0: The problem is that auto chess as a real-time game means that you have to have this knowledge in your head.
Speaker 1: Definitely a word.
Speaker 1: knowledge is definitely a worse problem in real-time games than it is in non real-time game.
Speaker 0: Unless the games are primarily dexterity skill based or things like like overwatch You got to know what every character does.
Speaker 1: Street Fighter is dexterity based, but you have to know how to know all the moves.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I hate.
Speaker 0: I know the hitbox.
Speaker 1: I don't like.
Speaker 1: and the price timing.
Speaker 1: I don't like testing knowledge.
Speaker 1: Right, cuz it's like.
Speaker 1: oh I actually would be better than this at you if I just like read a book, right?
Speaker 0: Okay, I do like games that do just test knowledge about a thing.
Speaker 0: Like I like quiz bowl.
Speaker 1: That's a trivia game.
Speaker 1: That's yeah That's different.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'm saying I like that kind of thing.
Speaker 1: But imagine like a game where it's like, okay, this game is testing to see who's faster.
Speaker 1: But if you don't know these ten arbitrary things, even if you're faster, you'll lose.
Speaker 0: Yep But every mile you've got to do a differential equation.
Speaker 1: So I learned some stuff that people who are you know, maybe dota or autochist players probably you're like, that's so obvious Scott.
Speaker 1: Why didn't you know?
Speaker 0: it's because because I don't read the documentation.
Speaker 0: I don't have time for that because autochist knowledge is a subset of like dota knowledge.
Speaker 1: It is so I've been able to learn over time just by playing a lot like the different item combinations.
Speaker 1: But Something I learned is that a there's this item called like the mask of madness And I knew that the mask of madness.
Speaker 1: to make it.
Speaker 1: you combine a mask and a quarter staff.
Speaker 1: Don't ask me how that works.
Speaker 1: And I knew what the mascot he hits yourself Like your attack speed and it's like really good item, but it silences you.
Speaker 1: so I didn't know.
Speaker 1: It doesn't actually even say this even if you even if you hover over it just says silences whoever the hero who's wearing it.
Speaker 1: What does silence mean?
Speaker 1: it means that you don't use your your power.
Speaker 1: It doesn't mean that your race or class ability synergies are canceled.
Speaker 1: They're not right.
Speaker 1: It doesn't mean that any of your passive abilities are canceled.
Speaker 1: It only means that your active ability is canceled.
Speaker 1: So if you put this on say kooka who shoots his big pirate ship, that's a bad idea.
Speaker 0: I don't know that character's name.
Speaker 1: It's the pirate ship guy.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I died.
Speaker 0: I know pirate ship guy, but that was Kooka.
Speaker 1: Okay, you nk It says right and the only reason I know the names because it shows them right there in the in the game.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and I thought that knowledge I do not have.
Speaker 1: it's the biggest word on the screen.
Speaker 1: the characters names in auto chess.
Speaker 0: I do not have proper noun permanence.
Speaker 1: anyway Pirate ship guy will only do will not do his pirate ship if you put that on him.
Speaker 0: So then why would you put it on?
Speaker 1: if you don't that's a bad idea.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: Also Say for example Luna the the the night elf who rides the the lion.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah Remember that name for some reason.
Speaker 1: Yeah, her ability is passive.
Speaker 1: She throws the blades that bounce between guys.
Speaker 0: So you want to put it on her?
Speaker 1: Canceled.
Speaker 1: so it just makes her way awesome to put it on her.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but remembering that I still can't figure out which items Stack and which don't if I put two masks on the same, dude Do I get double or not?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I have to figure this out.
Speaker 1: But another thing I learned is that you know Guys do damage or take damage they get mana and when their mana bar fills up to a hundred that is when they will use Their ability.
Speaker 1: Yep, right and then they'll have no mana and then they'll build it up and use their ability again if they survive.
Speaker 0: That's why I use the things that make the mana build up faster on Specific dudes that have only want to use it and do to have a power.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if you were to say give a mana item to Luna It would do basically nothing because her mana doesn't even matter.
Speaker 1: Why does she even have mana?
Speaker 1: who the fuck made this game?
Speaker 1: Because remember this game is a mod of Dota, right, but it's like they shouldn't even let you put that item on there Because it does nothing.
Speaker 0: For think about where this came from.
Speaker 1: I'm just saying I know this kind of knowledge stuff is you know bullshit.
Speaker 0: Here's the thing.
Speaker 0: It's not just not it's it's not.
Speaker 1: items don't stack.
Speaker 1: It should be like hey that person already has that item.
Speaker 1: putting it on them won't do anything.
Speaker 0: There is a also a difference between knowledge that is like intrinsic to the game itself Versus like knowledge of a cannon like some of these weird boards like Pax Pamir That game.
Speaker 0: if you know about that that area's history you will be better at the game.
Speaker 0: Hmm, but at the same time that game is arguably just like an exploration of that history.
Speaker 0: And but in a game like root if you read the rules of root, you know all the stuff you need to know to play Rude, but
Speaker 1: you know the cards a little bit
Speaker 0: Yeah, but but there's not that many and the cards are only in the context of the game.
Speaker 0: It's not like oh if you played boots back in the 90s, you'd know that this card is extra powerful, right?
Speaker 0: It's not like that.
Speaker 0: The problem here is that if you know how these heroes work because you play a shitload of dota a lot of things are more Intuitive to you, but they're also not explicitly stated.
Speaker 0: There's no there's no civil opedia in auto chess.
Speaker 0: that just explains all this.
Speaker 0: if I really want to know Yeah, I got a YouTube guy.
Speaker 1: I did so.
Speaker 1: I did check out some YouTube guys and learn some stuff.
Speaker 0: I feel like I gotta check out YouTube guy.
Speaker 1: I also learn.
Speaker 1: I got to figure out which items stack and which don't.
Speaker 1: That's what I need to learn next.
Speaker 0: so in some news.
Speaker 0: You might have seen this but Unity posted a tweet unity the unity that makes the game a game engine good game engine.
Speaker 1: There's a lot of other unities out there.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there are a lot of unities out there, but the unity 3d game engine tweeted on May 17th So not that long ago.
Speaker 0: Oh Find the date here.
Speaker 0: they tweeted this.
Speaker 0: this doesn't say.
Speaker 0: anyway They said and I quote we've recently delivered our first release of the year unity 2019.1 Which includes about 300 features, that's a lot of fucking features.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean they're probably counting really minor stuff.
Speaker 0: I mean when I release like an updated SDK like in the course of a quarter.
Speaker 0: We will be like.
Speaker 0: there are three features.
Speaker 0: We are adding yeah Many of which are especially helpful for developers.
Speaker 0: if they'd stop right there this would have been fine.
Speaker 1: in the game Every feature of a game engine necessarily be helpful for developers.
Speaker 0: There's no one other users that's the only user they have could be helpful to the monetization of the game engine itself.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we added a paywall sure.
Speaker 0: so basically unity announced The not thinking that this might be taken perhaps a different way from how they expected That they just released a shit ton of features that are helpful for game developers in the gambling industry.
Speaker 1: I mean yeah, you go to any casino for years now like yeah If I was making a game going back like 10 20 years like I don't know I don't know when it started, but pretty much almost all modern slot machines are basically just fancy video game consoles.
Speaker 1: They're not that are really weak.
Speaker 1: They're like you know and are more secure than say an arcade machine, but the the slot machine is just a video game.
Speaker 1: That's like no shittier than the one on your phone.
Speaker 1: Yep You can actually go on your phone to any app store Google or iOS and there are plenty of apps that are literally just Slot machine, but no real money But just like the real slot machine.
Speaker 1: so I played one once to see.
Speaker 0: half the people who saw this tweet thought What loot boxes that shitty and that is not what they were talking about?
Speaker 0: But that is why the game industry is already having a problem with this.
Speaker 0: it was particularly poor timing for unity.
Speaker 0: But no this appears to be just features for the casino who wants to make a gambling video game.
Speaker 1: Yeah, unity is probably.
Speaker 1: you want to make a slot machine software.
Speaker 1: Unity is probably a good choice.
Speaker 1: You can make it look real fancy.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's good slot machines.
Speaker 1: the programming of them is real simple.
Speaker 1: It's randomize a number and then you that takes a fraction of a second right and then it's it's win or lose According to some odds, and then you're just like all right.
Speaker 1: well They they lost.
Speaker 1: what are we gonna show on the screen just to?
Speaker 1: that will equal that particular loss.
Speaker 1: Do we give them knobs?
Speaker 1: we fiddle and twiddle right?
Speaker 1: It's like.
Speaker 1: it's like let's.
Speaker 1: it's all about just showing a fancy animation.
Speaker 1: It's like you randomize you get a result, and then you need to show an a corresponding animation to that result.
Speaker 1: that will You know.
Speaker 1: it's all the art part.
Speaker 0: It's not if I made it as a toy It's just throwing pennies and quarters into a toilet.
Speaker 0: well simultaneously.
Speaker 0: There's like four fidget spinners attached to the toilet mmm.
Speaker 1: So I should make the instant slot machine.
Speaker 1: you put your money in It spins away it does max bet and spins away all your money according to the real odds as fast as possible.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: so in a fraction of a second you put in like a thousand dollars, and it just goes.
Speaker 1: Here you go.
Speaker 1: your result is you lost everything?
Speaker 1: yeah, I spun and spun and spun until you either had zero or a jackpot Or a positive.
Speaker 1: if it's positive as soon as you go above your starting point We'll pause and let ask you if you want to continue, and if you hit zero will stop, huh?
Speaker 0: I feel like so effectively.
Speaker 1: you just do infinity spins with every press either stopping when you've made money or lost everything.
Speaker 0: I feel like there is an untapped and probably Immoral way to go with slot machines because slot machines are having a problem in that the only people use slot machines.
Speaker 1: It'll show you a print of all your individual spins.
Speaker 1: yeah along the way, that's it.
Speaker 0: That's the history that you need like that artifact?
Speaker 1: It doesn't but it is instantly like.
Speaker 0: but the only people use slot machines now are basically sad old people waiting for grim death to Finally take them so that the younger demographic is not going to Vegas to gamble.
Speaker 0: I feel like you could get a new Generation of people to sit in front of a slot machine and wait for grim death to give them sweet release.
Speaker 0: By making a progress quest style thing and like the UI make it not look like a shot slot machine.
Speaker 0: Make it look like an adventuring party fighting.
Speaker 0: It's just progress quest.
Speaker 1: I mean, but there's plenty of idle games.
Speaker 1: They're all over at steam.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I wouldn't.
Speaker 0: quite a few.
Speaker 0: I would make physical high production value idle games.
Speaker 0: I'm actually slot machines.
Speaker 1: see you have a candy box.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and you only get more candy by putting money in.
Speaker 0: yeah It's a slot machine.
Speaker 0: it acts like it is the same payout odds over time as a slot machine.
Speaker 0: But the money you're putting in is basically just making the heroes be better.
Speaker 0: Uh-huh I feel like that is a did.
Speaker 1: Whether you win or lose the game is is there?
Speaker 1: your heroes are winning.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the heroes are always winning, but but you're losing money the whole time, but you could win them you might win Eventually you're gonna lose obviously.
Speaker 1: Anyway, I don't know exactly how that's gonna work.
Speaker 0: I got an idea in my head actually so fun fact I actually met a dude who is like a game designer for casinos.
Speaker 0: like dude is sounds like a scummy Dude head of a team that just designed slot machines straight up And he talked a lot about that Monopoly slot machine that we saw that one time meanwhile the fire emblem and also Animal Crossing mobile game.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah They just got shut the fuck down down in Belgium because they're fucking gambling good and China's Seems like they're actually shutting down all the gambling games, too.
Speaker 0: So I don't want to go to do much deeper into the actual news, but unity Realized there was a problem.
Speaker 0: They deleted the tweet, and then they're really trying to back away from this and Based on your feedback where you moved a tweet and a blog post related to some upcoming 2019 features that are useful to craters They changed their framing to say real money game.
Speaker 1: So you basically just now you first you were like you admitted that you were going to.
Speaker 1: You wanted people who make slot machines to use unity and now you've admitted that the people who make you know iPhone games are basically making slot machines now in one hand.
Speaker 1: It's good because we all knew but now you've admitted even worse.
Speaker 0: but it's good in one sense because it means that they recognize that uh Loot boxes are a bad look so they they're like.
Speaker 0: no no no we're just doing the unethical casinos We're not doing the unethical loot boxes.
Speaker 0: Don't worry about that.
Speaker 0: So we'll see how this all goes in the end because I Don't think unity is going to stop making features for casinos.
Speaker 1: Why would they yeah?
Speaker 0: I feel like that is going to be their bread and butter in the long run because the game industry is having a lot of problems monetizing and I feel like the casino industry is Really gonna push into this space as hard as possible.
Speaker 0: so we'll see where this all goes in the end.
Speaker 0: and In other news what do you got?
Speaker 1: so Uniqlo the the store the clothing store, right?
Speaker 0: I was just there.
Speaker 0: They got a good on Nintendo series.
Speaker 0: They got a really good.
Speaker 1: They upgrade other one.
Speaker 1: That's just a junior.
Speaker 1: I saw someone wearing it.
Speaker 0: I got that shirt.
Speaker 0: It's real good.
Speaker 1: You bought it.
Speaker 1: Okay, I was gonna tell you I saw someone wearing it and then of course you already bought.
Speaker 0: I also got a really good Bowser shirt.
Speaker 1: There's a boo shirt, but the lady who's your socks the ladies?
Speaker 1: boo shirt.
Speaker 0: Oh, there's a. there's a man's version now if I saw it.
Speaker 1: It's just which one is it?
Speaker 0: It's the one where it's like it's a pocket shirt.
Speaker 1: No, not that one.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the problem with the pocket shirt is that it looks good and the boo is good except they offset the boo.
Speaker 0: So he's like cut off on one side and then there's another like Opposite cut off boo on the other side.
Speaker 1: ladies shirt is a black shirt with white polka dots and some of the white dots are boos.
Speaker 0: Oh, I like that.
Speaker 0: Yes, you could pull that off.
Speaker 1: Maybe it's a lady sure.
Speaker 0: So I wear a lot of lady shirts anyway.
Speaker 0: A lot of my a lot of my t-shirts are actually fitted like women shirts anyway.
Speaker 1: So they had a contest.
Speaker 1: look up the shirt - you know for the Mario shirts, right?
Speaker 1: And now they had a contest for Pokemon shirts.
Speaker 1: people submitted their Pokemon shirt design.
Speaker 0: Oh, it's a different kind of lady's shirt.
Speaker 0: It's not a fitted lady's shirt.
Speaker 0: It's a. yeah, I can't pull this off.
Speaker 1: That's not the one.
Speaker 0: Okay, cuz this also looks good, but that's not the one.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so the People submitted their Pokemon t-shirt designs, right?
Speaker 1: And they chose some winners and the winner was sort of like this ancient style Gyrodos the three magic harps under it.
Speaker 1: kind of deal looks good.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's.
Speaker 1: it's not a bad design.
Speaker 1: It's not my favorite one, but it's a good one.
Speaker 1: You know, there was some other honorable mentions down under.
Speaker 1: I like better.
Speaker 1: There was like the one I like the most is a great wave with a bunch of magic carbs in it.
Speaker 1: Ooh, yeah, and there's also a Gengar one.
Speaker 1: That wasn't bad.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so it turns out.
Speaker 1: the person who made this shirt was it.
Speaker 1: they accused this person Li Wenpei of stealing the design.
Speaker 1: because they start people searched online and saw this design being used on lots of other things and They're like, hey this person just saw this design online and submitted it.
Speaker 1: That's a bunch of bullshit right now.
Speaker 1: Normally that that would seem like a thing that normally happens.
Speaker 1: Yep, right?
Speaker 1: but actually Li Wenpei had an excuse so original that I believe it All right tracks.
Speaker 1: Li Wenpei's excuse was Yes, I put the design and made a few cell phone covers Before submitting it.
Speaker 1: He's like I made the design.
Speaker 1: I made some cell phone, you know cases with the design on it Before submitting it to the contest.
Speaker 1: I only made a few Right, and then some other people saw my design Ripped it off and made a bunch of other garbage.
Speaker 1: Right now they saw my cell phone cases.
Speaker 1: It's my design.
Speaker 1: Right, I believe that that's a like.
Speaker 1: you wouldn't say that if you were actually stole the design, right?
Speaker 1: That sounds legit.
Speaker 0: or That is a brilliant excuse in a copyright lax environment where it's very difficult to prove who actually originally designed it regardless Li Wenpei still up Schitt's Creek because Meanwhile him first place in the contest.
Speaker 1: Yeah The terms of the contest are you have not published this design anywhere ever before.
Speaker 1: Why?
Speaker 1: While making an excuse perhaps a true one.
Speaker 1: I believe it.
Speaker 1: Anyway - of saying no, I did not break rule 1 Breaking rule 2 so I think that's pretty hilarious.
Speaker 1: That's also part of why I believe it.
Speaker 0: Yeah Looks like he took that message down Yes, and and at the time of this article like a $10,000 payout for winning this thing, right?
Speaker 1: So we're gonna see what happens.
Speaker 0: Neither Uniqlo nor the Pokemon company will comment.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we'll see what.
Speaker 1: if this shirt ends up in the store or not It's gonna be interesting.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: Apparently the last news we have is that I think he said he's talking to Uniqlo.
Speaker 0: That's good.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that goes.
Speaker 1: I hope you can prove.
Speaker 0: you made the design so in some other news, there's some others review out.
Speaker 0: So I'm gonna link to this here.
Speaker 0: But as you know, I got an oculus rift and it's it's great But it's still like niche technology like it's still a heavy thing on the front of your face, which is fine.
Speaker 1: It's not it's not fun.
Speaker 0: I don't know why you're so down on it.
Speaker 1: I'm down on giant heavy thing on my face like the night.
Speaker 0: The only annoying thing about the oculus rift is that you do neck pain three now.
Speaker 0: You've never even worn it.
Speaker 0: you have no idea what it feels like.
Speaker 0: it doesn't in any way bother.
Speaker 1: How much does it weigh?
Speaker 0: I don't even know.
Speaker 1: you don't even notice it on a scale once you wear it.
Speaker 1: You don't even know more than my sunglasses.
Speaker 0: I mean, yes, that's too much.
Speaker 0: Okay Anyway, so the only annoying thing about the oculus is that it requires basically three sensors around the room.
Speaker 0: So I got a. you got to plug it into the computer to write that yeah But that doesn't get in the way either.
Speaker 1: Well, you got cables.
Speaker 1: You're stuck to a computer.
Speaker 1: You can't run around You can't do nothing.
Speaker 0: Yeah, cuz that's what we need.
Speaker 0: that VR room scale or seated scale is already enough for a lot of really interesting experiences.
Speaker 0: Yeah The cable from the headset is actually not a problem like it never gets in the way Partly because most games are designed.
Speaker 1: Not convincing me a head cables not gonna get in the way.
Speaker 0: I don't know how your mouse cable gets in the way.
Speaker 0: I would never use a wireless mouse.
Speaker 0: Hey cables I do not use wireless things.
Speaker 1: generally even the longest cable in the world is no good.
Speaker 0: Also, you can buy a thing that'll make the oculus wireless.
Speaker 0: It's just expensive.
Speaker 1: It sounds like a bad idea.
Speaker 0: totally works It's just.
Speaker 0: it's basically wireless HDMI.
Speaker 1: effectively Introduce lag them.
Speaker 0: No, we're not noticeable leg.
Speaker 0: The only problem with it is it's very expensive.
Speaker 0: Okay, and it needs a lot of power.
Speaker 0: Is he gonna wear like a battery backpack?
Speaker 1: sounds dangerous.
Speaker 0: Probably not dangerous just expensive.
Speaker 0: I don't think I will buy it.
Speaker 1: But anyway, I Gotta like yeah, like what the fuck is this a wiimote?
Speaker 0: I gotta put him in particular places.
Speaker 0: once they're set up It's fine.
Speaker 0: and because I mounted on the walls not really a problem.
Speaker 0: but it means Say I want to use the oculus in another room or I want to rearrange this room or do anything I gotta fudge with all that again.
Speaker 1: is it interesting how the we needed that little sensor bar with like lights?
Speaker 0: Well, it wasn't a sensor bar was just lights, but the switch does not need those.
Speaker 0: Well, the switch also depends on what you're doing.
Speaker 0: The switch does primarily accelerometer tracking which is extremely inaccurate for most use cases.
Speaker 1: saying you could play Wii bowling with a Switch, you know, whatever they call them.
Speaker 0: Yeah you could and it would be just fine partly because the Actual controls of that game are not that sensitive and kind of just make it work.
Speaker 1: But if you want to play it on the Wii, you got to have the lights.
Speaker 1: Yeah in the stick.
Speaker 0: so the RIT the oculus quest and the oculus rift s have now are now out and they are Basically version 2. so the existing oculus is gone and you can no longer buy it.
Speaker 0: and if you buy a regular oculus Yeah, it's the same size.
Speaker 0: All they've changed is that instead of Outside in tracking where the sensors are watching where you are and providing data.
Speaker 1: They put cameras in it It has inside out tracking.
Speaker 0: Not really.
Speaker 0: so inside out tracking means that you don't need any external sensors.
Speaker 0: the Headset itself will just use the environments to do the tracking and the hand Controllers are configured slightly differently.
Speaker 0: So the headset tracks the hands using that same technology.
Speaker 1: I'm not looking at my hands.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna look up.
Speaker 1: my hands are down.
Speaker 0: It still works for a lot of reasons that I don't want to get into because I'm so.
Speaker 0: you don't seem to care and if I talk about any details, you'll probably just fall asleep, but it's highly effective and It looks pretty good.
Speaker 0: The only difference between the oculus s and the oculus quest is that the s is just like the current oculus you plug it Into a computer and then it can play any VR game.
Speaker 0: Okay with a slightly higher resolution But otherwise, it's pretty much the same experience.
Speaker 0: Just you don't need these sensors and the inside out tracking just makes everything a lot easier to set up.
Speaker 1: So basically there's no reason to buy the old one.
Speaker 1: If you're gonna buy one you should buy this new one.
Speaker 1: Just better because you don't need shit around your room.
Speaker 0: But it's not that much better if you already have a good.
Speaker 1: not having shit around your room is I think significantly better.
Speaker 0: So well still not good enough, but significantly better But because I already it is but because I already have it set up I would I if I upgrade all it would mean is I reclaim three USB three ports on my computer.
Speaker 1: I guess that's true.
Speaker 1: If you've already got the old one, it's not better enough.
Speaker 1: It's sort of like iPhone 7s 7. you're good.
Speaker 0: It's a slightly lower refresh rate, but not enough to matter.
Speaker 0: but the resolution is higher but not that much higher.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so we'll see I might get it.
Speaker 1: What about the other one the oculus quest?
Speaker 0: actually you might be more interested in because the oculus quest?
Speaker 0: Just works without a computer at all.
Speaker 1: So it's a.
Speaker 0: it's just a headset.
Speaker 0: so they hand the controller.
Speaker 1: So they just put a phone inside the headset.
Speaker 0: They basically put everything you need in the headset.
Speaker 1: So it's a. it's a phone.
Speaker 0: It's not just a phone though because there is a third oculus that's been out for a while the oculus go.
Speaker 0: That's basically just a phone.
Speaker 0: it can only play a curated limited set of games It's not so it's more powerful than a phone.
Speaker 0: oculus cool.
Speaker 1: So it's a laptop and a monitor strapped to your face.
Speaker 0: oculus quest can play a shit ton of first-class games Like all the games.
Speaker 1: so it's a laptop strapped to your face.
Speaker 1: Yeah, how heavy is it with the chips in there?
Speaker 0: not that heavy like it's comfortable.
Speaker 1: it's got like a battery in there.
Speaker 1: There's all kinds of shit going on.
Speaker 0: That's comfortable.
Speaker 0: It just works and It is probably going to push.
Speaker 0: I think the oculus quest based on all these reviews now that people are actually I mean at least you're not so it but it's not.
Speaker 1: You're not connected to anything.
Speaker 1: So that's huge.
Speaker 1: Well, it means it doesn't need shit around the room either.
Speaker 0: Uh, no because it's inside out track.
Speaker 1: So now they've only got one thing left to do which is make it not heaviest.
Speaker 0: But it can't play like weird indie games or games that need like a lot of horsepower.
Speaker 1: Well, that makes sense.
Speaker 0: You want to strap a 1080 your face, but it'll not lay Almost every game that matters right now and it's easy enough to use and a high quality of experience.
Speaker 0: This is the first VR headset that is likely to make the jump from a niche market to an extended market meaning Not everyone is gonna buy one of these but everyone who has some money and wants VR.
Speaker 0: This is accessible to a huge group of people.
Speaker 1: I think that Still may because it's still not there, but it's got the not there you're talking about.
Speaker 0: It's probably 20 years away.
Speaker 1: Oh, then I don't give a shit.
Speaker 1: But the point is that is actually huge.
Speaker 1: for the thing that I see VR being used for the most which is kiosks demos All that kind of stuff is gonna be way better served With the oculus quest.
Speaker 1: that has the computer in it and no wires or nothing.
Speaker 1: Then the old school where you got a computer and a cable and shit in the room.
Speaker 0: But that's not what they're going for.
Speaker 1: I imagine if you're setting up a kiosk for your like demo whatever and which one are you gonna go with right?
Speaker 0: Well, there are other VR headsets.
Speaker 0: There's that valve one that I'm not gonna touch with a 10-foot pole and I'm mad by it and try it out.
Speaker 1: I think clearly that right now there is only what if you're gonna do a VR There is clearly a winner and some non winners, right?
Speaker 1: It's sort of a situation like back in the day where there was a Game Boy And then there was a Game Gear and a turbo graphics thing.
Speaker 1: and so the girl and it's like you look at those other ones And they're like, we're better.
Speaker 1: We got color.
Speaker 1: We're better.
Speaker 1: It's like clearly the Game Boy one is very well You know, I would argue the oculus is the Game Boy.
Speaker 0: I would argue the Game Gear Was superior except Sega did not foster a wide enough third-party network of games early enough for it.
Speaker 1: PSP was superior to uh-huh.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 0: The PSP's got some some points in his in his court.
Speaker 0: Uh-huh, the real tragedy in that era was the Sega Nomad was woefully under a Sega Nomad.
Speaker 1: It was not a. people don't know about this.
Speaker 1: Maybe the Sega Nomad was not a different console like the Game Boy.
Speaker 1: All right It was just a second.
Speaker 1: just a Sega Genesis that you could carry around with.
Speaker 1: it was kind of amazing.
Speaker 1: Like mostly you'd want to plug it into something into full-size Sega Genesis cartridge and shoved it in the top And it was just a screen and some batteries and a Genesis.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know who's?
Speaker 0: for you're at your grandma's house.
Speaker 0: You've got your Sega with you.
Speaker 1: It was literally just a portable television and a Sega Genesis in a plastic case where the cartridge slot on top Yep, and that was it and some battery holes.
Speaker 0: so if you were on them if you want like the nerd VR experience where you're gonna plug it into a computer and do The kind of stuff that I'm doing Get the oculus s. Yeah, it's gonna make it like four times easier.
Speaker 0: You know how you set up the room.
Speaker 0: like now bit literally I got to stand in the middle of the room Take one of the handsets and like outline do a dance space.
Speaker 0: No You outline the safe space and that way if your head or your hands get close the walls like up here in VR.
Speaker 0: So, you know where the walls are.
Speaker 0: you don't smack into them without riff with the rift s. You put it on and then it shows you the world Walking around through the cameras and you draw the safe space by just walking around your house.
Speaker 0: Okay, and it just saves it.
Speaker 0: it's really cool Cables though.
Speaker 0: No, it doesn't need a computer.
Speaker 0: Well, yeah, you have a cable.
Speaker 0: you walk around your room if it's a rift s. if the oculus go you just walk around Whatever space you're using.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so I'm probably gonna get this Just because I'd like to be able to set up the living room or this room depending on what I'm doing And that'd be really easy to do.
Speaker 0: Well, whereas now I'd have to move all three of these sensors So if any of our friends want a discounted Just as good but you have to do more.
Speaker 0: setup oculus rift.
Speaker 0: I've already had two of you ask I'll probably sell it to you at a discount because I'm just gonna upgrade.
Speaker 0: but anyway things of the day what he got, okay, so We live in the year 2019.
Speaker 0: I like I had to think about that for a second.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if we go to Rome in Italy There's some ancient biz there right?
Speaker 0: Yep, not as ancient as say Istanbul but still some ancient biz.
Speaker 1: there's like a calcium there.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right, you know, there's some good shit right old shit, but a lot of the most of the old shit ain't there anymore.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's been smashed replaced by modern buildings decayed Whatever.
Speaker 1: So you wonder right?
Speaker 1: It's like, you know, you're standing in Rome anywhere in Rome You stand even let's say you're at a restaurant your pizza restaurant in Rome.
Speaker 1: I'm sure there's one there, right?
Speaker 1: Right eating some pizza in Rome in a sort of modern kitchen is there, you know, whatever where you are sitting Thousands of years ago in the times of the Caesars in that exact spot.
Speaker 1: There was something else there.
Speaker 1: There was like I don't know a bathhouse or a forum or a fucking you know peasants house.
Speaker 1: I don't fucking know some soldier house.
Speaker 1: It's a palace Something aqueduct right.
Speaker 1: there was something there no matter where you are in Rome There was some ancient Rome thing in that spot Right the same way that in the spot where you're standing right now.
Speaker 1: There was some Native American shit in this spot.
Speaker 1: Yep, right.
Speaker 1: So if you go to Rome, which you know is newer than you know that, you know Times of cavemen.
Speaker 1: It was actually civilization and interesting stuff right now.
Speaker 1: Just like a tree Wouldn't it be cool to know exactly what was where right, you know, what was the layout of the old Rome?
Speaker 1: What buildings were there?
Speaker 1: Where were they?
Speaker 1: Right?
Speaker 1: What if you could walk around the old Rome?
Speaker 1: just you know Even though you're living in 2019?
Speaker 1: Well, it's a good thing that you live in 2019 because some Roman scholars at what's what school is this?
Speaker 1: it is Just scroll the top.
Speaker 0: Dr.
Speaker 0: Bernard Fisher, dr.
Speaker 1: Steven Zucker doesn't see what school they're from.
Speaker 0: No, it doesn't.
Speaker 1: it's on like a Smithsonian website, right?
Speaker 0: It's on smart history.org.
Speaker 1: Okay, whatever the point is these professors from school that we forget the the name of Forget.
Speaker 0: we didn't know it.
Speaker 1: they created a complete Computer, it's not like the highest quality like video game graphics, right?
Speaker 1: It looks more like AutoCAD from the 90s.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right.
Speaker 0: It looks like a missed knockoff game.
Speaker 1: Yes, but it's Completely accurate.
Speaker 1: as for to the extent of human knowledge CG 3d replica of Ancient Rome you can fly around look around walk around.
Speaker 0: I really want to walk around this in VR.
Speaker 1: You can see exactly where stuff was Right.
Speaker 1: What was where?
Speaker 1: What things looked like?
Speaker 1: they got some fake people walking around.
Speaker 1: you can see the sizes of things which is really important.
Speaker 1: Right how big was shit, right?
Speaker 1: And you this video that is on the page that I'm linking to is extra great because not only Do you get to they fly around Rome?
Speaker 1: But they tell you about all this stuff as if you were in a helicopter getting a free tour of Rome from some extra Knowledgeable people saying like oh, yeah That is the thing that was made for Emperor so-and-so to celebrate the victory in such and such a place You know.
Speaker 1: and that was an arch made for this a reason and that was a public bathhouse.
Speaker 1: And that was a public bathhouse.
Speaker 1: and this area is where Nero built a bunch of shit and the later Emperor's Un-neuroed it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they're like, yeah see that statue that used to be a Nero statue.
Speaker 1: Then they chopped its head off and put a godhead on it instead.
Speaker 1: because fuck Nero So there's a lot of good you're like.
Speaker 1: this is the circus Maximus.
Speaker 1: You can see this is where the the Caesars Palace connects directly to the circus the box Right, so you can walk from the inside of his palace to his box to see the chariot race.
Speaker 0: If you go to the Istanbul, you can actually walk through some of those things because a lot more of that is still there.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and they're like, oh, yeah See, this is where the circus Maximus.
Speaker 1: this is a picture of where the circus Maximus was today And it's like a field with some obvious sort of run down.
Speaker 0: and circus Maximus is like plus five Global happiness and said five.
Speaker 1: Oh, look at your memory knowledge base games bringing it back.
Speaker 0: So My video.
Speaker 0: this was making the rounds.
Speaker 0: It's not a GDQ, but it's an adjacent event.
Speaker 0: and yet the video explains it all in detail.
Speaker 0: This is a test bot run.
Speaker 0: So it's a tool assisted Final Fantasy one speed run For white mages for white mages.
Speaker 1: How do you do any damage?
Speaker 1: Ah Like you get amazing.
Speaker 1: you could hold out a really long time by constantly healing yourself But you'd be doing such low DPS.
Speaker 1: So every combat would take forever once they got hard.
Speaker 0: So one.
Speaker 0: this belies your knowledge of Final Fantasy because Final Fantasy one white mages can do some fucking hella Damage, well, it's the guys that are weak to healing you can bad guys.
Speaker 1: You can heal the dam.
Speaker 0: Scott Thor's hammer mage staff.
Speaker 1: Any of these ring a bell?
Speaker 0: No, really Zeus gauntlet.
Speaker 1: Look at rim with the knowledge base games again.
Speaker 0: You realize in Final Fantasy one the white mages wielded hammers.
Speaker 0: Yeah hammers do fucking damage, okay also a lot of the hammers.
Speaker 1: Why are the three white dead white mages though?
Speaker 0: Because he only does that he kills three of them right away and does the whole run.
Speaker 0: was just one white mage.
Speaker 1: What the?
Speaker 0: because it's faster that way because frame timing.
Speaker 0: This is a tool assisted run.
Speaker 0: Okay, wait, but here's why this is my thing of the day.
Speaker 0: It's not just an emulator tool assisted run or anything like that.
Speaker 0: This is a tool assisted run being played back by Taz bot on an actual physical fucking cartridge such as my works Yes, and has to stay in sync or else it gets said.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: Once they get it started They're like nobody walked near this one static shock and that cable will ruin the entire run.
Speaker 0: That's right, but to the commentary is a Plus.
Speaker 0: the commentary talks about tool assisted runs about Final Fantasy about how they pulled this off.
Speaker 0: How they beat chaos at the end is amazing.
Speaker 0: I knew the chaos trick, but this one actually they use the trick.
Speaker 0: which trick do you which trick you thinking of?
Speaker 1: I'm not thinking of a trick.
Speaker 1: I'm just saying they use the trick.
Speaker 0: There's multiple ways to kill chaos kind of instantly that are really funny.
Speaker 0: They do.
Speaker 0: one of the myriad ways to ruin chaos actually do legit just fight.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's not as fight.
Speaker 0: They get chaos to run away from the fight.
Speaker 0: So they win.
Speaker 0: Okay, you can get chaos to run away by using a certain spell.
Speaker 1: Okay, it's pretty good I should do that.
Speaker 1: No I can play.
Speaker 0: and then Anyway, if the bad part is this kind of made me want to play Final Fantasy 1 again have a lot of nostalgia for this Game.
Speaker 0: I go for it.
Speaker 1: I might Play the Final Fantasy 3 real Final Fantasy 3.
Speaker 0: I've played it a bad one.
Speaker 0: I played it.
Speaker 0: I didn't beat it, but I got pretty far.
Speaker 0: I also played fun Jobs and stuff.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I played Final Fantasy 2 most of the way.
Speaker 1: I'll play that piece of garbage game.
Speaker 0: I've played those games.
Speaker 0: That's what actually my favorite or I like.
Speaker 0: RPG speed runs in general.
Speaker 0: My favorite one ever is still Final Fantasy legend 2 At a GDQ.
Speaker 0: That's a real fun one in the moment.
Speaker 0: The book club book is the painful pages of pain by Troy Denning.
Speaker 1: I'm almost 80% done, but I haven't read in like a week because I'm not.
Speaker 1: I'm not riding trains anymore.
Speaker 0: I'm in about the same spot because I stopped reading at the same point Scott did when it got sunny out.
Speaker 0: At least now I'm not saying good or bad But I think you have hit the point in the book where it goes off the rails.
Speaker 1: It's been off the rails pretty much the whole time, but it goes further and further off.
Speaker 0: It's like oh the whole books gonna be in these mazes - Oh people just swapping limbs foot for a leg.
Speaker 0: Yeah, fuck it.
Speaker 0: Let's go.
Speaker 0: Let's roll.
Speaker 1: I already saw the foot for a leg.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: Oh that hand for a foot.
Speaker 0: I mean, yeah the hand for a foot Carfoot the best goddamn character.
Speaker 0: I love car foot that dude.
Speaker 0: You don't even know the full extent of his depredations.
Speaker 0: yet The book goes surreal and off the rails and that is why I remember this book being different from every other Dungeons & Dragons book.
Speaker 0: every other D&D book is just fantasy novel happens, and then it stops happening.
Speaker 0: This one is like here's some fucked up shit.
Speaker 0: That's actually kind of disturbing and we're not even at the tip of the iceberg yet, okay?
Speaker 0: Dear I wonder what you're gonna think about the ending now that we're in the trippy shit.
Speaker 1: Well I have to find out.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'm not even gonna spoil where it goes.
Speaker 0: I'm curious though.
Speaker 0: What do you think's gonna happen?
Speaker 0: Do you think anyone makes it out of the mazes?
Speaker 1: You know usually when I read or interact in any story in any medium right I can definitely think what's gonna happen.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like Wheel of Time book one You know the final confrontation is gonna be the main dude who becomes the old dragon dude But like it's the other dude for this one.
Speaker 1: I honestly have no Like like no idea at all.
Speaker 1: like of any you know I guess the most likely thing to happen.
Speaker 0: I'm really curious cuz I Having read it twice when I was young The ending all around when it ended.
Speaker 0: I thought all I could think was wow So I can only sort of like.
Speaker 1: I can't you know pinpoint exactly what's gonna happen, but I can say you know things turn out well for Lady of pain yeah, maybe demon dude things turn out poorly.
Speaker 1: Everyone else yeah, and beside that's all I can say that's all much.
Speaker 1: That's the only.
Speaker 1: that's as close as to guessing what will happen as I can get.
Speaker 1: I just imagine like the real Which characters get things turn out good and which things turn.
Speaker 0: the only thing?
Speaker 0: I regret is that this book needed an epilogue and the epilogue literally should have just been.
Speaker 1: Poseidon gets but he's angry.
Speaker 0: Two options either Poseidon is just in his temple sitting on his throne Something like ah shit didn't work no, and then he just thinks to himself wonder whatever happened to that threson guy.
Speaker 0: Or option B the lady of pain shows up in his house and fucking stabs, how can she get there?
Speaker 0: I don't read your book.
Speaker 1: I don't think she can get there.
Speaker 0: uh I would say that things cannot turn out well for the lady of pain because Well for the lady of pain still sucks for the lady of pain.
Speaker 0: I Guess this book is canon though, so I guess this is the lady of pains deal Is it?
Speaker 1: I guess isn't only the things in like like D&D book.
Speaker 1: What's a branded D&D book book?
Speaker 1: No, I mean like you know game books.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't know.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna Spate this for you a book club show.
Speaker 0: anyway two player games.
Speaker 1: All right, this was my idea.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so oh I got a thing up here.
Speaker 0: Let me pull up a two player games, so we've done talks about this before.
Speaker 0: like we bring this up whenever we talk about board games We'll start with board games like into video games, but two player games Are a very like interesting into.
Speaker 0: well, I guess two player games are like a unique difficult and interesting space.
Speaker 0: Three player games are their own like hellish can of worms and then end player games are like normal games.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's it's weird right.
Speaker 1: so for mathematically speaking right?
Speaker 1: It's like there's one player no player.
Speaker 1: three player and anything bigger than three is Effectively sort of mathematically similar.
Speaker 1: it becomes like they're like they're like three is a little bit political right.
Speaker 0: well I'd say three is Political, but three is special because three is hyper political in the sense of almost any three player game That is not a race or solitaire ends up being one player gets fucked and the other two players play the game right.
Speaker 1: it ends Up being basically a to a political game that becomes a two player game.
Speaker 1: Yep, anything instantly anything more than three is Normal political game.
Speaker 1: doesn't matter four or five six a hundred.
Speaker 1: There's article games right and then a two player game is a two player game and a one player game is a puzzle.
Speaker 0: Yep, but a two player game is interesting because let's talk about just board games You can't really make them have staying power unless you make them go or chess.
Speaker 1: yeah, so right.
Speaker 1: So there's basically the two player games available are coin toss.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we randomly decide who wins right?
Speaker 1: Rock paper scissor, it's we we decide things their decisions, but it is literally arbitrary.
Speaker 0: winner is arbitrary though it is theoretically possible as we know from that bot to Figure out someone else's poor decision-making in those completely arbitrary.
Speaker 1: But that's an edge case right anyway.
Speaker 1: And then most two player games right you know accounting for all the other factors right perfect information Or not or random or not They end up.
Speaker 1: You know since you're always acting in your best interest.
Speaker 1: You're just always making the optimal move every turn.
Speaker 1: That's all you're doing.
Speaker 1: There's no reason to do anything else.
Speaker 1: There's no third players or things to consider right?
Speaker 1: You're just trying to make your optimal move and your opponent is trying to make their optimal move.
Speaker 1: It doesn't matter it ends up being tic-tac-toe Right.
Speaker 1: the only difference is that you make it more complex than tic-tac-toe And it's no longer obvious what the turn should be.
Speaker 1: so it ends up being who is better at solving this puzzle against this other Person.
Speaker 0: yep, but that's where it gets weird because two-player games like you know Emily I live together and our friends Chris and Anthony like we have a lot of friends who there are two people who want to play games in the Western society tend to live in twos.
Speaker 0: yep, so if you get a two-player game and You play it like you would often because there's two of you You're gonna do the thing to that game as fast as possible.
Speaker 0: that Scott and I and the front row crew do to every game.
Speaker 0: You play it enough times to where you completely solve it and ruin it and have no reason never play it again.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like I've played.
Speaker 1: you know what two-player patchwork like a whole bunch of times It's like well now I pretty much you know whether I win or lose just comes down to the order of the tiles and who goes first.
Speaker 0: yep So like a town is a good example.
Speaker 0: It's a game that we reviewed a while ago.
Speaker 0: Good game.
Speaker 0: It's a real good game two-player game.
Speaker 0: But German board game feel like it's a pretty complex two-player game and Completely fair and completely symmetric.
Speaker 0: and yet even in this situation Scott and I played it against each other like five times five or six times and By the sixth time we were literally making the exact same decisions based on our hands.
Speaker 0: No matter what the game was always a perfect tie.
Speaker 0: everything came down to tiebreakers.
Speaker 0: tiebreakers upon tiebreakers.
Speaker 0: Like the game just lost all meaning and replayability.
Speaker 0: within six plays You can.
Speaker 0: it's very difficult to make a two-player game that doesn't have that happen unless it is just chess or go right.
Speaker 1: well So right.
Speaker 1: so I mean when rim says just chess or go he just means it's so complex that you can't possibly right make out some more moves because they just so.
Speaker 0: the Decision space is just enormous and it's right and then way if you make a game like that.
Speaker 0: There's only two ways to go with that big decision space either.
Speaker 0: The game is over complicated.
Speaker 1: the Duke is big big decision.
Speaker 0: Yes, right, but it could be over complicated in a non fun way like Twilight Struggle where the complication just slows down actual play.
Speaker 0: complicated in a fun way like the Duke yep, or You can just make it entirely abstract like go and then the heuristics become Abstract heuristics that you have to develop independently, right?
Speaker 1: This is other ways to make interesting two-player games, right.
Speaker 1: so you can include some sort of dexterity element Yeah, or some sort of a sport element.
Speaker 0: That's why two-player video games are really easy to make right?
Speaker 1: Well, I mean, you know any fighting game, but also like sports, right?
Speaker 1: It's like I you know, you could do just a race you can do boxing.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: One-on-one basketball is super fun, right?
Speaker 1: It's all.
Speaker 1: once you incorporate some sort of other measurable Analog ability suddenly a two-player competition that isn't just numbers is now more meaningful and interesting.
Speaker 1: Also, you can make a game even if it is a boring game, you know.
Speaker 1: Like tic-tac-toe you could just do two teams because two team game is effectively the same as a two-player game.
Speaker 0: Yeah, because there's no politics and the main reason people seek these two-player games with teams is to avoid politics.
Speaker 0: So the it's a pure test of skill as opposed to well Everybody banged up on rim.
Speaker 1: in round one you get the benefit of eliminating politics, but you get the also the benefit of Cooperating with another person and having the game, you know be more meaningful.
Speaker 1: So the the best example of that is bridge.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right.
Speaker 1: So bridge is a two team game, right?
Speaker 1: You can't communicate with the other person, but you still have the fun of playing with someone.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right Euchre does the same thing, right, but you're still.
Speaker 1: you know, see yeah, you get the idea.
Speaker 0: So it's interesting.
Speaker 0: the like a lot like a ton is the kind of German board game that if a game like that like you play one a similar game that has more than two players the game ends up having a lot more replayability and a lot more difficulty in reaching that solution largely because of the politics and the unpredictability of the other players.
Speaker 0: like Four people will take longer to converge on set strategies in a game than two players Because the like there's more total possibility of what other people might do Even if you ignore the cut the possibility that those people will do stupid things like when our group of friends plays Tigger's New Freighties.
Speaker 0: Even though we should have solved this game the game ends up still being a very fulfilling experience.
Speaker 0: But if Tigger's New Freighties were somehow a two-player game I know the rules.
Speaker 0: like one of the printings actually says you can play a two-player.
Speaker 0: It is deeply unsatisfying and no fun things happen at any point.
Speaker 1: There's lots and lots of games that are n-plus player games and the instructions either say yeah You can play two-player probably just to increase sales to people who only have one friend or they have special rules Like if you're playing two-player do this.
Speaker 0: Like Hansa Toytotica has a two-player variant.
Speaker 0: It's garbage, but it adds this extra crap and you can just.
Speaker 1: those are a great illustration though of how Significantly different a two-player game is from any other number of game and just how different again It's like a completely different.
Speaker 1: you take the same game in the same box almost the same rules You just go down to two players and suddenly it's nothing like what it is when there's three or four plus players.
Speaker 0: Yep So the game that seems the two-player game.
Speaker 0: that is not a video game not a sport as no dexterity component That seems to like seems like it's gonna have the most staying power.
Speaker 0: Might actually be Fox in the Forest.
Speaker 1: Hmm.
Speaker 0: It's okay cuz family I've been playing it.
Speaker 0: So I've been thinking about it a lot and The nature of the way its rules are written or why it's the case because it ends up focusing on Card counting and bluffing with just enough randomness.
Speaker 0: We've reviewed the game not gonna get to the mechanics But the fact that you're not just trying to get the most tricks.
Speaker 1: You're trying to get the right number of tricks because if you get right, there's an odd number of tricks So you can't tie.
Speaker 1: it's impossible even though it's two players.
Speaker 1: That's the first.
Speaker 1: that's the first genius mechanic.
Speaker 1: Right is like, alright, you're gonna play a game.
Speaker 1: They're what?
Speaker 1: 13 points, I guess Yeah, so if you have two players and all the points will be scored then Someone's gonna have more than the other person and you're trying to get more.
Speaker 0: But if you take too many you get no points and the other person gets a ton of points.
Speaker 0: Yep so Emily when we were playing actually the other day Emily completely wrecked me on that because I had a pretty good hand and I Thought I can probably take enough.
Speaker 0: So I took a bunch of tricks really early to like set myself and then I thought I could just like throw the rest away And be fine.
Speaker 0: It was a trap.
Speaker 0: I ended up taking every trick And that give-and-take like that Mechanic alone makes Fox in the forest like really powerful and has a lot of staying power Because you can bluff in a two-player game without politics.
Speaker 0: and then the fact that the cards give you abilities to rotate Trump and to like influence the play space and So the game.
Speaker 0: you even looking at your hand, like I go I play wizard and I got a hand I can have a pretty good heuristic as to what tricks I could take or not take and Managing the politics of the table.
Speaker 0: in a two-player game where Trump can change based on actions It's a lot harder to have that set strategy.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm I'm trying to get other games that seem like they are like avoiding the this two-player game problem.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean, you know longer patchwork is maybe one of the best two-player games.
Speaker 1: There is yep, but you know its main Replayability is due to the randomness of the order.
Speaker 1: the tiles come out, right?
Speaker 1: So it You know that I don't know.
Speaker 1: Well the other two-player games that I think have survived definitely I think what it is is that with the with patchwork if you're pro You're gonna sort of play it out faster.
Speaker 1: I think for a lot of people they would just never play patchwork out and just love it forever Even if they played it a ton.
Speaker 0: Yeah Well, like spring meadow and games that are races games that are more like I am trying to do my solitaire Oh, you're doing the solitaire.
Speaker 0: two player is not different than three player or four player.
Speaker 0: So I guess those all sort of get a pass.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like a Yahtzee you can play Yahtzee two-player like.
Speaker 1: what's the point?
Speaker 0: Yeah, because they're all effectively one player like you don't interact with each other in any meaningful way, right?
Speaker 1: But actually if you played say that's pretty clever Ganshin clever.
Speaker 1: it matters a lot to player that you know actually is pretty interesting because Now, you know, it's not actually a polyp There's no politics in it because you can't really you know vote for the other players in any meaningful way.
Speaker 1: But your actions do affect the other players.
Speaker 1: But when there's a lot of players, it's hard to pay attention all of them.
Speaker 1: But with only one person to pay attention to you can focus and back.
Speaker 1: I what did they need and deny them.
Speaker 1: so it takes less brainpower to get to the advanced level, right?
Speaker 1: It's not like.
Speaker 1: it's actually a different game.
Speaker 1: It's just you can access the higher game If your brain is weaker or put in less effort,
Speaker 0: yeah One thing I've noticed too with two-player games is that if you have a two-player game and play it a bunch it's very hard to play it with
Speaker 1: anyone
Speaker 0: other than the person you've been playing it with or Someone else who has also played it a lot Like if I bust out a town against like the world born.
Speaker 0: I played it a bunch of times they haven't and because it's two-player and there's no politics and there's very little randomness I will just win no matter what.
Speaker 0: At least the first time I play with anyone.
Speaker 0: so unless you pull your punches Once you start playing a two-player game, you're kind of locked in to the people who have played at the same number of times.
Speaker 1: I know this same thing Whenever I play someone in hive for the first time.
Speaker 0: Oh my god, you pull out.
Speaker 0: you pull out the spider or the beetle.
Speaker 1: I just say look.
Speaker 1: I've played this game you haven't.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna do the beetle.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna do the beetle attack.
Speaker 1: yep, and I'm gonna and you're gonna lose probably if you don't.
Speaker 1: that's awesome.
Speaker 1: and Then after you lose you're gonna play again and I'm gonna keep doing the beetle attack every single game.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna do the same beetle attack until you don't lose to it.
Speaker 1: Once you once you manage to not lose to the beetle attack Then we you figure that out.
Speaker 0: then I'm gonna do the tricky spider.
Speaker 1: No, then we're ready to play real hive.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right When you don't just get dominated by the beetle, I'm just.
Speaker 0: I'm really thinking about this now.
Speaker 0: I feel like there's the core of a panel here like a one on Specific like all these specific reasons why two-player and three-player are So different from all other numbers of players like in detail with a lot of examples.
Speaker 1: Well, the other the other Savior of the two-player game is of course, you know, the customizable game like imagine Netrunner or a miniatures game right where you choose your stuff, right?
Speaker 0: And that brings in that aspect of like two-player battle tech super fun brings the max and just fight it out, right?
Speaker 1: All those games you have this customized asymmetric asymmetric start it.
Speaker 1: that is what makes a lot of two-player games work.
Speaker 1: Well, because no matter how much you've mastered the game every single game you're venturing into the unknown, right?
Speaker 1: So like I said patchwork Randomizes the shared play space right like the board and I think you know more.
Speaker 1: a lot of games do do that.
Speaker 1: But I think more games need to do it more Randomizing the shared space.
Speaker 1: but when you can bring whatever you want the other person can bring whatever they want.
Speaker 1: All right, it's like rock-paper-scissors.
Speaker 1: Sometimes it is does just come down to rock-paper-scissors like oh my deck just beats your deck.
Speaker 0: Why don't you get that?
Speaker 0: but we talked about that.
Speaker 0: other show the expression like you get to express yourself, right?
Speaker 0: But they have an experience.
Speaker 1: but you if it's it's rock-paper-scissors, but then if it's not just an imbalanced Oh my I have a deck that counters yours I win if it actually is like.
Speaker 1: oh we have like a 50/50 chance of winning here with these.
Speaker 1: You know this combination, right?
Speaker 1: Then you have the added thing of the playing right and it's like a new thing like super new thing every single time.
Speaker 1: Plus if it's a card game, you've got the added randomness of shuffling your deck and you don't have to worry about Managers.
Speaker 1: game does not as the only randomness of the dice
Speaker 0: like you play magic or anything else where you're like any one of these like broader games with end players outside as opposed to like a Two-player customizable or semi customizable game locally You only have to worry about the local meta like the meta between you and your friends as Opposed to a broader meta with more friends or broader meta with a tournament scene.
Speaker 1: Well, the internet really, you know changed that a whole lot, right?
Speaker 1: I mean on my early magic days I had like a book that held all these decks in it.
Speaker 0: I think I had that same book.
Speaker 1: It's like an orange book.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and I wanted to afford to make most of those decks.
Speaker 1: It's like I didn't see any of those cards ever.
Speaker 1: I'm like, well, I guess I can't do any of this.
Speaker 0: One of the decks was like yo, dude You get some of this like serpent generator.
Speaker 0: make some poison and fucking poison the shit out of the other person.
Speaker 0: I was like serpent generator.
Speaker 0: What set is that?
Speaker 1: even from the point is?
Speaker 1: Yeah, and the point and that book was out of date by the time I got it.
Speaker 1: cuz new cards have been printed.
Speaker 1: But I think it's called like mastering magic cards or something.
Speaker 0: Oh serpent generator came back in fifth edition.
Speaker 1: Okay, fine.
Speaker 1: anyway, the point is that You know you when in the old days you had the limited money Limited resources right that local meta was sort of forced except for very connected people who could get around right?
Speaker 1: Nowadays with the internet, even if you have a local meta any person just knows Right what the best shit is and can buy the best shit on the internet.
Speaker 1: Yeah, everything's available the knowledge is available and the stuff is available to everyone.
Speaker 0: But then if you make a two-player game that's locally customizable like actually seven wonders duel Two-player drafts.
Speaker 0: that gets real fun.
Speaker 0: Mmm that gets real.
Speaker 0: actually seven wonders duel is a like phenomenal standout game.
Speaker 0: Have you played it?
Speaker 0: No, I bought it recently because I realized I didn't own it.
Speaker 0: we should.
Speaker 0: we'll play it not now but we should play it Uh-huh.
Speaker 1: So not ever.
Speaker 0: Bring it to the next packs, you know what.
Speaker 0: I'll bring it.
Speaker 0: I'll bring it on the 4th of July.
Speaker 0: Alright, I'm hungry.
Speaker 0: I think we can just stop here.
Speaker 0: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Speaker 1: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 0: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows It's actually recorded at night.
Speaker 0: and the patreon patrons for this episode of beat nights.
Speaker 0: Ah Correct Oliver Allen Joyce Heidi McNichol just like a dude guy kashar topish and linky g Jennifer Hitchcock Chris midgift my stady Com Jay band scooter lonely Roberto Kingsley Shawn Yeager Nicholas Brando.
Speaker 0: Mr Strong distraction for two one creations.
Speaker 0: and there may be other secret names You do not even know Shervin von Horo Rory Rochelle, Montanona Superboy sailor Vista Clinton Walton run from New Zealand Ryan parent rope and Lander Finn dread Lily Tenebrae Sean Klein Chris Reimer Thomas Han.
Speaker 0: and now I leave you with something that may be long forgotten.
Speaker 1: He's got money but not much good.
Speaker 0: he's got money but not much good.
Speaker 0: he's got money But not much got to do.
Speaker 1: the dollar.
Speaker 0: one two one two, take where my lasers at y'all.
Speaker 1: Where my lasers at.
Speaker 1: where my lasers at?
Speaker 1: where my lasers at y'all?
Speaker 0: Where my lead tell me where my lasers add and your mother tried to show me all the laser crabs and I got a bunch You.