Speaker 1: It's Wednesday April 29th 2020.
Speaker 1: I'm rim I'm Scott and this is geek nights.
Speaker 1: tonight We are reviewing be stars the anime season 1 from Netflix.
Speaker 1: Let's do this so one of the glories of Being stuck at home.
Speaker 1: Well, we don't actually have much more free time because like we're all still at least working like our lot Like we still have to do a lot of the things we had to do before.
Speaker 1: it's just that we can't really leave the house.
Speaker 1: So I'm playing a lot of play by mail or asynchronous games where I can take turns Whenever I happen to be free over the course of the day.
Speaker 1: That seems to be how I'm gonna spend a lot of my time during all this.
Speaker 1: So we're playing.
Speaker 1: now, you know, we've talked about a gig nights about those train games like 18 something like one eight something something The something anyone on Wednesday care about this.
Speaker 1: We're playing these games online, but we found a basically among that.
Speaker 0: It's about you know, some of the nerdiest board game you can possibly find.
Speaker 1: Yeah They're like.
Speaker 1: these are the kinds of games where you'll see like the people who look weirder than everyone else at your local like events Sitting in the corner by themselves playing what looks like the same game for more than four hours.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know you go to that corner of the game store where all the games look like only old dudes would play them.
Speaker 0: Yeah, yep.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but the picture of a train on the cover the art looks way bad.
Speaker 0: The graphic design is way bad.
Speaker 1: Yep, so we're playing one of those games online in addition now to like all the Civ games and everything else.
Speaker 1: So my advice to you out there is if you are looking for games to play Now is the time to try out play by mail or at least asynchronous games like their time has come.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: Not like we have any other opening bits.
Speaker 1: It's not like like oh what I was biking to work today and somehow like I didn't go anywhere No in my house.
Speaker 0: I'm not even sure I can't even shower.
Speaker 1: I did shy still shower every day.
Speaker 1: No, I don't but I don't wash my hair.
Speaker 0: I didn't even change.
Speaker 0: I don't even change my climb.
Speaker 0: I've been wearing these clothes probably for three days.
Speaker 1: Oh, well, see I think because I have to video chat so much for work at least from like waist up I'm always wearing like a nice collared shirt.
Speaker 0: pretty sure This shirt was worn during the last geekness.
Speaker 1: Oh, and I I could go to.
Speaker 1: I could go verify that I suppose.
Speaker 0: I suppose you could.
Speaker 1: So there is some news going on.
Speaker 1: I guess you can go first.
Speaker 1: It's a Japan related at least if not specifically anime related, right?
Speaker 0: So if you're a you know a weeb you probably buy stuff that you have shipped from Japan, right?
Speaker 0: It's a thing that happens Yep, especially if you use various websites that send Japanese stuff, right?
Speaker 0: So if you do this, you're probably aware the Japan post the Japan Japanese post office has Two major, you know Shipping methods that are used for people in the US buying nerdy goods, right and those are EMS and SAL right, so SAL is basically economy air service and EMS is like Express Mail service, right?
Speaker 0: So both of these are basically suspended for the time being since like the beginning of the month.
Speaker 1: so If you want any nerdy goods from Japan Or if you tried to mail anything to Japan like it's just not gonna happen.
Speaker 0: Well, you don't you wouldn't use these to mail to Japan.
Speaker 0: This is front.
Speaker 0: This is things from Japan.
Speaker 0: now.
Speaker 0: Okay, I see right you something you're sending something with the Japanese post office.
Speaker 0: the US post office hasn't?
Speaker 1: because I saw I saw other Articles I didn't read about a bunch of countries refusing any inbound mail as well.
Speaker 0: Yeah I don't know if what the USPS has suspended right like is they suspended priority mail like I don't know, right?
Speaker 0: But it's like they've suspended their priority mail equivalent.
Speaker 0: So you can't mail things to the you to certain countries at least right?
Speaker 0: So you can't if you're in Japan, you can't EMS or SAL something to the US and some other places that They're not sending to right now.
Speaker 0: So, you know obviously in the short term it makes it a little harder to get nerdy goods Right, and it means that various nerdy companies that sell Japanese goods to weebs around the world Have to like hold on to goods longer take pre-orders that they're gonna deliver on later You know have less sales period charge more for shipping find some other way to ship, right?
Speaker 0: You know, maybe some other carrier like FedEx will send it or who for a fortune or whatever they charge.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well the interesting is at the same time There's a lot of American vendors who have inventories of stuff already that go do that Run the convention circuit trying to sell that stuff because if you buy this stuff online It tends to be cheaper like it almost never is cheaper to buy stuff in person from vendors at like anime conventions
Speaker 0: The only the conventions unless
Speaker 1: you're buying weird old stuff,
Speaker 0: right?
Speaker 0: It would be that they bring a bunch of.
Speaker 0: they bring their clearance bin with them.
Speaker 0: That's not on their website.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but dig into that.
Speaker 1: if we if weaves are desperate in the US and there's no conventions where they would normally go and buy Like this the impulse buys that they just pick up from those bargain bins and at the conventions and nothing can get mailed.
Speaker 1: I feel like the domestic vendors might be able to finally clear out a lot of their inventory Depending on what that inventory is.
Speaker 0: if you got a bunch of old like Ron mo on half plush exactly domestic the domestic nerdy good vendors That normally would be at conventions now have all this stuff that they already have and I'll go to their websites.
Speaker 0: They're probably happy to sell it to you and they probably need to sell it because they want to stay in business Without all these cons happening.
Speaker 0: So seek them out and buy their stuff probably for cheap.
Speaker 0: But yeah, I think it's gonna be interesting because it's not like anime production has been impacted.
Speaker 0: Yes, it actually has.
Speaker 1: that was gonna be my news.
Speaker 1: I won't go into all of them.
Speaker 1: But there is a long list of anime series where episodes are delayed or things are slowing down because of coronavirus.
Speaker 0: Okay, well shows production slowing down.
Speaker 0: that's good and bad to hear yeah, but regardless the point is You know new new merch comes out.
Speaker 0: the merch won't come here.
Speaker 0: They'll be like this backlog and I wonder if certain series for example the one we're talking about tonight be stars.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if there's some Japanese be stars merch, but because of the timing of this will some series just naturally have less merch that gets exported?
Speaker 0: because You know by the time they're exporting again, they'll be new series and they'll export that merch.
Speaker 0: and so for you know Say a be stars which came out right now.
Speaker 1: that Is definitely like bootleg fan-made nonsense in the u.s.
Speaker 0: I don't think there's that many merch for that series in particular but I'm just saying that like the timing of when different shows come out in relation to the difficulty of exporting goods could cause the Quantity of goods for different series right and you know based on the timing of their popularity.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, that's something more or less.
Speaker 1: We haven't.
Speaker 1: we don't talk about anime cons on the show much anymore We don't really go to any but when we used to and we talked about this a lot more.
Speaker 1: one thing You should know about the industry Is that the demand from American fans for merch from particular shows is such a flash in the pan?
Speaker 0: Like it depends on the show, right?
Speaker 1: Like whatever the nice hotness is people really want it like attack on Titan.
Speaker 1: people would like Murder each other to get some merch from that show and then it just like suddenly evaporated.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean that's how it was.
Speaker 0: We went to anime Boston every year and every year There would be a different hot show and you go into the artist alley and whatever show had the most Artwork fan art that was selling hot.
Speaker 0: It's like you knew that was the hot show and it would be a different show every single year.
Speaker 0: Some shows be perennial to some extent right?
Speaker 0: It's like I can't remember the last artist alley at any kind of convention I've been to that didn't have a Doctor Who fan art Final Fantasy fan art or right or something like that.
Speaker 0: But other things sort of you know wax and wane and spike, you know, especially Something like a high Q for example, right?
Speaker 0: It's like this, you know.
Speaker 0: It's like it was a time and a year where like that was the biggest deal and every everyone was selling high Q stuff.
Speaker 0: It's like his high Q died.
Speaker 0: No, it's still got fans.
Speaker 0: It's still a thing.
Speaker 0: but if you go to an artist alley now It's like the fan art you're gonna see is like maybe one or two here and there from the people and they made that stuff When it was a flash in the pan, they're just still selling off those prints or whatever it is.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so in some other news or related to all of the crisis and everything in Japan I'm not gonna link to all the articles about specific delays and anime because you can just go look that up.
Speaker 1: But Buried in that on anime news network was a really short article that is a little more worrying around this.
Speaker 1: It basically is a statement from the Olympic Committee president That white.
Speaker 1: yes, you know the Japan Olympics were delayed from 2020 to 2021 But they've now quietly issued like that.
Speaker 1: quietly, but they issued the state Kira Kira averted by one.
Speaker 1: But they issued the statement basically saying that if the dates they've selected for 2021 Are not able to be used the toward the Japan Japan Olympics will just be canceled, right?
Speaker 1: There will be no further reschedulings right?
Speaker 0: If you can't do it next year, you can't do it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so Teaches you to not mess with the Olympics In some other news.
Speaker 1: We've taught.
Speaker 1: we've talked about this a lot a long time ago on the show as well.
Speaker 1: Diamond distributors is a problem for a lot of reasons But they're kind of the sole or primary distributor for almost every comic book store in America.
Speaker 0: Right if you own a nerdy store in America You know all of your goods that you're selling in your nerdy store.
Speaker 0: You're probably just buying them from diamond distributors.
Speaker 0: They have a big catalog right you you can get the catalog if you want.
Speaker 0: It's cheap, right?
Speaker 0: It's a big enormous thing like computer shopper used to be.
Speaker 0: yeah, and you order comic books mostly from it.
Speaker 0: But you also can order swag and even games and all kinds of stuff from that catalog statues Magazines all kinds of shit.
Speaker 0: you fill up your comic book store, and then you sell that stuff off.
Speaker 0: And we talked I guess if a week or two ago about how You know they're stopping some operation.
Speaker 1: right yeah Because they were affected by all the quarantine rules and because they're kind of a monopoly That really screwed over a lot of stores.
Speaker 1: granted a lot of those stores can't operate anyway.
Speaker 0: now right but also You know there's the company DCB service where I've been ordering comic books from since And they have a lot that.
Speaker 0: what that company does is they have a large warehouse in Indiana Where they basically because the way diamond works is you know the more you order the more of a discount you get right up to?
Speaker 0: a certain tier right.
Speaker 0: so Basically if you're just a little little comic book store with a you know in a small town you only order so much product from the catalog that you then sell to your customers, so You don't get a big discount.
Speaker 0: so your margins are small.
Speaker 0: right.
Speaker 0: if you open up say a giant warehouse in Indiana And you let people online you let them buy stuff right from you Which you're buying from diamond?
Speaker 0: But then also you make them pre-order two months in advance because the catalog comes out two months in advance of the stuff shipping.
Speaker 0: So now not only are you getting wider margins because you're getting the biggest discount tier from diamonds right?
Speaker 0: They're giving you the same copy of Batman for less money than they sell it to a different store for right because you bought a Thousand copies yeah But also you're increasing your margins because you're not buying a copy of Batman and having it sit on a shelf right you're buying Exactly the right numbers of copies of Batman because everything's a pre-order whereas in a comic book store They let you do pre-orders, and they really want you to because then again they more accurately predict how many to buy.
Speaker 1: That's why so many comic shops have that thing of tell us what you want And we'll have a little older where we give it to you every month.
Speaker 0: exactly please get a pull list.
Speaker 0: We really want you to write pre-order so we can make more money.
Speaker 0: right and you will get you the exact comics you want.
Speaker 0: But some people those are a lot of.
Speaker 0: there's a lot of drama around those.
Speaker 0: at comic stores people get pull lists and then Not come in and pick them up Just disappear they're not.
Speaker 0: the other thing is that people with a pull list at a comic book store even if you're a good customer And you come and pick it up on time right and you're constantly paying them you're paying after the books arrive Right.
Speaker 0: with DCB service you're paying when you order right so they have the money to buy the books before They order them from diamond.
Speaker 0: yep now diamond is the exclusive distributor for DC Marvel Dark Horse and image And basically almost all US comic books and a whole bunch of other stuff.
Speaker 1: yeah, yep So the news is they have officially announced a date where they will restart operations.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but how they're not gonna fully restart operations like it was nothing happened.
Speaker 1: They claim they're gonna start shipping to shops again on May 20th.
Speaker 0: Okay, but also is interesting service that I just talked about started some of their own Minor distribution operations off to the side.
Speaker 0: I think to help DC get comics out when diamond wasn't doing it.
Speaker 0: yeah So there's something going on there, but it doesn't know.
Speaker 0: they said it doesn't affect DCB service customers.
Speaker 0: It's just sort of a side thing that they happen to be doing because they have the capability and capacity to do so.
Speaker 1: Yeah now most comic publishers stop releasing books anyway.
Speaker 0: Yeah, almost every title is like delayed for a while.
Speaker 0: right it's like well if I can't sell it I'm not gonna keep drawing them.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so we don't know where this is all gonna Go, we don't know how well like diamonds starting back up will go if it'll even matter because the entire supply chain is disrupted like Them.
Speaker 1: coming back online in May might not actually have any impact on the actual industry.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'm curious if how many comic book stores are still open right that want their orders.
Speaker 0: They just went out of business.
Speaker 0: how many?
Speaker 0: Comic book you know have been created.
Speaker 0: That's like okay, so we're ready to distribute comic books again.
Speaker 0: All right well We haven't made any.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so you'll have to wait for us to make some more.
Speaker 1: and with all the delays will there be more smaller publishers Who don't fall into the evil alliance with diamond and use these other channels that have this brief window to come on to the scene While everything's disrupted?
Speaker 0: yeah pretty much.
Speaker 0: the only other channels are digital and in the u.s.. At least our digital Bookstore channels.
Speaker 0: and the bookstore channel is different because people don't.
Speaker 0: it is inside stuff right.
Speaker 0: it's not that inside.
Speaker 0: But if you make a book and sell it to like through a distributor to Barnes & Noble That's returnable.
Speaker 0: so Barnes & Noble gets it on their shelf And they never sell your stupid comic book.
Speaker 1: not all books like.
Speaker 1: there's weird different relationships like go read about what happened with TSR and bookstores back in the day.
Speaker 0: like they that shit sits on the shelf And then it goes in the clearance bin and no one buys it.
Speaker 0: they can return it right and get their money back.
Speaker 1: now return Usually means just prove to us that you destroyed it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like they don't actually send the book back a lot.
Speaker 0: They'll tear the cover off and throw it away.
Speaker 1: That's why you go to like dodgy anime cons and dodgy comic cons.
Speaker 1: They'll often be that one vendor in the back like that's just like a card table and under the card table They've got boxes and boxes of books without covers.
Speaker 1: They're illegally selling those.
Speaker 0: yep.
Speaker 0: Regardless, that's right.
Speaker 0: That's why books are a different deal than comic books.
Speaker 0: comic books is a direct market from diamond.
Speaker 0: It's not returnable.
Speaker 0: Yeah, which is a change it used to be until diamond came along.
Speaker 0: You can read all about that history in great detail online.
Speaker 0: But yeah that whole thing has been messed up by coronavirus in a significant way which shows you the weakness of monopolies.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so it's really that gets really.
Speaker 0: the story here is right.
Speaker 0: look What happens when you only have one company and something happens to it?
Speaker 1: Yeah, we need a diversity of supply chains.
Speaker 1: vertical and horizontal monopolies are a bad deal Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: so I got a really really brief geek bite cuz.
Speaker 1: as you know we've watched the first season of DuckTales the new one.
Speaker 1: It was really good.
Speaker 1: I'm actually watching the second season now like there's more seasons.
Speaker 0: Are there uh three?
Speaker 0: how many episodes per season?
Speaker 1: There's 52 episodes total.
Speaker 0: That's a lot.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 1: That just keeps going.
Speaker 1: Now season three is that I don't know.
Speaker 0: see watching it.
Speaker 0: That's good.
Speaker 1: season three is not out yet, but season two is the same length of season one, and I'm watching it now.
Speaker 1: It's like 90% as good as season one.
Speaker 1: It's a little less punchy though like.
Speaker 1: it's still good, but it's less Comedically dense than season one was.
Speaker 1: it's like the difference between Simpsons season five and Simpsons season seven I'd say sure so good like.
Speaker 1: I'm still enjoying it But it's a little less punchy and some of the beats are a little more predictable, but otherwise it's still just great.
Speaker 1: I just watched the episode where the three capieros show up, and that really hit me right in the nostalgia Mmm.
Speaker 0: So in other news right we always talk about One second.
Speaker 0: we always talk about how You got to go to the movie theater whenever there's an anime in the movie theater.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, just 100% if it's even if it's kind of meh.
Speaker 1: I've seen some meh movies in the theater cuz why not?
Speaker 0: Right exactly because it.
Speaker 0: you know it's like we're lucky to live in an era where we can do that sort of thing.
Speaker 0: However The you can't go to the theater right now.
Speaker 0: so What's happening is a lot of those anime movies especially the ones that were in theaters recently?
Speaker 0: Are available for streaming.
Speaker 0: so for example promare just became available for streaming?
Speaker 1: Yep, if you did not see promare in the theater it is.
Speaker 1: it is another.
Speaker 1: it is in the genre that I like to call Anime that saved anime.
Speaker 0: Yeah, exactly.
Speaker 0: and also You know some of those Anime that This is what happens that I look stuff.
Speaker 0: That's why I can't be on the computer while I'm podcasting set a separate place eyes open.
Speaker 1: This is why Scott keeps his eyes closed when we do the show.
Speaker 0: That's a good reason.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if I start looking at something It's like it's like a.
Speaker 1: he's like a dune navigator where he can't look through his normal eyes.
Speaker 1: He has to look through his prescient eyes to be able to talk exactly exactly.
Speaker 0: Some of those anime like promare that are now available for streaming are sadly You know that the big movie theater ones are not available in these sort of free Netflix fashion.
Speaker 0: They're available in the pay a few dollars.
Speaker 0: watch it on Amazon Prime YouTube.
Speaker 0: Yeah, whatever mood Which is fine?
Speaker 1: Yeah, I've watched a lot of movies like Jojo rabbit recently like a lot of movies I want to like.
Speaker 0: look you were gonna go to the theater and pay $14 to watch it.
Speaker 0: so at home, you're not gonna pay two or four right to watch it in HD or something.
Speaker 0: It's like it's fine.
Speaker 1: Yeah Cuz you have to buying digital movies cuz they charge a lot more if you want to have that to watch anytime you want.
Speaker 0: But well, it's like it's compared to paying, you know, what $20 a month for Netflix.
Speaker 0: It's like, okay Well, that's the cost of five movies.
Speaker 0: if I could watch way more than five and I'm there suit, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I could watch a whole season of something right.
Speaker 1: but plus it's like four dollars.
Speaker 1: Like that's less than I paid even if you don't take inflation into account to break the breakfast sandwich anyway, but in So yeah, just be aware of that.
Speaker 0: right promare is currently I think in that mode where you have to pay to watch it Individually.
Speaker 1: go pay to watch if you haven't seen it.
Speaker 1: It's about climate change and it's also about ice.
Speaker 1: Right literally now literally and figuratively.
Speaker 0: Now what about the ant the animated films that were in production that we were going to go see in the theater that we're gonna come Out soon, but we couldn't Even if you're like us, even if you're like us and you were you know Go into the theater to see things, you know for their one night only screenings.
Speaker 0: What do you do now?
Speaker 0: What are those, you know films doing now that there is no screening to have?
Speaker 0: Alright, so one the most awaited one I think is not even anime.
Speaker 1: It's a wolf walkers from cartoon saloon Yeah, the third of the sort of trill.
Speaker 1: it not really trilogy, but the third of the movies they've been making in this vein.
Speaker 0: There was secret of Kells there was song at a see right, you know, and now there there was some other ones They made that were not You know, those are like the Tom Moore directed one.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the ones that are like famous, right?
Speaker 0: There's also ones they did like breadwinner and such.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but anyway wolf walkers is the new hot one that everyone's waiting so hard for From the end of the Irish animation studio and it turns out that they've been working from home Awesomely and that shits coming out on time.
Speaker 0: but what's interesting to note is that Currently it there hasn't been any official announcement about the official G kids distribution of this film.
Speaker 0: G kids distributed, you know, basically all the big anime movies, right?
Speaker 0: And also basically all the cool.
Speaker 0: if G kids distributes an animated movie in the US you want to go see it, right?
Speaker 0: All the Uassa's all the you know Miyazaki's all that stuff is through G kids that just movie distributor And as well as the cartoon saloon stuff.
Speaker 0: But wolf walkers hasn't been officially announced as being distributed through G kids.
Speaker 0: But what has been officially announced to chagrin is that it will be on the like Apple plus Paid streamy thing.
Speaker 0: Oh the one I won't use Right, which I think would require you to have some sort of Apple device To be able to watch it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's not that's not great.
Speaker 0: So unless G kids makes an announcement soon, which who knows with the lack of theaters.
Speaker 0: It's like why do you need G kids, right?
Speaker 0: And with the Apple Plus already in place Apple may it's possible But it hasn't been confirmed that Apple might have locked in that wolf walkers with a pile of money.
Speaker 0: You Know and that's that you know, it's definitely an Apple thing, right?
Speaker 0: It's such like a prestige kind of project that would be right up their alley.
Speaker 0: So, yeah, I hope you have an Apple device, yeah Because I hate to.
Speaker 1: I don't want to pirate a Tom Moore movie like.
Speaker 1: no, maybe I'll pirate it But I'll just like cut him a check for like 20 bucks something like that.
Speaker 0: Who knows what's gonna be but we'll see.
Speaker 0: it could just be.
Speaker 0: you know that they haven't said anything yet.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's not.
Speaker 0: it's not a confirmed thing.
Speaker 0: It's just because the Apple thing was confirmed and the G kids hasn't yet.
Speaker 0: Everyone's like, oh no I hope I get to watch this movie.
Speaker 0: I've been waiting it for so long.
Speaker 0: I don't want to not be able to watch it.
Speaker 0: I don't want to have this said.
Speaker 0: also I don't want to have to be tweeted about doing something with wolves like right and I'll also I don't want to have to buy an Apple device and or subscribe to this Apple TV plus garbage that I don't want for anything else just to watch one movie.
Speaker 0: Yep, maybe I can free trial and watch it and I don't know.
Speaker 0: We'll see.
Speaker 1: Yeah, one of the things if I ever have real political power would be to bust up exclusivity agreements in all industries.
Speaker 1: yep, but anyway things of the day looks like your thing of the day is from Yesterday, so I think it's only fair that my thing of the day is from 2007.
Speaker 0: Okay Sure.
Speaker 1: so Unrelatedly, I was streaming myself playing DDR mostly as a challenge to see if I could synchronize that shed.
Speaker 1: That is harder than it looks but I did it.
Speaker 1: and then of course the videos immediately got copyright flag.
Speaker 1: No trouble just you know dance dance revolution music.
Speaker 1: All of that is not licensed to me to use and There's like 20 or 30 claims on each one of these videos, which is fine.
Speaker 1: But while I was looking at the claims just to click yes fine whatever.
Speaker 1: so my video would stay up.
Speaker 1: I I noticed that the people who own the rights to all of Captain Jack's music Were claiming them because I played a bunch of Captain Jack songs Which reminded me that Captain Jack existed and I went on YouTube and sure enough I found His most important work the music video he made to dream a dream.
Speaker 1: if you have never seen The official music video to Captain Jack's dream a dream It's something.
Speaker 0: It's great.
Speaker 1: It's something alright, so this video was uploaded on April 3rd 2007 and you might say oh, but it's so low quality.
Speaker 1: Now that's the quality of the video.
Speaker 1: You're not gonna get it.
Speaker 0: That's the this.
Speaker 0: well I mean, it's not it's.
Speaker 0: it's not the best video quality.
Speaker 0: They had an o7.
Speaker 0: It's the best digital video quality.
Speaker 0: they had an o7.
Speaker 1: yeah pretty much.
Speaker 1: This was clearly someone like taped this off of TV, and then uploaded it to YouTube.
Speaker 0: Yep You're lucky to see any of it.
Speaker 1: Yep, so what do you got so?
Speaker 0: You know long ago right one of our favorite comic creators right created a series called Mouse Guard And then Mouse Guard the Black Axe and there really much hasn't been new Mouse Guard since then.
Speaker 0: really it's sort of been like it Right?
Speaker 1: yeah, there was.
Speaker 1: there's the board game.
Speaker 0: There's the role-playing game There's all that like ancillary stuff right and while David Peterson is still out there doing all sorts of other stuff especially lately I know sadly.
Speaker 0: I think he had.
Speaker 0: I think the story I heard was that he was like taking care of his his ill mother and sadly she passed.
Speaker 0: I don't know when exactly But I guess if you want to put a silver lining on something like that.
Speaker 0: He now has a lot more time.
Speaker 0: so He has been doing a lot lately especially during you know everyone being trapped inside.
Speaker 0: if you're an artist you can do a lot trapped Inside.
Speaker 0: yeah, he works right from his house anyway.
Speaker 0: So he has been really killing it.
Speaker 0: He's been doing lots of twitch streaming and YouTube video uploading.
Speaker 1: Oh shit This is 40 minutes long.
Speaker 1: This is legit.
Speaker 0: What do you think I'm doing?
Speaker 0: my things of the day aren't trash like yours.
Speaker 1: You're saying that Captain Jack is trash.
Speaker 0: I'm not saying that Jack is trash.
Speaker 0: I'm saying that's a kind of a mad thing of the day like you know a 13 year old music video.
Speaker 0: So you know he's done lots of stuff like he's doing the equivalent of sometimes.
Speaker 0: He'll do the equivalent of like panels on his twitch stream right and sometimes he'll do like the equivalent of like a. You know a vendor table at a convention like he's selling stuff on his twitch stream, right?
Speaker 0: I saw him like one time.
Speaker 0: This is a while ago.
Speaker 0: actually he was drawing Something and he's like yeah, we're gonna put this on like a tote bag and sell it at the comic-con when there were still cons Right yeah, and he was drawing the whole thing right there talking all about it.
Speaker 0: Why he's deciding it this way?
Speaker 0: He said yeah We had to do it this way not that way.
Speaker 0: cuz this look better on the bag and you know the the way the printing Works.
Speaker 0: he's going all in right.
Speaker 0: It's like a super behind the scenes.
Speaker 0: You know life of life and work of amazing Comic artist.
Speaker 0: so here on YouTube just yesterday.
Speaker 0: He uploaded as rim said a 40-minute video That is a creator commentary on mouse guard the blackaxe number one.
Speaker 0: so like you don't see this kind of thing too often you see it in movies were like.
Speaker 0: you'll get a Commentary track where you know someone's talking while the movies playing right and you watch the whole movie, right?
Speaker 0: But this is like a dude going through his entire book like 40 minutes long for a not very large book right going into great detail about like what went into every page You know writing art for like everything Like what.
Speaker 0: I've never seen this before.
Speaker 0: I'm sure it's been done before right, but what comic book have you seen this for?
Speaker 0: I?
Speaker 0: Haven't?
Speaker 1: I'm definitely going to watch this entire video.
Speaker 0: So yeah read all mouse guards and then come back and watch this and you got time to read all mouse guards.
Speaker 0: It won't take you that long.
Speaker 0: There's not that many of them?
Speaker 1: Yeah, I give it link back to.
Speaker 1: I'm pretty sure we've reviewed multiple segments of mouse guard over the years.
Speaker 1: cuz it's good.
Speaker 0: It's really good up.
Speaker 0: So there you go.
Speaker 1: We are hanging out at home trying to make stuff.
Speaker 1: I hope this live streams working out.
Speaker 0: We're still tweaking the pipeline to be able to do geek nights remotely without interruptions And I know a lot less people are probably watching listening to geek nights because podcasting is way down.
Speaker 1: Yep, because no one's listening cuz they're at work doing work.
Speaker 1: That does not require the word part of their brain to interact.
Speaker 1: or they're commuting in a car or they're committing in a subway.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm, but if you're watching the live stream or you're hanging out with us like we're gonna keep we're gonna keep cranking out more content Bit by bit.
Speaker 1: just stay tuned.
Speaker 1: I got some more RTMP stuff set up.
Speaker 1: I also got the teleprompter like fully set up and working with the new camera.
Speaker 1: So stop sparkle eight and stay tuned Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: I don't know what it looks like Angie.
Speaker 0: Let's say geek night's downloads are on the decline for sure.
Speaker 1: Yeah, okay Whatever you log it in check.
Speaker 1: Yeah, why not?
Speaker 1: Yeah makes sense.
Speaker 1: I mean I have not listened to a podcast in four weeks.
Speaker 1: Not one.
Speaker 0: Yeah, no, I have not listened to podcasts really at all either even podcast I like.
Speaker 1: I'm not listening to the matter of time.
Speaker 0: And the other thing is a lot of the podcast that I do listen to which are and Surprisingly, they're still finding a way to keep going.
Speaker 0: Like they found more things to say our sports podcasts.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah I was like they found stuff to say.
Speaker 0: they're.
Speaker 0: they're all coming up with ideas and being creative.
Speaker 1: It's like some of the players I'm playing their own like video game versions of themselves and like doing stuff to twitch.
Speaker 0: So I'm just I'm talking about like sports journalists, right?
Speaker 0: It's like they're still coming up with ways to do content on the past on the future on all kinds of you know side stories Different angles things they would never waste time on before and it could be interesting.
Speaker 0: but it's like there's no sports happening.
Speaker 0: Why am I right?
Speaker 0: It's like I have just those podcasts just piling up and I'm not listening to any of them.
Speaker 0: Yeah, even though someone's working hard and being creative to come up with them.
Speaker 0: It's like well, I'm just not Not feeling it.
Speaker 1: Yep, and that's partly why we're not gonna double down and like make more episodes of geek nice.
Speaker 1: We're gonna keep making geek nice at the same pace, but we're gonna work on other projects where if we're stuck at home Anyway, we have space to do them.
Speaker 1: I'm not gonna talk about the details of those projects yet because We are very much trying to not shit talk about things until we actually deliver at least one iteration of that thing.
Speaker 0: but I've also heard about the psychological phenomenon where for for some reason if you say you're gonna do something out loud you your Brain feels like you've done it and therefore you are less likely to actually do it.
Speaker 0: stupid rain.
Speaker 1: Why you do this to me?
Speaker 0: It's like I. it conflicts with my intellectual Principle of wanting to be open with people and talk about.
Speaker 0: you know Like what's going on and not keep secrets, right?
Speaker 0: Cuz I always come complain about companies like not saying what they're doing.
Speaker 0: It's like why not you just get people hype if you tell us what?
Speaker 1: if I right now and be like, hey I'm working hard to make an episode of geek guys presents utensil this weekend.
Speaker 1: I actually am working on that but I don't know if I'll get to it this weekend cuz other stuff might come up and I even now feel pretty good.
Speaker 1: Like yeah, I just did something on that utensil that's been on hiatus forever, but I didn't do anything.
Speaker 1: I just said words and I see people in the chat are already excited about the fact that I mentioned the antenna thing.
Speaker 1: So there we go.
Speaker 0: There you go.
Speaker 0: I That's that many people in the chat were excited.
Speaker 0: one person person.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but that is This day sealed the YouTube comments like at least twice a week Because my youtube channel gets like 20 ish thousand views a month.
Speaker 1: But at least once or twice a week some random video that is not anything to do the tenant We'll get a comment on it.
Speaker 1: That is just like hey, what are you gonna start up the antenna show again?
Speaker 1: I'm really looking forward to the next episode.
Speaker 1: Like people they're like that comment exists on almost all our videos.
Speaker 1: It's Moderately annoying but I see why and I can look at the stats and even see where they're coming from.
Speaker 0: So I mean that's what happens to literally every creator who does more than one.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah How many people do we know who made a webcomic?
Speaker 1: are now rich and famous like they've made a million other things?
Speaker 1: But to this day 20 years later randos come into their mentions asking about their first webcomic that they stopped doing a decade ago.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Imagine if you're like the undertale guy and you do something else every.
Speaker 0: all the comments are gonna be like I'm a gun under town to candidate right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know you you if you make a hit movie if what he dies I hope in the far future.
Speaker 1: There'll be a tombstone that just says the undertale people, right?
Speaker 0: If you're if you're if you're Patrick Stewart and you go you you were acting in a play some Shakespearean shit.
Speaker 0: And you do.
Speaker 0: go to the press conference.
Speaker 0: Everyone asked about Star Trek, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, right It's the same shit that every famous person who does multiple different any creative person is famous.
Speaker 1: Well, there's two guys.
Speaker 1: There's the people always aware of the thing.
Speaker 1: They know you about like people see Michael Jordan.
Speaker 1: They ask about the Bulls.
Speaker 1: They don't ask about like any other aspect of his career.
Speaker 0: Yeah, no one asked him about being the owner of you know, the Hornets or whatever.
Speaker 1: You know.
Speaker 1: who does those questions?
Speaker 1: people like you me and Daryl Surratt, right?
Speaker 1: Anyway, so yeah, we're working on stuff.
Speaker 1: I am gonna try to work on the antenna thing like stay tuned.
Speaker 0: I'm Basically the you 10 a channel, right?
Speaker 0: So if you put anything else on there people like hey, where's you 10 a head?
Speaker 1: Yep, there that the you 10 a community is going strong, but it is definitely not growing Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: So let's just get right into it.
Speaker 1: You can find all their stuff on the internet, but we're taught we watch some anime.
Speaker 1: Uh, we're be stars.
Speaker 1: Way back when the manga was first coming out in Japan and wasn't even officially released anywhere like in the u.s.
Speaker 1: There were people in our forum who were posting screenshots of it like cat screen caps of it from the digital bootleg fans Up or fan translations.
Speaker 1: They were reading because it was that good and they were like that obsessed with it.
Speaker 0: Yeah This is definitely a title manga anime wise that I heard about and saw about coming way in advance like it was like it was hot and on fire when It was a manga right people were all over it and then Netflix grabbed it, right?
Speaker 0: So they call it a Netflix original but like.
Speaker 0: is it really original?
Speaker 0: you didn't write it like, you know for the Dracula thing It's like, you know, Netflix paid for it to be created from nothing, right?
Speaker 0: I guess they didn't create Castlevania itself.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's original Castlevania story.
Speaker 0: It's not an adaptation.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean it is this superficially Castlevania 3 but Right, like this is not an adaptation.
Speaker 0: This is Literally, I mean this is an adaptation.
Speaker 1: It's literally not to say where are you going?
Speaker 0: Manga the mom.
Speaker 0: I don't.
Speaker 0: yeah, the manga is turned into an anime straight.
Speaker 0: I don't know what changes their work?
Speaker 0: as I haven't read the manga, but I can't imagine that they were major changes.
Speaker 0: It definitely feels like manga, right?
Speaker 1: But basically there was a long slow burn where like everywhere I look in our forum on Twitter There was this handful of people that was slowly growing that were obsessed with this manga that wasn't out in the US yet And there's so much media out these days that even if I see something like that I tend to just wait for an official release.
Speaker 0: Well, also I just kept seeing.
Speaker 0: really I just kept seeing the imagery, right?
Speaker 0: I kept seeing the imagery of this, you know wolf dude and this bunny girl.
Speaker 0: All right, and they all Those are the three people I see and I could tell that okay, whatever this is from is clearly Dark, right furry and sexual in some way.
Speaker 0: Whatever it is.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I would describe describe the vibe I got as Psychosexual thriller with anthropomorphic characters, right and maybe it has some sort of horror element that I didn't know, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's that's just the vibe I got from all this artwork and images I saw around You know and it was a Netflix I guess original right and that Netflix paid an
Speaker 1: OAN instead of an OAV I
Speaker 0: guess you know Netflix said, okay well we'll license that manga and we will pay for a production of an anime based on that manga.
Speaker 0: and the first season 12 episodes is out and I watched a few and then because they had nothing else to do I watched all 12.
Speaker 0: Yep,
Speaker 1: we won't spoil anything at first but we'll spoil a few things toward the end of the episode because I want to talk about a few scenes that I thought were Particularly good, but we'll avoid spoiling stuff because I want to review it because not everyone's seen it yet first,
Speaker 0: right?
Speaker 0: It wasn't.
Speaker 0: it wasn't one of those things Where it was so good, like I was gripped and had to watch every episode right.
Speaker 0: if I was me it was that.
Speaker 1: Okay, I was like I could not wait to watch the next episode.
Speaker 0: If I wasn't stuck at home, I don't know if I would have watched every episode have been a little borderline, right?
Speaker 0: But it was definitely good enough for me to not stop watching it.
Speaker 0: It's not like I went it's not like I went.
Speaker 0: Oh, I'm gonna watch something else.
Speaker 0: This is me.
Speaker 1: I guess the way I'd pitch it like.
Speaker 1: what the deal with it is that one.
Speaker 1: it's very high production value Like the animation is phenomenal.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, it's 3d, but it looks great.
Speaker 0: Right?
Speaker 0: So animation wise it's obvious They're using you know, fully CG animated characters, right?
Speaker 0: But you know, there's some anime or animations that are.
Speaker 0: you know Toy Story like.
Speaker 0: yeah, this is 3d and you know, it's 3d.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like or the new ghost.
Speaker 1: That's what we're doing.
Speaker 1: We will not be reviewing on gig nights.
Speaker 1: Probably.
Speaker 0: Yeah, probably not.
Speaker 0: But Israel.
Speaker 0: it goes in the shells relevant to this to be stars in a small way.
Speaker 0: The it's also not one of those ones.
Speaker 0: We're okay It's a 2d anime, but we're using the computer to help us out right like, you know every 2d anime these days pretty much every single 2d animate 2d anime these days is Animated on a computer digitally.
Speaker 0: It's just.
Speaker 0: they're using 2d animation techniques and not 3d ones.
Speaker 0: or maybe they are using some 3d ones Like maybe like a. so Ken has you know, you can see this some 3d going on, right?
Speaker 0: But what you get here in be stars is clearly 3d, right Like Toy Story, it's fucking 3d CG animated anime series, but I don't know, you know the shading or whatever They're doing.
Speaker 0: Okay, let the movement do it rarely it it rarely looks like it, right?
Speaker 1: Well, even though it's more than it's.
Speaker 1: the characters are like Hyper-expressive and a very subtle movements and very like everything's very subtle and well done.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean you.
Speaker 0: it's like usually when you're watching one of those 3d animated series or if you see a still image from one It's like, you know, it's right you get still a lot of stills from be stars like random ones And some of them you'd be able to tell and a lot of them you wouldn't.
Speaker 0: yeah, and usually usually the times I can tell the most are when like people are walking and their feet are in the scene and Sometimes like the way the clothing will move Right and those sorts of things will sort of give it away or distract your eye a little bit, you know I saw some like pixelation types of things going around.
Speaker 0: you're like, you know the bottom of someone's pants and those sort of.
Speaker 0: you know Action scenes.
Speaker 0: you can sort of tell a little bit.
Speaker 0: But you know for the most part it's like, you know, it's it's a it's mostly a talking heads kind of show.
Speaker 1: Yeah like what's it really about?
Speaker 1: like if you follow the show it almost goes through a progression of like.
Speaker 1: it's about a lot of different things and It evokes a lot of like memories of other shows but in very like.
Speaker 1: well, we'll get into it.
Speaker 1: So first it's kind of just a school drama literally about a bunch of kids in the drama club in a private school like it's ostensibly about that and that's where the story starts and That's where a lot of just the action happens.
Speaker 1: Like there's just a bunch of people and they're in this drama club and one of their classmates got murdered and there's a story around that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, pretty much.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but the way that story is told and the way it's framed because it's kind of an isolated private school.
Speaker 1: There's definitely a you're where you're in the school or you're outside of the school and these are very different worlds.
Speaker 0: very antenna situation.
Speaker 1: It's utenna both in the way It's portrayed like their parents aren't really present.
Speaker 1: The kids are on their own.
Speaker 1: The student council is capitalized as capitalized C matters capital M.
Speaker 0: There wasn't really a student council.
Speaker 0: Well, there's almost like the drama club is the student to student council?
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, the drama club is basically the student council because Lewis is in charge of it and is Terrifyingly powerful dear.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but that all bleeds into real-world politics a little bit.
Speaker 1: It gets a little complicated but the weight some scenes are shot to like.
Speaker 1: it'll do that do ten a thing.
Speaker 1: Background characters just have blank faces.
Speaker 1: It'll like.
Speaker 1: it'll really do.
Speaker 1: the kinds of artistry that utenna does to make points to focus your attention To like drive the allegory of what's happening in a scene.
Speaker 1: It doesn't even has.
Speaker 0: it even has a crazy Random tangent right about eggs.
Speaker 1: It does in fact have the nanami tangent with that.
Speaker 0: As soon as that happened I was like, that's the egg.
Speaker 0: There it is.
Speaker 1: But it also does the thing that utenna does that princess tutu Does where there is a play that they are performing in the first part of the show and they perform it twice.
Speaker 1: But what is happening in the play is definite allegory to what is happening in the show.
Speaker 1: No, yeah, and what happens in the play affects the real world directly.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm, it's a lot of these antenna aspects going on.
Speaker 1: but then fast forward a little further watch more of the show.
Speaker 1: It's also about this psychosexual tension between Predators and prey.
Speaker 1: it's almost like a world where vampires live alongside regular humans and people get murdered kind of all the time in Society.
Speaker 1: just kind of agrees.
Speaker 1: That's Just happening.
Speaker 1: It doesn't really work.
Speaker 0: Well, it's what it is.
Speaker 0: It's it's like utenna and to where you know You know the surface thing going on.
Speaker 0: and then it's like actually there's all kinds of dark shit going on.
Speaker 0: People keep it hush-hush or it's hidden from you and it's sort of like a terrible secretive space.
Speaker 0: but it's not.
Speaker 1: but it gets into like all these ideas of like oppressor versus oppressed and predatory classes versus like predated upon classes.
Speaker 0: Well, you think it's a class thing.
Speaker 1: I think The thing is it does not map.
Speaker 1: This is the most important thing.
Speaker 1: It does not map one-to-one to real-world Oppressions.
Speaker 1: it is a complex map of its own devising.
Speaker 0: Well, I think what more than a class thing, right because everything's a class there.
Speaker 0: I think what it's really about is, you know, you have a society, right?
Speaker 0: And in human society that we live in right people have are still animals, right?
Speaker 0: A human being is an animal right and we still have.
Speaker 0: this is like, you know, super old Freudian nonsense, right?
Speaker 0: You know, you still have these animal instincts that you have because you're a human being who is an animal.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and oftentimes those animal instincts those you know urges your lizard brain has right are Contrary to the rules and and practices of society.
Speaker 1: Yeah Your conscious brain wants to follow but at the same time some of those things May or may not be innate or natural and some of those things may just be created by society and perception.
Speaker 0: Sure, but the point is is that by making a show in which everyone is Literally a furry animal of some kind humanoid, you know Anthropomorphic animal right and they're all mixed up together right all these different animals are forced to live together peacefully Right and they have to press
Speaker 1: making they have
Speaker 0: to repress their instincts.
Speaker 0: Right as animals to eat each other or do whatever their animal thing is, right?
Speaker 0: To live peacefully together.
Speaker 0: because normally right there, you know kramarti the rabbit in the lion's den That's some fucking rabbit that doesn't get eaten in the lion.
Speaker 0: But I guess at the same time that but look at that from the lion's perspective That's some fucking lion that doesn't eat a rabbit.
Speaker 1: But that structure lets it explore these really interesting issues.
Speaker 1: because in the world of these stars Some of these instincts are real physical manifestations Like you can't.
Speaker 1: the predator drive is like legit real It's like you can't.
Speaker 1: the show will not argue that there is a like social construct around that.
Speaker 0: But I mean, it's real for a real wolf too in the woods.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but I'm hungry wolf's gonna eat you but in the show is this so you've got a human s character.
Speaker 1: who has you know?
Speaker 1: Who is sentient?
Speaker 1: who has these real drives but simultaneously?
Speaker 1: some of the things that are going on with what these characters feel is either performative or Clearly is driven by society.
Speaker 1: So it starts mixing up gender roles predator prey roles and just societal roles together and because they don't map one-to-one with the real World it ends up letting you explore things that we don't have real world analogies for Right.
Speaker 0: Well, I mean, it's it's just by combined, you know, the just bringing the animal, you know Metaphor on top of humanity right just makes it way more complicated But also way more sort of obvious invisible, right.
Speaker 0: and it especially applies when you look at like the messaging around.
Speaker 0: You know vegetarian veganism, right?
Speaker 0: You know the society makes it so no one's allowed to eat any meats.
Speaker 0: Right because meat is someone else even though there were insects that were not sentient.
Speaker 0: I just want to point that out.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we'll just let that be.
Speaker 1: no bugs That's a Pokemon question.
Speaker 0: There's mammals and there's birds and that and all of it all other animals are not.
Speaker 0: Oh, is there a lizard person?
Speaker 1: I don't remember.
Speaker 0: I don't remember if there's a lizard person, but there's definitely mammals and birds.
Speaker 0: I don't know if there's anything else regardless But there's no monkeys.
Speaker 1: Maybe there is me where I'm saying, I don't know.
Speaker 1: but like those look at the main regardless To see where I'm getting at this with is not having a one-to-one mapping.
Speaker 1: So we've got the main character is this shy Quiet wolf guy who's just full of teen angst like he's just an angsty teenager and that's his main thing.
Speaker 0: He has a real predator drive Where he's a big giant powerful scary wolf and he loses control of himself and almost eats a classmate.
Speaker 1: like that happened Right.
Speaker 1: He's really.
Speaker 0: he's trying not to write.
Speaker 0: It's like he doesn't.
Speaker 0: you know his conscious brain doesn't want to but his animal instinct is I'm a big scary wolf gonna blow your house.
Speaker 1: But simultaneously it gets more complicated because there's another wolf in the show who is a female wolf who expresses and feels that Instinct very differently and acts very differently even though she may be feeling very similar thing.
Speaker 1: Like the two characters despite both being wolves have very different problems to solve approach them very different ways and perceive themselves in the world Around them differently.
Speaker 1: So already it's not as simple as a wolves feel this pressure But but also a lot of the other predators have this machismo and this bravado and they fight with each other in ways that this Angsty wolf does not want to.
Speaker 1: he's not interested in all this nonsense.
Speaker 1: He almost doesn't want to be the what he doesn't want to fill the role that society says predators should fill Right.
Speaker 0: Well his body does.
Speaker 0: his body does.
Speaker 1: his mind is conscious.
Speaker 0: his conscious brain does not.
Speaker 0: his conscious brain wants to be like a Nice guy hanging out in society.
Speaker 0: Everyone gets along peacefully and his body sometimes doesn't let him because it's a big scary wolf body and it almost gets into.
Speaker 1: it's not the feminine mystique, but it's a similar.
Speaker 1: that idea of Some of the things he feels are intrinsic and real to his physical form and some of the things he feels are societal roles that he rejects and are not intrinsic to him.
Speaker 1: and the show does a really good job of exploring the interplay between These two ideas while everything develops, right?
Speaker 0: And it's not a it's you know.
Speaker 0: I don't know if the dysphoria really applies because it's not like.
Speaker 0: he doesn't want to be a wolf or he feels like he's not.
Speaker 1: But he doesn't want to be like the jock wolf who's fighting with everyone for fun like that other right?
Speaker 0: exactly He's not.
Speaker 0: he's not like I'm not a wolf.
Speaker 0: I'm actually something else.
Speaker 1: He's like Not all wolves have to be.
Speaker 0: he just doesn't like some of the baggage that comes along with being what he is.
Speaker 1: Yep, right And then you've got the deer guy.
Speaker 1: if you see photos of this guy Lewis who's another one of the main characters he is a prey animal who is both jealous of and Fearful of the power that predators have like the raw physical power.
Speaker 1: and there is there is a an extreme psychosexual tension between him and Legos.
Speaker 0: everybody Every single.
Speaker 1: what between everybody and everybody?
Speaker 1: Sure, if I had to describe the show in one sentence these animals in school have psychosexual tension with every other animal in the school Right.
Speaker 0: Oh what I was saying about the the vegetarian vegan thing, right?
Speaker 0: It's like, you know in the real world, you know, it's a it's a difficult topic to discuss with people Right because it's like, you know, clearly there's that element of you know, you know, there's some natural aspect.
Speaker 0: It's like yeah lions just eat other animals It's just what they do right and we don't apply a moral thing to that right.
Speaker 0: but humans we know better Right, and it's like yeah raising all these cows right destroys the environment, right?
Speaker 0: It's we're treating some of the animals badly.
Speaker 0: There's all sorts of other things going on, but also we're smarter than the cow.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right.
Speaker 0: So here by turning on its head a little bit.
Speaker 0: It's like, okay Well animals are actual, you know, it's not like in the.
Speaker 0: in the real world We debate like how you know, is it okay to eat the cow because it's not so smart, right?
Speaker 0: Would you eat another person?
Speaker 0: No, right here.
Speaker 0: It's like.
Speaker 0: well the cow is as smart as you and you're a lion.
Speaker 0: It was also smart, right?
Speaker 0: You're a lion person and a cow person.
Speaker 0: Is it okay for that lion person to eat a cow person?
Speaker 0: Yep, right.
Speaker 1: or and you want to see how dark the show gets.
Speaker 1: a question that might be asked even in the show is is it?
Speaker 1: Allowable for a cow person to sell themselves to be eaten.
Speaker 1: Is that okay?
Speaker 0: Right and you basically get all it's like well now it's.
Speaker 0: now it's tough right you still have that same thing where it's like.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's only natural for the lion to eat the eat the wildebeest or whatever it is the light, right?
Speaker 0: But when they're both have human intelligence, it's like oh, it's not okay.
Speaker 0: Okay, it's not okay you decided.
Speaker 0: But now the lion is rip.
Speaker 0: What's he gonna eat?
Speaker 0: Okay, and now the Lions all all messed up inside right the strong animals, right?
Speaker 0: I think the carnivorous animals, you know, they're repressing their these instincts, right?
Speaker 0: and they have difficult lives even though they're powerful in society.
Speaker 0: and The prey animals right they're sort of like, okay, right we can you know They're always afraid right of these carnivorous animals Even if they don't actually get eaten, although sometimes they do.
Speaker 0: Yep, right.
Speaker 0: So they're sort of repressed in society, you know, societally Even though there are natural instincts on the inside of them They don't have to repress those in any way.
Speaker 0: And then it matters.
Speaker 1: but there's on top of all of that because the third main character the rabbit girl.
Speaker 1: She's a small She's a dwarf rabbit.
Speaker 1: She's like the weakest of the weak physically, but yeah, she's not.
Speaker 0: It's like smaller than all the other rabbits.
Speaker 1: and you see all these dynamics of like the larger rabbits bully her.
Speaker 1: she is Definitely shamed for being sexually promiscuous Right.
Speaker 0: She's all alone in the gardening club.
Speaker 0: She's the only member of the gardening.
Speaker 1: Her own reality as a prey animal and her complicated relationships with the nature of predators around her But also with other prey animals around her.
Speaker 1: she does not live up to the societal expectations of her Her animal nature or her gender.
Speaker 0: right but like everyone else she still has problems You know with the conflict between what her body will do on its own because it's a rabbit body and that's it does what it Does versus what her brain wants to do, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, you'll see her behave drastically differently, right?
Speaker 0: It's like when she has, you know Conscious control over the things she says and does like she's all badass and whatever and she stands up to a certain unnamed Character in episode near the end.
Speaker 0: something right?
Speaker 0: Yeah Exactly, but then sometimes like her body will just do something like run away, which is you know, like a rabbit and hi
Speaker 1: And
Speaker 0: cower, which is she characteristic
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm, like her foot keeps moving uncontrollably
Speaker 0: Yep, because her body is scared because it's a big bad wolf right in front of her.
Speaker 0: Yeah, her leg keeps trying to run away even though she has no desire to run away.
Speaker 0: She's just chillin and eating nice lunch with somebody.
Speaker 1: So all of that alone can make a pretty compelling like thrillers set in a high school like.
Speaker 1: that's enough, right?
Speaker 0: And there's so many different things, you know, you can you can say with that setup, you know about human society.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you can make you can make a call like a hundred episode series just with that.
Speaker 1: But that kind of just sets the stage for what the show seems to really be about because even in this first season of the anime by episode 9 The school politics are intersecting with the real-world politics.
Speaker 1: the The Pat like the deers path Lewis's path through being the head of this drama club and getting out of the school is like a political Path where he is working with the mayor who is a lion who is like legit connected to the Mafia and that matters Directly in the show pretty early on Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: Well, and then that starts getting into this intro It's the Yagas, it's not the Mafia.
Speaker 1: Well, yeah, it's the Yagas the cry.
Speaker 1: It's well the Shishi gumi in particular one criminal organization.
Speaker 1: Yeah But all of that starts happening and the show starts to get a little broader in scope that it's not just gonna be about These angsty teenagers dealing with this society.
Speaker 1: It's starting to show this class separations of the school is almost Literally a fantasy world compared to the real world outside it.
Speaker 1: Right much like a new final right.
Speaker 0: and the final thing is the title of the show which is be stars, right?
Speaker 1: It's a how many times does an anime say the name of the anime in the show?
Speaker 1: and it is not terrible, right?
Speaker 0: So during the show several times it comes up that some animals are you know, some people whatever they want to call them are Become somehow.
Speaker 0: become the be star or be stars, right?
Speaker 0: You don't know how many there are one at a time.
Speaker 0: Who's the current?
Speaker 0: be star?
Speaker 1: Not revealed a lot about it.
Speaker 1: it evokes for me.
Speaker 1: even in utana the lights have the ring go into the castle.
Speaker 1: Well, what does that mean?
Speaker 0: I don't know but everybody what does it mean to be the Rose?
Speaker 0: I want to.
Speaker 0: I want to win the Rose bride.
Speaker 0: It's like.
Speaker 0: that's the same idea.
Speaker 0: It's like this some of the people want to become the be star or be stars.
Speaker 0: There's some unknown process by which you become it.
Speaker 0: There is some unknown thing you gain by being it.
Speaker 0: Don't know who is it and it appears that what you don't know.
Speaker 1: when real power like that's a very important point kind of like In utana, the characters are seeking real power.
Speaker 1: Not the power always in this fancy world but power over the real world to right some wrong or fight some injustice.
Speaker 0: All we know is that you can become the be star somehow You.
Speaker 0: the path to becoming it involves being popular and or powerful or well liked and making Horrible deals with bad people.
Speaker 1: because that's what adults do outside of the fantasy world of the school right doing underhanded things Possibly to get ahead.
Speaker 0: It's it's not entirely clear.
Speaker 0: But what is clear is that like yeah, you can see that you know the main event of the show Which isn't addressed in season one at all, you know other than showing you that it's sort of on the horizon is you know?
Speaker 0: The battle to see who will become the be star and all that entails.
Speaker 0: But I think it's somewhat transparent right that there are some characters who were clearly set up and are actively a Like frontrunners for becoming be star and be actively trying well
Speaker 1: Remember the all that is their goal are in a clearly extremely expensive like private special school
Speaker 0: Right, but I mean it's a cliche that you know in a lot of stories to have something like this where you see some characters Who are trying to become the be star or a be star and are also a just feel like they're close to it like yeah They're probably in the lead or whatever it is But you just know that the unexpected character who isn't even trying who's like the main character will be the one right?
Speaker 0: It's the same as like.
Speaker 0: oh, yeah The the kid in the class who is obviously the main character of the show, but isn't as strong fast or smart.
Speaker 0: They're the magical person right you know.
Speaker 0: that's how it's gonna be.
Speaker 0: that's the cliche of cliches And I would be very surprised if the show did not Adhere to that cliche.
Speaker 0: if it made if one of the frontrunners was the one to become the be star Or be whatever I would be quite surprised.
Speaker 1: or will it focus more on what I foresee this was very happening.
Speaker 1: more is it focusing on how much of your principle do you sacrifice to get that real power and become the be star?
Speaker 1: and Was it worth it?
Speaker 0: Right and you know some of the characters say ask some interesting questions that are never answered.
Speaker 0: Like he's like.
Speaker 0: why do we have be stars in this world?
Speaker 0: Why right?
Speaker 0: It's like.
Speaker 0: it's like what?
Speaker 0: I don't even know what the be star is.
Speaker 0: that doesn't mean anything to me.
Speaker 1: or when you know the the primary Arc of the end of the first season where a character gets kidnapped and the Yakuza get involved and there's trouble.
Speaker 1: There's a scene between one character and the mayor Where the mayor sort of reveals some dark shit about the world like open yep And like.
Speaker 1: this is the price of being of power.
Speaker 1: Do you not want this power like are you gonna mayor's a mayor?
Speaker 0: the mayor is not a be star.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but the mayor has power, but the mayor is not that power.
Speaker 0: that power is special And if there are be stars out there It's like where the hell are they?
Speaker 0: how can they're not doing anything about it?
Speaker 0: and also how real if they even have that power.
Speaker 1: it's very clear that a big theme in the show is - is also going to be as it goes on how real is the peaceful facade of this society?
Speaker 1: because it's increasingly clear especially after you get to episode 9 that the Coexistence of predator and prey in this universe is not at all peaceful and is not fucking working, and there's also lots of Instances of segregation around.
Speaker 1: yes, and the segregation is along racial lines gender lines class lines And other lines to be determined.
Speaker 0: It's it's not sacred.
Speaker 0: It's not like extreme apartheid right?
Speaker 0: It's like yeah, you're living next to each other right?
Speaker 0: we see wealthy and powerful Animals of all species right a lot of species stick together.
Speaker 0: there does seem to be some amount of Prejudice against interspecies relationships.
Speaker 0: yup there seems to be you know these sorts of things.
Speaker 0: so It's like.
Speaker 0: it's there right.
Speaker 0: It's like.
Speaker 0: Oh yeah, this school is special because it has carnivores and herbivores together.
Speaker 0: Oh, so other schools don't other schools like a carnivore only school.
Speaker 1: It's one of those things The advice I give you.
Speaker 1: I don't think we're gonna do like a nutenna style like Tear-down of the show because I just don't have the energy right now.
Speaker 1: I got other things to finish.
Speaker 1: But this show will definitely when you as you watch it think about what questions get raised by the show But don't get answered by the show and think a lot about what doesn't get talked about.
Speaker 0: I think that's yeah It's definitely a show.
Speaker 0: I think that's actually maybe a flaw in the show is at least so far season one is that it's really great And asking questions and showing sort of a both sides II kind of thing right, but not having an opinion.
Speaker 0: Well, I think it doesn't really come out and say what like what it believes.
Speaker 0: It's just like oh look at this that makes you Think huh well, I think it's too soon You think about that cuz right now.
Speaker 1: It's all the all those questions are really just being raised in the course of following these angsty Teenagers trying to navigate this possibly fucked up world.
Speaker 1: So the primary focus of the show is so far as what we've seen is really on How do these three characters navigate this world?
Speaker 1: can they even change this world?
Speaker 0: So season two on Netflix is definitely coming.
Speaker 0: I don't know how many Netflix seasons.
Speaker 0: They'll make but I wonder it was crazy popular Sure, but would it be better to wait for season two or would it be better to?
Speaker 0: Abandoned Netflix and read the manga because you know the manga is way ahead of Netflix So far.
Speaker 1: planning to just watch the show because the thing one thing that struck me about the show from a reviewing standpoint is that Almost every episode just when I thought okay.
Speaker 1: I see where this is going something would escalate way faster than I expected or Something would happen that I did not expect at all.
Speaker 1: the show would swerve into a direction that I would.
Speaker 1: I did not anticipate the Sanctuary esque thing that happens in episode 9 Like at all and those more and there's a lot of shocking moments that have a lot of impacts.
Speaker 1: like the anime portrays them really Well.
Speaker 1: things like.
Speaker 1: characters will say something that even as the viewer you almost double-take for a second like wait What did they just say?
Speaker 1: what just happened?
Speaker 1: So I want to experience that with the rest of the show and not read the manga.
Speaker 0: So the thing that I think will keep me watching the show which I alluded to earlier briefly is the ghost the shell connection.
Speaker 0: Is that the best character in the show the panda?
Speaker 1: Oh you love that panda?
Speaker 1: I do.
Speaker 1: I enjoy the panda.
Speaker 1: I saw him to be what he was Before he.
Speaker 1: they revealed what he was like.
Speaker 1: I could see where that character was going.
Speaker 0: the panda.
Speaker 0: that clearly is Just Bato from ghost.
Speaker 0: in the shell yep is Obviously voice acted right down to like.
Speaker 1: do I need to go help that kid?
Speaker 0: his voice acted by a cute the voice of In a particular moment with his band the same character.
Speaker 0: It's the same voice actor.
Speaker 0: It is the best character in the show.
Speaker 0: all the other characters in the show have sort of you know good points and bad.
Speaker 0: Well my favorite character like or not like them Lewis's the interact.
Speaker 0: Oh, that's that's just rim the character.
Speaker 1: He's toga like.
Speaker 0: he's the toga character in toga less evil toga.
Speaker 0: well logo who might be good it might be bad and it's questionable.
Speaker 0: I
Speaker 1: Don't know if he will if Lewis will end up being a better person than toga or a worse person than toga Because the show leaves ambiguous at the end of season one What
Speaker 0: decisions
Speaker 1: the deer may have made relative to other things that were happening at the time?
Speaker 1: I'm being circumspect because you got to go watch the show.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean that is.
Speaker 0: I think that definitely is one of the better Like you know not favorite character like panda.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but Like better written characters, right?
Speaker 0: It's because you don't see too often right.
Speaker 0: someone like that is usually gonna be like a toga where it's like.
Speaker 0: okay they're the secretly evil student council leader or the Stern sort of.
Speaker 0: maybe looks like they're bad, but they're actually good.
Speaker 1: This is genuinely conflicted and complicated.
Speaker 1: Second guesses himself.
Speaker 1: does the change?
Speaker 0: I think my that that conflicted complicatedness Rarely is combined with that personality.
Speaker 0: right that personality and that position is Usually in anime stories, especially aligned with the particular kind of character in utenna.
Speaker 1: Toga is at no point conflicted with himself until the very end of the show.
Speaker 0: Oh, what about that whole part of the mill where he says they're doing nothing?
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, where he just lost himself But he's not conflicted.
Speaker 1: He's just lost.
Speaker 1: Maybe he doesn't have to make a decision He's just done the thing.
Speaker 1: any way coming turns out becoming the Beast.
Speaker 0: are that?
Speaker 0: what's gonna happen?
Speaker 0: is Lu is just gonna be lost For season two and come back in season three.
Speaker 1: Uh, did you see the the preview toga style?
Speaker 0: Oh, there's a preview at the.
Speaker 1: if you keep these edits at the end of season of the end of the last episode There's a stinger.
Speaker 1: that is basically the opening scene of season two and a character who has clearly taken a lot of painkillers Shows up and you just see a POV shot of Legosi turning around saying oh, hey Welcome back.
Speaker 1: Basically, like where were you?
Speaker 1: Then it ends with see you in season two.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, I did see that but it wasn't.
Speaker 1: it does not show you who that character Is I'm just assuming who that character is.
Speaker 1: I may be wrong.
Speaker 0: Okay, but like I did watch that.
Speaker 1: but the cool thing is all of the main characters and All of the side characters like even that chicken.
Speaker 1: They're way more complex and have way more depth than most shows would ever give characters with that little screen time.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they definitely.
Speaker 0: if a character shows up on screen even briefly.
Speaker 0: There's like a and has a face and a name.
Speaker 0: then they they bothered to come up with something about them.
Speaker 0: That is somewhat interesting.
Speaker 0: No character.
Speaker 0: There's something to chew on.
Speaker 1: right like the little girl shows up.
Speaker 1: Oh, she's flirting with Legosi.
Speaker 1: I see what's happening.
Speaker 1: the next scene Her and Lewis have a moment and you might think that moment is gonna be the moment you're expecting.
Speaker 1: it might be in fact the exact opposite of what you were expecting and you learn a lot about that wolf character and things are Not what they look like.
Speaker 0: But this point is if someone appears like this They there's something to chew on for any character.
Speaker 0: if there isn't then they don't bother to draw them and put them on there.
Speaker 1: Yep, if you see those characters at all, they're literally just like faceless utenna background people walking by.
Speaker 0: Yep, all right, so I need food.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: I love the hell out of this show.
Speaker 1: I highly recommend you watch it.
Speaker 1: but fair warning.
Speaker 1: This show is dark.
Speaker 1: There are you have to deal with themes of Not for kids cannibalism rape sexual violence Violence violence death.
Speaker 1: characters die.
Speaker 1: There is blood and gore.
Speaker 1: It is a rough show.
Speaker 0: You've got to be ready much every every warning you need.
Speaker 1: This is a tense psychosexual thriller.
Speaker 0: Yeah, this is like Almost perfect blue level warning here.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so be ready for that like be ready for this show to be.
Speaker 0: maybe should have said that at the start.
Speaker 1: I Mean, well if anyone tries to watch it Netflix will warn them.
Speaker 0: That's true.
Speaker 1: Netflix has a pretty long list of.
Speaker 1: here are the things in this show.
Speaker 1: You got to be ready for.
Speaker 0: Good job, Netflix.
Speaker 1: So yeah, I do recommend this is one of the better anime to come out in recent memory.
Speaker 1: It is one of my favorite anime in a while.
Speaker 0: It's a very rim anime.
Speaker 1: it is a very rim anime.
Speaker 1: I am deep into this.
Speaker 1: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Speaker 0: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 1: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 0: But unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night And the patreon patrons for this episode of geek nights are Alan Joyce Heidi McNichol Marty green.
Speaker 1: Yeah, just like a dude gag chart option link eg.
Speaker 1: you hold the key to my heart.
Speaker 1: But she packed my suitcase and sent me on my way.
Speaker 1: Clinton Walton Jay Vance ran from New Zealand Ryan parent drove and lighter Nicholas Brando Chris midkiff the thirst for hydrated ganon dread lily tenebrae Chris Reimer Finn Sean Klein Thomas Han Sherman von Harl Sean Yeager and a bunch of people who don't want me to say their names.
Speaker 1: We did record our Dumbo episode.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna put it up just for you patrons probably tomorrow.
Speaker 1: For now since we actually skipped the reluctant dragon, we get to go back and watch that and do a Disney show on that.
Speaker 1: Otherwise, stay tuned.
Speaker 1: I do plan to actually try to like script together and be ready to make your 10 episodes.
Speaker 1: The teleprompter was part of the reason I'm doing that.
Speaker 1: So stay tuned and now I leave you with.
Speaker 1: I find this all quite preposterous.
Speaker 0: Oh, I say good, sir.