Speaker 0: It's Monday March 30th 2020.
Speaker 0: I'm rim.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott and this is geek nights tonight.
Speaker 0: It's time for a tech news roundup.
Speaker 0: I Get so excited when I can do a tech news roundup.
Speaker 0: It means I got some.
Speaker 0: I don't have to worry about coming up with a Monday show.
Speaker 1: You hit for a one year.
Speaker 1: you can tell.
Speaker 0: all I got to do is go to slash dot which I don't recommend you going To because the people who use slash shot or troglodyte thought there are terrifying people in the slash shot comments.
Speaker 0: But it is a good list of the stories to talk about that.
Speaker 0: I can go find real links to them when I actually post the show.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so actually I got a tech opening bit.
Speaker 1: So as you know pretty much everyone's trapped at home, right?
Speaker 1: So of all people my brother messages me like this morning.
Speaker 1: I see a text message, and he's it says literally Here's the text message.
Speaker 1: Where is it?
Speaker 1: Build me a PC.
Speaker 1: That's all it says.
Speaker 0: I mean sure send me a check for $5,000.
Speaker 1: It's like this is a person who hasn't had a PC in I don't know how many years.
Speaker 1: He just gets by with his iPad, and I think he had a MacBook at one point, but it's so old It's not worth.
Speaker 1: You know doesn't do anything anymore.
Speaker 0: I would like that.
Speaker 0: is he gonna game on it or like?
Speaker 1: yeah He wants to play games and I guess Whatever.
Speaker 0: I don't know Falcon Northwest or something or alien.
Speaker 1: I was like maybe goodbye a Microsoft Surface or something.
Speaker 1: right you'll be fine with that.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: He's like building a PC.
Speaker 1: It's like cuz I remember when we were kids.
Speaker 1: You know I was the PC person.
Speaker 1: He was there with his like n64 in the late 90s.
Speaker 1: He didn't.
Speaker 1: he PC'd later And most of his PCing was like he played Warcraft 3 with like the actual original dota mod, right?
Speaker 0: We were actually both like my brother And I were both primarily PC gaming and NES SNES like that generation And we both kind of ditched consoles after that.
Speaker 1: for a while He played a lot of counter-strike, but then after that after you know he went to college, and then he pretty much You know stopped PCing.
Speaker 1: I don't think he had a piece other than that one MacBook.
Speaker 1: I don't think he's had a PC, but now he's trapped at home.
Speaker 1: Now suddenly he wants a real computer.
Speaker 1: He wants me to like put it together for all it is if you design it and put it together Then if there's any problem with it No, but I was like you know hey, you know how much money.
Speaker 1: This is gonna cost you.
Speaker 1: You don't have any computer parts.
Speaker 1: You're gonna have to buy.
Speaker 1: you know monitors mice keyboards Microsoft Windows.
Speaker 1: you gotta buy all kinds of stuff That you don't have.
Speaker 0: funnily enough one of my co-workers wants to build a gaming PC for his kid And yeah, he's actually pretty savvy.
Speaker 0: He just hasn't built a gaming PC in like 10 15 years.
Speaker 1: If you've built a PC ever you can build one now.
Speaker 1: yep.
Speaker 0: So mostly he was just trying to figure out.
Speaker 0: and the funny thing is he asked me.
Speaker 0: all he asked me is he's like so Are those AMD chips any good?
Speaker 0: because the last time I tried you said everyone's buying these days.
Speaker 0: I guess they seem like they work these days like I don't trust them enough.
Speaker 1: I already still don't trust them, but people keep buying them.
Speaker 0: so I see there are credible stories of people making AMD like Ryzen gaming PCs that post on the first attempt which sure I guess that's true I guess AMD.
Speaker 1: You know is because they're behind right there where they were behind Since they fell out of favor.
Speaker 1: They've been trying hard.
Speaker 0: meanwhile Intel is not pushed forward very right.
Speaker 1: Intel has been I think hindered in a lot of ways You know and I think Intel tried to foray into a lot of other Segments and markets and failed.
Speaker 1: you know.
Speaker 1: if you look at like you know all mobile chips.
Speaker 1: Intel did not win.
Speaker 0: Also apartment we hit another plateau of like.
Speaker 0: there are physical realities that prevent us from building stuff.
Speaker 1: Graphics chips.
Speaker 1: Intel did not win that department.
Speaker 1: They're trying to go up against GeForce with their video and video with their video cards not really going great.
Speaker 1: Yeah You know who knows?
Speaker 1: So yeah, maybe you know I mean nothing's invincible right.
Speaker 0: I mean that's why he mentioning that.
Speaker 0: that's why when people ask me I don't say oh Intel definitely I say my experiences are with Intel, but I do point people like hey You can look at this AMD area.
Speaker 0: just be warned.
Speaker 0: I'm not building another PC for nine years.
Speaker 0: so in nine years I'll see if AMD's are any good.
Speaker 1: Yeah, my brother might end up getting the AMD.
Speaker 1: who knows it's not my computer We're not my problem.
Speaker 0: You know I might actually try it out because the one I will have to build a new HTPC sometime this year the one in the living room from 2009 is Starting to have some problems.
Speaker 1: I just wonder how he wants to do like is he what gonna ship all these parts to my apartment?
Speaker 1: I put it together then he comes and gets it.
Speaker 1: or Gonna like You expect me to come there.
Speaker 1: I told him to do it himself.
Speaker 0: He's like no It's it's lit It is.
Speaker 0: this is like the Golden Age of it's.
Speaker 0: easy to put these things together.
Speaker 0: the heart.
Speaker 1: You got a lot of time to figure it out too from YouTube.
Speaker 1: Yeah
Speaker 0: plus nowadays if there would have been a video that would have showed me how to put the heatsink on my Thunderbird without breaking the motherboard and I know right if a video had said listen You're just gonna sound like you're breaking it Just keep trucking on and I could see a video of someone making that horrible noise without breaking it.
Speaker 0: I would have felt a lot better about that thing on.
Speaker 0: I was Terrified of putting that heatsink on that AMD.
Speaker 0: what a Thunderbird gigahertz that I got an RIT to replace the 800 that died.
Speaker 0: yep, but Let's get right into it.
Speaker 0: It's time for a tech news roundup, so we're not gonna talk about news We're just gonna go right into.
Speaker 1: Well, I got some.
Speaker 0: oh you got some more opening bits.
Speaker 1: Well, I got.
Speaker 1: I have a you know, since we're putting all the news in the main bit Yeah, I got some sort of semi geek bite that is technology related.
Speaker 1: Ooh, right.
Speaker 1: So there's this thing called a Jupiter notebook.
Speaker 1: Have you heard of this?
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, I use the hell out of that at work.
Speaker 1: It's pretty cool.
Speaker 1: Yeah Okay, you don't know about you know looks it's a big deal with like, you know Python especially right where our data analysis.
Speaker 0: Like if you got a business analyst who there's a data set and you want them to fuck with the data set Okay, you're probably using those features where you know, you're putting graphs mixed in with the code and also the text, right?
Speaker 0: Yep, or just like maybe they're gonna do some data analysis to then structure the data for import in some other system And they're gonna write all the code to do that.
Speaker 0: This is what they use to kind of fuck around with the data.
Speaker 0: I was like it's like two or three steps above using Excel or any of those tools.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I just wanted to use it to communicate with my co-workers, right?
Speaker 1: Like I could make a little notebook and send it to them to demonstrate what I was trying to tell them.
Speaker 1: You know code wise, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah But so, you know setting that up wasn't so wasn't very tricky at all.
Speaker 1: Just install it and run it.
Speaker 1: The thing is.
Speaker 1: the way it works is it's.
Speaker 1: it's one of those things where nobody these days wants to make a desktop app.
Speaker 1: Everyone wants to make a web app Yeah, but it's all.
Speaker 1: you run it locally which means it runs its own web server and then opens your browser and there it is.
Speaker 0: Yep, it's.
Speaker 0: uh, the only reason I'm okay with it is that other people do that part for me.
Speaker 1: Yeah Yeah, so the thing is not really about the Jupiter notebook It's about that want to talk about because that's just use it if you want.
Speaker 1: It's pretty cool Yeah, is that I'm using for all my development work home end at work.
Speaker 1: I use Windows subsystem for Linux, right?
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, all my code and this notebook included would be running in this sort of semi not Windows Linux land, right?
Speaker 1: But then what happens is when I run it It starts a web server in the Linux land and it's fine because that's still localhost the port that it's on.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but then I it's.
Speaker 1: it tries to open my browser and visit the web server automatically.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so I could just open up my browser.
Speaker 1: in the real I want to.
Speaker 1: I don't want to use some Firefox That's installed in the fake Linux.
Speaker 1: Hell no, right in in the fake in the X server on Windows I want to go to my real Windows web browser and visit.
Speaker 1: So I could do that by typing in the link which in the Windows Browser, but that sucks.
Speaker 1: who wants to copy and paste a link every frickin time from the terminal over to the browser, right?
Speaker 1: So I found it a handy trick.
Speaker 1: There's apparently a package called WUSL or I think is what it was called.
Speaker 1: But anyway, it had like a Little program that was like WSL open or something, right?
Speaker 1: I don't know if that's the exact acronym.
Speaker 1: It's something like that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'm googling for it.
Speaker 0: I give up.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but basically it was really crazy that I'm in this fake Linux and I type this thing and I press enter And it opens up the browser in the windows.
Speaker 0: You know go back to a younger.
Speaker 0: I'm working at IBM circa 2003.
Speaker 0: That would have been witchcraft Right.
Speaker 0: It's like I was running it Wine like wine to try to put like hacked DLLs to make Windows shit run on Linux.
Speaker 1: Right the Linux that I'm using is basically is literally actually bash dot exe.
Speaker 1: So it's bash dot exe.
Speaker 1: it runs and I'm using the bash dot exe and I type a command and that runs Firefox dot exe Outside of the bash dot exe.
Speaker 0: Well, if you just went back to me circa 2003 and just said bash dot exe will be a real thing I wouldn't have believed you.
Speaker 1: yeah, so I set some environment variables and I changed some settings in the Jupiter config and now when I run the Jupiter notebook it Run, it starts a web server in the fake Linux and then my real web browser in Windows opens a new tab aimed at it.
Speaker 1: Not too shabby.
Speaker 1: That's what I did today, but it was.
Speaker 1: you know, you know, it's funny at work.
Speaker 0: I actually wish I had more time to fuck around with these Jupiter notebooks because you know I'm I'm not supposed to be fucking with the technology I'm supposed to be like strategizing but like I see the things people are doing in there with these data sets And I just really want to play around.
Speaker 1: all it really is is a is an editor to make documents But you can put code in the documents but the code is attached to.
Speaker 1: you have a basically a server running that will Execute the code and you could rerun the code or move the code around.
Speaker 0: So if you have a giant you can just put that database there and write some code.
Speaker 1: interface with the database Right, and then you can take the outputs from the code you ran and pass them to other objects in the document like graphs and charts Visualizations or whatever, but other than that is just you know.
Speaker 1: Documents, right.
Speaker 1: so you and you make the documents.
Speaker 1: you can send them to someone else and then when they open it on their end Right, they open up this document.
Speaker 1: They can now interact with the code and the things in the document because it's running live code interpreter.
Speaker 0: Anyone listening to this who is like trying to learn Python just play with this thing.
Speaker 0: This thing actually is also a pretty cool place just to like fuck around with basic Python and learn like basic techniques.
Speaker 1: Yeah, because it makes it easy.
Speaker 0: You're not trying to write a whole application You're just you've written some Python code to interact with a structure that already exists.
Speaker 1: It also helps you make pretty nice you know documentation for certain things because you can eat when you're in the editor.
Speaker 1: you can easily save as La tech or PDF or all kinds of formats.
Speaker 1: and you know, like if you put a Jupyter notebook document for example in a git repository and push it to github and you go to github and you click on that document.
Speaker 1: GitHub runs it in the jupyter viewer and there it is.
Speaker 1: Yeah in all its fancy enos ways Instead of just seeing the source of the document.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: So man I don't even have a single Linux box running in my house right now.
Speaker 1: Just use Windows subsystem for Linux.
Speaker 1: I could yeah I guess I guess what technically runs Linux in this house.
Speaker 1: Maybe the Nintendo switch run Linux?
Speaker 1: I don't think so.
Speaker 0: Maybe my nasus thing might be based on Linux.
Speaker 0: I forget what that.
Speaker 1: oh, yes My Synology runs Linux.
Speaker 1: that router probably does.
Speaker 1: maybe.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I got a weird Verizon gave me a weird router now, so I don't know.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's not my old WRT.
Speaker 0: whatever.
Speaker 0: No, but whatever all right, but anyway now I guess it is time for Things of the day.
Speaker 0: What do you got?
Speaker 1: So we were at magfest and I saw panel on the schedule I think I've talked about on the show before previously classic Japanese PC games digital history behind barriers.
Speaker 1: right because the story is you know, I think all computer nerds and we sort of know this intuitively if but not Explicitly is that in the 80s 90s, right, you know the computers that were around the world, you know The the UK and Europe had a lot of.
Speaker 1: you know things like, you know, ZX spectrums and Commodores and not amigas, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, not everyone in like Windows on x86.
Speaker 1: right in the u.s.
Speaker 1: We had Macs apples You know Windows IBM PCs, right and in Japan they had PCs.
Speaker 1: But they were things like, you know with the thing that Metal Gear I did the MSX and you know The the tiger the the turbo graphics 16 with it was like the PC engine, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'd always heard all the MSX but I didn't know that it was a computer like a computer computer.
Speaker 0: I was a computer.
Speaker 1: it was a computer standard.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know there were lots of different computers that were all basically MSX compatible and they all ran the same.
Speaker 0: Mostly they were upgraded one, but my brain sex to my kid brain thought it was a gaming console because of Metal Gear.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right exactly.
Speaker 1: But basically, yeah, and there was what they call it is the Galapagos syndrome.
Speaker 1: Is this what this guy calls it which is like a perfect description, right?
Speaker 1: You think the island of Galapagos where Darwin went and saw the weird animals?
Speaker 1: Animals had been there somewhat separated from the rest of the world because they were near an island and they evolved Separately from the rest of the world.
Speaker 1: So in the 80s and 90s Japan's PC ecosystem was evolving on its own separate from the rest of the world, right?
Speaker 1: You know be mostly because for a wide variety of reasons, right?
Speaker 1: You know culture language all sorts of things and as a result all of the games Which is what we nerds are interested in that were made for Japanese PCs Were never ported never brought over, you know before emulators.
Speaker 0: You couldn't write good thing before emulation Like some of the stuff you'd worry about like Indian problems and nonsense like that all kinds of crazy stuff.
Speaker 1: Basically, there was a in.
Speaker 1: there were years and years and years where there were piles and piles and piles of amazing pieces of Software made in Japan for a variety of Japanese only computer PC platforms.
Speaker 1: Right, and I always knew that they were there but I didn't know much about it and couldn't learn much about it Didn't speak Japanese?
Speaker 1: still don't.
Speaker 1: and this guy did a panel where he's gonna you know Share that info and I was like damn I am going to that panel and I caught the tail end of it And even that last bit was fantastic, right?
Speaker 1: So the video of the panel is now online and I thought the quality was gonna be low.
Speaker 1: The lighting quality is low.
Speaker 1: you it's kind of a dark room, but you can still.
Speaker 1: the audio is actually really great.
Speaker 1: You can hear everything he's saying pretty clearly.
Speaker 0: I mean props to a cold guy and the magfest staff for like every year the video they do on their own has gotten better and Better.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's not a but you can sort of see what's on the projector mostly.
Speaker 1: Yeah You know, but yeah, it's like this is literally just a cheapo camcorder.
Speaker 1: They set up in the corner and push a button and don't really try to you know.
Speaker 1: But yeah, great great panel here for you to watch but the panel's not the thing of the day.
Speaker 1: My thing of the day is that at the very beginning of the panel?
Speaker 1: He says who was brought here by PC 98 bot.
Speaker 1: ha any any lesser people to raise their hands.
Speaker 1: So PC 98 bot is a Twitter bot that every four hours posts an image or gif of Some sort of game usually a weeb game.
Speaker 0: This is attention.
Speaker 0: Oh, you're right here.
Speaker 1: Yeah from the NEC PC 98 gaming, you know computer platform Which apparently had shit.
Speaker 1: tons of games made for it that you've never seen and probably never will see and probably never will play Ever almost any of these games, but there are some really amazing games here, you know The likes of which you know lots of visual novels lots of stretch term Dave strategy games RPGs all kinds of games some some revolutionary That you've never seen or heard of.
Speaker 1: most of them almost all of them and this Twitter account tweets images from them on the daily.
Speaker 1: so if you want to get a taste of what was going on in Japan in You know the mid-late 90s on the PCs that they had follow this Twitter account.
Speaker 0: alright, so I Saw this video talking about a virus that does something so crazy that I felt like I really need more virus talk right now.
Speaker 0: Well, this is a virus that does not in any way harm humans.
Speaker 0: In fact, it is a bacteriophage.
Speaker 0: So it kills and eat and effectively eats from the inside out bacteria.
Speaker 0: It's not a threat.
Speaker 1: Could we make a bacteriophage that kills say, I don't know all the bacterial illnesses in the world.
Speaker 0: There are actually Phage therapies, I think they were mostly pioneered in the Soviet Union, but they exist.
Speaker 0: They're still under research.
Speaker 0: like that is a promising field.
Speaker 0: Okay, bacteriophages because you know, if you if you don't remember your high school biology You know the little virus that looks like a little man with like little legs and a little head.
Speaker 1: It's those like a space lander.
Speaker 1: Yeah gonna land on some planet somewhere.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: It's got a little diamond It's got a d20 for a head and then some alien body and then some walking legs Like it's gonna come at you.
Speaker 0: Yep, like a little spider insect guy.
Speaker 0: So this virus dubbed the 5kz jumbo phage.
Speaker 0: it's one of those weird big boy.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it is.
Speaker 0: It's one of those weird big boy viruses like but it's still a really small boy.
Speaker 1: because the virus Yeah, it's bigger than the other virus.
Speaker 0: but like there are some viruses that are like so tiny It's not clear how they manage to survive in the wild on their own at all.
Speaker 0: Then there's big viruses that are so big they're like ridiculous compared to what you think of as the normal virus.
Speaker 0: These are weird biggens.
Speaker 0: But the thing that's crazy about them is that bacteria basically have no way to fight them off.
Speaker 0: They're like invincible Mm-hmm and what they do.
Speaker 0: and this videos three like.
Speaker 1: so even even if you break it up Even if the bacteria somehow like, you know breaks it into the enemy into pieces.
Speaker 0: it's still well more like all the ways like bacteria have all these different ways to fight viruses because Viruses are attacking them constantly and they're really good at killing viruses.
Speaker 0: But this virus does something that as far as I can tell and this video is these are experts who know way more about this.
Speaker 1: Then why don't we make a bacteria that can fight the corona?
Speaker 1: Well, it's like we're basically getting in and it's like a bacteria virus war going on around the whole world all the time that we Can't see.
Speaker 1: like a toner We're sort of and we're joining in on it trying to help one side or the other So that any of the combatants in the war that are harmful to humans always lose.
Speaker 0: If I've learned anything from any of the the political games we've ever played if other people are in a war do not fucking get involved in that war.
Speaker 0: No particular sieve game is coming to mind where I tried to help somebody out and I saw where it got me.
Speaker 0: Yep But anyway, what this virus does is it gets into the bacteria?
Speaker 0: Note that just in case you don't remember your high school biology bacteria do not have nuclei.
Speaker 0: There's no nucleus in a bacterium.
Speaker 0: No, the virus makes its own nuclei and hides inside of the nuclei and Controls the bacteria from in there.
Speaker 0: Okay, so none of the things the bacteria has.
Speaker 0: because the bacteria they don't have nuclei.
Speaker 0: They don't need an ability to like get inside of a nucleus to detect DNA damage or like fight with something.
Speaker 0: so the virus makes a nuclei and turns the bacteria into like Basically a mech suit that it wears like it's.
Speaker 0: it's just really amazing This video does.
Speaker 0: the reason I'm making this my thing of the day is that this is actually a really really complicated thing That my high school like AP biology knowledge Barely gets me to the point of being able to describe and I'm probably already wrong about ten things.
Speaker 0: but the way the Elegance with which this less than four minute video explains this and explains why it's so awesome is why I'm making it the thing of.
Speaker 0: This is like a plus internet content.
Speaker 1: as long as viruses don't come into human cells And I mean basically viruses that attack humans just break ourselves Right and just make them into like, you know, make a bunch of virus babies come out of them.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but it's like I use them the way the alien uses humans.
Speaker 1: basically Yeah But I you know at least that's actually preferable to say a virus going into human cells and replacing the nucleus with a virus.
Speaker 1: Turn I would turn into a giant mech suit for this virus My whole body I'll be much more terrifying.
Speaker 0: all I can think of also there are movies about that that old the Adventure Time short the muffin man where Bacteria in the end turned into a giant golem.
Speaker 0: and they're like we have a message from the tiny world.
Speaker 0: We can see you do number two.
Speaker 0: You are the number two All right in the better moment.
Speaker 0: As we've said many times geek nights is gonna sound weird for at least another two a month or so Probably.
Speaker 1: who knows how long?
Speaker 0: yep, cuz we are recording gig nights remotely via a discord and a bunch.
Speaker 1: Yes, when it's warm and biking season we could bike into the woods and record a geek night.
Speaker 0: Yep, or we could do a six feet of separation geek nights.
Speaker 1: We just stick with long-ass cables.
Speaker 0: We'll figure stuff out.
Speaker 0: We'll improve this pipeline.
Speaker 1: Neither of us are sick.
Speaker 0: So I think if we both safely escape here and wash our hands and go to a place Record a thing together the key is one of us has someone in their household who's still exposed to the outside world and one of us does not.
Speaker 0: Mmm, that's that's the only limiting factor right now, but for the foreseeable future We're doing geek nights remotely Which means one?
Speaker 0: We might talk over each other a little more than usual or there might be occasional awkward pause.
Speaker 1: I could have worn them with that when the episode started.
Speaker 1: Also.
Speaker 1: Do you notice how I just talked over you just now?
Speaker 0: - you might hear odd audio artifacts sometimes because I'm relying on a audio pipeline Scott put together on his own with Cheaper equipment than what I'm using here.
Speaker 0: It sounds pretty fine on our side, but I had one person complain But it was the person I expected to complain.
Speaker 0: No one else has complained.
Speaker 0: It was Luke.
Speaker 0: Yeah, of course but this also means we're not doing the YouTube live streams yet because The pipeline we've got is already a little bit delicate And if I try to live stream is on YouTube.
Speaker 0: that introduces another variable.
Speaker 0: by next week I think we'll start streaming these on YouTube again, but Hold your horses one step at a time Mmm, otherwise the book club book is supposed to be the tale of Genji, but have you read any tale again?
Speaker 0: Uh, I'm currently reading the tale of Kaiji.
Speaker 1: Oh very close same country Same country.
Speaker 0: It's uh, I'm not reading a lot right now because you think oh, we're locked inside all day.
Speaker 1: We'll read but the video game season.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: It is video game season.
Speaker 1: It is can't play video can't look at that good screen when you're you know on the subway, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I am now in like six online Multiplayer civilization games like I actually surrendered in one.
Speaker 1: So now I'm in one.
Speaker 0: You should join the one that does.
Speaker 0: culture just started.
Speaker 0: I guess it's too late.
Speaker 0: You missed it.
Speaker 0: good It's only four players on a tiny map and we're trying to only people who will take the turn.
Speaker 0: certain people were banned from this Game based on their performance in past games And also no one has been kicked out.
Speaker 0: So I think cloud play is now working fine in Civ 6 Which is a big step up from player damn turn for a lot of reasons Hmm.
Speaker 0: So yeah, it's pretty much video game season.
Speaker 0: The one thing I'll point out is that in lieu of maybe the book club and some other things for the short term Both Scott and myself are streaming a lot of games and playing a lot of the kind of stuff that we are not normally playing.
Speaker 1: I mean, I'm getting around to stuff.
Speaker 1: The thing is Every time I'm gonna go create something right which is like my plan.
Speaker 1: My plan is always make something which is of course a shit talk, right?
Speaker 1: I end up playing.
Speaker 0: I did do one of the things I said I do.
Speaker 0: You know My rule is if I say anything about it on this show during the moment Then I'm gonna force myself to do it no matter what.
Speaker 0: so despite the fact that there are no speakers in the computer room And there's almost no way to synchronize audio in a live stream for this purpose I live stream myself playing DDR for an hour and it totally worked.
Speaker 1: Okay, and fun with that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it was actually really fun.
Speaker 0: It was weird because I've actually never seen video of myself playing DDR before like ever.
Speaker 0: Oh, I've seen you play a lot of yeah I've seen you play a lot of DDR.
Speaker 0: never seen myself play a lot of DDR.
Speaker 0: That was an interesting thing to watch especially with.
Speaker 0: like a crazy song like so deeper max 300 doesn't look great.
Speaker 1: Let me tell you
Speaker 0: Well, you can tell cuz I'm usually smart
Speaker 1: if it's not exactly I can't
Speaker 0: like I'm smiling the whole time I'm just kind of dancing and kind of light on my feet But then in max 300 I am doing the opposite of smiling the whole time.
Speaker 0: I look Extremely concerned like I have this worried look on my face the whole time.
Speaker 1: That is correct.
Speaker 1: Yes That is an accurate description.
Speaker 0: Like if I have to be our face if I have to translate I basically I'm making a face that translates to oh shit.
Speaker 0: Oh shit.
Speaker 0: Oh shit the whole time.
Speaker 0: Pretty sure I look like that when I'm doing double black glade skiing as well.
Speaker 0: I'm also streaming the original xcom one.
Speaker 0: I'm just playing it through.
Speaker 0: no saves like.
Speaker 0: no safety saves.
Speaker 0: Just fucking good.
Speaker 0: if grenade comes into the sky Ranger into one mission.
Speaker 0: My whole team dies.
Speaker 0: Well, that sucks.
Speaker 0: Let's go Doing okay so far.
Speaker 0: I got two bases.
Speaker 0: I I Got a bunch of alien technology.
Speaker 0: I've actually captured an alien like.
Speaker 0: I'm doing well so far.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm not uh, you know doing some big-time streaming, but if people are out there Discord has a super super super easy feature that lets you stream it within the discord voice channel.
Speaker 1: It lets you stream one window of your computer.
Speaker 1: So it's so low effort compared to using OBS and doing a twitch or YouTube stream.
Speaker 1: That like every time I play a video game on my computer.
Speaker 1: I'm like I can click one button and stream this and I click it and like three listeners come because they're on the Geek night.
Speaker 1: semi-official somewhat blessed geek nights discord server.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so you should come to the discord server And if you see the little TV icon on the bottom right of the server, that means someone in there is streaming.
Speaker 1: I see other listeners streaming in there, too.
Speaker 1: So just hop on in and click on the appropriate voice channel and you can watch You know and and even talk to me unlike and if I was on Twitch you would have to chat and I would talk at You.
Speaker 1: yeah be weird, right?
Speaker 0: I feel like I should start streaming in there more because generally it's just OBS cuz I'm doing like a stream for everybody.
Speaker 0: But if it's like a low-effort stream where I'm not putting it like I'm just like in a stream, whatever I should go in there Right.
Speaker 1: It's.
Speaker 1: it's so low ever.
Speaker 1: It's not like to do the other OBS stream.
Speaker 1: I have to plan and set up right.
Speaker 1: Good Lord this it's like if I'm playing a game on my computer, I click the button.
Speaker 1: Why wouldn't I click the button?
Speaker 1: just grieving?
Speaker 0: DOSBox games that run full screen is via OBS is uh, I mean I did it like I didn't any problem doing it.
Speaker 0: But what a fucking nightmare it was to set that up, right?
Speaker 1: I'm telling you the discord is so easy.
Speaker 1: It's just like.
Speaker 0: it's also fun watching what my computer does cuz I can set my main 4k monitor to be 320 by 200 Resolution and my video card will totally do that and then it fucking does not know what to do with my other monitor.
Speaker 0: Yep, like my video card cannot reconcile having a 4k screen and a 320 by 240 Or whatever screen on at the same time.
Speaker 0: It's kind of funny to watch it struggle.
Speaker 0: Yep So yeah, we'll get right into it.
Speaker 0: It's tech news roundup.
Speaker 0: We won't linger too deep on any of these but this is just stuff that was in the news.
Speaker 0: We may have a lot to say we may not.
Speaker 0: it's just a pure list of nonsense.
Speaker 0: and we'll start with the least Interesting news because it was the first one on the list.
Speaker 1: At least you already preempted my.
Speaker 1: this is stupid news.
Speaker 1: who cares?
Speaker 0: This is why we don't think it's very uninteresting.
Speaker 0: This is why we often don't talk about raw tech news because very rarely do you care when like what.
Speaker 0: remember how excited I was When DRBD was added to the Linux kernel and how literally none of you gave a fuck about it.
Speaker 0: Well, yeah chromium edge is getting vertical tabs and a bunch of other features.
Speaker 0: I don't know who wants or likes vertical tabs.
Speaker 1: I also don't know who uses chromium edge.
Speaker 1: just use chrome.
Speaker 0: What's funny is in the enterprise world?
Speaker 0: People are still using Internet Explorer because their enterprises have not authorized the use of use of eggs.
Speaker 1: They're not even using regular edge.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they're using like the last Internet Explorer.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's amazing And I see bug tickets of people wanting that to be supported because in this day and age there are still banks that will not let anyone in their entire organization use a bread browser other than like IE9 or some shit.
Speaker 0: It's amazing.
Speaker 1: I don't even know what I use the last one But yeah, there hasn't been an IE in a long time.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I even then edge and I think edge is now dead to chromium edge, which is basically just Microsoft's version of Chrome.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's literally Chrome at this point.
Speaker 0: I use Chrome and Firefox kind of even Microsoft.
Speaker 1: stop using Internet Explorer, right?
Speaker 0: In some other news Whatever I mean you can hear enough about the virus like.
Speaker 0: we're not gonna talk about coronavirus.
Speaker 0: But there is there are people who are not just me and Scott and like Lawrence Lessig and nerds who care about this stuff Talking about a really important topic now the idea that we should treat broadband and the internet like a public utility.
Speaker 1: Like yeah, I mean that is a mainstream idea.
Speaker 1: now Yeah, I mean this is all these things.
Speaker 1: are you know obvious ideas that we've said for a long time, right?
Speaker 1: It's like when they made electricity and telephone into a utility in the US They said right you have to provide it to every single person in the country Even if they live in the sticks, you have to provide a certain level of service.
Speaker 1: Every phone call must get through Right.
Speaker 1: They said all these things.
Speaker 1: but meanwhile at the internet you've got people in the middle of nowhere You know who have no internet or have internet.
Speaker 1: that's too slow to do anything.
Speaker 1: And now they're stuck at home and they can't internet and it's that's a big problem.
Speaker 0: If they had no electricity schools are shut down so schools are supposed to try and do online remote learning.
Speaker 0: fine That's great.
Speaker 1: But I went at the school system has internet at home.
Speaker 0: Yeah, a lot of people don't have internet.
Speaker 1: school itself barely has internet.
Speaker 0: So none of that works.
Speaker 0: But everyone has electricity.
Speaker 0: most people have electricity at home and the people who don't have electricity?
Speaker 0: There are government programs to help them out.
Speaker 0: There are not a lot of good government programs to get everybody access to actual modern internet.
Speaker 0: It has to be fast.
Speaker 1: the FCC's efforts to convince Telecos to spread their internet to rural areas have been weak and subpar,
Speaker 0: but I think the virus now shows unequivocally that broadband high-speed internet access is as necessary as electricity and water and sewer systems in the modern era in a place like America and we really need to Treat it like a utility.
Speaker 0: I'm fine with there being private companies offering these services But there are.
Speaker 0: there has to be a like the post office if they're offering upgraded services, right?
Speaker 1: The thing is, you know telephone.
Speaker 1: there were only so many upgraded services.
Speaker 1: You could really get yep.
Speaker 1: It's like you make you make calls.
Speaker 1: What can you do?
Speaker 1: better audio quality electricity?
Speaker 1: more electricity, right?
Speaker 0: I feel like there's two ways to go either with internet.
Speaker 1: You can definitely have upgraded services.
Speaker 1: They can give you static IP addresses.
Speaker 1: They can give you more Redundancies.
Speaker 1: they can give you more bandwidth.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you lower latency.
Speaker 0: I feel like the way.
Speaker 0: Well, the ideal future would be other.
Speaker 0: we first we regulate the telcos much more heavily But beyond that we take the post office and we make them the government ISP and their mandate is they have to offer broadband Everywhere in the country and maybe you designate any.
Speaker 0: any place that has that can receive mail should be able to receive internet Yep, and maybe there are like special exceptions for extremely remote and isolated places with alternative service or whatever.
Speaker 0: But I don't care they've got to figure it out.
Speaker 0: That should be a public utility.
Speaker 0: That feels like something the post office should be in charge of yeah, but also just in general.
Speaker 1: I think the corona virus proves I mean it didn't need proving to us, but it gets needed proving to some other people that a lot of things Should be public utilities.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: I or I mean that aren't and you know What shouldn't be a public utility the cruise companies because they're not even registered in the u.s.
Speaker 0: We just let them all go bankrupt Fuck them.
Speaker 1: Yeah, basically, you know, it's like all the things, you know, even things you wouldn't think about right?
Speaker 1: That are things that we complain about that are problematic or bad or wrong or whatever As soon as there's any pressure on society in general.
Speaker 1: those things are like exposed.
Speaker 0: Yeah exposed.
Speaker 1: It's like hard It's like you ever see like this is kind of gross.
Speaker 1: But I learned this somewhat recently maybe months ago.
Speaker 1: that like if you have scar tissue and then like you sort of you know Fall into poor health like your body.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 0: See me.
Speaker 0: That's it.
Speaker 0: That's one of the primary symptoms of advanced scurvy, right?
Speaker 1: It's like your body is maintaining the scar tissue to keep your skin closed And if you somehow don't have enough nutrients or whatever the scars will just open up again.
Speaker 0: If you're very yeah If you read the prince of nothing in that second book of the first trilogy where there's like the dark magic and in the evil Plane like old wounds were reopening that wasn't magic.
Speaker 0: That was just scurvy Right.
Speaker 1: So it's the same kind of thing as for societies.
Speaker 1: when society has scurvy all these wounds It's like oh, you've got these shitty inefficiencies here We've got this corruption there and we're papering over it right with you know, our bullshit.
Speaker 1: Well like case in point sure injustice and then it's now this pressure.
Speaker 1: So all the bullshits gone It's like ah fuck
Speaker 0: Well, like look in a world where we don't need as many brick-and-mortar stores because we can order stuff online Which is what most people want like sure but we built that system in such a broken manner that the delivery workers Can't actually do their job during a crisis like this and are being exploited miserably.
Speaker 0: So Amazon and instacart which leaves my next news the workers are striking this week because they're not being protected They're being paid garbage and all of society relies on them now because he can't go to a brick-and-mortar store.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean I had never used instacart because that was always seemed like an evil uber ish business to me.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and even Amazon is also an evil business and I use him because I have to right.
Speaker 1: It's that comic with the peasant where he's like you also participate.
Speaker 1: Society you participate.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's me.
Speaker 1: But you know, I've been.
Speaker 1: I haven't been buying as you know much stuff and I'm definitely not buying anything now while there's a strike Go.
Speaker 0: but in a healthier more functioning society the people working in these places one would be making a living wage And two in a crisis like this could basically be given hazard pay and protection to continue to do that job.
Speaker 1: You know, I want to make a comment about hazard pay right because way back in the day.
Speaker 1: Right hazard people don't remember this because it was so long ago.
Speaker 1: Hazard pay was a thing and the deal with hazard pay was you got a job underwater welder.
Speaker 1: It's so dangerous oil rig worker oil rig workers.
Speaker 0: We're it like factory manager that we were gonna.
Speaker 1: we're gonna pay you extra money in order to Recompensate you for putting your life in danger, right and we eliminated hazard pay.
Speaker 1: Why did we eliminate hazard pay?
Speaker 1: because we eliminated hazard pay with OSHA?
Speaker 1: Which is the idea that no you shouldn't pay someone to put their life in danger.
Speaker 1: There should be a guarantee that your job must be safe.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there are all.
Speaker 0: there are exceptions for that.
Speaker 1: for like for example, obviously in the military There are obvious exceptions, but the point is we labor fought for a long time Right to get to replace a lot of hazard pay with the idea that no, we'll just guarantee job safety.
Speaker 1: Yep, right and now that you know, we had this coronavirus thing going on There's a crisis or simply cannot be guaranteed even in reasonable circumstances Right, but there's been this reversion to like, you know fighting for hazard pay.
Speaker 1: Well, I feel like you should be fighting for guaranteed workplace safe.
Speaker 0: well I feel like there should be two things going on because there is a Fundamental issue of if these jobs paid a living wage and society wasn't stretched to its absolute limits.
Speaker 0: We can have a more reasonable conversation about maybe there is a temporary hazard pay during a crisis like that kind of thing Just saying, you know the don't don't think.
Speaker 1: I just want people to recognize because hazard pay hasn't been a topic of discussion in a long Time right?
Speaker 1: I don't want people to just want to be able to realize that hazard pay is not as good as Guaranteed workplace safety, which is what you really want.
Speaker 0: The hazard pay is supposed like the concept of it is supposed to be for jobs that cannot be made safer Like what the first one Scott mentioned underwater welding.
Speaker 0: all the OSHA requirements in the world can't make that job safe.
Speaker 1: They make it as to make it simple, right you make it as safe as possible But you still pay the first.
Speaker 1: don't want a situation where someone just accepts.
Speaker 1: Okay, I'll play football with no helmet.
Speaker 1: How much paying me?
Speaker 0: All right, that's not except Look how hard it was to get hockey players to be forced to wear helmets.
Speaker 1: Right exactly and they didn't want to.
Speaker 0: they did not want to wear the helmets.
Speaker 0: Nobody forced them to and that one hazard pay.
Speaker 1: Hazard pay is a stopgap thing.
Speaker 1: It is not the goal, right?
Speaker 0: It should be a safe workplace.
Speaker 0: hazard pay is for Exceptional crazy jobs like underwater are a lot of.
Speaker 1: I'm seeing a lot of stories though out there where people are not taking measures That could be taken to make workplaces safer.
Speaker 0: Yeah But also and like in an emergency where you can't make it safer like these delivery workers in the short term that hazard pay Can't just be like here's an extra ten dollars an hour.
Speaker 0: It has to be like Life-changing money.
Speaker 0: don't risk your life.
Speaker 1: It has to be adequate compensation.
Speaker 1: Right the amount of hazard you're going into you need to be you know, correctly and justifiably compensated.
Speaker 1: if you know You just you're willing to do a dangerous job.
Speaker 1: That can't be made safer.
Speaker 1: if you're willing I have to go into the reactor and clean it.
Speaker 1: Well, I've been given all protection available.
Speaker 1: I'm only going in for two minutes because we figured out that's how long it's safe to go in there, right?
Speaker 1: It's as safe as it can be.
Speaker 1: I'm still probably gonna get cancer or some shit.
Speaker 0: No life endangering work without life-altering pay that's the slogan.
Speaker 0: a little too hard to say that in the picket line, but Mm-hmm, so not sure if this will be tech news or not yet, but Sony and companies like it have a long history of Conglomerating and D conglomerating and having business lines and all these sorts of nonsense.
Speaker 1: I mean Sony the same company makes cameras right makes televisions Makes Walkman, I guess somewhere makes intellectual property and then complains that the Walkmans and televisions Used a pirate.
Speaker 0: that I've been like record companies.
Speaker 1: they have Playstations they video game they make so much crazy shit.
Speaker 1: That's unrelated or related.
Speaker 0: Yep, but Sony in particular has always had this dual duality of on one hand.
Speaker 0: They made amazing technology for consumers in the space of media production and media consumption, but simultaneously they Make money from intellectual property that is directly threatened by that technology and they have never walked that line successfully ever no, so Currently it's all one big company with different divisions, but it looks like they're actually Splitting Sony electronics back into Sony electronics as a holding company.
Speaker 1: So they're It's still all in the same big umbrella like Google alphabet or whatever, right?
Speaker 1: It's not actually a separate company.
Speaker 1: You can't buy stock in Sony electronics own but and it has its own CEO and its own board.
Speaker 1: well, but internally now it should have its own management structure and Reorg on the inside with you know, some tech shenanigans or something.
Speaker 0: But also theoretically it would be more independent of the other parallel holding companies.
Speaker 0: the question for Technologists will be we don't have a lot to say because we don't know.
Speaker 0: this is pretty early news.
Speaker 0: Will this in the future lead to Sony electronics not worrying about intellectual property problems?
Speaker 1: I don't know about that.
Speaker 1: That's not gonna happen.
Speaker 0: or a potential split to not have this direct competition among itself.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean the question you could ask really is just is the management of it gonna be different?
Speaker 1: Yeah That it's being under a different or in like.
Speaker 0: I want to know who.
Speaker 1: the president of Sony electronics is Probably the same person it was before but is it gonna change because they're in a different position on the org chart?
Speaker 1: Right, but the answer to that is probably not because a Japanese company they do how they do.
Speaker 0: Yep, I guess the interest is never the good.
Speaker 0: to see if there's a technological impact of this would simply be because Sony makes great Hardware if the rest of the company doesn't interfere with it.
Speaker 0: So anyway, will they bring someone interesting it from the outside in to head this thing up?
Speaker 0: It doesn't look like we have any details yet.
Speaker 1: I don't think this is really a significant news.
Speaker 1: It's just a business news.
Speaker 0: So here's a fun one.
Speaker 0: Here's a real tech news.
Speaker 0: There's a bunch of SSDs.
Speaker 0: you Hewlett-Packard enterprise SSDs as far as I can.
Speaker 1: so are these the SSDs that are s ATA?
Speaker 1: or these the SSDs that are and you know M - these are says SSDs serially attached SCSI Solid so nothing anyone owns in their house.
Speaker 1: These are.
Speaker 1: no one listening to this has.
Speaker 0: one of these are things you're putting in.
Speaker 0: You're like saying or whatever.
Speaker 1: someone might have one of these at their job if they're at a tech worker.
Speaker 0: But the tech news is kind of amazing because I could foresee something like this happening on Consumer hardware as well because the possible.
Speaker 0: the problem is there's a firmware bug in these hard drives.
Speaker 0: Which for those of you who have hard drives at home?
Speaker 0: When was the last time you updated the firmware on your hard drives?
Speaker 0: It's there.
Speaker 1: You can go download updates like even for good CPU firmware updates and some of them come automatically with like Windows update But yeah, some of them don't.
Speaker 1: there's a lot of updates for things in your computer That you would only get if you went out and looked for them specifically and otherwise stuck with what your computer came with.
Speaker 1: the
Speaker 0: only people who care about firmware updates for like hard drives and shit are Nerds like us who want to make that last device in the Windows system manager show up with a real icon instead of just saying mystery device or because there's some specific thing we want to do with that technology or enterprise users who understand the danger of this crap, so Basically all these hard drives sometime in October will just brick themselves permanently
Speaker 1: Okay, and there's no way to unbrick them,
Speaker 0: I don't think so.
Speaker 0: unless and the data like the data cannot be recovered.
Speaker 0: It's just fucking dead to the world really.
Speaker 1: so even the chips the flash chips couldn't be like no taken off.
Speaker 0: You have got to update the firmware before this happens to you.
Speaker 0: you have 40,000 hours of runtime before it happens, okay, uh I. Well, I'm gonna bookmark this to remember in October to check and see if there are any major outages that are tied to this.
Speaker 1: Uh-huh how many how many.
Speaker 1: these hard drives could really be out there, and they're probably all in Nasus or so.
Speaker 0: yeah, but it's probably Nasus or sans probably sans.
Speaker 0: that might be driving virtualized infrastructure.
Speaker 0: I feel like a lot of the system administrators of application servers are Not actually working with the hardware itself and based on other things I've seen in the industry people who are managing the hardware itself are increasingly less capable because there's not as many jobs in that space.
Speaker 1: Well the major cloud providers aren't less capable.
Speaker 1: they're more capable because all the smart people are there yep But other places not so much.
Speaker 1: But I think that a lot of those places from what I've heard the storage at those large cloud providers is like constantly cycled.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's very unlikely that a drive would maybe even last that long to get to this point and in one of those places.
Speaker 1: Also, I think a lot of those the places that are super smart right are Mixing up their hard drive brands and models leaving me like this the net the giant NAS with five drives in it.
Speaker 0: I got up there.
Speaker 0: Three of the drives are the same serial number at the same time.
Speaker 1: the other two are same capacity drives same manufacturer different line Yep, and it's like that's just a general sort of good idea if you're serious business with storage is mix up the drives.
Speaker 1: Right you can't.
Speaker 1: you can't mix up your CPUs You've only got one.
Speaker 1: you can't mix up your RAM sticks because they need to match to get you know High speed?
Speaker 1: yeah, you can't really mix up.
Speaker 1: you would give you could.
Speaker 1: it's like yeah I would love to have a computer with two CPUs and one AMD and one Intel and if one fails the other one keeps.
Speaker 1: Amazing you can't do that right, but if you're in the cloud You know at a big place you can mix up the hard drives with different brands.
Speaker 1: you could get more multiple computers.
Speaker 1: So it's like okay.
Speaker 1: Let's not all buy the same CPU in every computer.
Speaker 1: this one has this can CPU this one Is that CPU?
Speaker 1: we'll put these RAM sticks in this one.
Speaker 1: these are different RAM sticks in the other one.
Speaker 1: So if some computers fail and some don't then you're alright.
Speaker 1: Yeah, your storage has multiple different drives.
Speaker 1: as some crash you replace them.
Speaker 1: you see oh all and then you can notice patterns.
Speaker 1: If you have such scale it's like huh all the all these hard drive.
Speaker 1: You look at your crashed hard drive pile.
Speaker 1: at the end of the day that you probably have every single day You keep tabs on which ones have higher rates of failure.
Speaker 1: You know which ones to order next time you go out to buy more drives.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so so we'll lightning round through the rest of these because I think we've gone on long enough.
Speaker 0: But you know lighting down to the rest quick comments or whatever one.
Speaker 0: Apple is now going to by default block all third-party cookies in Safari.
Speaker 1: I've been doing this for years.
Speaker 0: I've been doing it as a different except I've had to make exceptions for a lot of specific websites that just fail without a third.
Speaker 1: go to those websites.
Speaker 0: Yeah, some of the websites.
Speaker 0: I have to go to.
Speaker 1: Well, but I don't make third-party cookies on your website.
Speaker 0: the fun thing is whenever Apple does something like this whenever Apple makes something That was previously optional like this a default in Safari Usually almost every website other than like old fuddy-duddy government websites that no one knows how to update Tend to have to just bite the bullet and accommodate that.
Speaker 0: Because once that's the default on Apple a lot of people don't even know how to turn that off.
Speaker 1: and I mean forget People forget, you know I talked about in a recent thing of the day flash died because Apple killed it by saying no no flash an iPhone deal with it Yep up until then and then flash time then flash died.
Speaker 1: So this is one area where apps and now they do this third-party cookies will just die.
Speaker 1: now.
Speaker 0: Yeah Cuz any website that won't work without a third-party cookie won't work for anyone on an Apple computer and there's no way in hell.
Speaker 1: They don't care if it won't work for anyone with an Apple computer.
Speaker 1: It won't work for almost anyone using an iPhone iPhone iPad Right.
Speaker 1: That is what's gonna make it work.
Speaker 1: If they just did it on OS X that people would be like whatever.
Speaker 1: my website doesn't work in Safari.
Speaker 1: who gives a shit?
Speaker 1: Yeah, no one on OS X even using Safari.
Speaker 1: Yeah So people on iPhone and iOS They're definitely using Safari.
Speaker 0: This is a technology adjacent news.
Speaker 0: It's a very recent Supreme Court ruling but It has a weird implication Even though this is something that I guess we all should have known based on our knowledge of like constitutional law.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I still though I have to rim just told me about this before the show.
Speaker 1: I didn't hear about it before so I don't know all these details.
Speaker 1: So maybe some lawyer should chime in which we are not Yep.
Speaker 0: But basically there's a concept in American law that says you can't sue the federal government unless the federal government consents to being sued.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: It's pretty straightforward.
Speaker 1: It's like if I want to sue rim Right, I go to the government and I file the right paperwork and whatever at the courthouse and then somebody will serve rim.
Speaker 1: He'll get served right and he'll have to.
Speaker 1: he'll be get notified that I'm suing his ass, right rim can't say no I don't want you to sue me.
Speaker 1: But if you want to sue the government, I'll be like, hey government You fucked me over federal government, right?
Speaker 1: I want to sue you.
Speaker 1: the United States.
Speaker 1: You ever see those cases in the Supreme Court?
Speaker 1: was a United States verse so-and-so?
Speaker 1: yeah, all of those cases are.
Speaker 1: most of them are because somebody committed a federal crime and Federal government is prosecuting them with criminal case.
Speaker 1: but they're also times where it's United States versus so-and-so because so-and-so Sued the federal government and said that's wrong.
Speaker 1: You have to not do that.
Speaker 1: Whatever you're doing is bad and hurting me, right and The federal government said okay.
Speaker 1: We'll let you sue us.
Speaker 1: Let's go to court.
Speaker 1: They could have just said, you know what?
Speaker 1: Okay, it doesn't matter if we're doing wrong to you.
Speaker 1: We don't want you to sue us too bad We're not going to court.
Speaker 1: doesn't matter what face you file.
Speaker 0: this applies to the individual states as well.
Speaker 0: I'm not super clear on all the detail I didn't.
Speaker 0: that is new information to Scott if that is true There are a lot of things that sort of trickle down to the states But this is one.
Speaker 1: as far as I was aware if you sued the state of New York They could.
Speaker 1: I didn't know if they could say no or not.
Speaker 1: so they but I I previously would figure that that would depend on the New York State Constitution as best I can tell.
Speaker 0: they can say no and Basically where this is going.
Speaker 0: I'm not gonna try to summarize this whole thing But the Supreme Court case is about a photographer and videographer who spent like a decade Getting all this footage and photographs of the wreck of the Queen Anne's Revenge in North Carolina.
Speaker 1: Okay Duncan ship pretty cool.
Speaker 0: the state of North Carolina just took all a bunch of his stuff and started publishing it on their own.
Speaker 1: Were they using it for like their tourism promotion stuff?
Speaker 0: I don't even know what they were using it for.
Speaker 1: They did it for something they use it for.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't know but they published it.
Speaker 0: So we sued them saying hey, this is my footage.
Speaker 0: You can't just use it.
Speaker 1: That's right.
Speaker 1: If you're a photographer you take photos, that's your work.
Speaker 1: I asked you a ton of money to in time to make those photos.
Speaker 0: so when you sue the state without the state's Permission and there's a whole court case that went all the way up to Supreme Court about that and the Supreme Court came down Hard.
Speaker 1: the actual Supreme Court.
Speaker 0: Yep, Supreme Court of the United States Allen at all v. Cooper governor of North Carolina at all Alright, so what were the what?
Speaker 1: it was all just.
Speaker 1: it was a unanimous.
Speaker 0: It was decided on March 23rd.
Speaker 0: I don't know the unanimity or any of that yet.
Speaker 1: Well, I just said they came down hard.
Speaker 0: They didn't come down hard if it was five four I'm just reading the syllabus right now, but they came down hard in terms of the language.
Speaker 0: They basically like In general a federal court may not cure a suit brought by any person against a non-consenting state period.
Speaker 0: Yeah, of course, okay, but there's this whole thing where states can be sued directly if there's unequivocal Statutory language from Congress.
Speaker 0: basically like if there's a law that regulates something in a particular way like copyright law then like There's an exception to that rule.
Speaker 0: that I don't really understand.
Speaker 0: But basically the decision in this case seems to say that that does not apply.
Speaker 0: all the ways that have been argued To allow states to be sued for copyright don't fly at all.
Speaker 0: and This is not apparently new.
Speaker 0: new like.
Speaker 0: it's not a new President it's just a no.
Speaker 0: this president has never been applied in this manner in the realm of copyright in the sense that very few Copyright decisions or questions have actually been addressed by the Supreme Court.
Speaker 0: A lot of copyright law is never is still untested.
Speaker 0: like you
Speaker 1: This is as you say it is and there isn't some sort of thing that means that any state or the federal government Could commit blatant copyright infringement and that nobody could sue them for it Which means you couldn't stop them because copyright is a civil matter It's not a criminal matter
Speaker 0: yup,
Speaker 1: which means that for example If this is true as we understand it probably wrongly very wrongly The New York State as it is could create a Netflix.
Speaker 1: that is the New York State Netflix Provide it to all New York State residents, and it has every movie ever in it for free Including ones that are in the theater right now that were pirated with like a cam a shaky cam.
Speaker 0: Yep, that seems to be the case.
Speaker 0: I found a better summary cool even things from other countries And just every.
Speaker 1: you know the whole Library of Congress could just put every single thing in their entire archive up online for free.
Speaker 1: So the whole world.
Speaker 0: in essence the Supreme Court agreed with the Fourth Circuit Striking down the Copyright Remedy Clarification Act of 1990 this 30 year old amendment god that was 30 years ago.
Speaker 0: I've heard of the CRCA, but I didn't know what it did.
Speaker 0: I never heard of it because it read CRCA like CBD tPA and all those other things that I'd be vaguely pissed about.
Speaker 1: I heard I heard a CBD tPA, but that didn't go.
Speaker 0: so the 30 year old amendment to the Copyright Act of 1976 so in the night covered over 1976 was admitted in 1990 and It stripped states of their sovereign immunity where copyright was concerned.
Speaker 0: Aha, so that was settled until just now when the court the Supreme Court basically said yeah The CRCA fuck that states can do whatever the fuck they want fuck you.
Speaker 1: So there was also Congress passed a law that said states are not immune To copyright infringement suits, and then the Supreme Court said yes, they are.
Speaker 0: that seems to be the case.
Speaker 0: I'm sure a lawyer will correct some fiddly details there, but this opens up the door to what I like to call a Scott plan.
Speaker 0: We the one I just said yeah, New York State Netflix during the coronavirus crisis.
Speaker 0: Let's go all right.
Speaker 1: well Here's what you need to do.
Speaker 1: is you need to contact your state representatives your estate when you in New York We have assemblypersons, and we have senators right.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: you have in your state whatever state You're in.
Speaker 1: yeah, you know you're a common legislator.
Speaker 1: Right contact your state legislators you have them I just don't know what they are and then tell them about this and say hey Because this is the thing you should do.
Speaker 1: this and you need to present.
Speaker 1: frame your argument in terms of this will be Good for the state and a good usage of the state's money.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's how you need to frame it.
Speaker 1: So well not just I want free movies.
Speaker 0: I'm really curious to see what comes of this because this was news to me And I got to go back and actually read more about the CRC.
Speaker 1: does this mean that when Disney goes to the public school That's putting on The Lion King Play by the states that they cannot be sued?
Speaker 0: I see I have no idea like I barely understand how the federal stuff falls down to the states.
Speaker 1: I have no idea how this that's a real thing that happens all the fucking time Because I guess mean that a school can put on a showing of a movie that just came out in there in their Auditorium and charged for tickets.
Speaker 0: not a private school But what about a public school public score?
Speaker 0: what about a public library?
Speaker 0: That's run by the state.
Speaker 1: Well library is already do?
Speaker 0: they who libraries can't are having a lot of trouble with digital works these days.
Speaker 1: Yeah, this is interesting.
Speaker 0: Yeah, also.
Speaker 0: This isn't digital.
Speaker 0: This is anything the library Does this mean?
Speaker 1: now he hold on.
Speaker 1: does this mean that New York State could right?
Speaker 1: So we're just talking about like screening movies here right?
Speaker 1: no no no let's go.
Speaker 1: Let's go harder.
Speaker 1: the state hands out free copies of Microsoft Windows.
Speaker 0: Whoo that's just copyright right right?
Speaker 1: the state just hands out copies.
Speaker 1: I guess it's a cloud thing now, but they just hand out Adobe Creative Cloud licenses.
Speaker 1: I don't know now licenses.
Speaker 0: That's where they get you.
Speaker 1: I just say I'm just saying like you know could you just hand out Copyrighted things like hey the state is just printing DVD.
Speaker 1: I just need a copy of cool edit 2000.
Speaker 1: Yeah, just like you know Whatever.
Speaker 0: yeah, so I'm gonna read and learn more about this, and I'm sure the listener will tell us where we were wrong there.
Speaker 0: But who knows all right, and then briefly just going through the last little bit There's a story about how 5g uses more energy than 40 common sense.
Speaker 1: currently it uses a lot more though like It's a lot faster, and it's a lot more reliable.
Speaker 1: Yeah, how do you think you're getting that for free?
Speaker 0: No, so I think the last thing we're going to talk about is everyone has to video conference and work from home now in the US and around the world.
Speaker 0: yep, and There's definitely a divide between People who have a company that knows what they're doing that has some enterprise solution people who are at least tech savvy enough to know like The ways to share Presentations and video in a safe manner and then everybody else who's using zoom for some fucking reason don't use zoom.
Speaker 0: good guy Why is everyone using zoom?
Speaker 0: I never heard of zoom.
Speaker 1: I never heard of zoom But apparently it's just.
Speaker 1: you know people don't have access or don't have easy ways to video conference except FaceTime Which is people don't remember this.
Speaker 1: when FaceTime came out Apple said we're gonna make iMessage and FaceTime Open so that anyone can build on that platform.
Speaker 1: that never fucking happened right?
Speaker 1: I want to go find in the keynote where they announced FaceTime and cut that part out and be like hey if you did that That would have been pretty good.
Speaker 1: right now right because FaceTime is actually the best technologically speaking.
Speaker 1: Just only people with iPhones can use it.
Speaker 1: I guess.
Speaker 1: or Apple devices.
Speaker 1: So everyone else is like okay What are we gonna use right to do a video conference?
Speaker 1: the choices that are available are actually?
Speaker 1: Surprisingly few that meet the use cases of normal people.
Speaker 1: right Google Hangout?
Speaker 1: who has a Google Hangout setup?
Speaker 1: you'd have to have like an actual.
Speaker 1: you know Google meet.
Speaker 1: your company has to be using g-suite for that to work.
Speaker 0: Discord works really well But you have to set it up and then get everyone else to like make a discord.
Speaker 1: discord doesn't do a video chat between Everybody.
Speaker 1: it's just an audio chat.
Speaker 0: It's an audio chat and or a screen share, right?
Speaker 1: So if you want to do a screen share from one person in the chat
Speaker 0: Yeah,
Speaker 1: if you want to do a video chat where you can see everyone in the chat with a lot of people Right you can do an easy one-to-one with a lot of different solutions right?
Speaker 1: most of the video Conferencing solutions are made for like you're in an office room.
Speaker 1: the office room has a special thing set up And then someone else is the special thing or I have an app.
Speaker 1: the app connects to a system a proprietary system Doctor is using so I can chat with the doctor, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, there aren't.
Speaker 1: what else is there?
Speaker 1: That's like a whole bunch of people video chat together all at once almost nothing except for a stupid garbage zoom Which is being used because nothing else does what it does easily.
Speaker 0: that's available to everyone Yeah But also a lot of people are doing video chat where everyone's sharing video when that's not actually what they need.
Speaker 0: the use case you described.
Speaker 0: Yes, that's hard to do for most people and there is a need for that like trying to have your stand-up meetings with all your Engineers.
Speaker 0: you got a team of 10 like yep 10. video chat is great.
Speaker 0: I luckily where I work we have something that just works.
Speaker 0: global like it literally just works.
Speaker 0: It's so good Yes, but like not everyone has that but a lot of people are doing that when what they actually need is just sharing one screen And one person talking while everyone else listens and then possibly answers questions or passing the baton to someone else, right?
Speaker 1: So if you are doing the one video screen thing and not the I need to see everyone's face.
Speaker 1: We're all together.
Speaker 1: you can use discord like we just said because we're a nerd But you can also just use any.
Speaker 1: there's a variety of just search for webinar.
Speaker 1: There are several webinar systems out there any of which are pretty good easy to use and better than zoom.
Speaker 1: I just used a webinar the other day.
Speaker 1: my company had like at the global Company meeting right and so the way it worked is.
Speaker 1: there were five company executives You could see and you could see some slides they were showing.
Speaker 1: you couldn't see anyone else.
Speaker 1: Everyone else is just in the chat Yep and you could send global chat messages because they allowed it.
Speaker 1: they didn't have to and you could also send messages direct to them that Only they would see.
Speaker 1: to ask questions Yeah, and you could also ask questions in the company slack because company slack, right?
Speaker 0: But what's happening if it was?
Speaker 1: imagine a zoom with all the almost 500 employees in the company?
Speaker 1: That wouldn't have been too great.
Speaker 0: So the things that are happening out there that are sad and hilarious and all over the place are one.
Speaker 0: a lot of people are trying to use all the software right now, but Don't read the documentation and lack a basic understanding of anything related to computers.
Speaker 0: so shit's happening like the LA City Council was doing their meetings on zoom and People kept joining and playing porn and they didn't know how to stop that.
Speaker 0: so they had to shut the whole thing down.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they should use the webinar Yeah or on a zoom.
Speaker 0: a school was doing meetings and people are.
Speaker 0: people are just searching around.
Speaker 0: like a lot of these services will just Have URLs that you can access with no protection at all.
Speaker 1: Like only share the URL people keep I mean even you know, like the one little webinars I went to they were just URLs, but people and it's like reusing URLs they've already used.
Speaker 0: and now hackers and trolls are just finding URLs that have been published anywhere and just streaming porn to them.
Speaker 1: Right, it's you know, if you see your zoom URL gets, you know You send it say you're doing a webinar and you send the URL to all the viewers.
Speaker 1: Like I actually paid $20 for a webinar last week to learn some education.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right It was pretty it was pretty good cheap worth it, right?
Speaker 1: from a highly skilled individual and then Friggin I could have sent that link that I paid $20 for to like a hundred people.
Speaker 1: Yeah we didn't I wouldn't have had to pay.
Speaker 0: and also if you have a real use case like you're a city council or Like you run a company They're not pay for a real like enterprise to like buy something like they're not all great but like webex or go to meeting like there's services that just do this kind of stuff and Maybe you should have thought of this at some point in the past.
Speaker 0: Like what were you doing up to this point?
Speaker 1: They don't have.
Speaker 1: there's not enough IT people to go around.
Speaker 0: Yeah But even worse most of the people using zoom seem to be using it for one-on-one conversations But you're the like.
Speaker 0: there are a lot of ways to do that without zoom.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean, right It's like I'm saying zoom is garbage.
Speaker 1: Use it as little as possible.
Speaker 1: In fact zoom one of the only things that's available to anyone that does what I just said of having several people all talk Video at the same.
Speaker 0: but I have noticed the people who seem to keep sending me zoom invites are the same people who always try To get me to use what's app with them instead of anything more modern or good, right?
Speaker 1: If you need to do one-on-one Then you can just use like Skype or something.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I was actually not bad.
Speaker 1: or just on the Microsoft phone call You don't always need the video yeah, and if you both have.
Speaker 1: Seriously, if everyone you're talking to before you do this check to make sure is there anyone you're talking to you as an Android device?
Speaker 1: If not, you just use FaceTime.
Speaker 1: It's the best.
Speaker 0: the other thing people are like speaking.
Speaker 0: I've had to explain this to a few people lately.
Speaker 0: but most of these things that lets you video conference technically aren't allowed to be used by people under the age of 13 because of GDPR and or Child protect like child online copa stuff that is also technically creating.
Speaker 0: if you're a school You can't use any of this shit and that's why a lot of schools started doing remote learning and then suddenly shut down Because they can't actually have kids under 13 use these things.
Speaker 1: Yes, they need to make their own.
Speaker 1: They needs their separate school type systems the same way.
Speaker 1: I just said talk.
Speaker 0: Yes They're not willing to pay for that software.
Speaker 1: So the companies that make the soft schools won't have to pay for the software because they can't be sued for copyright.
Speaker 0: Yeah, bring it full circle And I think we can stop there.
Speaker 0: We'll continue to do the show remotely as long as we need to.
Speaker 0: we'll keep this content coming straight into your ears.
Speaker 0: the two Or three of you who are listening to this the listener.
Speaker 0: I Stole that joke from NPR.
Speaker 0: It's all politics.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I hope audition is still working.
Speaker 1: Oh it is.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I got my backup recording here on discord, which is what we are using.
Speaker 0: I'm actually sharing my browser with Scott in a discord while we do this.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 1: Are we good?
Speaker 0: I think we're good.
Speaker 0: Okay, see you guys on the flip side.
Speaker 0: This Has been geek nights with rim and Scott.
Speaker 0: special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 1: be sure to visit our website at front row.
Speaker 1: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 0: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audio.
Speaker 0: But unlike those other late shows it's actually recorded at night and the patreon patrons for this quarantacular episode of geek nights are Ellen Joyce, I can McNichol of Mardi Gras needs just like a dude guy chart option link eg.
Speaker 0: you hold the key to my heart.
Speaker 0: She said you're moving with your auntie and uncle didn't?
Speaker 0: Bel Air Clinton Walton.
Speaker 0: Jay Vance ran from New Zealand.
Speaker 0: Ryan parent drew open letter.
Speaker 0: Nicholas Brando Chris mink if thirst For hydrated Ganon dread Lily Tenebrae Chris Reimer Finn Sean Klein Thomas Han Sherman von Harl and a bunch of people who don't want me to say their name.
Speaker 0: We're getting better at this remote thing, but it's gonna take some time.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna tweak the pipeline a little more.
Speaker 0: over the weekend.
Speaker 0: I got new monitor speakers coming which will help but anyway now I leave you with Shit Sir.
Speaker 1: you're being stopped by an officer of the New York City Police Department Manhattan District.
Speaker 1: We're doing a hundred miles per hour in a 35 mile per hour zone, and I see your driver's license and registration, please Here you are.
Speaker 1: Thank you.
Speaker 1: Wait.
Speaker 1: Oh my god.
Speaker 1: You're Captain Jack.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah I'm so happy to see you my god.
Speaker 1: Thank you.
Speaker 1: Come over here Scott Happy to see you.
Speaker 1: Okay, my friends.
Speaker 1: Listen to you Listen to you have to autograph cards for your friends, and I have to use my race car cuz I'm late for show.
Speaker 0: So, can you please help me, you know, give me a hand, please.
Speaker 1: All right Okay, follow me and I'll give you an escort.
Speaker 1: Oh great now here.
Speaker 1: Here's one for your wife, too.