Speaker 1: It's Tuesday, November 3rd, 2020.
Speaker 1: I'm rim.
Speaker 1: I'm Scott and this is geek nights.
Speaker 1: tonight We are talking about among us Let's do this.
Speaker 1: So some relatively late-breaking news that we debated talking about on the show Partly because we don't have a second source on this.
Speaker 0: Yeah, this is reported by some tiny website running like WordPress.
Speaker 0: yeah,
Speaker 1: it was reported
Speaker 0: four days ago, and I only saw it just now on reddit and There's no like proof here, it's just someone writing a convincing story, I don't know what the deal is But if it's true, I guess it's You know worth talking about but I just have almost no confidence that this is true.
Speaker 1: Yep, so full disclosure.
Speaker 1: There's a single source that we do not recognize on this but the news They have broken is that Pac South has dates ready?
Speaker 1: Alternate dates replacing the original dates, but those dates are in late February so pushing the con out only a little bit.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so it's basically like that.
Speaker 0: what they're saying is that Pac South has moved already moved to late February And if for some reason it can't actually happen then they've got some backup dates, and they'll push it back again and again.
Speaker 0: But like it's basically that the actual news is they really want to have Pac South In 2021 and they're gonna try to actually have it and not cancel it.
Speaker 1: yep now you can read look at this article, but basically Even if Like 2021 like kovat gets better the trajectory is not looking good.
Speaker 1: I can't imagine any con happening safely until like August September at the earliest next year barring like Miracles.
Speaker 0: yeah, they're discussing the perhaps two lacks You know Guidelines in Texas you know basically making it legal for it to happen even though it may not be advisable.
Speaker 1: I can tell you I sure as hell ain't going about what thing I mean Blonde if there is a Pac South in February of next year there is zero chance that geek nights will attend this packs regardless of not a Things.
Speaker 1: they say we will.
Speaker 0: we will record a video of a panel that you can play in a room yep But there is no way and I would honestly at the start of which video.
Speaker 0: We will say everyone who's there.
Speaker 0: Why are you risking your lives to see us leave?
Speaker 1: Yeah, I would urge especially because this article talks about how and it seems to link to the Texas stuff.
Speaker 1: Texas has these ideas around like a certain capacity limit on large venues.
Speaker 1: that makes it safer.
Speaker 1: That is not safe.
Speaker 1: do not trust, Texas on this?
Speaker 1: nope Texas does not have a good track record in regard to kovat.
Speaker 1: if you're not paying You don't say I mean frankly.
Speaker 1: I'm already assuming.
Speaker 1: There's no packs East next year.
Speaker 1: So if there's no packs East there's definitely no pack South.
Speaker 1: if there is a pack South and no packs East and that's do solely to Texas having Dangerous and lax safety rules, then that's just egregious and frankly penny arcade to shut the whole thing down.
Speaker 1: They shouldn't allow the tax out to proceed like contracts.
Speaker 1: be damned Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: because let's be real.
Speaker 1: best-case scenario There is a vaccine by the end of 2020 until a huge percentage of the population has it.
Speaker 0: that doesn't seem like that seems.
Speaker 0: that seems an unrealistic.
Speaker 1: if unrealistic scenario then My very difficult lift on top of that already unrealistic scenario.
Speaker 1: So either This will be announced officially in the coming weeks, and then we're going to talk about how GNN has some fucking sources Just or just has local, Texas source.
Speaker 1: There's something up with GNN and we'll talk about that.
Speaker 0: and if this is not or anyone would be with basic journalism could have found This out, but they but no one bothered because it's not.
Speaker 1: that could be true because one thing there aren't a lot of journalists on the will pack South happen beat we Don't do a lot of investigative journalism We never really have but we do even less now than we used to like a decade ago.
Speaker 1: but The last time this was a topic that got seriously talked about was when people were trying to figure out the dates of things like Paxis to get hotel rooms and Investigative journalism did in fact uncover like a decade's worth of paxi states that have been a hundred percent legit up to this point.
Speaker 1: So you're right.
Speaker 1: It could just be that.
Speaker 1: No one thought to look at this.
Speaker 1: cuz packs South hotels Don't sell out like they never sell out.
Speaker 0: Yeah I mean a lot of the time.
Speaker 0: the word investigative journalism simply means there's a question that a lot of people want to know the answer to.
Speaker 0: And it's not just.
Speaker 0: the answer isn't just out there and Somebody went through the hassle of actually calling someone on the phone who knows the answer and told everyone else the answer Like one year man, like three or four mag fests ago.
Speaker 1: I remember I figured out the dates by calling a bunch of hotels and Asking about the mag fest room block acting like I was some business person and they would.
Speaker 1: they transferred me to someone.
Speaker 0: Well, that's not journalism.
Speaker 1: That's In the service of journalism, but I will full disclosure.
Speaker 1: I booked my hotel for that mag fest before I broke that news.
Speaker 0: Sure, that's only.
Speaker 0: that's just common sense.
Speaker 1: Yeah so yeah, we'll see how this goes, but There's no way packed south is happening next year Because if they push it out until the later half of the year it overlaps with other paxis and I just feel like that doesn't.
Speaker 0: The point is if this turns out to be true you should add this tiny tiny website geek news now to your follows because almost no one follows it which makes me not trust it, but if Fewer Twitter followers than that Ozzy Mandy's account I stopped updating.
Speaker 0: if it turns out to not be true You should block this account and this website so, you know not to accidentally read the fake news that's on it.
Speaker 1: Yep, so we'll see.
Speaker 1: If any of you are watching a live stream you got to see us do.
Speaker 1: our editorial decision on whether or not we're even gonna talk about this.
Speaker 0: I Mean we provided the context that this is, you know, some bullshit website says this.
Speaker 1: Yep So in some other news that is more normal news.
Speaker 1: If you've been watching twitch, I assume you're on Microblock.
Speaker 1: are you block as a lot of people refer to it.
Speaker 1: ad blocker because you don't want to see ads origin.
Speaker 1: Yeah origin other things called you block are not necessarily says you block and you block origin.
Speaker 0: You only use you black origin.
Speaker 0: do not use regular old you block.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we've talked on Monday episodes about how Untrusted ad blockers are actually very dangerous to you due to the nature of what you do.
Speaker 1: They see everything you're looking at.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you can trust me you block origin because it's all open source and everyone's looking at it all the time.
Speaker 0: But basically you have to be very careful if you add extra filters to it that are written by untrusted sources Because you know make sure that you trust those right before you go messing around.
Speaker 1: Yep, so if you now I don't actually watch a lot of twitch these days I've realized I was thinking about why I didn't notice this till I saw the news and heard you complaining about it.
Speaker 1: I pretty much watch VODs after the fact on YouTube where I don't see ads anyway, but Twitch ads are terrifyingly annoying but ad blockers block those ads.
Speaker 1: Twitch is not only Attacking the ad blockers to force ads through but the ads they're forcing through are basically PSA like they're trying to specifically?
Speaker 0: That's not exactly what is it?
Speaker 1: They're trying to.
Speaker 1: they're running the ads more often according to this article.
Speaker 1: then normal ads roll.
Speaker 0: No, so here's what happened first, right?
Speaker 0: Twitch was doing an experiment with mid roll ads which is the worst thing in the universe.
Speaker 0: because Right a man, you know, if you're watching say like live sports or something and there's a this ads There's a lot of them, but they stopped playing the sport to run the ad.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if you're watching a stream and like I just an ad is played by twitch and is not instant Initiated by the streamer that you're just missing what's happening.
Speaker 0: You're just missing the action and then it comes back and you missed a minute of whatever was happening or to who knows what.
Speaker 0: that's awful.
Speaker 0: They stopped doing that They Have.
Speaker 0: what they have been doing is just fighting with ad blockers, right?
Speaker 0: So there are pre-roll ads on twitch.
Speaker 0: if you're not subscribed to a channel and you're not paying for twitch turbo Which is nine bucks a month You see pre-roll ads.
Speaker 0: so you go to a stream and an ad will play and then the ad will be done.
Speaker 0: And then if you see ads after that the only ads you will see after that are ads that are part of the stream itself because the streamer is Showing ads through OBS or the streamer has pressed a button to tell twitch to play an ad to make them some money, right?
Speaker 0: So what happened was recent, you know, there have been a few times, you know Once like a couple months ago where it's like hey, I got you block origin, but I'm seeing the pre-roll ad.
Speaker 0: what the hell.
Speaker 0: so You?
Speaker 0: what you do when that happens is you can wait for an update and just deal with it Or you can go to the you block origin reddit where people are like, hey Here's the rule that you can add to your Steps to remove the ad.
Speaker 0: so we did those steps and it worked.
Speaker 0: and then just like last week There was another situation ads are back and everyone panics.
Speaker 0: So it's like alright do these steps.
Speaker 0: And we did those steps.
Speaker 0: and what was happening was first We did those steps removed the pre-roll ad but then mid-roll ads started to play, right?
Speaker 0: Which we thought twitch had stopped doing.
Speaker 0: right because it was just like an experiment that failed.
Speaker 1: I mean mineral ads are definitely coming everywhere because ad revenue is not doing well And people are desperate to milk that ad money before the whole bubble collapses, right?
Speaker 0: So there was so technological battle between the people trying to make an you block origin rule to stop that the ads and twitch itself.
Speaker 0: so the current state of things is that if you Go and you you set the best the best thing that they have managed to build to fight twitch ads is Some code that will stop the pre-roll ad entirely.
Speaker 0: However, what will happen is every 15 20 minutes or so.
Speaker 1: 10 to 20 minutes is what people have researched by studying it.
Speaker 0: right twitch will display.
Speaker 0: It's not an ad it's this still image with text that says it.
Speaker 0: basically they've detected sort of like cheating detection in a video game.
Speaker 0: They've detected that you've messed with the JavaScript on twitch itself And they stop.
Speaker 0: they.
Speaker 0: basically you don't see the stream.
Speaker 0: you see this purple page with white text in the video area for like You know 30 seconds to a minute, you know The amount of time a mid-roll ad would take.
Speaker 0: and it's like saying hey you've you know got software or something.
Speaker 0: That's you know, I can read the exact message, but whatever.
Speaker 0: but it basically says hey You've done something to mess with the performance of Twitter.
Speaker 1: Thanks for watching.
Speaker 1: You may be using a third-party tool or browser extension that is impacting site performance.
Speaker 1: for the best twitch experience head over to Twitch.tv to support the stream.
Speaker 0: right exactly.
Speaker 0: So they've detected that you're doing some shady biz And they're annoying you to make you stop using adblock, right?
Speaker 0: So, I mean if you go to twitch normally you're gonna see a pre-roll ad and then you're not gonna see anything after that.
Speaker 0: That's just right.
Speaker 0: So but if you try to block the pre-roll ad you're gonna get this bullshit.
Speaker 0: So what the tool that's been developed that that's the best we can do.
Speaker 0: as of this recording Blocks the pre-roll ad and then detects when the purple thing appears and auto reloads the page or cuz Just or you can just press ctrl R. So you're gonna.
Speaker 0: if that if you have this set up You're gonna miss like one or two seconds of the stream.
Speaker 0: basically how long it takes you to press ctrl R.
Speaker 1: So here's here's a sort of very interesting point at least for me.
Speaker 1: in my experience and my just preference.
Speaker 1: if the choice was see any ad at any point or See a non ad screen that just blocks me for a while every now and then I'd rather see the non ad screen like when I watch up here, but you give me what we don't want to.
Speaker 0: we don't want to write.
Speaker 0: But the problem with the non ad screen is not that it's an ad it's not.
Speaker 0: you're missing the stream.
Speaker 0: So the other thing that people have done is there are various sites out there you can use which Rather than watching the thing on twitch you actually because you can embed a twitch stream in another site.
Speaker 0: Right, so if you watch an embed the embed doesn't have ads it's an embed.
Speaker 0: The problem is if you're watching an embed Then you lose out on all the other twitch stuff.
Speaker 0: You're not in the twitch chat.
Speaker 0: You're not you know, you can't Sub you can't?
Speaker 0: you know?
Speaker 0: if there's maybe like a crowd control thing going on You can't do that right because you're.
Speaker 0: you're just watching the video itself embedded on another website But you won't see the ad the pre-roll or the mid-roll or any kind of ads ever and you don't even need a block now.
Speaker 1: I think we're burying the lead here though, because I think the the real story is that Twitch suddenly got aggressive against ad blocking.
Speaker 1: We're pretty early.
Speaker 0: That is Actually going on YouTube's.
Speaker 0: we had block which is now battling.
Speaker 0: twitch is battling with with the ad.
Speaker 1: That is not a good sign for twitches.
Speaker 1: financial security.
Speaker 0: There is a war going on between twitch and ad blocking.
Speaker 1: Yeah, someone like a chief revenue officer someone in twitch is either nervous about their revenue numbers nervous about ad trends.
Speaker 1: there's some fiscal reason why twitch is doing this because this kills goodwill with users of twitch with fans of twitch and It doesn't make that much more money.
Speaker 0: Yeah, basically, you know if you think about it, right?
Speaker 0: You know twitch wants to make money also from things like subs, right?
Speaker 0: It's like well You know, it's like usually.
Speaker 0: it's like hey I get my free prime sub right and maybe I'll sub someone if I watch them a lot.
Speaker 0: But also there's people who gift subs, right?
Speaker 0: So yeah, basically if you force ads and that's the only way other than not buying twitch turbo.
Speaker 0: You can fuck that nonsense.
Speaker 1: So I mean, I've already migrated to watching VODs on YouTube where I don't see ads anyway, right exactly.
Speaker 0: So If you're gonna do that, it's like well, I guess I'm only gonna watch twitch channels I'm subscribed to.
Speaker 0: right.
Speaker 0: if I can't if I know ad block mechanism will work, which means I'm gonna watch less twitch I'll probably stop subscribing and stop watching twitch altogether.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right and now you're losing that actual Five to ten dollars a month.
Speaker 0: for that's you know, I guess some of it's going just the streamers most of it.
Speaker 0: Oh, I don't know.
Speaker 1: I'd actually don't know what the split is on the five dreamers get at least as of the journalism on the verge right now in this article from today.
Speaker 1: they get 350 three dollars and fifty cents per thousand 350 for the streamer and 150 for twitch.
Speaker 0: when you find you spend five on a sub.
Speaker 1: No, this is per ad view.
Speaker 1: The ad view money is 350 per.
Speaker 0: They do not spend five dollars on a sub.
Speaker 0: how much goes to the streamer versus twitch?
Speaker 1: Yeah, they don't list they don't get.
Speaker 0: the streamer doesn't get all five dollars?
Speaker 1: Yeah, of course not because twitch has got to make money and which is sole way to make money.
Speaker 1: is all this nonsense?
Speaker 0: But that's gonna make me watch twitch less which is gonna make right.
Speaker 0: it's like well if I'm not watching or from blocking ads You're actually making less money here because you have this other revenue stream.
Speaker 1: Yeah It's just fascinating because like if this was geek nights Monday what we'd stress time and time again Is that blocking ads is an info information security issue?
Speaker 1: Never look at an ad on a device of any kind because ads are the primary vector of malware Mm-hmm reform out.
Speaker 1: It's a way bed.
Speaker 1: Like you should never let ads on block all head everywhere.
Speaker 0: always There is no circumstance in which you should see an ad that you could have blocked.
Speaker 1: Yep And it's interesting because the moral and ethical discussion around that would be that Some people who block ads or who have ads blocked for them.
Speaker 1: A good example is a lot of very old people are sort of tricked by advertising and buy things they wouldn't have already all otherwise bought and Shouldn't have bought.
Speaker 1: like that's one Avenue And the other Avenue is I'm never gonna buy anything from an ad.
Speaker 1: don't show me an ad.
Speaker 1: if you show No, if the ad makes it to me, you've ripped off the advertiser.
Speaker 1: if the ad doesn't make it to me You've only ripped off the platform.
Speaker 0: There's a lot of times where I'll see.
Speaker 0: you know I'll be forced to see an ad somehow and even it there.
Speaker 0: even cases where I'm forced to see an ad and I think oh That's actually something I might have bought but you know what because I saw it in an ad fuck you I'm not buying it at a site.
Speaker 1: I have a negative perception of something.
Speaker 1: I said if an ad it's not if I see an ad like on the street as much.
Speaker 1: but if an ad makes it Through my carefully curated ad blocking ecosystem.
Speaker 1: That means they're trying to annoy me and I'm done with them.
Speaker 0: Yep, I saw like.
Speaker 0: I saw an ad for like Like a cast-iron that was that looked as good as the the cruise it won But was cheaper.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and I was like.
Speaker 0: I was like, ooh that the ad makes it look good.
Speaker 0: But I was like, you know what?
Speaker 0: Hell no You bought an ad and I couldn't block it.
Speaker 0: go fuck yourself.
Speaker 1: so keep an eye on twitch and like how well they're doing financially over the next six months.
Speaker 1: because this is a Doing fine because Amazon Amazon Amazon just props it up exactly and that's the question of how long will Amazon prop it up.
Speaker 1: What not?
Speaker 0: maybe anti-trust mixer mixer went down.
Speaker 1: So yeah, it's really just tracing YouTube.
Speaker 0: You know how Facebook gaming isn't doing anything right shreds.
Speaker 1: you say Yeah Well, how's the friend Facebook doing?
Speaker 1: the shreds you send?
Speaker 1: All right, really briefly just a quick geeky bite.
Speaker 1: We'll review this game someday in the future when we're desperate for a Tuesday show.
Speaker 1: But you know, we play those train games.
Speaker 1: We reviewed a bunch of them.
Speaker 1: we just played our first game of 18 mechs, which is the railways of Mexico and it's super fun and Very different in some regards from all the train games.
Speaker 1: We have played up to this point.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we've played a lot of train games they've had you know this they all have, you know the base similarities But this one had a couple of mechanics that were not present.
Speaker 0: in the other ones You played.
Speaker 0: so like rule you look at the rule book and it's pretty much like yeah play train game.
Speaker 0: Here's a couple differences, but those couple differences had a large impact on play.
Speaker 0: So there's quite a bit to talk about with them.
Speaker 0: There's a. there's a big company merger.
Speaker 0: There's mail money that everyone gets automatically.
Speaker 0: the the villages are free.
Speaker 1: on your train route, you know There's no big diesel that has an unlimited route.
Speaker 1: instead You have a weird diesel that goes to fewer stations than the sixth train.
Speaker 0: But double revenue from those like a luxury short-range train is the best train you can get.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yep So anyway, it's a. it's a different train game from what we've played.
Speaker 1: And what I would say is that if you have played any of the 18xx games We've talked about and you liked them, but you want something that's very different from what you've played up to this point.
Speaker 1: I think 18mex is the one you dive into right now because it's the most different from the ones we have already reviewed on geek nights.
Speaker 0: Yeah that we've played.
Speaker 1: Yep And but I would definitely not play this one first if you have not played at least 1889 or 1846 This you would.
Speaker 1: there's trouble in this one If you haven't played another train game before and you also won't appreciate the things that are weird.
Speaker 1: Like if you play this one and go to those other games You'll actually put yourself in a weird position and probably be worse at train games, I think Yeah, that's really what I have to say about it.
Speaker 1: But the reason I bring it up is that we're all stuck at home because of COVID and 18mex is implemented on 18xx.games.
Speaker 1: You can play it legit online with your friends.
Speaker 1: They synchronously.
Speaker 0: it just works Mm-hmm, and I will teach you how to play train games for free.
Speaker 0: if you want to know how to play train games He's done it.
Speaker 1: They're the listener.
Speaker 1: Well, one of the listener has played a few games with us and it's been a fun time.
Speaker 0: Yeah So I guess other minor geek bite because it's way too much to discuss.
Speaker 0: I'm just gonna try to summarize it quickly.
Speaker 0: But you know Resident Evil has been like this major game series, right and I've never thought of myself as like.
Speaker 0: oh man I love Resident Evil.
Speaker 0: I'm a big Resident Evil fan, but you know what?
Speaker 0: I played Resident Evil 4 on the GameCube, right and then I just I think I played five like in one shot.
Speaker 1: at some point I feel like I watched you play most of four.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't know.
Speaker 0: and then I think I played six and seven Like.
Speaker 0: I just played them and forgot about them like but I did beat them, right?
Speaker 0: And I had played one but I never beat one.
Speaker 0: So recently since there's all kinds of cheapness on Steam and two and three got remade, right?
Speaker 0: I basically have every Resident Evil game on Steam.
Speaker 0: now every single one the whole thing.
Speaker 0: So I went and I actually beat one And I've been streaming these on the geek nights discord that you should come.
Speaker 0: Yeah to come see.
Speaker 0: and then I just beat two And now I'm playing three and I'm quite a bit of ways into three.
Speaker 0: So there's a lot to say about them, right?
Speaker 0: I'm only playing the remade ones.
Speaker 1: I think the most stellar review of them is the fact that you are actually playing remakes of these old games.
Speaker 0: I feel like if I remake makes the old ones are so janky.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they're basically unplay it.
Speaker 0: Like Resident Evil 2 the original PlayStation game had like tank controls like like friggin You know twin stick, right?
Speaker 0: It's like, you know, this one actually newer ones there.
Speaker 1: Yes Yes I know a lot of us Ludo types like game people like to talk about how those tank controls are actually a disempowerment fantasy as opposed to an empowerment fantasy Etc, etc.
Speaker 1: at the same time that disempowerment was largely a product of the technology at its time And there are intentional ways to do that better with modern technology.
Speaker 0: point is you know Playing them.
Speaker 0: I'm not like, you know, I'm basically like sort of like.
Speaker 0: my play style is like rush through them on normal mode Right, you're not.
Speaker 1: you're not like looking for every fiddly little thing and like full.
Speaker 0: I mean, I liked I collect all the ammo and the health and I try to open up all this stuff, you know.
Speaker 0: But it's like Resident Evil 2.
Speaker 0: I missed a lot of stuff.
Speaker 0: and also these games.
Speaker 0: they give you like two characters.
Speaker 0: You're supposed to play it with one character then play it with the other character.
Speaker 0: No, no, I play it with one character and then I watch the other characters differences on YouTube, right?
Speaker 0: It's like I'm not playing the game twice.
Speaker 1: Yeah These games of the ones I've played they're not like a quest for glory where like the three different characters are radically different experiences.
Speaker 0: Some of them they are kind of different but they're not worth at least for me to play an entire game again, right?
Speaker 0: Largely solving, you know the same puzzles fighting the same zombies, right?
Speaker 0: They have.
Speaker 0: they think they have different boss fights and different cutscenes and stuff like that.
Speaker 1: But Oh cutscenes and yeah cutscenes is watch on YouTube.
Speaker 0: Yeah But yeah, Resident Evil's a thing I'll probably talk about more after I play.
Speaker 0: You know I'm gonna beat three and then I'll see if I go and play.
Speaker 0: I haven't played for since the GameCube So maybe I'll keep going for I got to catch up to you.
Speaker 1: I gotta start playing these two if I ever have some free time.
Speaker 0: Yeah I mean You know the.
Speaker 0: the summary really about Resident Evil is what is Resident Evil?
Speaker 0: at least one two and three Four is suddenly like a different kind of game slightly But one two and three is just a combination of the point-and-click adventure game with the puzzling Puzzles in quotes like LucasArts.
Speaker 1: Right find the rooster by to put it into the rooster shaped keyhole that kind of thing exactly.
Speaker 0: It's that game combined with third person shooting Combined with your inventory is really scarce.
Speaker 0: You have hardly any bullets.
Speaker 0: Don't use them all don't use all your health because you'll run out.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right.
Speaker 0: You barely have anything.
Speaker 1: That's the survival horror like disempowerment fantasy, right?
Speaker 0: It's like you have like 20 bullets, right?
Speaker 0: So it's like you can't just go mow down all the zombies They're just gonna get back up anyway.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so use use your stuff sparingly and carefully and on the harder modes We're gonna give you even less shit to use.
Speaker 0: right.
Speaker 0: and it's those things combined, right?
Speaker 0: And so that comp that exact combination.
Speaker 0: I don't think all those elements existed well before Resident Evil 1 but that exact combination did not exist.
Speaker 0: So and it still there's not a lot of other games still today that use that exact combination.
Speaker 1: but anyway things of the day.
Speaker 1: so check this out, this is a soccer game or football depending on where you're from.
Speaker 1: and Basically, they've got an AI Camera person.
Speaker 1: like they didn't hire a camera person.
Speaker 1: The camera has some machine learning algorithm and identifies where the ball is and it like follows the ball.
Speaker 1: Kind of like if you had a thing that just automatically followed the puck or followed like whatever the action was in a sport.
Speaker 1: Alright get rid of a person you have to pay.
Speaker 1: the AI might do a better job except one of the linesmen is bald and That linesman head is very shiny and the camera keeps thinking his head is the ball.
Speaker 0: So you let soccer balls have black.
Speaker 1: You know hexagon but from this distance from as far away as it is and also it's a gets a good camera system.
Speaker 1: but like.
Speaker 1: it's the difference between like the NHL versus like the KHL in terms of like how well they Like actually have like what level of camera and fidelity and lighting and everything.
Speaker 0: KHL is legit pro league it is.
Speaker 1: but what camera are they using compared to what the NHL is using in their arena?
Speaker 1: like the actual camera lens sensor that kind of kit.
Speaker 1: So to the camera the the ball is a whitish shiny Circular thing moving around and this guy's head It's also a whitish shiny circular thing because the reflection on his head is so strong.
Speaker 1: The Sun is like coming right down at him in this perfect You know some block on his head.
Speaker 1: I hope he does.
Speaker 1: I guess eventually we're turned red and the camera would realize it wasn't a ball.
Speaker 1: but it's so funny because if you don't know it's an AI.
Speaker 1: you're watching this game and the camera just will like Turn away and start zooming in on this guy for no reason and then suddenly go Oh shit and go back to the game and then it'll keep drifting back over to this guy Like the cameraman is obsessed with this guy for some reason.
Speaker 1: So if you don't know it's an AI it's actually funnier to watch.
Speaker 1: But If you haven't listen to a geek nights Monday, this is exactly the kind of danger We were talking about with facial recognition machine learning.
Speaker 0: So we got So on this website XO das dot the - I Ey e dot us the ultimate XO das, right?
Speaker 0: I could just read the description.
Speaker 0: It says everything that's going on here, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, XO das is an attempt to catalog obtain and make playable every game developed for the DOS and PC booter platform Striving to find original media rather than scene rips, right?
Speaker 0: This collection?
Speaker 0: use a combination of DOS box and scum VM to play those games.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's what everyone uses the blah blah blah.
Speaker 0: this pack includes 7000 DOS games.
Speaker 1: fantasy empires is in there.
Speaker 0: The focus is on games that were either released in English or are fairly easy to play without a knowledge of the native language.
Speaker 0: This is not every DOS game ever made However, it is a very high percentage of all commercial releases.
Speaker 0: There are thousands of freeware homebrew and share.
Speaker 0: where our games that will continue to be added in future packs.
Speaker 0: Explore the release.
Speaker 0: XO das.
Speaker 0: Let's see fan a game.
Speaker 1: There are a lot of gay I start naming.
Speaker 0: start naming some games room.
Speaker 1: I mean fantasy empires is the one.
Speaker 0: All right, I'm waiting for it to load.
Speaker 1: It's yeah, I'm literally looking at the same thing.
Speaker 1: It's loading slowly.
Speaker 1: But yeah You can get these games to work with DOS box and fuckery.
Speaker 1: but Making it easy and accessible like this like putting it in the Empire is 1993 dot zip.
Speaker 1: Oh my god I'm gonna stream some fucking fantasy empires.
Speaker 0: Oh my god something else.
Speaker 0: name something else.
Speaker 1: Oh a raptor.
Speaker 1: call of the shadows.
Speaker 1: one must fall 20.
Speaker 0: That's Roger call.
Speaker 0: the shadows is absolutely there.
Speaker 1: It's it's there.
Speaker 1: I found it.
Speaker 0: What else he got?
Speaker 0: 20 odd?
Speaker 1: Kind of think of DOS games that I liked.
Speaker 1: other that I don't already have like tie fighter.
Speaker 1: I'm just oh my god.
Speaker 1: There are some.
Speaker 1: I haven't heard a half of these The seven thousand DOS games.
Speaker 0: You've definitely not heard of the vast majority of them.
Speaker 0: Yep the point is We back.
Speaker 1: This is our jam, you know, it's not there.
Speaker 1: it is one most all 20 97, you know, I never owned that game.
Speaker 0: There's 1991 does it whoo.
Speaker 1: Well, we'll have to see if it comes with the triple tank if anyone paid.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't know if this can if these are just the share wares and freewares or if they're the full games.
Speaker 1: But this is kind of a big deal for the same reason that nesticle.
Speaker 0: download this while you still can.
Speaker 0: They're like.
Speaker 1: nesticle was one of the first.
Speaker 1: yeah get this torrent.
Speaker 1: like stat nesticle was one of the first NES emulators that for a layperson kind of just worked and that really like opened up People being able to explore the NES library in an era when it wasn't super accessible.
Speaker 1: so this is actually a huge victory for game preservation and just for like the experience like how many young people might like the young nerd can just Take this hit a button and play some ancient DOS game.
Speaker 1: None of those people are gonna fuck around with DOS box to make that shit work Like I did.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and this torrent is five hundred and twenty seven gigabytes.
Speaker 1: That ain't bad.
Speaker 1: That's not that big.
Speaker 1: I'm pretty excited.
Speaker 0: It's not that big.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's it's big but I've downloaded bigger torrents in recent memory.
Speaker 1: The store is gonna get downloading ASAP.
Speaker 0: for me, okay good.
Speaker 1: Well you download it then you download it too and I'll seed you.
Speaker 1: Okay In the moment, there's only one meta if you're watching the live stream Are you haven't voted yet and you live in America and you're an adult running out of time?
Speaker 1: Yeah, like go fuck like.
Speaker 1: turn this off right now and go vote like this is it.
Speaker 1: There's no second chances.
Speaker 0: I highly doubt there's anyone listening or watching this live.
Speaker 0: who?
Speaker 0: Has the illegal ability to vote in the United States of America and has not done so yet?
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'll say if you are that person if you chose not to vote if you if you didn't vote if you could vote in America stop listening.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Fuck you.
Speaker 1: Like don't be a fan of geek nights.
Speaker 1: Just just delay.
Speaker 0: not only Not only you know, do you need to have voted?
Speaker 0: you need to have voted for Democrats only?
Speaker 1: Yep If you're in New York Democrats on the line of a different party like the working families party, that's a weird New York specific thing.
Speaker 1: But Joe Biden's name has to be on the thing you did whatever mark you need to do.
Speaker 1: if you didn't do that and you Could have get the fuck out of our stream.
Speaker 1: Like I'm not kidding.
Speaker 1: It's not a joke.
Speaker 0: No, it's not.
Speaker 1: But otherwise if you did vote or you're like, oh, you're maybe you're in line to vote on the West Coast or something.
Speaker 1: Don't obsess over the results tonight on Tuesday because unless Biden wins, Florida tonight We're not gonna know the answer for real for a few days.
Speaker 1: Like if you're just holding f5 on some website, all you're doing is adding stress to yourself.
Speaker 1: But you are not actually learning any new information nor are you going to do anything differently with that information?
Speaker 1: So my advice to you is if you can just don't worry about the answer to what happened until tomorrow.
Speaker 1: Then you can start stressing about it.
Speaker 1: Like take a night off.
Speaker 1: if you really can't do that Just wait for Florida and if Florida gets called for by you can go to bed.
Speaker 1: if it doesn't get called for Biden You're gonna be stressed and just force yourself to go to sleep because no new information will come out tonight.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's all I got.
Speaker 1: I hope you vote that.
Speaker 1: that's literally all that matters.
Speaker 1: So let's get into another game that involves voting.
Speaker 1: Among us.
Speaker 1: this was a game that came out a while ago didn't get a huge amount of traction.
Speaker 1: then coven happened everyone stuck at home and Among us it turns out is like The perfect game to stream with a bunch of friends.
Speaker 1: when you're missing your friends and want to hang out online and play a game.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we don't need to talk about how the game was like it came out.
Speaker 0: It was a tiny little unknown game that no one cared about and then became a big deal.
Speaker 0: Right because various streamers and other people brought attention to it.
Speaker 0: and such right.
Speaker 0: you.
Speaker 0: you already know that story and you can read about That story on the internet somewhere.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we got it.
Speaker 0: We got to break this game right because Inherently this game is a game.
Speaker 0: We've all played before.
Speaker 0: it's just mafia slash werewolf, right?
Speaker 1: Yep So I think we have.
Speaker 1: we had to have done a show on mafia at some point But basically I'm sure we have.
Speaker 1: these are all this the class of game.
Speaker 1: We're talking about here our social deduction games.
Speaker 1: They usually are along the lines of there's some number of good people and some number of bad people.
Speaker 0: The bad no one.
Speaker 0: and yeah, the information is hidden.
Speaker 0: So good people definitely don't know who the bad people are And bad people may or may not know who the other bad people yep, and generally the good people are trying to figure out who the bad people are and effectively vote them off the island.
Speaker 1: and Meanwhile, the bad people are trying to eliminate all of the good people until they are the majority and then they win Right.
Speaker 0: So the key to winning the game the games all of these games in this category have all sorts of other mechanics going around.
Speaker 0: But the inherent, you know The core is if you can figure out who is who if you discover the secret identities of the other players Then you're going to be able to win, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, and if you cannot successfully discover the secret identities of the other players You are going to lose.
Speaker 0: now as the bad guys know who everyone is or at least they usually Know who everyone is and they will they automatically win this.
Speaker 0: there They're acting basically as a timer and not so much as a player.
Speaker 0: Other than that, they're trying to avoid detection to keep the timer ticking.
Speaker 1: now There are two broad categories of these games in terms of if there is an intrinsic to the game Means to discover who the imposters are or the traders are or if the game is purely social deduction Right.
Speaker 0: This has been our gripe with these games for so long.
Speaker 0: Is that you know the default way?
Speaker 0: at least most people in our area or at least I think the United States learn to play Mafia slash.
Speaker 0: werewolf is a game where you know you go to sleep you wake up whatever but you have no Actual evidence to base as as a as a sit as in a good person in the game, right?
Speaker 0: There is no literal evidence you have on which to base your decisions of who to kill or not kill.
Speaker 0: Right, you're going based on your gut instinct You're going based on what people are saying.
Speaker 0: it ends up being a game of charisma of coercion of you know You know, yeah oration, right?
Speaker 0: those are the skills that end up mattering and you know other skill really means anything.
Speaker 1: and then all groups will end up into a meta where eventually some people in our group, it's myself Scott and our other friend Scott are identified as too dangerous at the game and Tend to just be murdered by everyone early.
Speaker 1: So there's some quiet and then everyone can play the game like normal Like the game ends up being a purely social experience now the way we always want to play Mafia is more like the original rules.
Speaker 1: There's a few ways that can be handled but one way is yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the key is a killer key rule.
Speaker 1: Yes The key rule is the different rule.
Speaker 1: that makes it more like among us and this is why I'm we're talking about among us among Did.
Speaker 1: the thing we've always wanted is The Mafia.
Speaker 1: all wake up one by one and they each point at who they want to kill.
Speaker 1: in the night.
Speaker 1: They all have to agree on the same person unanimously or no one dies.
Speaker 1: Therefore during the daylight when the social deduction is happening the Mafia people have to somehow communicate with each other Without revealing that they are all the Mafia who they're going to kill that next night.
Speaker 1: That's giving you something to latch on to.
Speaker 1: Scott and Scott keep trying to go after me.
Speaker 1: They are clearly trying to set up the murder of me tonight.
Speaker 1: if I get murdered tonight Scott's Mafia that kind of shit can work.
Speaker 0: or Regardless of what other people are saying you can see with your own eyes that rim keeps winking Right at Sally over there and it's like why does rim keep winking at Sally?
Speaker 0: He's probably Mafia trying to send her secret messages because they can only communicate during the day Provides you with real evidence to grab on to right to make up your own mind without anyone coercing you right or you know seducing you or Influencing you and you can see with your own eyes and smell with your own nose, right?
Speaker 0: Who's good and who's not good?
Speaker 0: and solve the puzzle.
Speaker 0: this real evidence now, right?
Speaker 0: So among us is basically proof that the thing that we've been saying all along which is yeah The older way to play is better where you have real evidence Is true.
Speaker 0: people are love among us way more than they love regular old mafia.
Speaker 0: Yep, so it's super popular.
Speaker 1: So the way among us works mechanically is very simple.
Speaker 1: And this is this is where the magic is in this game.
Speaker 0: It's so simple.
Speaker 0: It's basically they made this tiny little crappy phone game with the crappiest UI.
Speaker 0: Right that bear.
Speaker 0: you basically use one finger to like move around and there's giant buttons for the few actions You can take right.
Speaker 0: and then they've just ported that exact experience with almost no modifications and to the switch to the PC Everything.
Speaker 1: just play it on your phone.
Speaker 1: It's free ons on everything.
Speaker 0: It's like I Suggest paying the five dollars to not have any ads.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: So basically You're these little like bean looking spacemen really straightforward.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the aesthetic is really cute - yep You start on a spaceship or says other maps But you start in the place and there's a bunch of tasks that the crew has to do.
Speaker 1: the crew wins if they complete all the tasks Meanwhile the imposters they don't have to do any tasks.
Speaker 1: They win if they outnumber the regular people or they cause sabotage such that the ship explodes Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: So what this does is in the original mafia, right?
Speaker 0: The mafia or werewolves are the timer on the good characters, right?
Speaker 0: All the good characters.
Speaker 0: The only thing they have to do is figure out who the bad guys are and get rid of them.
Speaker 0: and there's a timer ticking Down until they lose.
Speaker 0: here, right?
Speaker 0: You have two independent timers that are competing with each other right the bad guys timer the imposters.
Speaker 0: their timer is we can oh I can only murder someone every 35 seconds 40 seconds Whatever it's set at and there's only one of me or two of us.
Speaker 0: so it will take us this long to kill everybody.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and then if they if they accidentally kill good people during a voting session Well, our timer just goes down even more.
Speaker 0: yeah, right and meanwhile the good players now have a timer of their own even if they fail at You know beating the bad guys.
Speaker 0: as long as they can keep their timer ahead if they can go around and complete all the tasks Without dying then they can pressure The bad guys the imposters into perhaps doing some messy murders and revealing themselves.
Speaker 0: They're now pressured right.
Speaker 0: so Investigation right.
Speaker 0: there are two clocks ticking down.
Speaker 0: whichever one hits zero first wins and You want to make yours faster and the social deduction basically makes huge adjustments to the clocks, right?
Speaker 0: So the clocks are kind of even right but the they're hugely adjusted.
Speaker 0: the social deduction still matters the most Because it adjusts the clocks so much.
Speaker 0: that like if you're good at tasks Yeah, that won't make up for the fact that you know, you got caught or whatever.
Speaker 1: So here's the real magic.
Speaker 1: the mechanics of this are so simple in terms of the the imposter people they can sabotage.
Speaker 1: We'll get to that in a minute.
Speaker 1: But basically when they murder someone there's that cooldown like 30 seconds 40 seconds.
Speaker 1: They can't kill anyone else.
Speaker 1: They leave a body behind.
Speaker 1: the only way to call the meeting where you decide whether or not to execute someone as Suspected of being an imposter is either to find a body in which case you can immediately report it or Run back to where everyone started and hit an emergency meeting button.
Speaker 1: So if Scott murders someone in like electrical and I happen to bumble into electrical and Scott's coming out And there's a body behind him pretty sure Scott's the imposter.
Speaker 1: I Can report that body and get him but then it can get tricky.
Speaker 1: Scott might have been playing something clever.
Speaker 1: Scott might have been set up the imposter might have been in the room had already murdered the person and jumped into the vent.
Speaker 1: only Impostors can move through the vents and left Scott to get framed.
Speaker 0: It's possible.
Speaker 0: Yeah,
Speaker 1: and that these mechanics cause all these avenues of social deduction All these avenues of discovery of the imposters avenues of trickery by the imposters to set someone else up it makes such a broad playing space that I Plays the game a ton of times with our friends and with a bunch of people like I believe played with randos to see how It went down.
Speaker 0: At least one interesting thing happens in every game, which is not something you can say about a game like mafia Yeah, and the other thing is that you could be playing, you know, regular old mafia where there's no evidence, right?
Speaker 0: You just might really believe that rim is the bad guy or you want to kill rim, right?
Speaker 0: You see you convince other people to do it and you don't know if you're right or wrong, right?
Speaker 0: You know you you may have a good strong hunch or you may know rim really well or something.
Speaker 0: But here you can witness a murder.
Speaker 0: you saw it, right?
Speaker 0: You know who done it a hundred percent There is no doubt whatsoever.
Speaker 0: You literally saw it happen and then but you're the only one who saw it happen And now you have to convince the other people of what you saw.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and then The other person who did the murder is probably gonna come up with some other lie saying you did it Right and now you've got it, right?
Speaker 0: But you know and that that fact that you really know the truth Makes all the difference in the world.
Speaker 1: The game is completely on its head and on top of that the tasks themselves are all Basically WarioWare games of varying difficulty and annoyance.
Speaker 0: They're way simpler than WarioWare games.
Speaker 0: They're a little slower than WarioWare games Which is on purpose because basically to do it some of them are just like click a button Literally and some of them actually do a thing.
Speaker 1: you'll get a task list and some of the tasks are really short and some of them But here's the key you gotta do them.
Speaker 1: you got a standard little bean guy there and do the task.
Speaker 1: So like I'll be doing a test that takes a while like the reactor and then it's like space team Yep, and then Scott say walks into the room behind me.
Speaker 1: Do I keep doing the task?
Speaker 1: Do I trust Scott?
Speaker 1: do I stop doing it and get away from him?
Speaker 1: Like am I worried about this?
Speaker 1: How do I proceed with that?
Speaker 1: It's got just gonna murder me.
Speaker 1: Maybe he's watching me to protect me.
Speaker 1: We're like, there's a lot of interaction that happens and because you can't talk during the game except during meeting You have to communicate non-verbally and the only tools you have are moving your little guy around Or stay much.
Speaker 1: Yeah or standing next to something.
Speaker 1: that could be a task But with the exception of a handful of tasks that have an animation where if you see someone do that task You know 100% they're not an imposter.
Speaker 1: some tasks don't have any such thing.
Speaker 1: So I stand next to admin to do the card swiping and so does Scott.
Speaker 1: Scott might just be fucking faking it.
Speaker 1: Just stand in there for 10 seconds.
Speaker 0: There is one way to.
Speaker 0: there is one way to tell that is very difficult to do is Alright, we both go stand.
Speaker 0: We both stand near a thing.
Speaker 0: Yep, right you finish the task, right?
Speaker 0: You were standing near the same thing.
Speaker 0: the task should take about the same time Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: There's a green bar at the top of the screen that shows how close all the tasks are to being completed And the good guys will win when it's completely full if someone stands near a task and walks away from it as it as if they Did it and the green bar doesn't move.
Speaker 1: Yep But and caveat some tasks are single tasks were like I do the swipe the bar moves.
Speaker 1: Some tasks have multiple steps where if you did the bar won't move until you do the all the steps.
Speaker 0: That's correct.
Speaker 1: So this is where the game isn't just deduction.
Speaker 1: There is a knowledge and skill component of.
Speaker 1: you can actually get better at the game by having better memory by Looking for patterns by noticing things like that by paying attention and by being able to string together a very coherent case.
Speaker 1: a lot of Impostors go down by being asked what are the last two tasks you did?
Speaker 1: And if the imposter wasn't doing tasks that won't be front of mind.
Speaker 1: if they try to make something up They might get caught in their lie.
Speaker 1: Like Joey Jojo might be like I was in navigation.
Speaker 1: I didn't see you do shit.
Speaker 1: And as a result, like you can see like you watch some streamers There are people who are good at this game in the same way that people are good at FPS is.
Speaker 1: So the final big mechanic the sabotage is really fun and clever.
Speaker 1: the imposter can like lock doors.
Speaker 1: So you can like lock someone in a room and then murder them or murder someone and then lock the room.
Speaker 1: so it takes a while for anyone to find the body and report it to give you more time to construct an alibi be seen by someone somewhere else.
Speaker 1: that kind of thing, but some of the sabotages have game effect like turn down the lights.
Speaker 1: now people can't see.
Speaker 1: it's easier to get away with murders.
Speaker 1: turn down comms.
Speaker 1: people can't See their own task list.
Speaker 1: Hit the reactor or oxygen.
Speaker 1: the the crew mates have 30 seconds to fix that or they just lose.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I've sort of there are ways to cheat.
Speaker 0: So if you the task list comms you can screenshot your game when it starts to get to save your task list.
Speaker 0: That's a good move or write it down.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: I just remember at this point because I play the game so much.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean at least at least the main map.
Speaker 0: I know the tasks and where they are.
Speaker 0: But the you know, you play different maps now, you gotta learn new tasks and they're coming out with a new map soon.
Speaker 0: That's apparently huge.
Speaker 0: I'm excited about that big a big math.
Speaker 1: now even better goes.
Speaker 1: There are things you can interact with that aren't tasks But can help you try to find the imposter or help you be the imposter.
Speaker 1: like in the main map.
Speaker 1: Everyone starts with.
Speaker 1: there's admin like in that room.
Speaker 1: There's a thing you can do where it'll show you how many of your friends are in each room everywhere.
Speaker 1: So if you're the imposter, you could look and be like, oh, I see that someone's alone and electrical.
Speaker 1: Let me just go help myself to them little murderer out of the way or You might be watching that to see.
Speaker 1: Oh, hey, there was someone in electrical.
Speaker 1: Let me go check They're by themselves and try to protect them.
Speaker 1: There's a camera you can go look at like security cameras.
Speaker 1: You might just witness a murder but the security cameras blink red.
Speaker 1: So the imposter and the players can see if someone's looking at the cameras.
Speaker 1: But I guess the moral of all that because I'm not gonna explain every one of these special things That you've explained almost every special thing so far.
Speaker 1: Yeah Well, I haven't gotten into the other maps and like there's a lot more nonsense than the other maps but basically the game adds like four core mechanics on top of mafia all of which are intrinsic and All of those together make this game surprisingly complex and nuanced and fun.
Speaker 1: Like this game is way more fun than you might expect for how simple it looks Mmm.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean it's it's you know, that's the thing for it.
Speaker 0: Just a throwaway game right by getting the rules, right?
Speaker 0: You know just making that small change You know something it's like oh you got the rules, right?
Speaker 0: Suddenly you have an amazing play experience.
Speaker 0: regardless of these all these other problems you've got and especially in coded times The game is social.
Speaker 1: So it's a very good game to just hang out with your friends in a discord while you play right.
Speaker 0: low Development cost right just slap together a tiny little thing.
Speaker 0: There's other people who are like, you know working on these huge games You know like big 3d stuff and you know all kinds of fanciness and like a million levels and like a million Cosmetic things.
Speaker 0: and who knows right all these people out there like you got MMOs.
Speaker 0: people are making out there Right things cost zillions of dollars.
Speaker 1: solid game and with solid mechanics could be the a-plus game of the year.
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 0: You know Candy Crush made more money than all of them, right?
Speaker 0: so all you got it and it doesn't have to be a Micro transaction kind of thing either right like Candy Crush was right you can make the money and make the sales.
Speaker 0: You just need the good rules right.
Speaker 0: the rules of the game is what's all about.
Speaker 1: Yep so The last little bit.
Speaker 1: normally in a game any game One thing that Scott and I are often annoyed by is if someone falls back on the Atari method of there's a million modes Figure out which one is fun.
Speaker 1: Like if the game is too customizable in that regard.
Speaker 1: Usually that's a sign of they didn't figure out which mode was fun.
Speaker 1: Something Among Us does that is actually very strong in my opinion is it starts the game at a good default.
Speaker 1: But you can tweak a lot of little details like slightly tweak the cooldown time of the kills or the view Distance of the imposter versus the players or how many tasks people have.
Speaker 1: so it basically lets you do the thing that Mafia and werewolf do.
Speaker 1: very well.
Speaker 1: We're like if the Mafia win every game then you add the Archangel.
Speaker 1: Yeah, add other roles to give the human the non mafia people a better chance.
Speaker 0: If the on the one hand right is like when a game gives you all so many options, right?
Speaker 0: There's a lot of games out there that don't give enough options, especially with controls for accessibility and that's a problem.
Speaker 1: But
Speaker 0: I think it's also when I see with these many options, especially for the gameplay specifically I often see that as like a designer crutch where it's like Oh, you didn't want to go through the game design play testing effort to figure out what the perfect settings should be.
Speaker 0: So you're just saying player do my work for me, right?
Speaker 0: Imagine if you got a board game and there's a bunch of pieces and the rule book was like Yeah, start with X dollars.
Speaker 0: figure it out yourself with the best number of dollars to start with and then you know How much does a settlement cost?
Speaker 0: Figure out how many resources it should cost.
Speaker 0: We're not quite sure.
Speaker 0: I didn't figure it out that it should be.
Speaker 0: you know, a sheep a grain or whatever, you know Yeah, it's like That's.
Speaker 0: you don't do that right?
Speaker 0: You need to.
Speaker 0: you're the game designer.
Speaker 0: It's your job to figure out the right answers for what the values should be for the best possible game experience.
Speaker 0: but you know in this case there does need to be some variability because as Players skills change you have different sets of players different number.
Speaker 0: There's so many variables that go in and affect what those best settings should be.
Speaker 0: So I think that yeah those You definitely need some sort of user control over the settings because it would basically be impossible to have an automatic thing.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right for any any conceivable game, but I do think they went a little bit too far.
Speaker 0: It's like it's too flexible.
Speaker 0: I
Speaker 1: know
Speaker 1: need that because when we were playing with our group you'll find that your group's meta will evolve semi independently of other groups and You sort of like I could figure out like okay the imposters are winning a bunch of times in the in a
Speaker 0: row
Speaker 1: But they're winning mostly by murdering.
Speaker 1: if I increase the cooldown slightly that'll restore balance.
Speaker 0: See, I think that on the one hand Right that sort of reactive method is how I see a lot of game designers with like living games.
Speaker 0: You know games like, you know Multiplayer games go wrong is that they see their current meta and they're like, okay that everyone's playing with that character Let's nerf them.
Speaker 0: All right, everyone's not playing that character enough.
Speaker 0: Let's buff them, right?
Speaker 0: It's sort of this reactive design and I think you need to resist that urge and instead Right.
Speaker 0: what you need to do is say well, how do we want people to play?
Speaker 0: We want people to play this way and instead do a proactive say well We want people to you know, do this more and do this less.
Speaker 0: Right, you know, it's not not even thinking about how they're playing now All right, just think about how we want them the perfect game to go.
Speaker 0: What settings do we put for that fear hypothetical perfect game to encourage those behaviors?
Speaker 0: right and not you know So much stick on carrot on the current behavior.
Speaker 1: Well, I would say the like the big brain version of this would be.
Speaker 1: all those fiddly options are fun But if you could figure out like because basically the the real race is how many players in the game are skilled at the game or not like that determines the meta until everyone gets to this like Moderately high level of skill and then the game sort of stabilizes.
Speaker 1: you could almost abstract it all into a slider of.
Speaker 1: Do you think you who run the server?
Speaker 1: Do you think the crew mates or the imposters are winning too often and you can?
Speaker 1: Click a button and it basically makes it slightly harder for whichever faction you're trying to make harder for and that would be it.
Speaker 1: And it could just roll all those things together soon.
Speaker 0: All right soon they are.
Speaker 0: They're gonna add player accounts where you can make an account.
Speaker 0: If you have that you can track data on each player like how fast is Scott at doing tests, right?
Speaker 1: Which maps to Scott win on the most you can also deal with?
Speaker 0: how good is?
Speaker 1: Griefing?
Speaker 0: how good is Scott at imposter versus not imposter?
Speaker 0: When you know and you could with all that data if they actually bother to collect it and analyze it which is really difficult to Do actually but they have so much day.
Speaker 0: They could collect so much with all these players You could probably you know, learn like the best settings to get you know The most you would.
Speaker 0: I think you'd want to optimize for the most exciting games right the ones that you know Go deep right don't end too quickly Where you know you get really close to finishing all the tasks and then it's a close call to whether the tasks get finished Or the final person dies, right?
Speaker 0: That's the game you want to optimize for right?
Speaker 0: How do we reach that game?
Speaker 0: All right, if you just optimize for like, you know 50% win rate imposter versus not.
Speaker 0: you might get a bunch of really sad games where either one team or the other it wins quickly Right.
Speaker 0: It's like oh, it's 50% win rate imposters and you know It's like.
Speaker 0: no, it's a really boring game.
Speaker 1: now, I guess that's where.
Speaker 1: because the game is so simple I find that this is one of those cases where like I personally do appreciate the fiddly level of control.
Speaker 1: But part of that is I think I have a very good sense.
Speaker 1: I think you do too of like when we play a game of among us what were the deciding factors in that game?
Speaker 1: and We're very good at like figuring out what to tweak to make the game be what we want it to be for our group.
Speaker 1: Because the thing is there's two groups.
Speaker 1: There's two types of play in this.
Speaker 1: a lot of people play it with strangers, but We do that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's popular with strangers, but we play it with like people We are already friends with.
Speaker 0: we play it in small groups for a reason would not play with a strange person.
Speaker 0: I do not know.
Speaker 1: so the strange Your games are interesting.
Speaker 1: part of the reason why they're adding on the internet is that?
Speaker 1: There is a common form of griefing.
Speaker 1: if you're playing with randos where a lot of people will quit any game where they're not the imposter and just join a different server Mm-hmm that they just really only want to play really just only one.
Speaker 1: I mean it is honestly I have more fun being the imposter.
Speaker 0: I don't really care too, but it's like For some reason I'm very good at imposter.
Speaker 0: I win often as imposter.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we got it.
Speaker 1: I don't Scott's.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna reference this the next time we play a game.
Speaker 1: Scott's good at him But if the imposter seemed like they're doing well, we're just executing Scott.
Speaker 0: That's not a bad idea.
Speaker 1: Yeah, dude.
Speaker 1: It's actually not a bad idea to do that to me either.
Speaker 1: like well I'm like 1%.
Speaker 1: sure it's rim, so let's just kill rim just to get that out of the way and then continue the game Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: So yeah, honestly like so.
Speaker 0: yeah this game looks like.
Speaker 0: you know you might if you're just on the outside looking in and you see Like all these kids are playing this among us and tweeting about it.
Speaker 0: You might think you know.
Speaker 0: Oh, it's just what you know.
Speaker 0: That's just another fortnight or another fall guys, or you know the.
Speaker 0: it's just you know.
Speaker 0: It's just some lame.
Speaker 0: Oh current game the kids are playing.
Speaker 0: It's not anything This game is but actually it is.
Speaker 0: it's.
Speaker 0: it's the actual solution.
Speaker 0: It's like hey they took the social deduction game And they made they did what we said and they made it not suck.
Speaker 0: and it turns out That's really popular you don't say yep.
Speaker 1: and they added right about and then they did it not.
Speaker 1: they add enough depth to it to give it a Huge amount of replayability not infinite.
Speaker 1: There is a perfect meta.
Speaker 1: eventually like there's a perfect play style, but You'll get a lot for your five bucks before you hit that point with your group of friends.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean, I'm sort of getting played out on a little bit right.
Speaker 1: well We haven't done anything like make the game hard yet.
Speaker 1: Nor we even played that one map more than a couple times right and they've got new maps.
Speaker 0: They got the new big map coming, so I'll probably go back to it once that big map hits.
Speaker 1: Yeah, this has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 0: be sure to visit our website At front row.
Speaker 0: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 1: remember geek nights is not one But four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night And the patreon patrons for this election day episode of geek nights are Alan Joyce.
Speaker 1: How do you mean nickel?
Speaker 1: Marty greenia Graham Finch you hold the key to my heart.
Speaker 1: I gotta wait for this tool tip to pop up.
Speaker 1: God damn the patreon but I thought not forget it.
Speaker 1: Yo home to Bel Air Clinton Walton J fans ran from New Zealand.
Speaker 1: Ryan Farrand Chris midkiff tried Lily Tenerbrae Just like a dude guy.
Speaker 1: Chris Reimer Finn Sherman von Horlant a bunch of people who do not want me to say their names.
Speaker 1: You might have noticed Emily and I got up our review of the three Caballeros Which I cannot stress is literally the angriest and horniest that Donald Duck has ever been and also Nearly the most body horror that Donald Duck has ever experienced.
Speaker 1: Otherwise stay tuned for a bunch more stuff.
Speaker 1: We're working on.
Speaker 1: I know I mentioned the utenna thing.
Speaker 1: We are working on pre-production and the cracks.
Speaker 1: Well, I am.
Speaker 1: Scott will only be involved when it's time for him to record his segment.
Speaker 1: So stay tuned on that.
Speaker 1: but God damn it like.
Speaker 1: go vote for Joe Biden.
Speaker 1: You still got time.
Speaker 1: If you're on the West Coast Depending on when you listen to this you might still have time.
Speaker 1: a lot of states have same-day voter registration.
Speaker 1: You can just roll over there register and vote all in one go.
Speaker 1: Anyway, let's hope this goes.
Speaker 1: Well, most of you are probably listening to this after we likely know the results of the election and Our Thursday episode might be very different depending on how the election goes, but for now I leave you with a very pertinent stinger Or party jello Tommy via Obeil
Speaker 0: a child and a child and a child child.
Speaker 0: child party jello or family Can be said to be boring?
Speaker 0: It's a yo-yo Parpigiano.
Speaker 1: Obeil a child and a child and a child child child boyo not party jello.
Speaker 1: Do me.
Speaker 1: Obeil a child and a child and a child.
Speaker 1: child child.
Speaker 1: Tina Sato Your Cartesian Tanya.
Speaker 1: Obeil a child.
Speaker 1: Obeil a child child child party.
Speaker 1: jello Tanya Oh Sono Sato Obeil a child a child a child.
Speaker 1: child child.
Speaker 1: Sono Sato Oh Oh Matina Sono Sato Obeil a child.
Speaker 1: Obeil a child.
Speaker 1: Obeil a child child child.
Speaker 1: Matina Sono Sato Yo travato Invaso party.
Speaker 1: jello Tommy via Obeil a child.
Speaker 1: Obeil a child.
Speaker 1: Obeil a child child child party.
Speaker 1: jello for Tommy via came in Santo de.