Speaker 1: It's Tuesday March 24th 2020 I'm rim and this is geek nights.
Speaker 1: tonight We are reviewing two games that are new to us.
Speaker 1: No return also known as as get kind zurich and square on sale.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: So if geek night sounds a little bit different that's because we are actually recording it remotely Which is something we've actually never done in the last 15 years like even one had to.
Speaker 1: we've never Done the show in any way except both of us sitting in a room.
Speaker 1: Scott lounging with his eyes closed me not looking at him at our microphones.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean why there was no reason to.
Speaker 0: we would just skip the show if we were apart for some reason.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right apart from the audio equipment.
Speaker 1: Yep, but it's difficult times.
Speaker 1: and to reiterate While we would probably be safe meeting up Probably is not good enough right now.
Speaker 1: If we can stay home and set up this kind of fucky Janky pipeline to do the show remotely because we've never had to do it before you can stay home for a couple weeks.
Speaker 0: We'll see if it's a couple weeks or longer.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know if it's warm enough to bike biking might be an option.
Speaker 1: Oh my god.
Speaker 1: I just gotta get nice.
Speaker 0: It's currently too cold.
Speaker 0: So what I'd think?
Speaker 1: well It was warm in a very long walk.
Speaker 1: It was warm enough over the weekend.
Speaker 1: There was that one day where it was like.
Speaker 0: I know it wasn't even a day It was like an afternoon and I basically as soon as it was warm I biked and then it got cold.
Speaker 0: they came back I came home and that was it.
Speaker 0: There was the end of the warm period.
Speaker 1: as soon as it got warm me and Emily was like, yeah And we ran outside and we went for a run and we came back and then the next day It was like 40 and raining.
Speaker 0: It was like four hour period of warmth.
Speaker 1: Yesterday was totally told.
Speaker 0: the Sun went down And I don't think I went outside yesterday.
Speaker 1: Uh, did I?
Speaker 1: I did go outside once to drop off a growler at the Baroness and get a new refilled growler.
Speaker 0: Oh, they just give you the whole thing.
Speaker 1: So what they're doing is they are basically they're doing takeout food only but they will give you beer and food And that is totally okay for a bunch of arcane reasons.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah I mean you can even get beer delivered from a bodega.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know beer delivery is totally legal and always has been in New York.
Speaker 1: So if you're not familiar growler, basically, it's just a milk jug that you completely fill with beer.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's about that size.
Speaker 1: It's like a gallon of beer.
Speaker 1: So we're gonna get a couple of those a week and Hopefully that will help keep the Baroness in business because I love that.
Speaker 0: I don't think they're gonna be going out of it.
Speaker 1: Yep, it's cool though.
Speaker 1: They basically got two employees in there and like we've known the guy for a long time because we've been going there forever and he's Super chill but because it's so empty and quiet I've got to talk to him a lot more and he's even cooler than I thought.
Speaker 1: he's like he lives nearby.
Speaker 1: He's driving to the Baroness for maximum safety.
Speaker 1: He had like they said of all these protocols of like how people sure you just walk there.
Speaker 1: if he lives nearby Well, he lives like 20 minutes away vice.
Speaker 1: Oh, that's not nearby It's nearby compared to like living in Brooklyn.
Speaker 1: Yeah Anyway, anyway, so in some meta news, uh Scott always like to point out that I like.
Speaker 1: I like noises.
Speaker 1: I mean I used to be a musician.
Speaker 1: I'm still kind of a musician.
Speaker 1: I've been playing my trumpet again, but So it's rims thing is.
Speaker 0: all he does is he you know, he makes yeah, he makes annoying noises.
Speaker 0: There's a device that makes annoying noises He wants.
Speaker 0: he finds out that a particular noise and noise you he'll make that noise.
Speaker 0: go out of his way to make that noise.
Speaker 0: It's possible.
Speaker 1: but one of the things that a musical instrument that I've always loved is the hurdy-gurdy Which is basically a violin where you don't need to bow or finger because those are the two things I cannot do.
Speaker 1: I am I am like preternaturally unable to play stringed instruments.
Speaker 1: But the hurdy-gurdy removes all of the challenges that I would have with a stringed instrument.
Speaker 1: It's basically.
Speaker 0: it also removes it sort, you know, the you know, the the finesse, right?
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah exactly It's a.
Speaker 1: it is definitely a a thick fingered instrument.
Speaker 1: It's the keytar equivalent of a violin exactly, but it's more like bagpipes of all things because it drones.
Speaker 1: so it's Some people may like this, but it's not air-powered Yeah, but it's still drones.
Speaker 1: Like.
Speaker 1: it'll basically play like crank.
Speaker 0: I thought you had to crank it up.
Speaker 1: You crank it constantly and a wheel spins past the Strings so you can basically just play infinite notes.
Speaker 1: They usually have one of the strings just going wah the whole time and then you play notes on the other string Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: So I bought a mechanical kit to make my own hurdy-gurdy and I'm a big is it?
Speaker 1: Oh, it's like a foot and a half tall when I finish.
Speaker 0: Okay, so it's not like cello sized.
Speaker 1: No No, they're like violin sized time.
Speaker 1: Okay, or even smaller.
Speaker 1: Maybe this is more like a banjo.
Speaker 1: the way I was looking at it Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: We'll see how it sounds.
Speaker 1: I doubt it'll sound great because it doesn't have like a resonating chamber like a like a well-made wooden instrument would have.
Speaker 1: but This will be a good way to find out if I actually want to play a hurdy-gurdy for real because if I do I'll just like helps get someone to make me a real hurdy-gurdy and I can pass my trumpet.
Speaker 0: The best homemade instrument you can possibly make is the cigar box guitar slash banjo Cigar box.
Speaker 0: you put a stick on it You put a cup a string or a few You know and the effort to make one is low.
Speaker 0: the style is pretty high Relative to the effort.
Speaker 0: the sound is pretty high relative to the effort.
Speaker 0: the ease of playing versus results is pretty high.
Speaker 0: It's just like, you know, it's not like a terrific amazing instrument.
Speaker 0: It's just the ratio of ease.
Speaker 0: You made it yourself.
Speaker 0: It looks cool and it sounds kind of good is really high ratio.
Speaker 1: So in terms of the ratio of effort to learn versus sounds pretty good.
Speaker 0: harmonica still wins Mmm, I don't know.
Speaker 0: I think cigar box guitar or even ukulele is probably easier than Harmonica, I don't know.
Speaker 0: I don't need to learn any mouth skills.
Speaker 0: Anyone with hands already has hand skills.
Speaker 1: I had the mouth skills to play basic harmonica stuff round down to basically zero if all you're gonna play.
Speaker 0: But a lot of people don't have any mouth skills at all.
Speaker 0: true It's like you have to at least learn some kind of embouchure if you everyone knows how to use the fucking hands.
Speaker 1: True that is way back when both of us were learning the harmonica I had an unfair advantage because of the trumpet and like my tonguing skills you had to learn extra skills from scratch.
Speaker 0: I played clarinet.
Speaker 0: I have mouth skills.
Speaker 0: I just you know, I think that barely requires an embouchure.
Speaker 1: I do not have any Discipline To continue and repeatedly practice something to mastery, but I will link to this kit because uh The people who make it it's on a player.
Speaker 1: Uh, yeah Parality comm they make like Woodcraft things and they have a lot of really cool stuff there and they're putting a lot of their stuff on sale Because a lot of people are stuck at home like bored looking for projects.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: So you got any news?
Speaker 0: I do have a news.
Speaker 0: It's sort of a Small news because the news is actually tomorrow.
Speaker 0: We're recording this on March 24th.
Speaker 0: You're probably listening on March 25th, which is when the news will actually happen.
Speaker 0: So it's a. it's a news announcing a news, but Sega has teased for the 60th anniversary of Sega.
Speaker 0: Some sort of announcement tomorrow.
Speaker 0: But if you look at the single teaser image that they have released Right, all the all it's.
Speaker 0: the only text they've released is ah, so you've come to this page.
Speaker 0: You must really like Sega.
Speaker 0: Please wait a little longer until the site is open.
Speaker 0: So I guess the site will open tomorrow.
Speaker 0: But the image in the teaser appears to be Sega satan Shiro what which is huge news for anyone who knows who that is.
Speaker 1: we were vaguely obsessed with him for a while at RIT because One there wasn't YouTube yet.
Speaker 1: So finally having one of these videos was already pretty novel and two He's just an amazing character.
Speaker 0: So if anyone who doesn't know when the Sega Saturn was a thing It was a bigger thing in Japan than the u.s.
Speaker 0: Where it kind of flopped mostly, right?
Speaker 0: the Advertisements for it.
Speaker 0: the Sega Saturn in Japan involved a character named segata San Shiro, which when you say it quickly sort of sounds like Sega Saturn Shiro.
Speaker 0: right Say Exactly Right, exactly.
Speaker 0: I think they received a set of commercials.
Speaker 0: You can watch all the commercials on YouTube.
Speaker 0: I'm sure they're they're all around and very popular.
Speaker 0: and the final commercial he died spoilers.
Speaker 1: Yep, but he dives saving Sega.
Speaker 0: Yeah season it was but the commercials are just an amazing character advertising the product in an amazing way.
Speaker 0: and you just you know, you you know when in the US knew about this character until You know internet came around and we were able to see Japanese commercials.
Speaker 1: I remember an early kinetic on someone was cosplaying as this.
Speaker 1: I got it.
Speaker 0: I got the picture somewhere I gotta find yes, but by that I already knew who it was at that point.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right I saw.
Speaker 0: I think at the first time it was like some someone at RIT was like have you heard of Sega?
Speaker 0: Sanjiro Sega, it's like oh here it is I. Anyway, so yes, they get so Sanjiro may be coming back or maybe his son or something or descendant or who knows?
Speaker 0: We'll find out by the time you're hearing this podcast problem.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if not a few hours afterwards.
Speaker 1: So in some other relatively minor news, uh half-life Alex is imminently arriving for people who have VR.
Speaker 0: I thought it was out already.
Speaker 1: I think it just came out just like there's.
Speaker 1: just reviews are being published.
Speaker 0: Okay, pretty sure it's out now might actually been today.
Speaker 1: I think it's out out Yeah, but I think it might have actually been out out as of literally today.
Speaker 0: Let's see when the release date is on Steam.
Speaker 0: half-life Alex.
Speaker 0: March 23rd yesterday.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: So I've seen some early reviews.
Speaker 1: I plan to play it Probably this weekend.
Speaker 1: I'm going to try to play the whole thing through but it Appears based on the early reviews I've seen but I have not played it yet that it is definitely one of those of the VR That's out.
Speaker 1: Not only is a peak experience, but it might be one of the best VR experiences possible.
Speaker 0: We're I mean the important the impression that I've got.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the impression that I've gotten is that yeah, every other VR thing is pooped.
Speaker 0: now This is like, you know much the way because like half-life 1 sort of set the bar, right and then half-life 2 Sort of also set the bar kinda it for you know, just in other ways, right but like VR is still pretty early technology.
Speaker 1: So like a lot of games have set the bar so far, but the bar is still relatively low.
Speaker 0: But valve, you know and basically announced like hey the reason we haven't released a half-life 3 We've made several of them is because none of them were good enough Like they refused to release a half-life.
Speaker 0: unless it sets a new bar And half-life Alex appears as if it might for you know, VR games be setting the new bar.
Speaker 1: So, there you go I will play it this weekend to see.
Speaker 1: but the VR game I've been playing lately is Currently one of the things that has set a bar because super hot was super great but pistol-width is Amazing what it is.
Speaker 1: It's a rail shooter Which is a perfect kind of game to make in VR because you can avoid a lot of the motion sickness problems.
Speaker 0: So it's time crisis.
Speaker 1: Okay, but it's it's John wick.
Speaker 1: You're basically just walking forward at a constant rate and enemies pop up everywhere and you got to shoot him.
Speaker 1: But the thing that makes it great is that it's actually not really a shooter.
Speaker 1: It's a rhythm game.
Speaker 0: There's games like that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there's pumping music and in this 3d VR world with a lot of abstract like imagery and abstract shapes and all this fun stuff.
Speaker 1: You're just doing this rhythm shooter and it feels like the scene in John wick one.
Speaker 1: We're just walking through murdering Russian mobsters one by one in the nightclub.
Speaker 1: It basically feels like that constantly and it's crazy fun.
Speaker 0: And also isn't that what?
Speaker 0: isn't that?
Speaker 0: what time crisis feels like?
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, but time crisis It doesn't have the like the heavy rhythm element.
Speaker 0: I guess that's true, but I have seen a rhythm shooters before.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, but I think this area is a various mechanism.
Speaker 1: This is blended.
Speaker 1: this a lot of what super hot did.
Speaker 1: Well what I mean isn't What Tokyo 911 does.
Speaker 1: well the game that we used to know.
Speaker 0: No, I mean there's already The the blade one beat saver, right?
Speaker 0: There's already.
Speaker 1: that's not a shooter.
Speaker 1: That's just a rhythm.
Speaker 0: It's a sorter It's a rhythm sword.
Speaker 0: Yes, and now you have a rhythm gunner.
Speaker 1: Yep, but the rhythm gun saver with gun There aren't.
Speaker 1: I have not seen a game that has combined all of these three things together.
Speaker 0: so wasn't there the one that used at the Omega thon the the Harmonics one that was like a rhythm gunner.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah that that does a lot of these feelings But it doesn't also have the Tokyo 911 feeling Hmm.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I guess visually that was just a bunch of colors and lights and things.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like a rhythm game that purely whereas this one this one is a rhythm game.
Speaker 0: But the visuals are actually a time crisis.
Speaker 1: visual yep, and dodging it feels exactly like it feels in that police 9-1-1 Whatever that we always played in Wildwood you and your police.
Speaker 0: No, no that gives great.
Speaker 1: And I got really good at it because it was as the arcades in a Wildwood got worse and worse and worse that one game Was still there way late to the party it was still just hanging out it barely worked And that was the only game I would play eventually.
Speaker 1: anyway, I guess it's time for things of the day.
Speaker 1: You you've talked up your thing in the day and now that I'm looking at it I see why I've seen this comic before.
Speaker 0: oh you have seen it before.
Speaker 0: yeah I have not seen it before at least not before yesterday, so Apparently there is this Hungarian comic strip, and I don't know if how you you know the.
Speaker 0: the alphabet of the Hungarian language looks you car.
Speaker 0: Yeah, looks somewhere between English and Cyrillic, so I don't know how to pronounce the words.
Speaker 0: I'll just so sorry anyone who knows how to read Hungarian.
Speaker 0: I assume that that the name of the character and the name of the comic is Drusika which is similar like the equivalent of Jessica.
Speaker 0: right hmm, but anyway, so this deal with this comic is it was created by Somebody named.
Speaker 0: what was their name?
Speaker 0: Hold on the creator's name is Poots I Paul which probably pronouncing that wrong also And it was published in some sort of publications magazines or newspapers in Hungary between the 50s and the 70s.
Speaker 0: so it had like a good like 20-year run.
Speaker 0: basically And even though it's Hungarian you can read these comics because there's very little dialogue in them.
Speaker 0: basically none It's almost all.
Speaker 0: the gags are entirely visual.
Speaker 0: occasionally They'll be like a sign with something written on it And each comic will have like a title like Jessica dresses the shop's window.
Speaker 0: Jessica is hiking Jessica in rush-hour traffic, right?
Speaker 0: And there's two different Twitter accounts that are posting comics from this.
Speaker 0: one of them is Jessica Daily and one of them is Jessica in order In order.
Speaker 0: one is publishing them in order duh Instead of just random selections is posting them one a day and is posting translations and contextual info.
Speaker 0: So I recommend the in order one over the other one mm-hmm But it's actually somewhat fascinating.
Speaker 0: I looked into how this comic became a thing in the u.s.. It's actually a 4chan deal Apparently Someone on 4chan because basically the idea of the comic is is it the main character is this woman Jessica Jessica?
Speaker 0: Whatever and each three panel comic like she's up to shenanigans and the shenanigans are usually sexy in nature But not always yep, but they're not over the line.
Speaker 1: They're just like.
Speaker 1: I don't know they.
Speaker 1: I get a tiny almost eraser.
Speaker 1: It's her kind of vibe like she's very lum ask in the way she interacts with people.
Speaker 0: right.
Speaker 0: It's weird cuz sometimes you know for something made from the 50s to the 70s in a communist Hungary right.
Speaker 0: sometimes It's sort of male gaze II obviously right which isn't so great, but a lot of times It's actually sort of like a feminist satire like Or you know sexually empowering in different ways right like the
Speaker 1: one where the guy is like being a little too Handsy at the dance and she she gets him.
Speaker 0: yeah, there's ones where this guys are too handsy and she like you know hurts them
Speaker 1: Right,
Speaker 0: but there's also ones were like she's into a dude, and she's like hey Right like there's one where she's dancing at like a costume party, and she's wearing like she's dressed like a you know French Aristocracy from 1800s big big dress and the dude she's dancing with.
Speaker 0: you know who looks like King herp.
Speaker 0: the derp Can't get close enough, and they're dancing awkwardly.
Speaker 0: so she sort of sneaks out of the dress And then she's dancing in like her underwear yeah, and it's sort of like hey.
Speaker 0: Yeah, what if?
Speaker 0: But yeah, you know not all the comics are sexy though There's some that are just like.
Speaker 0: this is one here where an old lady loses a bird so she climbs up the tree with a cage to go get the bird and She gives the old lady a cat and the joke is the cat ate the bird
Speaker 1: She's afraid of the mouse and she jumps into the arms of a much more dangerous animal.
Speaker 0: yeah So you know and also glad you know.
Speaker 0: the other thing that's great about this comic is just the art style and aesthetic of it Is crazy good?
Speaker 0: right It's?
Speaker 0: you know it gives me some Katie Skelly vibes going on, but you know overall I'm just way into it, so I recommend following this Twitter account.
Speaker 0: reading this comic And you know it makes me want to learn more about other You know comic strips from other countries that you know because it's not like there's that many new Newspaper comic strips.
Speaker 0: right they're all webcomics now.
Speaker 0: And I already do know a lot of webcomics from other countries to some extent right.
Speaker 0: But I don't know a lot about the old newspaper comics from other countries that didn't become world's Popular.
Speaker 0: yeah You know ones that were in smaller publications or at smaller runs or were never republished or licensed in other languages or anything like that, so Yeah, whoever found this and made it a thing late last year Thanks, and now everyone can enjoy it and you can see the follower counts on the Twitter accounts.
Speaker 0: the follower cats on the turn For these comics are increasing dramatically recently.
Speaker 0: Get in on the.
Speaker 0: get in on it, so I'm gonna cheat.
Speaker 1: I am linking to a channel I have linked to once before a while back.
Speaker 1: technology actions.
Speaker 0: well But I'll fail on you.
Speaker 1: I like.
Speaker 1: this video is pretty good because one of the things that I really am fascinated by our Electro mechanical devices like old pre like pre modern integrated circuit arcade machines things like that Like a pinball machine yeah, but this one is a fancy complicated jukebox with song selection.
Speaker 1: Okay, complicated song selection, and it's not a teardown of like the entire jukebox.
Speaker 1: So you did make some videos for all that too.
Speaker 1: It's a deep like half-hour long explanation of one specific part of the jukebox and it is a
Speaker 0: relay
Speaker 1: driven accumulator like an old-fashioned accumulator because In the era before I sees like if you wanted to put logic into something You there were design patterns to do that kind of thing and an accumulator is actually one of the like Core electronic components that you could use to build complex machinery
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm
Speaker 1: like you know if you ever learn how to make circuits like you learn about adders And you learn about making Nand gates and stuff.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I have a computer science degree.
Speaker 0: I learned that.
Speaker 1: yep I was supposed to have learned that yep, but I don't think a lot of people have.
Speaker 1: so if you want to see a Reasonably complex electromechanical accumulator that relies not just on circuits and Relays, but also on big heavy metal pins and springs that are holding them under tension This thing's actually pretty amazing.
Speaker 0: how a lot of the problem with a lot of those things though is like you know You know pinball machines right there always breaking and you have to keep fixing them right.
Speaker 0: so how often it?
Speaker 0: How reliable is this jukebox before super reliable?
Speaker 1: the machine actually is working and fully restored except for the coin?
Speaker 1: collection mechanism.
Speaker 1: no one can figure out how to make it work, haha.
Speaker 1: So all they did and the crazy thing is the way it works is there's a solenoid inside that when it's powered Pulls a bunch of levers and activates like a million circuits everywhere like.
Speaker 1: that's basically the equivalent of copy protection.
Speaker 1: They can't figure out how to make that solenoid be triggered by the coin accumulator.
Speaker 1: So instead they just hard-coded it to always be powered if the machine is plugged in What it's basically an always play mode Mmm in the meta moment.
Speaker 1: and like I said we're recording the show a weird way.
Speaker 1: So it might sound a little bit different and we're gonna have to tweak this process as we go on.
Speaker 1: But otherwise I think we can do the show like this just fine.
Speaker 1: I'll make some tweaks and by next week you probably won't even notice the difference.
Speaker 1: Maybe otherwise the booklet book remains the tale of Genji not the tale of Ozo.
Speaker 0: We'll see if we can do some reading.
Speaker 0: have you been reading?
Speaker 1: I have not because I've been playing the original xcom.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like because I'm at home.
Speaker 0: I don't have.
Speaker 0: I'm doing all this other stuff instead.
Speaker 0: It's like I got all this extra time of the day.
Speaker 0: I don't need to Read on the right way.
Speaker 1: I'm playing original xcom tonight I'll be starting to play some Animal Crossing and I'm also gonna be building my hurdy-gurdy pretty soon.
Speaker 0: I'm playing.
Speaker 0: I'm playing the new doom eternal Got a little bit of Zelda randomizer and I might play some Animal Crossing.
Speaker 0: We'll see.
Speaker 0: it's.
Speaker 0: you know, the $60 is the main thing.
Speaker 0: I mean it was less than that.
Speaker 0: I would play it.
Speaker 1: No question That's why I got it physical because I can always sell it to someone later or give it away.
Speaker 0: and I figured yeah I don't really like doing it.
Speaker 0: Whatever.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but I figured I've never.
Speaker 1: I've never been on an Animal Crossing train and while I have an idea of what the game is like I don't really know because I've never played it and I've never really seen anything about it except memes and Screenshots and other people who are into it talking about it.
Speaker 0: It's literally just walk around and do stuff.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so I'm gonna play it I'm gonna mooch around and see what the deal is.
Speaker 0: All right, maybe I'll play it.
Speaker 0: We'll see.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we'll see But otherwise, obviously we are not attending any conventions for the foreseeable future.
Speaker 1: The nope most likely the next convention we will even possibly be able to attend if it happens will be packs West.
Speaker 0: Well, that was already the next convention.
Speaker 1: Yeah Well, I was gonna be a Zenka Khan and kinetic on some other stuff, but I'm assuming everything through packs is cancelled.
Speaker 1: I'm not even gonna bother trying to go to those con.
Speaker 0: X may even be cancelled.
Speaker 1: It may well be.
Speaker 1: Hopefully things are good by unplugged and magfest.
Speaker 0: We'll see.
Speaker 1: I'm already making magfest plans.
Speaker 0: All right, that's good.
Speaker 0: We need those.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: So, uh, we are reviewing two board games today because while they're both pretty good And they're pretty deep games in terms of like what we could say about them.
Speaker 1: There's not a lot to say about them.
Speaker 0: No, no, no, they're relatively simple.
Speaker 1: There's a lot of reasons why this will be.
Speaker 1: There's not a lot to say so even though we always try to stretch it out and only do one game per show I feel like we really need to have talked about two games Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: So let's start with the game that I think we Internalized more and that I think we played more than once.
Speaker 1: that one Yep, and that I think we will want to own if you don't buy it.
Speaker 0: I'll buy it because Matt This was actually citizen.
Speaker 0: first look at PAX East and it was actually our friend Matt's copy.
Speaker 0: That was in the first look.
Speaker 0: not PAX is copy.
Speaker 0: Yep They're going.
Speaker 0: the game is called no return as As kinds of look if I don't know how to pronounce that German.
Speaker 0: But I do know that the the the it translates to there is no turning back Right and the game designer is Marco toy Bner.
Speaker 0: And basically there is no turning back is exactly what this game is about, you know We've played tons of board games out there that have some sort of dual currency system Right where the way to win the game is to get victory points, but there's also this other currency like money, right?
Speaker 0: So in st.
Speaker 0: Petersburg, it's very literal this victory points and there's coins.
Speaker 0: Yeah in Puerto Rico there's doubloons and victory points.
Speaker 1: Yeah I do.
Speaker 1: balloon in round two is worth way more than a doubloon in round eight Right and race to the galaxy, which is similar to Puerto Rico.
Speaker 0: It's a little more abstract than that, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah in Agricola It's a little bit more abstract, right?
Speaker 0: But there are some resources in the game it over Agricola that are worth less points and some that are worth more points.
Speaker 0: But the ones that are worth less points can be used to purchase things that get you points.
Speaker 1: So like if you if you've played Dominion There's it's a got a really good example because early in the game you're trying to get money.
Speaker 1: you're getting so you're like to have More buying power you're getting powers But none of those things actually win the game for you or wins the game for you are those green cards that don't do anything Usually right exactly.
Speaker 1: So no Panic time happens when people realize the game's ending and they get as many green cards as they can.
Speaker 0: All right, so the the implicit Idea in all of those games is that you have to decide at some point in the game.
Speaker 0: Obviously in the early game, you're not getting the victory points.
Speaker 0: You're in the early game.
Speaker 0: You can't get the victory points.
Speaker 0: You're getting all these other things to build a machine to get the victory points and it's sort of a gradual Gray line.
Speaker 0: you can get some victory points early, right?
Speaker 0: You can also maybe get some big money late and you can sort of Transition slowly from focusing on one to the other as the game goes and sort of feel your way through Right and then at the duchy panic time hard shift into victory point only mode.
Speaker 0: Yeah, no No return is a game that is pretty much taking that game mechanic making it explicit and Focusing on it to the exclusion of all else.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so every you're just going around and every turn you're basically like do I Continue to do the a phase or do I say fuck it and go to the B phase, right?
Speaker 0: You literally on your turn your everyone starts in phase a. in phase a what you're doing is adding your Taking tiles and building up a pool of points right that you could score.
Speaker 0: Right, so and then at the beginning of any of your turns you can say, you know what?
Speaker 0: I am switching to phase B. And of course the name of the game.
Speaker 0: There's no turning back, right?
Speaker 0: And as soon as you're in phase B, you can no longer increase your point pool.
Speaker 0: Your maximum score has been set But you are using the rest of the game in order to take that pool of points and actually convert it into points.
Speaker 0: Alright, so if you were to switch in a phase B too early you would end up converting all your potential points into points.
Speaker 0: And you're you would end up.
Speaker 0: the game would continue going with extra turns because you've switched too early And now you're not your met.
Speaker 0: Your score is not gonna be as high as it could have been had you switched a turn later and had a bigger pool.
Speaker 0: If you switch too late What will end up happening is you have a big pool of points that's full of so many points and you can't convert them.
Speaker 0: And then the game ends with some of your points are unconverted and even worse unconverted points are negative points Unconverted points are negative.
Speaker 0: So literally the entire game is decide exactly the right moment of switching from Increase your point pool to choose.
Speaker 0: you start eating up your point pool and converting it into actual points.
Speaker 0: Right, so the same as many many other board games.
Speaker 0: only just that one mechanic You know just super super polished.
Speaker 0: one thing one thing early
Speaker 1: And if you play it with people who are canny at games and who recognize this game for what it is It feels like a high-stakes poker game Like everyone's playing real carefully everyone's looking at each other and then suddenly someone's like phase B and then oh shit
Speaker 0: Right, if you think of a normal board game that has a lot of different things going on Right like a typical euro game is like maybe you know, like a chocolate chip cookie, right?
Speaker 0: This is literally just a chocolate chip It's all marshmallow one ingredient and they made that ingredient digestible and it's pure uncooked form.
Speaker 1: It's just eating the insides of Oreos.
Speaker 1: It's just eating the marshmallows from Lucky Charms and not eating the rest of that poison.
Speaker 0: Yep So yeah, if you you know, the game is quick It's me.
Speaker 0: It's just a bunch of tiles in a in a in a in a bag, basically Yeah, they could be.
Speaker 1: cards like this could be a card game.
Speaker 0: just fine I think the tiles make it easy.
Speaker 0: I guess it could be a card.
Speaker 0: I mean technically any game could be a card game because a card is the most Powerful physical game component.
Speaker 1: I defy you to make Maria a card game You could make.
Speaker 0: you could fear you couldn't make it good, but you can theoretically make Any board game out of cards only.
Speaker 0: no matter right?
Speaker 0: You can replace dice with cards.
Speaker 0: You can replace tiles with cards.
Speaker 0: You can place pawns with cards.
Speaker 0: Any any other game component can be replaced with cards.
Speaker 1: so one that's hardest to replace is maps unless you literally are just a bunch of cards and The map is just one big card.
Speaker 0: Yeah sure big card.
Speaker 1: But the mechanic the actual physical mechanics of the game are pretty good too because they're literally just you're laying out the numbers in Suits of colors and you have to go in order so you'll play.
Speaker 1: have this give-and-take of?
Speaker 1: Do I blow my load now or do I wait for more tiles to come into my hand kind of like lost cities?
Speaker 0: It's basically exactly lost cities.
Speaker 0: the tile playing is.
Speaker 0: it is a hundred percent lost cities.
Speaker 0: you go from high to low.
Speaker 0: right You know you can't?
Speaker 0: you got to put the same color or the same stack.
Speaker 0: You can't go inserting something in the middle of the stack.
Speaker 0: Eleven ten seven.
Speaker 0: well all your eights and nines are worthless now.
Speaker 0: Right you gave up on trying to find them and you can see the stacks.
Speaker 1: everyone else is making that part.
Speaker 0: You can't see their hand.
Speaker 1: nope, but you can see the stacks.
Speaker 0: so do you know the odds?
Speaker 1: So if a bunch of other people are really building big stacks of yellow Then that can inform your decisions in a pretty clear way.
Speaker 0: right and you still need you know When you're.
Speaker 0: when you switch to phase two let's say I build a big old yellow stack like eleven ten nine Eight seven seven.
Speaker 0: right it's got a lot of points in it.
Speaker 0: I need to have in my hand in phase two Tiles with very high number values to be able to eat those away.
Speaker 0: You can't eat up a lot of points unless you have big numbered tiles.
Speaker 0: So it can actually be dangerous to build a very strong pool Even if it doesn't take you very long to build it because it would take you so long to eat it away.
Speaker 0: You'll be left with like an eleven left on the board.
Speaker 0: It's a negative eleven.
Speaker 0: That's bad
Speaker 1: Yep or maybe if you like near the end of phase one when you're getting ready for phase two if your hand is just full of giant numbers then other players might Expect that they'll be able to eat more of their point total than they possibly could and you might start phase B early and just Go for it, and they'll all be left holding the bag
Speaker 0: You know?
Speaker 0: or let's like okay?
Speaker 0: I got my yellows right and I skipped over nine and eight and then I get them later and I go.
Speaker 0: oh I missed.
Speaker 0: I could have put them in my pool.
Speaker 0: It's like well.
Speaker 0: No that's fine.
Speaker 0: That's 17 points You can now eat away from the pool you did make.
Speaker 0: yeah, it's not too bad Just hold it You know.
Speaker 0: just hold on to them if you can't play them or if you see another player really needs something and if it's a big number hold on to it, but all your small numbers you kind of want to like I Feel like when you want to switch to phase two It's like you feel it coming.
Speaker 0: you can just sort of sense it like all right the games that we've reached the peak Play.
Speaker 0: play out all your small things that you can to get them out of your hand.
Speaker 0: So that way when you start phase B You'll have bigger things in your hand and you can have more efficient phase B. Yeah, right if you start phase B with a bunch of small things your phase B's gonna start with a whimper.
Speaker 0: Everyone's gonna see that you move to phase B. You're not gonna eat away that many points right away And then who knows what you're gonna draw out of the bag.
Speaker 0: you could be in big trouble.
Speaker 1: now on a more like abstract level One thing I would say to all of you is that this game?
Speaker 1: Well in the end be a lot like Yahtzee in that if Yahtzee mechanics are in a lot of other games if you get good At Yahtzee, then you will be good at that part of every other game that has it.
Speaker 1: if you get good at no return.
Speaker 1: You will start to recognize all the no returns and all the other games You play.
Speaker 1: like.
Speaker 1: if you play this game and get good at it.
Speaker 1: You will be a god at st.
Speaker 1: Petersburg.
Speaker 0: Yeah, yeah pretty much like I said There's so many other games that have that mechanic.
Speaker 0: right of.
Speaker 0: when do I switch from doing you know working on?
Speaker 0: This part of the game to that other part of the game?
Speaker 0: right you know pretty much every euro game.
Speaker 0: what crown of Amara rims favorite?
Speaker 0: Even seven wonders right when do I seven wonders.
Speaker 0: you start out by building up your little resource stack and then later?
Speaker 0: You're playing greens and blues.
Speaker 0: Right right.
Speaker 0: It's like all right.
Speaker 0: I don't need more resources anymore.
Speaker 0: green green green science science science.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the minion.
Speaker 1: I'm like dutchy dutchy dutchy dutchy right.
Speaker 0: so get good at this game, and then you will be able to See this same mechanic in every other game and be good at it as well.
Speaker 1: quick to play quick to teach Satisfying like half-hour tops.
Speaker 1: to play this game including teaching.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you can learn it.
Speaker 0: You could.
Speaker 0: anyone can play it accessible to everyone not just nerds.
Speaker 1: super good, so the other game.
Speaker 1: We played.
Speaker 1: I don't Think you should buy it.
Speaker 0: I don't know if you can buy square on sale.
Speaker 1: It's an actually.
Speaker 0: It's actually from 2005 But it's considered.
Speaker 0: first look because it was not easy to obtain in the u.s.
Speaker 0: It's like a Japanese published game, and we they somehow got a copy of it designed by a.
Speaker 1: so what I tied you right?
Speaker 0: so basically what this game is is it's Othello.
Speaker 0: you've played Othello also.
Speaker 0: that is Iago or Reversi.
Speaker 1: it's weird how many people to only notice Reversi.
Speaker 1: I ran into a co-worker like last month who?
Speaker 1: Literally had no idea what Othello was.
Speaker 0: I knew it as a fellow because that's what the board game in the store was called Right, but then on like on the computer.
Speaker 0: I was like Reversi.
Speaker 0: What's that?
Speaker 0: And I'm like oh, it's Othello same same and then and then on Linux in KDE Linux KDE on Linux there was a there was like K Iago or something and I was like what is Iago?
Speaker 0: I'm like oh, it's Reversi.
Speaker 0: How many different names are there for this stupid game?
Speaker 0: It's like Klondike solitaire.
Speaker 0: It's all these same names for this different names of this game now.
Speaker 1: I've never seen a game Incorporate Othello so nakedly before except like.
Speaker 1: actually you know what did of all things?
Speaker 1: Wario were on the Gamecube?
Speaker 1: Yes, but it did.
Speaker 1: but the point I want to make and just remember what I'm about to say And we'll get to it in later in this review.
Speaker 1: There is a fundamental problem with Othello in that the heuristics or the math like the hard math to Actually be good at Othello are not really human implementable like humans Cannot do that.
Speaker 1: It is very hard to learn that the right way to be good at Othello at any scale But it is trivial on a small board.
Speaker 0: You could do it it even.
Speaker 1: yeah like a four Tile board sure yeah six tile It's not like the tiniest.
Speaker 1: as soon as you get above like three by three.
Speaker 1: humans cannot be good at Othello.
Speaker 0: Well Othello is typically played on like what?
Speaker 0: five by five seven by seven something like that.
Speaker 0: But yeah, but a lot of the I don't know what the.
Speaker 0: I guess the actual board game is a huge board, right?
Speaker 0: But the most of the apps I played where it would let you choose the board size I remember five by five and seven by seven usually being defaults.
Speaker 1: But there is a easy algorithm for computers that can play Othello perfectly.
Speaker 1: if you play any like random Othello online There's a decent chance it implements that algorithm.
Speaker 1: You will never win.
Speaker 0: There's literally no way to just use that algorithm in your human head.
Speaker 1: It's too difficult for a human to do in their head.
Speaker 1: I don't think anyone's ever played Othello.
Speaker 0: Maybe I'll spend this this my free time.
Speaker 1: I tried.
Speaker 1: I. I actually have some really fucking complex.
Speaker 0: My heuristic for Othello is get in the corner.
Speaker 0: No one could take you once you're in the corner.
Speaker 1: my heuristic is based on a point value that I've assigned to every type of Square on the board and then that and then those points are mitigated or altered by board states.
Speaker 1: But I can't say like I can't say the rule for doing that I've just memorized certain patterns and if I see those patterns in the local area, I know how to interact with that area.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so square on sale is Othello.
Speaker 0: However, there is two big changes to this game, right?
Speaker 0: Change number one.
Speaker 0: Is it normally in Othello?
Speaker 0: Let's say I place in the top left corner and then the bottom right corner.
Speaker 0: all the Pieces on that diagonal would get filled in with my dudes if they're there like if they're filming already.
Speaker 0: Obviously you you're not allowed to play in a regular Othello.
Speaker 0: You're not allowed to play non adjacent.
Speaker 1: Yep, you gotta you gotta place it So there were.
Speaker 0: converts it so that wouldn't be a legal play in regular Othello unless they were all filled in anyway.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we're square on sale.
Speaker 0: It is a legal play for reasons We'll get into.
Speaker 0: but anyway, what happens in square on sale is the same thing I play one and I play another play a second piece and all the in-between places are now mine.
Speaker 0: but instead of just conquering them I Place my pieces on top of the enemy pieces that I've conquered Such that they're each place on the board.
Speaker 0: each square is stacking higher and higher right and how high the stack is is how many points that spot is worth and whoever has the top piece in the stack is The owner of those points.
Speaker 1: So if the yeah square that changed hands more times is just worth more points to whoever has it when the game ends And the game doesn't end when the thing is full like Othello it ends based on a whole bunch of rules Right.
Speaker 0: The second major thing in the game is that it is a bidding game.
Speaker 0: You don't just on your turn go on a spot that you want to go on You bid on a spot you want to go on with money, right?
Speaker 1: And you can then be on a random spot I could be like I'll bid on the corner.
Speaker 1: I'll just go on the corner right now.
Speaker 0: Yep And when you bid you have to basically just outbid the current bid on that spot.
Speaker 0: if there is one There might not be one in which case you could bid like a dollar right.
Speaker 0: you put your money on the spots that and the Next person who has to come around knows how high the bar is for bidding and then you don't get that spot.
Speaker 0: For three turns you bid you put the two on there it flips down to a one Right the next turn and then the turn after that.
Speaker 0: you actually would conquer the spot and if someone out bids you Right, they would take the countdown timer at its current state of two or one Right.
Speaker 0: and we have so now.
Speaker 0: if people keep out bidding on a spot it never ticks down because it just keeps staying Yeah at its current position.
Speaker 1: This is a little.
Speaker 1: it seems a little complex and it is a little bit difficult to teach this but once you start playing it makes sense, basically, you have a limited number of dollars and you can bid and Overbid and you'll just leave a pile of dollars on the space
Speaker 0: and when you basically what it means is you bid on a space And you win the space if no one out bids you for twice around the board.
Speaker 1: Yep, but Once you win a space Yeah You put your law square on top.
Speaker 1: But now your money stays there.
Speaker 1: and if it's us any space other than the edges every round Instead of doing your bid you can spend an action to take a dollar from all the stacks you've left out there.
Speaker 0: So you might normally on your right.
Speaker 0: so on your turn if you have any money in the middle nine spaces You would pick up one dollar from each of the nine spaces.
Speaker 0: Right that's left hanging out there to get your money back slowly because you have a limited money supply You just start with all your money, right?
Speaker 0: It's not like you're making money.
Speaker 0: It's like you start with all your money you put it out to bid and after if you get outbid you get all the money Back, but if you successfully bid then the money you bid slowly comes back to you, right?
Speaker 0: From I guess your people paying rent who live in the building you own.
Speaker 0: Yes is the metaphor, right?
Speaker 0: But if you put money on the outside spaces that not the nine central spaces the outside Five ten sixteen spaces, right?
Speaker 0: That money?
Speaker 0: because the outside spaces are stronger because it's a fellow right?
Speaker 0: Those are harder to take away.
Speaker 0: They're not more powerful.
Speaker 1: They're not as powerful as an Othello because someone doesn't have to maneuver Heuristically to take them.
Speaker 1: they can take them just by bidding on top of you Any time.
Speaker 0: those out the money that you put in those outside spaces.
Speaker 0: You don't just get back slowly from rents.
Speaker 0: You have to forgo bidding for a turn and then you can take one dollar from every stack you have on an outside space.
Speaker 0: so if you go for a lot of outside spaces try to make lots of strong Othello plays and put out lots of your Building square tiles then you will end up with your money stuck in the outside edges of the board.
Speaker 0: You'll have to spend your turns getting that money back when other people will come in and actually reconquer all the spaces.
Speaker 0: Yeah, while you're not bidding.
Speaker 0: and now what did you actually get right?
Speaker 1: and then I think the game ends.
Speaker 1: There's a bunch of conditions.
Speaker 1: But what are the conditions?
Speaker 1: is I think what if every square square has something in it?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think if every square has something in it the game end.
Speaker 1: if one player puts out others.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if you put out all your squares the game ends.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I Forget there might be another end condition, but there's another.
Speaker 0: This is one other mechanic.
Speaker 0: There's one other mechanic involving some jammies on the board to incentivize you spaces.
Speaker 0: There's little jammies on the board at the early game.
Speaker 0: So that let you like, you know can't get some extra points here and there.
Speaker 0: It's a sort of so if you go early and get conquered late, you still got some points for going early.
Speaker 0: But that's not really a big deal.
Speaker 0: It's more of a balancer Yep, though.
Speaker 1: They are substantial amounts of points.
Speaker 1: It's hard to get points in this game.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they're not insignificant, but they're they're just sort of like there.
Speaker 1: but that endgame condition that sort of leads to my point.
Speaker 1: Remember that heuristic thing.
Speaker 1: So Othello has Non-human like implementable heuristics like Othello.
Speaker 1: humans basically can't be good at Othello But this game plays in the same heuristic space, but because of all these differences from Othello.
Speaker 1: No, Othello heuristics actually work.
Speaker 1: So it's as complex as Othello in terms of humans probably can't build reasonable heuristics But simultaneously people are good at Othello will not actually necessarily be good at this game because for example in Othello If you get a corner space, there is literally no way to lose that.
Speaker 1: No, like it's invincible in this game Like corner spaces just get eaten.
Speaker 1: in Othello you can assign very clear point values to like how Worthwhile the space is because once the space is in it's locked in.
Speaker 1: it can only be taken from you by being attacked.
Speaker 1: within the placement rules of the game here, there are multiple avenues for attack and Othello ends Well when the game is sort of full and complete kind of like a go ending.
Speaker 1: but this game ends on other conditions.
Speaker 1: So you can't rely on the board filling.
Speaker 1: the game might end well before it fills and you're just hosed.
Speaker 1: So you can't even rely on any knowledge of Othello to be good at this game, right?
Speaker 0: Like I had a pretty good play on the board but then the game ended before my Night.
Speaker 0: the ticker ran out on my bid and the result of that was I didn't make the big play and my score Suffered a lot because of the timing of the game ending.
Speaker 0: not even worse made a bad play.
Speaker 1: I was doing really well in the beginning, but then I lost a bunch of places.
Speaker 1: But that was fine because based on my Othello heuristics because I played a hell a lot of Othello I knew that I would be able to retake those places pretty easily and I had a plan.
Speaker 1: And then again the game ended early which is not something that Othello heuristics take into account and I just got boned.
Speaker 1: I went from being in first place by a lot to being in second to last place.
Speaker 0: Yep So even though it's a pretty simple game, it's just got what.
Speaker 0: three or four components right up board squares Little money tokens and some jimmies, right?
Speaker 0: It's all it is is bidding on spaces and then Othello wing when you win the space Right and then adding up score.
Speaker 0: There's not a lot going on But there is way too much.
Speaker 0: that particular combination of simple ingredients ends up being way too complex for human brains.
Speaker 1: Yep, I don't think if I played this ten more times I would be recognizably better at it.
Speaker 1: Like I don't think I could get better at it without study and like for Othello.
Speaker 1: You know how I got better at Othello as a kid.
Speaker 1: study like reading books on it and like playing out Scenarios and memorizing patterns.
Speaker 1: that is what it would take to be very good at this game And I don't know if normal people are willing able to do that or if it's even worthwhile to do it.
Speaker 0: I don't know if the ceiling on the game is as high as go but it's very very high and the floor is Definitely lower than goes floor.
Speaker 0: I think this is much more.
Speaker 0: It's a much more accessible game than go like in go.
Speaker 0: You just basically just get destroyed until you get good enough and recognize enough patterns.
Speaker 0: You can actually kind of play this if you just have some brains.
Speaker 0: Yep, right, but you can't play it really well Right without a lot like super genius level.
Speaker 1: It's almost like while I was playing it like.
Speaker 1: I like to talk a lot about brain field and games Like.
Speaker 1: what does this game feel like?
Speaker 1: this game didn't feel like anything?
Speaker 1: I was.
Speaker 1: I was like reverting back to these like raw Naked heuristics and like I could not model the game in my brain.
Speaker 1: I was following when we first started like three or four rounds in.
Speaker 1: I was modeling it based on Othello and then because of the bidding and everything suddenly my mental model Deviated rapidly from what the game was actually doing.
Speaker 1: so I had to throw it all away and just play completely raw and the only the only
Speaker 0: way I was able to keep the game in my brain is what I was doing was basically Like it became I would try to look and figure out what to do and it became so messy that I just went like blank.
Speaker 0: And when I ended up what I ended up doing was just focusing on a small part of the game only and ignoring the rest.
Speaker 0: Yep, being like, okay.
Speaker 0: Here's my guys.
Speaker 0: Here's the play.
Speaker 0: Here's a play that I see that I can make.
Speaker 0: that could work.
Speaker 0: I'll recognize this one aspect of the game and focus on that and ignore everything else.
Speaker 0: and that didn't work out great But it got me to help me make a decision at least so about what to do.
Speaker 1: I want to play it again, but I don't think that will change anything I have to say about the game and I Really can't recommend anyone buy it.
Speaker 0: No, I mean first of all I don't recommend you.
Speaker 0: buy it because this is such an easy game to make.
Speaker 0: true You can you don't really need to buy it.
Speaker 1: if you could find like your grandpa's Othello You know the one with the green board and the little plastic things like the little.
Speaker 0: also I don't know if the game even has a publisher in the United States or in English.
Speaker 0: We were playing like a you know sort of a messy looking.
Speaker 0: I don't even know who published the copy we were playing well.
Speaker 0: It wasn't the original Japanese published.
Speaker 0: Maybe it was the European one, but we had rules printed from the internet clearly and not a real rule book.
Speaker 0: So yeah, I don't even know if you can purchase it if you can you know.
Speaker 1: this is there are two Threads in the board game geek forum for this.
Speaker 1: the first one was started 15 years ago, and it just says more information.
Speaker 1: The second thread is how to get a copy from eight months ago.
Speaker 1: There are a total of nine posts about this game on all of board game geek right.
Speaker 0: so if this is if this game is up Your alley I recommend You know making a copy and playing it that way and if you get really into it Find a way to get a legit copy.
Speaker 0: somehow I could see a publisher like say big cat games or someone publishing this in English at some point But I don't think that's happening right now.
Speaker 0: So do what you can, but yeah, this is not for everyone.
Speaker 0: But if you are someone who cares about games likes really hard games likes abstract games and bidding games you want that blank feeling that Scott described the like.
Speaker 1: I am in a world with no Heuristics like a world with no rules.
Speaker 1: What do I do?
Speaker 1: Yeah, like if you want a game where you can't apply Most of the things you know about games to it to get better at it quickly.
Speaker 1: This is the game for you, right?
Speaker 0: It's like.
Speaker 0: you know about bidding.
Speaker 0: that doesn't help you.
Speaker 0: you know about a fellow.
Speaker 0: that doesn't help you even though It's a bidding a fellow.
Speaker 1: primarily It's almost.
Speaker 1: you know.
Speaker 1: you know what it's like.
Speaker 1: you know in.
Speaker 1: oh god and music started playing.
Speaker 1: okay there we go.
Speaker 1: There's no weird pipeline with the remote thing.
Speaker 1: I think that got recorded on your channel, but anyway This you know.
Speaker 1: where was I going?
Speaker 1: I lost my entire train of thought.
Speaker 1: now I went blank.
Speaker 1: You know when you there's a language like German language You don't speak and there's cognates like some languages.
Speaker 1: use the same or a similar sounding word to mean something like tea Chai chai like you can kind of figure stuff out.
Speaker 1: It sounds very similar, but then there's false cognates a word that sounds a lot like a word You know, but it actually means something completely different like in French.
Speaker 1: I was writing a thing I remember I said like my aunt a formidable like my aunt is formidable.
Speaker 1: that does not really mean formidable.
Speaker 1: That's not what that means in English effectively, but formidable.
Speaker 1: and what formidable actually means in French.
Speaker 1: like they're not really the same thing.
Speaker 1: So you can be led astray by it appearing to be similar to something You know right.
Speaker 0: in Spanish someone might say cerveza, and you might think oh does that have to do with service, right?
Speaker 0: It's like.
Speaker 0: no that means beer.
Speaker 0: yep, okay.
Speaker 0: It's like.
Speaker 1: so This game has the is false heuristics.
Speaker 1: Yes, if you try to be good at that if you if you're good at bidding and good at Othello I think you will do worse at this game than somebody was never played a bidding game and has never played Othello
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm all right, so yeah, that's that's enough of that.
Speaker 1: I think that was a show.
Speaker 1: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 0: be sure to visit our website At front row crew comm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 1: remember geek nights is not one But four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 0: It's actually recorded at night.
Speaker 1: And the patreon patrons for this episode of geek nights the first time we've ever done this remote.
Speaker 1: That was harder than you would have expected even though We don't actually look at each other when we do the show being in the same room.
Speaker 1: There's a little bit of body language And such and also there's a slight delay in discord.
Speaker 1: that actually makes it really easy to talk over each other.
Speaker 1: So we're gonna have to get better at this.
Speaker 1: But anyway, the patreon patrons for this quarantine episode of geek nights are Ellen Joyce, Heidi McNichol, Barty Green.
Speaker 1: Yeah, just like a dude guy kashar tavish and link eg you hold the queer to my heart.
Speaker 1: I got in one little fight and my mom got scared.
Speaker 1: Clinton Walton J Bants right from New Zealand Ryan parent or open letter Nicholas Brando Chris midkiff the thirst for hydrated Gannon dread lily tannenbrae Chris Reimer Finn Sean Klein Thomas on Shervin Mount Horrell and a whole bunch of other people who do not want me to say their name.
Speaker 1: Stay safe out there Be like rim and Scott and social distance if you can.
Speaker 0: and now I leave you with The problem with comic books if the ink comes off on your hands.
Speaker 0: every time you turn the page You have to wash your hands.
Speaker 0: You turn the page you wash your hands.
Speaker 1: It ain't a page.
Speaker 0: it wash your hands and then you turn the page and then you watch the problem.