Speaker 1: It's Monday July 6th 2020.
Speaker 1: I'm rim I'm Scott and this is geek nights tonight.
Speaker 1: We are talking about quotes obsolete unquote technology.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: So, uh, you know, we can't.
Speaker 1: I can't do a lot of the things I would normally do During the summer in the quarantine like I can't go to the beach I can't do the super long bike rides or like bike rides that require me to take a train or anything Like.
Speaker 1: I'm kind of limited to the area I can get to Can't do any organized bike ride with other people.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: So what I'm increasingly trying to do is Find new ways to interact with the spaces I have access to.
Speaker 1: so on Thursday cuz we had a long weekend Thursday was last day of work Emily and I we went out to bike up and down the west side.
Speaker 1: now You might say but rim the west side is just a normal bike path.
Speaker 1: You can go bike there anytime and I often would normally during kovin.
Speaker 1: that bike path because it's really nice is Crazy crowded during the day like more people are walking and riding up and down that west side path that goes from the bottom of Manhattan to the top of Manhattan now then are like on a normal summer like it's
Speaker 0: also not.
Speaker 0: it's also even if it's empty It's not a great path.
Speaker 0: It's like you do it.
Speaker 0: It's like you do it a few times and then eventually you're like the novelty wears off like well tip of Manhattan again.
Speaker 1: Usually I usually like you head north on it and then you go over a bridge and you keep going north Mmm, so anyway, what we did is around 11 11 30 p.m On Thursday, we went and got our bikes and we went over there to bike around up and down the west side in the middle of the night.
Speaker 1: Okay, that context makes it really fun.
Speaker 1: Like that was really worth doing.
Speaker 1: There's a lot of different animals out.
Speaker 1: There's a very different type of person who's hanging out in those parks In the middle of the night.
Speaker 1: there were some.
Speaker 1: there were some chill parties going on.
Speaker 1: there was some stuff I saw that was fascinating But that was a very fun experience and I intend to All the paths I have biked to death during the day over the last decade in New York.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna do every one of those bike rides again in the middle of the night.
Speaker 0: Okay, the problem is a lot of the places to bike in the middle of the night are places that are Too much car and you'll die because it's night.
Speaker 1: and though there's a lot more than usual in this a lot.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there's a lot of closed places.
Speaker 1: Yeah, a lot.
Speaker 1: some bridges and bike paths closed some parks closed, but the west side never closes.
Speaker 0: No, it's just it's open.
Speaker 0: You can't close it.
Speaker 0: Really.
Speaker 1: Yep I think technically the parks next to it are closed after dusk, but the path itself is not Mmm.
Speaker 1: Alright, you got any news?
Speaker 0: Do I have this?
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, so check it out.
Speaker 0: these people announce this camera right called the pixie camera and At its core this camera is actually a kind of good to great idea and concept, right?
Speaker 0: So first of all, it has a Leica lens mount.
Speaker 0: So like like.
Speaker 0: a cameras are like, you know, the ultimate luxury brand of camera.
Speaker 0: They're super duper expensive But they are sort of unique, right?
Speaker 0: So it's sort of like they're not.
Speaker 0: they're not good and better enough to be worth the insane insane price, right?
Speaker 0: but they are Unique and cool and their lenses are very high quality Even though they cost like, you know way way way more than other lenses.
Speaker 1: I own one like a lens my entire my drive one.
Speaker 1: I don't think you have in any though that my camcorder has a like a made lens in it.
Speaker 0: Oh That's it.
Speaker 0: That's not the same as It's not the same as a like a m mount.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's not like a m mount lens, but like a m mount lens cost more than your entire camcorders.
Speaker 0: So if you want to use those lenses maybe you have one or there are some other companies that have made lenses for the m mount which You know, it's like.
Speaker 0: well if you want to use one of those lenses Even if you get a cheap one like Voigtlander makes some right which are still expensive but cheaper It's like.
Speaker 0: well you have to get some like a camera or there are some cameras you can get like a Bessa I think mates an m mount film camera, but there really aren't M mount digital cameras out there right other than the Leica ones which cost a fortune, right?
Speaker 0: So they're making a digital camera that has a Leica M mount on it and it's and it's not a like a camera.
Speaker 0: So it's like oh, that's that's good.
Speaker 0: Right and it's a rangefinder format camera Which is what like makes and there aren't enough digital rangefinder cameras out there that are high quality Other than like Fuji and Leica.
Speaker 0: right.
Speaker 0: and the other thing is this camera doesn't have an LCD screen on it.
Speaker 0: Which if you have a rangefinder, what do you need a?
Speaker 0: what do you need LCD screen for?
Speaker 0: right it just.
Speaker 0: you know Most digital cameras these days have the feature where you hook it up to an app on your phone and it sends the photos Over to the phone pretty much immediately.
Speaker 0: Yeah phones already got a really good screen like every single like even my Panasonic GF2 had that feature But my gh5 has it gh4 had it One has it.
Speaker 0: Might you may be surprised Jack using Wi-Fi slash Bluetooth my Fuji GF whatever it is 100 whatever has it right?
Speaker 0: So You know, it's a common feature, but they're like, hey, we have that feature now.
Speaker 0: Why do we need the LCD screen?
Speaker 0: We'll just have a little tiny screen on top for your settings your battery life, you know that sort of thing, right?
Speaker 0: And we'll have a little tiny little bit of memory in the camera to buffer up the photos, right and then we'll send them Over to your phone.
Speaker 0: So you just look at your phone Which is a better screen than we can put on the back of.
Speaker 1: this can reminds me of what was the Sony?
Speaker 1: Where it's just like a lens and the lens just sent the images directly to your phone.
Speaker 0: Yeah, exactly, right.
Speaker 0: So this is actually like in concept like hey, it's like I kind of want that.
Speaker 0: That's pretty great, right?
Speaker 0: so here's where it stops getting great is a. The sensor in this camera is only 11 megapixels so 11 11 11.1.
Speaker 0: So and it's a PSC.
Speaker 0: so The Leica lenses are designed for like full-frame sensors, which is what are in the Leica M cameras.
Speaker 0: Right, even the older ones like the Leica 8 and 9 have full-frame sensors Even though the Leica nines has a better as more megapixels than this the like.
Speaker 1: Let me put $10,000 racing tires on my Corolla, right?
Speaker 0: So the thing is I'm not like a megapixel fiend like who cares if you're not printing out the image?
Speaker 0: super enormous.
Speaker 0: You don't need all those megapixels.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm not making billboards right exactly.
Speaker 0: But the point is that You know, it's like hey 11 megapixels, it's like you just use the cat if your phone is the screen the phone has a camera.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so it's a carry around any camera That's not.
Speaker 0: the phone has to be better than the phone.
Speaker 0: I don't think this is better than the phone camera Right.
Speaker 0: So that's problem number one.
Speaker 0: The big problem though is they're charging how much money for this, right?
Speaker 0: $3,000.
Speaker 0: now that might make sense because a like a digital camera the Leica m10 costs like $8,000.
Speaker 1: Yeah Right now no just for perspective my Busted like four-year-old Android phone has a 19 megapixel sensor, right?
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: so if you wanted to write if you wanted to get a Leica m9 like a used one right which is a full-frame sensor That's been a takes the same lenses and is better than this and has a screen on it.
Speaker 0: You can get one of those for two to three thousand dollars.
Speaker 0: So cheaper than the pixie Right, but the real killer is that you could get.
Speaker 0: this has an aps-c sensor right now full-frame.
Speaker 0: you could get a Fuji Like X Pro 3 or whatever.
Speaker 0: It's called right.
Speaker 0: the Fuji makes rangefinder digital cameras.
Speaker 0: Yeah, tell it has a Fuji mount on it, right as opposed to a Leica M mount.
Speaker 0: But that thing only costs like $1,800, right and sure it has a screen on it.
Speaker 0: But it also does hurting me.
Speaker 0: it's cool, it's also vastly.
Speaker 0: it's vastly superior to this camera in every way.
Speaker 1: Hey, this doesn't even have a SD slot.
Speaker 1: You can't even put a card into it, right?
Speaker 0: Exactly.
Speaker 1: My phone doesn't have enough storage to keep all the raws.
Speaker 1: I take when I go out My phone does.
Speaker 0: but the point is is that Four-year-old busted Android.
Speaker 1: I've got a 60 this camera would make.
Speaker 0: this camera would make a ton of sense.
Speaker 0: It'd be amazing if it cost a few hundred dollars and maybe it was micro 4/3 and maybe had a better sensor.
Speaker 0: You know micro 4/3 wouldn't help it right, but just a better sensor.
Speaker 0: But yeah charging $3,000.
Speaker 0: The thing makes no sense whatsoever to exist.
Speaker 0: I don't understand.
Speaker 0: Why would anyone would buy this ever even if you're rich.
Speaker 0: if you're rich you can just buy a life.
Speaker 1: So I do get the impression there's a weird segment of the camera market.
Speaker 1: That's because I've seen like ads and people talking about this specific area in the business world of trying to sell like Cameras to people who use their cell phone for most photos but perceive that a handheld camera will do better.
Speaker 0: But handheld camera will do better if you buy one that's better.
Speaker 1: Yep, but who don't know how to use photography and in practice Want to interact with their photos entirely on their phone like they just want?
Speaker 1: it's like an accessory to their phone The accessories the wealth.
Speaker 0: so first of all, this is $3,000 so it's hitting only luxury people, right?
Speaker 1: Somebody doesn't know that their iPhone is probably literally better than this.
Speaker 0: So what I see so what I have seen from the celebrity Instagram crowd Right is people buying Leica cameras that are not the m10 the Leica ones that are easier to use, right?
Speaker 0: And I've seen them buying.
Speaker 0: also a very popular thing to do is get film cameras.
Speaker 0: So the context g2 is like an old film camera that's sort of like an instant kind of 35 millimeter deal That does have sort of interchangeable lenses and it's become it's still.
Speaker 0: it has become crazy popular And the price of it is very vastly inflated.
Speaker 1: What are the listeners even said?
Speaker 1: you can get a full-frame Sony a7ri 42 megapixel for less than this.
Speaker 0: Yes, you can.
Speaker 0: So this and I and you know what you can also connect your phone to that and get your photos sent directly over Right, so I don't know why.
Speaker 0: what they're thinking with this camera?
Speaker 0: it makes it makes no sense.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it just makes no sense to me at this price.
Speaker 0: it should be like $200.
Speaker 0: Then it would be amazing.
Speaker 0: I might buy one like $200 right just to you know, why not?
Speaker 0: So yeah, that's a thing.
Speaker 0: and then it's sort of related camera news, right?
Speaker 0: Olympus the only maker of micro four-thirds Cameras.
Speaker 0: well, not the only I mean there are a few other ones like black magic makes a few and such and such.
Speaker 0: but the only major manufacturer of micro four-thirds cameras besides Panasonic Olympus has sold their camera their consumer You know camera division to this other Japanese company and that oh my air conditioner is still on making noise.
Speaker 1: That's fine.
Speaker 1: No, mine's on to buy did.
Speaker 0: like though it is.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: I'm leaving.
Speaker 1: I'm leaving it on.
Speaker 1: that's fine.
Speaker 0: Deal with the deal with the noise listener, it's outside Yeah.
Speaker 0: So they have sold their camera business to some other Japanese company and that Japanese company is basically a shady liquidator.
Speaker 1: So I had an article that was my original link for this news that went out into a lot more depth about the liquidator.
Speaker 1: I got a 404 and I tried to go back to that page.
Speaker 1: So I'm like.
Speaker 0: Yeah, anyway, the point is Yeah, what this means for the future of micro four-thirds as a camera platform is sort of like a who-knows kind of deal.
Speaker 0: Right Panasonic could keep it alive or not.
Speaker 0: It's open so people can still make those cameras.
Speaker 1: It sounds the only other company you probably could keep it like fully alive because they have Panasonic.
Speaker 0: right, right.
Speaker 0: So so does a limp.
Speaker 0: but Panasonic Has you know added and they are making those other cameras that have a full-frame sensor?
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah Which has their their partner with Leica.
Speaker 0: It's the L mount cameras, right?
Speaker 0: So It's like.
Speaker 0: well, they're still making micro four-thirds stuff, but they have also launched this other line of You know cameras, right?
Speaker 0: So will they continue mega four-thirds or not?
Speaker 0: so if micro four-thirds dies and no one makes stuff forward anymore then a You might be able to get it for cheap Especially if you're not a professional like.
Speaker 1: that's how I get a lot of audio equipment.
Speaker 0: It's still great, right?
Speaker 0: Nothing wrong with it, right?
Speaker 1: If it dies dies, I'll go pick up a bunch of used lenses, right?
Speaker 0: Exactly You can get a whole bunch of stuff.
Speaker 0: or B You could sell your stuff to the people looking to pick up the cheap stuff Especially someone who's incorporated it into a professional workflow and doesn't want to have to change their pipeline or change Well, okay, so and then buy something else.
Speaker 0: right you switch a different platform, but I think the professional you just mentioned, right?
Speaker 0: That's the people where they sort of can't necessarily stick with it unless they have a ton of stuff because you can't get a repair You can't get a replacement.
Speaker 1: You can't get a warranty if this stuff is like, yeah I don't know how many of you have used professional camera equipment But it's getting support for it is really important because things break and weird stuff happen.
Speaker 1: I with this face you're like.
Speaker 0: if you're like say a professional photographer you're doing like, you know magazine stuff, right?
Speaker 0: And you're out.
Speaker 0: you're out travel you're doing.
Speaker 0: you're traveling the world taking photos It's like and you're shooting on Olympus.
Speaker 0: this usually because you're like.
Speaker 0: Olympus is sponsoring and supporting you with stuff, right?
Speaker 0: So it if anyone who is like one of those Olympus photographers now has to switch to something else Right, because even though they probably still have a bunch of gear and it will probably still work They can't be out on a shoot and need help and get boned, right?
Speaker 0: They need to have a living company behind them.
Speaker 1: like you're one really really low light lens get stolen and now you're just screwed because there's literally no way to get another lens like That for your platform, right?
Speaker 1: Except for the one shady guy on eBay who has one for a lot of money.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and you do is the one he sends you gonna work a whole.
Speaker 0: so So that's a. that's a thing now.
Speaker 0: So if you're buying camera if you're getting into a camera platform from nothing, right?
Speaker 0: It's like, you know micro four-thirds is still great, right?
Speaker 0: Are you gonna are you gonna spend a bunch of you know?
Speaker 0: You could go and get it for way cheap from someone dumping it and you know get in on the the cheap.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna keep an eye on on eBay because I could use a better zoom lens.
Speaker 0: Yeah, or You could you know get something else and avoid a dying.
Speaker 1: So in some other news Supreme Court Has a lot of rulings recently and I think historically they very rarely continued to issue more rulings into July Like they're doing more than usual.
Speaker 0: They're they're doing it.
Speaker 0: You know, I guess I don't know if the how the the online Arguments of Affected.
Speaker 1: I saw like scones last night people just kind of freaking out about the fact that they issued more in July.
Speaker 1: No, but they actually did a ruling that I didn't know was the case cuz I wasn't paying attention.
Speaker 0: Supreme Court algy-related.
Speaker 1: Yep today a little while ago like right before we did the show upheld a 1991 law that bans robo calls to cell phones.
Speaker 1: Now you might be wondering but black dynamite I Get an infinite number of robo calls to my cell phone.
Speaker 1: just because this is the law does not mean that anyone has been capable Of enforcing it at any point.
Speaker 0: Oh There's a law that you're not supposed to drive over X miles an hour on the road.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like dynamite Everyone's driving crazy fast on the road and no one's getting in trouble for it.
Speaker 1: So yeah I've tried to figure out what the deal was with.
Speaker 1: like what was the lawsuit around this that took until the year?
Speaker 1: 2020 to resolve.
Speaker 1: so here's the deal basically in Congress made a bullshit exception to this law That allowed automated robo calls to any phone number, even if it's a cell phone for the purposes of collection of government debt.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm, like.
Speaker 1: that's an oddly specific loophole.
Speaker 0: I think that's you know, as long as the government is the one doing the collection, right?
Speaker 0: You know like you are mine He's.
Speaker 1: so part of the ruling actually addressed that as well.
Speaker 1: quote six justices agreed that by allowing debt collection calls to cell phones Congress quote impermissibly favored debt collection speech over political and other speech in violation of the First Amendment.
Speaker 0: interesting because I was thinking each I See, but the way I would think of it is like what you're collecting.
Speaker 0: government debt Right is like it would be.
Speaker 0: the actual government is making the call right not some debt collector?
Speaker 1: No, but if a debt collector owns government debt like a student loan, yeah, see that's bullshit, right?
Speaker 0: That shouldn't even be allowed to happen, right?
Speaker 0: It shouldn't be legal for a non the non government to hold government.
Speaker 0: It should be like the IRS is calling you because you owe back taxes, right?
Speaker 0: It's like yeah They should be able to call yourself.
Speaker 1: So if that's the only way to contact you, so basically the lawsuit was a bunch of political consultants and pollsters.
Speaker 1: We're trying to get the entire law struck down because they want to make robocalls to cell phones.
Speaker 0: for a million reasons, of course Yeah, because they're the only ones right because the ban right is ineffectively banning robocalls from shady people.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right, but they are acting.
Speaker 0: they're legitimate organizations, right?
Speaker 0: They're political pollsters in the US right there, right?
Speaker 0: And so the law actually does stop them from giving you robocalls, right?
Speaker 0: It's the people who are successfully making robocalls.
Speaker 0: are people outside the law legal framework of the United States, right?
Speaker 1: So basically from what I can gather the issue was whether or not Congress could allow some speech but not other speech.
Speaker 1: and If they can't make those kinds of distinctions that the whole law should be unconstitutional.
Speaker 0: But yeah, I think it's clear that it can't if it can't be based on the content of the call.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so it looks like I haven't read the.
Speaker 1: this like just is kind of breaking news.
Speaker 1: I haven't read the opinion yet, but it looks like this backfired on them and the Supreme Court actually even got rid of that 2015 exception.
Speaker 1: Okay There's a money quote here America from the decision.
Speaker 1: Americans passionately disagree about many things, but they are largely United in their disdain for robocalls.
Speaker 0: That's true.
Speaker 1: During arguments in the case Justice Stephen Breyer got a cut off when someone tried calling him.
Speaker 1: He said after he rejoined the court's arguments quote the telephone started to ring and it cut me off the call but I don't think it was a robocall.
Speaker 1: so I think I think the Online arguments are not going super well based on that statement.
Speaker 1: I feel like they're getting interrupted into.
Speaker 0: I'm curious.
Speaker 0: I know we have some international listener out there at least one, right?
Speaker 0: Are there robocalls a problem in other countries right as they are in the u.s.
Speaker 1: Like?
Speaker 1: this is the broader point why I brought up this news in the u.s.
Speaker 1: Robocalls are bad enough to where the idea of a phone number is just fucked.
Speaker 1: Most people don't answer their phone when it rings at all or if they have put it.
Speaker 0: There is a setting on my iPhone and everyone should be aware of this setting it.
Speaker 0: My iPhone is set to automatically not ring if the phone number that is calling is not in my contacts.
Speaker 0: Yep, there's a similar Android setting and if somebody wants to call me And it's a legit call they should be leaving a voicemail, right?
Speaker 0: So sometimes it's pretty rare that a robocall leaves a voicemail, but it happens occasionally Yeah, right, and I just delete it.
Speaker 0: no big deal.
Speaker 0: And I know it doesn't interrupt me or bother me.
Speaker 0: It happens super rarely right and I have an app that I you know, there's various apps out there.
Speaker 0: I don't know which ones are better.
Speaker 0: So I don't recommend one or over the other.
Speaker 0: But I picked an app from the App Store that blocks many robocalls.
Speaker 0: So that helps also.
Speaker 1: but the broader point here is that Because like look there's a Supreme Court case about they had to pass a law to block spam in the United States on phones because of the very heavy restrictions and Regulations around the telephone network because it was invented a long time ago.
Speaker 1: There's a lot of regulation around it.
Speaker 1: it is used very differently today from how it was used back then, but basically By because of all these restrictions on the ability to restrict phone calls No one like Verizon or Sprint or anyone who runs the cell network could probably just block these robocalls automatically today by flipping a switch like that would be trivial just like spam blockers,
Speaker 0: but
Speaker 1: Generally, and I'm not getting into specifics There's a lot of laws and regulations that say phone calls have to get through.
Speaker 1: you can't arbitrarily block phone calls Even though most people would gladly let someone arbitrary block arbitrarily block phone calls to them to avoid these robocalls.
Speaker 1: The only reason people use email today is because there's no such regulation.
Speaker 1: It's not illegal to block spam So everyone blocks spam, but it's effectively illegal to block robocalls Thus making phones completely worthless as a means of contacting someone who you have not already contacted.
Speaker 1: The reason this is an even weirder problem now Is that Phone calls from numbers you don't recognize are one of the primary means of doing contact tracing for COVID.
Speaker 1: and it turns out I read a separate article Nobody answers their phones when the government calls and nobody even listens to the voicemails when the government calls.
Speaker 1: So contact tracing is not working that well because people are trained to know that anytime their phone rings and they don't know the number It's spam and they don't answer it.
Speaker 1: There's no way to solve this without radically restructuring how telephone numbers are regulated.
Speaker 0: You could just stop robocalls.
Speaker 0: if they blocked all robocalls at the variety at the telco level I think it would only take a matter of months for people to regain trust in phone.
Speaker 1: I think so, too.
Speaker 0: I think it would.
Speaker 0: it would take like no time at all, right?
Speaker 1: It's like we have a society to one accept false positives Like occasionally a call would get blocked that you want it just like we do with email.
Speaker 0: I think it would be pretty rare because almost all of the illegal robocalls are coming from outside the country.
Speaker 0: Yeah from a few sources.
Speaker 1: Ah, but they look so yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right.
Speaker 0: So what I think?
Speaker 0: I think the way it would sort of work is like you would report a robocall To like Verizon would see like a flurry of calls coming in and like a few would get through and then they block.
Speaker 1: Yep, right Like if one source calls multiple phone numbers in the same area code in a short span of time that gets flagged for review automatically
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm,
Speaker 1: but
Speaker 0: or like you would you would get it you would get a call and it would be a scam and you'd report it And then they'd fit.
Speaker 0: they'd look in the logs Figure out exactly where that came from and then close off that route and that person would lose phone service to the u.s.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right from wherever they are or it would be certain.
Speaker 0: The problem is you would get into.
Speaker 0: issues were like, let's say there's like a phone carrier right and say I don't know pick a country country X right and that carrier, you know There's like a neighborhood and in the neighborhood There's a bunch of grandma's Right and one
Speaker 1: robocall scammer
Speaker 0: and one robocall as a little office with some scammers in it, right?
Speaker 0: And they're all on the same phone, you know network thing, right?
Speaker 0: but we already accept the risk of what you just described for all of the All of the grandchildren of those grandmas who immigrated to the United States wouldn't would have a problem with grandma calling them.
Speaker 1: But we already have that today with email.
Speaker 1: if you if your email provider is using IPs that are adjacent to dodgy IPS your emails don't go anywhere.
Speaker 1: We already accept that.
Speaker 0: I guess.
Speaker 0: I guess that's true.
Speaker 0: I mean in the old days before there was AI driven grandma's using the shady ISP that the spammers use for her email.
Speaker 0: You're not gonna get grandma's email in the days before.
Speaker 0: the problem is is that grandma can choose a different email provider.
Speaker 0: Grandma can get a Gmail.
Speaker 0: Yeah, grandma can't change the phone company in country X. Yeah, but grandma well companies just where you live.
Speaker 1: but grandma might be banned from editing with Wikipedia forever because grandma only has two ISP options both of which are blocked by Wikipedia.
Speaker 1: Could be yeah I remember in the RIT days I would like when I ran an email server like I blocked Any email that came from an IP address outside of the United States at one point to try to stop spam?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think the government could also like eminent domain Google's anti-spam technology.
Speaker 0: and You know you know you wouldn't even have to force a company like Google to like make anti-spam for phones.
Speaker 0: You could just make a government contract to do it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they happily would fall over their selves themselves bidding on that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you could just be like hey who wants the government's putting up bids for the the?
Speaker 0: you know the u.s.
Speaker 0: anti-phone spam blocking software That will be applied to all incoming phone calls.
Speaker 0: Who wants to build it?
Speaker 1: One billion dollar but anyway things of the day.
Speaker 1: So I did not know the thing I'm about to talk about.
Speaker 1: This is the kind of thing that I feel like I should have known.
Speaker 1: I feel dumb for having not known it.
Speaker 1: Basically you ever notice how when you get a deck of playing cards like a standard deck 52 cards The ace of spades is always fancier than all the other cards.
Speaker 1: like the design on it is usually a lot fancier than the other Suit.
Speaker 0: yeah, I mean, it's just sort of like.
Speaker 0: it's sort of like a just an accepted truth.
Speaker 0: It's like yeah, the ace of spades is the awesome card ace of spades.
Speaker 0: right?
Speaker 0: this?
Speaker 0: you know the songs ace of spades?
Speaker 0: Yeah, right.
Speaker 0: It's like it just is.
Speaker 0: so Cuz I know I'd not until just now I just sort of accepted it as a truth of the universe.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I saw this tweet and my brain said why didn't you ever ask this question?
Speaker 1: you dumb piece of shit?
Speaker 1: Is the kind of thing you would want to know about this?
Speaker 0: is the guy really want to know now?
Speaker 1: Yeah, so the answer is actually really good.
Speaker 1: This is a Twitter thread that explains it all.
Speaker 1: the answer involves King James the second Goddamnit And the English text system and also a specific breed of chicken.
Speaker 1: I'm not joking So the short answer is and you could read this thread to get all the details.
Speaker 1: is that in England in the 1600s?
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm King James the second introduced a tax on playing cards.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there's been a tax on playing cards even in the US today.
Speaker 1: There's a little sticker on playing cards Yep, so in order to basically Up to that point there were rules requiring anyone making playing cards to put their printers logo on the cards in the deck.
Speaker 1: So people would know who printed those cards to help in the tax investigations.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: So later in 1765 the English tax office introduced to be able to make better compliance with these taxes a Standard design for the ace of spades the duty ace.
Speaker 1: So every deck of cards the ace of spades was the receipt that you had paid the taxes and had a really complicated design.
Speaker 1: That would have been hard to forge and everyone who was authorized to make trading cards had like the die to print this Standard.
Speaker 0: I say so if you were if you were if the at the printing at the printing company where they were making cards.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if you dutifully paid your taxes, the government would give you this thing to let you print.
Speaker 0: aces of spades Yep, and and every few days you are not paying if you're not paying your taxes They would take that away from you or change it for everyone else.
Speaker 0: Yeah So your ace of spades is and you're playing cards would look man and they'd know that that was an illegal.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if you were caught with the deck of cards that didn't have the duty a city What if I just had an old Aztec from pre-tax, I don't know the details of 1765 era English law unfortunately, but the thread actually links to a bunch of references.
Speaker 1: I think we can answer that question.
Speaker 1: So over time they kept making that design more and more complex to make it hard to counterfeit because people got really good at counterfeiting The ace of spades.
Speaker 0: Yeah, of course.
Speaker 1: So they started doing something that today we would probably call more like Baroque Like I made a Baroque design but in the 1800s for Reasons related to those chickens and maybe to a certain Women's hairstyle of the day they called that ridiculous ornamentation that was hard to counterfeit.
Speaker 1: Frizzling they said that it would that the design was frizzled mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: That ties into a woman's hairstyle.
Speaker 1: and then a particular kind of chicken That was called frizzled because they had the Polish frizzle feather.
Speaker 1: The frizzle feather chicken kind of looked like the design the standard design for the ace of spades.
Speaker 1: Once the laws were updated to where they relaxed it and you were no longer required to do the duty ace They came up with modern stuff like that little thing you see on a bicycle deck today.
Speaker 1: People just kept making fancy ace of spades because they had been throughout all of history and many of the card makers Included bird wings and or that frizzled chicken in reference to the frizzling.
Speaker 1: Okay, that's why you'll often see a cock on the ace of spades in a fancy deck of cards.
Speaker 0: Oh, I've seen cocks on the ace of spades before.
Speaker 1: so if this actually answered a lot of vague questions.
Speaker 0: I had never asked Yeah, that sounds great.
Speaker 0: Yeah, somebody got so when I was in college learning The basics of logic and computer science.
Speaker 0: there was a little like free software kind of program They they had a download link for.
Speaker 0: I think ran on.
Speaker 0: I think was like a Java app.
Speaker 0: I think someone might even written at the school I don't know, but it was like a little GUI that would let you you know basically virtually build electronic logic circuits with gates and flip-flops and clocks.
Speaker 0: and you know voltage ground light bulb.
Speaker 0: You know little LCD displays with numbers on them.
Speaker 0: You know all the basic circuitry without having to get out your breadboard or your soldering iron or any of that bullshit, right?
Speaker 0: You could just do it right on your screen with your mouse and keyboard because I you know Even though I went to school 20 years ago.
Speaker 0: It wasn't Right And it saves the school a lot of money.
Speaker 0: You don't have to buy have a whole electronics lab full of you know all these supplying all the students with gates and everything.
Speaker 0: You know, it's like everyone can just do it home all they want, right?
Speaker 0: So, you know, I haven't seen an app like that like around practice haven't looked for one.
Speaker 0: I'm sure there's plenty to choose from But I discovered this one recently, I don't know how old it is.
Speaker 0: it might be around for a while But it's new to me.
Speaker 0: It's a website called logic dot Lee.
Speaker 0: logically, but the dot goes after the C, right?
Speaker 0: And their app cost $60.
Speaker 0: It is not free But they have a free demo.
Speaker 0: you just logically dot logic dot Lee slash demo.
Speaker 0: that lets you use the app In some limited extent for free, but it even though it is a very limited extent it runs in a browser.
Speaker 0: It runs beautifully.
Speaker 0: It looks like a desktop app and It's.
Speaker 0: I really don't see why you need more features than what I see in this demo if your purpose is to learn The basics of electronic logic right which is all you would really want to do with this I see.
Speaker 0: if your flip-flops Yeah So yeah, I mean you you know, it's like even if you just need a refresher on like how the different kinds of flip-flops work.
Speaker 0: It's like you could just pull one out and mess around with it and be like oh, yeah That's how it works right hook up some light bulbs to the outputs And you know hook up some clocks and switches and power to the inputs, and you'll you know you figure it out, right?
Speaker 0: So yeah, if you you know and also, I guess if you're a student Getting started you know in the computer science land right or electronic engineering land or anything like that if Your school did not teach this to you, or it's maybe recommending some other app this app might be Worth it to you, and you know if you're really doing a lot of this kind of stuff You know maybe the $60 might even be worth it.
Speaker 0: if you're like actually designing circuits You know for some projects or something right?
Speaker 1: Yeah?
Speaker 1: I did looks like actually I like the simulation option that it just it traces the path of all the logic.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's way better than the app that we had in.
Speaker 0: oh yeah, and it's in a web, and it's in a web browser.
Speaker 0: So there you go.
Speaker 0: I just thought it was really cool, and I think it is really.
Speaker 0: if anyone knows there's a better one Let me know cuz you know, but does it there?
Speaker 0: my I imagine there's probably better ones that run on the desktop.
Speaker 0: I don't know if there's better ones that are in a browser.
Speaker 1: right yeah This reminds me a lot of a very similar app I use in like inside of Atlassian confluence to draw like flow diagrams like almost the exact same user Interface.
Speaker 0: oh like yeah, but that's just.
Speaker 0: those are just just something like.
Speaker 0: yeah, it doesn't simulate.
Speaker 0: Yeah, this is actually you know simulating the electricity.
Speaker 0: right you're making the actual circuit.
Speaker 1: Yeah, this is cool stuff.
Speaker 1: all right in the moment We're just hanging out in quarantine.
Speaker 1: stay tuned.
Speaker 1: We're gonna be appearing at a bunch of online conventions And we're as many as we can work our way into.
Speaker 0: we'll figure it out.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I guess we'll do.
Speaker 0: Pat We'll figure write some panels.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 1: yeah I got.
Speaker 1: we got to put in the rest of the packs online ones at least I got to put in the new one.
Speaker 1: you and I were talking about it.
Speaker 0: the packs online panel submissions are live.
Speaker 0: so if you're out there and You have never ever done a panel out of packs.
Speaker 0: Maybe you live somewhere You don't have enough money or whatever.
Speaker 0: you don't have the means to go to a packs.
Speaker 0: right.
Speaker 0: you have any panel idea whatsoever Right?
Speaker 0: I highly recommend Submitting a panel submission to packs online.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you have nothing to lose.
Speaker 0: There's no penalty for getting rejected.
Speaker 1: Yeah, worst case They say sorry we can't fit you in this year cost nothing to submit right.
Speaker 0: so submit B. There's gonna be a lot of acceptances because packs online is gonna be so many days long right That they're going to need content to fill it up, so I'm willing to bet I don't have confirmation of this But I'm willing to bet that Content that would not be accepted at an actual in-person packs where time and space are more limited.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we'll be more likely to be accepted to packs online Like we're submitting like.
Speaker 1: so you know we're submitting our normal kind of stuff But we're gonna submit some weird or like some forward-thinking types of panels that we normally wouldn't even bother trying to submit to packs right.
Speaker 0: And lastly it could be you know your chance to like get out there right?
Speaker 0: so you know.
Speaker 0: maybe You you know you're not someone like us who's like a media podcast II person who's got like a thing to say.
Speaker 0: Maybe you're just making maybe you made a tiny little indie game, right?
Speaker 1: It's like do a panel and promote it.
Speaker 0: You can get free promotion Just you know.
Speaker 0: find some way to spin it to make it look like your panels not just an advertisement for your little indie Game.
Speaker 0: right and go out there, right?
Speaker 0: Make it happen.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if you're passionate about a title like a genre of you like saying you play 18xx games And that's your whole life I'll bet a panel just explaining what the deal is with those and like walking through like the history of them would probably I would Go to a panel like that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like I've played enough 18xx that I could do that panel.
Speaker 0: But there's people who are way deep in 18xx is their only thing in life, and they are the ones who should do that panel.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we will focus on the panels where we actually have some expertise right?
Speaker 0: It's like there's a lot that I could do, but I want you know there's only some that I should do.
Speaker 0: So it's like think about what you should do right.
Speaker 0: because guess what you can yep and you know.
Speaker 1: even if like I know some people who have submitted panels to packs for like a People who read those submissions at packs and other kinds like it like they notice a lot of times you might be surprised They'll see.
Speaker 1: felt like I used to run a panels department.
Speaker 1: I'd look through submissions And I'd see panel ideas that I thought were cool that I couldn't fit in.
Speaker 1: but over the years I'd see like oh that same person keeps submitting that idea that I think is cool that I can't fit in.
Speaker 1: and one year I was like you know what fuck it.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna make room for that dude who submitted this panel on mushing for like five years.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna put it in the schedule.
Speaker 0: so the panel.
Speaker 0: not enough people went to it But I went to it.
Speaker 0: that panel was good.
Speaker 1: Yeah that I wish I could have gone to it.
Speaker 1: I was busy.
Speaker 0: a lot of dog pics.
Speaker 1: if I recall correctly I was sidelined dealing with a convention crisis during that panel.
Speaker 0: dumb dumb dumb.
Speaker 1: But convention crisis on the scale of real-life crisis is the equivalent of someone spilled some water like it's not Kids crying because Markiplier is not here whatever.
Speaker 1: All right, yeah, otherwise YouTube discord all that stuff.
Speaker 1: Let's get into it.
Speaker 1: There is a lot of technology that oh yeah people assume based on nothing is Obsolete, but in fact is widely used and not only not obsolete, but still like very important, right?
Speaker 0: So I'm you know I thought of this because I was thinking about the earlier picture.
Speaker 1: I put up on the screen is MIDI Right.
Speaker 0: yeah the earlier news I thought about you know cuz like you know with the micro four-thirds dying right and it now it's like sort of obsolete But also it's like hey actually this that stuff.
Speaker 0: It still totally works right and it's totally still useful But there's nothing wrong with it right and I look around and it's like actually you know it's like some technology is truly Obsolete like there is.
Speaker 0: you know it had its time and it is just worse right.
Speaker 0: for example the five and a quarter floppy drive.
Speaker 0: Right it is just worse.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and any other kind of storage the movable removable store I know.
Speaker 1: second a three and a quarter inch floppy appear.
Speaker 1: three and a half three and a half five and a quarter three and Not that that knowledge matters anymore.
Speaker 0: It doesn't matter.
Speaker 1: That's how I was that there was my dumb mnemonic.
Speaker 1: I always remembered five and a quarter three and a half and I met.
Speaker 0: only purpose today of a five and a quarter drive and disk is to Operate if just for historical museum curation preservation purposes, right?
Speaker 0: For places that still have old hardware being used yeah that could be could and should be replaced But for some reason they just haven't upgraded yet.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but but it's what.
Speaker 1: that's the difference.
Speaker 1: or something that is Obsolete, but is still being used as opposed to something that is not actually obsolete.
Speaker 1: You just think it's obsolete, right?
Speaker 0: So something that you think is obsolete, but is not actually obsolete for example the CRT Tube right yeah, so it's like okay.
Speaker 0: You know LCD screens are pretty much mostly just better.
Speaker 0: Why would you still want a tube right television?
Speaker 1: Do you need an extremely high refresh rate for some reason?
Speaker 0: right so they are making LCDs these days with extremely high refresh rates Right, but this they still have.
Speaker 0: this sort of like.
Speaker 0: you know small amount of lag that goes on right and The amount of lag that you get.
Speaker 0: you know if you got like a GameCube, but you want to play smash melee It's like you need a CRT.
Speaker 0: You can't just can't even on an LCD with like no pre-processing bullshit.
Speaker 0: It's like.
Speaker 0: it is noticeably significant to the point where people who aren't crazy can tell No, that's what I would say.
Speaker 1: the reason It's not obsolete even though that might sound very similar to the example where you said something is obsolete like a museum.
Speaker 1: I think the difference is people there is a current need to actively play these games and non CRT technology cannot Completely 100% handle that use case Mm-hmm once they're in.
Speaker 1: if they the future there's a plasma display or an LCD that is 100% as good as the CRT for that use case.
Speaker 1: that nanosecond CRTs are now obsolete in that realm forever.
Speaker 0: Yep Another thing related.
Speaker 0: right it's like analog film right.
Speaker 0: it's like you think oh analog film.
Speaker 0: Why would you use that?
Speaker 0: It's just worse right except actually it's not just worse.
Speaker 0: the resolution on analog film is actually insane Right compared to the resolution of even the best digital cameras around.
Speaker 0: obviously if you get like a digital Medium format camera the resolution is so insane that you're not going to improve on that with analog right, but actually cost wise Right.
Speaker 0: so to get a full-frame Camera, you know with a really high resolution sensor costs many thousands of dollars You can go to the drugstore and still buy a disposable 35 millimeter film camera.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and That has the same size sensor as like a you know Nikon d4.
Speaker 1: we don't want to derail the show by talking about film grain and how they're right.
Speaker 1: ultimately a resolution on like.
Speaker 1: it's not.
Speaker 0: There is ultimately a resolution.
Speaker 0: But the point is you know the the even though the power of it has been you know of analog film has been obsoleted by Digital cameras, it's so much cheaper, right?
Speaker 1: Well like regular old cassette tapes were not as obsolete by better technology existing because they were still a like accessible means of accessing audio recording technology to consumers.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm like when other came out because that's we're not obsolete because I couldn't record to a CD Cassette tape was the only way I could record anything.
Speaker 1: because that's we're not obsolete until well well into the CD our era Correct.
Speaker 1: and this is a nuance that a lot of people who aren't close to specific technologies Really like lose track of.
Speaker 1: like it amazes me how many people even like people who are our age This isn't like an old young thing who just assume tech they haven't seen in a while is obsolete Especially when it comes to things like development frameworks Like yeah Java Web Start that sucks, right?
Speaker 1: There are still cases where Java Web Start or the successors of Java Web Start make sense.
Speaker 1: They're not obsolete yet.
Speaker 1: They're just not preferred Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there's all.
Speaker 0: if you're not about software that's not obsolete.
Speaker 0: Oh boy, right?
Speaker 0: There's there's tons, right?
Speaker 0: It's like there's weird image formats.
Speaker 0: Like, you know that it's like oh you think oh, we'll just use JPEGs.
Speaker 0: now I have.
Speaker 0: it's like what do we need these other, you know image confirm?
Speaker 0: It's like no, there's still a time and a place for for a bitmap for a tiff.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know it's like all these old things or all these video codecs and formats like another thing we can't get deep into but There are video.
Speaker 1: when you think most people when they think of video codecs What they're actually thinking of is the container format and inside of that container are audio and video like codecs.
Speaker 1: I'm really oversimplifying here.
Speaker 1: a Huge variety of those exist and a lot of them are in wide use for a lot of reasons.
Speaker 1: some things are Extremely low CPU usage like they don't need a lot of power to decode but they're very large instead.
Speaker 1: Like there's a lot of trade-offs there.
Speaker 1: Or like your your film camera example.
Speaker 1: another example of where you might want a film camera or where there's a use case for them Is the requirement to photograph?
Speaker 1: Phenomena in a place that has an extreme amount of electromagnetic radiation.
Speaker 1: that would prevent a modern digital camera from functioning.
Speaker 1: Mmm, but a physical camera with only physical mechanisms and film could take photographs in such an environment?
Speaker 0: Yeah, sure.
Speaker 0: Absolutely.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but what I run into the most that I think is the funniest.
Speaker 1: and even in high school I ran into people who tried to tell me that MIDI was obsolete like MIDI MIDI MIDI.
Speaker 0: actually MIDI 2.0 Came out and is vastly superior but MIDI one is used extensively in modern music production.
Speaker 0: MIDI is everywhere.
Speaker 0: You can't avoid it.
Speaker 0: if you actually go to music studios, especially songwriters Those sorts of people it's like there's just MIDI everywhere.
Speaker 0: It's just like outside of the music industry like studios recording studios that set of place.
Speaker 0: It's like you don't see the MIDI.
Speaker 0: Yep, right because maybe you could.
Speaker 0: it's weird because MIDI used to be a thing that was in everyone's computers in like the 90s And it was removed from everyone's computer.
Speaker 0: All right, cuz we don't need it anymore.
Speaker 0: We just have you know.
Speaker 1: But wave my computer still has it because I have pro audio equipment and I have two MIDI keyboards Sure, but most people's computers does not.
Speaker 0: most people will have some sort of software that would if you happen to get a MIDI file And wanted to play it would somehow play it right, but you know used to have a Sound Blaster 16 that had MIDI hardware in it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that was the only is the all 32 audio in your game, right?
Speaker 0: The audio in chips challenge was MIDI files and it would basically, you know Your chips challenge.
Speaker 0: when you played chip challenge on Windows 3.1 It wasn't playing a recording of a song it would actually.
Speaker 0: it was as if there was a digital keyboard Like a Casio keyboard in your computer and chips challenge would play that keyboard Right, like a player piano like like a player piano this while the game was running.
Speaker 0: But it doesn't work that way anymore.
Speaker 1: So this is like MIDI is a good example.
Speaker 1: I want to go a little deeper in like.
Speaker 1: why is MIDI not obsolete?
Speaker 1: because if you look at the actual protocol I mean MIDI 2.0.
Speaker 1: It came out recently, but Five years ago ten years ago 20 years like MIDI has survived through the ages.
Speaker 0: But if you ever using the first time I saw MIDI actually I mean MIDI is so old that they were using.
Speaker 1: when I was in elementary school I was fucking around with MIDI on my 486, right?
Speaker 0: I mean I saw.
Speaker 0: the first time I saw it really set up for music production.
Speaker 0: I had seen it for music on a computer but for the production in high school The there was.
Speaker 0: if you took the music theory class instead of going in band.
Speaker 0: They had keyboards with MIDI and computers and stuff, but but I there was a kid I knew I think he's that I don't know what happened to him.
Speaker 0: I think he's must be a conductor or some shit somewhere.
Speaker 0: But like when I was in it was like my my parents friends kid.
Speaker 0: and even when he was like young He was like that violin playing conducting Prodigy kind of kid, right, you know that kind.
Speaker 0: And in his house, he had a Commodore 64 with MIDI hooked up.
Speaker 1: Oh Yeah, I wasn't until the 486 era But I had a MIDI keyboard connected to my 486 and I was trying to compose music and playing around with it.
Speaker 1: if you read the spec MIDI seems archaic to the point that it's laughable.
Speaker 1: but Among all the way all the proprietary ways people tried to do the simple task of synchronize a bunch of separate instruments together electronically.
Speaker 1: MIDI was the generic format that could work with everything and become a standard because all it really is is a means to Signal basically a piano roll to or from any number of it.
Speaker 1: Well, not any number.
Speaker 1: there was a limited MIDI because this is old technology an arbitrary number of devices.
Speaker 1: MIDI is also used for things like controlling lights and effects on stages.
Speaker 1: as a result because MIDI you can plug an Arduino in a MIDI controller and program something to be like if I hit this key on my keyboard it lights up a light bulb somewhere or does something on my computer like.
Speaker 1: MIDI is an extensible and really useful protocol.
Speaker 1: and Because it's so low-level and so generic But that makes it very obtuse to learn the details of.
Speaker 1: it's difficult to learn how to use MIDI correctly.
Speaker 1: It's more it's easy to learn how to use MIDI to accomplish a task.
Speaker 1: It's hard to learn how many works at the low level because you have to learn a lot of old archaic crap.
Speaker 0: I found I just you know, the That person that I just mentioned.
Speaker 0: Yeah Assistant conductor at New York Philharmonic It's definitely the right person because it says they made their conducting debut at age 11 with the Greater Bridgeport Youth Orchestra.
Speaker 0: So it's definitely the same person.
Speaker 0: so yeah, I guess they went on to go do what they wanted to do good for that person.
Speaker 0: Yeah, all right.
Speaker 1: Now there is a weird case of technology.
Speaker 1: That is Obsolete but necessary but still in use but no one will ever change it like.
Speaker 1: there's an a gray area I'm thinking about is like nuclear weapon control Because that's a weird case where the old technology is Objectively obsolete like to the point of ridiculousness like we're talking 8-inch floppies.
Speaker 1: If you've never heard of an 8-inch floppy, there's a reason that is ancient compared to five and a quarter floppies.
Speaker 0: Yes, but it works.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so and why are you gonna replace it?
Speaker 0: It's working.
Speaker 0: It's still working But you could replace like.
Speaker 0: they probably have a giant room full of giant computers.
Speaker 0: They could replace with one computer.
Speaker 0: But why would you go through the effort?
Speaker 0: you have this thing that works.
Speaker 0: it's sitting there running.
Speaker 0: It's doing its very very important job.
Speaker 0: very very well.
Speaker 0: I don't fuck with it for no reason other than to use less computers, but the fact that it's obsolete Introduced became a feature.
Speaker 1: It's so obsolete that it makes it Extremely difficult to hack or mess with that kind of system Like the amount of expertise you could use.
Speaker 1: you would need to fuck with a system that is as archaic as that.
Speaker 1: Became a feature effectively for this extremely narrow use case.
Speaker 1: Mmm, like so Galactica like it's that.
Speaker 1: it's that situation exactly.
Speaker 0: There's also similar use cases relating to not the Like places on earth or different people's, you know life, right?
Speaker 0: So it's like think about something like an iPod.
Speaker 0: right an iPod is pretty much obsolete because there are just better Portable music playing devices like.
Speaker 0: even the shittiest Android phone with the shittiest UI is Gonna have like a music playing app on it.
Speaker 0: We'll have more storage than an iPod probably more battery life have a better user interface right than an old iPod, right?
Speaker 0: So it's like why would you why would you want the old iPod right?
Speaker 0: It's like well actually The old iPod could be gotten cheaper and people live in a poor place or the battery will last longer.
Speaker 1: Oh, look Sony still makes Walkman.
Speaker 1: There's mp3 players 8 gigabytes of storage.
Speaker 1: That's pathetic compared to a smartphone.
Speaker 1: I get my an Android phone for a quarter this price.
Speaker 0: Maybe it's.
Speaker 0: maybe the iPod is lighter.
Speaker 0: Right because it's you know, it's not.
Speaker 0: the super old ones won't be because they have spinning drives in them But yeah, I had one of those I guess but like an iPod nano is gonna be smaller than any Are about the size of an SD card.
Speaker 0: They're like a tiny little clip.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they're basically iPod shuffle situation Which if you're running biking you just want to bring some music with you But you want it to be as light and unobtrusive as possible.
Speaker 1: There's still a use case for that Thing.
Speaker 0: I mean, you know, I guess Apple watch does it.
Speaker 0: it's also yeah, but you know You get the idea is like something that like, you know, it's like oh this has no purpose anymore.
Speaker 0: It has been defeated.
Speaker 0: But actually if you have a specific case for it, right where you're you're doing a weird thing Right, maybe you're even.
Speaker 0: maybe you're going camping and just want to carry a light load.
Speaker 0: Yeah, suddenly it makes sense.
Speaker 1: like another example when DVD came out it made The purchasing of read-only VHS tapes completely obsolete like overnight especially because the ps2 coming out rapidly increasing adoption and driving down the price of a DVD player, but No one until really the computer era had an accessible means of recording a TV show The time shift it like until we had TiVo's and things like that.
Speaker 1: VHS was the only way to do that and thus VHS was not only not obsolete But was in active use way later than you might realize.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, like way longer longevity than the cassette in a lot of ways.
Speaker 0: You also have some cases where someone has a piece of technology that is so Expensive relative to their wealth, right so that they can't really replace it easily or they wouldn't want to write.
Speaker 1: So like all my old firewire audio equipment if I if I didn't have enough money to upgrade all of that I would still be using all that old firewire audio equipment.
Speaker 0: Well, not just that but like let's say but it is obsolete.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but let's say you have a car, right?
Speaker 0: It's like you don't want to buy.
Speaker 0: just buy a new car, right?
Speaker 0: Each I mean assuming you're you're in car land, right?
Speaker 0: You have no choice or whatever, right?
Speaker 0: Because you shouldn't buy a car.
Speaker 0: But you got an old car and it still works.
Speaker 0: There's no reason to replace it.
Speaker 0: doing so will be expensive even though there are better newer cars, right?
Speaker 0: so this car is so old that it doesn't have like an aux audio input or You know an iPhone Bluetooth integration is an old car.
Speaker 0: So you using like an FM transmit II thing.
Speaker 0: That's an obsolete technology But because you've got an old car right with no reason to replace it.
Speaker 0: you still need that old obsolete Technology to use.
Speaker 0: you can hear music from your new iPhone.
Speaker 1: as a kid I had a device that was an 8-track tape and you could put it into a car a track player and then in the back Of it it had a slot to slide in a regular cassette tape.
Speaker 0: I had one that was Cassette tape and on the outside of it came a wire that you would plug into your iPod.
Speaker 0: I had one of those too and you put it into the cassette tape part of the.
Speaker 1: But I guess The real point I think I can make around this concept because we're just exploring this concept to see if we can come up with like more narrow show ideas taking up one.
Speaker 1: Technology that is specialized and solves a niche problem tends to have a lot more longevity Because there are very few people Willing and able to try to solve those problems.
Speaker 1: MIDI solved the problem well enough.
Speaker 1: Nobody really had a vested interest in making something that fully covered the use cases of MIDI.
Speaker 1: if anything large companies Have an interest in making a competing proprietary format and trying to steal market share over to their bullshit proprietary platform, right?
Speaker 0: It's just because there's something better right doesn't mean it's better.
Speaker 0: You can't.
Speaker 0: it's very hard to unseat something That's good enough.
Speaker 0: if something's that's at the current thing that's out There is kind of sucky and has lots of problems, right?
Speaker 0: Then it is very easy to unseat it with something vastly superior.
Speaker 0: They were it was easy to unseat VHS with DVD.
Speaker 0: Yeah for read-only it was not so easy to unseat DVD with booray.
Speaker 0: Yeah Well in a lot of ways DVD is still sort out there kind of a little bit.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know, it's not.
Speaker 0: it's not totally dead It's more it's less dead like VHS was when DVD came around.
Speaker 1: set-top DVD writers never displaced VHS recorders.
Speaker 1: No computers did that instead.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right, but the other thing I could say is that You can.
Speaker 1: generally.
Speaker 1: this is just like a generalized piece of advice.
Speaker 1: You can make a very good career out of Understanding Something that a lot of people think is obsolete, but in fact is widely used.
Speaker 1: Like that is a way to guarantee you will have a job for the rest of your life.
Speaker 0: I think the last thing is that the Regardless of how much you know computers the actual silicon right is replaced with faster smaller more energy-efficient silicon IO devices are largely Unaffected right.
Speaker 0: It's like it's like oh, okay So I got a camera with a better sensor.
Speaker 0: the sensor is the silicon right I do a newer better digital camera Lenses or lenses man, right?
Speaker 0: Oh, I got a brand new awesome computer.
Speaker 0: Well, your mouse is your mouse and your keyboards your keyboard, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know your your webcam is I guess, you know once once we got like modern laser mice or like modern optical mice.
Speaker 1: There's not a lot more advancement that's gonna happen there anytime soon, right?
Speaker 0: It's like a microphones a microphone, you know, I mean look we can do the stars a guitar speaker.
Speaker 1: We we did the show until like four years ago with the same microphone that Lyndon Johnson used to give presidential addresses, right?
Speaker 0: It's like, you know, you can get some fancy new amp with fancy silicon in it, right?
Speaker 0: You can upgrade that part and then your speakers from your studio in the 70s are probably going to be almost as great as brand New speakers.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's speakers just figures figures right.
Speaker 0: audio, you know video in out audio in out.
Speaker 0: it's like those accessories.
Speaker 0: and You know ancillary devices your headphones, you know that shit does not go out of style.
Speaker 0: It's really hard to replace it because all of those things are good enough.
Speaker 1: Yep, and material science advances are not Destabilizing enough like yeah, they're slightly lighter drivers and modern monitor headphones, but they're not.
Speaker 1: it's not like a revolution Right.
Speaker 0: and Moore's law, you know pushed silicon right to obsolete many many generations.
Speaker 0: very rapidly Right, you know, but now it's Moore's laws kind of slow now.
Speaker 0: So even the silicon obsolete this obsolation is slower than it used to be.
Speaker 1: so, uh, I just Googled for obsolete technology and there's a Wikipedia article that is literally called List of obsolete technology and it's a list of technology and what replaced it.
Speaker 1: and then if it's still used for anything and the Number one is bathing machine Replacement no longer required due to changing social standards of morality.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: old obsolete technology.
Speaker 1: hourglass replacement clock.
Speaker 1: Correct sundial replacement clock.
Speaker 1: swamp cooler replacement air conditioning.
Speaker 1: Still used for dry climates because they're way more efficient.
Speaker 1: if you live somewhere you could use them.
Speaker 1: Yep, this is all linked to this.
Speaker 1: This is actually a really interesting list.
Speaker 1: I wish I'd googled this at the beginning.
Speaker 1: We could have probably driven a lot more conversation by looking at this thing.
Speaker 0: Even even think about sundials.
Speaker 1: beer replacement firearms.
Speaker 1: sword replacement firearms.
Speaker 1: Sure Forts replacement vulnerable to air attack.
Speaker 0: I think this Wikipedia article does not have a lot of editors maybe listeners, I want all the listeners to go to this Wikipedia article and Everyone make one change to it.
Speaker 0: I'll do I'll make I'll make one change to it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'll make one as well.
Speaker 0: Everyone make one edit to this Wikipedia page.
Speaker 0: It'll be like a brigade regaining of a one Wikipedia article, but no Don't play don't vandalize put real like a real update right here.
Speaker 0: do an honest real update to this page.
Speaker 0: as rim Send me a link to the page.
Speaker 1: I think it's something to pack animals replaced by trucks and vans two different articles.
Speaker 1: Ocean liner replaced by airliner.
Speaker 1: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at front row crew.com for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 1: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 1: But unlike those other late shows It's actually recorded at night and the patreon patrons for this Monday episode of geek nights are Alan Joyce Heidi McNichol Mardi Gradia just like a dude guide.
Speaker 1: your option Graham Finch.
Speaker 1: You hold the key to my heart.
Speaker 1: She gave me a kiss and she gave me my ticket.
Speaker 1: Clinton Walton J Banch's render New Zealand Ryan Perrin Nicholas Brando Chris midkiff the thirst for hydrated gannet Gannon dread a Lily Tenebrae Chris Reimer Finn Sean Klein Shervin von Harl and a bunch of people who don't want me to say their names.
Speaker 1: I just uploaded like 12 more standalone and live anime reviews that I'm gonna slowly trickle out on YouTube.
Speaker 1: Maybe I'll post all of them in the patreon earlier.
Speaker 1: I got to figure that out.
Speaker 1: I did as promised start some pre-production on the utana episode.
Speaker 1: I think we have a plan to be able to get that out this month.
Speaker 1: So stay tuned on that.
Speaker 1: the format is gonna be a little different.
Speaker 1: My you'll see what I mean, but basically I'm gonna mostly make the thing myself, but Scott's gonna record his own Independent analysis.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna cut back and forth.
Speaker 1: I think it's gonna work.
Speaker 1: You'll see maybe it won't but It's really hard to do a show like that over discord, so we're gonna do the best we can.
Speaker 1: Anyway, stay safe out there.
Speaker 1: and here's something that is best left forgotten.
Speaker 0: Well years ago a nine-tailed fox suddenly appeared.
Speaker 1: if you believe it I Am a ninja clan ninja clan.
Speaker 0: here we stand Naruto.
Speaker 0: I'm on my way Naruto.
Speaker 0: I'll be okay getting ready to fight on set.
Speaker 0: Come on best friends by my side.
Speaker 0: sasuke is really cool Sakura the beautiful Oh.