Speaker 1: It's Tuesday June 30th 2020.
Speaker 1: I'm rim.
Speaker 1: I'm Scott and this is geek nights tonight.
Speaker 1: We were talking about the ends of games Scott.
Speaker 1: do you hear it?
Speaker 0: The wrong ends.
Speaker 0: let's do this.
Speaker 1: So there is a lot of gaming news and there's even some breaking gaming news.
Speaker 0: So there's a lot of broken gaming news.
Speaker 0: That's for sure.
Speaker 1: We'll start with breaking then we'll go into broken.
Speaker 1: I think let's start breaking because a while ago.
Speaker 1: I don't think we even did a show on it Did we?
Speaker 1: I don't even remember.
Speaker 1: there was a thousand years ago.
Speaker 1: But that Amazon eSport game finally came out in like a beta form, right?
Speaker 0: So all right, so the long the long story quickly, right?
Speaker 0: So There was Amazon's was making games.
Speaker 0: They were making a game called breakaway.
Speaker 0: That was supposed to be an eSport first and foremost.
Speaker 0: It was sort of like an isometric view real-time action game where there was a ball and you would try to get it in But also fight.
Speaker 0: I was trying to get into that game.
Speaker 0: I don't think I managed to play it for even a few seconds died.
Speaker 0: I once met a person who worked on it.
Speaker 0: They told me it was a garbage fire that they didn't give me too many details.
Speaker 0: I wasn't able to talk to them again.
Speaker 1: remember that conversation because I was standing.
Speaker 0: it was at magfest, right?
Speaker 0: A friend of our a friend of ours also worked on stuff adjacent to it at Amazon at one point.
Speaker 0: But anyway Amazon is now making another game which we did a whole episode on right?
Speaker 0: Did we do we do an episode?
Speaker 1: I was saying I don't remember if we did an episode or not because time we.
Speaker 0: so Anyway, Amazon was making another game as the game is called crucible.
Speaker 0: It was sort of a MOBA sort of an FPS combo, but not fully really.
Speaker 0: But anyway, it came out as like an open beta free kind of thing.
Speaker 0: We played it for a day or two just to like, you know, we didn't.
Speaker 1: doesn't look like understand.
Speaker 1: So that tells you everything you need to know about our opinion of this game.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we played it for a day or two.
Speaker 0: The it was just there wasn't anything about it.
Speaker 0: That was like man.
Speaker 0: that specific thing is garbage.
Speaker 0: There was also absolutely nothing good about it where I could say wow, that's really fun It was just.
Speaker 1: it was like eating a really mediocre grilled cheese sandwich like one made with like not just American cheese But because that can have its time and place but like Wonder Bread and the bottom tier of American cheese Like it's edible.
Speaker 1: It's serviceable.
Speaker 0: No, because that what I would go you because it's Wonder Bread It's like wasn't?
Speaker 0: imagine eating a food that is not you.
Speaker 0: you don't say ew But you get absolutely no enjoyment from.
Speaker 0: you know what it is and also no nourishment.
Speaker 1: It is the road trip.
Speaker 1: We took to Rochester where we ate at that big boy at the rest.
Speaker 0: Okay, that was you it wasn't you.
Speaker 1: it was the most unsatisfying meal I've ever had in my life.
Speaker 1: It was not.
Speaker 1: My stomach was full but to quote Chrono Trigger I was still hungry.
Speaker 0: Anyway, it's a nothing game you.
Speaker 0: all you do in this game is walk around aim your crosshairs on things and hold your mouse button down and watch their health bar decreased to zero or die first unless there are Groups of people.
Speaker 1: and then the game is who spots who first but not like in a counter-strike valor and like exciting way but in a Oddly boring and unexciting way like city.
Speaker 0: when the game came out It was free-to-play.
Speaker 0: it got a lot of hype and press so a lot of people played it.
Speaker 0: Of course, they had thousands of concurrent players.
Speaker 0: It was a big deal.
Speaker 1: I have like 12 hours into it all told I kept playing it to try to figure out what I didn't like about it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, anyway, the point is that now they have like a hundred concurrent players.
Speaker 0: So they're they're shutting it down unlike breakaway, which they just shut down completely.
Speaker 0: They may shut this down completely It may happen But for now what they're doing is they're closing it off to new players and they're just.
Speaker 0: it's now closed beta Until they're gonna learn.
Speaker 0: they said they're gonna listen to player input Which makes me thinks it might be a tribes to situation and not the good part.
Speaker 0: But I guess if you're already a bad game, you can't really ruin it with player input the way tribes to did.
Speaker 0: true But I guess counter-strike didn't listen to player input and it only got more popular.
Speaker 0: Here's the point is they're gonna heavily rework the game because no one's playing.
Speaker 1: but here's the trouble.
Speaker 0: It doesn't matter what their business model is.
Speaker 0: No one's playing.
Speaker 1: It's the reason we didn't review.
Speaker 1: it was specifically that I didn't have any like one flaw to point out.
Speaker 1: Like Scott pointed out it was just a very like unsatisfying experience for a variety of reasons But like I couldn't come up with a half-hour worth of things to say about it, but it's video game.
Speaker 1: the video game Okay, but like it was just a worse risk of rain with this like Unfun.
Speaker 0: well risk of rain one is good.
Speaker 1: risk of rain - is more like this Yeah but imagine risk of rain - where there's other people just sharing the map with you and One of the two teams just gets wiped randomly based on who hit like secondary attack Earlier when the two groups met.
Speaker 1: like that's the kind of game it was.
Speaker 1: but what I also noticed was that Everyone I talked to who played it also had this like completely gray blank opinion of the game and I didn't see Anyone talking about it online like at all Press.
Speaker 1: the press talked about it because it's Amazon had a lot of money behind it had a lot of push But like no human being I know who plays games who is not a journalist paid to play games said One word about this game.
Speaker 1: even people I know who I saw were playing it.
Speaker 0: All right, well crucible don't bother with it you haven't already and if you have already don't bother continuing.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and I guess thank you.
Speaker 0: I don't think you need to be told that because no one's playing just the fact that we're so desperate to have shows.
Speaker 1: We didn't even bother to review a game that I put 12 not desperate for.
Speaker 0: Tuesday shows True.
Speaker 1: So that's now let's talk about broken in games.
Speaker 1: We don't even we're not gonna go through an exhaustive list here, but Tabletop in particular in the gaming world has had a lot of issues with harassment and racism as I'm sure you all know and Those issues
Speaker 0: are really
Speaker 1: getting worse a lot faster than they're getting better right now.
Speaker 0: Oh, well, I think it's you know, it's a little snowball effect, right?
Speaker 0: It's like, you know, some people get canceled here and there.
Speaker 0: right, you know A few people are brave and they they call out, you know Who's guilty or accused of harassment or racism or sexism or discriminatory?
Speaker 0: practices or abuse of some kind etc, etc, and You know It used to be that people would largely not speak up because doing so would bring great consequences on to you the speaker.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the victim would just suffer more if they as they you know, try to get seek justice.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and also, you know, it's like okay Well, I'm willing to suffer more as long as I get the justice.
Speaker 0: you wouldn't get the justice.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it was it was a bad deal But what's happening lately is we're seeing a a lot of support for victims right more So than before even though it is still a very, you know hazardous path to take right?
Speaker 0: So I do not blame anyone who does not you know is not brave enough or you know willing to take you know call out their abusers or whatever.
Speaker 0: and Likewise we're starting to see some justice not the full justice that is necessary not even close But some justice.
Speaker 0: we're seeing people get fired.
Speaker 0: We're seeing people resign.
Speaker 0: We're seeing you know We're not seeing this kind of justice at the government level or at the big big big big places But we're seeing the medium and the small places, you know And it's pretty much happening.
Speaker 0: every single nerdery that I see across every single area of nerdism That I see I see some at least small justice happening.
Speaker 0: I
Speaker 1: guess that the real change I'm seeing just now like in the last two and a half weeks in tabletop gaming is the shift from most companies say nothing and or only address specific complaints raised at them very narrowly to a to a very different operating model where almost every company is issuing statements and trying to get ahead of this stuff and taking some actions and Companies that are refusing to say anything are very much standing out for choosing to say nothing during this time.
Speaker 0: All right, so a we're you know, because you know victims see other people getting some justice They're more willing to come out and then that causes other victims to be more willing to come out and so on and so on.
Speaker 0: So we're finding out who the secret or not So secret shitheads are.
Speaker 0: if you knew or didn't know certain game companies have not issued any statements about anything And that's very you know, and even companies that are making Vacuous statements and not taking any action, right?
Speaker 0: You know, that's still better than not saying anything because obviously the company that's not saying anything is is yep It's like.
Speaker 0: it doesn't cost you to suck to anything to those vacuous statements.
Speaker 1: So the reason why I see those as a positive step is that while they are vacuous and they are not even like a billionth Of the way toward what we need they show something that is best illustrated by the advice the last fire marshal I worked with gave me.
Speaker 1: he said very specifically I don't actually care if the rooms are overcrowded as you know Just in the course of like you running your event.
Speaker 1: What he said is I walk very slowly down the hallway and I just want to make sure that if you see me coming You can hide problems from me until I pass because that proves that you at least give a little bit of a shit.
Speaker 1: If you can't even fake it then you are beyond saving and I'm gonna shut you down.
Speaker 1: So a company that can't even fake it is Way worse than a company that I think it's.
Speaker 1: I think it's simply it sees The profit motive is on the right side of history Not the wrong side and is trying to be on the right side to avoid consequences.
Speaker 1: That's not the best motivation, but it's better than nothing.
Speaker 0: I think it's more than that.
Speaker 0: It's like saying black lives matter cost you nothing truly gets the.
Speaker 0: it's it like you can just say it all day.
Speaker 0: It's like okay that it's just so easy, right?
Speaker 0: I get to say three words.
Speaker 1: I mean it costs you shitheads on Twitter screaming at you, but you shouldn't be trying to make money from those people in her church.
Speaker 0: I mean, it's literally just say three words.
Speaker 0: It's like, okay, that doesn't accomplish.
Speaker 0: that doesn't accomplish anything.
Speaker 0: right to say the three words.
Speaker 0: The point is is that if someone is refusing to do that That is so easy right to make a statement that they might not even believe in to just lie And just say three words if they're refusing to put forth that minimal effort, right?
Speaker 0: Like maybe they are racist but and they refuse to say the three.
Speaker 0: it's like.
Speaker 0: that must mean If you're refusing to say those three words, okay, it must mean that you're racist.
Speaker 0: So it's just like oh, well now we can see who's good and who's bad.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like and it doesn't just saying it doesn't mean you're automatically good, but it at least means aha They're not a stubbornly racist person.
Speaker 0: They might have to go but they don't have to go first.
Speaker 0: It's like.
Speaker 0: it's like they you know, it's like okay We're gonna.
Speaker 0: the justice is going down the line right and sort of sorting the queue right for the scales, right?
Speaker 0: It's like, okay, you might tip the scale but you weigh less than that guy, you know reminds me.
Speaker 1: It reminds me of a game.
Speaker 1: We used to play in middle school.
Speaker 1: I don't remember what we called it, but they'd make us play it.
Speaker 1: No, this was late elementary school because it was gym class.
Speaker 1: They'd line up everyone on one side of the gym like in race classes and you had to run to the other side of the gym.
Speaker 1: Whoever got there last was eliminated and then you had to run to the other side of the gym.
Speaker 1: Whoever got there last was eliminated.
Speaker 1: and you just keep going till there's only one kid left.
Speaker 0: Oh And that's two teams.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Oh Good games a good game.
Speaker 1: But in this case, it's.
Speaker 0: but I guess people could sandbag it.
Speaker 1: Yeah true true.
Speaker 1: I Mean, it's basically just a guy.
Speaker 1: mean kids would say the problem is that is just a game with two teams Just to keep kids busy for an hour.
Speaker 0: I mean, yes, but as other things going on.
Speaker 1: But the concept of all right everyone.
Speaker 1: there is slightly less racism over there.
Speaker 1: The last person who gets there gets called Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: So Dungeons & Dragons is getting independent like the video game industry had a huge thing.
Speaker 1: We're not even gonna try to address that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, okay Yeah just I mean there's so many of these to address.
Speaker 0: right cards against humanity.
Speaker 0: company got blowed up got blowed up for like.
Speaker 1: Not just the stuff you it's deservingly.
Speaker 1: all of these are deserving fucked up stuff way beyond what anyone would have even dream.
Speaker 0: These are all deserving blobs, by the way, even frickin Bon Appetit, you know magazine getting blowed up.
Speaker 1: Yeah Dungeons & Dragons getting blowed dragons getting attacked from like five a hundred percent justified angles.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah Who else who else is taking heat right now?
Speaker 0: I can't even keep track.
Speaker 0: There's so many.
Speaker 1: the only thing that gave me that made me a little bit happy was that as the names of specific Abusers just were paraded around Twitter None of them are people I know respect or work with So far.
Speaker 1: oh Sorry careful to check that list.
Speaker 0: some tabletop war game companies are Good and some are not.
Speaker 0: Yep I mean, you know, it's like there's a stereotype that the kind of people who play those games are old bearded white guys.
Speaker 0: Who you know our old bearded white guys?
Speaker 0: Not I'd say that every old bearded white guy is Cuz I I will one day be one.
Speaker 1: but we're not gonna go deep into this thread right now.
Speaker 1: This is like a topic you do a whole show on but basically in that world war games are interesting because Depending on where you look at that discourse you see very different people having very different conversations.
Speaker 0: The point is whatever game companies you are Patronizing right you are gonna want to take a look at.
Speaker 0: you know The Twitter's do a little searching and figure out if they're on the shit list or not.
Speaker 0: Yeah Because the shit list is evolving Rapidly.
Speaker 0: I just say growing rapidly not evolving.
Speaker 0: I don't see anyone coming off.
Speaker 1: Yep No, like oh it turns out that wasn't true.
Speaker 0: pretty much all true because I think I've never seen one of the hoods.
Speaker 1: So, yeah, so in some other news there's a game that's now there's a date for it.
Speaker 1: the date is July 7th Which is real soon.
Speaker 1: It's called super liminal and it's basically this like Hyper non-euclidean puzzle game and I didn't realize it was gonna come out on the switch.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well just it's gonna come on PC too, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, but so it's a FPS.
Speaker 0: Why would I buy it on switch?
Speaker 1: Uh, I mean, I don't know actually don't know if it'll come out on PC.
Speaker 1: I originally thought it was gonna piece be a PC exclusive But it's listed on Nintendo's site and that's the only thing that's linking to it right now.
Speaker 0: Are you sure this isn't some game that's already on PC.
Speaker 1: I haven't checked Because it's been a thousand.
Speaker 0: it's on the epic game store by now - I have a game store.
Speaker 1: That's why I don't have it.
Speaker 0: It's on Steam.
Speaker 0: add to your wish list.
Speaker 0: plan.
Speaker 0: release date, November 2020 November.
Speaker 1: Okay, so it's gonna come out on the switch July 7th, and it's gonna come out on the PC on Steam in like November.
Speaker 0: Well, it's gonna come out on Steam in November, but it seems to already be on the epic games.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right on the epic game store.
Speaker 1: No But The game looks like it'll work on switch because it's basically this game like.
Speaker 1: watch the video and you'll see It has a little bit of like vague.
Speaker 0: Oh, it's also gonna be on PS.
Speaker 0: So out now it says on the web the developer publisher what I don't know is pillow castle games.
Speaker 0: So it says on their website out now epic game store coming soon.
Speaker 0: switch ps4.
Speaker 0: Xbox later steam.
Speaker 0: I'll wait for steam.
Speaker 1: if I play all I might just get it on switch because the game I feel like the switch form factor and like looking around might be good because the game I don't like to play.
Speaker 1: with FPS with two choices it feels like it has a Little bit of that like the game you linked me to an to chamber like here's a non euclidean place to help us there.
Speaker 0: There are quite a few games of the FPS puzzle platformer genre Where things are like crazy and don't make sense because that's the kind of world you can make in a video game like
Speaker 1: the Stanley Parable You make nine right turns and you are not like you are in a place.
Speaker 1: You should not physically be able to be.
Speaker 0: Well, I mean portal sort of was the one that sort of that started that whole, you know FPS puzzle platform thing.
Speaker 1: I saw a lot of indie games in the indie mega right that did this in the past.
Speaker 0: Yes, but they're always saying is that experience is very tiny right?
Speaker 0: is that after portal there was an explosion of sort of indie games Taking that FPS puzzle platform model and just pushing it way further?
Speaker 0: But they pushed it into a place that you know I don't think is very accessible to most people because it's like it messes with you Like.
Speaker 0: yeah, I think I think anything harder than portal is just gonna be like a lot of people are just gonna be like bar for something.
Speaker 0: It's like what is going on?
Speaker 1: I try to VR experience.
Speaker 1: That was here is a non-euclidean space and it made me Extremely disoriented in a weird way.
Speaker 1: really quick, right?
Speaker 0: But yeah super liminal is one of those and it seems to be a very.
Speaker 0: it might be the second most polished one I've ever seen because it looks like graphic wise.
Speaker 1: it looks about as good as the Stanley Parable.
Speaker 1: Yeah, most of the ones that I've seen are very You know indie and the mechanics are things like you see the person like pick up an object and then like hold it So it's close to their eyes and then let go of it.
Speaker 1: And now it's massive because they change the perspective like it's that kind of nonsense.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like it's sort of like reach up and pick the moon out of the sky kind of situation where you know The objects, you know the true size of the object, you know looks further or closer.
Speaker 0: You know because that's how we perceive the sizes.
Speaker 0: You know the distance of things is based on their size Right and also based on logic and the game sort of just.
Speaker 0: you know You can tell the trailer of the game that that it turns that on its head right.
Speaker 0: a small object that you think is far away is actually a close object.
Speaker 0: a Object that you think is small and close is actually far away and large.
Speaker 1: and the reason I'm like talking about this even though I Have not played it is that I've seen a lot of trailers for games like this before.
Speaker 1: This is the first one where I watched the trailer and I thought wow I get it and that looks really fun kind of like Baba is you.
Speaker 1: I saw a little bit of gameplay and I was like Oh, ah that that's a game for me.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, the only negative thing I think I can say about it is it seems a little escape roomy, but I mean portals escape roomy.
Speaker 0: So portal is basically just a portal is literally escape room.
Speaker 0: It's every ever only every room has the same key And you got I'll have the key from the start.
Speaker 1: In some other minor news, there's a game we talked about a long long long long time ago called natural selection.
Speaker 1: I love that game.
Speaker 0: I mean it was it started as a half-life 1 mod.
Speaker 0: That was you know I was an RTS plus FPS a dream that no one has not come true in any other game since right where one person is The commander building the base and everyone else is the soldiers and it was also an asymmetric Marines vs.
Speaker 0: Aliens game.
Speaker 0: So it's basically natural selection.
Speaker 0: since we played the half-life 1 mod when it came out in the early 2000s It was like a dream game, you know doing things that no other game has done before or since.
Speaker 0: yep.
Speaker 0: So and it sort of died and I made NS to came in and is to the company that made NS2 Went on to make other games.
Speaker 1: They made what the sea game unknown worlds entertainment is the publisher and the developer.
Speaker 1: What on the water?
Speaker 1: yes engine specifically for NS2.
Speaker 1: and then they said oh we should make other games to make money to fund NS2.
Speaker 1: Yeah Yeah, yeah, let me see what their current repertoire is.
Speaker 0: subnautica that's the other game they made.
Speaker 0: let's see Nautica is the main one, but they're working on something else now that has not been announced because they were doing job postings They saw on Twitter.
Speaker 0: Oh Yeah, they made under.
Speaker 0: they made natural selection - then they made subnautica and natural selection - has now sort of Community run kind of thing, right?
Speaker 0: There's like an arrangement where there's people keeping it alive and I had a very recent update June 26 Like it's.
Speaker 0: they're still working on it the Metro update.
Speaker 0: So yeah This game is alive and it is better than it was the last time I played it many and it's on Super sale because of the steam summer sale.
Speaker 0: If you don't have it already, yeah You can get this game for $2.00.
Speaker 0: it's a dream game.
Speaker 0: It's a FPS and RTS.
Speaker 0: one person's commanding everyone is Soldiers.
Speaker 0: it's like the game you wanted.
Speaker 0: it's been around for like 20 years, but it's the only game that's done it.
Speaker 0: Yep, and people are.
Speaker 0: not only some people are playing it but not nearly as many people as should be.
Speaker 1: now You might ask room.
Speaker 1: It's gone.
Speaker 1: Why weren't you playing it all this time?
Speaker 1: And when it first came out while I did play a lot I did.
Speaker 1: I did too But it was still kind of buggy and it had performance issues back then and I think it's just.
Speaker 0: you know I just sort of fell out of it after playing it a whole bunch and also the skill cap was pretty high And my skills are pretty low.
Speaker 0: So You know, yeah, and also I played it at a time where it's development on it Slowed down.
Speaker 0: is the unknown worlds?
Speaker 0: people went to go work on subnautica, right and that community support That's been keeping it fresh came much many years later And I didn't get back into it since then because I was doing other things.
Speaker 1: I was playing like netrunner Yeah, but I've reinstalled it and started playing it again.
Speaker 1: All those performance issues are gone.
Speaker 1: I can't say if it's because my video card is probably like four orders of magnitude more powerful than the one I had.
Speaker 1: Who does?
Speaker 0: I'd note netrunner was very popular at unknown worlds HQ.
Speaker 1: Ah So yeah, I'm gonna be playing some natural selection off and on.
Speaker 1: if you want to play to see we get some games together Maybe I'll live.
Speaker 0: Yeah, maybe I installed it again.
Speaker 1: Maybe I was terrible at ns2, but we'll gladly play.
Speaker 0: I'm better at marine than alien.
Speaker 1: I am actually better at alien than marine But I don't know if that is still true.
Speaker 0: I'm bad at all the roles like lurk and fade where you have to be fast Oh fades I can't fade and I'm bad with the and I'm bad with the jetpack, right?
Speaker 1: But anything and it's like me wasting my my resources to fade means we instantly lose.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the slower ones.
Speaker 0: I'm better.
Speaker 0: I'm good with onos.
Speaker 1: Great at onos and as one I was.
Speaker 1: the thing I was the best at was actually being either being the one guy with a grenade launcher or Being the lurk.
Speaker 1: I was so good at the lurk in ns1.
Speaker 0: I saw It's like ns2.
Speaker 0: right natural or one or two right capturing those resource nodes right like mattered a lot Yeah, and you look at like go back to crucible right capturing those resource.
Speaker 0: No shit.
Speaker 0: It didn't really matter Right.
Speaker 0: I think what it is is all these games these FPS is where they want the players to capture nodes Right and you like you just get these sort of points.
Speaker 0: It's like ns2.
Speaker 0: those points are literal currency you spend like a board game, right?
Speaker 1: and I think that gives the and the economy is real tight like ns1 even I remember like we'd be playing and like The commander be like, oh shit They're taking down the RT in the cafeteria.
Speaker 1: fucking get your asses over there right now.
Speaker 1: Or I'm gonna we're gonna I'm gonna quit and we lose.
Speaker 0: right.
Speaker 0: and I think that Making those resource points into a currency as opposed to like leveling up players, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah is What makes capturing resource nodes is like an ns2 like a great fun thing and Doing it in other games is always me also just the fun of like having someone who's playing a commander playing an RTS Literally giving you orders and telling you what to do.
Speaker 1: But it's up to you on how to execute those orders like if commander sucks you can ignore them.
Speaker 1: Like there's a lot of fun dynamics that just don't exist in most other games.
Speaker 1: but anyway things Of the day, what do you get?
Speaker 1: Well, I know what you got.
Speaker 1: It's really good.
Speaker 0: So yeah, so Back in a long time ago Like in the 50s 60s, right?
Speaker 0: There was a man named baba see baba.
Speaker 0: sigh I don't know how to pronounce his name.
Speaker 0: I'm sorry.
Speaker 0: It was a man from Senegal right in Dakar, right?
Speaker 0: You probably heard of Dakar.
Speaker 0: so they have the Dakar rally.
Speaker 0: It's basically on the left side of Africa.
Speaker 0: on the top We're the big bubble part.
Speaker 0: Dakar is like this little thing that sticks out of the desert like on the the very left side of Africa.
Speaker 0: it sticks out of Senegal and that's like the main best city of Senegal.
Speaker 0: is Dakar right?
Speaker 0: It's like we're all the good stuff.
Speaker 0: So this man from Dakar he played a game a board game called drafts Which is basically a version of checkers or checkers is a version of drafts But like, you know, it's called international drafts.
Speaker 0: It's quite similar to checkers.
Speaker 0: You can look up the rules online.
Speaker 0: There's.
Speaker 1: I don't want to get into the variants of checkers and etymology.
Speaker 0: We are not getting into that.
Speaker 0: if you can look at that up yourself you have internet because you're listening to this.
Speaker 0: I know you have internet.
Speaker 0: We're only available on the internet.
Speaker 0: and in supposedly a French drafts player went to Dakar met Baba see right and played and Supposedly got destroyed at drafts And said oh shit.
Speaker 0: You're way good at this and brought Baba sigh.
Speaker 0: see I'm sorry.
Speaker 0: I'm just gonna.
Speaker 0: I'll stick with.
Speaker 0: see I don't know.
Speaker 0: back to Europe right to play.
Speaker 0: and in 1962 right Baba played against 150 players simultaneously.
Speaker 0: this video of this it really happened videos a hundred and 150 drafts players lined up at their own boards, right.
Speaker 0: so you could imagine like, you know 150 checkers players with a checkers board in front of them and Baba would walk around the room taking his turn one board at a time And then he would have to take 149 turns before he got back to your boards.
Speaker 0: you had all that time to think about your turn.
Speaker 0: Yeah And he would come and look at your turn.
Speaker 0: look at your board for like a second and take his turn.
Speaker 1: like most of these Boards he doesn't even stop walking.
Speaker 0: Yeah, he just keeps walking.
Speaker 0: He's like turn turn turn turn turn and you sit there and think he takes 149 turns and then you take your turn and then he takes his turn and then he passes on.
Speaker 0: and he some of the people Sitting in that room right not all of them, but some of them were like champions of this game, right?
Speaker 0: So it'd be like you.
Speaker 0: imagine me going around a chess tables, right and like, you know What's his name?
Speaker 0: max is there right at one of the tables, you know?
Speaker 0: It's like.
Speaker 0: I didn't know he was a champion or anything But he was just one of the people amongst all the others.
Speaker 0: Anyway, Baba beat all of them every single one.
Speaker 0: He went on to win the French championship, right.
Speaker 0: the next year.
Speaker 0: There are apparently, you know, you know it was disputed but apparently they later on declared him the victor.
Speaker 0: but anyway You know There's not a lot of champions in board gaming other than like chess and this guy is the true greatest of all time.
Speaker 0: Right, if you're talking about like, you know board games, like.
Speaker 0: there's no famous monopoly champion.
Speaker 0: There's no famous diplomacy champion.
Speaker 0: I mean there are champions of those games because they do have competitive scenes.
Speaker 0: Even the Scrabble champions, which have a very organized competitive scene are not famous.
Speaker 0: Can anyone listening to this name a Scrabble world champion without looking it up, right?
Speaker 0: I probably only named champions of chess and go I imagine right board game wise even though other games or magic magic you can name.
Speaker 0: So here you go.
Speaker 0: My man My man Baba is probably one of the greatest, you know If he had been alive at a time when different board games were played, right?
Speaker 1: I can imagine this guy walking up and down the row of a bunch of games like tickets are afraid.
Speaker 1: He's just be like boop boop boop.
Speaker 0: Or if he or if he had played chess or go which did exist at the time, right?
Speaker 0: It's just he happened to play drafts.
Speaker 0: But yeah, true board game champions are few and far between and hard to come by.
Speaker 0: So, you know whenever you find out about one, right?
Speaker 0: They should be Celebrated and revered.
Speaker 0: I think we need like a board game a competitive board game Hall of Fame.
Speaker 1: if one doesn't exist Why don't we make it declare that we're the ones who run it?
Speaker 0: If it doesn't exist, we could no one stopping us.
Speaker 0: That's how all those things start.
Speaker 0: It's just someone that twin galaxies just some people just starting it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they declared themselves the authority, right?
Speaker 0: So we could do that.
Speaker 1: and if we did boom all we have to is make a first-class inductee guaranteed.
Speaker 1: We make a website we make a board that votes and that's it.
Speaker 1: We just start inducting people.
Speaker 0: Sure, let's say we need trophy and we need we need a building and we need to put plaques in the building.
Speaker 1: We could start with a purely and you have to write.
Speaker 0: you have to write those little museum context things next to each person right to tell their story and Then we need to collect like we need like a curator who can like, you know, get artifacts like, you know, uh His Baba sees traps draft table his drafts board his pieces, right?
Speaker 1: Anyway, so you're not familiar with a PX accessible player experiences.
Speaker 1: This website is actually Really really in-depth like you should check this out even if you're not a game designer.
Speaker 1: But basically it is and a deep exploration of the most important design patterns for designing Accessible games video games tabletop games anything.
Speaker 1: How do you make games accessible to different kinds of audiences?
Speaker 1: and the best part about this site is that it gives practical examples and specific advice on very very nuanced things like Precision or flexible text entry or like having second channels of communication Like.
Speaker 1: I don't want to even do this site at a service by explaining any of these in detail.
Speaker 1: you should just check this out, but it also addresses a lot of the Weird and often spurious arguments that a lot of game designers like to make against accessibility For usually stupid reasons, but it makes it very clear that these are design patterns that can expand the audience that can access a game.
Speaker 1: I'm even gonna quote this website because it's very they just they say it so well Providing access to your games and adapting the challenge.
Speaker 1: change and adapting the challenge changes your game.
Speaker 1: But we're not saying you should limit or water down the experience your game offers.
Speaker 1: if you want your game to offer the edge of The sea tension of stalking a wild animal through the forest then that's the player experience You should be aiming for.
Speaker 1: what a PX offers is a way to think about whether you could provide that Experience to players who have different types of disabilities.
Speaker 1: So like if you're saying oh my game requires you to hear like it's a sound thing.
Speaker 1: fine Sure, you can make that choice.
Speaker 1: But are there other design patterns you can implement in your game to make it more accessible to all the other areas of disability all the other types of players or all the other places that aren't specifically depending upon the specific game vision you have?
Speaker 1: this website is actually like Should be one of your first go-to resources.
Speaker 0: What if you're designing a game and I feel like a lot of people, you know And this is true of just all products in general is that people who make products tend to think of if they do think of Accessibility at all, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I often think of it.
Speaker 0: last like okay.
Speaker 0: We've made our website.
Speaker 1: Let's get someone to try it out.
Speaker 0: Let's right Let's get some accessibility consultants and edit the website to make it accessible and fix it up.
Speaker 0: It's like no no, no, no, no, you got to do that shit from the start.
Speaker 0: Otherwise by the time the accessibility people show up to look at your finished product, right?
Speaker 0: That's you're right.
Speaker 0: They're gonna be like, oh you got like overhaul all this shit.
Speaker 0: You're like Yeah, all right, even if you mean well and you're gonna do it.
Speaker 0: So you should.
Speaker 0: if you're going to be making games and you want them to be accessible You should be you know, reading the relevant things here In advance of starting on any UX type components, you know Like your your your game rules don't really have any accessibility from right?
Speaker 0: They might I guess it's possible But usually that you can start just making game rules without you know, worrying about the accessibility too hard.
Speaker 0: It's mostly once you get into the interface of the game.
Speaker 0: All right, how do our people interacting with the rules?
Speaker 0: Yep, as soon as you start with that like you're gonna make a game board, you know, it's like.
Speaker 0: okay I've imagined this game.
Speaker 0: Oh now I'm making a board for the game up.
Speaker 0: now You got to think about accessibility because you're making an interface but like.
Speaker 1: here's an example how deep these go.
Speaker 1: if you click on any one of these patterns it gives you a Really detailed explanation with like five or six examples from real games of implementations of those patterns to a depth that Like you can just crib from this website and probably design a good game Irrespective of accessibility that you're adding right?
Speaker 0: The point is there's no excuse you can't be like, oh, I didn't know.
Speaker 0: Well, here was a free website that told you jackass.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the I didn't know excuse applies to like Advanced edge cases.
Speaker 1: this stuff is should be like game design 101.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if you and especially if you're making a game with any kind of budget, right you're zero excuse for not You know fully complying with pretty much everything on here.
Speaker 0: Yeah,
Speaker 1: or at least if your game is weird and like require like you not every game can accommodate every one of these but you should at least have looked at every one of these and at least had the conversation of
Speaker 0: Could
Speaker 1: we apply this to our game or not?
Speaker 1: Like does this work or not and apply as many as you can?
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: All right in the meta moment It's been a thousand years since the last time we streamed geek nights.
Speaker 1: It's been a month since the last time we did a show.
Speaker 1: This feels like it's gonna be a really long year and the only conventions will be attending our online conventions.
Speaker 0: It's pretty much it.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: So there is a book club book, which is the tale of Genji the first novel in all of human History, yeah, and I haven't read one page of it since I have last been on the New York subway, which is probably February or March The illusion.
Speaker 0: it's already July.
Speaker 1: tomorrow what I will and you're probably listening to this Well, both of us are very lucky and that we have jobs.
Speaker 1: we can work from home.
Speaker 1: But what that means is that on one hand?
Speaker 1: I feel like I have all this free time because I don't have to commute and I can't go anywhere.
Speaker 1: So I should be getting a lot more done in my free time and like me I am getting a lot more sleeping done.
Speaker 1: I'm also getting a lot more sleeping.
Speaker 1: But the reality is still working eight hours a day.
Speaker 1: I don't actually have more free time.
Speaker 1: My commute was only like five to ten minutes anyway.
Speaker 0: So on this whole geek nights thing takes a lot of time.
Speaker 0: You should stop doing this.
Speaker 1: Geek nights takes a lot more time to make remotely than it does in person.
Speaker 1: That is not a lie.
Speaker 1: And also there are things that we want to do that would be so hard to do not in person that that's why we're not Working on them.
Speaker 1: There's things I want to work on with Scott.
Speaker 1: We really just can't work on them unless we get together physically and set up some cameras and that's not gonna fly anytime soon.
Speaker 1: So nope.
Speaker 1: So, yeah, otherwise my best advice to you join our discord join our forum follow Scott and me on YouTube and we're gonna try to Increasingly do projects that we can make progress on.
Speaker 1: that do not require us to share Spit air with each other for the foreseeable future Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: So yeah this uh, we've done this before.
Speaker 1: this is a Panel idea we're working on.
Speaker 1: Scott's done a lot of work writing this one.
Speaker 1: We kind of take turns.
Speaker 0: Yes Alright, so I've been writing this panel for like, you know, I actually only spent maybe a couple days on it.
Speaker 0: But there were long gaps between those couple days.
Speaker 0: But I wanted to make a panel because it's a topic that just kept coming up all the time About game endings.
Speaker 0: and the problem is I can't think of a name for the panel because if we call it endings Yeah, they're like, oh you mean like the end of Final Fantasy 4. if you say the end of Megaman or you know It's like the.
Speaker 0: you know gate video games that are single-player have like these endings You get to the end of the game and after you beat the square boss.
Speaker 0: There's like an ending.
Speaker 1: if we call it something I'm talking about that.
Speaker 1: if we talk about call it like the end of games People might think we're talking about like future post-scarcity like weird nonsense.
Speaker 1: I could see that.
Speaker 0: but no I'm talking about ending conditions in Ortho games.
Speaker 0: right so, you know When does football end when the clock runs out?
Speaker 0: when does a monopoly end when someone and everyone's bankrupt except one person, you know When does an 18xx game?
Speaker 0: and well when add do you know the?
Speaker 0: when the the bank runs out of money at the end of that operating round or whatever?
Speaker 1: and we've talked about this as Part of a lot of our other lectures in the past like our ones on.
Speaker 1: take your damn turn like how to make games go Faster in designing game rules.
Speaker 1: We talked about this at length and how to win at games.
Speaker 1: We talked a lot about ending conditions, right?
Speaker 0: It's something that comes up frequently as a portion of other panels and I was like, hey I can just do a whole panel and zoom in to just that one topic.
Speaker 0: So since I 90% wrote the panel, I just didn't make slides for it.
Speaker 0: I figured hey we can use this as a topic of a geek nights episode.
Speaker 0: Yeah Right anyone who hears this episode won't have to watch the panel and then we can maybe get some ideas while we talk about it.
Speaker 0: Maybe that when we make a video to send to an online convention to show of this panel and we have slides It'll be better because we use this geek nights episode to improve upon it.
Speaker 1: And since we haven't played any new games We get a free show ID and also we're losing, you know again because of kovat and the lack of conventions A lot of times we'll workshop a panel at a few cons before we get like the final version.
Speaker 1: Can't really do that now.
Speaker 0: So no.
Speaker 0: All right, so The first thing we got to talk about when it comes to game endings is that every game has to have an ending.
Speaker 1: Well, what would I say?
Speaker 1: that other panel if it doesn't end?
Speaker 0: It's not a game Right, well you said if you can't quit It's not a game.
Speaker 0: quitting is relevant to the game endings, right?
Speaker 0: Cuz a quitting is also an ending sort of right.
Speaker 0: But yeah, if a game doesn't have an ending condition, it's not a game.
Speaker 0: It's like a trap.
Speaker 0: You're stuck in this in this, you know fake rule set like, you know, it's like, you know The law of the world is is not a game even though it's rules that you follow Right because you can't escape it.
Speaker 0: It's not easy.
Speaker 1: And when all players don't want our bankrupt if it just didn't say that if the just it was just like whoever has the most Money and the game just keeps going Yeah, what doesn't even say whoever has the most money just says roll the dice and keep moving.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like, you know It's not a game has to have an ending, right?
Speaker 0: So The thing is it's like, okay, you're designing a game, right?
Speaker 0: You have to have an ending or you have to write a rule that says the game ends when X right?
Speaker 0: Doesn't matter if it's a video game or a board game or a sport, right?
Speaker 0: You have to come up with this rule.
Speaker 0: When does the game like pause?
Speaker 0: So one player gets ten points the game ends that frame Right, and of course, we're also all only talking about ortho games, right?
Speaker 0: You know, it's like when does?
Speaker 0: when should your win should D&D end?
Speaker 0: when should your tabletop role-playing game end?
Speaker 0: When should your single-player video game end whenever you feel like it?
Speaker 0: When should Animal Crossing end whenever you feel like you have to be Bowser?
Speaker 1: No, you don't Know.
Speaker 0: you could just stop, right?
Speaker 0: But if it's a game where it's a competitive game between two or more parties teams players where there is some sort of ranking system to determine who is the winner and and you need an end point and that that Endpoint is also when you say who the what you declare the winner right at the same time.
Speaker 0: So the victory conditions are really tied in with the with the ending conditions.
Speaker 0: But the point is we're only talking about the endings of ortho games, right?
Speaker 0: So, let's talk about the different types of endings that are out there.
Speaker 0: right.
Speaker 0: so we already mentioned timed ending.
Speaker 0: Right, you just play until a certain time.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like Right, we play until a certain score.
Speaker 0: pong you get ten points then the game is right.
Speaker 1: as soon as someone gets ten points We're in board games play until one of three highly specific things within this game occur Like someone builds this particular building or someone uses up all the victory point chips.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that would be like a resource clock.
Speaker 0: Those are sort of clocks, but they're sort of abstracted clocks to where it's like, okay There's a pile of sheep in the game and we're gonna end the game when there's no more sheep left.
Speaker 0: It's like well, that's also.
Speaker 0: that's sort of a clock.
Speaker 0: It's just sort of a player controlled clock.
Speaker 0: to some extent they could take more or less.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah Like sheep some of those sheep
Speaker 0: are constantly being used though Like so we like sheep back
Speaker 1: always slowly wind down and players might be able to like pump the gas or pump the brakes But some of them are a clock that the players have complete control over.
Speaker 1: like as soon as any one player does X the game Ends.
Speaker 1: like the clock is just one bit like one minute from midnight and any player can walk over just push it.
Speaker 0: Right, some games don't have it.
Speaker 0: They have an ending but the ending is sort of not indeterminate like go Right just sort of ends when both players agree.
Speaker 0: like ah, yes.
Speaker 0: This is ended.
Speaker 0: you have won, right?
Speaker 0: And they can.
Speaker 0: usually rather than playing it's like the board is a hundred percent full.
Speaker 0: This is the final score.
Speaker 0: like they can just sort of see that what this who's who has won and has taken more territory?
Speaker 1: I realize we we do that with our train games to to a significant degree.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's because the games have problems which we're going to talk about.
Speaker 0: Yeah Some games will have multiple ending conditions.
Speaker 0: the game ends when a or B or C and You know this.
Speaker 0: it could end in three different ways.
Speaker 0: Puerto Rico could end with someone fills up on buildings or when the colonists run out or when the victory points run out.
Speaker 0: So it's like three clocks and whichever one is the fastest.
Speaker 1: No I found usually in those cases one of the clocks is the is the clock that runs out first 90% of the time like very rarely, but do they run out?
Speaker 0: but there are other games.
Speaker 0: I'm just talking about the idea of several clocks.
Speaker 0: I'm just using Puerto Rico as an example.
Speaker 0: There's no point in Exploring Puerto Rico itself, right?
Speaker 0: It's not relevant.
Speaker 0: So there are some games with that have multiple conditions where one of the conditions is like the main Condition like say route in route you're trying to get X victory points to 30.
Speaker 0: I think I forget how many some number of victory points where you win route.
Speaker 0: But there's a secret escape hatch dominance, right?
Speaker 0: It's like the game.
Speaker 0: and and when someone gets this many points or It ends when this other thing there's a secret way to end the game on the side, right?
Speaker 0: Some games combine multiple things together, right?
Speaker 0: So for example Boxing right.
Speaker 0: you could end the game when there's after a certain number of rounds that have been agreed to beforehand or When someone gets knocked the fuck out right.
Speaker 0: two different ways for a boxing match to add counter-strike.
Speaker 0: You can end when you kill the entire other team knock the fuck out or the bomb goes off.
Speaker 0: I mean two different two different ways to end.
Speaker 0: Another thing is you get there's player elimination endings, right?
Speaker 0: So some games that have player elimination the game doesn't end for everyone at the same time.
Speaker 0: It ends for one player one or more players at a time and eventually only one player or team remains.
Speaker 1: And I guess there are games that are just eliminate players until only one is left.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: Yes, there are And those are all the game endings I could think of.
Speaker 0: So if anyone thinks of any that don't fit into one of those categories Right.
Speaker 0: Let me know Because you know, I pretty much every game I could think of, you know, since those categories are kind of broad Right.
Speaker 0: It was it's you know, every game pretty much falls into one of those.
Speaker 1: I feel like one aspect of this panel like in the last third.
Speaker 1: Well could be picking up several specific games and exploring them using.
Speaker 0: we got analogy Yeah, but it's like, you know, you think of like, oh well that games difference like.
Speaker 0: no, that's a resource clock.
Speaker 0: Yeah, oh that game is different.
Speaker 0: No, that's an escape hatch on the side.
Speaker 1: Okay, like how when we talk about like the end of games in terms of like what determines winning Once all players are grandmaster superstars and all games are either random arbitrary or solved like same thing No game does not fit into one of those three categories and arguably two of those categories are the same
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: So we've.
Speaker 0: those are all the ways the game can end that we could think of right?
Speaker 0: So you're designing a game and you have to write this ending rules for your game that you're designing.
Speaker 0: Which one of those do you pick?
Speaker 0: how what how are we going to somehow objectively determine?
Speaker 0: What is the best ending for your game?
Speaker 0: We don't want the game to be too short.
Speaker 0: If the game is too short, it'll be an unsatisfying experience.
Speaker 0: I didn't get to play with all the toys in the game.
Speaker 0: Right, imagine playing like Magic the Gathering and you only have one, you know.
Speaker 0: They decided you have 20 hit points in Magic the Gathering right?
Speaker 0: Imagine if you magic that you get to life.
Speaker 0: It'd be like lightning bolt.
Speaker 0: It's like I didn't had a whole deck of cars.
Speaker 0: I didn't even get to play with.
Speaker 0: that's not fun.
Speaker 1: Yeah, or maybe give everyone sure that I want to build at the end.
Speaker 1: I never get it up.
Speaker 1: No game will ever go on long enough for me to use that creature right.
Speaker 0: if you gave everyone 50 health It's like okay.
Speaker 0: Well now everyone no one dies from health.
Speaker 0: Everyone dies from running out of deck right because the game goes so long or then players start coming in with.
Speaker 1: here's my 400 card Deck, let's go, right.
Speaker 0: And it's also another example of a game with multiple ending conditions and victory conditions.
Speaker 0: Right where deck or life or poison or whatever.
Speaker 1: right as a house side?
Speaker 1: I was obsessed with winning magic games.
Speaker 1: Like when I was deep into magic by anything other than hit points.
Speaker 1: I really wanted to win with poison or deck run out to the point that I tried to force it to the exclusion of Everything else right?
Speaker 0: So how are we going to determine what makes a good game ending and what makes a bad game ending, right?
Speaker 0: Okay So the first thing that makes a bad game ending and I think this is pretty much this this bad thing is like the worst Bad thing which is pretty much the.
Speaker 0: the primary Motivation for this panel right is this one bad thing which is when the victory condition occurs before the ending condition.
Speaker 0: So we have already figured out who has won the game.
Speaker 0: right it has already been pretty much determined.
Speaker 0: Yet the ending rules for the game are such that the game is not over and thus we are forced into what is known as Garbage time which is where players one or more players must continue to play the game because it's not over or they're not eliminated.
Speaker 0: But we already know who has won this game.
Speaker 0: There is no reason for us to keep playing.
Speaker 0: Why are we doing this?
Speaker 0: Right, obviously the most Number one culprit is monopoly that everyone knows.
Speaker 0: even even non nerds know that monopolies over before it's over and they just stop playing.
Speaker 1: Yeah But this applies to it a lot more games than people realize think it applies to so many freaking a lot of players, honestly Never fully understand a lot of the games they play enough to recognize when this is happening.
Speaker 0: Well that that is the thing that absolutely happens is that people do not realize the game is over even though it's over.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right, which is actually that helps the game, right?
Speaker 1: Even though through no fault of the games like age of steam like you can be losing that game.
Speaker 1: But not notice because the mechanics of the game are fun enough for you.
Speaker 0: Right, just give Hudson with them.
Speaker 0: right if players don't notice that the game is over when it's not over They won't be upset.
Speaker 0: But if you do notice that it's over when it's not over Then it's not fun to play anymore.
Speaker 0: because you're like, why am I doing this?
Speaker 0: I'm Mike.
Speaker 0: I only have so much time in my life.
Speaker 0: Why am I spending it doing this BS?
Speaker 1: I mean, I remember we do you and I got 41 playing Puerto Rico.
Speaker 1: We'd be like four rounds in and be like, well Alex won.
Speaker 1: let's just start over let's just stop right yet.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: Also, sometimes even though a game may not have a winner already determined, right?
Speaker 0: It will.
Speaker 0: they will have a loser right?
Speaker 0: So this happens.
Speaker 0: it gives us more than two players only.
Speaker 1: Get politics in right.
Speaker 0: you got four player game Right and one of the turn three.
Speaker 0: one of the players is doing so badly.
Speaker 1: They can't win like a train game.
Speaker 1: We played a little while ago where I just made a really big mistake early on and there I was just done.
Speaker 1: There's literally nothing I could do to catch up, right?
Speaker 0: So it's like if you don't eliminate that player or and that you could end the game too, right and declare a winner.
Speaker 0: But if you don't eliminate that player Then that player is now a spoiler that is gonna mess with the rest of the game Even though the other players have a reason to continue playing.
Speaker 0: so you should eliminate them.
Speaker 1: or you know It becomes political that player can choose the winner or The game changes and it becomes how do the other players exploit the losing player, right?
Speaker 0: Now that's all.
Speaker 0: all that stuff is well and good in a non-competitive storytelling game, right?
Speaker 0: But we're talking about ortho games where we care about winning and losing and that sort of thing would be undesirable.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right.
Speaker 0: It would also be under.
Speaker 0: and it's it's funny because usually we talk about the opposed motivations of spectators versus Participants.
Speaker 0: right, but actually when it comes to game endings the What benefits spectators is pretty much in perfect alignment with which what benefits true layers?
Speaker 1: imagine like you're watching a football game Where the one team's up 70 to nothing.
Speaker 0: You turn it on change channel.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right.
Speaker 1: This is your reasons.
Speaker 1: You're there for that.
Speaker 0: But right if you're watching a game or participate right and someone's participating right the reasons You want the game to end it generally the same time.
Speaker 0: right, you know When when victory has been determined close games are exciting.
Speaker 0: They keep you there.
Speaker 0: They keep you there for extra innings, right?
Speaker 0: You want to keep watching that close tied baseball game into extra innings.
Speaker 0: So, you know what spectator and the player until they get tired.
Speaker 1: listener Avi just said something very interesting that I'm thinking about now because we just thought I just said like Oh and you're up by 70 points like oh you turn off the game.
Speaker 1: But the reality is I'm watching the Rangers and Z bads gotten five goals and the game's over but there's two more periods.
Speaker 1: I'm actually more invested because now it's just like I get to watch this pounding and what this listener just said was that I quote.
Speaker 1: My cousin said she likes that monopoly has so much garbage time because it lets her celebrate her victory.
Speaker 1: She's the one who won and she gets to sit there forcing everyone to deal with the fact that she won until they either quit.
Speaker 0: I'm sorry that your cousin is a sociopath, but I as a spectator watching a sport.
Speaker 1: I I would glad like we that Newman game the hockey game we talked about where the RIT won 24 to nothing.
Speaker 1: Would we leave in the second period when they were only up 14 to nothing?
Speaker 0: There was there a special circumstances outside the game of us Burying the other team that made it enjoyable.
Speaker 0: if you were there Any less bad or if you were alone in the arena watching that you would have left earlier, I don't know.
Speaker 1: I Don't know.
Speaker 1: I feel like there's something to explore here.
Speaker 0: anyway.
Speaker 0: The point is is when the end of the game comes too far after the victory has already been determined It it's very unsatisfying in most cases like the Super Bowl is actually a perfect example there.
Speaker 1: if the Super Bowl is determined in the first Like half I just don't even watch the second half, but if it's a blowout toward the end and there's only a few minutes left.
Speaker 1: That's a totally different situation.
Speaker 0: So ideally you want some alignment between the victory condition and the ending condition.
Speaker 0: Right such that you know pong is in tennis.
Speaker 0: They're perfect, right?
Speaker 0: It's like it's ten.
Speaker 0: It's nine to one.
Speaker 0: Well, the other person can still win.
Speaker 0: they can score nine in a row, right and watch them.
Speaker 0: I got ten stuff like a men's immediately all the time.
Speaker 0: I Was in like a Verizon store who I was with someone who was buying a new phone and There was I think it was US Open was on maybe so, you know a year or two ago I don't remember last year.
Speaker 0: I don't know whatever and Thousand years ago.
Speaker 0: I think it might have been like exactly a year ago.
Speaker 0: Anyway, the point is Federer was on TV and I saw it.
Speaker 0: He had match point.
Speaker 0: He didn't win.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I Remember that very specifically.
Speaker 0: So that's that's one thing.
Speaker 0: Another thing you want to avoid right that can be bad is Let me look at my what I wrote.
Speaker 1: See, this is why we spend some effort on these panels before we like finish them.
Speaker 1: You you guys don't usually see the like us putting it together and figuring out our ideas.
Speaker 1: I'm making sure the points are making are consistent.
Speaker 0: All right, so if the ending condition Happens too soon.
Speaker 0: I talked about this a little bit already.
Speaker 0: Right, the game can often be unsatisfying because you didn't get to play the whole game.
Speaker 0: Imagine playing Puerto Rico and you only got to build a few buildings.
Speaker 0: You didn't get.
Speaker 0: you never get to use the big buildings, right?
Speaker 0: But there are other problems with that too besides not being able to play with all the toys and that Is.
Speaker 0: it gives a great advantage to players who are using aggressive strategy up or set plays like or right?
Speaker 0: It's like okay.
Speaker 0: this game in this game ends very very quickly, right?
Speaker 0: There's a way to end it after like two turns Right.
Speaker 0: So there's a thing I can do to score as many points as I can in two turns.
Speaker 0: and now any Longer term strategy now becomes like unviable, right?
Speaker 0: So like in Magic the Gathering again, or usually see in CCGs a lot.
Speaker 0: or you know other games, you know there's always Agro verse control people talk about right whereas like Agro is play small cheap things early, you know Do lots of damage right away.
Speaker 0: me go face in Hearthstone, right?
Speaker 0: Becomes very strong because you can end the game quickly and then control is don't lose don't lose don't lose.
Speaker 0: The game goes on long enough and now I can play cards that cost a fortune.
Speaker 0: Right that I couldn't play on turn one.
Speaker 0: and now the person who played up was Agro.
Speaker 0: played all their cards.
Speaker 0: They don't have any left.
Speaker 0: and now I can win you.
Speaker 1: this The meta a little bit like I remember in the revised era of Magic.
Speaker 1: there were some periods where tournament play Burn decks like just a red fucko deck Pretty much like they wouldn't win a hundred percent of the time.
Speaker 1: But they were so powerful that you really couldn't try other strategies.
Speaker 0: You need to balance that ending condition right if you have this sort of Agro control lineup in your game strategies such that Agro can win right and Control can win.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and so you want to like get it just on that line right there - we're like.
Speaker 0: You know Agro can't win too fast because then controls busted.
Speaker 0: They know what game weirdly and you can't make it.
Speaker 0: So Agro goes too late because if Agro takes too long to win then control comes in and Agro can't win.
Speaker 1: You know what game actually illustrates that pretty well and I think walks that line very well that old tabletop game.
Speaker 1: No one remembers this game.
Speaker 1: I like it.
Speaker 1: Attica.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the temples or or or normal game.
Speaker 1: you'll play the normal game But someone could win with the temples and yeah, if someone starts going for it, you got to stop them.
Speaker 1: It's you can win that way.
Speaker 1: That is a perfectly valid way to win.
Speaker 1: I've seen it happen.
Speaker 0: or there's no going back a game.
Speaker 0: We reviewed recently that we played effects.
Speaker 0: ease, right?
Speaker 0: you know like tons and tons of games have that dynamic of Agro and control and You need to make sure you can't have your ending condition happen too soon, right?
Speaker 0: Too late is a problem because you get garbage time but too soon is a problem because then aggressive strategies become favored and long-term plays become worthless and a lot of this.
Speaker 0: your Game content doesn't get used because you have it.
Speaker 0: doesn't that game content never happens until you get to the late game.
Speaker 1: That's the worst I can think of.
Speaker 1: a lot of magic playing Starcraft.
Speaker 0: Imagine playing Starcraft and you build infantry and you can destroy the enemy base with infantry.
Speaker 0: You never use tanks You never use planes.
Speaker 0: You never use anything, right?
Speaker 0: You just play it with infantry.
Speaker 1: Yep I feel like when like an agro strategy tends to be overpowered usually it's because that is actually a Degenerate strategy in the game like Kayla's old Kayla's.
Speaker 1: there's all these different ways You can win in that tabletop game, but there's really only two paths that are viable and one of them is just superior.
Speaker 1: So there's really no point in trying anything else.
Speaker 0: Don't even mess with those other systems Alright, so I mean so here's what you do.
Speaker 0: You want to figure out the perfect ending time ending method for your game, right?
Speaker 0: So there's a. there's a way we can do this mathematically.
Speaker 0: is it make a chart and on the chart?
Speaker 0: We're gonna graph time on the x-axis and on the y-axis We're gonna do percent chance to win and we're gonna draw a line for each participant, right?
Speaker 0: So, okay Well, so the player doing Agro, you know It's probably gonna have a big spike and then come down a whole bunch and the control player will have sort of a longer Low line that then spikes up later, right?
Speaker 0: Something like that.
Speaker 1: and I feel like maybe in play testing you if you gather data on a game You can turn that graph into a heat map and see if there's a nice like linear progression there if your average plays over time Right.
Speaker 0: It's like maybe play your game without an ending condition, right?
Speaker 0: Maybe say like You know magic right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, and there's.
Speaker 0: no we're not going to say how many hit points it takes to win.
Speaker 0: We're just gonna do as many damage as you can right and we're gonna record how much damage everyone took on each turn Right over time.
Speaker 0: and then we're gonna say aha Here's the the over this many games where we've collected data, right?
Speaker 0: It's like, you know, no matter regardless of which type of deck people were playing right on this turn.
Speaker 0: You know the the 20th turn, you know the average damn, you know, most decks did about 30 damage by then, right?
Speaker 0: So if we set the HP to win at 30 and we start play testing that Then what will happen is the game will probably end around this turn and everyone should have kind of equal chance of winning and The game will be pretty close right, you know.
Speaker 0: Just something basic like that.
Speaker 0: The problem is you can't just stop there because by setting the ending condition you are then affecting the Graph right?
Speaker 0: It's like it's one of those things where it's like quantum physics, right?
Speaker 0: As soon as you mess observe and mess with it, it moves you can't you can't pin it down, right?
Speaker 0: So it's like aha.
Speaker 0: We'll make the game end on.
Speaker 0: I've determined mathematically.
Speaker 0: We'll make the game end on turn 10 because on turn 10 and all the strategies are really close That'll be a really close ending right?
Speaker 0: So whoever's ahead on turn 10 deserves to be the winner.
Speaker 0: Oops by changing that rule players now play differently because they see the game will end on turn 10 and now on turn 9 They're all making crazy plays to get more points.
Speaker 0: Hmm, right or you know stuff like that.
Speaker 0: And it's like well that messes up.
Speaker 0: all my data is now I got to move my line again.
Speaker 1: I feel like there's a topic here kind of a side thing of.
Speaker 1: there are a lot of games especially more like poorly designed tabletop games not so much in video games where What ends the game is complicated enough to where players can't fully engage with it or even predict it.
Speaker 0: Well, sometimes they can control it right so you could make a game.
Speaker 0: where if do the resource clock, right?
Speaker 0: So here's how you do the resource clock.
Speaker 0: you do the same data gathering right with your ending condition and you say, okay, you know on turn You know this looks like about the time the game should end, right?
Speaker 0: This is where you know, I looked at how the players were doing on average.
Speaker 0: I collected all this data.
Speaker 0: This is when the game should end and you say, okay Rather than you know Saying the game ends when a player gets X points because that's the score that players had at that time on average or whatever Right.
Speaker 0: you say okay at that point in the game what were the average number of Lands played right in total?
Speaker 0: and you say oh, okay Well, we'll just make the game end when you know that many lands are played right?
Speaker 0: You can look at all the different quantifiable resources in the game Real time in the world number of turns player score player money player cards in hand player cards and deck player Properties owned player money, whatever it is in all the resources that are in your game Whatever your game is tiles left in the stack and carcass own meeples left, whatever Right, and if you graph those you can pick any one of them Right and say oh well and the game based on that one or that one or a combination of three of them Right by looking at what their values were at the right time in your little in your data gathering Right and any one of those could become your game ending clock.
Speaker 0: And of course though as soon as you choose one, right?
Speaker 0: Like I said, the players are going to move based on that.
Speaker 0: if you say All right magic ends when the 20th land is played someone's gonna make a deck that just rushes land onto the board.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right to end the game immediately, right, you know They'll do one damage and then they'll rush 20 lands and now messes up your whole thing.
Speaker 0: Yeah So it's it's very so.
Speaker 0: you have to basically make this.
Speaker 0: you have to collect this data pick something Playtest pick a different thing play test pick a different thing.
Speaker 0: But the metrics you're looking for in your play tests Right are the game.
Speaker 0: I should go long enough for everyone to enjoy the whole game and all the things there are to do in The game.
Speaker 0: you don't want it to end before people get to play with all the toys.
Speaker 0: Right, you don't want the game to go too long into garbage time where people are sitting around doing nothing and playing for no reason When someone's already won, right you want it to end is right before it's hard to actually mess up ending to you.
Speaker 0: You know too soon is better than too late.
Speaker 0: Right, if you end the game a turn too soon You're probably not going to be upset.
Speaker 0: right if you end the game ten turns too soon.
Speaker 0: Okay, yeah, but if you end the game two turns too late that you'll probably will be upset about that because you just wasted two frickin turns for no reason, right.
Speaker 0: So, you know err on the side of ending a little too early not a lot too early a little too early Right, plus people love shorter games.
Speaker 0: It's more marketable.
Speaker 1: Yeah To most demographics at least right.
Speaker 0: I'm talking about a little bit shorter Right, if you go crazy shorter problems a little bit shorter usually good, right?
Speaker 0: Usually makes your game feel tight makes the fear of players feel pressured, right?
Speaker 0: It's like it's like a good thing.
Speaker 0: All right, you know games where it's like.
Speaker 0: I played out everything exactly perfectly And then it ended like that could be satisfying but I think it gets a little.
Speaker 0: you know players sort of rest easy Right, you don't get that excitement, right?
Speaker 0: You're not like trying to score it on sides kick with two minutes left You know, that's you want that push right make your game and a turn earlier than you normally would have ended it.
Speaker 0: Anything like that.
Speaker 1: All right, so yes for over an hour.
Speaker 0: so I think good but yeah the panel.
Speaker 0: I wrote a lot more than that and more and a lot more details.
Speaker 1: We're definitely gonna have like here's some case studies Like let's look at this game and see how these end mechanics actually work out.
Speaker 0: Yep, exactly But yeah, that's that's what game endings are super important, right?
Speaker 0: You could actually ruin a game that would otherwise be great by having bad ending rules And you can't save a bad game with good ending rules.
Speaker 0: So no matter how you know, you've got to make a good game, right?
Speaker 0: First and foremost, but that ending rule is going to be so important.
Speaker 0: It could break it can't make the game, but it can break it And that's why this is really worth exploring in even great great detail.
Speaker 0: I think exactly the right moment.
Speaker 1: There's more than an hour's worth of content in this space.
Speaker 0: Easily it's like.
Speaker 0: it's like you probably do like a 10-week lecture Choosing the game ending right but think really hard.
Speaker 0: This is just the smallest aspect of gaming.
Speaker 0: that applies to every all gaming video games sports board games everything.
Speaker 0: So if you're making games think really hard about the ending.
Speaker 1: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at front row crew comm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 1: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 0: But unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night And the patreon patrons for this episode of geek nights are Alan Joyce, Heidi McNichol Marty green It's just like a dude guy Shartavish and Graham Finch.
Speaker 1: You hold the key to my heart.
Speaker 1: She gave me a kiss and she gave me my ticket.
Speaker 1: Clinton Walton Jay Vance ran from New Zealand Ryan Perrin Nicholas Brando Chris mid get the thirst Horhydrated Gannon dread Lily Tenebrae Chris Reimer Finn Sean Klein Shervin Ron Hall and a bunch of people who don't want me to say their Names might have noticed we stream this one again partly because We don't want to distract from the protests, but they seem to be getting a lot of things done and the needle is moving.
Speaker 1: Keep it up.
Speaker 1: but we are slowly resuming normal geek nights operations also partly because we use that time to completely rejig our pipeline.
Speaker 1: to avoid the Nondeterministic latency in streaming at some point in the future I'll probably do a little Patreon exclusive where I'll explain the previous pipeline and why it failed and why I wasn't willing to deal with fixing it and then the new pipeline.
Speaker 1: that seems to Be working fine.
Speaker 1: that pretty much just involves discord and carving Scott's face out of the discord We're using to do the show.
Speaker 1: But anyway all that aside Stay tuned for shows as usual.
Speaker 1: I don't know if we'll do one on Thursday because the holidays beginning Maybe we'll just take a break, but I leave you for now with something that Well, I don't know what you're gonna think of this.
Speaker 2: by greeting the guest warmly and holding brief conversations as you serve them You say to our guests?
Speaker 2: We're glad you're here Let's take a closer.
Speaker 2: Look at greeting guests.
Speaker 2: Every conversation you hold with guests should begin something like this.
Speaker 0: Good evening Or hi, how are you?
Speaker 2: Once you've greeted the guest start a brief conversation.
Speaker 2: try asking a question the guest can answer in a sense or two.
Speaker 2: You might ask something like this Is it still hot out there or this?
Speaker 0: Did you catch a game last night or this?
Speaker 0: Have you tried the lasagna?
Speaker 0: It's my favorite.
Speaker 2: Don't forget to hold quick conversations with our younger guests to.
Speaker 2: Children often play a big part in deciding which restaurant their parents visit.
Speaker 2: We want them to feel welcome and special here, too.
Speaker 2: So start conversations with children by saying something like this.
Speaker 1: What grade are you in at school?
Speaker 2: or this?
Speaker 0: Have you decided
Speaker 1: what dessert you're
Speaker 2: gonna have?
Speaker 1: Or this do you like hot fudge sundaes?