Speaker 0: It's Monday December 21st 2020.
Speaker 0: I'm rim, I'm Scott and this is geek night.
Speaker 0: tonight We are talking about the last decade in technology.
Speaker 0: It's like a mega tech news roundup, let's do this.
Speaker 0: It's uh, you know, it's funny because we did that.
Speaker 0: Usually we'll talk about this more in the main bit but we usually skip a lot of episodes around this time of year because we got like holiday stuff going on in conventions and We kind of baked that into our schedule and our process.
Speaker 0: and I realized part of the reason why we were struggling to come up With shows that we weren't skipping shows like we normally do.
Speaker 1: We're always struggling to come with shows.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah But we were struggling more because we usually have some slack at the end of the year.
Speaker 0: where there's like a week or two where?
Speaker 0: We won't do shows.
Speaker 1: Well anyway, so, you know normally nothing's happening because we're staying at home doing nothing.
Speaker 1: But something happened that I got to talk about right?
Speaker 1: All right, so My family long ago, right?
Speaker 0: It's about the tapestry No, and the children?
Speaker 1: when the children became adults right in the late 90s to the early 2000s, right?
Speaker 1: It became sort of silly to continue to buy gifts for you know each other.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so and also bothersome.
Speaker 1: so we did like one time we tried to do like a Not Secret Santa where you'd still have to buy a gift.
Speaker 1: right but like one of those Trading game ones, you know and it was it was meh.
Speaker 1: So that was it the end.
Speaker 1: just hey the gift we give to each other is you don't have to deal with any of that gift.
Speaker 1: nonsense.
Speaker 1: It's like fuck that noise, right?
Speaker 1: Amanda's family still does Christmas with presents or whatever and they all feel obligated to buy presents for every single other person and it seems like a big hassle and they What they end up doing is just telling each other exactly what they want and then buying it.
Speaker 0: Emily's family is a good middle ground where it's a lot of like low-key gifts that are just like generally nice but not like what I mean.
Speaker 0: Yeah, not like the traditional like here is a present.
Speaker 0: That is a big deal and might be expensive.
Speaker 1: It's more like well It's like my family does not like never buy gifts.
Speaker 1: what they do is like sometimes they'll be somewhere and they'll see something and they're Like, you know so and so would fuck.
Speaker 1: Oh my god Look at that.
Speaker 1: so and so would fucking love that and they'll just buy it.
Speaker 0: Oh, it's a trial device.
Speaker 0: It looks like a boo in a cornucopia.
Speaker 1: All right, right It's like and the next time they see that person they'll be like here.
Speaker 1: I got you this, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know, that's our friends.
Speaker 0: all are like we give each other gifts.
Speaker 1: when like we find something that is gift-worthy Or someone will just be like, you know, oh man, you know, I lost my you know scarf.
Speaker 1: It's like oh, I mean, I'll knit you one.
Speaker 1: Yeah, which one you want, right?
Speaker 1: You know that kind of thing, right, but there's not this formal must buy gift holiday thing, right?
Speaker 1: So You know, we don't really Need or want anything.
Speaker 1: we have everything we could.
Speaker 1: possibly We're well off and live in New York like right when I get Secret Santa's I'm like donate to a charity in my name.
Speaker 0: that is not racist or You know, etc, etc, like literally everything that I transphobic or I either have or is not reasonable.
Speaker 1: right, they all the things that you could actually get me as a gift are Unreasonable to give as a gift.
Speaker 1: like yes, please Let me upgrade my.
Speaker 1: you know, too many thousand dollar bicycle with a bicycle that is five times more money.
Speaker 1: it's like Upgrade my computer with one that has four 3080s in it.
Speaker 1: You can do that.
Speaker 1: That works.
Speaker 1: You can put four 3080s in one computer.
Speaker 1: They make those right?
Speaker 1: It's like there's nothing.
Speaker 1: What else could you get me?
Speaker 1: Right, I can't even imagine a boat.
Speaker 1: get me a boat.
Speaker 1: It's like what can you buy me?
Speaker 0: give me some mansions gig.
Speaker 0: get me a life of idle pleasure.
Speaker 1: Get me a DDR machine and a place in which to keep it.
Speaker 1: Now if someone could get me those things like yeah Sure, so Amanda's mom messages and she's like, you know The gift that she's getting us was like in the mail and it was many pounds like 50 plus pounds already.
Speaker 1: I'm like, I'm like, oh There is nothing that weighs that much.
Speaker 1: That is something that we need and want.
Speaker 0: maybe a 30 90. there are three slots wide Right.
Speaker 0: I'm like and we'll go in this house The house where I can't record without tearing down my living room.
Speaker 1: This is already trouble.
Speaker 1: whatever the hell this is I Love it because I already know the story of what this is, but I don't know what the dimensions are right, but anyway, the box shows up and we drag it upstairs.
Speaker 1: Amanda drags upstairs and Luckily, it's a box in a box.
Speaker 1: So opening the outer box.
Speaker 1: I didn't I was.
Speaker 1: I already said, okay I'm gonna open the outer box.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna try to see if I can identify the item simply from the writings and whatever papers are in there packing slip something.
Speaker 1: So I don't have to open the inner box because already good chance of me needing to get rid of this thing.
Speaker 1: Whatever it is, right?
Speaker 1: So what it is, it was a lot of money.
Speaker 1: first of all, right, which is ridiculous but it's some sort of like Automatic hydroponic garden thing and it's way too big to fit anywhere in our apartment.
Speaker 1: The idea at its core is not awful.
Speaker 0: Oh, that's the kind of thing.
Speaker 0: I would love if I had a house.
Speaker 1: Well, the problem is the.
Speaker 1: the idea at its core is not an awful idea.
Speaker 1: Right a little hydroponic system to grow stuff because you know, you don't have a yard, right?
Speaker 1: That's that's like the core idea is good.
Speaker 1: The problem is the size obviously is a problem.
Speaker 1: The cost is also a problem, but it was a gift.
Speaker 1: but the cost is still a problem because what this amounts to is a pot and A light.
Speaker 1: that's it's really.
Speaker 1: it's a pot and a light.
Speaker 0: so it's a weed grub gonna grow some weed pretty much Not that kind of pot.
Speaker 1: It's like I could go to the garden store and even if I bought a very good growing light because there are cheapo ones And it's and fan.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we got a cheap one hanging from the ceiling to keep our plants alive in the winter.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but if you got a fancy one, it still would only be less money than this thing And I mean ours is literally.
Speaker 0: I bought a light bulb for $20 and I hung it right.
Speaker 1: you have a four dollar outlet Yeah, but I mean you could buy a good one.
Speaker 1: It would wouldn't be as expensive as this.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and you can get a pot at the garden store for nothing, right?
Speaker 1: They just got stacks of them.
Speaker 0: That kind of stuff is just like in every shape and size timing it for like what kind of plant you're growing.
Speaker 1: Sure.
Speaker 1: Sure, but that's the thing is you could just You know just on your phone use like your reminders app to be like I actually just for my crap old plants on the windowsill.
Speaker 1: I have a Google task.
Speaker 1: That's like water the plants It just boop, right?
Speaker 1: What this thing has to justify its enormous price is all sorts of unnecessary technological integrations akin to remember that juice thing the where you'd like juicer.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you put the bag of fruit and it would.
Speaker 1: it was like connect to Wi-Fi and squeeze the juice out or whatever.
Speaker 1: This is like that.
Speaker 1: It's like it has.
Speaker 1: I shit you not.
Speaker 1: it's not an exaggeration.
Speaker 1: This is why I'm talking about in tech day as Amazon Alexa integration Right.
Speaker 1: It's got Wi-Fi.
Speaker 1: It's got like all this ridiculous stuff To like.
Speaker 1: it can take care of the plants when you're not at home.
Speaker 1: when you are at home It can adjust the lights.
Speaker 0: It's like this really sounds like a weed grower because the thing so from trying to invest in that industry Is that weed plants in particular compared to most other plants are little divas and if you look at them wrong They just die.
Speaker 1: So people is the thing very much sold environments much like the juicer.
Speaker 1: Oh, it comes with you have to.
Speaker 1: you can't just like get some seeds and toss them in.
Speaker 1: it has these proprietary Like little seed things you have to buy from them Coffee cups or some bullshit, right?
Speaker 1: So they're like these little triangle.
Speaker 0: That is very different from what I was imagining.
Speaker 1: So basically at the top of the pot There's like a plastic.
Speaker 1: I didn't open it to.
Speaker 1: I just looked at the pictures on the internet at the top of the pot.
Speaker 1: Imagine that there is a sort of piece of plastic with holes in it and You have these sort of cones and you put the cones through the holes Pointy side down and the pointy side is now where the seeds are in the water.
Speaker 1: the hydroponic right?
Speaker 1: No dirt Yeah, and then it comes the.
Speaker 1: the plant would come out the top of the cone and towards the.
Speaker 1: the light that you have Right, so without some I guess you could just get like a cone of some kind that fits in the hole And as long as the bottom reaches the water and is appropriately has holes in it You could grow other things you wanted to in there.
Speaker 1: You can't just toss a seed in the water That's just a seed in water.
Speaker 1: That's not gonna do anything.
Speaker 1: So, yeah, don't buy this thing.
Speaker 1: But also be.
Speaker 1: we are now burdened with this giant box taking up a lot of our apartment Waiting to figure out how to get rid of it.
Speaker 1: It's not like we can carry it to those full disclosure.
Speaker 0: when we heard this story We were like, ooh, I wonder like because we would need up we needed a better girl life.
Speaker 0: Then we looked it up to like see what the deal was and we were both like yeah that can stay at Scott's apartment.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like getting rid of it is now an ordeal.
Speaker 1: so instead of giving us a gift we have been given an ordeal.
Speaker 0: At least it's not a great ordeal.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm hoping that I emailed the company.
Speaker 1: They haven't gotten back to me.
Speaker 1: I'm hoping that they will say yes some sort of delivery person will come And just take it right away and the money will go back to whoever we want to deal with it.
Speaker 1: But um, I don't know what's gonna happen.
Speaker 1: We'll see.
Speaker 0: Yeah Cuz I think back way back when my camera died and I finally had to like ship it back to get a replacement.
Speaker 0: The only way to actually ship it back was to like go physically to a UPS store or a FedEx.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I feel bad though for whatever delivery person had to unnecessarily Carry this thing from A to B and now B to who knows where.
Speaker 0: oh, it's tough in general Like the like obligation rituals of American society can often be odd Yeah, but I mean like, you know, some delivery person's got to do this.
Speaker 1: and then how much fossil fuel was wasted transporting this.
Speaker 1: It's just like it's just.
Speaker 0: oh, you know, yeah, I was these were I was the kid rose.
Speaker 0: the gifts were like I just wanted anything.
Speaker 1: Yeah I didn't have any money and I have wanted stuff.
Speaker 1: You know how many Nintendo it's like.
Speaker 1: I would go to it.
Speaker 1: I would go to Toys R Us and there was a wall of Nintendo and I got to pick one like once a month.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right, maybe.
Speaker 1: and so it would be like hey, I want every single one of these I don't care what even the crappy ones.
Speaker 1: I want every single one.
Speaker 1: So it's like you could.
Speaker 1: you could never run out of gifts to get me.
Speaker 1: just keep buying ones I don't have and we're good to go.
Speaker 1: But now I have every NES game that has ever been made in any country ever on a hard drive or a micro SD card.
Speaker 0: That is now very silly Yeah, so my only my only recent tech adventure is I actually bought a Fitbit because I wanted a more reliable heart rate monitor.
Speaker 1: How is it any more reliable than like Apple watch?
Speaker 1: Well, partly the same method.
Speaker 1: This is the same method.
Speaker 1: the Apple watch does so one.
Speaker 1: I don't have an apple like shiny Android watches and they but I'm saying it just shines a light into your arm.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah doesn't use a different method It's.
Speaker 0: it's more like what algorithms does it use and how often does it track and everything?
Speaker 0: But basically my Android watch was only good for like specific like I'm going for run right now And I wanted to do like more long-term like heart track.
Speaker 1: So it doesn't.
Speaker 1: it doesn't track when you're not running.
Speaker 0: It doesn't unless I turn that stuff on like it doesn't.
Speaker 1: Oh the Apple watch just tracks all the time.
Speaker 1: But obviously if you do exercise it then it like yeah Constantly tracks for the duration if you're not actively if you haven't told it you are currently working out.
Speaker 1: It'll just check it once in a while.
Speaker 0: Yeah That's what this does.
Speaker 1: you can even if you like pay attention which I never do but you can actually see the green light turning on underneath.
Speaker 1: You know.
Speaker 0: the other thing was.
Speaker 0: I realized that Strava at some point seems to have gotten rid of the ability to just connect sensors To it directly.
Speaker 0: it'll only integrate with like other apps to get heart rate data.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I've never tried to connect to it directly used to be able to used to be able to buy like a Bluetooth like ant Whatever like a whatever compliant heart rate monitor, and it would just work.
Speaker 1: and they seem to have gotten really I just I mean I'm these days and doing everything in Swift and then Swift just when it Swift is done.
Speaker 1: It just saves its results to Strava.
Speaker 1: And if I do another a non biking exercise You know I just use on the Apple watch.
Speaker 1: I just say Apple watch I am Italy.
Speaker 1: Apple watch will actually tell me it'll be like hey Are you walking outside now, and I'll be like you got me Outside and it's like okay.
Speaker 1: You want to record this and I'm like yeah fine, whatever.
Speaker 1: But the only time I would use Strava directly is if I'm biking outside, which not doing too much of yeah.
Speaker 0: But it was interesting because one thing I wanted to see was you know it's been a while since I tracked like My heart rate all the time like overnight into data analysis And I've been training really hard like Morse like this year when kovat.
Speaker 0: What did I do?
Speaker 0: I doubled down on getting totally ripped.
Speaker 0: So I wanted to like actually track like.
Speaker 0: how is that affecting my heart rate long term?
Speaker 0: because we had a conversation recently among our friends where people were Calling into question my current max heart rate and my current resting heart rate.
Speaker 1: well you were used.
Speaker 1: you were.
Speaker 1: you were you know doing A usual rim right saying something that is technically correct, but is also an exaggeration Like yes my maximum heart rate is this and it's like.
Speaker 1: that is a heart rate that your heart reached for like one Single reading at one moment.
Speaker 0: Now that I've had this Fitbit I'm tracking it kind of reliably with the same measure.
Speaker 0: I discovered that the Android watch.
Speaker 0: I have not that accurate.
Speaker 0: this thing is way more consistent.
Speaker 1: Okay, I'm actually surprised.
Speaker 1: How consistent the Apple watches.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, I'm sure they have watch.
Speaker 0: I don't great I just don't have an eye now.
Speaker 1: Well.
Speaker 1: I now no longer feel it.
Speaker 1: I was thinking of buying one of the strappy chest ones now.
Speaker 0: I don't care I would only get enough stress chest one if I was also getting the ones that track Chest expansion and compression.
Speaker 0: so I can do more advanced metrics, but you can't use those with Strava anymore, so I bother.
Speaker 1: Well, I could use them with Swift.
Speaker 0: Yep Yeah I can safely say that my resting heart rate is like locked in at 47 beats per minute and my sleeping heart rate is like Okay, yeah, I don't know my sleepy one because I just I charge the Apple watch overnight.
Speaker 0: Part of the thing about the Fitbit is it'll last constantly tracking for like a week Like nothing.
Speaker 1: it's probably not doing anything else.
Speaker 0: Oh, it is doing nothing else.
Speaker 0: It'll show me the time with the screen a little bit and I can see my heart right now And it doesn't fucking do anything else, but it won't show you like your text messages.
Speaker 1: now.
Speaker 1: Two watches.
Speaker 1: you weren't two watches?
Speaker 0: well actually I don't know where my Android watch is anymore cuz about Couple months into COVID I just stopped wearing it.
Speaker 0: cuz I'm not going anywhere.
Speaker 1: can't on your phone say find my watch and then your watch will start.
Speaker 0: beep I could but my watch ran out of battery probably months ago.
Speaker 0: It's somewhere in the apartment.
Speaker 0: Oh Notice how I stopped talking about my heart rate for a while.
Speaker 0: that's cuz I don't know where my watch is.
Speaker 1: good job.
Speaker 1: Well, it's not far.
Speaker 0: That's good I guess but mostly the only before we get into the actual like tech show.
Speaker 0: The thing I noticed is if it's alright like yeah, take it or leave it.
Speaker 0: But what bothers me is that thing I noticed about Strava and as I poked around the ecosystem of Health related metrics collection devices just being able to be used with software is getting increasingly Siloed and monetized in a way that I am uncomfortable with.
Speaker 1: Oh, I mean, I'm feeling in the bicycle area, right?
Speaker 1: There's the ant ant plus standard whatever and everything seems to work with that no matter what you get.
Speaker 1: So I'm not feeling too bad in the biking area, but I guess there and there might be problems in other areas.
Speaker 1: Yeah, because I mostly all the bike computers all the bike all the bike sensors that I've seen are ant ant plus whatever It's called and all the bike computers support them.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and all of the apps that bike people actually use, you know Zwift Strava the other ones that compete with those right ride with GPS, whatever.
Speaker 1: They're all using the same thing and they all work together.
Speaker 1: and I feel like it's in a situation where if any of Those apps tried to say we don't want to work together.
Speaker 1: We want to do our own thing.
Speaker 1: Everyone just stop using that.
Speaker 0: Yeah It's mostly what Strava seems to have stopped working with is just use a raw device that doesn't have some sort of other app or service associated with it.
Speaker 1: Also at the same but at the same time in the bike computing space There is pretty much Wahoo and Garmin and no one else's.
Speaker 1: that's it.
Speaker 1: Right?
Speaker 1: So but neither of those The Wahoo apps on your phone don't really do what Strava ride with GPS do.
Speaker 1: They're really just for sort of yeah working with the computer.
Speaker 1: So you think so they need those integrations.
Speaker 1: if Wahoo or Garmin made a Strava Competitor or a you know ride with GPS competitor, which would be hard to do, but they could do it Then they could pull away if they wanted to yep.
Speaker 0: But basically that's part of the other reason I got this thing is what I've been using to track all my other health stuff is Google Health and just.
Speaker 0: I was thinking a lot recently about What's Google gonna shut down next and I don't really trust that any of the Google Fit stuff is gonna stick around.
Speaker 1: Google Health is so shutting down.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so I need I wanted to move to something that will probably stick around longer.
Speaker 0: So Fitbit does all the stuff.
Speaker 0: I was using Google Hell or Google Fit or whatever for.
Speaker 1: so there is something though to say that Even though I think under normal circumstances Google would have shut down a lot of things that it has I mean even more than it already has.
Speaker 1: yeah, is that anything that is basically a part of Android that is sort of matching a feature?
Speaker 1: Yeah
Speaker 0: Like an Android phone will just kind of do some health stuff automatically because that Google Fit exists
Speaker 1: Right is like there are things that they have to have on Android because iOS has them right so they feel like they also have To have them even if no one uses them.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so whereas on Apple's side It's like Apple has all this stuff and you're like how many people are actually using that shit?
Speaker 1: Using the Apple home automation thing that they have the Apple I home or whatever the hell it's called, right?
Speaker 1: It's like there's got to be no one fucking using that thing But Apple keeps it there and that forces.
Speaker 1: I guess Google now thinks it has to have that also For some god-awful reason right?
Speaker 1: So it's like, you know an Apple people will never tell you right?
Speaker 1: It's like how many people actually talk to Siri.
Speaker 1: how many people actually you know use the like the EKG thing that you put in the Apple watch?
Speaker 1: How many people are actually doing that versus you put it there you talk about it you forget about it And it's now just a thing Whereas you know, but Apple won't kill those things whereas Google wants to but they might not because Apple is there.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I'm just being cautious with Google on anything that I'm actually like, yeah, I'm back up that I back up that shit.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, I've exported all that data out.
Speaker 0: I've got a plan now.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah Even though it's really hard to get data out of Fitbit too, but I think that'll last longer.
Speaker 0: Yeah, yeah, we'll see.
Speaker 0: Anyway got any news?
Speaker 1: What was my news?
Speaker 1: oh, yeah really tiny news.
Speaker 1: So, you know how?
Speaker 1: these days you go to some websites and this banners.
Speaker 1: they say yo, we got some cookies you want them And I've you know, you can install.
Speaker 1: I have a plug-in in Firefox a Firefox add-on that hides a lot of those Banners, which is nice.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah I should still add block micro block just to not show me the GDPR banners, right?
Speaker 1: So this is because of the GDPR law in Europe general data protection regulation.
Speaker 1: It's not a US law.
Speaker 1: so if you're not operating your You know business in Europe, I feel like a US only like eShop or something.
Speaker 1: You don't have to do this.
Speaker 1: and what's Europe gonna do right?
Speaker 1: Just don't take European orders.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you're good to go.
Speaker 0: And if you do but if Europe isn't a big deal you see some people who just like Block Europe from their site.
Speaker 0: the end that's happened actually more often.
Speaker 1: You can do it.
Speaker 1: So github is.
Speaker 1: this is owned by Microsoft now, right?
Speaker 1: It has been for a little while and they operate worldwide as worldwide as they can places They're.
Speaker 1: they're usually the ones getting blocked right because they're hosting something that the country doesn't want, right?
Speaker 1: Like software that helps you get through, you know, evil firewalls and things like that.
Speaker 1: So anyway so GitHub has removed all of these GDPR cookie banners from its site.
Speaker 1: Well, they're clearly operating in Europe.
Speaker 1: They have a lot of users in Europe and they're a business operating in Europe.
Speaker 1: They charge money to European companies to use github with their company accounts.
Speaker 1: So how how are they doing this?
Speaker 1: How do they get rid of their banners?
Speaker 1: It's really fucking simple.
Speaker 1: How they got rid of the banners, they stopped using fucking cookies.
Speaker 0: The buried lead the thing.
Speaker 0: no one fucking talks about that.
Speaker 0: Those banners are only there because you're collecting evil data for advertising networks, right?
Speaker 1: So you're actually allowed to have cookies on your site.
Speaker 1: You're just not allowed to have any Non-essential cookies, right?
Speaker 1: So the cookie that keeps you logged in to github that cookies allowed.
Speaker 1: That's a normal cookie usage, right.
Speaker 1: if the cookie added some other features to your website Like maybe I don't know what else you would use a cookie for besides keeping you logged in these days There's other ways to do this, but that's it.
Speaker 0: Every site that has a GDPR cookie warning is using cookies for nefarious purposes Right.
Speaker 1: GitHub does not send any information to third-party analytics services, right?
Speaker 1: I guess they're analyzing you themselves.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's just their own analytics, right?
Speaker 0: They only have like.
Speaker 0: no third party can uniquely track you.
Speaker 0: only they can uniquely track you use the website.
Speaker 1: GitHub will only ever use cookies that are required and none to track display ads or send information Anywhere.
Speaker 1: and because they're only using cookies basically to keep you logged into github, right and nothing else They don't have to display the stupid banner.
Speaker 1: So when you see the banner on the website, right?
Speaker 1: Don't just think Oh this stupid law.
Speaker 1: It's just like a reminder.
Speaker 1: It's like you knew this already, but I just want to remind you right that it's like.
Speaker 1: don't just blame this law from Europe Right, don't just blame.
Speaker 1: there are other parts of that law we can discuss other times.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that may or may be good or bad that laws Is it both a blessing and a curse is my opinion, but this aspect of the law the cookie banner aspect, right?
Speaker 1: You see the banner.
Speaker 1: you're like all the stupid law put this banner here.
Speaker 1: It's like no that website you're visiting, right?
Speaker 1: Maybe they poorly designed the banner and made it extra annoying, you know, maybe that's their fault, right?
Speaker 1: Maybe you know, right but what's really is that website that's putting up that banner is a operating in Europe Which is why not right?
Speaker 1: and be they are Announcing to you.
Speaker 1: They're tracking your ass and selling information about your behavior on that website to someone else and therefore If you're going to accept those, you know, don't like accept the cookie Right.
Speaker 1: Just try to get rid of the banner without accepting the cookies.
Speaker 1: Fuck them.
Speaker 1: yeah, they could get rid of that banner if they just decided that your experience on the website and having you be a Happy customer slash visitor was more important to them than selling your data to somebody.
Speaker 0: black dynamite.
Speaker 1: So right, so when I when you see that banner right in your I think most of the time myself included people think That annoying law or I make this banner go away.
Speaker 1: You need to think this evil.
Speaker 1: This is an evil website telling me it's evil website.
Speaker 1: yeah, that's what you need to test.
Speaker 1: the first thought you need to think when you see the banner show up right is This is an evil website that's been forced by law to tell it to notify me of its evil ways.
Speaker 1: Fuck this website.
Speaker 0: Yeah, also a subtle point.
Speaker 0: You don't have to click accept to use websites.
Speaker 0: You're actually they're not allowed to do that.
Speaker 0: You can instead click on the banner and go in and actually say no don't fucking use those cookies and they have to comply Or they're a deep shit.
Speaker 1: Yep, you can basically find some way to get rid of the banner without clicking Except cookies.
Speaker 1: I don't think I've ever clicked except cookies once in my life.
Speaker 0: No, I don't think I have either.
Speaker 0: Of course, I usually don't ignore the banner.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there may I don't remember I may I don't know it's and I can't guarantee that.
Speaker 1: but like I don't remember doing it And I guess I can look at my people see what's in there.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's definitely not my default behavior.
Speaker 1: And yeah, you could always do that.
Speaker 1: If you're worried that you might have clicked it one time just delete all your cookies and start over again Into places, right?
Speaker 0: So, uh, we're.
Speaker 0: we don't really have like.
Speaker 0: there's not enough information for us to talk about the biggest news like deeply But I just want to touch on it and link to a couple of websites you can read about it.
Speaker 0: But if you're not aware solar winds got hacked like crazy and For for a bunch of complicated reasons almost definitely Russian state-sponsored espionage and this is a big deal.
Speaker 0: like this story is one of the most important tech stories of the decade and Ongoing, like we don't know the extent of the damage from this because it's a big deal and everyone's trying to figure it out.
Speaker 1: Yep, so if you don't know solar winds is basically sort of like a Cisco competitor kind of.
Speaker 0: yeah sort of easy way to ish.
Speaker 0: Kinda, you know How do I manage my network and enterprise infrastructure generally?
Speaker 1: Yeah, you're like, you know Why you?
Speaker 0: this is literally like the enterprise kind of crap that I built my whole career around.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like you don't you know, this is not a something that normal people are, you know Concerned about right?
Speaker 1: It's like it's only a business thing.
Speaker 0: Yeah like the kind of person who knows a lot about solar wind stuff is the kind of person who uses like computer associate software or BMC software.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but anyway, what happened was is in order to log in to some solar wind stuff they were using this thing called duo which is a single sign-on service right sort of like one login or even you know, Like login with Google is a is a single sign.
Speaker 0: single sign on is not trivial to implement.
Speaker 0: There's a reason why there are vendors that provide tools and even hosting to do it.
Speaker 1: Yeah active directory Solution right, you know kinda but anyway So what happened was is there was some sort of vulnerability?
Speaker 1: where by There are these?
Speaker 1: when you set up duo right on your end, right?
Speaker 1: You're the company and you're gonna say, okay I want all my employees to log into all of our company systems with duo.
Speaker 1: So we're gonna set up duo and we need a private key that we're gonna hide from everybody right except for us and the duo company and then That will be used for you know, verifying when people log in right generating You Know TOTP all kinds of secret stuff.
Speaker 0: We're trying to avoid like this in detail because it's it's.
Speaker 0: it's a little bit as a point.
Speaker 0: You don't know how this stuff works.
Speaker 1: the point is if you get a hold of that key, right the only ones who should have that key are duo and The company that is using duo for their systems, right?
Speaker 1: If you someone else were to get that key, you could just log in.
Speaker 1: Yeah, as anybody.
Speaker 0: in general having a private key to anything gives you absolute power.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so and duo even in the documentation is like yeah, don't let anyone get this key y'all you'll be you'll be boned.
Speaker 1: and so SolarWinds was using duo and the key got out and Therefore people were able to log in to SolarWinds systems at many companies And they were able to log in, you know, basically almost Undetectedly because obviously it was detected as almost undetectedly, but basically they didn't need to have the two-factor authentication Right.
Speaker 1: They were able to.
Speaker 1: just you know, sometimes you go to a website and it'll be like, okay Tell me your two-factor authentication code and you're like remember me for 30 days.
Speaker 1: So I don't have to do this hassle again and it's like, okay And the way it does that is with a cookie Not a cookie.
Speaker 1: that will not a cookie that will generate a GDPR banner a normal cookie.
Speaker 1: And now you don't have to type in your to TP again for 30 days, right?
Speaker 1: But if you have the secret key You could just use that secret key.
Speaker 1: just make the cookie and just put it in your browser out of whole cloth.
Speaker 1: Just open up a blank web browser Take the secret key run some code Go to into your browser and be like new.
Speaker 1: you can actually do this.
Speaker 1: You can go into your browser if you didn't know and go new cookie and just create cookie up.
Speaker 0: Just type some stuff in there.
Speaker 1: You can be like front row crew.
Speaker 1: calm new cookie, right of key.
Speaker 1: Your name You know value, you know, Joey Jojo Shabbat in the early days of cookies and web browsing Are you?
Speaker 0: I would like look at cookies that were on my computer to learn things about websites.
Speaker 0: I might have been interested in messing with it.
Speaker 1: You can still do that.
Speaker 1: But yeah, and then we're going to be a lot more human readable and simple Sure, but then you go to front row crew.
Speaker 1: calm and guess what your bread browser is gonna send.
Speaker 1: front row crew calm the information That your name is Joey Jojo Shabbat.
Speaker 1: You won't see it but that data will go over the wire and our web server will ignore it and do nothing with it Because it's not looking for that, right?
Speaker 1: But regardless you could go in and say yes session ID equals a correct working session ID and you'll just be logged in.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you don't have to you don't have to type in any username password do to be nothing Yeah, and depending on the system you're interacting with you might not even leave like log traces.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it'll just look like you.
Speaker 1: someone was logged in and doing stuff and the only way you could like notice That's something shady was going on.
Speaker 1: You'd be like, wait a minute Because you couldn't like make a user you had still a login as an existing user.
Speaker 1: You could like wait a minute.
Speaker 1: rim was logged in and doing stuff from Russia Right from the shady VPN service in I don't know an island, right?
Speaker 1: Something.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: Now there's a lot of things going on here.
Speaker 0: Like there are reports that solarwinds they are their own update server had a password that was literally like solarwinds 1 2 3.
Speaker 0: But suppose That was not even used as part of this attack that was just discovered by accident.
Speaker 1: Like well, it's you know, once you get attacked suddenly, you know, the eye of Sauron is upon you.
Speaker 0: I guess there's two takeaways for all three takeaways.
Speaker 0: I think you need like.
Speaker 0: we cannot talk about this yet because there's not enough info.
Speaker 0: just read these articles.
Speaker 0: But number one Probably the single biggest threat to large enterprises and governments like in the United States For like a hackers and attacks like this.
Speaker 0: It's probably this this kind of attack the supply chain attack.
Speaker 0: You don't attack the fancy bank.
Speaker 0: you attack the dumpy ass software vendor that the fancy bank uses to do something boring Mm-hmm, because the bank is gonna run that software inside of its network and just trust it in many cases Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: The second takeaway is Uh as this as you know, like that password thing we talked about even without supply chain attacks The guess the best way to put this is security in most places like everywhere is a lot less Capable than you probably think and very much at the edges of these networks.
Speaker 0: if you get past the edge You're bait.
Speaker 0: you basically get root at that point.
Speaker 1: Yep, pretty much.
Speaker 0: and the third sort of like.
Speaker 1: it's sort of like you can take really good care of your keys to your safe Deposit box, you know keep them separate and be super hide them in a really good place And that does nothing for you.
Speaker 1: If the safe deposit box at the bank has like, you know a drop ceiling and someone just comes in through the roof of the bank.
Speaker 1: Yeah, which has happened.
Speaker 1: I've seen that in the news.
Speaker 1: That's why I mentioned it.
Speaker 0: Yep, or like case in point, you know many of my jobs.
Speaker 0: I you know, I'm an expert in the fixed protocol this like finance protocol Like that's a. I know a terrifying amount about the stupid protocol, but in the old days like a decade ago You know how that protocol was secured.
Speaker 0: It wasn't.
Speaker 0: it was plain text stock orders and transactions all this stuff We're just ASCII raw human readable being sent over networks with no security at all.
Speaker 0: Why was that not a problem?
Speaker 0: because it was all inside of private networks and private lease lines So no one really had access to that.
Speaker 0: But if anyone got inside that network, it was all just there.
Speaker 0: get root on any server that interacted with this stuff.
Speaker 0: There's the whole transaction log.
Speaker 0: There's everything.
Speaker 1: So you can start trade and you can start trading.
Speaker 0: yeah, you should.
Speaker 0: In fact, I was once at a place where it wasn't me, but someone else a developed a QA person Accidentally connected to a production connection and century like hundred thousand dollars worth of orders of a test suite out to the market And they all executed
Speaker 1: only a hundred thousand.
Speaker 1: Whoo.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know how we fixed it.
Speaker 0: He wrote a script that wrote the inverse of every one of those orders and we ran it through the same QA pipeline to undo the positions.
Speaker 0: Okay, and we actually made a profit.
Speaker 0: so it was really funny in the end, but it was also Terrifying.
Speaker 1: also, you're fired.
Speaker 1: Yeah Accidentally made us money and you're fired.
Speaker 1: We have to tell the SEC about this.
Speaker 0: We did have to tell them about it, of course he did.
Speaker 0: I'm not joking Yeah, no, no, it was I. I helped write some of the incident report for that.
Speaker 0: It was a. that was a. that was what I know.
Speaker 0: that was early in my capital markets.
Speaker 0: career Shall we say cost several multiple jobs ago?
Speaker 0: but the third takeaway here that I think is Really needs to be talked about and it's kind of terrifying that our own government because of the incompetence of the current Republican administration Is not talking about it.
Speaker 0: This is a state-sponsored Attack on American markets and American infrastructure.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean also world, you know.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, it's except the state committing the thing.
Speaker 0: Oh, they're definitely.
Speaker 0: I'm confident.
Speaker 0: similar attacks are going on globally right now But it is pretty directly clear that the Russian government is behind these attacks.
Speaker 0: no one seems to disagree on this fact and I don't think the United States is even like Remotely prepared to deal with actual modern cyber warfare.
Speaker 1: No, I was trying to tell this to someone the other day.
Speaker 0: It's I was watching that conversation you were having.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like if you're a Russian right a Russian tech person Yeah, and you are for some reason the evil and not opposed to your own government, right?
Speaker 1: You like you're a Russian who likes Russia.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like you're into Putin like you're down for this or at least you're not, you know opposed, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like you're or maybe you know, you're terrified of that government and this is a way to not get you know.
Speaker 0: There's a lot of reasons someone might do this kind of thing.
Speaker 1: I'm saying the only like even me as a tech person.
Speaker 1: the only reason that I could see not Wanting like if I imagine Scott, would you like to apply for the job work for Russia being you know?
Speaker 1: You know engaging in you know clandestine espionage via computer.
Speaker 1: I would say the only thing I don't like about that job is the morality of who I'm working for.
Speaker 1: There's literally nothing else about that job that I find unfun uninteresting unexciting.
Speaker 0: that kind of job itself would be Super fun.
Speaker 1: some of the best About that job sounds fucking awesome, except I'll be working for the bad guy.
Speaker 0: All of our IT was the class where half of us were computer security and the other half were hackers.
Speaker 0: And then you swap the next quarter one group.
Speaker 0: You got to provide a bunch of services.
Speaker 0: Don't get hacked.
Speaker 0: the other group your only job.
Speaker 1: I took that class as well.
Speaker 0: No, it was a fun class anyway So the own.
Speaker 1: so obviously there are probably plenty of highly skilled Technological people in Russia who are loyal to Russia and are perfectly happy with that Otherwise awesome job because they don't consider it to be an evil job the way I do.
Speaker 1: yeah Meanwhile in the United States right.
Speaker 1: if the United States was hiring that for position come to the NSA or the CIA and do clandestine computer espionage for United States right.
Speaker 1: and even if The you know we got rid of all the Republicans and was only Democrats in both Congress and the president And it was all Democrats.
Speaker 0: Let's even assume magically It's the only that is always doing the right thing and there is no ethical question.
Speaker 0: magical future world right?
Speaker 1: They're only asking me to do Espionage.
Speaker 1: is that I am okay with?
Speaker 1: right?
Speaker 1: that I can see are for the good of the world.
Speaker 1: that job sounds like awful.
Speaker 1: That sounds like the worst job to work right with all sorts of government bureaucracy bullshit.
Speaker 0: This is.
Speaker 0: the US government would never ever hire the kind of person who is good at that kind of thing, right?
Speaker 1: It's like you know and not even I'm not opposed like the core principle of being a public servant like I'm all down with that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's just actually being a public servant in the United States especially for the federal government is Awful, it's like there's so much bullshit.
Speaker 0: You got a deal like oh wait, so I work That in my life I can work way harder make like a tenth what I will not attend more like a fifth of what I Make now have to move somewhere.
Speaker 0: I don't want to live and deal with bureaucracy.
Speaker 0: Yeah, maybe I'll just stay in the private sector.
Speaker 1: Right exactly And that's why we're getting our asses kicked.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but one of the one of the one of the major reasons we're getting our asses kicked Yeah, but what I'll leave you with is and I'm not saying that a kinetic force is what we should do Don't get me wrong, but no American doctrine.
Speaker 0: Is that a text like this?
Speaker 0: cyber attacks are tantamount to kinetic attacks like.
Speaker 0: that is an act of war and we reserve the right as a nation to respond with either Cyberattacks or kinetic attacks like.
Speaker 1: yeah, that's only that's I'm pretty sure.
Speaker 1: you know I've that's been true for a while But I believe that since no one has ever fucking you know Done that it's pretty much become a you.
Speaker 1: You know.
Speaker 1: yeah Yosemite Sam you're crossing this line.
Speaker 1: Nobody is ever gonna do it.
Speaker 1: It's not it's not actually true.
Speaker 1: It's only written on paper an excuse in case someone actually gets the balls to do it, but there's something even worse.
Speaker 0: It's there's this like there's a way worse.
Speaker 0: part of this.
Speaker 0: everything We're talking about is like they attack the government directly which happened like the Department of Energy got hacked by this like FYI Yep, and if you don't know what the Department of Energy does go look it up because if you don't know what it does You're probably gonna be really surprised when you find out what it does.
Speaker 1: the Department of Energy doesn't handle the power plant.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the Department of Energy handles energy.
Speaker 1: The big energy.
Speaker 0: yeah the biggest the biggest we know about.
Speaker 0: Anyway, but the real places where these where these attacks will happen Even if our government was secure is all the support structure around our government the economy itself Private power companies like that whole sector.
Speaker 0: if you think it sucks to work for the federal government doing IT Imagine working for like a power company in Oregon.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right Con Edison's IT.
Speaker 0: Yeah imagine that job.
Speaker 1: I see I see their website and how it works.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I see that website.
Speaker 0: I know what it would be like to be.
Speaker 0: it's not.
Speaker 1: oh, it's got okay parts, but it's also Obviously not a place I want to work.
Speaker 0: but anyway things of the day.
Speaker 0: So remember a while ago, we found the worth it kids channel and had a million great things.
Speaker 0: So can't just leave.
Speaker 1: that was that.
Speaker 1: was you who found that I actually watched any of those?
Speaker 0: you haven't watched Big Top Burger.
Speaker 0: I Don't remember though the Wow go watch Big Top Burger.
Speaker 0: The show is really short.
Speaker 1: I might have.
Speaker 1: I don't remember.
Speaker 0: It's about a clown and a bunch of people dressed as clowns working in a burger truck.
Speaker 1: I Don't think I saw that.
Speaker 0: It's it's up your alley specifically anyway.
Speaker 0: So I found another channel like this randomly this jewel haver.
Speaker 0: But this channel I just found.
Speaker 0: this video was recommended to me by the algorithm, but it was just this like weird like early 80s looking computer rotoscope kind of thing and it's called playing an RPG for the first time and it's just this.
Speaker 0: Animated comedy sketch of an adventurer is often his first adventure and he sees a rat and he murders it.
Speaker 0: then he sees a ghoul and he murders it.
Speaker 0: and then he goes into town looking for a quest and I thought it was gonna be okay funny, but about halfway through it goes from pretty funny to Really funny.
Speaker 0: the voice acting in this is stellar.
Speaker 0: This is equally funny to some of the worth it kids, but for different reasons.
Speaker 0: this thing was really really funny to me.
Speaker 0: I'm not even gonna spoil it.
Speaker 0: It's three minutes long.
Speaker 0: This channel is worth subscribing to based on this video alone.
Speaker 1: I Actually just in my mind as I was thinking of my current thing of the day a Flash came in and was like wasn't that gonna be the thing of the day, but I guess that one will be Wednesday.
Speaker 1: So You know me I like a fossil but I really like a trilobite That's.
Speaker 0: one of the first things I learned about you was that you like trilobites.
Speaker 1: Trilobite is a cool-looking fossil.
Speaker 1: if you find a cute one.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the problem is if you had an actual live trilobite somehow that would be scary as fuck.
Speaker 1: Get that thing away from me, right but a trilobite fossil is hella cool.
Speaker 1: So I found this article like a month ago and I dug it up here for my thing of the day today And it's basically do you know like the first time anyone saw a trilobite?
Speaker 1: And it's like there was this guy in like, you know, some royal collection and like Oxford who noted this fossil He thought it was some kind of flat fish or something Welsh the Reverend lewd.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they don't know if it's like Lloyd lewd something like that.
Speaker 1: Anyway, but he was you know credited as yeah, this is Southwestern Wales.
Speaker 1: Yeah credited as being like the trilobite discoverer, but that's obviously the colonialist interpretation.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like he didn't discover the trilobite, right?
Speaker 1: He's just the first person to in English writing in the West, you know Make note of it in a scientific journal, right?
Speaker 1: So that's something.
Speaker 1: but it's not like a discover right.
Speaker 1: and this article really goes pretty interesting Goes into like.
Speaker 1: yeah, actually People going way way way way way back to super ancient times You know, these were you know Stone Age right.
Speaker 1: think Stone Age.
Speaker 1: the rocks are real important in the Stone Age.
Speaker 1: That's why it's the Stone Age right.
Speaker 1: people are making things out of stone.
Speaker 1: They were paying a lot of attention to stones.
Speaker 1: They didn't have television.
Speaker 1: They didn't have internet.
Speaker 1: So yeah, they're playing with rocks.
Speaker 1: They would note and be like, you know what this rock is a real special rock.
Speaker 1: It's got look it's different Look, it's a mini and there were like cave drawings of trilobites, right and people would make You know jewelry's out of trilobite fossils and stuff and it's like the trilobite was discovered way before This dude at Oxford.
Speaker 1: so really fascinating here.
Speaker 1: history of the trilobite that I did not know is is obvious.
Speaker 1: in retrospect Trilobites are cool.
Speaker 0: All right in the meta moment.
Speaker 0: I have not put up the signal.
Speaker 0: I have not read for the Tale of Genshin.
Speaker 1: I I thought I was in bed last night and I'm like I could do it.
Speaker 1: I could do it Cuz I don't have to go to work.
Speaker 1: I don't gotta do nothing.
Speaker 1: I could just do it right now.
Speaker 0: You know what I ended up doing.
Speaker 0: I never reading a long article about CIA tactics Because I've been watching a bunch of lectures from that woman who did the TED talk on like CIA Disguises and I went down a deep rabbit hole.
Speaker 1: I'm going back to playing that um that Hades game that I almost beat.
Speaker 1: I'm just gonna beat it and then I'll be good.
Speaker 0: Ah, yeah, I'm finished I'm getting near the end.
Speaker 1: You think you're getting near the end?
Speaker 1: You have the eye?
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah that that opened up some things.
Speaker 0: I found some interesting conversations.
Speaker 0: Some people are were.
Speaker 0: some of the characters in this game are worse than I thought and some of them are actually better than I thought.
Speaker 1: Yep Chowderman Showed.
Speaker 0: I pointed some friends at the Chowderman's music video the other day.
Speaker 1: There's one spread the chowder love.
Speaker 0: You know what the Chowderman music video from that game reminds me of the music videos that were on Windows PCs in the multimedia era.
Speaker 0: Well, that's what this is trying exactly, but specifically octopus of love if anyone remembers that one.
Speaker 1: Yes So, yeah the Conventions not happening.
Speaker 0: at least there's gonna be like an online Zenkai con so we'll figure out.
Speaker 0: we'll probably do something for that.
Speaker 1: Am I gonna go to Zenkai con?
Speaker 1: Whoa.
Speaker 0: Yes, this would be Scott's first Zenkai con in like a decade.
Speaker 1: It's been that long.
Speaker 0: I think the last Zenkai con you went to it was still in King of Prussia.
Speaker 1: I know I went to one in the other in the nuke in Lancaster.
Speaker 0: Yeah once you lent Lancaster one time I go every year because it's actually my favorite small Lancaster two times.
Speaker 1: it's possible.
Speaker 0: I could check the archive.
Speaker 0: I have that database of every convention performance.
Speaker 1: They have gone to Lancaster two times, but I definitely went at least one time because there's a comic book store near the train station.
Speaker 0: You know what?
Speaker 0: I actually don't track.
Speaker 0: Yes, you did.
Speaker 0: We stopped at that comic book station both years.
Speaker 0: a comic book store by the station.
Speaker 0: I don't track which of us went to a con.
Speaker 0: I only track what panels we did.
Speaker 0: but I can usually derive if you were at a con Because you really never do cons without me, but I often do cons without you and I'm gonna go do a con without rim.
Speaker 0: Now do it go for it go.
Speaker 0: But if anyone wants Scott at their con to do a talk without any rims because you don't need some you don't need hair then Invite Scott with that but then come to me privately and make sure that I'm also there and make me the moderator of Scott's panel.
Speaker 1: Don't do that.
Speaker 0: That'll be really funny.
Speaker 1: It won't be funny someday.
Speaker 1: Maybe the moderator of rims panel.
Speaker 0: But for the time being we're gonna be doing online cons only.
Speaker 0: so stay tuned.
Speaker 0: We're gonna.
Speaker 0: if there is an online convention that you would like to see us do something at especially if you'd like to see us do something other than just pre record a panel and give it to you like
Speaker 1: and The online convention already has enough not white not straight not dudes on its roster.
Speaker 1: That is the point for it that they can afford to add two white dudes and still be okay.
Speaker 1: Then have the convention call us up.
Speaker 0: Yep Otherwise, I don't have any more work the rest of this week.
Speaker 0: So, uh, I'm gonna work out some stuff, but I'm not gonna say what.
Speaker 0: so I don't shit-talk anything, but I'm working on two.
Speaker 0: I'm working on two projects that you might see the fruits of and a third project that I ain't saying shit about for another couple Years.
Speaker 1: the only things I am actually doing that I've Can say that I'm doing because I've done them is I am streaming myself solving advent of code every day Yes, and some good Scott problem-solving ASMR.
Speaker 0: I Guess.
Speaker 1: and then I'm a bike and I biked again after a little break.
Speaker 1: I'm biking to nowhere.
Speaker 1: so you can come and watch a twitch stream of me biking in place stationary biking And talk to me about anything appropriate while I am For when I know and if you don't and there's no times on these things, it's pretty much whenever I feel like doing them Every day that I'm not working just on my twitch channel.
Speaker 1: You can also come to our discord and there is a channel on the discord.
Speaker 1: that will tell you when the twitch goes live And you can click on that and so forth.
Speaker 0: I haven't been hanging out in that discord much the last couple weeks.
Speaker 0: I've just been really busy, but I'm getting back to my normal life.
Speaker 0: I got a bunch of work stuff going on.
Speaker 0: That's actually taking a lot of brainpower and time But I'm trying to get back to my normal life of goofing off more and doing more like geek night stuff with all of you.
Speaker 0: So stay tuned Mm-hmm, uh That's all I really got there.
Speaker 0: Let's get right to the main bit.
Speaker 0: We we thought for you know, we're not going anywhere There's no holiday travel.
Speaker 0: So we're actually around for the entire end of the year to do shows.
Speaker 0: We happen to have exactly two weeks left of the year meaning one geek nights episode of every day.
Speaker 0: So a great way to not have to come up with a show I thought was let's talk about like 2020 like what we did in 2020.
Speaker 1: Yeah Every magazine and every media outlet in the whole world has these stupid repeating things.
Speaker 1: This is why you know, you know time magazine is always like person of the year.
Speaker 1: You know why they do that because that's a whole one whole issue.
Speaker 1: They don't have to fucking think about what the title of the cover story is gonna be.
Speaker 0: Why do you think I get so excited when Scott lets me do a tech news roundups?
Speaker 0: Like I don't have to do anything.
Speaker 0: Let's just go find some tech news, right?
Speaker 1: So here we go four episodes.
Speaker 1: You don't have to think about what the thing is.
Speaker 1: We're just gonna do Decade and maybe also year in whatever.
Speaker 1: so in tech, right?
Speaker 1: 2010 verse 2020 and also I guess 2019 verse 2020 maybe right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, something like that.
Speaker 0: So we'll keep it fluid for the Monday show.
Speaker 0: We'll see how this goes.
Speaker 0: But this is actually particularly easy for me because I moved to New York City In late 2009, yep I also moved to New York City in very early 2010 like the end of 2009 right after you.
Speaker 1: so for my life right Everything changed very.
Speaker 1: it's very easy for me to remember what 2010 this Decade was like because I just have to think about my entire time.
Speaker 1: not not, you know working in New York City Which is much longer but living on my own in New York City Right.
Speaker 1: is this decade?
Speaker 1: where is the previous?
Speaker 1: anything that isn't me living in New York was a previous decade.
Speaker 0: No, what's weird?
Speaker 0: so you think about the fact that the previous decade included the entirety of college and Like the first five years of geek nights That's right.
Speaker 0: Like I was being on the radio in Tokyo.
Speaker 1: Yes, that happened.
Speaker 0: That was the thing.
Speaker 1: That was the thing one time in the ancient.
Speaker 1: I have the wave file for it somewhere.
Speaker 1: Yep, I saw it in my backups.
Speaker 0: Anyway, I also had this idea.
Speaker 0: I thought all right I'm gonna go back in Google Photos and scroll back down to like January 2010 and I'm hoping those photos will like jog my memory of like things I Didn't start using Google Photos until 2011.
Speaker 1: So I have a better way to jog my memory because Luckily or at least for technology specific.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah new egg orders.
Speaker 1: No, luckily or unluckily, right?
Speaker 1: I was my apartment in 2010 Maybe 2011. it was early in the decade.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah You got was burgled.
Speaker 1: It was burgled.
Speaker 1: There's an episode about it and I Had to list all the things that were burgled for insurance purposes because I had renters insurance.
Speaker 1: You should get renters insurance if you rent.
Speaker 1: get it today.
Speaker 1: It's so cheap cost like a dollar.
Speaker 1: If you can afford to rent you can afford renters insurance you.
Speaker 1: it's like must-have.
Speaker 0: you spend more money on losing quarters in the laundry.
Speaker 1: I've spent like $100 a year on renters insurance for ten years.
Speaker 1: the one payout is I'm still making a profit anyway.
Speaker 1: so What kinds of things Technology were?
Speaker 0: so here's a big one.
Speaker 0: I can think of a big change that began right in the early 2010s like it was actually 2011 when this happened, but Adobe switched from buy our software to we are software as the service pay us a monthly fee and you'll always be up to date.
Speaker 0: that was about a decade ago, but I think there's a theme of the decade of this was the decade of a huge amount of software used by professionals shifted to subscription models and the whole like ecosystem of software as a service completely Reimagined itself.
Speaker 1: Well, I just think cloud everything in general.
Speaker 1: Yep, right.
Speaker 0: I mean creative everything.
Speaker 0: It's in the title Yeah, everything clouded.
Speaker 1: right.
Speaker 1: you stopped using Microsoft Office, right and you started using Google Drive.
Speaker 0: Yeah, or you started using like Microsoft's Office cloud thing, right in 2010.
Speaker 1: What was Google Drive was just like what like a cute thing that they bought from someone else like Google Docs.
Speaker 0: I wonder what my oldest file even is on Google Drive.
Speaker 0: Let me do a query.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like everything moved to the cloud.
Speaker 0: Like.
Speaker 0: I moved everything I do to the cloud.
Speaker 0: for the most part I like change how.
Speaker 1: it wasn't just a place for it wasn't just like Flickr where it's like, okay, you have your local file collection and you share it on Flickr.
Speaker 1: It's like no now your your file collection is just on.
Speaker 0: the 2010s was the decade where I shifted to.
Speaker 0: Almost everything I do is either software.
Speaker 0: I subscribe to or a web browser.
Speaker 1: Yep, pretty much All.
Speaker 1: but here in 2010, right?
Speaker 1: The con the game console that I had was a week and maybe Xbox 360 that I barely.
Speaker 0: we both bought those Xbox 360s and they got rid of them.
Speaker 1: Yeah Is that right?
Speaker 1: that 4k was not a thing in 2010?
Speaker 1: right 20 the 2010s was 4k going from.
Speaker 1: basically in the beginning part of the decade only.
Speaker 1: maybe like ultra professional TV movie people could have any 4k fucking anything.
Speaker 1: and now like GoPros have had 4k since forever.
Speaker 1: I bought the gh4 this decade, which was like the first like, you know Consume almost almost consumer like highest end but still consumer Possible prosumer camera and it could record 4k video.
Speaker 1: It was like the first one Basically, and now every camera has 4k like the cheapo.
Speaker 1: GoPros have 4k.
Speaker 1: They've had him for years.
Speaker 1: right.
Speaker 1: 4k TVs are not ridiculous.
Speaker 1: 4k monitors are not ridiculous.
Speaker 0: I'm looking at two 4k monitors right now doing gig nights.
Speaker 0: I bought them recently.
Speaker 1: People have monitor, you know, people have very high-resolution screens Even if they're not 4k.
Speaker 1: the pixels now are so small.
Speaker 1: at the beginning of the decade 1080p was like the best right?
Speaker 1: It was like yeah 1080p's fuck.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right now 1080p's like yeah.
Speaker 0: This was the decade where 16 by 10 as an aspect ratio just finally disappeared completely.
Speaker 0: rest in peace.
Speaker 0: I miss you.
Speaker 0: the world standardized on 16 by 9 or but I you know what I noticed with compute.
Speaker 0: computing shifted to like tablets for one thing, but monitors are all 16 by 9 or the ultra wide gamer format and Laptops shifted to whatever fucking weird aspect ratio just to make the hardware good.
Speaker 0: No one cares.
Speaker 0: Yep, pretty much like laptops are all weird aspect ratios, which would have messed with my early 2010 sensibilities And I just don't care in the 2020s.
Speaker 1: Now the smartphone, you know was really Originated in the previous decade with the palm trio the other palms.
Speaker 1: iPhone is from 2000.
Speaker 0: I got my first smartphone in like 10.
Speaker 1: It was the first iPhone 2006 or 7.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: iPod nano was 2005.
Speaker 1: I want to say it was late 2008.
Speaker 0: I got my first smartphone ever because my work gave me a modern blackberry like a like a one that actually Blackberries were very last decade blackberries.
Speaker 1: Um, but if you look at the numbers on smartphone adoption Smartphone adoption while they did exist there were iPhones in the late 2000s.
Speaker 1: They were numbers wise.
Speaker 1: They were only the domain of the wealthy the tech enthusiasts the well-connected the you know I guess elite whatever you want to call it people like me.
Speaker 1: Yeah Who had a lot of money with those are the only people who had like iPhones?
Speaker 1: By the way with 3g only right in the late 2000s Only in this decade that everyone has a smartphone.
Speaker 1: Everyone has 4g.
Speaker 1: right 4g didn't really exist in the late 2000s.
Speaker 0: like we went from smartphones are this playground and people like really rely on Wi-Fi or Specialized tethering devices - and like people have replaced their computers with smartphones.
Speaker 1: Yeah, people just don't have computers anymore and that goes hand in hand with the cloud thing.
Speaker 1: Right is that it used to be that you needed your even though you had this other smartphone II stuff.
Speaker 1: Right those first smartphones.
Speaker 1: you would plug in your iPhone to your computer to sync it with iTunes, right?
Speaker 1: It couldn't do its own thing.
Speaker 1: It couldn't live on its own.
Speaker 1: Whereas we went from that to well everything's in the cloud.
Speaker 1: So really your computer doesn't matter.
Speaker 1: You're not storing anything locally.
Speaker 1: You can just throw your computer in the garbage as long as you've erased it.
Speaker 1: You know for safety's sake right get a brand new one and be up and running so quickly because all you do is log into All your services and you're good to go.
Speaker 1: Everything.
Speaker 1: nothing's on your computer anymore.
Speaker 1: All right, your software's not your computer anymore.
Speaker 1: And that was like this dream that they had in the 90s or 80s even older of this sort of Networked computer.
Speaker 1: and that's actually what they started with.
Speaker 1: right the mainframes.
Speaker 1: You would just be at a terminal.
Speaker 1: and so what they were thinking with like You know thin clients and stuff right in the 90s 2000s was like hey You're gonna have a computer and I guess the chrome the chromebook was also sort of attempting to do this.
Speaker 1: You're gonna have a computer that's really just a terminal and you're gonna all the work is gonna be done by CPUs in the cloud.
Speaker 1: Right, you're gonna do nothing locally, but what ended up happening was simply absconding right sort of repurposing the web Right and web api's as a way to.
Speaker 1: okay.
Speaker 1: You still have a local CPU.
Speaker 1: that's doing a bunch of stuff but Most of your data and the software is on some other computer and we're gonna send you part of the software to run locally but not all of it and So you're getting that effect right but not necessarily the original imagined implementation.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the you know client-only computer.
Speaker 1: I think in general though that all happened in the past ten years.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so computer workstations like an actual like full-on PC as much as they decline in terms of normal people using them People who don't have like a purpose for them as a tool or a gaming PC or whatever.
Speaker 0: we saw the like full talk of this more on Tuesday next week.
Speaker 0: the fall of and then like ultra Renaissance of PC gaming like PC gaming in the previous decade before the 2010s was in a real like coming into a really bad state and Like it has had a lot of ups and downs, but it's like it always exists.
Speaker 1: So we like can never die.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but it's like exploded over this past decade coupled with It's easy to forget like the beginning of this decade was an era where Intel was the undisputed master computer chips Like that was like the end of the Nehalem era in the beginning of the Sandy Bridge era Like that was when we went from don't waste your money on an Intel to fucking.
Speaker 0: don't buy anything but Intel.
Speaker 0: for the love of God Yep, it'll boot on the first.
Speaker 0: try works every time like that We.
Speaker 0: that was.
Speaker 0: that was a sea change for me and how I worked with computers.
Speaker 1: computers became now I don't know if I'm gonna buy another Intel, you know That's a long time the one I have but like.
Speaker 0: but it's hard to remember that the decade that 2010 computers unless you had a lot of money.
Speaker 0: We're still fickle and unstable Mmm, and the 2010 through 2020 computers like desktop workstations are so rock-solid Even if you get like an AMD like.
Speaker 0: they're fine.
Speaker 0: They're easy to build.
Speaker 0: people can build computers without knowing a lot about computers.
Speaker 0: that happened during that decade.
Speaker 0: Like that whole decade was like that.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Oh, we started with Windows Vista.
Speaker 1: now, we got Windows 10.
Speaker 1: Yeah, all those other windowses were in between there, whatever Storage.
Speaker 0: I'm trying to think about what kind of storage I had in 2010.
Speaker 1: But uh, oh, yeah, let's talk about right.
Speaker 1: So we went from.
Speaker 1: there were SD cards in The 2010s because I'm in the early the late 2000s because I had a crap.
Speaker 1: Oh digital camera Right a little pocket cannon power shot, whatever and it took an SD card.
Speaker 1: But I think that SD card was maybe like I don't know what the maximum size was like four gigs Maybe 16 gigs at the most.
Speaker 1: like it was not big.
Speaker 1: Yeah at all.
Speaker 1: It might not even been that big.
Speaker 1: I might just be missed.
Speaker 0: and like USB flash drives went from Critical to why do you even own one over the course of this past decade?
Speaker 1: I see best SD card 2009. can I even find this?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I usually look at what was I buying in 2009?
Speaker 1: Which flavor of SD?
Speaker 1: Yeah, four gigabyte something like that.
Speaker 1: eight or sixteen?
Speaker 1: Yeah, four.
Speaker 0: so in the 2009 so like four minutes of a gig nights panel, right?
Speaker 1: So in 2009 you could get like 16 gigs would be like a big one.
Speaker 1: 32 was like the biggest expensive mega one like if you had a camera that shot raw Most people.
Speaker 1: I guess we're using compact flash then because the SD wasn't big enough.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like the Marantz not the Marantz takes compact flash still, right?
Speaker 1: Now.
Speaker 1: so I think that 2010s were clearly the rise of flash memory.
Speaker 1: not just SD micro SD right But also m2.
Speaker 1: right m2 basically didn't exist.
Speaker 0: Yes, these were still like oh if you're fancy put an SSD in your computer and they weren't that big either.
Speaker 1: Nor were they actually the best right.
Speaker 1: the density of flash memory Absolutely exploded this decade and now you can get you know ridiculously large Storage you can get.
Speaker 1: like an iPad.
Speaker 1: you can get an iPad.
Speaker 1: I think with like a terabyte of storage.
Speaker 1: I think and I've had Pro does is there?
Speaker 1: is there a terabyte option?
Speaker 1: Let me see.
Speaker 1: Hold on This big ones is?
Speaker 0: I mean the computer I have now that I built several years ago Like fuck God like five years ago at this point.
Speaker 0: I bought a one terabyte m.2 by NVMe drive.
Speaker 1: If you buy an iPad Pro your choices are 128 256 512 or a terabyte.
Speaker 1: So big big flash storage is taking over the world.
Speaker 1: Yeah tiny micro SD cards.
Speaker 1: We started off last decade with like a regular old fucking USB.
Speaker 1: I don't even know.
Speaker 1: do we even have micro USB?
Speaker 1: I think I might only had mini.
Speaker 0: I think we had.
Speaker 0: I think we had made I don't remember but yeah, I feel I don't remember.
Speaker 1: But anyway, the point is micro but now USB C.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it took over like lightning cables Is like the cheap option for like crappy stuff and stuff.
Speaker 0: that doesn't matter but everything's USB C now.
Speaker 1: Yep Camera sensors, I already talked about 4k, but you know, that's not just the screens But I just want to say also the cameras.
Speaker 1: right cameras at the beginning.
Speaker 1: get a get a digital camera from 2010 and compare it To 2020. it's like chocolate and shit.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's not even close.
Speaker 0: I mean I think about the camera we used to use to record gig nights compared to what I got now, right?
Speaker 1: The camera that you get in an iPhone today even a low-end iPhone today is better than a like a Canon Multi-d mark whatever from ten years ago, right?
Speaker 1: That camera obviously also has advantages that the iPhone won't have but I'm talking about just like the image, you know sensor Right just unbelievable advancement in that area.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah in 2010 I bought a 4 gigabyte USB flash drive USB 2 so slow as molasses.
Speaker 0: I spent ten bucks on that thing day.
Speaker 0: four gigabytes of very slow storage Mm-hmm, but it's not just that you like.
Speaker 0: storage like that got bigger.
Speaker 0: It's that how people use storage changed a lot Like we went from.
Speaker 0: you put files on USB sticks and pass them around to everyone.
Speaker 0: just transfers files directly via or via the cloud.
Speaker 0: Yep, pretty much like I have.
Speaker 0: you know what I use the USB store.
Speaker 0: I was a stick for recently.
Speaker 0: I had a. I have a cheap car to get through COVID if there's emergency travel.
Speaker 0: It has a USB hole in it.
Speaker 0: I put a USB stick in that hole.
Speaker 0: It'll play mp3s on that USB stick.
Speaker 1: There's better ways to do that, but that's a way.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's a way that that car supports natively cuz that cars from 2012.
Speaker 1: Yeah So what was I gonna say?
Speaker 1: There was something else?
Speaker 1: Oh Oh my god, why did it just slip my mind?
Speaker 1: I Talk about something while I try to remember.
Speaker 0: So let's talk about some other big changes that have happened Especially in technology that affects us like I think about how we record gig nights.
Speaker 0: We saw the final death of firewire.
Speaker 0: like firewire is finally gone and there is professional audio equipment that uses modern stuff like USB-c has basically actually Finally replaced firewire and I went driving this giant Mackie mixer.
Speaker 0: Do.
Speaker 0: now I have this tiny little one you thing that does like everything that Mackie did and more is Just better in every way.
Speaker 0: just plugs in with USB-c just works Like the geek.
Speaker 0: nice pipeline has gotten so much tighter and the other thing related to that We went from.
Speaker 0: it is a gigantic difficult expert pet task to stream any video to anyone to.
Speaker 0: OBS exists and streaming is trivial and free for people to do.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we're using like you stream right?
Speaker 0: Oh my god We did a live stream.
Speaker 0: What did we do that?
Speaker 0: I think that was actually 2007. we did that streams something like that.
Speaker 0: But streaming was hard.
Speaker 0: like think of what.
Speaker 0: think about when did we start streaming gig nights live?
Speaker 0: Kind of recently during this decade because it was kind of a pain in the ass until pretty recently.
Speaker 1: So for consumer technology Right.
Speaker 1: I think the absolute biggest advancement in any single like narrow thing and versus its impact on the entire world is It wasn't invented this decade, but the advancement of the lithium ion battery.
Speaker 1: Oh my god.
Speaker 1: and the last ten years is basically behind Everything else right?
Speaker 1: It's like, you know, I'm not a fan of the electric car not a fan of any car, right?
Speaker 1: But you got your electric car basically was not a thing ten years ago.
Speaker 1: Now people just drive them around like it's no big deal.
Speaker 1: Yeah You got your every single device you have that you walk around with being not super heavy had lasting a long time Right all these things even if the chips were all.
Speaker 1: they all kept up with all the chip Advancements and every other area right that we've you know advanced in.
Speaker 1: if the lithium ion battery had not advanced It's like Apple would be like, well, we made this really tiny Apple watch at this tiny amazing screen and this tiny little CPU But the battery lasts ten minutes or it's as big as your arm.
Speaker 0: Yeah like I got to the point to where I have a hot and it burns your arm like I have a powerful laptop that I Could play like sieve six on for like hat like four to six hours before I have to plug it in.
Speaker 0: like That's kind of amazing how far that advanced from.
Speaker 0: like How desperate I was for there to be holes if I was on like a plane or a train like by the time there was An outlet on those two things I could plug computers into.
Speaker 0: I didn't need that outlet anymore You know.
Speaker 1: and obviously all these technologies that we've been talking about have Horrifying capitalist externalities.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah Yeah, you want to talk.
Speaker 0: the biggest theme of the last decade is technologies converged on a singularity of cyberpunk dystopia.
Speaker 1: Yes, but I think the lithium Right the need for the world's desire for lithium going up has maybe caused more damage than any of the other Things.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right.
Speaker 1: It's like.
Speaker 1: it's like yeah horrifying.
Speaker 0: they you know Not just lithium and rare earth metals like there's a small number of things we need to drive.
Speaker 1: It is like the elephant in the rare earth metal room, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like, you know, it's like, okay Yeah, they're mistreating workers in a factory making phones.
Speaker 1: That's horrifying and the worst right?
Speaker 1: It's like where do you see where the lithium comes from?
Speaker 1: It's even more horrible, right?
Speaker 1: It's like and and that lithium is in Everything Like almost like it's rare that you would even want to buy something Like.
Speaker 1: what do you need in life that you don't already have unless it's powered by a lithium-ion battery?
Speaker 1: so
Speaker 0: one thing I have appreciated about this is that We also saw because lithium batteries got better and because like the software and the understanding of how to manage them got better a lot of things converge to the point to where a Lot of stuff now charges in a standard unified way via USB.
Speaker 0: Like who would have thought over the last decade that USB would become the modern power outlet for most things Mmm, like.
Speaker 0: I didn't think USB would be it Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: So yeah, I guess yeah, you know, obviously, you know the Twitter.
Speaker 1: we talked about the dystopia.
Speaker 1: right Twitter existed in the late 2000s.
Speaker 1: Yeah Facebook existed way before then.
Speaker 0: who would have thought that Facebook would rise to cause possibly more damage to American society than any other social technology?
Speaker 0: I mean that seriously.
Speaker 0: Facebook should be right.
Speaker 1: but none of those things Really took off and became world conquering.
Speaker 1: world owning things Until this decade, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, they existed last decade, but they were pretty much the realm of like Computer people right?
Speaker 1: It's because of the battery the phone the cloud.
Speaker 1: That was the the only platform which could skyrocket those existing things To be more than what they were right.
Speaker 1: they were, you know, maybe not completely innocent But relatively innocent in there, you know young days.
Speaker 1: But the that platform that we invented this decade is what allowed those things to just conquer the entire world and ruin us all.
Speaker 0: well, I'd say.
Speaker 0: in general technology like if you look at like 1990 through 2000, you know The information age like internet went from not existing for any practical purpose for normal people to existing But wasn't like fully realized yet and there was a lot of ideas about like what we could do with it But it wasn't quite in
Speaker 1: the space outlaw.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: The 2010s was like, all right We're building and like the 20 things were we build all this stuff and we almost Discovered that humans might not have been ready to be able to talk to each other all at the same time Mm-hmm, like it might literally be that humans are not ready for that technology.
Speaker 0: I said this a decade ago and I think I was right.
Speaker 0: Not that it was hard to be wrong about this that Social technology like this and the idea of like memetic warfare would become real.
Speaker 0: here We are.
Speaker 0: our news was literally about hacking and like cybersecurity Meme warfare has became real in a literal sense this decade And I don't know what's gonna happen like I can't even predict like that space evolved more between 2016 and 2020 than it did between 2016 and like 1916. yeah, right.
Speaker 1: So it's like on the one hand it sort of feels like man Technology doesn't move anymore like it used to right because we had huge movements, right?
Speaker 1: We went from you know CD to mp3 Spotify.
Speaker 0: I went from like cassette 8-track to cassette Like a decade but cuz you have to CD to mp3 to nothing like I just stream stuff that went by like a lightning.
Speaker 1: Right also, yeah that because of the cloud thing right we went from mp3 to stream this decade.
Speaker 0: Yeah We killed physical media except for collectors and nerds and people who don't have access And people who really just insist on principle and like collectors and take it down.
Speaker 1: I'll just pirate it.
Speaker 0: Come on Oh Piracy you didn't get destroyed.
Speaker 0: piracy kept plugging along in about the same rate.
Speaker 0: It always has.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, absolutely nature.
Speaker 1: well life finds a way Sure, obviously But you know if you think it's like even though there were these huge Change, you know society shattering advancements in technology in the 2010s, right?
Speaker 1: like what we said where we started and where we are now it feels like it's slower because Those changes are like more Incremental.
Speaker 1: it's like ah, we've replaced this USB with yup USB C Whereas before we were replacing like serial cable with us.
Speaker 0: before we replaced nothing With cell phone and then we replace cell phone with smartphone.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: It's like, you know, we're the.
Speaker 1: they're meaningful upgrades We're getting but we're still getting and they're.
Speaker 1: they're you know, just as earth-shattering.
Speaker 1: But when you just look at them on face value, right?
Speaker 1: It's like you.
Speaker 1: look at 2000 verse 2010 2000. it was like, you know, Motorola StarTech and 2010 was like iPhone.
Speaker 1: Yeah, or I want to say great Maybe iPhone 420 like the difference between but but different, right?
Speaker 0: For like 3.1 is almost earth-shattering by itself, right?
Speaker 1: But then you look at like iPhone 4 from 2010.
Speaker 1: I think that's right versus iPhone 12 and it's like oh that's not actually That huge.
Speaker 0: Yeah well part of this is there's.
Speaker 0: there's a trailing edge of.
Speaker 0: some of what happened this decade is Brand new.
Speaker 0: technology is extremely destabilizing and even though like you said we have this perceptionist moving slower It's actually moving faster and faster.
Speaker 0: The rate of change is accelerating and the but - there's this lagging indicator of People are adopting the technology that came about us in the beginning of this decade exactly.
Speaker 1: We are way ahead of the curve the curve right that we hit in the 2000s.
Speaker 1: We had all this stuff.
Speaker 1: Yeah that stuff was adopted by the entire world and then Polished in the 2010.
Speaker 0: that is where a lot of this earth-shattering societal change happened.
Speaker 0: It wasn't someone invented social media.
Speaker 0: It was a critical mass of humans have access to social media.
Speaker 1: All the things we invented in the 2000s the 2010s wasn't about inventing new things as much as it was about Deploying the inventions of the previous decade to all humans who could possibly access it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right.
Speaker 1: and then making it easier and you know Incrementally making it nicer and nicer and nicer because so many people have it.
Speaker 1: Well now there's more money in it to do that part, right?
Speaker 0: So something that's actually stuck out in my mind the last couple of months partly cuz I'm at home a lot I'm watching a lot of documentaries and read more just like nonfiction science.
Speaker 0: It is easy to forget that in the last decade a Terrifying number of Scientific discoveries and advancements have happened that are kind of literally pushing into understanding the nature of existence.
Speaker 0: We there are things that we just think we know that.
Speaker 0: yeah We're literally discovered this decade.
Speaker 1: quantum all that stuff about like teleporting photons and shit all that stuff happened this day Like cut like there are.
Speaker 0: we've discovered all more about space in the last decade than possibly the previous 30 years Mm-hmm, and it seems like we almost have this and I say we is like society especially American society even like nerds like us.
Speaker 0: We're very guilty of it.
Speaker 0: The example I always use is doesn't it feel like Pokemon always existed like Pokemon's been around forever?
Speaker 0: You almost like your brain almost make up memories of it around since then the mid to late 90s.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like I was in high school and Pokemon was invented like yep, pretty much.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but it's easy to think Oh, yeah, this quantum physics thing that just seems obvious like yeah, what we knew?
Speaker 0: we knew that what a hundred years ago.
Speaker 0: It's like no we learned that thing Four years ago.
Speaker 0: No one knew that before.
Speaker 1: four years ago Or at least someone had written it as a theory and that was in it floating around in your mind.
Speaker 1: But then the experiment that proved it right is like happened here.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but we're also large.
Speaker 1: Large Hadron Collider was 2010s, but right some of these last decade talk about that trailing edge.
Speaker 0: This decade was a huge advancement of material science and quantum mechanics.
Speaker 0: The next decade is going to be not the met like not the like mass-market societal adoption of technology using that but the early practical applications of some of that advancement.
Speaker 0: the danger is Those advancements are Almost too powerful and too dangerous and the only people who will be able to leverage them in the next decade are mega corpse and states.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean the perfect example of material science I think is carbon fiber right.
Speaker 1: if you look in the 2000s carbon fiber was like this thing you saw someone making in a lab.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right for some fan Or maybe it was and then it was on like an f1 car or something which is still is you see like a concept for a?
Speaker 0: Carbon-fiber bike.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right and now I mean there.
Speaker 1: I think there were carbon-fiber bikes maybe in 2000 But the point they were not accessible, right?
Speaker 1: It's still not it's still not cheap.
Speaker 1: But now if you have money, you can just get carbon fiber whatever.
Speaker 1: you can get a carbon fiber camera tripod You can get a carbon fiber, you know backpack, you know the carbon fiber fucking anything, right?
Speaker 1: So whatever fit, you know, there are other fancy materials were.
Speaker 0: so the first carbon fiber bike wasn't until the late 80s And it was bespoke.
Speaker 1: Yep, yeah, I mean they.
Speaker 0: I was saying they existed but like now I go to a bike shop Like every bike has a carbon fiber fork at least.
Speaker 1: Yep, ever all of them pretty much, right?
Speaker 1: It's all over the place.
Speaker 1: Yep, but
Speaker 0: I sued like a thing that I this sounds dumb But I've thought about this this whole decade cuz I I travel a lot I always like my whole adult life a lot of my career has been traveling and the thing that has stuck with me is you can tell when there are big advancements in material science when things get thinner and smaller to the like and planes
Speaker 1: Seats
Speaker 0: and armrests and backrests and like all that like boring stuff You don't think about.
Speaker 0: we're able to get thin enough to like cram Additional rows of seats into planes without reducing the space people have access to.
Speaker 1: Also they took away legroom because they're assholes.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah They did also reduce space but some of that change was because the seats could literally be thinner Because material science had advanced to that point.
Speaker 0: Material science advanced to a I keep saying terrifying degree.
Speaker 0: But it's kind of true in the last decade in ways that are not obvious to people who don't work in these fields.
Speaker 1: so now it's hard to see a decade out right because You know, it's hard to see.
Speaker 1: but what I can see in the more immediate future.
Speaker 1: We're talking about the chip war, right?
Speaker 1: That's happening, right?
Speaker 1: I still believe everything I've said about chip wars so far.
Speaker 1: It's gonna have a huge impact.
Speaker 1: I think something else, you know What you have to do is you have to look around and you have to be able to see Right.
Speaker 1: It's like we look at like an iPod right an original iPod classic.
Speaker 1: and you look at an iPod classic today The first iPod.
Speaker 1: and you say wow, look at that chunky ugly boy.
Speaker 1: But when it was new, it's like wow, that's fucking amazing, right?
Speaker 1: It didn't look chunky at all.
Speaker 1: It didn't look stupid that it was making a bunch of noise with the spinning hard drive in it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know, it didn't look stupid that it's hard drive is small or any, you know, anything like that, right?
Speaker 1: It looked perfectly amazing But only in retrospect does it look chunky and bulky and obviously there was so much room for improvement.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so you have to do is you have to look around at things that seem To you currently as normal and you know great But actually they're chunky chunky boys in 2020 and they can be shrunk down.
Speaker 0: So the chunky chunky boys that I see right now CRT is for me Unless CRT is monitors like LCDs because CRT is couldn't really shrink beyond a certain point but LCDs wouldn't like.
Speaker 0: they were pretty thick at the beginning of this decade and Now like even a pretty cheap LCD is crazy thin.
Speaker 1: I'm talking about things that are chunky in 2020 Right.
Speaker 1: Can you see something now that looks normal now, but is actually in 2030?
Speaker 1: You're gonna look at it and say right.
Speaker 1: So the things I see are the phones that fold.
Speaker 1: Yep, right full screens that bend screens that bend.
Speaker 1: they're gonna make the screens because now they're selling them.
Speaker 1: They're selling them in the store right now.
Speaker 1: So in ten years You're gonna have the screen that bends.
Speaker 1: I think is gonna be the real like super thin like in your bag Like the tablet is just gonna be like floppy like flop a flop a flop.
Speaker 1: Ah, right It's not gonna be like a rigid rectangle.
Speaker 1: You can roll it up.
Speaker 1: You can whack your fly with it, right?
Speaker 1: It'll be fine something like that.
Speaker 1: the other thing I see this really chunky Again in the battery department, you'll look at like e-bikes, right, you know The lithium-ion battery applied to so much transportation not just cars bikes scooters all those things You know.
Speaker 1: drones all 2010s, right?
Speaker 1: the e-bike is of 2020. a 2030 is gonna look like Not an e-bike.
Speaker 0: I think By not be chunky right now the e-bike.
Speaker 1: It's like it's chunky things stuck on your down tube, right?
Speaker 1: No, it's just not.
Speaker 1: you're not good.
Speaker 1: It's not gonna be there.
Speaker 1: It's gonna look like a bike.
Speaker 1: I Think I'm gonna know it's an evil.
Speaker 0: even broader I think e-bikes over the next decade are going to become an ubiquitous and critical part of transportation Infrastructure in cities and sub.
Speaker 0: hopefully.
Speaker 1: well, that depends on policy not on tech.
Speaker 1: Well, the Biden Is there for that?
Speaker 0: Yeah, the cabinet pick for transportation seems down for this.
Speaker 0: so we'll see.
Speaker 1: well You know, he's half there, right?
Speaker 1: You know, he's a compromise, dude but yeah, there's Those are the only chunky boys that I can see in my immediate eyeball that come to mind.
Speaker 0: yeah, I this over the course of this decade because we've gone on way long so we can probably wrap this up soon, but My relationship with technology.
Speaker 0: I used to have to carry a lot of devices and I used to have to like think about how will I do X in location Y?
Speaker 0: and I used to have to still plan a little bit for certain kind.
Speaker 1: We went to mag fest carrying a big tub of stuff.
Speaker 0: Yep I don't be carried less and less and less.
Speaker 0: I don't carry like anything with me anywhere anymore And I always have access with our.
Speaker 1: we can pay with your phone.
Speaker 1: now for real Yeah, just pretend like like oh that'll never happen.
Speaker 1: Nope.
Speaker 1: You I do it at the grocery store.
Speaker 1: Yep every friggin time.
Speaker 0: So, you know, so hopefully we don't descend into an even deeper cyberpunk dystopia But I don't know if we can avoid it in the near term.
Speaker 1: So I guess we're not gonna talk about just 2020 or just this year.
Speaker 0: Oh, we've already gone on for almost like an hour and a half here.
Speaker 1: All right, that's all right.
Speaker 1: Then the rest of the episodes will be decade only.
Speaker 1: no decade.
Speaker 1: Oh, right.
Speaker 1: We didn't do any other year, right?
Speaker 1: So decade only and I guess we missed our first opportunity in 2010.
Speaker 1: We'll do it again in 2030.
Speaker 0: All right, so Wednesday, we'll see.
Speaker 0: we'll talk about animation and anime and comics for the last decade.
Speaker 0: Yeah This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Speaker 1: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 0: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays and make comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 1: But unlike those other late shows it's actually recorded at night.
Speaker 0: and the patreon patrons for this episode of geek nights Our Al enjoys hiding.
Speaker 0: McNichol and Marty greenia link eg a fresh dot net slash tilde rim slash podcast - beta.
Speaker 0: Graham Finch you hold the key to my heart.
Speaker 0: Now go through the last year or so a podcast and make rim saying Clinton Walton run from New Zealand.
Speaker 0: Ryan Perrin Review mad bull 34 cowards dread lily tenebrae just like a dude guy.
Speaker 0: Chris Reimer Finn Shervin van are all and a whole bunch of people who do not want me to say their names.
Speaker 0: Don't travel anywhere for the holidays.
Speaker 0: And now I leave you with a blast from the multimedia pass.
Speaker 1: It turns me She's got the shiniest skin So long you are my octopus of love to please.