Speaker 1: It's Wednesday December 23rd 2020.
Speaker 1: I'm rim.
Speaker 1: I'm Scott and this is geek nights.
Speaker 1: tonight We're talking about the last decade in animation and comics 2010 to 2020.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: So, uh, I figured cuz I'm stuck inside I wanted to put up some fairy lights some Christmas lights to out of the balcony.
Speaker 1: Normally, I don't even bother with that kind of thing.
Speaker 1: Like there's enough Christmas going on around me, but I'm stuck inside.
Speaker 0: We had a can even see your lights here in the back and facing nothing.
Speaker 1: What a million people see it.
Speaker 1: There's a giant muse.
Speaker 1: There's like four or five hundred apartments that all have balconies face.
Speaker 0: You're just showing it to the other building and I showing it to like the street.
Speaker 1: No, no, I'm showing it to all the other people who have apartments in this whole complex.
Speaker 1: Yeah to myself.
Speaker 0: No, no one on the street can see it.
Speaker 0: only people in this like.
Speaker 1: I didn't want an apartment facing the street.
Speaker 1: There's cars honking out there.
Speaker 0: I'm just saying like you're showing it to a very small number of people like Several hundred apartments full of people plus for it's for me.
Speaker 1: It's for me and Emily to look at like I see the lights when I wake up in the morning And they're out there.
Speaker 0: you should hang them on the.
Speaker 0: if you wanted there for you.
Speaker 0: You should hang them on the other building But you could see them.
Speaker 0: it would be better to see ones on someone else's Apartment.
Speaker 1: only one other apartment has put up lights in the whole complex.
Speaker 0: Yeah, because it's silly to put them up on the inside part.
Speaker 1: It's the why that's worse.
Speaker 1: There's more people would see him there.
Speaker 0: It's like if you had a house in a suburb and you only put your Christmas lights in the backyard.
Speaker 0: Them Neighbor in the back could see them now because where is that privacy fences?
Speaker 0: They could see them over the fence like this.
Speaker 1: I'm saying it's not like that at all because there's a huge number of apartments that all see them.
Speaker 1: Like many people have apartments facing inward not outward in this neighborhood.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so I went.
Speaker 1: I got some.
Speaker 1: we had some ancient ancient like regular Christmas lights like the.
Speaker 1: you know The green string with the simple plug and that one particular light bulb and I got him out looking and Half of the strand didn't light because you know They're old.
Speaker 0: and that's the thing that can happen due to the way Christmas lights are really shitty and they weren't using you know The modern ones.
Speaker 0: I think of LEDs.
Speaker 0: so that doesn't happen.
Speaker 1: Yeah, people still apparently mostly buy non LED ones because LED works a lot cheaper.
Speaker 1: well LED ones are expensive or LED ones are dangerous.
Speaker 1: bootleg nonsense.
Speaker 1: What most LEDs Christmas lights you can buy are?
Speaker 1: The kind of thing that would be featured on big Clive for catching fire.
Speaker 1: Good lord Are they dodgy like probably illegally imported shit?
Speaker 0: It's not that hard to make one.
Speaker 0: It's yes it is.
Speaker 0: How hard could it be?
Speaker 0: I made it I made an LED menorah, it's just fine.
Speaker 1: So here's the main reason why these are a problem one.
Speaker 1: They have to keep.
Speaker 1: they have to do voltage conversion.
Speaker 1: You can't just run it.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you've got to put resistors on there.
Speaker 1: So, you know, it's not not resistors Don't convert voltage Scott.
Speaker 0: Oh, you need to turn it to DC first and they got it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you got all.
Speaker 1: you need logic in there.
Speaker 1: You need a bunch of stuff.
Speaker 0: There's any logic?
Speaker 0: you just you just need a. you know, you can take DC you can actually use.
Speaker 0: if you powered it you know you could do.
Speaker 0: that would work really well.
Speaker 0: is At the end of the cable instead of having you know, a power cable.
Speaker 0: just have a USB.
Speaker 1: They've helped.
Speaker 1: those exist.
Speaker 1: people sell those.
Speaker 0: they're really nice Yeah, and then you could just then that's already done for you because like you can do if you've got you're putting Christmas lights indoors.
Speaker 1: That's like the perfect way to do it.
Speaker 0: Just get USB once you can use whatever USB power you want and then have a string of LEDs.
Speaker 1: Right, just don't plug that shit into like a computer USB port.
Speaker 0: Are you know you plug it into like you would take like your phone charger and plug it in with that, right?
Speaker 1: so basically the problem with LED lights is that most of them are like.
Speaker 1: UL has never seen these things before.
Speaker 1: These things are imported dodgily And even though they often say that they are waterproof the reality is most of those LED Christmas lights are not even close to waterproof.
Speaker 1: because well, the lights are all waterproof at the Cape.
Speaker 1: the cable that plugs into the wall will have some sort of transformer in it and then a box that has the circuitry to do things like change the colors and stuff.
Speaker 1: and Those things aren't waterproof at all like they're dodgy and not safe for outdoor usage.
Speaker 1: And if you want ones that actually do work nicely outdoors and are safe.
Speaker 1: They're like 40 bucks a strand.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah It's not you know, the like.
Speaker 0: I know people like to light their pools with LEDs, right and was like underneath the pool.
Speaker 0: They'll be like little domes with LEDs under them.
Speaker 0: It's like that shit ain't cheap at pools expensive enough already.
Speaker 1: So basically I did.
Speaker 1: I got one.
Speaker 1: I got the smallest strand of lights I could to put up out there and They could.
Speaker 1: they were expensive because I got ones that are actually waterproof Actually designed for outdoors had a UL logo on them that didn't look like it was bootlegged.
Speaker 1: Yeah And they'll probably last the rest of my life.
Speaker 1: They're using like no power.
Speaker 1: It's actually kind of amazing how little power they use compared to even half a strand of traditional lights.
Speaker 0: Yeah, oh yeah, cuz they're LEDs right exactly.
Speaker 1: they're also wicked bright and have way more colors.
Speaker 1: cuz they're just aren't you can.
Speaker 1: I can Light individually to do whatever color I want it to be.
Speaker 0: I said my LED menorah.
Speaker 0: I can do any color I want and any light with any kind of pattern they could change while it's on.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you can have it cycle and rotate and do all kinds of stuff.
Speaker 0: So it's that those actually really good.
Speaker 0: I think that must be what the people who are doing those like fancy displays outside are using the ones that like.
Speaker 1: Yes, the tricky part is you often can't get those in very long strands and they very rarely can daisy-chain like traditional lights.
Speaker 1: So a lot of the fancy ones outside are still traditional Regular old light bulbs like incandescents because they're just at that scale.
Speaker 1: that's easier.
Speaker 1: The consequence is they use way more power.
Speaker 0: Well, I mean, you know you see like people make like, you know LED video walls, right?
Speaker 0: Screen I've made out of a bazillion LEDs and a grid but you're just.
Speaker 0: it's so big and you're so far away that it looks Really great.
Speaker 0: Yeah So you can use.
Speaker 0: you can set up something like that and just imagine that same sort of video Tron setup, right?
Speaker 0: Except instead of you know being in a rectangle you just split up the LEDs all over the place In front of a house right down the street on the side of the driveway up In Santa's ass wherever you got to put them, you know.
Speaker 1: So yeah, that's literally all that's going in my life and I don't have work this week.
Speaker 0: So I'm like wearing pajamas right now work of this a week or a next week.
Speaker 1: I got to work next week.
Speaker 1: I got a lot to do next week.
Speaker 0: actually Just you know waking up do whenever I feel like doing.
Speaker 0: I feel like after the show I'm gonna have someone deliver some food for me to eat and Maybe I'll bike to nowhere.
Speaker 0: I biked this morning do whatever I feel like doing.
Speaker 1: play some video games.
Speaker 1: Mmm talk about some of the video games.
Speaker 1: I'm playing.
Speaker 0: maybe next week I'm playing some games also.
Speaker 1: I guess we'll get into it.
Speaker 1: So just like on Monday, we're doing the show on like the decade of anime and animation everything, but there is some news.
Speaker 1: There's actually some extremely important news.
Speaker 1: I'll link to this verge article that goes to into it in detail.
Speaker 1: Sony who if you don't recall owns Funimation Has bought crunchyroll for 1.2 billion dollars from if you didn't know who owned crunchyroll AT&T.
Speaker 0: yeah, so You know we've talked before about antitrust and stuff and how unifying and merging and stuff is not great for you know Assuming you're already on board with capitalism or whatever right now.
Speaker 0: It's not good for a host of reasons That we but it struggle it always fight.
Speaker 1: There's this competing like this duality of interest in that on one hand We need to break up monopolies to make sure there's competition and a free market and to make sure that no company gets too powerful And starts to have undue influence, but on the other hand as a consumer I only want to go to one web page to do a particular kind of thing.
Speaker 0: yep That's a constant struggle is?
Speaker 0: I only want to go to see Some things.
Speaker 1: I never even work with epic store because I didn't want to have two things on my desk.
Speaker 1: right.
Speaker 0: there are some things in the world that benefit from Unification of there being only one thing and there are some things that benefit from having Choices.
Speaker 0: in this case society loses but user experience wins and it's hard to get the best of both worlds unless you For you have.
Speaker 0: the capitalism will never give you the best of both worlds.
Speaker 0: the only way to get the best of both worlds is To force it either by saying Here's an open standard that everyone must follow.
Speaker 0: period so like say for instant messaging.
Speaker 0: right you could be like.
Speaker 0: everyone must use this Xmpp even though Xmpp is not great just using this example and then choose whatever Thing you want.
Speaker 0: so in web browsers right it's like okay, you know choose whatever web browser you want.
Speaker 0: Here's how HTTP works yep, but then the other thing.
Speaker 1: messaging used to be that way, but it's all proprietary again.
Speaker 0: Yep, the other thing you can do is you can say okay?
Speaker 0: There's only one thing, but it has to follow all these rules.
Speaker 0: right.
Speaker 0: there's one telephone system.
Speaker 0: It must work this way You know you can't.
Speaker 0: you have to provide service to everyone.
Speaker 0: right here's how the numbers work.
Speaker 0: No deviating right it's not her etc.
Speaker 0: So you know that's how it goes.
Speaker 0: so but that his thing with the anime situation.
Speaker 0: It's like okay You don't want to have to get 10 subscriptions to be able to legally watch all the anime.
Speaker 0: because I've.
Speaker 1: but the weird thing is My like crunchyroll because it has a lot of the stuff that people don't talk about that.
Speaker 0: I want to watch Yes, but like how many times have we done a geek nights episode on some tiny show?
Speaker 0: that's got like short episodes?
Speaker 0: Or is a really weird thing like yummy Yeah clothes Key clothes any of these kind of things?
Speaker 0: It's like the Netflix ain't doing those right.
Speaker 0: funimation ain't doing those as to my knowledge right crunchyroll was like specializing in.
Speaker 0: so you know Bananya.
Speaker 0: right.
Speaker 0: it's like without crunchyroll you would not have no bananya right in the u.s.. It's so tiny.
Speaker 1: But at the same time every time I wanted to watch a bigger anime It was either on Netflix which I paid for or funimation, which I didn't pay for
Speaker 0: Right as those other services are just into those big shows that you can get a lot of people to watch.
Speaker 0: crunchyroll As a service would go sort of that extra mile To get this long tail of the smaller anime the animes that otaku's knew about some of them quite popular right And get them subtitled fast right sometimes same day as the you know simulcast or whatever.
Speaker 0: if you cared about that which I never did right at a. And it's it's you know pretty good.
Speaker 0: remember a crunchyroll started as just piracy.
Speaker 0: Yeah, people forget that crunchyroll just started as a website that was blatantly pirating everything it was.
Speaker 1: It wasn't too far before.
Speaker 1: the start of this decade was when crunchyroll made that shift to be legit.
Speaker 0: Yep, exactly.
Speaker 0: and then they sold right.
Speaker 0: and look at these other all the manga piracy pirating websites.
Speaker 0: They weren't able to make that crunchyroll transition to legitimacy.
Speaker 0: or did they even try?
Speaker 1: I don't think they tried.
Speaker 1: I also think that sadly despite one of the news's we're going to talk about don't think there's enough money in that in the American Market, I don't know if there is either or not, but that's but anyway.
Speaker 0: so Crunchyroll is bought.
Speaker 0: it is not yet unified But presumably this might be received is gonna be a mix of good and bad for the anime fan in the United States.
Speaker 1: on one Hand Sony now has near absolute power over the American anime industry In terms of legal anime watching in the US.
Speaker 0: you're gonna be having in your Netflix and your Sony.
Speaker 0: those are your two choices And I think we're gonna.
Speaker 1: what I suspect we'll see is Sony will Start to go after shows that are made by regular studios and Netflix will double down on funding their own anime to be made Via studios.
Speaker 1: that that's what's been.
Speaker 0: that's been happening.
Speaker 0: Yeah We might see.
Speaker 0: I think you're gonna see unification of Funimation and crunchyroll.
Speaker 0: So you're not gonna have to be like ah damn the show is not on the service I want.
Speaker 0: you're gonna subscribe to the one service and get all the shows.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right and that's gonna be I guess a positive.
Speaker 0: who knows what the price will be though, right with their monopoly power They might be able to jack up the price on us.
Speaker 1: I think I was watching some anime.
Speaker 1: that's Funimation.
Speaker 1: that was also on Hulu.
Speaker 1: cuz we had a free trial of Hulu.
Speaker 1: But yeah, I think now there's no reason to watch Hulu at all for anything.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: Well, they're not unified yet crunch your own Funimation is still separate.
Speaker 0: Yeah But yeah, you're also gonna be seeing I guess bad news.
Speaker 0: one company deciding right which things to bring over And you know translate and stream pretty much.
Speaker 1: So they're gonna be at that.
Speaker 1: so far in the ecosystem pretty much everything gets brought over, right?
Speaker 0: But well, they will.
Speaker 0: they start making different choices because there's no one else.
Speaker 0: It's not like they don't have to say Oh, no, if we don't bring this over someone else will and and steal our customers.
Speaker 0: They'd like our customers have to go with us.
Speaker 0: We have all the anime no one else has.
Speaker 0: we can just bring over just enough anime to keep them Subscribed and we don't need to bring over your you know, or do a bunch of hard work to try to.
Speaker 1: now Here's are the.
Speaker 0: you see the magic of a bananya and try to spread it, right?
Speaker 0: They can just be like, yeah We'll get your borutos and we're good.
Speaker 1: If we look at just animation as a global industry instead of focusing just on anime It gets a little more interesting because part of the reason AT&T Was willing to sell crunchyroll was that they're going the Netflix route and partnering with HBO max
Speaker 0: Mmm
Speaker 1: Which as you know is getting all of the pristine.
Speaker 1: a lot of the prestige animation Likely venture brothers the adventure time stuff like HBO max has got a lot going on as we've talked about in previous geek nights.
Speaker 1: I think the players in this space now are gonna be Sony HBO and Netflix and those will be the three.
Speaker 1: that's where animation is.
Speaker 0: apples trying a little bit.
Speaker 1: Apple's barely got the wolf walkers exclusive.
Speaker 1: it look even Apple people were complaining about the exclusive on Apple TV.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well, I mean now that the thing is Apple's big thing.
Speaker 0: historically Animation wise movie wise has been their ties with Disney Pixar But this is their own thing.
Speaker 0: now that Disney has their own thing Apple has lost that and I think that's gonna.
Speaker 0: that pretty much Really hurts Apple videos prospects.
Speaker 1: I wouldn't be super shocked if Apple over time gets out of this business and just Basically tries to take a vague from give up.
Speaker 0: easily.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but business wise the better way to go would be to provide first-class experiences for all these other services.
Speaker 0: I do all those services have first-class like a plus Apple TV apps and they they when they're on you go to watch an Apple Keynote, they're like we got Disney Plus app.
Speaker 0: How great is that?
Speaker 1: You know, yeah, but Apple I wonder I don't know how widespread Apple TVs usage actually is.
Speaker 0: Well a bunch of people getting free trials when they get iPhones.
Speaker 0: I didn't activate mine.
Speaker 1: Yeah But I'd love to see the stats on how many people get a free trial and don't bother.
Speaker 0: Yeah, speaking of I was told by Tom Moore on Twitter director of wolf walkers that you would be able to Buy wolf walkers on iTunes like buying a movie, but apparently I looked on iTunes and it's not there.
Speaker 0: I think it really is Apple TV plus exclusive.
Speaker 0: You have to have a free or non free subscription to Apple TV plus to watch it legally in the US.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's a shame.
Speaker 0: So, yeah, I think another you know.
Speaker 0: one last thing though is in terms of going over to Japan to try to license anime.
Speaker 0: right When I think you're actually see one of the more positive sides of monopoly power is We.
Speaker 0: when it's wielded against the consumer it's bad.
Speaker 0: But when it's wielded against another company, it can sometimes be good or bad right depending on for the consumer But it's almost never good for the workers in those companies right depending on whose side you're on right?
Speaker 0: So like when Amazon right?
Speaker 0: I remember here's a better example Walmart.
Speaker 0: I remember this dude.
Speaker 0: He taught he was a. he was a lawnmower company.
Speaker 0: He made lawnmowers and he made really good lawnmowers like high-quality ones Right.
Speaker 0: and Walmart wanted to buy his lawnmowers and put him on the shelf and they said hey We want you to make we don't want to buy the lawnmowers you have.
Speaker 0: those are too expensive and fancy for Walmart customers.
Speaker 0: We want you to make a shitty low-quality lawnmower that's cheaper.
Speaker 0: that has your brand on it, right?
Speaker 0: It's a special model just for Walmart.
Speaker 0: and it's like if he says yes He becomes mega rich because suddenly Walmart right signs a check to buy all those lawnmowers from him, right?
Speaker 0: And if he says no, it's like, you know, he has his principles and he can go home, right?
Speaker 0: And but that's a lot of power Walmart has as being such a big company, right?
Speaker 0: So in the same way that you know that power can be used for good.
Speaker 0: That's why single-payer health care is a great idea because you can go to all the pharmaceutical companies and saying this is what we're gonna Pay for that drug deal with it.
Speaker 1: now.
Speaker 0: a better way to get would know Those pharmaceutical companies.
Speaker 0: but obviously but in this case you'll have you'll have funimation crunchyroll Sony Going to Japan or I guess they are Japan.
Speaker 0: They're Sony.
Speaker 0: They're in Japan But going to the anime studios of Japan and saying you want your anime to be on computers streaming in the US legally, huh?
Speaker 0: This is what we're gonna pay.
Speaker 0: the end right as opposed to negotiating, right?
Speaker 0: They'll just set the price because it's them or yep the highway right nothing.
Speaker 1: The thing is.
Speaker 1: what's interesting is this means that the way I like the streaming servers are to use assuming crunchyroll and funimation Like merge their stuff completely.
Speaker 1: I'll basically have an account on all three places that I would ever want to watch animation.
Speaker 1: So I'll be covered as a consumer.
Speaker 0: We'll see.
Speaker 0: So this isn't necessarily a news is something that's holy's.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's a tweet.
Speaker 0: It's something that's always true or it's been true for quite a while.
Speaker 0: We can almost put this into the main bit area.
Speaker 1: We've talked about this many times, right?
Speaker 0: But this you know.
Speaker 0: But you know I actually tried to when I was trying to find the tweet that as somebody retweeted this week I actually found many tweets about this because like people trying to drive this point home because it's not in the consciousness of People who think about comic books and graphic novels in the US even though it's so true, right?
Speaker 0: and it's like when you think about comic books graphic novels in the US you think about You know, what's?
Speaker 0: the general consciousness is like Marvel and DC the big two right with their superheroes.
Speaker 0: stuff right is being the top Right, even if you look at Eisner Awards, which do have plenty of non superhero things.
Speaker 0: There's plenty of superhero things in the Eisner Awards even even now, right?
Speaker 0: It's like San Diego comic-con you go there Superheroes all over the place, right and it's like.
Speaker 0: that's the thing people think of.
Speaker 0: and then under that you think of like.
Speaker 0: You know, you got your mangas and you got your indie books, you know your image your IDW your whoever's right your dark horses.
Speaker 0: And then under that, you know, you got just other graphic novels artsy people mocha type stuff, right?
Speaker 0: But the fact is if you actually look at numbers, right?
Speaker 0: It's this tweet says the big two aren't Marvel and DC they're Dave Pilkey and Raina Tegelmeier, right?
Speaker 0: So Scholastic is the biggest Comic book company and yeah, but nerds won't talk about that.
Speaker 1: I mean, they're already.
Speaker 1: they won't talk about manga.
Speaker 1: They're definitely not gonna talk about that.
Speaker 0: Do you know how much like captain underpants?
Speaker 0: Do you know how much that sells.
Speaker 0: the amount it sells is so ludicrous, right?
Speaker 0: It's like there are more kids reading that shit than have ever read like any spider-man ever.
Speaker 1: Next tweet in that thing.
Speaker 1: It's so.
Speaker 1: so on point.
Speaker 1: Jeff.
Speaker 1: Kitty has sold 200 million books since 2007.
Speaker 1: That's more than all Avengers comics have sold since their launch in.
Speaker 0: Yeah Anyway, and he says anyway some nerd told me I don't know much about me.
Speaker 0: comics Right, is that the?
Speaker 0: even when they were like big right say like, you know Like Golden Age comics and Superman was a big deal, right?
Speaker 0: It's like, you know Superhero comic books even when they were great and and huge and everyone was buying them.
Speaker 0: I've never been as big.
Speaker 1: They were dwarfs by a scholastic book by some random manga worked by Disney ducks, right?
Speaker 0: You want to talk about sales, right?
Speaker 0: Let's talk about one piece, right?
Speaker 0: H-year Oda has sold more one piece worldwide.
Speaker 0: Is that I don't know.
Speaker 0: Is it the best-selling book period in the history of baby other than the curse?
Speaker 0: I don't even know if it's.
Speaker 0: yeah It's like.
Speaker 0: I guess it's not Bible level, right?
Speaker 0: But it's like if you take all the one piece volumes combined You are getting pretty high on that list of like best-selling as of September 2019.
Speaker 1: So a little over a year ago one piece Has sold 454 million copies globally according to the statistic I found online, right?
Speaker 0: So Jeff Kinney has sold 200 million books since o7.
Speaker 0: h-year Oda has sold for two Jeff Kinney's.
Speaker 0: So Jeff Kinney's already bigger than every Avengers comic ever.
Speaker 0: all the issues Right.
Speaker 1: and h-year Oda is like to Jeff Kinney's Kenny is a little bit above blackjack But a little bit below detective Conan, right?
Speaker 0: It's like Right, so when you got I think you know, the comics media is such an un.
Speaker 0: you know There's not a lot of money in in talking about comics.
Speaker 0: even these, you know small low-budget Journalistic outfits that have tried to talk about, you know get into comics journalism, you know They either have to go full superhero and talk about superhero movies and all that other stuff Right.
Speaker 0: the same way a comic book store has to sell a whole bunch of other stuff Right, the comic book news has to talk about a bunch of other stuff.
Speaker 0: Or like the tiny indie ones and the comics journal It's like those things actually they.
Speaker 0: they said yeah We're gonna be a low-budget high-brow kind of thing and you know They try to keep it going and they worth it.
Speaker 0: Not a lot of them able to keep it going.
Speaker 0: all the comics journalism these days is fan journalism, which is has the wrong perspective.
Speaker 0: Superhero comic books making a podcast and not kids talking about captain underpants Let's.
Speaker 1: it's more interesting that I think cuz it's fans who Often have a grudge against all the things that are more popular than their thing and try to rationalize how their thing is actually bigger.
Speaker 1: I think some of it is not unconscious bias, but conscious active bias.
Speaker 0: hmm, maybe or you know, it's just You know the the.
Speaker 1: I think another part of it is the American comic.
Speaker 1: like superhero comic industry does a good job of controlling What limited amount of their media gets talked about in mainstream news?
Speaker 0: Controlling their movies are a big thing, right?
Speaker 0: So the intellectual property of spider-man is enormous.
Speaker 0: Yeah, much more than cats underpants hasn't had a movie Although I don't know why he hasn't.
Speaker 0: cuz how much money would that thing fucking make?
Speaker 0: Jesus Christ, you'd have like everyone under the age of 10 in the whole country going to that.
Speaker 0: But it's like just the Percy how big a thing is Compared to how big it is perceived to be.
Speaker 1: there was a captain underpants movie in 2017 shows what I fucking know.
Speaker 0: Was it in theaters, uh, yeah budget 38 million box-office 125 million That's that's lower than I expected.
Speaker 0: Why I still made a lot a bunch of money.
Speaker 0: I'll take hundred something million, right?
Speaker 0: Why not?
Speaker 0: but it's like the the perception of how big things are right is based on the Media journalism.
Speaker 0: how much people talk about it how much people tweet about it, right?
Speaker 1: There's also a Netflix show.
Speaker 0: Okay, how big things actually are is?
Speaker 0: Unrelated to that right there are things that are relatively not that popular that get talked about a lot Right.
Speaker 0: the people who run the big media companies the people who run television talk about things that are on television because that's where they make their money right.
Speaker 0: so that you know If you're CBS and you have golf on the news is gonna talk about golf, right?
Speaker 0: But guess what?
Speaker 0: If League of Legends is bigger than golf.
Speaker 0: You're not gonna feel like it's bigger than golf.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like what was that thing?
Speaker 1: more people watch the overwatch championships than watch the Super Bowl, but no one's talking about that
Speaker 0: right exactly, so There's this mismatch and you have to be constantly aware of it because even if you block all ads everywhere always Right that consciousness of just the general you know media right will cause a mismatch in your brain of how big is a thing really?
Speaker 0: or is that Actually a not as big thing?
Speaker 0: that's just talked about a lot.
Speaker 1: You know where we see this a lot right now And I think there's a lot like.
Speaker 1: a lot of toxic consequences happen as a result.
Speaker 1: is the cosplay at conventions and the cosplay and nerdery Non like nerd inside baseball.
Speaker 1: coverage of fan conventions of all kinds Focuses almost entirely on the cosplay that's true Which you can understand why like some reporter doesn't know sent like go cover.
Speaker 1: this Convention sees a bunch of people in crazy costumes gets a whole bunch of b-roll at that and they're good They pack up and leave but not go to like the basement panel room to sit through something for an hour.
Speaker 0: Well, but also cosplay is kind of big right?
Speaker 0: It is.
Speaker 1: it's big to a point play that your panel It's not like the focus of these cons that a lot of people think it is.
Speaker 1: A lot of people have a perception that it is the primary focus of almost all these cons.
Speaker 0: and you see a lot of people You've made a chart I've made a pie chart of like primary thing.
Speaker 0: you are here at this con for cosplay would be the biggest wedge But it would not be a wedge that is greater than 50%.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but what I think I've seen happen is that is at comic cons that sort of becomes a self-fulfilling prophecy, which fine.
Speaker 1: But then there's other cons that don't support cosplay and cosplay people tend to have an outsized impression of how big they're like industry and like the space around them is and then they seem to Get mad and cause drama when they're at conventions that don't support them the way they expect to be supported.
Speaker 1: There's a whole thing going on there but anyway things Of the day.
Speaker 1: What do you got?
Speaker 0: What do I have?
Speaker 0: so, you know the old toy?
Speaker 0: Right the chattering teeth.
Speaker 0: you wind it up and it's just a set of teeth and they start chattering like.
Speaker 1: I think I saw that for the first time in Pee Wee's great big adventure.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's used.
Speaker 0: You know a lot you see it's like, you know cartoons.
Speaker 0: I never had one but it was like a common slapstick comedy device, right?
Speaker 0: You know, you would see.
Speaker 0: it's a kind of thing you would see next to a mad magazine, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, or you know like right in the same collection of like a whoopee cushion.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah No, yeah, right.
Speaker 0: so the that was invented by a person specifically Obviously, right a person named.
Speaker 0: What's this dude's name?
Speaker 0: It's not in the title of the YouTube video.
Speaker 0: Goldfarb Eddie Goldfarb, probably an old Jewish guy.
Speaker 0: So yet I did not know until today.
Speaker 0: today I learned Eddie Goldfarb.
Speaker 0: it lives.
Speaker 0: He's like invented kerplunk.
Speaker 0: Eddie Goldfarb is 98.
Speaker 0: Not only did he invent the chattering teeth and kerplunk.
Speaker 0: He invented like the gun that shoots bubbles He invented a shark attack the board game like the amount of stuff that Eddie Goldfarb has invented toy wise is like.
Speaker 0: why is this this person like, you know?
Speaker 0: I don't think it's an exaggeration to say Like is probably unlike the great artist level like Picasso van Gogh level of Contributions to art.
Speaker 1: if you consider a toy art, which I think is obvious I mean think those kinds of toys like blended into the background of like Americana and the fabric of comedy.
Speaker 0: right, so it's like.
Speaker 0: This amazing person has been unknown until today.
Speaker 0: There's a video about this person.
Speaker 0: He's living in a retirement place in somewhere Looks like a nice one.
Speaker 0: Yeah, he's got like a whole house.
Speaker 0: You can walk.
Speaker 0: He's 98 And he's not as well as he is when I'm 98.
Speaker 1: I'll consider that a win.
Speaker 0: Yeah in the video they show it's like a little mini documentary about him.
Speaker 0: It shows like what his life is like hanging out with the old people being active.
Speaker 0: He's still got a workshop.
Speaker 0: He's still making toys in there, right?
Speaker 0: He's got a little lathe.
Speaker 0: He's got all kinds of action going on.
Speaker 0: He knows and not only that this is a cool old man, right despite being 98. right Despite being a veteran of World War two.
Speaker 0: who's doing radar on a Navy submarine, right?
Speaker 0: Pretty sure.
Speaker 0: World War one didn't have the submarine.
Speaker 1: World War one did have the submarine.
Speaker 0: He's not a World War one veteran because there are yes, but World War one had the submarine didn't have this kind of summary.
Speaker 1: Anyway, you would be surprised how advanced the submarines of World War one were.
Speaker 0: I guess I would be.
Speaker 0: the point is Despite being 98 in the video.
Speaker 0: They show this dude.
Speaker 0: He knows he's googling for other toys to see if someone's patented it already.
Speaker 0: He's you know talking to Siri.
Speaker 0: right to do is to get the weather Right.
Speaker 0: He's using a 3d printer to make shit in his workshop as like this is a dude who kept up with the time.
Speaker 1: Right, that's one of the most important things you can do in your life is just keep up with the times, right?
Speaker 0: This is not someone who's like and you know still do I'm cranky and doing it the old-fashioned way.
Speaker 0: I think about another video I saw recently of the the guy who's still making phyllo dough the old-fashioned way.
Speaker 0: and it's like a tourist attraction Almost because it's not economical to make phyllo dough the old-fashioned way.
Speaker 0: It's really slow and laborious And but it's like that kind of life that the very old You know craftsman leads right.
Speaker 0: and it's like, you know, that's kind of what I want to be when I'm an old man.
Speaker 0: I want to be the old Craftsman type old man, right?
Speaker 1: But I hope I'm still recording some thing like geek nights when I'm 90, yeah, we'll see what happens.
Speaker 0: But I think you know, I saw the old phyllo man and I was thinking that's who I want to be old phyllo man.
Speaker 0: But now that I see old chattering teeth toy man.
Speaker 0: I'm like, you know what while old phyllo man is amazing, right?
Speaker 0: There's actually you know, I think there's something to be said here for old You know toy man being I guess better in that he's managed to maintain The essence and importance of the craftsmanship but not out himself to traditions and tools.
Speaker 0: Right without being stubborn about the tool, right?
Speaker 0: It's like, you know, it's.
Speaker 0: it's like you can still take great, you know.
Speaker 0: Be some great photographer using a brand new digital camera and some Photoshop.
Speaker 0: You don't just got to use film in the and the the darkroom forever.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right, but you can you know.
Speaker 0: I think what's important is that with whichever method or tools you're using that you're the old person who's still you know Making stuff right whatever whether it's phyllo dough or photos or toys right and keep keeping it going, right?
Speaker 0: So yeah, great little 20-minute documentary here highly recommend.
Speaker 1: All right, so I got a simple thing.
Speaker 1: it's a technology conventions video or connections video, but I haven't linked to this guy in a while, but He cuts a hole in the side of a dishwasher because he's replacing it.
Speaker 1: So he does some video of like what goes on into dishwasher and explain.
Speaker 0: So he puts like a piece of plastic over the side with a camera next to it.
Speaker 0: Basically.
Speaker 0: Yeah Before yeah.
Speaker 1: So the dishwasher with a light that you and I are often mad about in a very good way.
Speaker 1: for everyone who doesn't realize this All he basically talks about why all the people who wash their dishes before they put their dishes in the dishwasher Just like fundamentally misunderstand how dishwashers work.
Speaker 0: Well modern dishwashers.
Speaker 1: Yes, old dishwashers were fine, too.
Speaker 1: You've never had to rinse off your dishes before you put them in a dishwasher.
Speaker 0: I mean I never have.
Speaker 0: but I was all under the impression that the reason that people did was because old dishwashers were shitty And so they needed.
Speaker 1: so old dishwashers were even better at this than modern dishwashers.
Speaker 1: They just were more wasteful.
Speaker 0: Okay, cuz I was only the impression that people were rinsing dishes because old dishwashers didn't get them all the way clean and new ones Did.
Speaker 0: but is that?
Speaker 0: I guess that's wrong?
Speaker 0: Maybe it's not old dishwashers, but people had shitty dishwasher.
Speaker 1: Yep, or more importantly people.
Speaker 1: The current problem people are having is that they're using those pods instead of regular old dishwasher formula, which is fine.
Speaker 1: It's like the same I use.
Speaker 0: I use one.
Speaker 0: It's not a pot.
Speaker 0: It's not like a plastic bag one.
Speaker 0: It's like a. it's like a cube almost like a little rectangle of solid powder.
Speaker 0: That's just been packed.
Speaker 0: Yeah It works pretty great.
Speaker 0: I don't have a problem.
Speaker 1: Yep, but basically if they if you use those But yet don't put any detergent in the pre-wash thing.
Speaker 0: That is usually the reason why dishwashers don't actually wash unless people because they're not using the the what's it called the blue stuff Not even the blue stuff.
Speaker 1: you put two of those pods in but one pod in the main thing and put one pod just In the Bob.
Speaker 1: just tuck it in.
Speaker 1: the way dishwashers worked before the pods is.
Speaker 1: you put a bunch of detergent in the cup that opens midway through and you put Some detergent in the cup that's already open.
Speaker 1: That's just right there in the first cycle.
Speaker 1: Oh Interesting, okay, you know dishwashers watch where it wash things.
Speaker 0: I did my.
Speaker 0: I don't know if my dishwasher has a.
Speaker 1: I am confident your dishwasher does support that like if you have a Bosch cuz.
Speaker 1: Some newer dishwashers have given up.
Speaker 1: They've realized that people just use those pods and they redesigned how they work.
Speaker 0: Yes, like my dishwasher.
Speaker 0: There's one thing it opens and there's two Compartments in there separated by like a little bridge.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's that's just I think to help you measure the amount of detergent.
Speaker 0: Right because they both of those open together.
Speaker 0: It's just one little.
Speaker 1: You know the real key is there are two doors.
Speaker 0: I have seen though some dishwashers that have two flaps that are separate for different things.
Speaker 1: Mine has one.
Speaker 0: I have only has one flap.
Speaker 0: it opens and that's it.
Speaker 1: But basically the the gist of it is and also the drain impeller on most American dishwashers is.
Speaker 1: Actually, remember how I said I weigh.
Speaker 1: when I was a kid grandma had a dishwasher just had a full-on garbage disposal in it.
Speaker 1: Okay, most modern dishwashers do have something like that in them There's little blades in the impeller at the bottom.
Speaker 1: that does.
Speaker 1: that runs the drain.
Speaker 0: I think mine might actually have that even though we're told in New York that we don't have.
Speaker 1: The ones in dishwashers are apparently legal in New York because they don't count as garbage disposals.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but if you have some brands they replace that with a stupid little filter.
Speaker 0: instead You got a clean like regular right exactly as I was looking for the filter in the dishwasher and I didn't find one.
Speaker 0: And it sometimes it does make a noise.
Speaker 0: that sounds that could be you know blade esque.
Speaker 0: so yep.
Speaker 1: But basically he points out even doesn't like.
Speaker 1: he does this whole thing.
Speaker 1: You can watch but you don't even have to like.
Speaker 1: Put like.
Speaker 1: maybe if there's like a pound of rice on the plate like get rid of that.
Speaker 1: But even if there's a chunk stuck to it if you actually put dishwasher detergent in for the pre-wash It'll wash that stuff off like completely fine.
Speaker 1: and most people who complain about the dishwasher were not working.
Speaker 1: Well, just don't understand how to use their own dishwasher.
Speaker 0: my dishwasher has been working very well.
Speaker 0: I've just been using the automatic mode on it not choosing any special modes.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna go read the manual for it and just double-check to make sure we're using it optimally.
Speaker 0: the other thing I did not know soon a great job though.
Speaker 1: So is that the pre-wash on most dishwashers?
Speaker 1: uses it assumes that the hot water because it's plugged into your hot water tap that the hot water will come in hot.
Speaker 1: and if your Apartment or house is the kind of place where it takes a while to get hot water Your dishwasher actually will work way shittier.
Speaker 1: It won't heat that water for the pre-wash cycle because it assumes it'll unless it's a really fancy dishwasher Or it'll assume that the water coming in is already hot.
Speaker 1: So if you run your tap until hot water comes out first your dishwasher that's not working So well will magically probably work a lot better.
Speaker 1: It's just a video that's like at the level.
Speaker 0: I guess that would only happen if like you woke up and turn the dishwasher on right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, pretty much.
Speaker 1: Otherwise, I get hot water pretty much instantly.
Speaker 1: It's unless I wake up and take a shower before like 6 a.m.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right.
Speaker 0: So then you're Yeah, anyway, anyway, let's get ready.
Speaker 1: We've been a moment.
Speaker 1: We ain't doing anything.
Speaker 1: We're stuck at home.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'm continuing to be home for the rest of the year and going back to work January 4th, so I'm continuing to work on Playing video games.
Speaker 1: mostly I'm off work this week.
Speaker 1: I see you're playing Hades.
Speaker 1: I gotta play that so we can talk about it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, play that we'll talk.
Speaker 0: Well, it's a good game.
Speaker 0: It's very.
Speaker 0: it's an action RPG.
Speaker 0: That's very slay.
Speaker 0: the spire esque.
Speaker 1: Think tonight I'm gonna finally play either tonight or this week.
Speaker 1: this week later the week I'm playing phasmophobia cuz everyone's saying real good things about it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, what is that Cora co-op like ghost fighting game?
Speaker 1: Okay, it's one of those games that is good in that it supports VR players and desktop players pretty well And in fact, some of the roles are better for desktop or better for VR.
Speaker 1: That's that's a hybrid model that I think will be very good for game designers to internalize Over the next five or six years.
Speaker 1: as not everyone has VR headsets Like making you get like Star Wars quadrants.
Speaker 1: the game that works well with VR But doesn't require VR is a sweet spot of design right now.
Speaker 0: I definitely think in general games that require Different you have.
Speaker 0: you have different roles for different players that require different skills.
Speaker 1: I want to see radically different interfaces Right.
Speaker 0: that require different interfaces different skills different equipment different things are very good because they are very inclusive, right?
Speaker 0: It's like you want to play something with your friend and you're really good at head-clicking So you want to play counter-strike and your friend is not good at head-clicking, right?
Speaker 1: That's a selection.
Speaker 1: They could they could be the commander instead.
Speaker 0: exactly.
Speaker 0: So just games where different roles are actually very very different and to the point where the people are almost playing different games.
Speaker 1: I'm a big fan of like radical asymmetry in games lately.
Speaker 1: Anyway, both tabletop and video.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah Give me that captain sonar action, right?
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, so submarines again Captain sonar World War one.
Speaker 1: you uh, you really didn't know.
Speaker 1: there were submarines in World War one That was like not good ones.
Speaker 1: That was odd.
Speaker 1: They were actually really good.
Speaker 1: That was kind of the entire German war strategy after the Schleifen plan failed.
Speaker 0: Isn't that pretty sure?
Speaker 0: you know does boot is World War two, right?
Speaker 1: Ah Right, I'm just not gonna touch that one.
Speaker 0: Let's get into the main thing.
Speaker 0: You don't?
Speaker 0: you don't know do you?
Speaker 1: now, I don't know Scott you boats were used in World War one.
Speaker 0: I'm looking it up now anyway.
Speaker 1: Anyway, we're talking about the last decade.
Speaker 1: It is World War two.
Speaker 0: I was right.
Speaker 1: You're right on that one.
Speaker 0: Okay, I was right about why were you boats in both?
Speaker 1: but the you boats that were used in World War one were Not way far off from modern diesel submarines in a lot of surprising ways.
Speaker 0: Well it the one they had in dazboo, which is World War two is real shitty.
Speaker 1: So I can't imagine Well, we hate that one was they were not pleasant to be in and they were dangerous.
Speaker 0: Alright, let's let's move on.
Speaker 1: So We figured you know end of the year.
Speaker 1: every year We're gonna do shows like this cuz it's really easy to come up with this idea But we're not.
Speaker 0: well wait ten more years before you do shows like this.
Speaker 1: Well, we can do the year like last year next year thing.
Speaker 0: No, let's do 2020s and 2030s the next time we can do this show.
Speaker 0: Sorry.
Speaker 1: No, okay Okay, then I'll ask you to come up with well I guess next year.
Speaker 1: We'll probably just take time off this time of year because there won't be a pandemic murdering everyone.
Speaker 1: That's the only reason we're doing all these extra shows right now.
Speaker 1: It's so weird to do a show when I didn't go to work.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we can only hope anyway, usually if one of us doesn't go to work, please don't bother doing so.
Speaker 0: What happened this decade 2010 to 2020 in animation comics, whatever?
Speaker 0: So what I seen is that at least as far as animation goes right, you know, there's it's sort of Like this, how did it go for me personally versus how did it go for the industry?
Speaker 0: kind of difference, right?
Speaker 0: and so For I think what happened is that if you look at when I looked back at my my data on my computer here All right, what was happening around 2009 2010?
Speaker 0: Right?
Speaker 0: is this sort of shift happened where a lot of things?
Speaker 0: ended started right sort of booted up and All those shifts that happened.
Speaker 0: then the rest of the decade you can see everything that happened.
Speaker 0: it was sort of those the the end result of that just either continuing or increasing or Accelerating.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there wasn't like.
Speaker 0: I didn't see a lot of major shifts afterwards between say 2010 2011 and 2020 like one thing that really stands out Adventure time which we've talked about a lot recently on geek nights because it's still going.
Speaker 1: technically Adventure time started in 2010.
Speaker 1: There you go the pilot was in 2007, but the actual show adventure time the premiered for real in April of 2010 and sort of set the tone for the decade of animation especially in America.
Speaker 1: How many shows only exist because adventure time like broke that ground for them to make a show like that.
Speaker 0: Yep, Cartoon Network like shifted its gears from what it had before then, you know Your Dexter's labs your Powerpuff Girls right and all that stuff right.
Speaker 0: Adventure Time was like, alright Alright, this is now how Cartoon Network do right.
Speaker 0: and then you got your Steven universes and all you're right.
Speaker 1: Like.
Speaker 1: there's a serial show that builds on itself that grows that deals with complex real even adult themes But yet it's still accessible to kids.
Speaker 1: Adventure time broke a lot of ground in terms of representation.
Speaker 1: It's even scary to think back on like that.
Speaker 1: that was even controversial in popular culture So recently like within this decade But it was.
Speaker 1: the networks wouldn't even let.
Speaker 1: Marceline and bubblegum kiss.
Speaker 1: and here we are in 2020 where there was a whole special dedicated to and then they kiss and Steven universe ran in entirety.
Speaker 0: I was always surprised that Powerpuff Girls let them have him even though him was not on very many episodes.
Speaker 1: Yeah, every Powerpuff Girls character by a lot him was definitely the best Powerpuff Girls character bar.
Speaker 1: No, no, I even made a mash-up of My Little Pony and Powerpuff Girls with him at one point.
Speaker 0: So that's another thing right.
Speaker 0: My Little Pony friendship is magic.
Speaker 0: another cereal, right?
Speaker 0: When did that show?
Speaker 0: fucking start right that and it ended.
Speaker 0: it's pretty much this decade.
Speaker 0: is the My Little Pony decade.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right that started then and it went through and it ended all within 2010 to 2020. there wasn't something that started in the late 2000s.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: So think Adventure Time and My Little Pony friendship is magic.
Speaker 1: That's that those are some power.
Speaker 0: Yep, that's pretty much like the defining American animations, right?
Speaker 0: So Anime wise right.
Speaker 0: you look and You know the 2000s we had like this big anime boom in the u.s.
Speaker 0: Right and all that kind of action.
Speaker 1: You know that that happened right when Oh crunchyroll went for like actually went legit at before the decade and sort of Exploded onto the scene like that was this decade.
Speaker 1: if we had to say anything about anime It was that anime truly got mainstream in the u.s.
Speaker 1: Like it.
Speaker 1: a lot of people watch anime who don't even think about it being anime.
Speaker 0: I think that was true before also, but now it's just you know more true.
Speaker 0: I guess I don't know.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it will the ecosystem stabilized in a big way.
Speaker 1: and we're seeing like just now at the end of the decade There's a radical shift in the industry yet again Hmm,
Speaker 0: but I think what I'm trying to say is that there were like a set of studios both Japan, you know I guess companies right meaty companies in that industry both Japan side and u.s.
Speaker 0: Side right and some of them still exist from you know way back right, but it's sort of the organization of those companies Sort of shifted around that time and then you know, there hasn't been too big of a shift since then, right?
Speaker 0: So like for example Sad times right Satoshi khan passed away in 2010.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so that sort of put a close on that biz.
Speaker 1: But then we saw Masaki Yuasa rose over the course of this decade Yuasa just bad in a thousand and producing way more anime than any human has a right to Write.
Speaker 0: pretty much, you know 2010s was the decade of us.
Speaker 0: It was also the decade of like studio trigger coming out of you know Nowhere right.
Speaker 1: anime was saved again and again and again and again.
Speaker 0: Yep, it was the decade of hosted a hosted.
Speaker 0: it existed, but summer wars came out in 2010, right?
Speaker 0: So hosted a put out, you know a movie every I don't know.
Speaker 0: What's his schedule?
Speaker 0: two three years?
Speaker 0: He's got another one coming soon.
Speaker 0: that we should have been news.
Speaker 0: They just announced what it was.
Speaker 1: Yep Meanwhile, you know, I realized something but I actually want to mention briefly around that the whole seeding ground like the ground That was made that made space before the show that actually did this first was venture brothers.
Speaker 1: But that shit started in 2004 and they produced them so slowly.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but it's not your brothers I don't think it's for children now, but it did the it did like a lot of the things that Adventure Time did and Steven and shows like it did.
Speaker 1: Venture brothers kind of did those sorts of like storytelling tropes and storytelling techniques of a serial First in this era, but it was kind of obscure aimed at a different audience and was put out so slowly That no one realized what they were doing until well into this decade.
Speaker 0: But also you look at say Studio Ghibli, right?
Speaker 0: It's like before 2010s, right?
Speaker 0: They were solid.
Speaker 0: They were releasing their movies, right?
Speaker 0: They had that run, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, and then it was you know, Princess Mononoke, right was I guess around 2000 ish, right?
Speaker 0: Princess Mononoke, I think was because I remember it being in a theater in Israel in the year 2000.
Speaker 0: And then you know, they had their you know spirited away was also in the 2000s, right?
Speaker 0: One they've had right and then Right and then sort of even they got into the 2010s.
Speaker 0: that's sort of when it's like Miyazaki retires He unretires Goro puts out a movie something else, right and they sort of like, you know destabilized a bit that regularity that just powerful march of Ghibli movies sort of you know, Definitely
Speaker 1: a sense of a decline of Ghibli as a driving force and a rise of all these other studios and creators.
Speaker 0: Yeah, even the you know, the the brooms one that was like a spin-off of Jim like that.
Speaker 0: Yeah former Ghibli people They didn't make a good movie.
Speaker 1: No, and we haven't even talked about Eric in the witch, which I am 100% down with 3d CG anime like do not get me wrong here that Lupin movie, which we're gonna watch soon We're gonna watch it real soon.
Speaker 1: Yeah this week definitely watching it this week But you're rigging the witch kind of looks like last decade Pixar animation.
Speaker 1: Like it does not look good Who knows who knows?
Speaker 0: So, yeah, and then you know that sort of pattern right that has been established.
Speaker 0: right of you know The the.
Speaker 0: you know that after that shift has just sort of maintained right those studios making those anime movies They just kept putting movies out on a schedule.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Oh, what's his name?
Speaker 0: Of course?
Speaker 0: How could I forget cloud guy?
Speaker 0: Makoto Shinkai Makoto Shinkai.
Speaker 0: This has been also the decade of Makoto Shinkai Obviously right on that same schedule right of you know Putting out movies, but I think it wasn't actually until you know When exactly did your name come out because that was like the first big successful one, right?
Speaker 1: I mean that was I was on a flight and I watched it because it happened to be on a Delta.
Speaker 0: your name is actually from 2016. it's like Shinkai we knew about like even we were in college.
Speaker 0: We knew who Shinkai was.
Speaker 1: I still think it's second best movie is a place promise?
Speaker 0: Yeah, probably But you know, they got the five minute centimeters per second, whatever.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know even though we knew who Shinkai was in the early 2000s mid 2000s Didn't really bust out until this decade and become a big deal, right?
Speaker 0: You know on that same level as you know, your Yuwasas and your everyone else, right?
Speaker 0: So
Speaker 1: but yeah A broader point around this decade is that it really feels like we are living in this golden age of animation right now like a red like a mega Renaissance of just animated shows across a variety of Studios a variety of styles like there is more good animation to watch now than there might have ever been.
Speaker 0: Well, I think you know you have people who grew up Really, you know watching a lot of animation caring a lot about Animation, right?
Speaker 0: You know like cuz think when we were you know kids what was available on TV for us at that time.
Speaker 0: You know people who came, you know before us had like Hanna-Barbera garbage, you know garbage, right, but You know, they didn't necessarily, you know Looney Tunes were in the theaters, right?
Speaker 0: They weren't on TV necessarily.
Speaker 1: But I was a kid who like Rejected American animation like at a very young age and got hyper obsessed with anime for a long time.
Speaker 0: So we had Looney Tunes so we were able to see you know, we had Disney movies, right?
Speaker 0: We had you know weird little mermaids Lion Kings all those right.
Speaker 0: and we had you know The we up to those Dexter's labs and we also had like B tasks and all that every right We.
Speaker 0: that was like when we grew up people who grew up after us.
Speaker 0: They were starting to just get like Pokemon is on TV.
Speaker 0: Right, you know they're.
Speaker 0: you know, it's like they were just direct to the anime.
Speaker 0: not anime is this rare special different thing.
Speaker 0: But also the Looney Tunes weren't there anymore Necessarily right, you know.
Speaker 0: the B test wasn't there and such.
Speaker 0: And now if you're a kid, are you even watching cartoons on TV?
Speaker 0: You just watching YouTube, right?
Speaker 0: You know.
Speaker 0: so the people that are our age are adults who are working and They're working around the world and they have powerful computers of which it's now easier to make animation better animation.
Speaker 0: Not that it's easy ever but it's you know They can make it.
Speaker 0: So that's why we're seeing.
Speaker 0: what we're seeing right now is people our age who grew up seeing the things that we saw are now in charge of.
Speaker 1: you know the case in point.
Speaker 1: an example that stands out very strongly for me is that Netflix Castlevania because that is Clearly like that is a labor of love of the kinds of people who when they were young saw Vampire Hunter D and said all I want is something that's like that More more like that, please.
Speaker 1: and here we are.
Speaker 0: So I think that is another thing that happened sort of later in the decade is the.
Speaker 1: the second half of the decade was Netflix.
Speaker 0: it's Netflix specifically I think but this sort of because look Netflix has got right now.
Speaker 1: Castlevania Hilda Kipo was the on Netflix, which was fantastic friends.
Speaker 1: It's Disney show I think but Dragon Prince.
Speaker 1: Yeah, Dragon Prince which got picked up for what?
Speaker 0: four or five more seasons like they're gonna do a lot of seasons for Dragon Prince.
Speaker 1: Yeah Disney like the reboot of DuckTales there were.
Speaker 0: there were more Disney's thing I think.
Speaker 0: gravity falls I think was the start of the Disney.
Speaker 1: Gravity Falls was there toad?
Speaker 1: if into this like new era of TV gravity falls was a fantastic show.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah Um, what was the other thing?
Speaker 0: Oh, of course, so I think pretty sure Didn't our favorite?
Speaker 0: didn't Secret of Kells come out in oh nine or oh, I was gonna talk about that last.
Speaker 1: so, uh into the.
Speaker 1: The Tom Moore trilogy began I think late 2009 early 2010 was Secret of Kells because remember they had budget trouble.
Speaker 0: like we're lucky They're even able to make cows for a lot of only were able to make wolf walkers cuz Apple gave him money.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they went to get money wherever they could get money.
Speaker 1: So look over the course of the decade they made those three like Movies for all time.
Speaker 1: that trilogy I think will will be looked at forever as an important Milestone.
Speaker 0: and just theatrical animation those movies like I think about so many my 80s animation, right?
Speaker 0: You know, you're thinking Thundercats He-Man Transformers Voltron.
Speaker 0: Now, you know original My Little Pony Care Bears gummy bears, right.
Speaker 0: you think about 90s, you know.
Speaker 0: You're starting to think about.
Speaker 0: you know, those, you know, the Dexter's labs and the.
Speaker 0: you know, those sorts of things, right?
Speaker 0: The Ren and Stimpy's You know the Duggs, right?
Speaker 0: That's the 90s thought right in the 2000s.
Speaker 0: I guess it's like what the Spongebob's right of the world.
Speaker 0: But I can only you know in my life I can only think about in the 2000s catching up on All of the anime the great anime of the past that had suddenly become accessible, right?
Speaker 0: You know the even partly.
Speaker 1: that's that's our more of our like personal experience Even though those things were older right.
Speaker 0: and also when I look at you know, the US Animation of the 2000s right?
Speaker 0: It feels like, you know, 2000 to 2010.
Speaker 0: It feels like at that time that run of Disney movies, you know, the Aladdin Lion King run had sort of yeah Yeah, you know Pixar I guess started late high school So late 90s, so I guess there was.
Speaker 0: there was a lot of Pixar action in the 2000s.
Speaker 1: Definitely, you know your cars and your well, I'm thinking I'll stop my head of.
Speaker 1: like animated movies I saw in the last decade that stood out like Tangled was good.
Speaker 1: Arrietty was okay.
Speaker 1: We talked about that while he's 2008 how to train your dragon a cat in Paris, right?
Speaker 0: So 2000s was like the the Pixar run right?
Speaker 0: Not that that run is ended But I think it's you know, they sort of had the sole control of that right like Dreamworks is there but it wasn't You know with their Shrek's I guess also, right but Pixar was really like the premier American animated movies of the 2000 to 2010 right and now to 10 to 220.
Speaker 0: We have not just like this, you know few things to focus on.
Speaker 0: It's like all those things we said there's such a variety.
Speaker 1: That's what stands out the most decade, you know, like we get a show like Bojack Horseman Which I know that is not.
Speaker 1: like you're not interested in a show that is adjacent to Californication but that show was important and very good to get in birdie.
Speaker 0: That show I should got canceled right?
Speaker 1: Well, it got re-picked up.
Speaker 1: stay tuned, but to get birdie I don't think anyone's made a show like that that had a mass audience before.
Speaker 1: Like I say how much animation I'm just watching on a daily basis like right now like the it just kept accelerating The decade just accelerated and accelerated and accelerated to the point that I have to like cue up which show I'll watch next and they're All great,
Speaker 0: and this doesn't include Like independently animated things on YouTube, right
Speaker 1: exactly.
Speaker 1: Channels we link to like worth it kids big top burger like low tiered Independent like publish on YouTube.
Speaker 1: animation is having its own golden age right now.
Speaker 0: Yeah I mean YouTube wasn't launched until 2005 so YouTube did exist in the previous decade, but it wasn't a thing until this decade.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So what YouTube has done for animation has largely been this decade almost entirely Right and not just YouTube but you know and and comics also what Twitter has done for comics is Twitter came out in 2007 But it wasn't really a thing we talked about in the technology episode.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know what Twitter and all these other social media platforms have done for comics, right?
Speaker 0: We talked about in the first part of this show in the news, right?
Speaker 0: You know the.
Speaker 0: you know, you're Right, you're Captain Underpants and you're Raina Tegelmeier right being like the biggest.
Speaker 0: You know what the third biggest comic is in the US.
Speaker 0: is that dude drawn the Nathan Pyle guy with his little alien comic.
Speaker 0: You know the stupid aliens that they won't say the noun they'll just describe the thing.
Speaker 1: Oh, no, like.
Speaker 0: instead like.
Speaker 0: instead of saying comic they'll say like space ice or something, you know Let me put let me put all the irregular things inside of regular objects.
Speaker 0: Exactly that guy right who makes those comics.
Speaker 0: He's like the third biggest comic seller.
Speaker 0: And how did he get that way?
Speaker 0: Hosting a comic on Twitter.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right.
Speaker 0: That's 2010s.
Speaker 0: That's this decade.
Speaker 1: Though in my personal interaction with comics and animation.
Speaker 1: What I find is that I've been watching a lot more Animation this decade for a lot of reasons.
Speaker 0: I have been reading a lot of your comics.
Speaker 0: I think you're react well also fewer comments and your reaction to all the animation is oh my god Let me watch all this great anime.
Speaker 1: I'm just watching it like something new comes out.
Speaker 1: That's so good.
Speaker 1: I just have to watch it for for me.
Speaker 0: It's like okay.
Speaker 0: There's way too many things.
Speaker 0: I don't have time for all that shit.
Speaker 0: Let's only watch the extremely good ones and sort of cue up other things.
Speaker 0: when I got some time Mmm, because if I tried to watch them all that's all I would do I would write I would not have time for anything else.
Speaker 1: I mean, we're like we're in the right now.
Speaker 1: We're in the middle of trying to finish Hilda before another show comes out right cuz season 2 of Hilda just dropped.
Speaker 0: so comics wise right at least personally comics wise cuz I have.
Speaker 0: I've ordered.
Speaker 0: I have I guess I don't know if it's good or not, but I've every month since like 2006 I've ordered comics online for this one website right where I get a big discount and I have to pre-order them and I can just see my full order.
Speaker 0: history forever there and Basically what I can see is that in the 2010s the early 2010 I was still buying a lot of comics right and what was happening was I spent myself right the 2000s buying up sort of like a library of all of the like You know already known Great American graphic novels right like full runs of like vertigo stuff right like all this stuff I had never read not just American, but also Mike.
Speaker 0: Oh, let me buy all the Akira's Let me buy all the.
Speaker 0: you know whatever it is all this stuff I had never read that already exists right I was able to.
Speaker 0: I've spent a lot to acquire like and read all of it Right that's like the whole light.
Speaker 0: You know all this stuff going back to forever in the past right as comics Aren't that old as right?
Speaker 0: I mean I guess if you just count illustrations They're super old, but you know in terms of comic books they started in the early 19s that you know 1900s right there didn't go back that far.
Speaker 0: and then in the towards the 2010s what was happening is I was sort of Getting all the the stuff.
Speaker 0: that was sort of like the industry catching up to reprinting old stuff like.
Speaker 0: I see a lot of like Orders like blackjack like they were still trying to get all the Tezuka into English.
Speaker 0: Yeah like that right And you know like there were but there were still.
Speaker 0: there were like these hot new things Right that we're still coming out then right Whereas now like what happened is basically a lot of those things ended or caught up right to Write the ends, so it's like yotsubo's buying a yotsubo every month, and then that was it.
Speaker 0: and now I get a yotsubo Whenever there's a yotsubo, which is every year or few.
Speaker 0: right they don't come out that often.
Speaker 0: So there aren't too many things.
Speaker 0: I'm following actively that are coming out Regularly and actively or if I am following they come out with a trade once in a while.
Speaker 1: Honestly the only things I'm following actively regularly as they come out are there are two comics that I'm reading.
Speaker 1: I guess three nothing special.
Speaker 1: I'm still just reading that like actively as it comes out.
Speaker 1: order of the stick And I'll go back.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'll go off.
Speaker 0: I am right.
Speaker 0: so it's like I Definitely at some point in the 2010s messed up my personal webcomic like reading system.
Speaker 1: Well, that's something it's I found it difficult to really engage with a like.
Speaker 1: I have a really easy pipeline of.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna watch some cartoons And I'd like to watch them on all my devices like.
Speaker 1: it doesn't matter what device I use everything just works.
Speaker 1: But depending on the comic I run or read it's.
Speaker 1: there's multiple places to go.
Speaker 1: There's different apps.
Speaker 1: some comics Just don't lend themselves to digital formats.
Speaker 1: like.
Speaker 1: there's a lot of cereal.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the cereal webcomics the order of the stick types that I do really like But I haven't read order to stick in so long cuz I forgot where I left off.
Speaker 0: It's been so many.
Speaker 1: I think it's getting near the end.
Speaker 0: Oh, that's good.
Speaker 0: But yeah, it's like I have to you know like go get it.
Speaker 0: somehow I have the books the book at the paper books are probably the easiest way to read it now, right?
Speaker 0: So I feel like for those it's like I'm just gonna wait to your paper book now It's too much for me to go try to read it on the internet, right?
Speaker 0: And the comics I'm reading on the web are the like the one-shot.
Speaker 0: You know funny joke comics because they're on Twitter.
Speaker 0: if you tweet out your funny comic right and then I can see it.
Speaker 0: I can't do the thing I used to do every morning where I'd like open up one tab for every webcomic and see if there was a new strip.
Speaker 1: that And in Megatokio updated even though it's Thursday and they definitely didn't.
Speaker 0: I haven't done that in a decade.
Speaker 0: I can't even remember all the comics that were in to go check on.
Speaker 1: so another thing with us because we've gone on for a while already that in our personal engagement because this is this hasn't been a Radical change though.
Speaker 1: It is more accessible.
Speaker 1: Now.
Speaker 1: Anime movies are much more like this decade.
Speaker 1: They've been in the theaters in America in a way that they were not in the previous decade.
Speaker 0: You know It was a special event in the 2000s if an anime movie was gonna be in 2010.
Speaker 1: It's like I'm looking at old Gignets episodes.
Speaker 1: We went to a physical theater to watch like almost every anime movie that came out.
Speaker 1: That wasn't a sequel.
Speaker 0: We also live in New York, but no like they're screening everywhere.
Speaker 0: Yeah It's like if there wasn't a pandemic wolf walkers was ready to screen across the country.
Speaker 0: Yeah in all kinds of theaters Yeah, so it's like yeah You know some of them have limited Runs like one or two nights here and there
Speaker 1: but we'll go and we see the same people at those screenings Like there's people in New York who I recognize just because we end up at the same theater to watch the same anime movie.
Speaker 0: but yeah, the movie theater has really opened up to You know.
Speaker 0: not, you know, just Disney animation, but all you know and DreamWorks and whoever but everything, right?
Speaker 0: It's gonna be there even if it's just for a few nights or maybe more than a few nights Who knows.
Speaker 1: so if I had to guess I think what's gonna happen over the next decade is.
Speaker 1: Animation is going to finally break out of the weird American obsession with the idea that it's primarily for kids or it's violent porn.
Speaker 1: It's already broken out of that in a lot in a big way.
Speaker 1: But I think that cultural idea that is weirdly pernicious in America is going to die its final death in the next decade.
Speaker 1: Animation is just another form of visual storytelling and people won't think that much about it.
Speaker 0: But the old people dying will help with that, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think so.
Speaker 0: I think.
Speaker 1: maybe then we'll get more movies like Rango which Did come out this past decade.
Speaker 1: that movie is not as old as you might remember as being.
Speaker 1: hmm.
Speaker 0: So I don't know what will happen right because I don't know too much of like, you know, the industry Developments right behind the scenes information upon which you would need to base that kind of prediction.
Speaker 0: but I can say what I'd like to happen right is I would like to see a Cartoon saloon esque explosion from other countries, right?
Speaker 0: We got us.
Speaker 1: Japan Ireland, right France has always been up there.
Speaker 0: Yeah, France has always been there, right?
Speaker 1: It's like let's see the German animation explosion.
Speaker 0: Give me the nice either.
Speaker 1: Romanian animation explosion, right?
Speaker 0: India India hit us with your animation here.
Speaker 1: Oh my god.
Speaker 1: Imagine a decade where?
Speaker 1: Bollywood like like the Bollywood equivalent of anime arises like you can't tell me.
Speaker 0: there Plenty of filmmakers in India, there are people who can draw in India make, you know See your money make a movie a 90-minute full-length animated feature film and you know Aim for like Oscar with it when you're making it right do the best you fucking can right you can do it.
Speaker 0: I believe in you.
Speaker 0: I want to see it.
Speaker 0: I got my money and I shut up and take it honey for you.
Speaker 0: You know Brazil.
Speaker 0: Brazil could do it too.
Speaker 0: Probably I think Brazil has done some G kids I think did put out a movie from Brazil.
Speaker 0: I didn't see it though.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think there I mean there are a lot of great movies animated from all these countries.
Speaker 1: The difference is they don't get mass releases like in America.
Speaker 1: They're not widespread like they're not known except to people like us who would go to like a film festival to see them.
Speaker 0: Well, they're also not the kind the kind of movie that gets from you know, one country to another like that.
Speaker 0: You know, at least to here is something that has like sort of like indie movie theater appeal.
Speaker 0: Yeah, no one's mate you have to make that you can make it with the mass appeal, right?
Speaker 0: Even though it's a foreign film right?
Speaker 0: Look what Parasite did right, you know, it's like you can do it, right?
Speaker 0: You know Akira did it but that was yeah the greatest achievement of animation ever.
Speaker 0: good luck.
Speaker 1: But I think honestly of all the shows that were pushed some of this like push the American audience to be more open to All this.
Speaker 1: honestly, I think it's Bojack.
Speaker 1: I think that opened some people's eyes in a way that Shows should have been able to do but weren't able to.
Speaker 0: for some reason you don't even need to hit the American audience.
Speaker 0: Just try to hit audience outside of your country.
Speaker 0: Whatever your country is, right?
Speaker 0: Just you know, screw stupid Americans, right?
Speaker 0: It's like if you're you know, don't try to target any one other place.
Speaker 0: Just try to make something that anyone in the world will enjoy, right?
Speaker 0: The other thing I hope to see but I don't know if we will see is and I guess this applies to the video game industry too, but we haven't done 2010s in gaming yet is some sort of fixing of the Animation labor market where basically if you work especially in Japan and anime or I guess other places.
Speaker 0: you're being paid nothing working long hours.
Speaker 0: It's horrible, right?
Speaker 1: I do think the animation industry is going to.
Speaker 1: I think both the animation industry and the video game industry globally are about to hit a brick wall of.
Speaker 1: It is literally impossible to make these things at this scale with our current at global economic system.
Speaker 0: I would love to see a labor side reckoning and reorganization that way and then come out on the other side and that would be the 2020s of.
Speaker 0: You know the same way that there was a sort of a you know twist up in the 20 late to that.
Speaker 1: I would like to see that in both animation and games.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and every industry.
Speaker 1: Yeah Well, I mean obviously right destroy capital.
Speaker 0: those are those are the artistic in capitalism Belinda est.
Speaker 0: Yeah that we're focused on.
Speaker 0: that have the this problem, right?
Speaker 1: so so the last thing on a personal note cuz you know, we Got our start doing anime like panels and lectures at anime cons.
Speaker 0: like years They were they were the easiest to get into because they were small-time.
Speaker 1: 2002 if the 2000s was the era of us centering our convention lives and our panel lives.
Speaker 1: and like a lot of stuff around Otakon and a line going to a lot of anime cons.
Speaker 1: the 2010s is interesting.
Speaker 1: in 2009 That was the last Otakon before they kicked us out of this off the staff and there was drama.
Speaker 1: and then we switched to anime Boston and we went to ban on my boss and every year all the way up to 2016 It's a lot longer than I thought we went to that many anime.
Speaker 0: Yeah the last I liked anime Boston.
Speaker 0: I had a good time there.
Speaker 0: I would go to it still if it was not a slight hassle.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and You know, like it's really good con.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's a really good time.
Speaker 1: It's partly that.
Speaker 1: one thing we did is when we first started geek nights We leaned heavily into anime and like we weren't like we got adjacent to a lot of real work in the anime industry in America.
Speaker 1: We did not like pursue that and we actually doubled down hard over the last decade Into video games instead and that's kind of the main focus of geek nights like video games.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well, I think what happened was is that we had a stockpile of anime that we had seen and Comics that we had read already.
Speaker 0: right that we could then do shows on But we were not reading and consuming new ones at a rate at which There were.
Speaker 0: you know the rate at which you do geek nights episodes, right?
Speaker 0: I'm not watching if I do a show every other week 26 anime series a year yeah, or 26 and new animated, you know, if you count movies and TV series and comic series Right or just comics in general.
Speaker 0: I am NOT Reading or watching 26 new ones a year even if never
Speaker 1: mind All the research and reading like part of the reason we were able to do so many things back then like the old decades as we did geek nights four nights a week and we spent
Speaker 0: a lot of time on
Speaker 1: Like staying abreast of the global anime industry to be able to speak to it fluently.
Speaker 1: if we're gonna give a talk like research knowing things Can't keep that even do it that much other people did it way more than us Yeah, and gladly a lot of the people who were doing podcasts around the stuff in parallel with us.
Speaker 1: They doubled down on anime and moved into the anime industry like Mike tool big part of the American anime industry now.
Speaker 0: Yeah But yeah, it's like, you know back then I had like 50 anime series I had already seen.
Speaker 0: so I can do 50 podcasts right out of nothing now.
Speaker 0: I haven't seen 50 more Even if I had watched all of the.
Speaker 0: you know, everything on crunchyroll made full use of my crunchyroll subscription.
Speaker 0: It's like.
Speaker 0: I don't still don't know if there would be enough for all these geek
Speaker 1: But also a lot
Speaker 0: of those I'm not gonna watch no matter what right,
Speaker 1: but we also we Exhausted all of the low-hanging fruit of things We have like a crude knowledge about like the kinds of lectures we could give at anime cons are not that Informative to anyone who reads nowadays because people have caught up.
Speaker 1: but video gaming we have a we continue to push forward.
Speaker 1: We're not really pushing anywhere but gaming right now because we had lives or never.
Speaker 1: almost 40.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well, I think part of what it is also is that you know, if you if and in any area Right, there's sort of like big things that come out right no matter what the area of art or media is.
Speaker 0: You know if you're in sports, this is Super Bowl, right?
Speaker 0: Even if you're like a hockey reporter Super Bowl is gonna enter into your article that week somehow, right?
Speaker 0: What?
Speaker 0: what did the hockey players are watching the Super Bowl something like yeah You know, who are they betting on stuff like that?
Speaker 0: But for us it's like, you know when it comes to anime there are certain anime series.
Speaker 0: They're like the big anime series.
Speaker 0: what like there's some Demon Slayer thing is like the big thing now like that.
Speaker 1: Well Attack on Titan is getting its final season Okay, but it's like.
Speaker 0: I guess we watched Attack on Titan when it was new But it's like used to be that we would watch all the big series that came out Even if they weren't our thing.
Speaker 0: we watch full metal alchemist.
Speaker 1: we watch, you know We would watch shows to completion just to be able to speak to them and under and like learn about them.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I watched some Naruto, right?
Speaker 0: You know, it's.
Speaker 1: you know, this is a broader trend and geek nights as a whole.
Speaker 1: We used to do reviews of things we didn't like Like we give bad reviews of things.
Speaker 1: We basically only review things we like nowadays because I'm not spending time on you know I'm not watching.
Speaker 0: I know not saying these things are bad I'm saying I haven't seen them right.
Speaker 0: but I know there are things that I know exist are big and I haven't seen them and Probably won't like.
Speaker 0: you're my hero academia's right your your Demon Slayer's your Boruto's, right?
Speaker 0: All these these like huge anime's that I know are huge anime's that people are talking about a whole bunch.
Speaker 0: I'm probably never gonna watch a single episode of them ever right because they know what they are and I don't have time for that But I did.
Speaker 0: I have read all of one punch man, so that's that's definitely a 2010s explosion.
Speaker 0: bring on the one punch man.
Speaker 1: But yeah I think in terms of us will continue to like Wednesday will always be Animation nights because we want we still watch a lot of anime and a lot of animation.
Speaker 1: There's a lot to say but what we're not doing is we're not.
Speaker 1: I don't think we're gonna ever go to anime Conventions again, like we're not gonna be giving lectures and might be able to go to never go to one again.
Speaker 0: I just don't think I will be going to one regularly and consistently Right.
Speaker 1: We're also not gonna go to one and like put on a lot of panels and lectures.
Speaker 0: If I went to one and didn't put on a bunch of panels and lectures, what would I spend my time doing exactly?
Speaker 1: There's a. there's a whole thing around that of.
Speaker 1: we've sort of backed away from any convention where there's not active doing Directly related to the convention.
Speaker 0: Yeah But yeah, you know you think about other areas.
Speaker 0: right it's like video games.
Speaker 0: I'm not playing the the huge video games that I know are huge.
Speaker 0: Everyone's talking about right?
Speaker 1: I'm not playing your cyberpunk I mean people play them and talk about them and we can't we focus on other things that are less popular Tabletop gaming though.
Speaker 0: We still are sort of playing the big things, right?
Speaker 0: We you know, I play we play these rules.
Speaker 0: they came out right that's big and recent.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like There's new big tabletop releases like.
Speaker 0: we'll play those games like, you know, we'll go to PAX We'll play them one time and see what the deal is You know, so I think that's you know where you can speak to a little more than yeah.
Speaker 1: also just Study gaming more.
Speaker 1: we focus on it more.
Speaker 1: We pay attention to the industry more.
Speaker 1: I pay less attention to the anime industry toward the end of this decade than I did at the start of this decade by a lot Yep.
Speaker 0: Yep, definitely paying less attention.
Speaker 1: But yeah, I look forward to this golden.
Speaker 0: how we're paying less attention yet sort of like Enjoying the fruits more right?
Speaker 1: It's yeah, like I'm just watching a shit ton of anime and it's all great, right?
Speaker 0: It's like we're spending less time Inspecting the bark of the tree and more time just eating fruit.
Speaker 0: And wow, the trees making some fucking awesome fruit these days.
Speaker 0: Let's eat all this fruit.
Speaker 0: Oh my gosh.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Meanwhile, though in gaming I'm still like picking apart the bark and chewing on it.
Speaker 1: put it under.
Speaker 0: well you you're eating all the fruit Whereas I'm like, I'm gonna get that best fruit up there and eat just that one.
Speaker 1: Right now that most of the fruit we're eating is from the train tree.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well in the board game area All right, so here's to a hopefully interesting 2020s.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: Hmm bring on the good stuff.
Speaker 1: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott.
Speaker 1: special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brand ok for the logos.
Speaker 0: be sure to visit our website at front row.
Speaker 0: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 1: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 1: But unlike those other late shows It's actually recorded at night and the patreon patrons for this Episode of geek nights are Alan Joyce Heidi McNichol Marty green.
Speaker 1: Yeah link eegee a fresh dotnet /tilde rim slash podcast - beta Graham Finch you hold the key to my heart.
Speaker 1: Now go through the last year or so of podcasts and make room sing.
Speaker 1: Clinton Walton read through Zealand Ryan Perrin Review mad bull 34 cowards dread lily tenebrae just like a dude guy.
Speaker 1: Chris Reimer Finn Shervin van are all in a bunch of people who do not want me to say their names.
Speaker 1: So now tonight, I think I'll leave you with something that I doubt many of you have ever encountered.
Speaker 0: Then I trusted the priest.