Speaker 1: go live.
Speaker 1: It's Thursday, July 30th, 2020.
Speaker 1: I'm Rim.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott.
Speaker 1: And this is Geek Nights.
Speaker 1: Tonight, we're talking about power tools.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: Warm today.
Speaker 0: Warm yesterday.
Speaker 1: And gonna be warm for a while now.
Speaker 1: We're in the middle of a long running heat wave in New York City right now.
Speaker 1: It is crazy hot.
Speaker 1: I'm not complaining.
Speaker 1: I love this shit.
Speaker 1: But since the quarantine started, I run a half marathon every weekend.
Speaker 1: I'm trying to do one every single weekend for the entire summer.
Speaker 0: It's gonna be kind of hard with this AQI situation.
Speaker 1: I'm just doing it anyway.
Speaker 1: I've done half marathons on upper orange days before.
Speaker 1: I'm just doing it.
Speaker 0: Well, this is the weather even before there was a deadly virus.
Speaker 0: Even before they were like, "Yeah, gotta cancel the Olympics biz out of
Speaker 0: this.".
Speaker 1: It's interesting because the air in New York, at least in the first part of the quarantine, was better than it had ever been because there weren't any cars.
Speaker 1: But now as things are starting to open up, cars are coming back and the air is getting bad again.
Speaker 1: But it's only like a 50 today.
Speaker 1: It's still actually way better than it would be normally.
Speaker 0: You know what's found interesting is that the hallways in my building outside of the apartments are always frigid cold.
Speaker 0: They air conditioned the hell out of those hallways.
Speaker 1: Ours has central air conditioning just for those, but all the units are doing separate AC.
Speaker 0: Obviously, you can open your door to get free air conditioning, I guess.
Speaker 0: So what I noticed though is we set our air conditioner temperature at 78, which is I think higher than just about everyone.
Speaker 1: Yeah, mine is 76.
Speaker 0: But that is what Con Edison recommends as the most efficient, and it's not uncomfortable.
Speaker 0: It feels just fine in the apartment.
Speaker 0: You're not upset when you're in here that it's warm.
Speaker 0: Unless a whole lot of people come in, then it can get kind of warm.
Speaker 0: But other than that, I think most people in the building are setting it way lower than that, I would imagine.
Speaker 0: The thing is, I noticed starting around a couple days into this heat wave, the hallways are suddenly warmer than our apartment, which has never happened before.
Speaker 1: Trouble brewing.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: No matter what, the hallway has always been way, way, way colder than our apartment, but suddenly it's warmer than our apartment.
Speaker 0: And our apartment is probably one of the warmest ones in the building considering how high we set the AC for efficiency's sake.
Speaker 0: So that's interesting.
Speaker 1: Obviously, there's no follow-up.
Speaker 1: You didn't check on what's the cost.
Speaker 0: I just assumed the building is being cheap.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: But one thing with these, my half marathons, because it's like with the heat index, it's like a hundred degrees when I run these sometimes.
Speaker 1: And it's not really heard my times.
Speaker 1: Like I'm still getting them under two, but like not that much under two.
Speaker 1: But the one thing I noticed specifically is that my average heart rate is like 10 to 15 beats per minute higher during this heat wave than it normally is.
Speaker 1: It's at like 170 something for the entire run.
Speaker 1: When during normal weather, it's at like 160 for the entire run.
Speaker 1: I've never had data like that before to pour over, but it's interesting to be able to do those comparisons.
Speaker 1: But the reason why I bring all that up is my news, because there's an article breaking, making the rounds like yesterday, and it's not sensationalism.
Speaker 1: It is true.
Speaker 1: But the article basically says, and there's a bunch of people reporting on it.
Speaker 1: It's New York Times.
Speaker 1: I'm not linking to them because the paywall, but it basically says that New York right now is not, by any definition, the climate that everyone thinks it is.
Speaker 1: It is actually officially humid subtropical.
Speaker 1: Like New York City is a humid subtropical climate.
Speaker 0: Fantastic.
Speaker 0: That's almost my favorite climate.
Speaker 1: Which does explain a lot of things like how we've sort of morphed into, instead of having a spring, summer, winter, fall that are relatively equal length and well-defined, we basically have a really short spring.
Speaker 1: Fall is split into a late summer and then a rainy season, and we're having a rainy season in New York.
Speaker 1: The interesting part of this news is not that, because that is real.
Speaker 1: That is not sensationalism.
Speaker 1: That is a thing.
Speaker 1: That happened.
Speaker 1: We live in a subtropical climate now.
Speaker 0: Sweet.
Speaker 1: The news that's interesting is that historical analysis has confirmed New York City has been humid subtropical for five years now.
Speaker 0: Oh, okay.
Speaker 1: It's been this way for a while.
Speaker 1: No one thought, like, no one was talking about it.
Speaker 1: No one was like, what should we consider that?
Speaker 1: maybe the climate has changed in this place?
Speaker 1: But it has, and I found an article that's not behind a paywall.
Speaker 0: There's this thing called climate change.
Speaker 0: that's been happening.
Speaker 0: I don't know if you've heard of it.
Speaker 1: Yep, and it's happening a lot faster than a lot of people realize.
Speaker 1: So, New York summers are going to be like this forever, basically.
Speaker 1: Like, that's never going to change.
Speaker 1: This is a normal New York summer.
Speaker 1: This heat wave, we're probably going to have a heat wave like this every year around this time.
Speaker 1: We're probably going to also have a rainy season once or twice a year, depending on how things go.
Speaker 0: Sweet.
Speaker 0: Cool.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: It's kind of like watching a tornado rip through some stuff.
Speaker 1: I can enjoy that because I did not cause that.
Speaker 1: And while I want to prevent that from happening, doing everything I can.
Speaker 0: Yep, exactly.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: So, I don't know.
Speaker 0: I mean, I guess I could turn off the air conditioner entirely.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but increasingly the evidence shows that individual action like that is not what needs to happen.
Speaker 1: We need industry to be reformed and we could afford it if we say confiscated Jeff Bezos' money.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 0: I'm pretty sure that I've read things like, yeah, like one big boat full of, you know, one big giant cargo container ship is making more pollution than all of New York's air conditioners combined.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: Regulation of industry and agriculture is the key, coupled with seizing the wealth of billionaires.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Well, you know.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but that's a topic for another show.
Speaker 1: So, you can read this article if you want to see the details of this.
Speaker 1: You can read the New York Times article if you want to get the full details, but I don't pay for that.
Speaker 0: Well, you know, you said seizing the wealth of billionaires is a topic for another show, but in fact, that is my news.
Speaker 0: So, you know, there have been various times throughout the US history, you know, where the CEOs of major technology companies or other notable nerds like, you know, have been called in to, you know, congressional hearings to bear witness under oath.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And Congress people are able to ask them questions and force them to give truthful answers under some threat of law.
Speaker 1: Like now to set this up before Scott talks about this, because it's a good topic.
Speaker 1: But normally the way these hearings go down is Democrats either ask like pointless, boring questions or they ask the good questions.
Speaker 1: And Republicans tend to just follow up on like fascist nonsense or like like Republicans just do ridiculous bullshit in these hearings.
Speaker 1: Like they never contribute meaningfully.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: That's like the normal operation of these types of hearings.
Speaker 0: So we did do, I believe, a tech show on monopolies at some point.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 1: I feel like we have all four of these companies should be broken up.
Speaker 1: That is our personal opinion, if you were.
Speaker 0: Well, that's apparently the opinion of the subcommittee chair.
Speaker 1: The problem is we want to break them up because we want to seize the wealth of incredibly rich people for the good of all and not let these bad outcomes happen from these like shadow run style mega corps.
Speaker 1: But generally in America, conservatives want to break up tech companies because they see tech companies as resisting their efforts to install fascists.
Speaker 0: Sure.
Speaker 0: But, you know, the Democrats want to break them up because they believe that they're violating antitrust laws, harming and harming their constituents.
Speaker 1: So you have two groups that want the same thing for radically different reasons.
Speaker 0: Regardless, usually when you get these congressional hearings, you have, you know, there's like a direct opposition.
Speaker 0: So whoever is bearing witness is getting, you know, softball, easy questions, getting their ass kissed by one side, like, hey, Mr.
Speaker 1: White supremacist, why is it true that you are not, in fact, a threat?
Speaker 0: Yeah, stuff like that.
Speaker 0: And the other side will be like, you know, you know, trying to tear into them and give them a hard time.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And you see this not even just at, you know, things like this where you're talking to CEOs, but even like when they get, you know, potential new judges in and they're questioning them to see if they're going to be fit to be a judge.
Speaker 0: You know, it's like, well, you know, if it's a Republican judge, the Republicans are like, oh, how great a judge are you?
Speaker 0: Are you the greatest or just a little less great than that?
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And it's the same the other way, too.
Speaker 0: If a Democratic judge is coming in there.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: The Democrats are like, oh, how great a judge are you?
Speaker 0: Anyway, so.
Speaker 0: But you get to see.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Tim Apple.
Speaker 1: I will never not laugh at the Tim Apple joke.
Speaker 0: Sundar Google.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Jeff Amazon.
Speaker 0: And.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Zuck face.
Speaker 0: The replicants.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 0: And Zuck face.
Speaker 0: So all four of those people, notice the Microsoft was not called in because Microsoft had to go through this ringer a long time ago.
Speaker 0: You should read up on that.
Speaker 0: Someone actually commented on YouTube video like Bill Gates, happy he retired so he didn't have to go through this.
Speaker 0: And I replied, I'm like, he went through this.
Speaker 0: He was on trial even.
Speaker 0: It was even worse.
Speaker 1: And it was a different situation back then.
Speaker 1: And not to get into it, but I think a lot of the anti-trust actions against Microsoft were badly misplaced based on Congress knowing as little as you think they know about technology.
Speaker 1: They knew.
Speaker 0: They still know.
Speaker 0: They still know a little about.
Speaker 0: But
Speaker 1: back then during the Microsoft antitrust, regardless,
Speaker 0: though, there was still the fundamental point was that regardless of the other details in the case at the time, Microsoft was using its Windows platform monopoly to gain unfair advantage in other non-operating system markets, which is an anti-trust violation of law that still exists.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Even though our antitrust law is weak, that is still a violation of the weak ass law we have.
Speaker 0: And all four of the companies whose CEOs were being called on in this hearing as witnesses are guilty of the exact same thing and many, many other things.
Speaker 0: But what was interesting was that usually you have this opposition where one side is ass kissing and one side is grilling.
Speaker 0: Both sides were grilling for different reasons.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: One side was grilling for, I guess.
Speaker 0: actually some of the Republicans didn't go to conspiracy theory land, but some did.
Speaker 0: One of them did ask his and that for only one time, though, which is the worst part of the whole thing, like even the white supremacy parts were not as bad as that part, because at least these guys were getting grilled.
Speaker 0: So it's like to see four of the most powerful people on earth.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: The wealthiest people imaginable.
Speaker 0: In control of the largest companies on earth.
Speaker 1: Congress could just like take away their fortunes.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they could.
Speaker 1: Like Congress does ultimately have power over these four people.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Being grilled.
Speaker 0: Regardless of whether the intentions of that grilling were good or bad.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: They did not have a good moment.
Speaker 0: But there were, you know, there were some definite highlights here.
Speaker 0: If you don't want to watch the whole six hour hearing, even though you could fast forward a political answers.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: I'll look into that for you.
Speaker 0: My office will get back to you on that.
Speaker 0: I don't want, right.
Speaker 0: That sort of thing.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: But there were some notable highlights to be seen that are worth checking out.
Speaker 0: You should definitely see the closing statement of, you know, the chairman where he's just like, yep, some of these companies should be broken up and others, all of them should be regulated heavily.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: He's just like, like his conclusion was just like, F you, how are you?
Speaker 0: I think Tim Apple got off a little easy because a, his company actually is less of a monopoly than the others.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Is like.
Speaker 0: the only real thing that can go on after him for, in terms of antitrust is the app store.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: With his 30% cut.
Speaker 0: Like what else does Apple do?
Speaker 0: That's a monopoly.
Speaker 0: They're just really big, but they in no way control any market.
Speaker 1: What besides they control the market of people who have iPhones.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: That's it's like they, they don't get, you know, it's like, like they don't control me.
Speaker 1: I got an Android phone here.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Facebook's out there buying up Instagrams, buying up WhatsApps, right.
Speaker 0: Doing, you know, antitrust obvious, you know, antitrust violations, right.
Speaker 0: Amazon, you know, you could go, oh my God, you can't even begin with them.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And of course, Google just using their power.
Speaker 0: The fact that they completely own search to then control everything else.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: YouTube advertising and phones and this and that.
Speaker 0: Um, I was disappointed that nobody, when they were questioning them, I don't know if there's maybe a rule against this when they were questioning them, they didn't pit them against each other at all.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: So for example, right, they were asking, um, like, uh, who were they asking?
Speaker 0: Oh, they were asking, uh, Facebook about some apps that Facebook had that were banned from the Apple app store for being privacy invading.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And I'm like, and they're asking Zuckerberg about his apps that got banned from the Apple app store.
Speaker 0: But Tim Apple's right there.
Speaker 0: Ask Tim Apple about Facebook's apps and why he banned them from the app store.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Why they didn't ask Jeff Bezos about how, you know, when they're grilling Tim Apple about how come he's taken a cut on all the apps.
Speaker 0: Why don't you have Jeff Bezos?
Speaker 0: Who's right there?
Speaker 0: Because his Kindle app, you can't buy a Kindle book in the Kindle app on the app store because he doesn't want to let Tim Apple take a 30% cut.
Speaker 1: Well, what do you want, you want the sergeant of arms to walk over there and put a knife in the middle of the room and then they will be instructed in what to do.
Speaker 0: Well, they were all the witnesses and a couple of the Congress people were on video.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: I saw people critiquing their backdrops.
Speaker 0: Which was notably Cisco WebEx and the CEO of Cisco was not there.
Speaker 1: I mean, Juniper, Juniper competes with Cisco.
Speaker 0: They were not using it, but they were not using FaceTime or Google Meets or right.
Speaker 0: But yeah, there was also the, my favorite part was when they asked about whether China steals technologies from US companies and everyone gave a wishy washy answer.
Speaker 0: and piece of shit, Zuckface who gave shitty answers to everything else.
Speaker 0: This one question, which is asked by a white supremacist, by the way, right.
Speaker 0: He asked the question for xenophobic and racist reasons.
Speaker 0: Asked in bad faith.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: But the question is a legitimate one.
Speaker 0: Do you think or know of China, Chinese government stealing technology from US companies, which they absolutely do.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: They don't respect the intellectual property laws of any other country.
Speaker 0: And whether those laws should be respected is another question entirely, but do they steal?
Speaker 0: Yes, they do.
Speaker 0: Tim Apple, whose factories are in China, gave the wishy washy answer.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Google, who hopes to do business there, give the wishy washy answer.
Speaker 0: Jeff Bezos said, yeah, I heard of it, but it's never happened to me.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: I don't know any specific instances.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 0: And Zuckface says, it is, I believe it is a well-recorded and well-established fact that they do it.
Speaker 0: And I'm like, thank you.
Speaker 0: That's the only good thing I've heard you say in your whole life.
Speaker 0: Why couldn't you answer every other question that exact same way?
Speaker 0: You coward.
Speaker 0: So you should watch it for that.
Speaker 0: Um, and there you go.
Speaker 0: But yeah, this, uh, this is maybe the best congressional hearing I've watched since, uh, there were like those IP hearings back in the day where like, uh, you know, Zoe Lofgren was, uh, giving them the grill, right.
Speaker 0: SISPA business back in those days.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 1: I've seen a few good ones over time.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: There's, there's good ones out there.
Speaker 0: Uh, and if you really, if you like this kind of action and you don't want to watch it for six hours, right.
Speaker 0: I suggest what you do is go and find the YouTube channels or social media accounts of your favorite Congress people.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 1: They will push clips of themselves having good moments.
Speaker 0: My favorite, you know, everyone loves AOC, but my favorite is actually, she's my, I mean, she's up there right.
Speaker 0: Top five easy.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: But Katie Porter is actually my favorite.
Speaker 0: If you go and look at Katie Porter's YouTube channel, all she posts is videos of her grilling the shit.
Speaker 0: I was disappointed she was not here to grill these four people.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Cause man, she really, she nails them good.
Speaker 0: Um, and yeah, so that's my news.
Speaker 0: This is big deal.
Speaker 0: It's uh, it's Monday stuff, but you know, I'll put it on Thursday.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: I actually have a Monday news around a specific instance of China stealing data from American companies, but I want to save her for Monday because I want to talk about the exploit specifically.
Speaker 0: Ooh.
Speaker 1: It's uh, it's an interesting story about a tax app.
Speaker 1: I got a cute up.
Speaker 1: one last news.
Speaker 1: If you didn't notice.
Speaker 1: Uh, so it turns out Donald Trump, our president killed Herman Cain indirectly.
Speaker 1: He had a rally, you know, during the pandemic and encourage people to not wear masks.
Speaker 1: Herman Cain appears to have gotten the coronavirus at that rally and is now dead.
Speaker 1: I don't know what else I think is going to keep happening because there has been a sort in America where generally conservatives are resisting wearing masks and taking basic precautions and non-conservatives are wearing masks and taking basic precautions and we're seeing this start to affect our electoral politics.
Speaker 0: Well, I'm really curious, right?
Speaker 0: You know, it's like I would like it if people stopped dying.
Speaker 0: That would be ideal.
Speaker 1: But what if America decides on its own that only a certain like a subset of the population will die at a much higher rate by their own choice?
Speaker 0: But the problem is, from what I've seen statistically, it's that people with less money are more likely to get COVID-19 and die and be unwell.
Speaker 0: Uh, so I'm really curious, is it, is the disease killing more poor left-leaning people or is it killing more right-leaning people who refuse to wear masks and take precautions?
Speaker 1: Well, masks and precautions, all the polls and studies I see seem to indicate that non-white people comply way more than white people do.
Speaker 1: Liberals comply way more than conservatives.
Speaker 1: But do they, urban people comply way more than rural people.
Speaker 0: But do they die less?
Speaker 0: Well, it's it, the, the people who are complying more have less money.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: But if they live in a place where there's more compliance, they are safer than if they lived in a place with less compliance.
Speaker 0: But those places also have more people.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: But look, we're seeing New York, an extremely dense city, has vanishingly few cases day by day.
Speaker 1: now compared to...
Speaker 0: It's still like hundreds.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: A few hundred in a city of so many million compared to...
Speaker 0: It's not, it's still not great.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I think there, there are 290 yesterday in the whole city.
Speaker 0: You want to go ride the subway to work?
Speaker 1: Oh no, I'm not going back to work until like, we're next.
Speaker 1: July is like the earliest date that's even been talked about.
Speaker 0: One of my coworkers went to my office today and I was like, hey, how's my desk do it?
Speaker 0: I was like, hey, how's my desk do it?
Speaker 1: Like, I don't think I'm going to go back to my office in 2021 the way things are going.
Speaker 0: I don't think so either.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: But anyway, on a much lighter note, it is time for the things of the day.
Speaker 1: This is a real short video.
Speaker 1: It's 37 seconds long, but it is a sound that is, you are very unlikely to hear.
Speaker 1: And it's a sound that if you do hear it, you are probably involved in a very, very bad situation.
Speaker 1: It is the sound that a giant turbine engine makes if you drop a screw into it.
Speaker 1: Oh, this is a turbine engine that they have cut off of something and cut the shaft out of, uh, for like, like a jet engine, uh, basically.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: And they've got to just lay in there.
Speaker 0: I think it's like, if you were flying it, so if you were flying in an airplane and you heard this noise, that means a screw just is in the air somehow flying, got into the front of the engine.
Speaker 1: Well, this is the sound it makes if the turbines not spinning, like you're working on doing maintenance and you drop a screw into it.
Speaker 0: It is.
Speaker 1: It does not make the sound you think it would make.
Speaker 1: I was very surprised by what this sounded like.
Speaker 0: And also my, my guess would be something like a, like a date, like a ding, but then the ding would resonate like, and they become like, you know, I thought something similar.
Speaker 1: I was completely wrong.
Speaker 1: I'm not even going to spoil it.
Speaker 1: The video is 37 seconds long, but the best part is the guy in the video is like, yeah, if you ever hear this sound, you're about to have a real bad day.
Speaker 0: Don't turn the engine as long as you don't turn the engine on.
Speaker 1: Oh yeah.
Speaker 1: But basically there's no way to get that screw out of there.
Speaker 1: Like you're just fucked.
Speaker 1: You just cause millions of dollars.
Speaker 0: You take it apart.
Speaker 0: That's expensive and difficult and time consuming, but you can do it depending on the magnet.
Speaker 0: magnet magnet can also help you depending on the turbine.
Speaker 1: Some cannot be taken apart.
Speaker 1: They must be cut apart, destroying them.
Speaker 0: Why would you make something like that?
Speaker 1: Uh, depending on what that, how was it made?
Speaker 0: Everything that's made can be unmade.
Speaker 1: Imagine here's, here's that analogy.
Speaker 1: There are fancy suits and dresses that are used for special occasions where you are sewn into them and they cannot be removed except by cutting.
Speaker 1: And to put them back on requires being tailored and re-sewn.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but you can still tailor it.
Speaker 1: You could rebuild the thing, but sometimes a piece might be forged or cast in one piece where there is no way to access the internal parts of it because of you need it to be one piece for its own materials.
Speaker 0: Well, how would the screw get in there?
Speaker 0: then if it's one piece, if there's an opening in the front, there's an opening, then you can use a little, uh, you know, what's that?
Speaker 0: The arthroscopic surgery, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, you may be able to, it depends.
Speaker 1: Anyway, this video will tell you what that, you will hear what this sounds like because the dude just drops a screw into a turbine and you will be surprised by the sound.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: So my thing of the day, so in Japan, there was a television show called Mito Koman.
Speaker 0: I don't know how to, I don't know if I'm pronouncing it correctly, but it was one of those period dramas, right?
Speaker 0: That took place in like, you know, olden times, right?
Speaker 0: And it actually ran for an insanely long period of time from like the late sixties to like 2011.
Speaker 0: I think the show ended.
Speaker 0: It's what Wikipedia says.
Speaker 0: Anyway, this is like a super popular long running, you know, TV, TV drama that was in prime time.
Speaker 0: Um, big, big deal.
Speaker 0: Uh, but obviously anyone who's not from Japan probably wouldn't know or care about it.
Speaker 0: I've never watched an episode, right?
Speaker 0: I don't know what it's like.
Speaker 0: I just know what exists and what its name is.
Speaker 1: Um, I'm watching any live action thing that I've never watched from like older Japan.
Speaker 1: I'm watching like Odorodai Sousa-sen.
Speaker 0: Exactly.
Speaker 0: This is way older than that.
Speaker 0: Oh, I guess not.
Speaker 0: I guess it's both older and newer.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Uh, anyway, so what I do know about, right?
Speaker 1: Is that, oh, this is Neil Nadelman's YouTube channel.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: In the year 1991, right?
Speaker 0: Uh, a student at an art school made student film.
Speaker 0: Uh, and the student film is Godzilla versus Mito Koman, right?
Speaker 0: So it was basically the.
Speaker 0: it's about right.
Speaker 0: Godzilla fighting, you know, Mito Koman from that TV show, right?
Speaker 0: In case you don't know who Mito Koman is, uh, now you know, and the thing about this student film is that the person in the film who is, uh, basically doing everything, this one student, what's his name?
Speaker 0: The name is in the description.
Speaker 0: Shinya Takashita.
Speaker 0: This guy did absolutely everything in the film.
Speaker 0: Directed the film, right?
Speaker 0: Shot the film, right?
Speaker 0: As a student, he wrote the film, did everything, right?
Speaker 0: Including acting as every single character in the film.
Speaker 0: And not only the characters like Godzilla and Mito Koman and Mito Koman's followers that you would expect, but also as characters such as the power lines that Godzilla grabs onto or gets thrown into and things of that nature.
Speaker 0: Um, it's only 11 minutes long.
Speaker 0: I hope he got an A on this.
Speaker 0: It is a legendary, um, it's not anything new.
Speaker 0: It's just something that's new to, I think, a lot of nerds out there.
Speaker 0: I've known about it for quite a while and I was just digging through my YouTubes and I was like, hey, here's the thing of the day.
Speaker 0: People probably haven't seen this.
Speaker 0: We didn't use it as thing of the day before.
Speaker 0: Check it out.
Speaker 1: Pretty cool.
Speaker 1: In the meta moment, the Book Club book's kind of on hold because we don't really have time to read during this quarantine.
Speaker 1: Like we're stuck at home.
Speaker 1: We're not traveling.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: Ah, we're playing a lot of train games.
Speaker 1: Follow me.
Speaker 1: Follow Scott on YouTube and all the other places.
Speaker 1: we're doing stuff because we keep doing stuff.
Speaker 1: We're trying to do the stuff that we can do from home without having to go out anywhere.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I got, yeah, I got nothing else.
Speaker 0: I guess we could just list off in case for some reason someone listening to this does not know every place you can find us on the internet.
Speaker 0: There is our website, frontrowcrew.com.
Speaker 0: There is a forum at community.frontrowcrew.com.
Speaker 0: There is a forum at forum.frontrowcrew.com.
Speaker 0: that is read only that preceded the current forum at community.frontrowcrew.com.
Speaker 0: There are three Twitter accounts.
Speaker 0: My rim, my Twitter rims, Twitter, geek nights, Twitter.
Speaker 0: There is a Facebook page that I don't, it barely works.
Speaker 0: I don't know if anyone goes to it, but it exists.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Delete your Facebook accounts.
Speaker 0: We have a geek nights Instagram.
Speaker 0: That's also Facebook.
Speaker 0: I have an Instagram.
Speaker 0: They're not posted to very often, they exist.
Speaker 0: We have a discord server that you can join.
Speaker 1: It's moderately rocking.
Speaker 1: There's stuff going on in there.
Speaker 0: We have, I guess, the stupid Patreon.
Speaker 0: Don't give rim any money.
Speaker 0: Give your rim money to something worth giving money to.
Speaker 1: But that's where there's sideshows, which you don't have to pay for.
Speaker 1: They're mostly public, those things.
Speaker 1: Me and Emily are reviewing every Disney theatrical animation in chronological order.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: I have a YouTube channel.
Speaker 1: It's my YouTube channel.
Speaker 1: The three Caballeros and Saludos Amigos.
Speaker 0: I know a rim has a YouTube channel, which is also the official geek nights YouTube channel.
Speaker 1: So like all our panels and like mainstream stuff is there plus my bullshit.
Speaker 1: And then Scott's YouTube channel is some of our other shows, Scott's bullshit and like other side content that randomly will stream with Scott instead of mine.
Speaker 0: There is an actual geek nights YouTube channel that I have regained access to.
Speaker 0: That's like youtube.com/geeknight.
Speaker 1: The problem is all our subscribers are on my channel.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: We lost access to it for so long and I don't, we would need someone at Google to like help us merge, merge them somehow.
Speaker 0: I've been streaming Paper Mario on Twitch.
Speaker 0: Oh yeah.
Speaker 0: Paper Mario.
Speaker 0: I'm probably going to do that again soon.
Speaker 1: I'll finish it.
Speaker 0: There is, there's gotta be, oh, there's a geek nights newsletter that you can subscribe to.
Speaker 0: that is mailed a few times a year, maybe whenever I remember and put it.
Speaker 0: enough effort.
Speaker 0: Cause it's it's work.
Speaker 1: Oh, and the Baltimore and Ohio railroad just IPO'd at one 50.
Speaker 0: Well, okay.
Speaker 0: Well, I mean, that's what's going to happen.
Speaker 1: I gotta, I gotta think about if I want to IPO IC.
Speaker 0: Okay, go ahead.
Speaker 0: Anyway, we're playing games still.
Speaker 0: You should, you should find us on the internet.
Speaker 1: All right, let's get into it.
Speaker 1: Power tools, completely nice generic topic.
Speaker 0: I guess, uh, you know, the thing is as like, as much as I have used power tools enough to do an episode on them, I primarily avoid power tools and we'll use handheld tools unless a power tool is like necessary.
Speaker 1: I prefer power tools and almost all cases for almost all things.
Speaker 1: But now that I live in apartment, I use them less because I tend to not do the kinds of projects I would do previously, but I still use power tools pretty much exclusively for anything I would do with tools, unless it's a really, really trivial job.
Speaker 1: Like tighten a screw.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: But like sometimes they're tightening a screw and it just won't tighten.
Speaker 0: I have a power screwdriver I'll use.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: But like, cause I like a nice torque setting so I can choose like exactly how tight I want the screw to be.
Speaker 0: It's like, if I can screw it in by hand, I'll screw it in by hand.
Speaker 0: But the only other time I'll reach for the power screwdriver is like, okay, I've got to screw in 30 screws.
Speaker 0: I guess I'm not doing them all by hand, even if I could do one by hand.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: But even for a single screw often I'll use a power tool.
Speaker 1: because of the consistency and the like, I can make things like, I can get better tolerances in my work.
Speaker 1: Like I don't like the screw.
Speaker 1: It's like, if you're screwing something in, depending on the nature of the screw, if you're doing it by hand and you don't have a screw guide set up, then you might angle a little bit.
Speaker 1: It might like wear out a little bit of the thread as you're creating it, depending on what, whether or not you drilled a pilot hole with a drill, I can just be like, perfect pilot hole, perfect screw.
Speaker 0: Well, I mean, you're not going to do a hand drill.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: The only thing I would do with a hand, they do have hand drills, right?
Speaker 0: You crank it like this.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I had one as a kid.
Speaker 1: I actually used it a lot because I was often doing work in a place where I didn't have power.
Speaker 0: Oh, okay.
Speaker 1: It was a giant pain in the ass.
Speaker 1: You like double crank it and it had this like brace around it.
Speaker 1: I hated that thing.
Speaker 0: Well, I think it's like, if you think about other tools, not just hardware power tools, right?
Speaker 0: It's like, um, usually what you see is that if there is a more powerful tool, especially like computers, right?
Speaker 0: More, it's like, even if you're doing a small job, it's like, well, the more powerful tool still is more efficient and does a better job, right?
Speaker 0: Why would you use a weak tool?
Speaker 0: But when it comes to like the kind of, you know, hardware kind of work, constructiony work, right?
Speaker 0: Household repair type work.
Speaker 0: A lot of times the minimum power of the power tool is too strong for a more delicate work.
Speaker 0: Like you would never use a power tool when you're working on your bicycle, like ever.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: Because it would just screw the screw in too hard.
Speaker 1: Well, I've said, so I have seen, like, I watched my bike shop use a power screwdriver, but it was a power screwdriver that had a fancy torque system on the front.
Speaker 1: So it was basically just a powered torch.
Speaker 0: Sure, sure, sure.
Speaker 1: That's fine.
Speaker 1: But no, do not put your carbon fiber bike together with a power screwdriver.
Speaker 1: You're going to die.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Um, but yeah, it's just like, you know, there's, it's surprising how like, you know, in, it's like, you're like, oh, just more power.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: So for example, on a power tool, for example, we talked about this during kitchen appliances, right?
Speaker 0: But it's like my stand mixer.
Speaker 0: It's like, there's not really any reason to mix by hand so much once you have the stand mixer or a bright, it's like, it's just even at it.
Speaker 0: Cause it has such a weak power setting.
Speaker 0: It's like, it can do everything.
Speaker 1: Well, that's a good power tool.
Speaker 1: There are a lot of, like a lot of people have only ever experienced crappy power tools.
Speaker 1: Like you go to, you go to Sears, not that Sears will exist much longer if it even still exists, but I don't think it does.
Speaker 0: I don't think it does either.
Speaker 1: You go as a kid, like you go to Sears and there's like a $20 power drill.
Speaker 1: That piece of shit is too powerful for anything you're going to do.
Speaker 1: And it's going to break.
Speaker 1: If you do anything that actually requires power.
Speaker 1: But I just always think back to in middle school shop class in sixth grade, the dude who was running that class asked one question of the class.
Speaker 1: He gave us a test out like midway through the class.
Speaker 1: And this was going to be our grade.
Speaker 1: It only had one question on it.
Speaker 1: And the question was basically there is a cheap option for a tool like a $1, like the cheapest version of this tool that exists.
Speaker 1: There's the, the $40 version you'd buy at like a Sears.
Speaker 1: And then there's the professional one.
Speaker 1: And the, on the question was just when would you use each one of these three tools?
Speaker 0: I mean, the cheap one, if that's all I can afford and it's going to get the job done.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: If I'm going to do a job once, like if I need to buy a tool to like change the oil in a car once before I sell that car, I will buy the cheapest possible tool.
Speaker 1: If I hang stuff on my wall, like I don't hang things on my wall that often.
Speaker 1: I don't need a laser leveler.
Speaker 1: I can use the bubble.
Speaker 1: It'll be good enough because I'm not doing it that often.
Speaker 1: But if I was hanging stuff on my wall every day, I'd have a laser leveler.
Speaker 1: And I think about that a lot, kind of with chairs and everything else in my life, I either buy the cheapest thing that will do the job or I will buy the correct tool for the job.
Speaker 1: And I try to avoid anything in the middle.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: But yeah, so let's talk about specific power tools, right?
Speaker 0: What's your favorite power tool?
Speaker 0: Well, I have a story about, uh, the nail gun.
Speaker 0: I got a nail gun story.
Speaker 0: So with the nail gun, if you don't know, it's, it's just like, it's like a hammer and nails all in one, right?
Speaker 0: You put nails in it, you push it up against something, you pull the trigger and it fires a nail into whatever you're pushed it up against.
Speaker 1: They're pretty much for, if you got a hammer in like a thousand nails, like if you're writing, like I've only ever used a nail gun in my life, roofing, never for any other task.
Speaker 0: So, uh, there was one time I was not part of the group at school that would put that we worked, did anything involving a drama or the school play.
Speaker 0: But one time I was in, uh, AutoCAD class and the teacher who taught the AutoCAD class was one of the shop teachers who was in charge of that.
Speaker 0: And one time we just sort of left class, just like, I don't remember what the circumstances were, but like class just sort of casually ended, I think because the teacher was working on that instead.
Speaker 0: So we, so I went and I was just like, all right, you know, I'll hammer this.
Speaker 0: I think where they were making a boat.
Speaker 0: Um, what, what play has that shuffle off to Buffalo song in it?
Speaker 0: Ah, I'll Google it.
Speaker 0: Oh, you're going to, you're going to Google it.
Speaker 1: 42nd street.
Speaker 0: That was the school play that year, 42nd street.
Speaker 0: And they were making a big boat.
Speaker 1: I've never actually seen 42nd street.
Speaker 1: I've seen clips.
Speaker 0: It's good.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So the, uh, there was a boat that they had to make for the set, right?
Speaker 0: There people go up the stairs on the boat and there was like an upper deck, right?
Speaker 0: You know, sort of situation anyway.
Speaker 0: So, uh, just hammering, you know, like the frame of the thing was existing already, but we were hammering, uh, just, you know, wooden boards to the panels onto the side of it.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: So then it was solid and not just a wooden frame.
Speaker 0: And I was just using, you know, a hand hammer and nails.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And I was going very, very slowly, but, uh, I was doing okay.
Speaker 0: And the teacher had a nail gun.
Speaker 0: And then of course the teacher was the kind of teacher would fool around and like pull back the safety on the nail gun and just shoot nails around.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: That's always a good time.
Speaker 0: Not at anyone.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Obviously at other things.
Speaker 0: That wouldn't cause damage.
Speaker 1: My middle school shop teacher had a lot of, "Hey kids, watch this
Speaker 1: lessons."
Speaker 1: Yeah, exactly.
Speaker 1: Which were always super fun.
Speaker 0: Sure.
Speaker 0: Uh, you know, so then eventually, you know, I've been sitting there for a while.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And the shop teacher's just like, "All right, you're taking too
Speaker 0: long."
Speaker 0: He comes over with the nail gun.
Speaker 0: He's like,
Speaker 0: "Finishes."
Speaker 0: You know, basically what was going to take me probably another hour in, uh, less than a minute, the nail gun.
Speaker 0: Uh, but the nails that he put in, right.
Speaker 0: Where A, uh, the heads on the nails were smaller.
Speaker 0: So that could be a positive or a negative.
Speaker 0: I guess pulling them out would be harder.
Speaker 0: I don't know if that's true for all nail guns.
Speaker 0: Um, you know, when's the last time I used a nail gun?
Speaker 0: Probably then.
Speaker 0: The year 1998 or 99.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I was like 15 the last time I touched a nail gun.
Speaker 0: Uh, but it made them harder to see, but also harder to remove.
Speaker 0: Obviously it was faster and easier, but also it was just sort of more haphazard, right.
Speaker 0: You know, it was like doing it by hand.
Speaker 0: I was putting them, spacing them more evenly, being more careful, right.
Speaker 1: When I was doing roofing, there's so many nails to put in that the nail gun was the only way to do them with very good spacing and very good, like the nails are all perfect.
Speaker 1: Like I actually found the nail gun was not a haphazard way.
Speaker 1: Nail gun was for precision and repeatability.
Speaker 1: You were just being lazy.
Speaker 0: Right, right.
Speaker 1: The teacher did not precisely, he just sort of went around the edge like Which makes sense if you're making a set for a play that's going to run for what, two weeks?
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: And that was the lesson that I learned right then.
Speaker 1: Do the minimum effort for the maximum payoff?
Speaker 0: A lesson that I learned from that teacher, right.
Speaker 0: Great teacher because, I mean, he successfully taught me a lesson that I remember to this day.
Speaker 0: Therefore, great teacher, right.
Speaker 0: You can't see it from your house, right.
Speaker 0: He's like, yeah, you could bang a nail into this all janky, right.
Speaker 0: Even someone sitting in the front row will never see it.
Speaker 1: That is the same advice that we always give to people at RIT.
Speaker 0: No matter how we nail this in, right, as long as this, it's important that it's put together well so that the students in the play don't fall down or hurt themselves, right.
Speaker 0: But other than that, it's like as long as it looks good enough, you know, even if we spend the time here, an extra hour to make this absolutely perfect, right, the people in the front row will not notice any difference from the job that we have done in five minutes.
Speaker 1: Yup, that's the same philosophy that led us to the radical realization at RIT.
Speaker 1: The low B is the most efficient possible grade.
Speaker 1: There's no pluses or minuses.
Speaker 1: Getting 80% is the same as getting 89%.
Speaker 1: So you would actively, aggressively seek that low B.
Speaker 0: In terms of appearance, right, not in terms of other things.
Speaker 0: And so I think that is really, you know, not only a great life lesson, but also the essence of the power tool, right.
Speaker 0: It's like, yeah, if you saw something carefully by hand, right, or like you sand something carefully by hand, right, as opposed to using a power sander or like a belt sander or something.
Speaker 1: But I'm going to sand something much better with a power sander and a buffer than I would by hand, like much more delicately, much more controlled.
Speaker 0: Well, not if it's small.
Speaker 1: Well, if it's really small, what am I, what am I doing?
Speaker 1: That's finishing work.
Speaker 1: That's a very different ballgame.
Speaker 0: I'm just saying like you're doing, you know, something carefully.
Speaker 0: You can, you know, like I would never tap threads.
Speaker 1: Like if I was putting threads into a piece of metal to be able to put a screw in it later, I would never use a power tool for that.
Speaker 1: I would definitely use like a manual tap.
Speaker 0: Right, but I'm saying it's like when you're doing something by hand, you're looking at it very closely, noticing very, very small details, right.
Speaker 0: And it, but the thing is no one else will notice those small details.
Speaker 0: You're wasting your time, right.
Speaker 0: It's going to look incredible if you don't.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but it depends on what you're doing.
Speaker 1: Like the saw is not a good analogy because if you're sawing wood, your hand sawing will always be a messier job.
Speaker 1: that'll be less precise and less good than using like an actual table saw or a bandsaw or something.
Speaker 1: Like you're not going to do as good a job.
Speaker 0: You know, it could be some filing action.
Speaker 1: Filing is not sawing.
Speaker 1: I said sawing.
Speaker 1: You want to talk about filing?
Speaker 1: That's a totally different ballgame.
Speaker 1: It's like I'm metalworking.
Speaker 1: I spent a lot of time working on stuff as a kid.
Speaker 0: You can file wood.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I guess.
Speaker 1: Like you can shave wood too.
Speaker 1: Anyway.
Speaker 1: Got a plane?
Speaker 1: You gonna plane some wood?
Speaker 1: You ever plane wood?
Speaker 0: No, but I've seen people plane wood.
Speaker 0: Planing sucks.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: You need, you need arm strength to plane stuff.
Speaker 1: If I had to, like, because I have a lot of anecdotes, but most of them are either like some kid, like a kid cut his finger kind of halfway off in middle school
Speaker 0: because, but
Speaker 1: he was trying to sand a piece of wood by holding it up to the side of a bandsaw because he was a moron.
Speaker 0: What the fuck?
Speaker 1: That's a thing people do.
Speaker 1: I saw people do it more than once.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 0: Our, our shop classes stress safety so much and nobody heard them.
Speaker 0: Oh yeah.
Speaker 1: The teacher wasn't around.
Speaker 1: Kids immediately started trying to like launch drill bits out of the drill press.
Speaker 0: Everyone followed the safety protocols very carefully.
Speaker 1: I'm just giving through the Wikipedia article.
Speaker 1: There's a list of power tools.
Speaker 1: One of them that's listed is just the crusher.
Speaker 0: What is the crusher?
Speaker 1: It's a, it's a crusher machine designed to turn large rocks into smaller rocks or to turn smaller rocks into sand or rock dust.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: Let's not mess around with that.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I've never used a crusher in my life.
Speaker 0: I think it's also just like growing up, we didn't have a lot of power tools, right?
Speaker 1: The totally different childhood.
Speaker 1: I grew up with like, other than like, it's like, like our garage was full of power tools and like, I used them for projects.
Speaker 1: My grandpa had a full woodworking shop, like a complete industrial woodworking shop.
Speaker 0: My grandpa had a shop, right?
Speaker 0: And he had like a table saw and some other stuff.
Speaker 1: My grandpa's shop was two stories and had an entire production line.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Not that big.
Speaker 0: It was just like, you know, workshop in the basement.
Speaker 1: He had his, like, he had a bandsaw, he had a jigsaw, and then he had his high precision jigsaw.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: And we had like drill, you know, uh, I had, we had a sander that shakes like, right?
Speaker 0: Power sander.
Speaker 0: Uh, you know, but it's like, we just, you know, mostly used not power tool.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: I guess the tool, the power tools I use the most are like, Dremel's a power tool.
Speaker 1: I use Dremel's and drills the most, but I think that's just because as I became an adult and did not own a house anymore, the kinds of projects where I would do use any other power tools, like back when I made that DDR pad, I used a whole bunch of power tools to make that DDR pad.
Speaker 1: Uh, I don't do things like that anymore because I live in New York City.
Speaker 1: So all the stuff I've done recently is all drills.
Speaker 1: It's all just drill stuff.
Speaker 1: If I lived outside of the city, I think I would invest in like a relatively cheap drill CNC and probably use that for a lot of my projects.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I think if I did have more like a space and was working on stuff, what I would be doing is, uh, as I was working on projects, right, I would buy tools as needed.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 1: Well, I would assess what the thing I did, the thing I did, I didn't do as a kid because we just had all the tools that I would do now.
Speaker 1: Cause I didn't do this.
Speaker 1: when I made that DDR pad, which meant every couple of days I'd go, Oh fuck.
Speaker 1: And then I'd go to the hardware store and buy like a tool I didn't have.
Speaker 1: And then a few days later, Oh fuck, I'm missing yet another thing.
Speaker 1: Cause I didn't plan this project.
Speaker 1: I would plan the project, figure out what parts would need like a real modern power tool to make it efficient or good.
Speaker 1: And then buy all the tools I needed before I started the project.
Speaker 1: And I would never buy a tool.
Speaker 1: I didn't have a project already lined up for.
Speaker 0: Something else I noticed is that, you know, like the first power tools that I used were all plugged into the wall.
Speaker 0: Like the drill that I still have.
Speaker 1: Batteries barely existed back then.
Speaker 0: So if your only option is a, it was a plug into the wall drill, right?
Speaker 1: I had a lot of pneumatic tools too.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: We had an air compressor.
Speaker 1: I'd fire that thing up and plug the pneumatic tools in.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: That's the good stuff.
Speaker 1: We had the pneumatic drill.
Speaker 1: That thing made so much goddamn noise.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: But battery powered stuff did come right.
Speaker 0: But a lot of it was weak.
Speaker 0: Like the battery powered screwdriver I have is actually extremely old.
Speaker 0: Uh, relatively speaking, it must be from like maybe the nineties or early two thousands.
Speaker 0: I don't even know, but it's actually not that powerful.
Speaker 0: It kind of goes, it doesn't go like, right.
Speaker 0: It's our, it spins very slowly and weakly.
Speaker 1: Uh, I mean, like we had an electric lawnmower and even that had a cord going all the way back to the house because batteries, lithium batteries did not exist back then.
Speaker 0: Like gas lawnmower.
Speaker 0: We had plug it in.
Speaker 0: That's what I'm saying is that the lithium ion battery is, you know, we think of it always in terms of phones and our electronic devices was actually a huge, huge development for power tools.
Speaker 0: Cause now a, you don't have to plug them in then and they can be powerful and they won't be as heavy.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 0: And they won't run out of energy in like five minutes.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: And what, especially once they standardize, like depending if you buy from like the same company or like the same set of companies, you can buy generic batteries that will work in all your power tools.
Speaker 1: That, that changed everything.
Speaker 0: Cause my first, even, even my vacuum is like a battery vacuum.
Speaker 0: Now I don't have to plug it.
Speaker 0: I've never, it was the first vacuum I've had in my life that didn't have to be plugged into the wall.
Speaker 0: That wasn't just like a little dust buster.
Speaker 1: The tool I had the most fun with though, like, cause whatever is in my middle school had like a really advanced shop.
Speaker 1: Like we had a plastics lab, like we had all these different plastic forming tools and all sorts of fun.
Speaker 0: You lived in white people town.
Speaker 1: No, this was when, this was when we lived in the poor town before we moved to the white people town.
Speaker 0: No.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 1: I never took shop once we moved to Sterling Heights.
Speaker 1: I didn't take shop in middle school.
Speaker 0: I didn't take shop in high school either.
Speaker 0: They, I took, like I said, AutoCAD.
Speaker 0: Great.
Speaker 0: But they did have it.
Speaker 0: They had all kinds of fancy stuff.
Speaker 0: They had actually an entire garage.
Speaker 0: You could learn like, you know, to be an auto mechanic on my high school.
Speaker 1: We had that too.
Speaker 1: And I kind of wanted to do it, but that class always filled up.
Speaker 1: But, uh, we, uh, had in the middle school, a CNC drill press and a CNC lathe.
Speaker 1: And that was like the moment when the idea of automation, like really clicked with me as a kid, because I watched this thing and I was like, wait, I can basically write code like the turtle program and then a robot will do what.
Speaker 1: I told the, and my brain, my kid brain in sixth grade was just like, Oh fuck.
Speaker 1: Oh wow.
Speaker 1: Oh, I want one of these.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I mean, we had that in high school, right?
Speaker 0: When we were doing AutoCAD, right?
Speaker 0: You could have, there was one of the AutoCAD classes was like mechanical CAD.
Speaker 0: And if you took that, you would make things and you would design like parts.
Speaker 0: And then they had a CNC to make the parts that you drew in AutoCAD.
Speaker 0: Uh, and that was with late nineties technology.
Speaker 0: Right?
Speaker 0: So what they have today is like incredible compared to that.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I was typing to the listener.
Speaker 1: There's a, there's a lively chat going on right now.
Speaker 0: Oh, that's good.
Speaker 0: Have fun, have fun.
Speaker 0: Lively chatter.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: But, uh, YouTube and lively chat with them or not.
Speaker 0: You have something better to do, but yeah.
Speaker 1: Nowadays, like just living in an apartment, the drill and the like handheld saw, like the jigsaw style handheld saw are the only tools that I use with any regularity, but I use them kind of often.
Speaker 1: And I try to use that drill for everything because it's a really great drill for what I paid for it.
Speaker 1: And it has torque settings and all the stuff I might need.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: It's like, I was actually had to do a project recently and, you know, some of my friends were suggesting, Oh, you can just, you know, they were like, get these tiles.
Speaker 0: And instead I was, I was trying to put some stuff onto my, uh, my little balcony.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I remember you were talking about that.
Speaker 0: I ended up just getting the cheapo piece of fake grass, AstroTurf in a roll, right?
Speaker 0: It's working.
Speaker 0: Uh, that's good.
Speaker 0: But they were like, yeah, you can get these patio tiles.
Speaker 0: And I'm like, Whoa, those actually look way better.
Speaker 0: And then I think they might've been way better than the fake piece of grass.
Speaker 0: Uh, the problem is to cut a tile is not something you can really do without a power tool.
Speaker 1: And it's like, and depending on the tile, you might want like a water cooled like table saw, right?
Speaker 0: It's like, I'm not buying like a circular power saw just to cut a few tiles and then never need it again.
Speaker 0: Also, that's a really dangerous tool that I don't have a lot of experience.
Speaker 1: That's actually the last thing I wanted to get into.
Speaker 1: Cause one thing I've realized is that like, even talking to you now, I've realized that I have weirdly like, I know a lot about power tools.
Speaker 1: I'm very comfortable using them, but I know that most people our age are not in America.
Speaker 0: Like, I mean, even in the shop classes that I took, well, I think you, you know, you're also mostly hanging out with people who don't work in, you know, industries and fields.
Speaker 0: Yeah, true.
Speaker 1: Like my, my, my circles are very much like people on Twitter.
Speaker 1: Your friends are not like construction workers and plumbers and things, but I grew up where my dad part, like I did a lot of roofing as a kid.
Speaker 1: cause my dad did a lot of roofing to help support the family.
Speaker 1: Like families working three jobs across two parents to keep us going.
Speaker 1: And as a result, like my, like everyone in my family was like very well versed in power tools, like the entire extended family.
Speaker 1: Everybody knew how to use power tools and it was assumed that everyone taught their kids how to use power tools at a very young age.
Speaker 1: I was learning like table saw safety.
Speaker 1: Like I'm talking when I was like eight and I know that is not everyone's experience.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: But I mean, you know, even the tools I did learn to use, like in shop class, we used like table saws and right.
Speaker 0: It's like you go to the hardware stores.
Speaker 0: Like there's a bunch of other tools there that were not taught in class and were not used for any like home kind of projects.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: But I guess it's like I would watch people on TV, use them like Norm Abrams or whatever.
Speaker 1: I watch all those shows as a kid too.
Speaker 0: Although it's like I chose, like I always saw him using like his router to like, you know, make edges around the, you know, piece of wood when he was making furniture and, you know, he'd like, uh, you know, do all kinds of fancy stuff.
Speaker 0: I've heard it's been so long, right?
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Um, but it's like, you know, I saw all those tools, but I didn't know anyone who owned any of those tools because who did?
Speaker 0: I know there was a furniture maker and no one was going to teach me how to use them.
Speaker 0: I can learn from YouTube now, but I'm already like 30 something years old.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: It's like, you know, and I just go to the store and even got out of jail until he was like 45.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 0: It's like going to go buy something I don't know how to use.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Is dangerous.
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 1: Well, that's the thing that
Speaker 0: the YouTube
Speaker 1: era maybe will fix things a little bit, but one thing that always struck me when I encountered people, like when I was a kid, especially, and I encountered people like in that shop class, the powered, like there's a certain class of power tool, like a dremel or like just a drill, like a drill.
Speaker 1: You just go to Home Depot and buy if you don't know better, not like a pneumatic drill or anything where it's pretty obvious how to use them.
Speaker 1: And the dangers in them are also pretty obvious, but most power tools, I think the difficulty with them for most people is that the dangers are not obvious.
Speaker 1: Like there's obvious, like you look at a table saw and you can imagine the dangers looking at it.
Speaker 1: Like you can imagine all the ways you can touch the sharp spinning part, but people don't imagine like they don't know how to use it safely.
Speaker 1: And there's a lot of non obvious dangers to these tools.
Speaker 1: Like if you leave the Chuck in a drill press, like the thing that you use to tighten the drill bit on and you spin that drill press, that Chuck will fly like a bullet and could kill someone.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I think the most the most dangerous thing that the thing I'm scared of the most is the lathes, right?
Speaker 0: It's like a laser.
Speaker 1: It's only scary because you're right next to it and you can't wear gloves because you really got to have that fine control.
Speaker 1: You've got to be confident in your abilities.
Speaker 0: There is this thing that is spinning really fast and it's like, oh, it's just like maybe you're making a table leg, right?
Speaker 0: It's like or maybe it's a metal.
Speaker 0: It could be a metal lathe too.
Speaker 1: But I mean, I prefer CNC lathes because while I was very comfortable working with lathes, that was a younger rim who was more reckless.
Speaker 1: I don't know if rim today wants to just like be working up close with a high like a high speed, powerful.
Speaker 0: It's like, OK, so there's like a thing spinning really fast and it's like you poke it with tools to, you know, grind away and around evenly.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: But hey, it's like, well, what if you're wearing like, you know, you know, wouldn't even think about it.
Speaker 0: It's like your hoodie has some strings coming out.
Speaker 1: Oh, I think about that.
Speaker 1: That was a big part of my childhood.
Speaker 1: tutelage and power tools.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: It's like one of the strings from your hoodie goes down into the lathe a little bit while you're leaning over it, gets wrapped around and basically was going to pull your head and smash it.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 1: Don't lean over the lathe.
Speaker 1: Make sure the lathe is high enough where you can work from the side, like it's right.
Speaker 1: There's this whole concept because it's an industrial stuff, too, of any power tool has like safe lanes and dangerous lanes.
Speaker 1: Like imagine like planes or rays radiating out from the tool where there is more danger than other places.
Speaker 1: You could shake hands with danger, shake hands with danger.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 0: But yeah, it's like, you know, I think that's the fundamental thing is you have a power to the chat.
Speaker 1: It's just like, you know, my expertise and even I maintain a healthy fear.
Speaker 1: slash respect for lathes.
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 0: The lathe is super dangerous.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Well, rotational injuries are the scariest injuries.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: Crushing is like a number three on that list.
Speaker 1: Don't Google some of the other ways you can get hurt with power tools.
Speaker 0: When you gain efficiency.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Since I'm used to working with computers.
Speaker 0: Efficiency gains with computers.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: If you use more powerful tools.
Speaker 0: and this is like, you know, a famous writing by Neil Stevenson, the whole hog, where he compares the Unix operating system to this drill made by the Milwaukee Tool Company, the whole hog, which is just a ridiculously powerful drill that is not for normal people.
Speaker 0: I don't.
Speaker 0: I've heard they maybe don't make it anymore or the current model isn't as strong as the old model or something like that.
Speaker 0: Regardless, where it's like, yeah, look, the operating system is more powerful, but also you can mess up because it's more powerful and there's less, you know, mechanisms, safety mechanisms and restraints on it.
Speaker 0: You could end up deleting all your files by accident and you're just screwed.
Speaker 1: Like if you set the torque settings wrong on a fancy drill and you try to like screw a drywall screw in, you might just go and put a huge hole in your wall and destroy everything.
Speaker 0: But the difference with the power tools is the danger is irreparable harm to human bodies.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 1: Or you're probably like, oops, I knocked down this wall in my house.
Speaker 0: Unless you're working on medical devices or something like that or, you know, aerospace software or something of that nature.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Messing up is just going to hurt data or maybe cost someone money.
Speaker 0: It's not going to do well.
Speaker 1: You know, there is a confluence between the two where there is still harm.
Speaker 1: Medical equipment.
Speaker 0: I said that 25.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I said that already.
Speaker 1: I think there's more instances of that than people realize though.
Speaker 0: There's probably a lot.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 1: I mean, cars, like every car has a lot of computers in it doing stuff.
Speaker 0: That's the thing is like a car is a power tool.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: You know, yeah.
Speaker 1: I mean, lawnmower is even listed in Wikipedia as a power tool because I've used a non-powered lawnmower before.
Speaker 1: It sucks.
Speaker 1: I used it once.
Speaker 0: It sucks ass.
Speaker 1: I'll qualify.
Speaker 1: It's great.
Speaker 0: And I was mowing a very, very tiny.
Speaker 1: It's really, really great as long as you maintain it and keep the blade sharp.
Speaker 1: Sharpening the blade is not worth the effort.
Speaker 0: I used one to mow a very, very tiny New York City lawn, like the tiniest.
Speaker 0: And it still sucked.
Speaker 0: Oh, my grandparents had one.
Speaker 1: It was great.
Speaker 1: You could mow a jack.
Speaker 1: We had like an acre lawn.
Speaker 1: You could just mow it.
Speaker 1: It was fine.
Speaker 1: But you had to sharpen that shit every time you used it.
Speaker 1: That took longer than mowing the lawn.
Speaker 0: It was not.
Speaker 1: I think yours just wasn't sharp.
Speaker 0: It was very sharp.
Speaker 1: I don't think it was sharp.
Speaker 1: If it was sharp and well made, like manual mowers are really, really easy to use.
Speaker 0: Just pushing it.
Speaker 0: It was just so heavy to push.
Speaker 1: Oh, that might just be a Scott problem.
Speaker 0: I was pushing it.
Speaker 1: Of course, as a kid, I had a mower that I used.
Speaker 1: sometimes that was sort of powered, it would kind of pull itself along.
Speaker 0: Oh, we didn't have that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we had that.
Speaker 1: That was real nice.
Speaker 1: Except sometimes it would pull a little too far and I'd have to mess with it to not let it go into the sidewalk or go where I didn't want it to go.
Speaker 1: It was not super safe either.
Speaker 0: We just had normal old school style, but gas powered ones where you'd push it.
Speaker 0: But eventually we just stopped mowing the lawn and paid someone to come and mow it with a giant commercial mower.
Speaker 0: It's like, oh, that's easier.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: And then I never had a lawn again.
Speaker 1: But I think in terms of like a lot of people in the US in particular over time, I think there is less exposure to power tools for a lot of reasons for people.
Speaker 1: And I don't know if that's necessarily a bad thing.
Speaker 1: No, I mean, it's like, you don't need to use power tools unless you have a use case for power tools.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: It's a good thing they exist for and they keep developing and improving upon them for increased safety and efficiency.
Speaker 0: It's like, imagine if everything was still made with handheld tools.
Speaker 0: We wouldn't have anything.
Speaker 1: Or imagine like early power tools, you know how they were powered?
Speaker 1: There were giant rotating wheels and pulleys in the ceiling and you would basically put a rope or a belt over one of those things down and then wrap it around the tool you're going to use.
Speaker 1: And it's just spinning next to you and spinning in the ceiling while you're working.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: Stuff like that.
Speaker 1: And pneumatic power tools, like they're way good.
Speaker 1: But also, if you fuck up with a compressor, it'll kill you and everyone in the room.
Speaker 0: Or hydraulic as well.
Speaker 0: Very dangerous.
Speaker 1: Or like a lot of early power tools weren't grounded.
Speaker 1: Just get electrocuted by the drill.
Speaker 0: Oh, I guess that could happen too.
Speaker 1: Double insulation was not a thing in a lot of early power tools.
Speaker 0: You know, I mean, really all power tools, when you think about it, are the modern ones, right?
Speaker 0: Are just motors attached to a thing, right?
Speaker 0: It's just, okay, so we have electricity, we're converting the electrical force into mechanical force.
Speaker 0: Either rotational or linear.
Speaker 0: And then we're putting a normal old tool on the end of the motor, right?
Speaker 0: It's like, okay, we converted electricity into spinning and now...
Speaker 1: Oh no, that's going even better.
Speaker 1: We're taking that power and giving it a user experience.
Speaker 1: Like a way to guide it to do something.
Speaker 0: You know, it's like, okay, we have a spinning motor.
Speaker 0: We'll put a saw on it.
Speaker 0: We got a spinning motor.
Speaker 0: We'll put a drill bit on it, right?
Speaker 0: We'll have a spinning motor.
Speaker 0: Okay, we'll put some gears to make it into something linear, you know.
Speaker 1: But I guess in terms of like practical advice to the people listening to this show, what I would say is, there's a certain low tier of power tool that everyone should probably have and be able to use.
Speaker 0: Like friend.
Speaker 1: Oh my god, a dremel and like one real handheld drill.
Speaker 0: And the soldering iron, which I guess is a power tool, even though that uses heat and not mechanical energy.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but I guess there also isn't really a free power equivalent of that.
Speaker 1: What are you soldering before?
Speaker 1: you had a soldering iron?
Speaker 1: How are you doing that?
Speaker 0: You just welded.
Speaker 1: Yeah, how are you well?
Speaker 1: Well, yeah, welding is a whole different topic we're not talking about.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: How did they connect wires to vacuum tubes back in the day?
Speaker 1: Solder existed then.
Speaker 0: Solder must have existed.
Speaker 1: So did soldering irons.
Speaker 1: Electricity has been around for a long time.
Speaker 0: When did it not exist?
Speaker 1: And using electricity to make metal hot has existed for as long as humans have harnessed electricity.
Speaker 0: I suppose so.
Speaker 1: But basically, other than that low tier stuff, don't buy a power tool unless you understand it and understand why you need it and what it will do for you compared to a much safer non-power alternative.
Speaker 1: If you can answer all those questions, you're good to go.
Speaker 0: I'd also make sure it's something you're going to use frequently.
Speaker 1: More than once?
Speaker 0: You could, well, you could rent a power tool, of course.
Speaker 0: That's a good idea.
Speaker 1: I have many times in my life rented power tools.
Speaker 1: But like that's just a thing.
Speaker 0: If you're only going to use it a few times, it's like doing it by hand is still, even if, you know, even if it would have saved you like two hours on two jobs, right?
Speaker 0: If you're never going to use it again, you're better off just, okay, just spend the two hours, use your handheld, whatever.
Speaker 1: This has been Geek Nights with Rim and Scott.
Speaker 1: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design, and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at frontrowcrew.com for show notes, discussion news, and more.
Speaker 1: Remember, Geek Nights is not one but four different shows.
Speaker 1: SciTech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays, and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 0: Geek Nights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 0: Geek Nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 0: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.
Speaker 1: And the Patreon patrons for this episode of Geek Nights are Alan Joyce, Heidi McNichol, Mardi Grania, Just Like a Dude, Guy, Jart Abhishan, Graham Finch, You Hold the Key to My Heart, She Gave Me a Kiss and She Gave Me My Ticket, Clinton Walton, Jay Banch, Ren from New Zealand, Ryan Parham, Nicholas Brando, Chris Midkiff, The Thirst for Hydrated Ganon, Dread, Lily Tenebrae, Chris Reimer, Finn, Sean Klein, Shervin Van Horl, and a whole bunch of people who do not want me to say their names.
Speaker 1: Uh, yeah, it's real hot, and it's gonna get hotter.
Speaker 1: But now, I'm gonna leave you with something that I hope you don't remember.
Speaker 0: Welcome to Larry King Live.
Speaker 1: How do you explain Tim Allen?
Speaker 1: Oh, Phil Collins is.