Speaker 1: It's Thursday, September 24th, 2020.
Speaker 1: I'm Rym.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott.
Speaker 1: And this is Geek Nights Tonight.
Speaker 1: Continuing our trend, we're talking about werewolves.
Speaker 0: Let's do this!
Speaker 1: Considering we just interviewed Epi about the wolf spell RPG, we also just reviewed wolf walkers.
Speaker 1: We've talked a lot about wolves recently.
Speaker 1: I mean Beastars and BNA.
Speaker 1: both have a hot wolf as a main character.
Speaker 1: It's a weird time.
Speaker 1: I feel like we should talk about wolves.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well it's also almost October, the Geek Nights birthday of Halloween.
Speaker 0: So I see no reason not to start doing some monster episodes.
Speaker 0: Let's get that werewolf action.
Speaker 1: Especially because in the old days, we would talk a lot about and follow Monster Madness.
Speaker 1: But I'm kind of sick of the individual who did Monster Madness.
Speaker 1: And even if he's doing more Monster Madness, I kind of just don't watch his stuff anymore.
Speaker 0: No, that was too long ago.
Speaker 0: That was another life.
Speaker 1: That was definitely another life.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: I think the moment where that life ended was when we went to the screening of his movie.
Speaker 1: Not that the movie was bad, the movie was great.
Speaker 0: We're talking about the EDM.
Speaker 0: You think the movie was great?
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 1: For what it was, it was pretty great.
Speaker 1: Like, I enjoyed the movie.
Speaker 0: It was alright.
Speaker 0: I don't think it was great.
Speaker 1: You know what?
Speaker 1: I'm glad we went and saw it in a theater in the matter that we did.
Speaker 1: However, I do not ever want to interact with the people who are in that audience with us ever again in my life.
Speaker 0: No, I do not.
Speaker 1: To quote a Rick and Marty line when he's being booed by a crowd, "I relish your boos.
Speaker 1: I know what makes you
Speaker 1: cheer.".
Speaker 1: So yeah, I got some news.
Speaker 1: We try to avoid talking about this stuff on tech days, but check this out.
Speaker 1: Facebook, if you weren't aware, is currently in a lot of trouble with the European Union.
Speaker 1: Mostly around privacy issues and data security issues and data transfers over national borders and all that kind of stuff.
Speaker 0: What really the core of the issue is that Facebook collects data on Facebook users, European people, people living in the EU, and then that data is moved from the EU over to Facebook servers in the United States.
Speaker 0: So there is now a database in the United States, US computers, that have an enormous amount of data about European Union citizens that is outside the jurisdiction of the European Union.
Speaker 0: So the EU is like, "Hey, if we pass laws or regulations regarding the handling of data about EU citizens, that server over there is going to escape our laws and that's not cool.
Speaker 0: You're exporting this data and we can prevent you from exporting it because we're a
Speaker 0: government."
Speaker 0: A legitimate government.
Speaker 1: And there's a lot of stuff going on in this space.
Speaker 1: Like Facebook has, if you aren't aware, a history of misusing, abusing, not securing data.
Speaker 1: It's a big problem.
Speaker 1: That's a big part of how the 2016 election went the way it went.
Speaker 1: So Facebook is in trouble with Europe and there's a bunch of lawsuits going on, but the story, which was from the 22nd, two days ago, was that Facebook warned Europe, basically they threatened them, it's almost extortion, "If Europe doesn't back down on these rules, Facebook will just stop working in
Speaker 1: Europe.".
Speaker 0: Alright, go for it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, bring it.
Speaker 1: That is exactly, if I was the European regulator, my first response would be,
Speaker 1: "Wow.".
Speaker 0: It was that easy to get rid of Facebook in Europe?
Speaker 0: Wow, that's fantastic.
Speaker 1: Make them comply with minimal privacy regulations and they're gone?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I wish, oh man, if you had told me it was that easy to get rid of Facebook for a whole multi-country zone, I'd be like, "Yes, that's
Speaker 0: great.".
Speaker 1: So the story that just broke yesterday, so one day later, was that Facebook at least denies that it will pull out of Europe over this issue.
Speaker 1: But if you read into the article, that's partly because Facebook, I don't know if their bluff got called or what, but they're still trying to sue and avoid these regulations coming at them, and they're arguing that Ireland is treating them unfairly.
Speaker 1: This is one of those situations that doesn't mean much yet, but depending on how this progresses, there are really three possible outcomes, two of which are really good for us.
Speaker 1: Either Facebook pulls out of Europe and is no longer a problem in Europe, which will basically really impact Facebook's ability to continue to make money and exist in the US in the long term, probably.
Speaker 1: Two, the compliment to that, Facebook actually gets kicked out of the European Union, or gets fined such that they pull out of the European Union to avoid paying those fines, that could go down.
Speaker 1: Or three, the other way it could go, Facebook complies with Europe's data transfer and privacy rules, which means Facebook is much less of a threat to the world.
Speaker 0: So,
Speaker 1: the only bad outcome would be if the European Union caves and lets Facebook continue to do the things that it does, and doesn't actually force this issue to come to a head, I get the impression the EU is more than willing to drag this out and drag Facebook down.
Speaker 0: There's also an interesting confluence here, where I believe this to be true, the last time I read about it, which was admittedly a while ago, so this could be wrong, but people use Ireland, big companies use Ireland to avoid taxes, but also, I believe that in the EU, they decided to task Ireland with enforcing the GDPR and other tech things.
Speaker 0: It's like the EU is a whole bunch of countries, so they're like, "Okay, we made these regulations.
Speaker 0: Ireland, it's your job to enforce them.
Speaker 0: We're going to give this one for
Speaker 0: you.".
Speaker 0: So, the same country that's enforcing the regulations is also this tax haven.
Speaker 0: There's a conflict of interest there, but that goes both ways, too.
Speaker 0: It's like Ireland wants companies to funnel their money through them, but they also have the power to pull some, if it's a tech company especially, they got some power over them, so there's stuff going on there.
Speaker 0: If you are interested in that angle, Google it.
Speaker 0: Instead of listening to things I said that were probably wrong.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but I can link to these two articles at least, and you can follow this one thread that hopefully will have some consequences for Facebook, and we'll see how things go.
Speaker 1: In a more pressing, I guess, do you have any news?
Speaker 0: Is there any news going on these days?
Speaker 1: I mean, other than the coup attempt, other than the Supreme Court no longer being a legitimate body, all that stuff.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't know.
Speaker 0: It hasn't been a legitimate body for a while.
Speaker 1: I think it finally tipped fully over the abyss now.
Speaker 1: Considering they already picked a date for voting on confirming the nominee, despite the nominee not actually yet being even named.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we'll see about that.
Speaker 1: Well, there's no way to stop it.
Speaker 0: There is.
Speaker 1: Well, there's no procedural way to stop it.
Speaker 1: There's no legal way to stop it.
Speaker 0: Maybe.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't know.
Speaker 0: All the news is, like you said, too big to discuss.
Speaker 1: For two white guy podcasters to talk about it.
Speaker 0: In a Thursday section, right?
Speaker 0: It's like, I don't know, what small thing has happened?
Speaker 0: It's like there's new game consoles.
Speaker 0: Who cares, right?
Speaker 0: There's a PlayStation whatever, and an Xbox whatever, and there's a new Nvidia card, which is basically the same as a new PC console.
Speaker 0: And Nintendo's going to have a new Switch next year, even though that's not officially announced yet, right?
Speaker 0: I guess the story there that's common to all those things is, you know, people trying to buy a thing, right?
Speaker 1: Oh yeah, I gave up trying to buy the thing I want to buy.
Speaker 0: I think a lot of people trying to buy the thing don't need it.
Speaker 0: A lot of people trying to buy it are trying to scalp it.
Speaker 1: What's fascinating though is that the one that they all bought, the 380 that everyone's buying.
Speaker 0: I said thing because it applies to the PlayStations also, or the Xboxes, right?
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: But really, why don't any of these companies just institute a queuing system where you put it in order, they'll take as many orders as they can get.
Speaker 0: Imagine Newegg has a million people who want something.
Speaker 0: Okay, we'll take a million orders, and then they start getting stock in, right?
Speaker 0: And they say, okay, well, every time we get a shipment, it's about 200 of them or something, right?
Speaker 0: And then when they think a shipment's coming, they email the next 200, 300 people, they're saying, hey, if you don't cancel, we're going to charge your card, right?
Speaker 0: As soon as we get one for you.
Speaker 1: On one hand, there's no good reason for them not to do this.
Speaker 1: It's like an obvious feature.
Speaker 0: And you would get more orders on your site instead of people going to--.
Speaker 0: There's a bunch of sites that are sites you would never buy something from, right?
Speaker 0: If you could just buy everything from Newegg, you would.
Speaker 0: But people end up buying from some shady eBay place or some other place because-- I have never bought something on purpose from eBay directly because I've never trusted it.
Speaker 0: People are going in like Best Buys and waiting in line and paying too much.
Speaker 0: And it's like people would rather just go to Newegg.
Speaker 0: If Newegg had this queuing system, they would take orders and fill them that other places are getting.
Speaker 0: Those other places would be severely damaged.
Speaker 1: So I think I can explain why no one implements this feature.
Speaker 1: They won't make any more money because they'll sell the same number of the thing.
Speaker 0: No, you won't.
Speaker 0: There will be people who would, you know, to avoid the effort of having to F5, right, would just place their order on Newegg and just wait rather than F5 and have to trust some shady site where they end up buying it from.
Speaker 1: Those same people will just come back to Newegg like a year later and buy the thing.
Speaker 0: Maybe, maybe not.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: Also, they don't have that many to sell.
Speaker 1: Basically, I'm confident that building out all that infrastructure, like making a queuing system, just wouldn't be worth the effort.
Speaker 1: There wouldn't be any actual return for them because there wouldn't actually really be more of that thing.
Speaker 1: And also, the people who would actually queue, because remember, most people wouldn't even engage with a system like that.
Speaker 1: The people like me who would queue, as soon as I see one for sale anywhere, I'm getting out of that queue.
Speaker 0: But you have to be right, but you have to actually succeed at buying it elsewhere.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: But also, if I can't get it, there's a certain time range beyond which I don't even want it anymore.
Speaker 1: Like at 3080, I want it because it would be a long-term investment for my pipelines.
Speaker 1: If it takes a year for there to be in stock enough for me to get one, a year from now, other video cards are already on the horizon.
Speaker 0: Oh, you're getting that queue.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but that queue doesn't exist because, again, it's the same problem.
Speaker 0: You could say, "Hey, if you're still in the 3080 queue and a 4080 comes out, you're at the start of the 4080
Speaker 0: queue.".
Speaker 1: You know what you could do?
Speaker 1: You could make a website that the whole service is, "We will queue four things for
Speaker 1: you.".
Speaker 0: I mean, I think people did that.
Speaker 1: There are a ton of those.
Speaker 1: I'm actually in some discords that run bots that queue you to try to buy things.
Speaker 1: And you know what happened?
Speaker 1: When the 3080s went on sale, there were a bunch of posts in there right away that said, "Here are all the
Speaker 1: queues.".
Speaker 1: And then they never would post an update unless someone actually got one.
Speaker 1: And there was never a post since then because no one got one.
Speaker 0: I think it's, you know, Nvidia considers, you know, their line, at least, is like, "Hey...".
Speaker 0: You know, I mean, the PlayStation, Xbox, they have no line, right?
Speaker 0: It's like, yeah, that's a consumer product.
Speaker 0: They should make enough for the demand, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, and they're gonna.
Speaker 0: They just suck.
Speaker 0: They will eventually.
Speaker 0: Nvidia, their line is like, "Hey, we didn't really expect normal people to need this ridiculous thing, right?
Speaker 0: It's only for... It's so powerful.
Speaker 0: Gamers don't need this.
Speaker 0: We didn't think we would need to make that many before we went on sale because...".
Speaker 1: Yeah, they thought they could, like, make more later and, like, people will be operating over time.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they're like, "How many people in the world actually need this
Speaker 0: thing?".
Speaker 0: And they think a small number because... So that's when they start selling.
Speaker 0: If they thought that all gamers would need a 3080, they would have made more before they went on sale with them.
Speaker 1: And the coins, like, people aren't mining coins with this shit like they used to.
Speaker 1: I think I know why there's all this extra man.
Speaker 1: One is the AI stuff in it.
Speaker 1: Like, you could do AI stuff with these chips.
Speaker 1: Kind of like in the early days when KUDAs started appearing.
Speaker 1: And you could, like, write code that would run on that KUDA system, all those cores.
Speaker 0: I think it's also just been the right amount of time since, you know, the previous cards.
Speaker 0: And people are stuck at home playing games more.
Speaker 0: True.
Speaker 1: I mean, I'm running a 1080, which I've had for a while.
Speaker 0: The timing of the release is coming up.
Speaker 0: You know, September is a great time to release a new expensive product.
Speaker 0: You know, because it's back to school time and then it becomes holiday time.
Speaker 0: That's why iPods and iPhones are always September, October, right?
Speaker 1: The two things that seem to be driving that demand for this particular video card seems to be the thing you said.
Speaker 1: But the two other things are, one, a lot more people have 4K monitors now.
Speaker 1: That's true.
Speaker 1: And the video cards they have, a lot of video cards can't actually drive anything at 4K at a reasonable frame rate.
Speaker 0: I mean, I have a 1070.
Speaker 0: It can do 4K.
Speaker 0: Sure.
Speaker 1: Yeah, 1070 is a already, like, relatively expensive card.
Speaker 1: Because remember, that was expensive when it came out and it didn't ever get cheaper.
Speaker 0: Old cards are not- It's not any cheaper than it used to be.
Speaker 1: It costs about the same as what a 3080 would cost new, except for the scalpers.
Speaker 0: But isn't the 3080, like, significantly faster?
Speaker 1: Yeah, because old video cards don't get cheaper.
Speaker 1: They just disappear.
Speaker 0: But the new one is the same price as the-.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there's a lot of reasons for that.
Speaker 1: But the other thing that's going on is actually VR.
Speaker 1: Because the 3080 is necessary to drive high-end headsets fully.
Speaker 1: No video card up to this point that consumers would have could fully realize the high-end headsets.
Speaker 1: So, very high resolution and very high frame rate.
Speaker 1: So, people who have a Valve Index actually, like, really want this card.
Speaker 1: I suspect that is a big chunk of the extra people trying to buy it as soon as possible.
Speaker 1: Because VR is another thing that had a little uptick because people are stuck at home all the time.
Speaker 0: That's true.
Speaker 1: Like, there's more people in VRChat now than I, like, ever saw ever before COVID.
Speaker 1: And VRChat didn't get better.
Speaker 1: Like, there's not much new in there.
Speaker 1: In fact, parts of it got worse to accommodate all these new people coming in.
Speaker 1: Like, now I go to any public space, there's a million people, it's crowded.
Speaker 1: I gotta, like, go hide and make private spaces to get away from these mobs.
Speaker 1: But anyway, in some topical news to the fact that the world's on fire and there's crises.
Speaker 0: This news is- there's a trend, but the trend in this- I just had an image of us, like, sitting at a desk podcasting in, like, an open field with, like, zombies walking around.
Speaker 1: And we're like, "So yeah, the zombie apocalypse is
Speaker 1: coming.".
Speaker 1: And there's a military helicopter flying by and we're just sitting at a desk podcasting, like, in the middle of the- We're just like, "Guys, like, at the end of the show, like, make sure you go take out some zombies, like, to help us out.
Speaker 1: We really gotta deal with these
Speaker 1: zombies.".
Speaker 0: But anyway- So, I was biking to work today and man, you know, usually, you know how you shoot a zombie or two on the way to work.
Speaker 1: Oh, you know, I always tried to, but I was outta- I ran outta ammo.
Speaker 0: I got, like, this perf- I got this perfect headshot.
Speaker 0: The zombie was riding a fixie, so I really wanted to take that one out.
Speaker 1: Now, I just imagined that scene of, "Oh, you shot zombies.
Speaker 1: Splanders.
Speaker 1: He was a
Speaker 1: zombie?".
Speaker 1: So, this is one of those stories that is so laughable and yet, at the same time, 100% real and happens a lot.
Speaker 1: The moral of this news is very simple.
Speaker 1: Cops lie.
Speaker 1: Like, cops just lie.
Speaker 1: Police officers, especially in the United States, will just lie.
Speaker 1: They lie in court.
Speaker 1: They lie to you.
Speaker 1: If a cop ever says, like, "Hey, you got any
Speaker 1: weed?"
Speaker 1: Just like, "Just give it to me.
Speaker 1: I'll throw it away.
Speaker 1: No harm, no
Speaker 1: foul.".
Speaker 1: No, they're gonna arrest you as soon as you pull that weed out.
Speaker 0: What are you gonna tell me next?
Speaker 0: I don't- I can't believe that.
Speaker 0: You gonna tell me next, what, bricks are red?
Speaker 1: There are non-red bricks.
Speaker 1: So, this story is about a police officer.
Speaker 1: It's topical because the police officer, the story was, early on, ambushed and shot.
Speaker 1: You can guess the context of being ambushed.
Speaker 1: He's a cop in Louisiana.
Speaker 1: You can imagine everything that happened there and why this is a problem.
Speaker 1: Black Lives Matter, fuck the police.
Speaker 1: Anyway, a further investigation, and apparently not even a very long investigation, determined that this officer was not, in fact, shot by an ambush.
Speaker 1: He was shot by a cop.
Speaker 1: In fact, he was shot by himself.
Speaker 1: He shot himself, and he covered it up by saying he was ambushed, and this was very easily determined to be a lie.
Speaker 1: He has now been released on Bond.
Speaker 1: Yeah, he was in custody, and you can read this story.
Speaker 1: The moral is, like, seriously, a cop will make up a story about being ambushed, rather than admit that they shot themselves by accident.
Speaker 1: The fact that they made up the ambush and lied, and the fact that they shot themselves, are both reasons why there should not be police like this.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: There's a reason why- Was that your thing of the day?
Speaker 1: No, it was just news.
Speaker 1: That was topical.
Speaker 0: Oh, okay.
Speaker 0: I thought we were done with news.
Speaker 1: But anyway, it's time for Things of the Day.
Speaker 1: So, check this out.
Speaker 1: I'm not into sneaker culture.
Speaker 1: Like, I could not give a shit, but I like striking shoes.
Speaker 1: Also, you can tell I've lived in New York long enough that I said sneaker, instead of tennis shoe, like almost all English-speaking people in America say.
Speaker 0: I've never not said sneaker.
Speaker 1: Yeah, because you've lived in the weird East Coast.
Speaker 0: Most Americans say tennis shoe to refer to- So, what did you think when the movie Sneakers came out?
Speaker 0: So, sneakers- You thought it was just about people sneaking?
Speaker 0: You didn't understand that it was a pun?
Speaker 1: In most of the country, people know that sneaker is a synonym for tennis shoes, but no one uses the word sneaker in most of the country.
Speaker 0: It's the only word I used.
Speaker 1: Yeah, most people in America will say tennis shoes to refer to any sports shoe, and in fact, I have literally been in conversations where someone said, "Oh, I need some tennis tennis
Speaker 1: shoes.".
Speaker 1: They'll even say tennis shoe like it's one word.
Speaker 1: But I found some really cool striking sneakers that I like enough to where I actually just bought them like right now, right before the show, before I talked about them.
Speaker 0: Are you gonna wear them?
Speaker 1: Yeah, someday when I get outside again.
Speaker 1: They are sneakers that have the aesthetic styling of a T120 VHS tape box.
Speaker 0: Are they actually comfortable or the right size?
Speaker 1: Well, they're the right size.
Speaker 1: I got the right one.
Speaker 1: But this is the kind of shoe that I would basically wear like when I'm going out of conventions or something or like me.
Speaker 1: I don't know where I'll wear it, but I don't have any shoes that look like anything.
Speaker 1: All the shoes I have are just running shoes or like the grayest, most generic-looking tennis shoes.
Speaker 0: Okay, I mean like, you know, something like that is something I would look at and say that's cool, but would not actually wear.
Speaker 1: Well, the thing is, remember, I've got that t-shirt that is just a Betamax like logo.
Speaker 0: Well, the t-shirt I think with that style is different than a shoe.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think this shoe, I'm kind of doubling down on my like 80s high-fi aesthetic.
Speaker 1: I actually got a bunch of shirts and stuff.
Speaker 0: There is plenty of clothing you can get with that aesthetic.
Speaker 1: Yup, and I am collecting more and more of it because someday I can go outside and wear clothes instead of just wearing a shirt and whatever and sitting in front of a camera all the time.
Speaker 0: A shirt and something.
Speaker 1: There's something down there.
Speaker 1: My bare ass is not touching my chair, usually.
Speaker 0: You laid a towel on the chair.
Speaker 1: I have, in fact, attended business meetings where I'm wearing a dress shirt on the top and there is just a towel at the bottom.
Speaker 1: The only pro move, the pro move is being so confident that you will not stand up by accident.
Speaker 1: So what do you got?
Speaker 0: So in other cop news, so here's a situation, I think, where was this, Ohio or something?
Speaker 0: I don't even know, it doesn't matter.
Speaker 0: There was some court and this gentleman was appearing in court to get sentenced.
Speaker 0: It's like, "Hey, you got a court appointment, come in, we're gonna, you know, tell you your
Speaker 0: sentence.".
Speaker 1: Yeah, but already guilty, like it's only bad news.
Speaker 0: Yeah, yeah, the dude was pretty much, I think his crime was he had some meth.
Speaker 0: He's a meth dude, right?
Speaker 1: Oh, okay, yeah.
Speaker 1: It's like, okay.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the person who needs help, not jail, but anyway.
Speaker 0: I think he got sentenced to six months, right?
Speaker 0: I guess prison/jail of some kind.
Speaker 1: Well, if you're thinking it is what I'm thinking, then he's gonna get a lot more than six months now.
Speaker 0: Maybe, but in this video, because of course, even a small courthouse in a, you know, place like that has cameras everywhere, right?
Speaker 0: You know, it has security, police, right?
Speaker 0: Deputies, bailiffs, et cetera.
Speaker 0: When they're bringing this gentleman through the courtroom after sentencing, the gentleman runs.
Speaker 0: And usually, you would expect this kind of video to end with like hilariousness as someone who foolishly runs fails to foolishly run.
Speaker 1: That's usually the case.
Speaker 0: Instead, this video is funny because the man successfully runs and the three Barney Fife's that let him get away, one of them does this.
Speaker 0: You'll see in the video, they dive, there's like a downward staircase and the dude, the running dude goes around the railing and down the stairs really fast.
Speaker 0: The cop behind him tries to like jump over the railing to like stop him, right?
Speaker 1: But he like dives head first like Superman.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and it's like, uh...
Speaker 1: He just slams straight into the wall, is clearly immediately unconscious and just slides down the stairs behind the guy.
Speaker 0: I don't think he's un- he's not doing well.
Speaker 1: He looked un- he hit, he literally dived head first at speed directly into a wall.
Speaker 1: You see his head hit the wall and he just falls and slides down, not moving.
Speaker 0: The point is, there's so much to tell in this ama- the video is the thing of the day.
Speaker 1: The video is pretty- like you can hear the yak and sacks.
Speaker 1: Amazing video, yes.
Speaker 0: So that's the wise thing of the day, but there's so many stories to tell here, right?
Speaker 0: Is six months in prison/jail really what a meth guy needs?
Speaker 1: No, they need to be in a hospital or like a treatment place.
Speaker 0: Right, it's like, you need something, right?
Speaker 0: This is not- this whole situation is bad, right?
Speaker 0: Why- what- like?
Speaker 0: the bailiff is basically like, you know, you can see like the deputies can kind of run except for the stupid Superman one.
Speaker 1: Oh, the bailiff can't really walk.
Speaker 0: The bailiff can't really walk and it's like, is that dude, you know, regardless of any other qualities, is that person qualified for that job?
Speaker 0: It's a physical job where you have to chase people, right?
Speaker 0: Right?
Speaker 1: So it's like- I've been in courtrooms where shenanigans happen and a bailiff had to put somebody on the floor.
Speaker 0: Right, exactly.
Speaker 0: You know, cops are, you know, all bad, right?
Speaker 0: And these ones are not only bad people, they're bad at their job.
Speaker 0: Yeah!
Speaker 1: Like, you watch the video and it's like, you know what, guy?
Speaker 1: Go, go for it.
Speaker 0: It's like, even if we're not gonna, you know, you haven't, you know, infringed upon anyone's rights or been racist to anyone or done anything like that, you cops are clearly all not qualified for your jobs.
Speaker 0: You let just some dude, a meth dude just run and they got away from you.
Speaker 0: You suck at this.
Speaker 0: Well, like, you know, we- If I fucked up that much at my job, I would be let go.
Speaker 1: You and I remember talking about this on Geek Nights back in like 2006 at length where we were like, most cops are so incompetent that we should have gun cops that are very special and most cops should not be gun cops.
Speaker 1: We should not let them have guns.
Speaker 0: These cops did not use their guns.
Speaker 0: They just tried to run and grab the guy, but they just failed and sucked at it.
Speaker 1: In relatively hilarious fashion.
Speaker 0: Yes, this is like, you couldn't film something better than this in like a Jackie Chan movie.
Speaker 1: So, in the meta moment, still at home, we were live at the Penny Arcade Expo.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna get the video on YouTube.
Speaker 1: We were live at the Crunchyroll Expo.
Speaker 1: I don't know if I have the rights to put that video on YouTube, but I'll figure out where you'll be able to watch it at some point.
Speaker 0: You don't need to, 'cause we've done that panel before.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we did a little more like, it was a better, like, timed, focused version of it, but it's not materially too much different from what we did at Henry Boston.
Speaker 0: We can always record it again if they're gonna be meh about it, right?
Speaker 0: Yep, yep.
Speaker 1: But, uh, we, uh, have a panel coming up at, uh, Meg West.
Speaker 1: That is a short and super fast version of a panel we've done before.
Speaker 1: And we're gonna be doing more online content, more videos, more stuff as time goes on.
Speaker 1: I spent all this time making that stupid pipeline to record these panels.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna use it.
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 0: Otherwise, hopefully- The book is still the tale of Genji.
Speaker 0: Perhaps.
Speaker 0: We'll read it sometime in the future.
Speaker 1: Maybe when it starts getting cold.
Speaker 1: I could see that being the time.
Speaker 0: Maybe.
Speaker 0: Is there anything else?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I'm riding the bike to nowhere, and one listener came to watch me ride a bike to nowhere.
Speaker 0: Which, it's really boring.
Speaker 0: I don't know why you would, but you can talk to me while I ride a bike to nowhere, which is nice.
Speaker 0: Nice for me.
Speaker 0: Someone to talk to?
Speaker 0: 'cause no one else is here right now, so.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: But just keep following us in all the places.
Speaker 1: 'cause we're doing stuff and we're gonna keep trying to do more stuff.
Speaker 1: Now that we've got, we're past all of our, like, convention panel deadlines.
Speaker 1: So now we got some time to back up into some other projects we're working on.
Speaker 1: So, yeah.
Speaker 1: Let's get right into it.
Speaker 1: It's coming up on October.
Speaker 1: It's not October yet.
Speaker 1: And a class of monster that we could discuss at length is the humble werewolf.
Speaker 0: So yeah, werewolves, I feel like, you know, you think about the classic Hollywood monsters of Halloween, right?
Speaker 0: You know, the vampire, the Frankenstein monster.
Speaker 1: You got the Dracula, the Frankenstein, the werewolf, the mummy.
Speaker 0: The mummy, right?
Speaker 0: And I feel like werewolf is always sort of like the weakest one.
Speaker 1: Well, it depends.
Speaker 1: I definitely noticed throughout my life in pop culture, not just movies, but pop culture in general.
Speaker 1: Like, what are people talking about?
Speaker 1: What do people dress up as?
Speaker 1: Among those four monster types, I guess witch, like, is up there too.
Speaker 1: There's, like, this ebb and flow of which ones are in season.
Speaker 1: Like, vampires will be really big for a while.
Speaker 1: But then people, like, really get into mummies for some reason.
Speaker 1: Mummies are big for a while.
Speaker 0: No, zombie, I guess, also counts.
Speaker 1: Yeah, zombies had, zombies were real big, like, in the early to mid-2000s.
Speaker 0: Yep, yep, yep.
Speaker 1: Like, when I was a kid, it was, like, Frankenstein's.
Speaker 1: Like, multiple kids dressed up as Frankenstein's monster, like, every year at Halloween.
Speaker 1: Like, that was just a thing.
Speaker 0: I just feel like werewolf always getting the short end of the stick, right?
Speaker 0: 'Cause it's, like, if you ever see any, think of any, like, media property where there's, you know, all of them combined, sort of, together.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: The werewolf is always sort of like the first guy, right?
Speaker 0: The lowest in the totem pole, the weak, the weak henchman, right?
Speaker 0: Yep, well, 'cause they usually just- The Dracula is usually the boss.
Speaker 1: 'Cause they're wearing, 'cause, let's be honest, in almost all media that's ever been made, especially live action, the werewolf costumes look like shit.
Speaker 0: That is a factor, I believe, yes.
Speaker 1: Like, they look like a person wearing a really shitty dog costume, like, 90% of the time.
Speaker 0: That's true, that's true.
Speaker 0: I think also, though, is that if you think about a lot of media portrayals of werewolf, right?
Speaker 0: Werewolf is rarely just this direct villain, like, werewolf coming to get ya, right?
Speaker 0: It's more that the illness of lycanthropy is the villain, right?
Speaker 0: And the actual person who is a werewolf is, like, more troubled and sort of a Kafka-esque metamorphosis similar to the fly.
Speaker 1: It's like a very low- It's not a bad- It's like on the low tier of body horror.
Speaker 0: Right, Incredible Hulk kind of situation, right?
Speaker 0: Where it's like, you're not some villain who just wants to go around hurting people, right?
Speaker 0: Like a Dracula who just wants to, you know, be evil, or, you know.
Speaker 0: Frankenstein's monster is also misunderstood, but, you know, a werewolf is not an evil.
Speaker 0: It's just like, oh, I've got a problem, I keep turning into a wolf.
Speaker 1: Well, well, it depends, because in Dungeons & Dragons, canonically, both werewolves and wolfwares are always chaotic evil.
Speaker 0: Okay, bad job, D&D, you messed it up.
Speaker 1: So I'm curious, 'cause we were talking about this before the show.
Speaker 1: Were you aware that in almost all D&D, there is a difference between a werewolf and a wolfware?
Speaker 0: I've never heard of a wolfware.
Speaker 0: In fact, if I Google for wolfware, it's like- You're gonna find the second- You're gonna find, like, clothing and apparel for a college whose team is the wolves.
Speaker 1: Type it all in one word.
Speaker 0: Oh, okay, let me try it.
Speaker 1: And you're gonna find the Forgotten Realms wiki that talks about wolfwares.
Speaker 0: Wolfware, NC State University.
Speaker 0: What the fuck, when I typed- Oh, you're spelling were all wrong, Scott.
Speaker 0: Oh.
Speaker 1: That's what's going on here.
Speaker 1: Type wolfware and spell it correctly.
Speaker 0: I didn't type- you would think that, oh, I did software, but there's also wolfware, W-E-A-R, and now I'm gonna find clothing and apparel, I bet.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: No, were is spelled W-E-R-E, it means man.
Speaker 0: Wolfware, Forgotten Realms.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: It looks like a sad wolf, dude, from- Yeah, so the deal with first ed, second ed, D&D was that werewolf and wolfware are both two different things, but they're both evil.
Speaker 1: Werewolves are humans who, because of lycanthropy, transform into wolves.
Speaker 1: Wolfwares are wolves who, because of reasons, turn into humanoid wolves.
Speaker 0: So they don't have the mind of a human.
Speaker 1: They have a mind of a wolf, but they can kind of turn into a man.
Speaker 0: So if there was a wolfware and a werewolf standing next to each other, you wouldn't be able to tell the difference.
Speaker 0: But one of them would transform back into a human, and the other would transform back into a wolf.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: And you wouldn't know which was which while you were just looking at it.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: So that's your D&D- so I bet there's plenty of people who played a D&D plot where it's like, our party member turned into a werewolf.
Speaker 0: Oh no, now we don't know which one is the werewolf and which is the wolfware.
Speaker 0: We don't want to kill our party member by accident, oh no.
Speaker 1: Where- I just can't believe you spelled a werewolf.
Speaker 1: That's really funny to me.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 1: What do I know?
Speaker 1: a wolfware from a werewolf?
Speaker 0: Software.
Speaker 1: But werewolves also, like, werewolf movies, the ones that were about werewolves, like you said, they always sort of had the exact same plot until relatively recently.
Speaker 1: At least all the ones I remember.
Speaker 1: But like, vampire movies were all over the place.
Speaker 1: There were like, this one's the good vampire, or there were, it's literally just Dracula, or Blackulas, or all the different ways they go with vampires.
Speaker 1: But werewolves are always just kind of, yep, it's almost always a dude turns into a werewolf and they have to kill, like, the werewolf that bit them to turn them back into a human.
Speaker 1: Happy ending.
Speaker 0: I think what it is, is, you know, there are comedic Frankenstein, right, you know, that's obvious.
Speaker 1: I mean the monsters.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: There's plenty of comedic vampire.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: But when you, you don't think, when you think of vampire, you don't think of, like, comedic vampire.
Speaker 1: Leslie Nielsen is a vampire.
Speaker 0: Right, you don't think of that first, right?
Speaker 0: When you think of Frankenstein, you don't think of young Frankenstein first.
Speaker 0: You think of that second, right?
Speaker 0: But when you think of werewolf, at least for me, I think of Teen Wolf, American Werewolf in London, like, those come first, right?
Speaker 0: I don't think of scary, anything with a scary werewolf that's coming to get you.
Speaker 0: that's evil and dark first, right?
Speaker 0: So I think that contributes to the reputation of, you know, werewolf not being, you know, the sort of, you know, head honcho of scary monsters.
Speaker 1: Yeah, which I think part of it too, like, it comes back to movies.
Speaker 1: The movies, the costumes for the werewolves usually were not, like, you couldn't really emote or act too much in them.
Speaker 1: Like Dracula can just dress fancy and actually act.
Speaker 1: Frankenstein's monster can stand there and act, like, pretty directly.
Speaker 1: Mummy is a simple costume.
Speaker 1: Like, it probably doesn't get in your way that much, but a werewolf costume is always all this, like, weird, ugly prosthesis and big mouth stuff that probably can't move that well for talking and looks weird when they talk.
Speaker 0: Especially in older movies.
Speaker 0: Newer movies, not a problem.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: But you can do your acting when you're not in wolf form.
Speaker 0: It's just once you become a wolf that you have the problem of not being able to act, right?
Speaker 0: So you, it's the human character that you're sort of identifying with when you're in the story, right?
Speaker 0: Because, you know, and then once it becomes a wolf, it's just like, it doesn't even talk, really.
Speaker 1: I remember as a kid, I always wanted, like, a movie that was, like, about cool werewolves, but there really, like, weren't any.
Speaker 1: At least not any.
Speaker 0: You would definitely have to go, you would have to go down the furry road where when you werewolfed, you could still talk, right?
Speaker 0: And I don't think that happens too often.
Speaker 0: Usually the werewolf is just, like, more of a beast, right?
Speaker 0: That just bites and attacks.
Speaker 1: So I did pull up this list, this Rotten Tomatoes thing of the 25 werewolf movies to watch, and I'm curious to see if we've actually seen all these, like...
Speaker 0: We probably haven't seen that many.
Speaker 0: I mean, Frankenstein meets the Wolfman, I've seen.
Speaker 0: Because, honestly, werewolf movies aren't really that great.
Speaker 0: I mean, if you look at these Rotten Tomatoes, most of them are...
Speaker 1: The Curse of the Werewolf is all the way up at 50 in 1961.
Speaker 1: Oh, shit, I think I have seen this movie.
Speaker 1: I've seen Curse of the Werewolf.
Speaker 0: There are some of these that I've seen and don't remember a single thing about, right?
Speaker 0: So, like, yeah, I've seen Werewolf of London, what do I know about it?
Speaker 0: I can't remember, I have to watch it again, right?
Speaker 1: You know, people always say that one.
Speaker 0: I've seen Teen Wolf, I barely remember anything from it.
Speaker 0: I remember Teen Wolf pretty well.
Speaker 0: We saw Underworld in the movie theater, I remember nothing other than it was dark and gothy, right?
Speaker 0: I didn't remember that it had werewolves, I thought it was vampire-y.
Speaker 1: Did I see that?
Speaker 1: I still am not, I don't remember if I saw Underworld or not.
Speaker 0: I think we did in the theater, or maybe we saw... I don't remember what we saw.
Speaker 1: I don't know if we've seen it, based on this...
Speaker 0: We might have seen Dracula 2000 and thought it was Underworld.
Speaker 1: That is plausible.
Speaker 0: Or Dracula 20-something, it was Dracula something.
Speaker 1: Well, it's not Transylvania 6 5000.
Speaker 0: I think it was Dracula... I think we either saw Dracula 2000 or Underworld in the theater, and I remember nothing about either one of those.
Speaker 1: But I guess, Werewolf of London is like, everyone always points to it like, "Oh yeah, that's a classic werewolf
Speaker 1: movie.".
Speaker 1: But I'll be honest, that movie's not that good.
Speaker 0: I mean, it's not bad, but it's obviously not good enough to be memorable, because all I remember about it is that I saw it.
Speaker 1: American Werewolf in London, because Werewolves of London is the song.
Speaker 1: But, did you ever see the sequel, American Werewolf in Paris?
Speaker 0: Well, I think there's also the movie that's on this list, which is just Werewolf of London, from 1935.
Speaker 1: I've never actually seen that one.
Speaker 0: Oh, okay.
Speaker 1: Wolfen... I think I've seen Wolfen.
Speaker 0: I've heard of Wolfen.
Speaker 1: I saw a lot of those.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think also, it seems like as far as, you know, as like cultural phenomenon go, right?
Speaker 0: It's like, there are people who are like into zombies, right?
Speaker 0: Zombies are like a thing, right?
Speaker 0: You go to the store, you can find plenty of zombie things, right?
Speaker 0: There's several zombie properties, right?
Speaker 0: You know, you got your Knights of the Living Deads, and anything of the deads, right?
Speaker 0: And you've got your... what's the other one?
Speaker 1: What, World War Z?
Speaker 0: No, that's one.
Speaker 0: The one that was a comic and then became a TV show.
Speaker 1: Walking Dead?
Speaker 0: Yeah, that one.
Speaker 1: What's going on?
Speaker 1: You don't remember your zombie properties?
Speaker 0: Vampires!
Speaker 0: Yeah, vampires, you got plenty of vampire properties going on, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, and vampires have had multiple reimaginings in recent history.
Speaker 0: You got your Anne Rises, you got your Vampire Hunter Ds, you got your Castlevanias, you got everything.
Speaker 1: Yeah, remember at the beginning of Vampire Hunter D, the girl is like, "Oh, so you're a vampire hunter.
Speaker 1: My father was a werewolf
Speaker 1: hunter.".
Speaker 1: And as a kid, much like Dammit Dwayne with the horses in your tenna, I remember as a kid, I was like, "Tell me about the werewolf hunters.
Speaker 1: Is there werewolf hunter D?
Speaker 1: Is there a movie I can watch that covers
Speaker 1: that?".
Speaker 1: Because I was in fourth grade, what the fuck did I know?
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 0: But when you think about werewolves, there aren't big werewolf properties that have continued.
Speaker 0: Not like a TV show, I can't think of any comic book, right?
Speaker 0: The werewolf is like a side character in another horror thing.
Speaker 0: I think there was a werewolf in what, that Twilight thing had a werewolf, right?
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 0: But it was like, yeah, wasn't that like?
Speaker 0: one was werewolf, one was vampire?
Speaker 1: Yeah, and the werewolves were weird and different.
Speaker 1: Which could be fine, I like reimagining monsters like that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, no, that's fine.
Speaker 1: But if you look at this list...
Speaker 0: But I'm saying it wasn't a werewolf continuing property thing, where there became werewolf fans who were interested in werewolf content all over the place.
Speaker 1: I think most of those people either became...
Speaker 0: Those were zombie fans, they just want everything zombie.
Speaker 1: I think most people who are werewolf fans just became furries.
Speaker 0: Uh, could be.
Speaker 1: Because I look at this movie list, the number one is the Wolfman, and number two is American Wolf in London.
Speaker 1: The Wolfman is like the archetypical, that is not a wolf, that is just a man wearing a dog costume.
Speaker 1: And it's got 90%, I remember the movie not being that great even as a kid.
Speaker 1: I guess the acting was good, but the movie was just not that great.
Speaker 1: And particularly, the werewolf transformation scenes were always extra shitty in these movies.
Speaker 0: Well, sometimes they were combination shitty, but also impressive at the same time, depending on the year it came out and the techniques that were used.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like a 40s movie gets a lot of a pass for like they were doing what they could.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 0: It's like simultaneously not good enough, but also like, "Oh, that's actually like the highlight of the film right
Speaker 0: there.".
Speaker 1: It's tricky though, because it's highlight of the film from its era, but also not good enough.
Speaker 1: But in the modern era, it just looks awful.
Speaker 1: Like it doesn't hold up.
Speaker 0: So the general, you know, the generic story of werewolf, right, is that somehow... This is the thing, is like despite werewolves being like this sort of, you know, second tier, second class monster, right, everyone knows how werewolves work.
Speaker 1: Yeah, just like you ask any random person like, "What's the deal with
Speaker 1: Spider-Man?"
Speaker 1: They know.
Speaker 1: Ask any random person, "How do you fight a
Speaker 1: werewolf?".
Speaker 1: They'll be like, "Yeah, Silver
Speaker 1: Bullet.".
Speaker 0: And I think that comes from the fact that even though there isn't like something focused all about werewolves, right?
Speaker 0: If you look at any other intellectual property, story, thing, any syndicated property, any ongoing thing, right?
Speaker 0: You're gonna find a werewolf episode, right?
Speaker 0: You'll find like, you know, I don't know if this is true or not.
Speaker 0: I'm just guessing, right?
Speaker 0: It's like I'm thinking of things that have a lot of episodes.
Speaker 1: Like Adventure Time has multiple werewolf episodes.
Speaker 0: Right, I'm sure that DuckTales probably has a werewolf episode.
Speaker 0: I'm sure that, what else has a lot... I'm sure there's some Looney Tune werewolf episodes somewhere.
Speaker 1: Is there a werewolf in JoJo's Bizarre Adventure?
Speaker 0: Maybe, I don't know, but it's like just think of anything that has a lot of episodes and there's probably a werewolf episode in there somewhere.
Speaker 1: Werewolf, JoJo's Bizarre Adventure.
Speaker 1: There is a werewolf episode in JoJo's Bizarre Adventure.
Speaker 0: There's probably Spider-Man fights a werewolf probably, you know, here or there, right?
Speaker 0: You know, it's like... Werewolf arc!
Speaker 0: Oh, okay.
Speaker 0: But yeah, that is why everyone knows about werewolf because it's like no matter what you're into, werewolf showed up at some point.
Speaker 0: Right, you know, and you know, it's like, yeah, if there's a full moon, the werewolves turn into a wolf uncontrollably.
Speaker 0: As soon as the sun comes back, as soon as the moon goes away, they turn back.
Speaker 0: If you get bitten by the werewolf, guess what?
Speaker 0: You're a werewolf now.
Speaker 0: And if you need to kill him with a silver bullet, otherwise you can just sort of, even if you chop him up, like I guess they heal like Wolverine or something.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and that varies from like story to story.
Speaker 1: Like in some cases...
Speaker 0: Obviously, even vampire rules vary as well.
Speaker 1: Those are the basics, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, like sometimes the werewolf is just a monster.
Speaker 1: Sometimes it's fully like cognizant of its situation.
Speaker 1: Though the latter is pretty rare and mostly more recent.
Speaker 0: Yep, yep, yep.
Speaker 0: But yeah, you know, and it's like, uh, werewolf... I don't know.
Speaker 0: What else is there to say about a werewolf?
Speaker 1: Media in general always annoyed me because the rules were like nothing ever changed between all the media.
Speaker 1: And there was never an interesting story.
Speaker 1: It was never.
Speaker 1: like someone becomes a werewolf and it fucking kicks ass.
Speaker 1: Let's go.
Speaker 1: But there are vampire movies.
Speaker 0: That's true.
Speaker 0: That's a good angle.
Speaker 1: That's literally what bothered me as a kid is that vampires, there could be awesome vampires.
Speaker 1: But werewolves were never awesome.
Speaker 1: They were just a disease that had to be cured by the end of the movie.
Speaker 1: I remember the movie, the werewolf media that I remember the most clearly, weirdly enough, is Stephen King's Silver Bullet.
Speaker 1: Pretty sure it's Gojo.
Speaker 1: You never did it, sir?
Speaker 0: No, I never heard of it.
Speaker 1: Really?
Speaker 1: I want to say it came out in the 80s.
Speaker 0: You know how many things Stephen King has made?
Speaker 1: I've read Stephen King's fantasy novels that are not even published under his own name, so...
Speaker 0: They're not Dark Tower or whatever?
Speaker 1: Well, so they may be in the Dark Tower universe, if you ask him.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 1: But there's lore about that, I guess.
Speaker 1: I don't like the Dark Towers.
Speaker 1: I didn't really care.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I've never read a Dark Tower, so I don't know.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but I've read some of his fantasy books that might be in the Dark Tower universe, but were published under a different name.
Speaker 1: And I did not know they were Stephen King at the time.
Speaker 1: So, in 1539, Martin Luther, like the Martin Luther, used the word "Beerwolf" to describe a hypothetical ruler worse than a tyrant who must be resisted.
Speaker 1: And there's a whole article here on "Beerwolves," which I'm trying to figure out.
Speaker 1: this etymology, because I don't actually know... My knowledge of the origin... I know the origin of werewolf stories, like Vlad Tepes, that kind of thing.
Speaker 1: But the origin of werewolves, I mostly just know vaguely Scandinavian stories about people getting bit by wolves going crazy, probably just rabies.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but...
Speaker 1: But I don't know any deeper than that.
Speaker 1: Like, I've never really...
Speaker 0: I don't know anything.
Speaker 1: Looked into the history of werewolf stuff.
Speaker 0: I don't know anything about it either.
Speaker 0: Why am I qualified to do this podcast about a thing I know nothing about?
Speaker 0: I'm just talking about what I do know.
Speaker 1: So where would you rank a werewolf then, compared to other monsters we might talk about?
Speaker 0: How are we ranking a werewolf, right?
Speaker 0: Are we ranking it in terms of how strong it is?
Speaker 1: Let's go by power level first.
Speaker 1: How powerful is a werewolf?
Speaker 0: Power level?
Speaker 1: Like, on average, how powerful is a werewolf compared to Frankenstein's monster?
Speaker 0: Well, if we're going with the fact that a werewolf, when it's not in wolf form, it's a person, so that's garbage, right?
Speaker 0: It's not even monster level.
Speaker 0: So when it's in monster form, it doesn't have human brain, it has wolf brain.
Speaker 0: Which is still dangerous, because a wolf is dangerous.
Speaker 0: You meet one in the woods... We're going with classic werewolf here.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: But, you know, that's obviously immediately losing to any monster that has human thought, like a vampire, right?
Speaker 0: It's like, no chance.
Speaker 0: Obviously, a real human with a gun beats a wolf, so a vampire could have a gun and just shoot the wolf.
Speaker 1: Gotta have a silver bullet, though.
Speaker 0: Yeah, a Frankenstein monster has slight human cognition, not as much as a vampire, but it's ridiculously strong.
Speaker 0: It could definitely beat a wolf in a fight, so I don't see a reason why it couldn't beat a werewolf in a fight, except it might not have a silver bullet available.
Speaker 0: That might be a disadvantage.
Speaker 0: So it's like, I think that fact that if we're going with the "you have to use a silver bullet to beat in a fight," then it can't lose to anything that isn't intelligent enough to use a silver bullet.
Speaker 1: Yup, it's a lot like in D&D, where you got a regular sword, and maybe you also have a silver sword.
Speaker 1: you carry around just in case.
Speaker 0: So even if there was a monster that was ten times stronger than the werewolf, right?
Speaker 0: Let's say a Sharknado or some shit.
Speaker 0: Sharknado doesn't know anything about silver bullets.
Speaker 1: A sharknado cannot come after you of its own volition, like a werewolf can.
Speaker 1: The shark in the Sharknado is not controlling the nado.
Speaker 0: There's some sort of Junji Ito-esque, you know, great white shark with legs that walks around on land, right?
Speaker 0: And it would just eviscerate the werewolf in terms of strength, right?
Speaker 0: It's just so dangerous.
Speaker 0: But the werewolf wouldn't be dead, and the shark can't use a gun, so the werewolf is gonna win eventually.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think about most media.
Speaker 1: I think about that's popular and known about werewolves, it's usually they beat the werewolf by tricking the werewolf.
Speaker 1: Because the werewolf is easily tricked.
Speaker 1: They lure it somewhere, and then they get it with the silver bullet.
Speaker 1: Like, they gotta plant it in advance.
Speaker 0: Can't you just walk up to it and shoot it?
Speaker 0: Why do you gotta lure it?
Speaker 1: I mean, where is it?
Speaker 1: Is it coming after you right now?
Speaker 1: Like, silver bullet, it's going around killing random people in the town.
Speaker 1: And this kid is trying to hunt it down.
Speaker 0: I see, I see.
Speaker 0: Yeah, yeah.
Speaker 0: That makes sense.
Speaker 1: We should watch Silver Bullet as a movie night.
Speaker 1: Do a show on it.
Speaker 1: It's a pretty good movie.
Speaker 1: 'Cause it's not, it's about the kid.
Speaker 0: It's more of a- It says 45% here on your Rotten Tomatoes list.
Speaker 1: Uh, Wikipedia says, an authoritative source, this film is considered a cult classic.
Speaker 0: Uh-huh.
Speaker 1: That's not always a positive- Also, it's got both young Corey Haim and a young Gary Busey.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: One of the Coreys?
Speaker 1: But, uh, the movie mostly focuses on, like, it's more of a kids on bikes movie.
Speaker 1: Like, that genre than it is a werewolf movie.
Speaker 1: It just happens to involve a werewolf is the villain the kids on bikes are going after.
Speaker 1: It's basically just like a long-form episode of Scooby-Doo.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean, that's, when I think of werewolves, Scooby-Doo is honestly the first thing I think of.
Speaker 0: Someone pretending to be a werewolf is a Scooby-Doo villain.
Speaker 1: Yep, I might, if I think, if I hear werewolf, the first thing I think is, like, D&D werewolf.
Speaker 1: And then number two is Scooby-Doo werewolf, then everything else is after that.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: And yeah, after that is, you know, comedy movie werewolf, right?
Speaker 0: Teen Wolf.
Speaker 1: But the Scooby-Doo werewolves were always, like, extra worthless.
Speaker 1: 'Cause they were, like, they were always, like, sadder than the regular old villains.
Speaker 1: 'Cause it is, of course, just like the old white guy in the end when they take the werewolf mask off.
Speaker 1: But, like, the werewolves in Scooby-Doo were never at any point threatening.
Speaker 1: Like, the pirate ghosts in Garfield were scarier than the werewolves in Scooby-Doo.
Speaker 0: I mean, I think werewolves in general aren't that threatening.
Speaker 1: Well, look, they can only come out in the, like, under the light of the full moon.
Speaker 1: So they can't really, like, they can't get you most of the time.
Speaker 0: They don't have any, like, magical sort of power to them, right?
Speaker 1: Other than their Wolverine power to turn into a werewolf and not, uh...
Speaker 0: It's, like, you could just sort of, like, lock your house and they can't get in.
Speaker 0: Just not, not even for the Dracula reasons.
Speaker 0: It's, like...
Speaker 1: They could just smash the door down.
Speaker 0: Sure, okay, but it's, like...
Speaker 1: They often do in movies.
Speaker 0: They're not creeping around the corner, like, you know, over in Alien, right?
Speaker 0: Alien is, like, way more dangerous than a werewolf.
Speaker 1: I mean, Alien is more dangerous than anything we're talking about right here.
Speaker 1: Ah!
Speaker 1: But what if a werewolf bit the alien?
Speaker 0: Oh, shit!
Speaker 0: 'Cause now you got an alien.
Speaker 0: It's gonna get its teeth through the exoskeleton.
Speaker 1: I don't know how deep you got a bite.
Speaker 1: That's never consistent.
Speaker 0: The Predator is way more dangerous than the werewolf.
Speaker 0: It's not even close.
Speaker 0: 'Cause the Predator can use a silver bullet.
Speaker 1: Yeah, Predator can hunt an alien.
Speaker 0: Predator probably...
Speaker 1: Predator is literally, like, "Well, I'm gonna go hunt a werewolf.
Speaker 1: Let me get my specialized werewolf hunting spaceship.
Speaker 1: Because that is my entire
Speaker 1: culture.".
Speaker 0: I think that's really... That is the thing, is that all of the... Even Frankenstein's monster, right, doesn't have any magical powers, right?
Speaker 0: But is still sort of supernatural in the fact that it is, like, not... It's, like, made of human body parts, like, resurrected.
Speaker 0: You know?
Speaker 0: But, yeah, even though the fact that the werewolf transforms is supernatural and it can't be killed without the bullet or whatever, the lack of supernatural power is no form of mist or... It's literally not that much more dangerous to you than an actual wolf.
Speaker 0: Just slightly larger and scarier, right?
Speaker 1: I guess the main difference would be that one thing in a lot of werewolf media...
Speaker 0: And wolves, regular wolves, have a pack.
Speaker 0: A pack of regular wolves is way scarier than one werewolf.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but what about movies where there's a pack of werewolves?
Speaker 0: That's scary.
Speaker 0: I think that's what you have to do if you're gonna do the scary werewolf movie, is you have to have a whole pack of them.
Speaker 1: That is the plot of American Werewolf in Paris, the sequel to American Werewolf in London.
Speaker 0: Oh, okay.
Speaker 1: But the plot is also that the people who are werewolves make a drug that they can use to turn themselves into werewolves whenever they want, and it's really, really stupid.
Speaker 1: They also set up a romance between the main dude and the girl.
Speaker 1: The girl's the werewolf, and he's trying to cure her of the werewolf, like the lycanthropy.
Speaker 1: But, spoilers, this movie fucking sucks.
Speaker 1: They set up this romance, and then they have the scene where, like, she transformed into a werewolf, and it is just super gross, and, like, just not... The romance feels weird the whole movie after that scene, because of how gross the transformation is.
Speaker 1: The movie is so dumb.
Speaker 1: Like, do not watch that movie under any circumstances.
Speaker 0: But I'm saying, just imagine a bunch of werewolves that move like a regular pack of wolves, right?
Speaker 0: And they have a villainous intent, a unified villainous intent, right?
Speaker 0: You know, I think that could be, that could work.
Speaker 1: Where I think werewolves work the best is actually in role-playing games.
Speaker 1: Like, that is where, like, if you're a game master, it doesn't even matter what the system is, werewolf is a similar type of plot to, like, body snatcher, in terms of, like, how you're gonna mess with your players, but werewolf just opens all these possibilities.
Speaker 1: Like, you may decide a character's a werewolf, and, like, stuff's happening at night, and the party's, like, trying to figure out who the murderer is, but one of the players is actually the murderer, 'cause it's a werewolf thing.
Speaker 1: I think I've literally played in that game two or three times in my life, playing D&D.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think that definitely works, because, you know, like I said, the werewolf is not a straight villain, and it's, most of the time, it's a normal person.
Speaker 0: So you're playing, you know, a character in some game, it's like, okay, we can, like, you can just tack werewolf on to whatever else you're doing, and it's not actually that disruptive to your, you know, your game.
Speaker 0: If you suddenly tack vampire on, or, you know, something else, that's, like, a huge deal, right?
Speaker 0: Can't go out in the sun.
Speaker 0: But vampire, basically.
Speaker 0: I'm a werewolf?
Speaker 0: Okay, that's like a modifier.
Speaker 0: It's almost like equipping an item, like, it's pretty low tier.
Speaker 1: Also, there's a role-playing game, so you can roll with it.
Speaker 1: Like, maybe the whole party's like, let's just be werewolves now.
Speaker 1: This is way better.
Speaker 1: I'm way stronger.
Speaker 0: We talked about that on Tuesday.
Speaker 0: Only that was regular wolf.
Speaker 1: I guess what it does is, it's, like, werewolf.
Speaker 1: stories in games tend to be more around the mystery of who is the werewolf.
Speaker 1: Where vampire movies aren't usually, who's Dracula?
Speaker 1: Like, Dracula's right there, how do we get him, is usually the plot.
Speaker 1: Or, how do we protect the person?
Speaker 1: he bit once before he comes back and finishes the job.
Speaker 1: But they tend to know who the vampire is in a lot of vampire stories, because nobody knows who the werewolf is, and that's the plot of most werewolf stories.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it'll just be night.
Speaker 0: Someone's getting bit, and it's like, well, it could be anyone that wasn't with me, right?
Speaker 0: And I think that's why we think about the game.
Speaker 0: Mafia, is also sometimes called werewolf, right?
Speaker 0: Because it's like, who is the one doing these murders, right?
Speaker 0: And it's like, mystery, who, we don't know.
Speaker 0: And even the person doing it might not know.
Speaker 1: That is the magic for a game.
Speaker 1: When the culprit is a player who does not know they're the culprit, that, in almost any system, will lead to really, really fun moments.
Speaker 0: But yeah, I guess that's all, I don't think anything else to say about werewolf, and I'm getting hungry.
Speaker 0: I'm sure there's people out there who know way, way, way, way more about werewolf than we do, so you should talk to them.
Speaker 1: Yeah, or wolfwares, if you want to talk about wolfwares.
Speaker 0: We're just trying to make an entertaining podcast, and you know, keep up our streak routine here.
Speaker 1: We stayed awake, 'cause like, vampires, I think we both have a lot more to say.
Speaker 1: I think I could talk about vampires a lot longer than I talk about werewolves.
Speaker 0: Partly due to the lack-- I've actually read Dracula, the book.
Speaker 1: I think partly, it's like you said, it's due to the relative lack of good and compelling werewolf stories that aren't the archetypical werewolf story.
Speaker 0: Like, we need a lot, we need more-- The werewolf is always an episode of something else.
Speaker 0: There's never the ongoing werewolf thing.
Speaker 0: It's very rare.
Speaker 1: We need the deconstructed werewolf story, just like we got deconstructed magical girl, deconstructed vampire.
Speaker 1: We need really good deconstructed werewolf that isn't just their furries.
Speaker 0: I feel like there's definitely been plenty of attempts, but none of them have obviously hit it big.
Speaker 0: So.
Speaker 1: So, last thing before you go, one thing.
Speaker 1: So, the game Werewolf in Mafia, I did play that Among Us game.
Speaker 1: It's set in space, nothing to do with werewolves, but it's the same game.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: It solves a fundamental problem of Werewolf in Mafia.
Speaker 1: The Mafia, in this case the imposter, has to get away with their shit for real, live, and do stuff.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I know.
Speaker 0: I've seen the game.
Speaker 1: I've played it with our friends.
Speaker 1: It's actually really good.
Speaker 1: You should play it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I know.
Speaker 0: I've seen-- I was basically, you know, just following my Steam policy of, even though it's five bucks, my policy is don't buy the Steam game unless you're about to play it right this second.
Speaker 0: That's a good move.
Speaker 1: I bought it because I played it right that moment.
Speaker 0: Yeah, as soon as I'm about to play it right this moment, someone's like, "Hey, let's play it right
Speaker 0: now.".
Speaker 0: I'm like, "Okay, five bucks, let's
Speaker 0: play.".
Speaker 0: But I just haven't because that moment has not come yet.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I saw what kind of game it was.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Oh, and so last, we got a-- I saw a funny clip on Twitter where a dude walks in a room, sees another dude, and sees some legs.
Speaker 0: With no torso on them and a bone sticking out with some blood spurting.
Speaker 0: And then they leave the room, and then immediately the game stops, and it's like, "Who is the whatever
Speaker 0: imposter?".
Speaker 0: And it's like the person who was in the same room with the legs.
Speaker 1: So the deal is you can't communicate during the game until-- But that person knew who it was.
Speaker 0: Exactly.
Speaker 1: Until a meeting is called.
Speaker 1: The only way to call a meeting is to find a dead body and do a thing to report it, or run all the way back to the cafeteria in the middle of the map and hit a button.
Speaker 1: So if you witness a murder, the murderer might chase you down before you get to that button.
Speaker 0: Yeah, maybe.
Speaker 0: That's very "They Were
Speaker 0: Eleven.".
Speaker 1: It is very "They Were
Speaker 1: Eleven.".
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So that lets you eat.
Speaker 1: We have a question from the stream.
Speaker 1: I think we can answer pretty quickly.
Speaker 1: How do you feel about the werewolf story in Skyrim?
Speaker 0: I played Skyrim.
Speaker 0: I beat that game, and I do not remember any werewolf action.
Speaker 0: Ah.
Speaker 0: So that tells you how much-- Or it tells you the way I play Skyrim, because I've also played Oblivion and beat-- Those are the only two old scrolls.
Speaker 0: It was Oblivion and Skyrim, and I beat both.
Speaker 0: And I remember... not much.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I was trying to think back to Skyrim.
Speaker 1: I was like, "Where were the
Speaker 1: werewolves?".
Speaker 1: I didn't beat Skyrim.
Speaker 1: I gave up.
Speaker 1: I got like ten hours in, and I just kind of--.
Speaker 0: I remember the start where I had to punch a dragon.
Speaker 0: I remember climbing up a mountain where there was like a yeti.
Speaker 0: And I remember yelling to knock bad guys down and then stab them with my sword.
Speaker 1: Did you get all three fus ro da, or are you just like fussing?
Speaker 0: No, yeah.
Speaker 0: I got the whole thing.
Speaker 0: I beat the whole game.
Speaker 0: And then I remember at the end of the game, you went up this big mountain where there was a really big dragon, and then you beat him.
Speaker 0: And then there was--.
Speaker 0: Oh, you also went to this hall of like-- You went to Viking heaven, basically.
Speaker 0: A Norse-ish heaven place.
Speaker 0: And you saw all the great champions there.
Speaker 0: And then after that, you beat the boss, or before.
Speaker 0: That's basically all I remember from Skyrim.
Speaker 1: Ah, you know what else we really need here?
Speaker 1: We need more non-wolf werethings to make these stories interesting, too.
Speaker 1: Give me some werebears.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: I also remember from Skyrim, there was some sort of ancient, sort of a token-esque dwarven hold under the ground that had been abandoned.
Speaker 0: It was like a big factory kind of place.
Speaker 0: And I remember going down there and cleaning it out, and that's where all the good loots were.
Speaker 0: All right, thank you.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's what I remember from Skyrim.
Speaker 0: I don't remember any werewolves.
Speaker 0: I'm sure they're in there, but I remember them not.
Speaker 1: This has been Geek Nights with Rim and Scott.
Speaker 1: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design, and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at FrontRowCrew.com for show notes, discussion news, and more.
Speaker 1: Remember, Geek Nights is not one, but four different shows.
Speaker 1: Sci-Tech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays, and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 0: Geek Nights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 0: Geek Nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 0: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.
Speaker 1: And the Patreon patrons for this episode of Geek Nights are Alan Joyce, Heidi McNichol, Marty Green, you're just like a dude guy.
Speaker 1: Graham Finch, you hold the key to my heart.
Speaker 1: There was a dude, looked like a cop, standing there with my name out.
Speaker 1: Clinton Walton, Jay Bantz, Ren from New Zealand, Ryan Perrin, Nicholas Brandow, Chris Midkiff, Dread, Lily Tenebrae, Chris Reimer, Finn, and a bunch of people who do not want me to say their name.
Speaker 1: And Shervin Von Horl, because it short-sorted the list in a weird way.
Speaker 1: I'll never, at any point, edit whatever we do at the end of this show here.
Speaker 1: This stinger is always recorded in one take, no matter what happens.
Speaker 1: And I'll let you in on a secret.
Speaker 1: I usually don't know what the actual stinger is going to be until long after I've recorded this audio.
Speaker 1: So now, I leave you with something you've definitely forgotten.
Speaker 1: [singing in Japanese].