Speaker 1: It's Wednesday October 14th 2020.
Speaker 1: I'm rim Scott and this is geek nights tonight.
Speaker 1: We are talking about an anime.
Speaker 1: I am confident.
Speaker 1: None of you have actually watched extra olympia kick-a-loops.
Speaker 0: Let's do this All right, so check this out.
Speaker 0: This is ridiculous.
Speaker 0: thing happened right and it's not over yet.
Speaker 0: So there might be a follow-up which is good because we need opening bits, right?
Speaker 0: So I Pre-ordered something from CD Japan.
Speaker 0: if you don't know CD Japan is basically a website where you can buy Japanese, you know media physical medias, right around for a while.
Speaker 0: It's been around for a long time.
Speaker 0: I think I ordered the first time ever ordered something from there.
Speaker 0: I was in college.
Speaker 0: So they've been around for at least 15 20 years and it's it's.
Speaker 0: it's not a cheap website But it is very reliable and trustworthy and legit.
Speaker 0: They will send you real products right for the price you pay And they won't.
Speaker 0: you know, they they're your chart.
Speaker 0: you're paying full price, but you're not getting ripped off.
Speaker 0: So there you go free free advertising Japan.
Speaker 0: But there was like these Evangelion anniversary OS teas that I ordered a long time ago.
Speaker 0: I pre-ordered the many many moons in advance and my idea was you know It might be a little difficult to get digital versions of these right anywhere even piracy.
Speaker 0: So I'll be the one to rip them and then I'll sell it.
Speaker 0: a book off or something which I've done in the past with Japanese DVDs and CDs, you know You know buy them rip them cash them in right get you most of your money back.
Speaker 0: so What happened was I you know, as long as when you're living in New York Packages sometimes say they're delivered and they're not right sometimes.
Speaker 1: I've never had that happen in a deck sometimes.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean sometimes I've had the opposite where something was delivered, but I didn't order anything.
Speaker 0: Okay, sometimes it happens because it got delivered at the wrong address.
Speaker 0: Sometimes the market is delivered to like make Amazon happy that the thing was delivered on time and then actually deliver it the next day.
Speaker 0: Alright, so that Amazon's not like hey, this was delayed right gets mad at the post office.
Speaker 0: Sometimes, you know, it gets stolen.
Speaker 0: That's happens right if you have a doorman that doesn't happen as much.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so this package said it was delivered But my building didn't have it and the next-door building didn't have it and the next next-door building didn't have.
Speaker 1: ah That's the good check cuz that once a package got delivered to the other identical building next door.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: So, uh, I Finally go and this thing always happens to me Regardless of whether it's a missing package or a bug report for software or any crazy any problem in life.
Speaker 0: You know you reach that point where you're trying to solve it yourself.
Speaker 0: You can't solve it yourself and you end up Emailing somebody right to get the help.
Speaker 0: it's like well, I guess I got a contact customer service now and I shoot off the email and Immediately after shooting off the email I discover the problem happens every time.
Speaker 0: so it's happened.
Speaker 0: So and it's like Kevin.
Speaker 0: so it feels like it happens very very often to me.
Speaker 0: I send the email and then solve it and I wish I hadn't sent the email.
Speaker 0: but you can't pull email back.
Speaker 1: Yeah, anyway, in fact, I remember way back when we first moved into beacon you ordered that let the cunt the Leatherman Mm-hmm and didn't arrive.
Speaker 1: and then you said told Amazon there's like the early days of Amazon like I was buying stuff on it.
Speaker 1: You were like, hey I didn't get my Leatherman and they sent another one and it literally arrived the day you sent that email and we got two Leatherman's.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well, but it was horribly destroyed.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so that package definitely went through the ringer.
Speaker 0: anyway the point is that What happened to this package?
Speaker 0: Why?
Speaker 0: why was it not here?
Speaker 0: Why was it delivered?
Speaker 0: So it had been so long since I had used CD Japan That I didn't.
Speaker 0: I was I was careless and I didn't check the ad the shipping address or the billing address And usually you don't have to because they'll catch you and be like, hey, we're not delivering there.
Speaker 0: That doesn't match your credit card or whatever, but I didn't.
Speaker 0: they just sent.
Speaker 0: they just sent it.
Speaker 1: I know why the credit card is super lax on that.
Speaker 1: in the last they're getting.
Speaker 0: they used to be very strict And now they're very very lax.
Speaker 0: Yeah So Was it sent to my previous apartment?
Speaker 0: if that's the case I could have just biked over there You know walked over there and got in the package, right?
Speaker 0: Just rung the doorbell or whatever seen it there or you know contact the person who lives in that apartment.
Speaker 0: now No, it was not sent there.
Speaker 0: All right, where was it sent?
Speaker 0: Apparently the last time I ordered anything from CD Japan It was I was working at my previous job at Broadway calm.
Speaker 1: My company specifically disallows anyone having anything delivered to the office?
Speaker 0: My current company does but Broadway calm didn't and I wouldn't do it.
Speaker 0: I wouldn't abuse it and do it too often But I would do it for things like something from Japan that I don't want to get stolen right on my doorstep Right, so I did it occasionally.
Speaker 0: So that's the address they had on file and it got sent to the Broadway calm office.
Speaker 0: So I tried to call them and no one was there.
Speaker 1: Well, that actually makes sense.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I know that a Broadway is closed that I know a lot of people at that company have been furloughed because Broadway is closed And I know that I was just very very lucky in my timing of deciding to change jobs about two years ago.
Speaker 0: if I had Not done so I might be in trouble right now, right?
Speaker 0: So, yeah that package presumably is in that building somewhere.
Speaker 0: it could just be like Sitting on a desk or maybe no one's at the on the floor.
Speaker 0: Maybe it's at like the the door person at the bottom of the building has it.
Speaker 0: I don't know who has it over there got to do a high even let's break in and guy left.
Speaker 0: I left a voicemail right and no one got back to me.
Speaker 0: So I might have to like figure out who to email.
Speaker 0: I don't know who's still there to email even if I did email.
Speaker 0: so yeah It's it's gonna be interesting trying to get the package.
Speaker 0: Like if I just go and get it, it's gonna look like I'm going into a building and stealing a package.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know, it's interesting that who do you email problem?
Speaker 1: Cuz There's not a problem now like I'm pretty much set in my career But when I was trying to get a bigger job in my early days and I like applied to jobs they always wanted references from previous employers, but multiple of my previous employers had gone out of business Mmm, and a lot of these forms like required a phone number and an email address and an address and all this stuff
Speaker 0: For my real problem.
Speaker 0: Is that like?
Speaker 0: I go to the website and it's like the person I actually want to contact.
Speaker 0: It's like.
Speaker 0: yeah, usually they're keeping like CEOs email secret and stuff.
Speaker 0: It's like I want to contact the reception desk And it's hard to do that.
Speaker 0: Right, like the place I'm trying to contact is the place that they should be trying to make me contact instead of anyone else.
Speaker 0: I'm not trying to contact someone to like, you know ask for a job.
Speaker 0: Usually they're trying to sell anything.
Speaker 1: Yeah, usually they're trying to prevent you from like bothering Tim Apple or Steve Google Exactly.
Speaker 0: I'm not trying to do that.
Speaker 0: I want to talk to the reception desk where the package is.
Speaker 1: Didn't learn a trick a long time ago from a guy I was working with?
Speaker 1: he's that sales stuff, but he he would send emails to generic Common white dude name at company calm.
Speaker 1: because even if the company had naming conventions Usually old white dudes who work there had special exceptions and had emails like Steve at company calm And that usually worked and he actually got people to respond to him and it was a. it was something you can keep in the back of your head if you know that the CEO of a company is an old white dude, and you'll want to get in contact with that person and you know their first name.
Speaker 0: Yep, but the thing is usually that works at certain size companies, but when you get really big, right?
Speaker 1: if you know it goes to like the administrative assistant of Executive management group.
Speaker 0: right if you email like just me.
Speaker 0: if I send an email to like Jeff at amazon.com or Jeff visas at Amazon.com it goes to probably someone whose job it is to read that email box.
Speaker 0: Yep Well, it's probably.
Speaker 0: that's probably a job even when I worked at IBM.
Speaker 1: I had a shared secretary So no one could call me directly.
Speaker 1: they would call and someone would call me and say hey This person is trying to contact you.
Speaker 1: Do you want to talk to them or should I get rid of them?
Speaker 0: I would all the only time outside people try to contact me.
Speaker 0: Is there recruiters or They are a vendor that I have already worked with and has my email Like like, you know, it's like you start, you know manage like I'm managing like, you know Oz stuff.
Speaker 0: I'm at login into the Oz account.
Speaker 0: They have Oz has my email.
Speaker 0: So the Oz sales associate calls me and it's like hey, hey buy some more Oz.
Speaker 0: It's like not got enough Oz.
Speaker 0: I Know I know what I doing.
Speaker 1: so in some Minor news keepo and the age of wunderbeasts, which I've talked about multiple times.
Speaker 1: on the show I think I've geeked by did it several times because they had two seasons.
Speaker 1: The third and final season just hit Netflix like two days ago.
Speaker 1: So the sit that's what they wanted to do.
Speaker 1: That is the end of the show that it like.
Speaker 1: the show is complete.
Speaker 1: It is exactly what it was intended to be and I have not seen season 3 but based on our season 1 and season 2 when I'm very excited about season 3 that show is just a Solid stand-up kids show and I learned something.
Speaker 1: remember what I geeked by did it.
Speaker 1: I talked about how they had a character kind of just come out as gay like Not even a big deal like in the middle of a random episode.
Speaker 1: Apparently that was literally the first time that has ever happened explicitly on a animated show in America That was rated all ages.
Speaker 1: Okay, that is both good news and just really really sad news Like yeah great, but really in your 2020 Like they will.
Speaker 1: the late 2019 was when we hit that milestone.
Speaker 0: Well, okay, it's like that long.
Speaker 0: Yeah, some ways we're ahead and in some ways we are so behind.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: You got any other news?
Speaker 0: Yeah, just you know, I know we've talked in the past because we saw the first five minutes of it at Annecy that digital Annecy But the much-awaited CG Lupin the third movie known as Lupin the third Colon the first.
Speaker 1: I'm hoping they make Luton Lupin the third the first two.
Speaker 0: I hope so.
Speaker 0: But anyway, all for all intents and purposes appears to be a You know excellent execution of the Lupin formula.
Speaker 0: We're gonna know when we see the whole thing.
Speaker 0: It's going to be in theaters on the October 18th and 21st.
Speaker 0: I think we've discussed that recently.
Speaker 0: That's less than a week away.
Speaker 0: if theaters where you live or even open don't go.
Speaker 0: right We wouldn't.
Speaker 0: but our theaters are closed.
Speaker 0: we can't go.
Speaker 0: so if their decisions made for us they're open in New Jersey right.
Speaker 0: So my plan was of course just wait until it was available somehow digitally or you know Maybe even hope someone else gets a bure and rips it or get a bure rip it and sell it.
Speaker 0: a book off Right.
Speaker 0: But it has now been announced G kids is gonna put it on digital Which is the kind of did not the digital Netflix kind the kind where you go to Amazon or iTunes or somewhere like that or YouTube and Pay money to download it and then you can watch it as many times as you want.
Speaker 0: So it'll probably cost 15 bucks plus who knows That will be on December 15th and the boo rays and the guest steel book Which is just Booray in a fancy case is going to be those will be available on January 12.
Speaker 1: This deal book comes with an exclusive 18 by 24 inch lithograph.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean my days of buying.
Speaker 0: those were brief area out.
Speaker 0: In fact 15 plus years ago 100% of the lithographs I owned were Star Wars lithographs I think the only fancy I say.
Speaker 0: I bought a Trigon DVD that had a thing of some kind in it.
Speaker 0: I bought a Macross box set that had a thing in it.
Speaker 1: Oh, no, I bought those lithographs standalone.
Speaker 1: I paid like 20 bucks for these.
Speaker 0: talking about DVDs.
Speaker 0: I bought that had special stuff, right?
Speaker 0: So I think that had the.
Speaker 1: I had the eye of Vogler.
Speaker 1: that came with my job That's true.
Speaker 0: I had a Voltron the first season first season of Voltron and first season of Transformers.
Speaker 0: both had stuff in them.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and then Gundam seed, I guess I had a box that I slowly filled that had stuff.
Speaker 0: and those I guess the only DVDs I bought with stuff.
Speaker 0: Oh, right.
Speaker 1: You bought Gundam seed with the box that came with DVD one and then you filled the box with that.
Speaker 0: I filled it is yeah, and now that's all gone.
Speaker 0: I I have the D. I have the discs.
Speaker 0: I don't Wow.
Speaker 1: Remember when shows would come out like episode by episode or DVD by DVD?
Speaker 0: What a those those DVDs had four episodes on him, I think so they were not a bad deal.
Speaker 1: I mean, that was the old anime thing.
Speaker 1: You'd get a VHS or a DVD would have four episodes and they'd come out about once a month.
Speaker 1: See you basically had to either have the discipline to only watch one episode a week or you'd get that DVD.
Speaker 1: You'd watch all four episodes and they just say fuck cuz there's a cliffhanger and wait a month Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: Yeah, those are the only DVDs ever bought with special stuff and I'm surprised They still make those and that someone still buys.
Speaker 1: people love that stuff.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: Well, yeah, I love this movie.
Speaker 0: I hope like very likely.
Speaker 0: so we're gonna be doing an episode on it.
Speaker 0: You can expect the first Wednesday after December 15th that there is a geek nights episode.
Speaker 1: They're probably will be because we're probably.
Speaker 1: I mean, there is no way we're traveling for the holidays this year.
Speaker 0: It's if go I work.
Speaker 0: if my job does not Increase the amount of vacation days I can hold over to 2021 in which case in 2021 I'll be going on a mega vacation as soon as that is safe to do.
Speaker 0: If that does not happen, I have a lot of vacation days to use in December.
Speaker 0: I'll basically and I already have the final week of December off from Christmas to New Year's.
Speaker 0: anyway by default I will basically not be working most of December if they do not increase the numbers.
Speaker 0: So I will definitely be watching this movie on December 15th, which probably be a day that I won't be working.
Speaker 1: So some other news.
Speaker 1: if you're not familiar with this because it's in Queens It is there is a museum called the Museum of the moving image.
Speaker 0: This is really funny about this museum.
Speaker 0: So this is a museum that you know I went to once and then I would go to occasionally once or twice a year for like screenings of movies or whatever.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I always go for a screening or like a special exhibition.
Speaker 0: That's only special exhibition or someone's visiting or you're hanging out with a new person and you take them there because they haven't been there But you've been there, right?
Speaker 0: So, you know, it was always this situation where you know museums have memberships, right and The deal with the museum membership is that if you go enough or you attend enough of their events It ends up paying for itself.
Speaker 0: All right, yeah, and you get you get to cut the line and you you know You can just go to the museum for free.
Speaker 0: You don't have to pay tickets every time.
Speaker 1: It's the kind of thing you do especially like botanical gardens are good place.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah Exactly, exactly any sort of physical location, you know arts and educational Institution place right museums galleries that sort of thing.
Speaker 0: So like a special libraries, right?
Speaker 0: So I would calculate every year like how many times did I go cuz it's I can walk there It's super.
Speaker 0: I can city bike there in five to ten minutes.
Speaker 0: It's right.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you're way close to it even compared to us And it's a short walk.
Speaker 1: for us.
Speaker 0: It's pretty equidistant.
Speaker 0: It's like a triangular.
Speaker 1: Anyway, I think you're close up.
Speaker 0: Who knows Google.
Speaker 0: my point is while you're talking Okay, the point is I would calculate was the membership worth it?
Speaker 0: and it was always pretty borderline whether the membership was worth it, right?
Speaker 0: So this year I was like, I think last year I think the membership would have been worth it.
Speaker 0: the number of times I went.
Speaker 1: because I think oh, so you finally pulled the trigger.
Speaker 0: 2020 was the year the beginning of 2020.
Speaker 0: I got a membership and then I went to Paxie.
Speaker 0: That's definitely a shame Because 2019 the met it would have.
Speaker 1: if I would have been member at 2019 I would have saved money, but I we have seen some kind of amazing stuff at the museum over the years.
Speaker 1: It's a fantastic museum like give you example of what this place is like.
Speaker 1: it is one of the only places in New York that can actually Play like scream a nitrite trade print like those old film stocks Mmm, like it has a bunch of cool stuff like that.
Speaker 0: You can see everything there from a complete collection of Star Wars toys To actual models of.
Speaker 0: you know Those buildings and Blade Runner and the in the scenes where it's like showing you the cameras going over all these, you know The cyber city.
Speaker 0: right.
Speaker 0: they have the actual models that were filmed.
Speaker 0: They got all sorts of you know, ridiculous stuff there That is amazing and they screen movies and 70 millimeter regularly.
Speaker 0: Yeah You know, so
Speaker 1: what they are doing is they're not doing so hot because the kovat obviously and
Speaker 0: right the current Current exhibit was like a big 2001 exhibit because they show that movie a lot because they have a 70 millimeter print and people go to see it occasionally.
Speaker 0: They had the actual babby I saw.
Speaker 0: I went to the.
Speaker 0: we went to the exhibit before they closed it.
Speaker 0: But I mean they get before the museum closed.
Speaker 1: so they doing so hot.
Speaker 1: So they have a Kickstarter that just launched to help them fund a bunch of online stuff and get things going To try to bring as much of their content as they can to people during kovat and also kind of to help them survive Until post kovat.
Speaker 0: they have a lot of awesome stuff like that.
Speaker 0: You see the awesome stuff.
Speaker 0: That's on display there.
Speaker 0: They have a lot of awesome stuff.
Speaker 0: That is not on display.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like they preserve props from a bunch of famous movies, even if you can't go see them like they do Channel yeah, their YouTube channel will show you all kinds of good stuff.
Speaker 1: So, yep, so I.
Speaker 0: and they also have lots of amazing video game exhibits.
Speaker 0: because it's not like.
Speaker 0: it's not a movie museum it's a the.
Speaker 0: it's a the Moving image.
Speaker 0: So any moving image animation, right?
Speaker 0: They have a whole exist a little section there where they show you.
Speaker 0: there's like a Live.
Speaker 0: it's like basically a fake TV studio there.
Speaker 0: that shows you What it would look like if you were sitting in the tractor trailer outside the baseball stadium Controlling the broadcast for the baseball game.
Speaker 1: Yeah So they.
Speaker 1: so the rewards like are the reason.
Speaker 1: part of the reason I'm bringing this up Is that this museum is really important and it really needs to survive.
Speaker 0: The other reason I bring it up is that the real neighborhoods gonna be way crappier if it closes.
Speaker 1: The rewards are pretty interesting because they're trying to be clever with it.
Speaker 1: Like at one tier they give you like special zoom backgrounds and twitch emotes like they know the deal.
Speaker 1: The $20 tier is a bread baking demonstration with some famous people.
Speaker 1: Okay, like they're gonna basically have a limited number of people.
Speaker 1: like sit in the zoom call and like learn how to make bread with some fancy people Copies of some publications they put together.
Speaker 1: There's.
Speaker 1: it's a bunch of cool interesting stuff.
Speaker 1: But yeah if you care about moving images in any way like if you want to in the year 2060 be able to go to this place and see an exhibit on the rise of animated gifs This is the kind of museum that'll have that they already
Speaker 0: had a gif exhibit.
Speaker 0: They had the whole front.
Speaker 0: what when you walked in in the entranceway They basically were using projectors and there was some sort of installation thing that had like memes all the way down The front though because most of the walls in the museum and the main areas are white.
Speaker 0: So they're broadcasting this whole, you know meme gift type thing all over the front wall behind the The ticket booth, you know, I guess in front of the the ticket desks or whatever.
Speaker 1: Yep, the building is just cool to like.
Speaker 1: the stairways are disorienting like it's a. it's an interesting one.
Speaker 0: disorienting stairway.
Speaker 1: What is there?
Speaker 0: another stairway?
Speaker 0: there's the.
Speaker 0: I Mean the one you're gonna use.
Speaker 0: is that big white one?
Speaker 0: Yeah, there are.
Speaker 0: there are like yeah But there are like fire escape type ones behind the doors you can use.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, I guess they're just normal stairwells.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they're just normal stairs.
Speaker 0: They're not exciting like the disorienting stairway like don't they had the one.
Speaker 1: You'll see when you get if you've never been there when you finally get to this museum You'll see what I mean about that one stairway.
Speaker 0: It's just interesting like for example like a lot of like these quirky like indie video game Installations that I'll see at places like magfest.
Speaker 0: I'll then see at museum of the movie.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: All right All right.
Speaker 0: But anyway, I think of the day.
Speaker 0: what about my thing?
Speaker 1: is that wasn't my thing of the day that was just news.
Speaker 0: Oh, I thought that was.
Speaker 1: that pause was.
Speaker 1: so I can just slide the thing of the day thing right in there.
Speaker 1: Okay?
Speaker 1: but anyway things Of the day I decided arbitrarily.
Speaker 1: I'm only doing spooky things of the day for the rest of October.
Speaker 0: cuz I don't have enough spooky things of the day.
Speaker 1: Oh, that means I'm gonna have.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna have to force it.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna have to find spooky things.
Speaker 1: So, okay, my thing of the day is a 14-second tick-tock But it encapsulates my love of pranks following up from your skeleton prank one a couple days ago Very simple classic prank a prank that my uncle Performed on my mom when they were kids.
Speaker 1: to similar effect a prank that Parents and grandparents in my family have performed throughout the years.
Speaker 1: It's a very simple prank.
Speaker 1: The caption is my daughter's upstairs playing Ouija with her friends and it's obviously a dad and he's walking around like live streaming on his phone and tick-tock and he goes over to the circuit breaker and he goes up to The upstairs circuit breaker and he jiggles it a little bit and in the distance You hear a bunch of like six-year-old girls screaming and that's it.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: Okay What do you got?
Speaker 0: that's it that's alright.
Speaker 0: so, uh, I don't know, you know people are probably aware of this Especially people listening to a Wednesday geek nights, right?
Speaker 0: But you know Japan has a declining birth rate situation.
Speaker 0: Their population is getting older and their population is moving to cities and away from you know, rural places, right?
Speaker 0: So you watch a lot of anime or you watch Japanese media and you'll always see portrayals of like, you know seaside village or oceanside village or you know Stuff like that.
Speaker 0: and those places like a lot of them are going to like completely disappear as no one lives there anymore, right?
Speaker 0: I think I read somewhere like a large some what percentage it was they predicted for like the next x-years of just abandoned Japanese villages in rural places that like no one literally no one will live there anymore.
Speaker 1: I mean America.
Speaker 1: a similar revolution like there are a lot of ghost towns in the West sure.
Speaker 0: So another result of this is that of course there was a lot of infrastructure built that becomes abandoned.
Speaker 0: And of course one of the things that's gonna be abandoned when the birth rate declines is schools.
Speaker 0: You just don't need is met.
Speaker 0: you had a bunch of schools when you had a bunch of kids and now you don't have any kids.
Speaker 0: Anymore, it's like we don't need all these school buildings anymore.
Speaker 1: Yeah, because the room of golf is empty Right.
Speaker 0: So I've seen I've seen some people actually turn schools into like haunted attractions because you know school.
Speaker 0: Horror is a genre right, you know getting scared into school building, but here this video it's like a travel.
Speaker 0: it's like a travel log video on YouTube by this person Sherry why?
Speaker 0: and They're on this Japanese island and the island had a school that is now empty.
Speaker 0: I guess people are moving away from the island or the population is aging.
Speaker 0: It's you know an example of this happening for real and instead of being turned into some horror Situation right like an amusement park the old abandoned school on the Japanese island has been turned into a lovely cafe.
Speaker 0: So here's a lovely travelogue video at the abandoned school cafe and I hope we can see the malls of the United States end up like this and not end up like Who knows what?
Speaker 1: Alright in the meta moment.
Speaker 1: We're uh stuck at home still so I don't know what you want.
Speaker 1: We can't really do much except what we're already doing.
Speaker 1: But I did upload if you want to see the panel we gave at pecs online.
Speaker 1: I've uploaded a director's cut because there were very specific Rules and formatting for how I put together.
Speaker 1: the one we actually like did sound like pseudo live at pecs So that one they have a VOD in the middle of this like eight hour video you can watch But this is a standalone one edited and cut together the way we normally edit and cut together our panels.
Speaker 1: So you want to see our brand new talk?
Speaker 1: It's just on YouTube right now.
Speaker 1: You just click on it.
Speaker 1: It's there.
Speaker 1: That's it Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: I'll do this.
Speaker 1: All right Our other talks coming soon.
Speaker 0: The book club book is still technically the tale of Genji.
Speaker 1: I guess the last fiction I've read in my life is still some pages of the tale of Genji on the train home Sam's Same.
Speaker 0: if you don't count like, you know comics or whatever.
Speaker 0: Yeah, pretty much reading or nonfiction or something on the internet That was a lie.
Speaker 0: That would count as fiction.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, I guess that's true.
Speaker 1: I mean to half my Twitter timeline.
Speaker 1: Yeah But yeah, no cons whatever we don't.
Speaker 0: we don't got any more meta than that, you know what the deal is, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah type the word coming nice into you into Google or YouTube.
Speaker 1: in fact type the word geek nights into any text prompt you have and Something good will come of it something bad.
Speaker 0: If there's a place on the internet if there's an app you use you can find us on that app probably.
Speaker 0: so I mean if you Really need our help for that.
Speaker 0: You already found this podcast.
Speaker 1: In fact, if there is an app you use Where you think somehow us being on that app would work and enrich your life and we're not on that app I want to know what the fuck that app is and why you're using it Seriously.
Speaker 0: All right So here's we're looking.
Speaker 0: we're like we're on Monday and we're saying man we got into episode Wednesday We're gonna do it on.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: So we got a crunchy roll and I click on shows in the top left and I scroll down and I look at all the shows.
Speaker 1: Scott I are like look I start.
Speaker 0: well, I do what we do and I'm judging anime by its cover.
Speaker 0: I'm judging I'm just judge a judge and I'm like, nope.
Speaker 0: Nope.
Speaker 1: I wanted to watch decadence, but it's not on c-roll.
Speaker 1: So I'm gonna wait.
Speaker 0: I yeah, we have heard many people, you know It's getting to the point where I've heard several people say something's up with that decadence show.
Speaker 0: That's worth watching and now it's on my list.
Speaker 0: It's in the queue.
Speaker 0: So maybe if you're out there looking for a show to watch I can't tell you if it's good or not But I can tell you the word on the street is that decadence is a show worth watching.
Speaker 1: buzz about buzz is persisting.
Speaker 0: Yes, so that is not the show that we were talking about today.
Speaker 0: I scrolled down and I saw a very interesting Image because all you're seeing on the crunchyroll shows page is basically movie posters Right sample thumbnails for shows and it looked really fascinating.
Speaker 0: It looks somewhat vapor.
Speaker 1: when I was about to say when you said wrote you were like, oh look at this one.
Speaker 1: And I looked at it.
Speaker 1: My first thought was some kind of vaporwave anime.
Speaker 0: what right?
Speaker 0: It looked this poster looked with a vaporwave aesthetic.
Speaker 0: because you know, the the Statuesque, you know Greek bust is often used in vaporwave imagery.
Speaker 0: But no, it was actually about Greek stuff and also about like the Olympics.
Speaker 0: and I was like, oh is this like a promotional anime?
Speaker 0: For you know, the Japanese Tokyo Olympics that is somehow incorporating, you know, Greek stuff.
Speaker 0: but also the look of it gave me strong vibes of This sort of you know Yes, that's sort of gag manga B or E nonsense Japanese comedic style that we like a whole lot.
Speaker 0: So I'm like, well, how about?
Speaker 0: I said rim and I say rim look at this one and he's like, that's the one.
Speaker 0: We're doing a show on that.
Speaker 0: So here we are.
Speaker 0: We're gonna talk today about what's this thing called?
Speaker 1: It is called Oh God red extra olympia kikilos And it's a.
Speaker 0: it's one of those shows.
Speaker 0: the episodes are only five minutes.
Speaker 0: There are 21 episodes on crunchyroll as of this moment, but the Wikipedia says there are 24 episodes.
Speaker 0: I don't know if the remaining three are just not out yet or if they're just not on crunchyroll yet.
Speaker 0: And there's also a manga that it's based on.
Speaker 1: so the first thing I got to say is that like I actually want to read the description the official description of the show because To meet Rose was a young man in ancient Greece who was a potter's apprentice, but also rather timid otaku Despite pursuing the arts.
Speaker 1: He was blessed with natural athletic talents one day.
Speaker 1: He gets dragged into a village conflicts Yada yada yada.
Speaker 1: somehow he ends up in 1964 Tokyo.
Speaker 1: It sounds like a like a typical anime where there's gonna be some like pot going on.
Speaker 1: But then when you watch it, they're five minute long episodes.
Speaker 1: It's a combination of limited animation and stop-motion.
Speaker 0: This it's like claymation.
Speaker 1: I say five minutes.
Speaker 1: It is five minutes including the full-length opener and full-length closer.
Speaker 0: Yeah Everything that happens in ancient Greece is stop-motion claymation.
Speaker 0: the stuff that happens in modern Japan is the claymation Greek guy with 2d flat Japanese, you know, it's 60s.
Speaker 0: Japan is no modern Japan.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's 1964 Tokyo, right?
Speaker 1: Okay, Tokyo police, right?
Speaker 0: So Tokyo is 1964.
Speaker 0: Everything's flat and 2d.
Speaker 1: You know what?
Speaker 1: It looks like a lot.
Speaker 1: It really is reminiscent of the animation style of yamashibai Mmm, like.
Speaker 1: it's really unique like it's clearly 2d like when the old man like turns to look at Dimitrios.
Speaker 1: He's clearly a two-dimensional like piece of paper.
Speaker 0: Yep, I mean there was a seat as a scene.
Speaker 0: I don't think you saw this scene because I don't think you watch this many up.
Speaker 0: I only got up to episode 12.
Speaker 0: They're playing volleyball and they do a parody of.
Speaker 0: Is it?
Speaker 0: was it attack number one?
Speaker 0: is the Japanese right?
Speaker 0: Is that what it's called attack number one?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I didn't say number one is the volleyball anime.
Speaker 0: There's a very brief scene where they're parodying attack number one and all these basically thin You know.
Speaker 0: 2d.
Speaker 0: pictures of volleyball playing high school girls.
Speaker 0: There are strings you can see that are making them move up and down.
Speaker 1: Yeah right Yeah, you can even see strings when I throw in the beans at the school festival Like you see strings pulling the beans like up and down again.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: It is super low-budget, but I gotta say It's legit.
Speaker 1: This show is funny as shit.
Speaker 0: How could it not be?
Speaker 0: you could tell that and we knew that just from the time the gate.
Speaker 1: There are a lot of shows like this that end up not actually being that funny Like the jokes are really telegraphed or they move really slow Like I have seen short quirky looking shows like this that just aren't actually that good.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: What was the one?
Speaker 0: What was the one where the guy was an alien and was like just really really good at everything in life?
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, the prince whatever like he was the prince of the school.
Speaker 0: I forget I forget what it was called even though I watched the whole thing.
Speaker 1: only the first episode was funny And then it just to kind of petered out.
Speaker 0: Right, but then you have other ones like Cromartie, which just stay good the whole time.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: This is more like Cromartie.
Speaker 1: It is just yeah, if you think you see where it's going.
Speaker 1: It kind of just rolls past that it jumps all there.
Speaker 0: However, while while also while having that same sort of you know, Japanese humor style as Cromartie There is a contiguous plot that makes sense and they stick with it and follow on it.
Speaker 0: It's just that all of the interactions with that plot are these you know, ridiculous characters acting ridiculously.
Speaker 0: But the main, you know story and motivation.
Speaker 1: the mayor who's a piece of shit, right?
Speaker 0: There's a mayor in the town.
Speaker 0: They're in a they're in a poor ocean side village, right and the mayor wants money.
Speaker 0: And there's you know They want to hold an Olympic style event to make money because he heard other people are having Olympics.
Speaker 1: Why don't we have some Olympics Dimitri?
Speaker 1: That's all you suck at your job.
Speaker 0: make the Olympics happen instead Right, and there's all sorts of conflicts involving like Spartans who are way too strong and scary.
Speaker 1: really funny, right?
Speaker 0: There are the people who hold the actual Olympics right coming after them and you think oh, this is a show like that's sponsored somehow by the actual Olympics Like it's like no.
Speaker 0: No, it is not.
Speaker 0: This show is like basically calling out in several episodes like how you know The Olympics is tainted by sponsorship.
Speaker 0: The Olympic Committee is overbearing its intellectual property and strong arming people.
Speaker 0: It's also calling out ancient Greece.
Speaker 1: it like it has this whole bit where it's like the Olympics were great Except for women who weren't allowed to participate.
Speaker 1: yep, it's like Today I had to tell two different slaves what to do Exactly on the one hand.
Speaker 0: It's sort of under a punch-out esque, you know almost racist Exaggerated stereotypical depiction of ancient Greece, but also there's like these nuggets of truth Constantly bringing out right teaching you actual real things about ancient Greece.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like yeah, that was true That yeah.
Speaker 1: But I guess why it's so funny is like the.
Speaker 1: the weird art style kind of just fits and you just roll with it Like you don't even notice it.
Speaker 1: after we watch a couple episodes Like it just it works, but the jokes are actually they're not only real like legit funny But they're pretty dark and often extremely
Speaker 0: mean
Speaker 1: Like the characters are mostly jerks to each other except the old guy who is weirdly patient with his naked Greek man It keeps popping into his house.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well, that's the thing.
Speaker 0: I think that's the the.
Speaker 0: that's if every single character in ancient Greece except maybe Apollonia, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah is sort of ridiculous in some way.
Speaker 0: the 1964 Japan is like the straight man.
Speaker 0: It's like instead of having you know, the comedy where there's you know The the the straight man and the not straight person right here.
Speaker 0: You have the you know, the funny man, whatever.
Speaker 0: right here You've got the ancient Greece is the funny man.
Speaker 0: It's two different settings and 1960s Japan is the not funny, right?
Speaker 0: Everyone there has common sense, right?
Speaker 1: Oh, I guess we're speaking ancient Greek.
Speaker 1: So I guess you're from Greece.
Speaker 1: All right, whatever Do you want to come to the school festival?
Speaker 0: Right, you know everyone in Japan even the kid is just like oh, you're my baseball card.
Speaker 0: Go ahead, right?
Speaker 0: They're just acting like normal people.
Speaker 0: They're not weird in any way and they're they're very tolerant of.
Speaker 0: you know The one visitor from the ancient times but like like an example of the mean humor.
Speaker 1: so the Demetrios his job is to paint vases and Like just paint, you know, they're that typically for us.
Speaker 1: and in for is in hydras Greek vase filled with stuff and he got those paintings on the side and Demetrios sucks at it Like he is famously bad at this.
Speaker 0: Well, I mean he's bad at it and that he's not doing it in the way that you see in museums, right?
Speaker 0: He's doing.
Speaker 0: it's actually like I couldn't draw like that.
Speaker 0: It's actually a really good drawing but it's an intentionally silly and out of style and out of character drawing for the side of a Greek vase and that's why it's
Speaker 1: so you get to the future and the old man has one of his vases that like survived through the ages like thousands of years and He's like, oh my art.
Speaker 1: Ah, and the guy's like it's shit, but it was painted 2400 years ago.
Speaker 1: It's honestly so shitty that I hate leaving something so shitty out But it is valuable and he's just like crying the whole time.
Speaker 1: There's a lot of dick jokes too Like oh, yeah a lot of dick jokes.
Speaker 0: So my favorite joke is actually the recurring joke.
Speaker 0: The opener to this show is the same every time it's the same.
Speaker 1: I skipped a William tell overture while they have done stop-motion animation with Greek plates, basically, right?
Speaker 0: So basically I was after the first few times seeing it.
Speaker 0: just to save time and get through the show faster I would skip the exact.
Speaker 0: it's exactly 30 seconds long.
Speaker 0: So I just skipped to the 32nd mark, but the closer to the show It's a god you re closer.
Speaker 0: It is different.
Speaker 0: every single time There is this character who's like, you know someone so so and so Greek name the bard And it's this clay dude with a lute I guess or a harp or you know, whatever.
Speaker 0: something like that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, something like that.
Speaker 0: And he sings a completely different song.
Speaker 0: that is a completely different topic right?
Speaker 0: and that song teaches you something kind of or Or at least a sardonic take on something Right.
Speaker 0: or it's like the song always has like you have to watch the full closer The closer is telling you something that might.
Speaker 0: that's usually relevant to the episode You just watched or about to watch or about ancient Greece or something and they sing a whole song.
Speaker 0: That's different song every time.
Speaker 0: it's like they can.
Speaker 0: they put behind The in the background while this claymation guy is singing Stock footage.
Speaker 1: public domain footage is one actor who they keep using to portray Zeus, but he kind of looks like Jesus.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's at this people.
Speaker 0: I think the people who worked on the show are in the.
Speaker 0: they often just put on like Sparta helmets and do stuff in the background.
Speaker 0: So it's like the closer is like you're looking forward to it.
Speaker 0: It's like oh, well, they can do for the closer this time It's like it's like exciting stuff.
Speaker 1: But yeah so the Greek guy just keeps going back and forth in time between 1964 Tokyo and ancient Greece and he does it a lot like.
Speaker 0: it's not like a special one-time thing.
Speaker 0: It's basically like he's just doing it constantly First.
Speaker 1: it happens mysteriously every episode but eventually the mayor's like get fucking back in there to that Tokiopolis whatever and figure some shit out for me.
Speaker 0: Yep, I just but it does draw, you know, it's like on the one hand It's so silly but on the other hand that they are drawing like these straight Comparisons of you know things happening in 60s Japan and things happening in ancient Greece to show you like yeah This thing from ancient Greece is happening in 60s Japan and is still happening today.
Speaker 0: It's like, you know, you had a you know, the ancient pentathlon and now you have the modern pentathlon.
Speaker 0: This is where this is where modern pentathlon comes from and I'm like I knew about modern pentathlon already.
Speaker 0: But if I didn't this would be educational.
Speaker 1: Yeah well Especially because it makes a lot of like sort of side subtle points like there's this bit where he's designing new games and in ancient Greece they're stupid games because he's not good at this.
Speaker 1: So the mayor throws them all in the ocean in the future.
Speaker 1: all of those paintings He made had been found and historians were reading way too much into them.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm There's also like it gets oddly maudlin a couple of times.
Speaker 1: Like what was I think was episode 9 where Randomly the old man just like yeah you want to come to the movies with me and then they watch movies about like World War 2 and war and
Speaker 0: Yeah, because the well because the ancient Greek guy right is that the story they tell?
Speaker 0: at least is that in ancient Greece?
Speaker 0: Most of the wars were not very bloody like you would just say.
Speaker 1: there were a lot of ceremonial wars Depending on what era you're looking at.
Speaker 0: Yeah, or at least not, you know, not that many people died They probably injured probably plenty, right?
Speaker 1: Not to say that there weren't any bloody wars, but the guy cut the mayor's like war is great when I win But it sucks when I lose.
Speaker 1: and then the war guy comes he's like, yeah I'm gonna loot a bunch of the rough.
Speaker 0: the main character Demetrius that really doesn't like conflict and war and fighting right at all Even if it's fake.
Speaker 0: and he at one point it seems like a war.
Speaker 0: He's have managed to avoid war somehow even with Spartans for so long with his, you know clever or somewhat not clever ways And eventually he the war looks like it's actually gonna happen for real and he super doesn't want it to happen.
Speaker 0: He goes to Tokyo and he asks a guy in 60s Japan, right?
Speaker 0: You know, how do I stop war?
Speaker 0: and the guy takes him to the movie theater and shows him actual war movies.
Speaker 1: So it's like the whole second half of that episode which so it's about two minutes of screen time.
Speaker 0: Yeah, he's like.
Speaker 0: he's like, yeah, we lost a war.
Speaker 0: We haven't had a war since.
Speaker 0: he's like well When are you gonna have another one?
Speaker 0: He's like, we probably aren't gonna have another line.
Speaker 1: He says is I don't think we'll go to war anymore.
Speaker 1: and then it's just like the episode just gets maudlin and he like the guy sits through this movie on war and The old man just has one more thing.
Speaker 1: He's like not all of mankind's advancements are great.
Speaker 0: Yep, it's like friend.
Speaker 0: It's such a silly show.
Speaker 0: They take the time out of their five-minute episode to do that And then and then I do the crazy closer, I think that one's about trip I on Yeah, and then the next episode he starts out immediately right.
Speaker 0: it picks up where it left off.
Speaker 0: He's like, oh my god war is really bad.
Speaker 0: I can't let it happen.
Speaker 0: I have.
Speaker 0: he's even more desperate to avoid the impending war in ancient Greece Because he's seen how bad war is in you know, 1940.
Speaker 1: So in terms of like how this show got made in the studio cuz I loved it.
Speaker 1: Like this show is great.
Speaker 1: Like you're an anime fan this is the exact kind of weird crap to watch that you're not gonna see anywhere else like the stuff that we are.
Speaker 0: so Lucky that someone is like crunchyroll.
Speaker 0: It's like how much money they make it on this.
Speaker 0: But yeah, like the effort put in to subtitle and distribute this does that really help?
Speaker 1: Like then a hundred people have even bothered to put a star on this show in crunchyroll Right.
Speaker 0: So the fact that this is even subtitled for consumption by anyone anywhere that you know.
Speaker 0: I wonder where like is it to watch this in Japan?
Speaker 0: Is it like on TV like a specific moment?
Speaker 0: Like between two TV shows for five minutes like at midnight or something like who even knows where how it's broadcast there.
Speaker 0: But it's like, you know to put in the effort and to pay for this.
Speaker 0: We are so lucky that someone has done this even even in fan sub days.
Speaker 0: What a fan summer have found this got and been able to get the video of it.
Speaker 1: It would have been like the rare tape that gets screened at an anime con at midnight.
Speaker 1: It is no.
Speaker 0: I like the one guy who knows right?
Speaker 0: No one would even know about it.
Speaker 1: Yep, so I tried what.
Speaker 0: there's probably so many shows like this that we don't know about.
Speaker 1: So I tried to figure out more about like where it came from.
Speaker 1: So the direct like a lot of the people associated with this show don't even have their own pages on the anime news network.
Speaker 1: But the creator of the I guess the manga that this is based on or at least the creator of the story Mari Yamazaki.
Speaker 1: Mari Yamazaki actually is known for a few other things that we might have talked about like that Roman bath manga.
Speaker 0: Yeah There's a mom as a manga.
Speaker 0: I don't know if it was ever animated.
Speaker 0: thermae Romai.
Speaker 0: I don't know how to remain Romai.
Speaker 1: not only it had a firm a Romai and had a manga a TV show and a live-action movie.
Speaker 1: and then I said that's in the live-action movie.
Speaker 0: I know about it, but I never actually watched it.
Speaker 0: I think I read like a few pages of it in a bookstore once because the cover looks really awesome Right because it's the same style art round.
Speaker 1: It's kind of the same plot like a.
Speaker 0: it's kind of the same plot.
Speaker 0: There's a Roman dude who has like.
Speaker 0: there's a pathway in the Roman bathhouse that like takes them to.
Speaker 0: like, you know Japanese bathhouse is sort of like a connection.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and then he sort of brings, you know The Japanese bath stuff to Rome and this is sort of the same thing.
Speaker 0: You have a guy a great Greek guy connecting with Japan to write bring Sporting stuff to ancient Greece.
Speaker 1: So she also did the Steve Jobs manga Which hmm I knew existed.
Speaker 0: I think I knew it existed I think when I thought I was under the impression the Steve Jobs manga was a serious.
Speaker 0: it is straightforward biography.
Speaker 1: It is based on Steve Jobs biography, but it's like a mom.
Speaker 1: Okay, so it's it of it.
Speaker 0: Oh, so it's not a ridiculous one.
Speaker 1: Nope, it's just straight as far as I can tell.
Speaker 0: It's not like, you know Teleporting to Japan to get ideas to put in an apple - or so I mean thermite Roma is also like pretty played pretty straight from what I've read of it.
Speaker 0: Oh, okay I thought it was ridiculous.
Speaker 1: Like this is I thought I think it's a lot less ridiculous than this.
Speaker 1: This is like maximum ridiculous.
Speaker 0: So I was slightly slightly questioning.
Speaker 0: There was an episode of this show that we're talking about today, right?
Speaker 0: Where the closing song was about Nero the Roman Emperor How he how he cheated at the Olympics.
Speaker 0: So that was the tie-in.
Speaker 0: but I'm like, hey, that's Rome not Greece.
Speaker 0: What are you doing?
Speaker 1: Remember the Romans were obsessed with Greece and tried to like me.
Speaker 0: where I culture they were indeed like our.
Speaker 1: one anecdote I remember learning in high school was that Alexander the Great Wanted to participate in like some equivalent of the games.
Speaker 1: they wouldn't let him because he wasn't Greek enough.
Speaker 1: He had to prove that even though he was from Macedon.
Speaker 1: He had enough Greek heritage.
Speaker 1: There was like a whole thing.
Speaker 0: He'll prove it with a sword up your ass.
Speaker 0: So him.
Speaker 1: the anime studio Doesn't appear to have made any other anime Nobishiro lab, I couldn't find like any info about them.
Speaker 1: So I ended up going to their actual website which has like a demo reel and a few things.
Speaker 1: I don't know if the studio is just one, dude But the studio seems to be like a studio for hire type situation.
Speaker 1: that'll make Experiences and things.
Speaker 1: all I'm saying is if we ever want to make the gig nights anime I kind of want to hire the studio to make it.
Speaker 0: That's all you.
Speaker 0: But seriously two guys get to a podcast.
Speaker 0: it gets teleported to the ancient days of Japanese radio to learn from.
Speaker 1: That would be great.
Speaker 1: Or in ancient Japanese why we keep saying ancient Japanese radio?
Speaker 1: someone doing old-timey radio is ancient.
Speaker 1: I mean ancient by what definition the 20s are my definition your definition.
Speaker 1: I guess kids today are like yeah, the 80s were an ancient time.
Speaker 0: People today like there's people a lot of people today.
Speaker 0: Just don't even listen to radio.
Speaker 0: It's true.
Speaker 1: Well that makes it archaic.
Speaker 1: It doesn't necessarily make it ancient.
Speaker 1: ancient anyway, I Don't see any reason.
Speaker 1: if you're listening to geek nights Anime because we don't review the kinds of anime that the other anime podcast tend to do usually.
Speaker 0: We'll probably review the dega dance someday.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but If you listen to geek nights for your anime reviews, this is a show you must watch.
Speaker 0: Yeah, this is a show.
Speaker 1: if you're here listening to this now Wednesdays are the least popular geek nights night.
Speaker 1: We have a curated a particular audience of people who like a particular kind of show.
Speaker 1: just go watch the show right now It literally.
Speaker 1: it'll take you like an hour or two to watch everything and you're done.
Speaker 0: They're five minute episodes and you skip the first 30 seconds.
Speaker 0: What's 20 times four and a half, right?
Speaker 0: 21 times 4.5 It'll take you 94 minutes.
Speaker 0: as long as it takes to watch one movie a short movie a normal length movie.
Speaker 0: You can watch all 21 episodes of this on crunchy.
Speaker 1: If we had discovered this show and we were running the RT anime club We would definitely have shown it immediately at the next meeting.
Speaker 1: We would have canceled whatever we had on the schedule.
Speaker 0: We would have shown the entire show.
Speaker 1: We would have shown Of course with the openers.
Speaker 1: We showed the fucking opener to risky safety every episode.
Speaker 1: Of course, I know this opener.
Speaker 0: Yeah See ya, that's the thing.
Speaker 0: it also.
Speaker 0: I think it also, you know, especially not just with the Olympics but with The Greek ness living in a you know, predominantly Greek Neighborhood or at least a neighborhood that has a lot of you know, Greek stuff going on.
Speaker 1: I was think back to when someone put that top bike pump in Athena's hands.
Speaker 1: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott.
Speaker 1: special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening.
Speaker 1: music can't leave for web design and brand.
Speaker 0: Okay for the logos be sure to visit our website at front row crew comm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 1: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 0: But unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night And the patreon patrons for this episode of geek nights are Alan Joyce hiding the nickel Marty grainy.
Speaker 1: I just like a dude guy Graham Finch.
Speaker 1: You hold the key to my heart.
Speaker 1: I sprang with the quickness like lightning disappeared.
Speaker 1: Clinton Walton Jay bands run from New Zealand Ryan parent Chris midkiff dread lily tenebrae Chris Reimer Finn Sherwood about oral and a bunch of people who do not want me to say their names.
Speaker 1: So, uh, yeah that anime was way better than we expected.
Speaker 1: I hope you actually do watch it.
Speaker 1: Uh, stay tuned for we do next Wednesday might have something interesting for you.
Speaker 1: But now I leave you.
Speaker 1: Fuck you Sit moss, I'm not familiar with that address.
Speaker 1: Shit.
Speaker 1: What about the guy?
Speaker 1: you look bottom eyes.
Speaker 1: You know why I'm such a happy first.
Speaker 1: What about the guy?
Speaker 1: you look bottom eyes, you know why I'm such a happy first.
Speaker 0: Okay, I'm having a party tonight.
Speaker 1: Who the hell invited you?
Speaker 1: Ricker see it party.
Speaker 1: Hey, don't worry about me Know you're lying.
Speaker 1: I got four kids.
Speaker 1: What the fuck?
Speaker 1: Shit.
Speaker 1: So what happened to number five?
Speaker 1: you got what the fuck.
Speaker 1: What is.
Speaker 1: it is exactly the same about every single vacation you have every day.