Speaker 0: It's Monday, March 16th, 2020.
Speaker 0: I'm rim.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott and this is geek nights tonight not working from home.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: That was the best title we could come up with for what this episode actually is.
Speaker 0: So what's new?
Speaker 0: open ebitwise?
Speaker 0: think we're both working from home now.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: They told me I mean like.
Speaker 1: if they said go to work I'd be like all right, and I would go to work.
Speaker 1: if they said hockey is open We're having hockey I'd go to the hockey.
Speaker 1: but they said no hockey is closed and work don't come to work.
Speaker 1: So I'm not going to work and I'm not going to hockey.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we it's not there to go to.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we've been practicing and I could go to my work and be alone.
Speaker 0: We were doing a lot of people working from home thing for a couple weeks But now we're in the situation where due to the city's rule changes and everything in midtown being empty It's just 100% work from home.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm like.
Speaker 1: so after I left work on Wednesday night They messaged and said all right, we're gonna test working from home for everyone Thursday in front.
Speaker 0: Oh, we did that a couple weeks ago.
Speaker 1: Of course my team You know, I guess the rest of the company doesn't have this but my team of programmer people Basically, we already worked from home sort of whenever we wanted mostly right?
Speaker 1: I you did it actually less than other people.
Speaker 1: I just did it like when I needed to get shit done like laundry or you know chores errands.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and anyway It's already knew I could work from home.
Speaker 1: I need to test it.
Speaker 1: But they said all right Thursday and Friday, right?
Speaker 1: So I went back Thursday morning to get the computer came back and then I think it was Friday after work.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there's a message like okay all next week working from home and then apparently sometime on Sunday The message was work from home until April 6th, which is this week next week in the week after so At least April 6 who knows.
Speaker 1: so that is the.
Speaker 1: I woke up this morning and turn on the work computer Assuming I was working from home this week.
Speaker 1: It's like no working from home pretty much all month.
Speaker 0: Yeah, pretty ready for it.
Speaker 0: We Emily and I both working home made some lunch.
Speaker 0: Like we're just cooking food because restaurants are all closed.
Speaker 0: Obviously.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they'll do delivery or takeout.
Speaker 0: Yep I'm gonna see tomorrow if the Baroness will continue to do takeout or if they're just gonna shut down.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so on Saturday Saturday Sunday, I think I forget.
Speaker 1: I think it was Saturday.
Speaker 1: I don't remember.
Speaker 1: It was just a blur.
Speaker 1: Basically, I'm home all the time.
Speaker 1: So there's no separation.
Speaker 0: Yeah That's the thing that we're talking about that topic.
Speaker 0: But the people when I've worked from home for long periods of time The lack of separation starts to make your life just feel like one long day.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so We're like, okay, let's order, you know, since we're all stuck at home.
Speaker 1: Let's order delivery from Vesta.
Speaker 0: Half fancy get the lasagna.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and so delivery shows up very promptly.
Speaker 1: delicious food, right?
Speaker 1: The delivery guy hands me the hand the bag.
Speaker 1: I take the bag.
Speaker 1: I turn around.
Speaker 1: I say goodbye.
Speaker 1: He goes in the elevator.
Speaker 1: I close the door.
Speaker 1: I start walking towards the table and then All the food falls out of the bottom of the bone.
Speaker 1: Oh, no That is not what I expected.
Speaker 0: I thought it was gonna like.
Speaker 0: then the doorbell rings.
Speaker 1: No, whoa, and I'm like, I'm just like I there was like less than a fraction of a second Oh where I felt something wrong.
Speaker 1: And then I'm looking at food all over the floor.
Speaker 0: I know that feeling.
Speaker 1: I know only the Brussels sprouts stayed in their metal container with plastic lid.
Speaker 0: No, it'd be easier to deal with them than the lasagna because I assume you got a lasagna.
Speaker 1: Oh, there's a lasagna on the floor.
Speaker 1: There was a cheesecake on the floor.
Speaker 1: There was a pasta on the floor.
Speaker 0: The worst thing is what do you do other than go?
Speaker 1: So We I called the restaurant and it was like look this is crazy But this is what happened.
Speaker 1: and then I called grub hub and they said, okay Well, we'll refund you for everything except Brussels sprouts.
Speaker 1: So then because we were so crazy hungry we ate the Brussels sprouts.
Speaker 1: So I call and then I called the restaurant back and I said, you know what?
Speaker 1: We're just fucking coming there.
Speaker 1: so we went there and We ate exactly the same thing we ordered.
Speaker 1: And then we went back home.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it was.
Speaker 1: it was Really me.
Speaker 0: That's a you know, I remember a moment.
Speaker 1: It was very meh.
Speaker 0: It was similarly a meh moment, but this was way back and we lived in Beacon and I was just real sick.
Speaker 0: I had like a real bad flu.
Speaker 0: you were like off at work like doing your normal thing.
Speaker 0: I was home alone was sick and The only food we had left in the house that was like easy enough to cook when I was sick was the last Jamaican beef Patty.
Speaker 1: Oh you and your Jamaican beef patty.
Speaker 0: I used to love those things.
Speaker 0: So I found out they were basically just a hundred percent trans fat.
Speaker 0: But I mean I didn't.
Speaker 0: trans fat wasn't known to be bad back then.
Speaker 0: So I have the Jamaican beef patty and I've heated it up in the convection oven and I put it on.
Speaker 1: Remember that a convection oven?
Speaker 0: Well the little toaster oven a regular toaster toaster oven.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it did.
Speaker 0: It also is a convection oven.
Speaker 0: it had a convection mode.
Speaker 1: I don't think you had a fan in it.
Speaker 0: Oh, it did.
Speaker 0: I remember that one very well, which one you're talking about?
Speaker 0: mine?
Speaker 0: the one that broke and we threw it away later.
Speaker 0: Anyway, I cooked this Jamaican beef patty and I put it on the last of the of the kitchen Where I had from RIT when I lived in the dorms those clear glass plates that were scratched to hell.
Speaker 0: Okay, and I turned around and it caught on the sleeve of my towel.
Speaker 0: I was wrapped in because that's how sick I was and it and the towel flung the plate End-over-end onto the ground and the plate shattered on the Jamaican beef patty.
Speaker 0: Oh the last food we had.
Speaker 1: There's no eating that beef patty now.
Speaker 0: I Am not too proud to admit that I did end up eating about a third of that Jamaican beef patty.
Speaker 1: shards of glass in your gut.
Speaker 0: So this glass broke into big chunks and there was a piece of Jamaican beef patty that had like broken off and was on the floor Just dirty but without it.
Speaker 0: So I basically picked the dirt off the bottom and like cut the cut it up and I ate what I could and that was Literally the saddest meal I've ever had in my entire life.
Speaker 0: and now your son do the big Wall Street money Used to eat Jamaican beef patties Jamaican beef patties while hiding my car from the repo guy And eating eating Johnny cakes on a regular basis.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: Well, it was not that long ago in my life anyway.
Speaker 0: Yep, though.
Speaker 0: There is one pretty interesting and good news about Grubbub and like delivery orders and all that They have suspended the Commission's they charge to independent restaurants.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: So why don't they just do this permanently?
Speaker 0: Well, because then they can't make any money too bad.
Speaker 0: I mean, yeah, we should nationalize a bunch of things like.
Speaker 0: I'm not getting there I'm just saying that this is a private company.
Speaker 0: That is this is not pure altruism.
Speaker 0: It's definitely enlightened self-interest because if you are the company that delivers food from restaurants to people and all the restaurants go out of Business you to go out of business.
Speaker 0: So it is in your enlightened self-interest to help restaurants not go out of business.
Speaker 1: That's true.
Speaker 0: and to they're only doing it for independent restaurants.
Speaker 0: Like if you order from McDonald's, they're still gonna charge McDonald's that Commission.
Speaker 1: I didn't know McDonald's was on Grubhub dude.
Speaker 0: All the fast food is just why would you?
Speaker 0: I could get Taco Bell delivered here right now.
Speaker 0: I could get White Castle delivered here.
Speaker 0: Please don't.
Speaker 0: I kind of want to get a White Castle Please don't?
Speaker 0: White Castle has a vegan options.
Speaker 0: now They got a possible White Castle.
Speaker 1: still White Castle whether it's vegan or not.
Speaker 0: I love White Castle.
Speaker 0: Okay, White Castle, you know my brain.
Speaker 0: my mouth not my brain so much but my mouth and maybe my brain stem Really want to eat a Jamaican beef.
Speaker 1: If I owned White Castle, I would open up a new restaurant called Black Castle And it would actually be like ridiculously high quality food.
Speaker 1: Not like, you know fast food, but it would be like Black Castle.
Speaker 0: No white or White Palace maybe.
Speaker 0: Yeah Yeah, make the portcullis just the portcullis portcullis.
Speaker 0: Yeah, make the other fort white fort anyway.
Speaker 1: Yeah food all over the floor.
Speaker 1: her was you know in the grand scheme.
Speaker 1: That's not really a disaster But it just felt so disastrous because to be so hungry and to have all the fixed food all over the floor and like the wasting of the food just felt so bad.
Speaker 1: I mean a lasagna all over the floor.
Speaker 0: the scale in the scale of our two stories and the time separation.
Speaker 0: They're very different stories, but I think we both felt in that brief moment the same pain just like some great just like a great force.
Speaker 0: One mouth suddenly is very sad.
Speaker 0: Oh I feel like that gave the Thursday show.
Speaker 0: food disasters.
Speaker 1: I don't have any other food disaster.
Speaker 0: I have a couple not many.
Speaker 0: most of them are more.
Speaker 0: my parents failed in a cooking of some kind.
Speaker 1: I remember at least one fire in the stove.
Speaker 0: I remember a lot of food disasters at RIT that were not caused by us but we.
Speaker 0: the fire alarm would go off and we'd come out and We can all tell which apartment caused the problem and multiple times.
Speaker 0: It was a specific apartment and had two people who we know living in it.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm, but I don't think we ever caused it.
Speaker 0: Nope so, uh, I Was feeling.
Speaker 0: you know, usually around this time of year I get antsy I get that spring feeling that well.
Speaker 1: Hey, first of all, we have not done a Monday show since last year.
Speaker 0: Yeah already March Monday was like the hardest hit by our.
Speaker 1: Monday is still the hardest day to do.
Speaker 1: send us Monday show ideas because we Don't have any.
Speaker 0: Yep, cuz usually when you run out of Monday show ideas rim wants to do I would be happy if Monday was just what's the most recent tech news?
Speaker 0: Let's just do it twitch style, but better.
Speaker 1: But anyway so The rule that we have come up with is that we can do tech news roundup once a year and that happens to be in March.
Speaker 1: the last time we did it was.
Speaker 1: it's been over a year since the last tech news roundup But yet I was already doing a tech news roundup the one time.
Speaker 0: usually that the story goes rim says Let's do a tech news roundup.
Speaker 0: Scott says when was the last time we did it and rim says fuck Yeah, sometimes it go rim Scott.
Speaker 0: Scott says when was the last time we did it and rim says it's been over a year.
Speaker 0: And then I'm really excited and we do it.
Speaker 0: I wasn't ready.
Speaker 0: No next Monday the next Monday show We do will definitely be a tech news round.
Speaker 1: Oh, we send us ideas to the Monday show after that one Yep, but also send us tech news.
Speaker 1: Yep, cuz I haven't found any tech news.
Speaker 1: I'm used.
Speaker 1: I got a news That's from last year.
Speaker 0: All right, here's the tech news.
Speaker 1: So rims doing his news first, I guess.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so said he at home Is pretty forgotten by younger people like young people don't even know this exists.
Speaker 1: Yeah, this was basically the first Major project that was distributed computing, right?
Speaker 1: Well, there was this distributed computing to consumer PCs.
Speaker 1: Yeah the idea that Someone with a lot of computer processing that they needed to do Would in the olden days get a supercomputer.
Speaker 1: and there are still supercomputers that do these things that used for like weather modeling and shit.
Speaker 1: Right, but what they said he at home was like, hey, we don't want to pay for a supercomputer.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: Let's break up all of our input data in the chunks send the chunks out to Different people with normal computers at their homes and those normal computers will process that input data using their home desktop Intel CPU and they'll be volunteering their CPU and the program will run when the person's not using their computer and Now it won't slow them down when they are using the computer because otherwise the CPU is just going away sitting there not being used.
Speaker 1: Yeah And then we'll send all of its outputs back to the main central repository will be stored and collated and then we'll send them more inputs.
Speaker 1: and It was a really good idea.
Speaker 1: A lot of people followed on.
Speaker 1: Yeah, this is real exciting.
Speaker 0: And remember this shit is from 1999.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 1: So in college a lot of people ran this.
Speaker 1: I ran time to time.
Speaker 0: I ran in high school.
Speaker 1: Yeah And it was a thing and it's continued to be a thing.
Speaker 1: and they would process the data from.
Speaker 1: that of you know radars and telescopes listening to radio signals from outer space and the idea was basically to Look at all the data that no one's looking at too closely to figure out the amount of data They were collecting was so enormous.
Speaker 1: You're listening to all of outer space 24/7 to a vast variety of radio frequencies at all times.
Speaker 1: That's a lot of data coming in.
Speaker 1: you need a lot of you know.
Speaker 1: You can't look at it all with even with a supercomputer.
Speaker 0: Yep and remember back then there weren't like bitcoins to mine or anything like this was it.
Speaker 0: and Because a lot of the people had computers were more nerdy people were kind of into it and it was partly like people got Excited about SETI and excited about science.
Speaker 1: It felt also like, you know, I'm helping.
Speaker 1: well, not just you're helping but like hey I bought this computer, but I'm not sitting at it It's just sitting there going to waste this expensive fancy machine and back then it didn't use that much power.
Speaker 1: It's pointless for it to sit here doing nothing.
Speaker 1: This is great.
Speaker 0: I mean the computer I ran this on first had like a 40 watt power supply.
Speaker 1: Yeah So since then there have been a lot of other.
Speaker 1: there's a platform called Boink Bo Inc.
Speaker 1: that hosts many Similar projects and you can choose which projects you want to dedicate CPU time to.
Speaker 1: yeah a big one I think still which has also been going on for a super long time And I think it's still going on is folding at home, which does protein folding.
Speaker 1: Yep to find various medical.
Speaker 0: I think I even saw a coronavirus one folding protein specifically to help that research.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so I think that's still out there.
Speaker 0: But yeah, so the news is SETI at home is Finally after all these years 21 years suspending operations And there's a lot of reasons for that.
Speaker 1: part of that means they're just not sending out new inputs to people who are running it.
Speaker 0: They're basically gonna spin it down for now partly because the architecture didn't really hold like it's old architecture.
Speaker 1: Yeah Over the years.
Speaker 0: Yep, they're even telling people.
Speaker 0: Hey, we encourage you to try these other boink based projects.
Speaker 0: Well, we decide what to do next.
Speaker 0: but it's on one hand The project is so old the tech has moved a long time like a long way since then.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah - They've got a lot of data that now they're like.
Speaker 0: SETI at home did identify a bunch of things that require further study.
Speaker 0: Now they need to do that.
Speaker 0: They need to do the part.
Speaker 0: That's not as easy.
Speaker 1: Couldn't it just make SETI at home to process the things that were already processed?
Speaker 0: possibly?
Speaker 0: But the problem is will send out to you something all the work that people already did to Search through it, but not to turn this into the like distributed computing thing.
Speaker 0: But the kinds of problems that are like use like the things that make sense to do this kind of distributed computing for a very particular kinds of problems.
Speaker 0: not every problem can be mapped to packets of Questions that can be answered by untrusted hardware.
Speaker 1: Nope Not at all.
Speaker 0: And it's a very like.
Speaker 0: there's a whole trust.
Speaker 0: but verify Mechanism in these systems that we do not have time to use all kinds of stuff going on there.
Speaker 1: That could have been our Monday show idea.
Speaker 0: Yep, but basically what they said is one.
Speaker 0: The result table has grown to the point where it no longer fits in their main memory.
Speaker 0: That's been slowing down the validators and the simulators which is causing result table to grow even further.
Speaker 0: They want to get that down to a managed manageable size.
Speaker 0: They're doing a whole bunch of stuff, but Probably said he at home will reemerge someday on a more modern platform with a different type of problem to solve.
Speaker 0: but Probably this kind of research does not need your individual computers help right now.
Speaker 0: No, and there are better problems to aim those computer resources at and not mining bit not mining bitcoins.
Speaker 0: Yeah, don't mind don't mind your coins.
Speaker 1: Yeah Don't mind any kind of coin and I I'm.
Speaker 0: all I want to talk about is just that this is a very long running and I would argue Extremely successful project and Historically significant.
Speaker 0: it only said to me how many people will only be learning about it today because it's ending Even if they weren't doing it, like I think a lot of younger people just don't even know it existed.
Speaker 1: Yep alright, so Usually when news happens we completely forget about it and the only news we talked about in the news section of the show is news that happened that day because I come to Do the show and I open up the news and I look and I see what's on the news that day.
Speaker 1: So if there was a news even the day before a geek nights episode It's unlikely to be talked about on a geek nights.
Speaker 1: Yep, and since we haven't done a Monday show since last year there was a news since last I think it was late last year that we didn't discuss in any Monday show because we haven't done a Monday show.
Speaker 0: I think we've talked about it a little bit.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we talked about it between us but not on the show.
Speaker 0: or maybe we did and we just couldn't find it.
Speaker 1: But yeah, or we did talk about it on the show and we didn't actually remember.
Speaker 1: we did But I remembered because I couldn't find any decent tech news.
Speaker 1: I managed to remember this old tech news because people are talking about VPNs because they're working from home.
Speaker 1: yep, right and there was a VPN related news and that is there is a project called wire guard.
Speaker 1: right and Wire guard is pretty good VPN, right?
Speaker 1: It's it's if you look at the source code relative to like other VPNs like say open VPN or any of those.
Speaker 1: it's simpler easy to understand more well-coded more modern Just pretty much better in most ways Right.
Speaker 1: It's like a legit quality VPN for 2020.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: Nice and generic.
Speaker 1: It's pretty easy to set up Right and the news is that this VPN is B was.
Speaker 1: I mean, it's old news already like a few months old.
Speaker 1: It is being included in Linux kernel.
Speaker 1: it's like the kernel has this VPN just fucking in it.
Speaker 0: Yep, right.
Speaker 1: So basically for all intents and purposes This is now the VPN of choice like, you know All those other VPN softwares get out of the way.
Speaker 1: Wire guard is the king right now.
Speaker 0: This is.
Speaker 0: this is similarly big news to way back when DRBD became a common part of Linux, right?
Speaker 1: And I don't think people are using that too much anymore.
Speaker 0: I do still see people using it.
Speaker 1: It's not being non used but I think it has been eclipsed.
Speaker 0: Well, I think it's been eclipsed by cloud computing Yes, and because you don't need to solve that problem that way if you're not using physical hardware directly exactly.
Speaker 1: But yeah, so I think you know There's a lot of people who are still currently using other sorts of VPNs and I gonna I think you're gonna see Over the next you know year or a few They're slowly all gonna be replaced with this the way that get another Linux project,
Speaker 0: right?
Speaker 1: Slowly erased all the other source control.
Speaker 0: I think you'll see a lot of remote access applications only.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's only been a few months right.
Speaker 0: but even games I think bit by bit like I think people will use Wireguard on the back end of things.
Speaker 0: They're building that need a like pseudo local land, right?
Speaker 1: And also this VPN since it is included in the kernel, right?
Speaker 1: You can now when you're writing say a server that runs on Linux you can like count Possibly on it being there and then you could use it for something.
Speaker 1: So like, you know, you could make all incorporate VPN into other projects much more easily without requiring That.
Speaker 1: you know the people running your project like separately set up a VPN.
Speaker 0: Well, like today say an old PC game like tribes - you want to play that with people on the internet?
Speaker 0: You need to make some sort of fake network.
Speaker 1: You need to make a fake VPN or a VPN of your own and then run tribes - and have tribes to think it's on A land.
Speaker 1: Yep, right.
Speaker 0: This would make that way easier.
Speaker 0: If you just embedded that into your hacked libraries and you're right you can make it.
Speaker 1: you can now make a game Right and the game would connect to with Wireguard, right?
Speaker 1: Invisibly and now everyone running the game is on a land with everyone else is playing the game Yeah, and now can play with each other.
Speaker 1: So that's one.
Speaker 1: That's just one idea.
Speaker 0: Yep, and you know what.
Speaker 1: and also it would say much better more secure, right?
Speaker 1: Open-source VPN.
Speaker 1: Oh my god Definitely does not have backdoors inserted by the government or any kind of shenanigans like.
Speaker 1: also you can trust this shit.
Speaker 0: scan Other VPNs like looking at the configuration kind of like how it were like how you configure it.
Speaker 0: It's pretty straightforward.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, it's way.
Speaker 0: This is not rocket science.
Speaker 1: It's actually like as like I said It's like a big step up in VPNs versus the same way they get was a big step up and they even say I'm gonna quote their own website compared to Behemoths like swan.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I be sec.
Speaker 0: Yep open VPN open SSL in which auditing the job, right?
Speaker 1: For example, right open SSL on open SSL is a giant project that has a million cryptographic kinds of related things.
Speaker 0: You can probably insert legit straight-up malware.
Speaker 0: No one would notice right you put it.
Speaker 1: but open SL is enormous cuz it's like it's like a Swiss Army knife.
Speaker 1: Encryption is security wire guard is just VPN.
Speaker 1: It doesn't do anything else.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right.
Speaker 1: So that's why it's a lot better at it.
Speaker 0: I'm increasingly a fan of elegant simple tools like this that are a server client But also just the library to use to do that thing.
Speaker 1: so if you are out there and You are about to set up a VPN a new or a V say you're a tiny game studio And you don't have a work from home.
Speaker 1: solution VPN like structure somewhere.
Speaker 1: Yeah anywhere.
Speaker 1: This should be the first thing you look at.
Speaker 1: It's for a setting that shit up.
Speaker 0: No, I do think Generally it like if you're running a service or a company or a group you should try to use Tools that are already natively online and don't require a local like a LAN.
Speaker 0: But a VPN is a really quick way to take like an internal dev environment with giant assets that you haven't ported to Amazon Accessible to everyone or like right?
Speaker 1: I'm saying just listen to our VPN episode.
Speaker 1: Yeah uses of VPN, but then use this one, but this one did not exist.
Speaker 1: We made that ever.
Speaker 0: What the fuck did we?
Speaker 1: or these just wasn't included in the kernel?
Speaker 0: I want to listen that all this what the hell did we tell people to use?
Speaker 0: Cuz I've set up VPNs before on like Cisco routers and that shit sucks.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Well now you don't do that anymore Anything with Linux kernel run.
Speaker 0: Hello darkness my old friend.
Speaker 0: one last news More of a PSA, but I saw this story out of the UK and I feel like this could be a bigger problem For various reasons.
Speaker 0: there seems to be a temporary toilet paper shortage in a bunch of parts.
Speaker 1: I don't know why.
Speaker 1: I still don't understand why you're buying TP.
Speaker 1: I got enough TP.
Speaker 0: I don't think your butts clean enough.
Speaker 1: I got plenty and the store has some.
Speaker 1: well.
Speaker 0: So the funny thing is as much as I see all these shortages of TP in the US Even when I was in Midtown like Wednesday last week.
Speaker 0: Yeah Like the TJ's and like all the like Costco's are also a lot of everything.
Speaker 0: the Kate Elliott toilet paper So did like the CVS like all the non big stores the toilet paper factory doesn't have like a shortage of paper.
Speaker 1: They're still churning out rolls at the same rate.
Speaker 1: They were before there.
Speaker 1: You're just buying them too fast for no reason Yep, unless you were happen to have run out and like everyone's gonna be like my great aunt's house.
Speaker 1: So they got too much TP.
Speaker 0: But my PSA is this if you somehow run out of toilet paper and have like a week where you can't get any Do not make air sats toilet paper out of things that are not flushable.
Speaker 0: That is how you get fat birds.
Speaker 0: Oh my god, like that will literally destroy the sewer system And then you're gonna have a problem.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah Like and I'm particularly talking about any of those flushable wipes that say they're flushable.
Speaker 0: Those things are not flushable.
Speaker 1: No, but the only thing you should flush down the toilet is poop.
Speaker 0: Yep He water TP all their body fluids.
Speaker 0: Like if you have a collection of blood you need to get rid of like sure vomit.
Speaker 0: Yeah all that.
Speaker 0: Well, it depends on how much blood.
Speaker 1: I guess it's okay.
Speaker 1: Cuz like, you know if you're sick and like you pee blood you should.
Speaker 0: you can flush that if you've got The doctor if you have got more than say a quart of blood just hanging around.
Speaker 0: Do not pour that down the drain.
Speaker 0: call either the police or a hospital.
Speaker 0: cuz someone Either I didn't have that either an ambulance or a police car needs to show up at your house And I'm sure you don't need any virus related news on geek nights.
Speaker 1: You can get that from places with actual doctors, but I don't want to let anyone know That Because there are no large gatherings and there should not be large gatherings, I guess for safety.
Speaker 1: That is what Doctors smarter than me say.
Speaker 0: no more than 50 people should get together in major cities as of like Dateline 630 p.m.
Speaker 0: EDT on March 16.
Speaker 1: Anyway, because there are no large gatherings There is a very big shortage of blood that we just mentioned.
Speaker 1: Right because usually blood drives happen at large gatherings like anime Boston Is a shockingly big blood drive.
Speaker 1: Yeah It's like.
Speaker 1: basically they have tables to donate blood and during anime Boston all those tables of blood donating were occupied the entire time of anime Boston And I saw lots of you walking anime Boston with like the gifts you got for donating or what?
Speaker 0: I gave almost every year the only I remember the last two years.
Speaker 0: I didn't give partly because I was worried I would get sick anyway from a from the nerds at the con with it.
Speaker 0: Not because of anyway.
Speaker 1: the point is It is safe to go and donate blood.
Speaker 1: if you go to a blood donating place, right?
Speaker 1: They're hoping you come.
Speaker 1: there's not.
Speaker 1: it's not a crowded place.
Speaker 1: It's a place full of doctors.
Speaker 1: It's a clean place.
Speaker 1: Yeah, don't go there if you're fucking sick Jesus Christ.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and if there's a line out the door like yeah Maybe like no usually you make an appointment.
Speaker 1: You don't just show up But there will be a blood donating place near where you live wherever that is.
Speaker 1: Go there.
Speaker 1: I'll probably make an appointment whenever it's not I have to go to work.
Speaker 1: It's like I time.
Speaker 1: Yep And yeah, as long as you're not sick and answer their questions, honestly, don't lie to them.
Speaker 1: Yeah Even though there's one question that we know but that's not a topic for today.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that question bullshit.
Speaker 0: We know that question is bullshit.
Speaker 0: Yeah, everyone smart knows that question is bullshit.
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 0: but anyway, it's time for Things of the day.
Speaker 0: so I gotta be.
Speaker 0: you know, a lot of the channels I watch on YouTube lately as Much as I love them.
Speaker 0: I can't just make them my things of the day because it's like tech moan the 8-bit guy big Clive.
Speaker 0: like.
Speaker 0: a lot of the videos I watch are from the same set of like 20 YouTube people who like Terrapin dodgy electronics or I will not link lock-picking lawyer again Yeah, unless he opens a lock by breathing on it.
Speaker 0: But I found one that I can link to because I haven't talked about it on geek knives yet Practical engineering my favorite channels.
Speaker 0: because one they're really short videos like five to ten minutes long.
Speaker 0: No - they're actually practical useful engineering concepts and skills.
Speaker 0: and they're things like uh Say you got like a tiny dam on a tiny creek in your town and you wonder what the deal is with like all those weird ridges at the bottom or like a berm or a Rainage-ditch or any of those kinds of things.
Speaker 0: these videos explain like the physics and Engineering behind those in a very direct and practical way and it teaches actual useful practical skills.
Speaker 0: Okay, like how do you hold pipes together?
Speaker 0: How do you hold pipes together underwater or underground?
Speaker 0: The answer is not weld them together very rarely.
Speaker 0: Do they do that?
Speaker 0: Why if you if you have a faucet, here's one that actually might be super useful to some of you You have a faucet in your house or your school where if you close it too quickly You hear like this bang in the distance.
Speaker 0: That is real fucking bad news.
Speaker 0: It's called a water hammer.
Speaker 1: No, I have not had that never encountered that.
Speaker 1: no But I've had what faucets?
Speaker 1: we turn it on and they go and it goes digga digga digga and then the water comes out.
Speaker 0: Yep, this can explain that too.
Speaker 0: Okay, this channel is just real good And the one I'm gonna link to is why do pipes move underground like you put some pipes down.
Speaker 0: Why do they move?
Speaker 0: Why is this a problem?
Speaker 0: Why do pipes?
Speaker 0: pipes break if nothing touch the earth is alive?
Speaker 0: It has nothing to do with the earth.
Speaker 1: things get hot and cold.
Speaker 0: nope Okay, it has to do primarily with the pressure of the fluid going through the pipes Coupled with when there are curves or joins in the pipes.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm and it talks about that in detail.
Speaker 0: Yes, there are there like if there's an earthquake.
Speaker 0: Yes, that'll also Pipes, you know shit if you didn't fill the pipes in the right way.
Speaker 0: but this channel is just really cool because it mostly shows very like He'll make a little rig to like demonstrate the principle that you could literally just go in your backyard and make in like a couple hours.
Speaker 1: So what he got so way back in the 70s, right some?
Speaker 1: Enterprising person.
Speaker 1: What's their name?
Speaker 1: Steve Peck.
Speaker 1: Steve Peck, right?
Speaker 1: After you know Looney Tunes had ended over a decade earlier, right?
Speaker 1: At least they had Warner Brothers to stop making new ones before they started again, obviously, right?
Speaker 1: Made their own Elmer Fudd Bugs Bunny Daffy Duck cartoon in which Elmer Fudd is a drug dealer in Central Park and I clicked The mafia the mafia bosses.
Speaker 1: Oh my boy You're 70 are pressuring Elmer to sell his drugs to pay them what the what he owes.
Speaker 1: and Daffy and bugs are the addicts he's trying to sell to.
Speaker 1: and You know, they try to pull a fast one over on them because that's how they do.
Speaker 0: I see people make videos like this to my little pony all the time.
Speaker 0: Why is this man?
Speaker 1: They basically did a complete Animation right.
Speaker 1: they animated all the characters and did all the voice acting.
Speaker 1: only the most of the backgrounds are just like video of Central Park as opposed to drawn backgrounds And it's a complete Animation.
Speaker 1: it's like actually well like seven eight minutes long and a half minutes long, right?
Speaker 1: It's like a full Looney Tune length.
Speaker 1: So the story.
Speaker 1: I think the person said that they showed it.
Speaker 0: They showed you
Speaker 1: text Avery and text Avery loved it and what it would have was said like this is incredible Except I'm 80 years old and I can't offer you a job because I'm 80 years old yeah, and they showed it to Jones and Chuck Jones was conservative and like get this the fuck out of here you piece.
Speaker 1: No, I said something not nice.
Speaker 0: The coolest thing about this though is just that 1975 this is like yeah, this person had cells and animated by hand, right?
Speaker 0: They definitely you can see the VCR tech and like.
Speaker 0: they weren't the best at animating But they were pretty good better than me Yeah, especially considering the tool set yet available in 1975.
Speaker 1: the characters are off model The animations are little blare the resolutions bad, you know But still way better than I would do.
Speaker 1: and for a 70-something doing it at home, right?
Speaker 1: And also it's the writing.
Speaker 1: is you know, the pace is a little off?
Speaker 1: It's not.
Speaker 1: it could use an editor too, but it still got some good gags in it.
Speaker 0: pretty funny.
Speaker 0: This is the kind of thing before YouTube in the modern internet where someone would like Have this file or have a VHS tape and bust it out at a party.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, and people would like not even believe that it existed.
Speaker 1: It's gonna be like a legendary VHS that like a few people would have a copy of yep But now it's on YouTube.
Speaker 1: ever can see it.
Speaker 0: This is actually kind of amazing and not that many.
Speaker 0: This is only got 30,000 views.
Speaker 1: Yep I don't know what's up with that and 69 subscribers.
Speaker 0: I'll subscribe to Steve Peck.
Speaker 0: I hope he hasn't done anything bad.
Speaker 1: We'll find out.
Speaker 0: Comments are turned off on this too for some reason.
Speaker 1: It probably should be Surprise there hasn't been a copyright takedown from Warner Brothers.
Speaker 0: Maybe there has been.
Speaker 0: one of the things they can do is turn off comments on your videos find out and monetize them.
Speaker 0: We'll see in a moment.
Speaker 0: The geek nice book club book is the tale of Genji.
Speaker 1: I'm reading it.
Speaker 1: All right, no commute.
Speaker 1: So I got no commute.
Speaker 1: Does that mean less reading or home?
Speaker 1: Saving on less between one and two hours a day?
Speaker 0: The problem is it more reading but if I'm home and I have time saved I'm either making YouTube videos for geek nights or I'm playing overwatch.
Speaker 1: Yeah I have been producing more content and playing more games and and I've been reading more comics but less Book and I see a lot of your board.
Speaker 0: There's like 20 people watching this live stream, right?
Speaker 1: People do and you got everybody's working from home.
Speaker 1: go make something.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we're making right now at least.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm making something right now.
Speaker 1: Follow my example.
Speaker 1: if you like me so much and make something and stop watching and listening to something.
Speaker 0: Why don't I retail of Genji now?
Speaker 0: because commuting and poop it at work for the two times I would read it.
Speaker 1: Maybe I should just do it whenever I poop period.
Speaker 0: Oh the home poop.
Speaker 1: Yeah Yeah, if I poop Kindle app only that's the rule.
Speaker 1: That's the new rule.
Speaker 0: All right, that's my new strategy.
Speaker 1: the new rule Clever if you poop you can.
Speaker 1: the only app you're allowed to open is an e-book reading app.
Speaker 1: Yep All right.
Speaker 1: That's a new rule.
Speaker 0: This is the way.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: I Saw the whole Mandalorian and I love it.
Speaker 0: Okay, you should watch though.
Speaker 0: There's only four more episodes.
Speaker 1: I got it stuff to watch.
Speaker 0: All I'm saying is no, they do turn into plot stuff.
Speaker 0: It's not just more.
Speaker 0: Here's the curse.
Speaker 1: I'm sure they do.
Speaker 0: Yeah Anyway, otherwise, we do not have any conventions for a while Not just because of coronavirus, but because actually our next scheduled major convention.
Speaker 0: It was gonna be PAX West anyway.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so we'll see if PAX West happens Like it looks like 50/50 as a. yeah, but we'll see never bought a plane ticket so nerd and tie.
Speaker 0: It seems like they're gonna try to do an online Convention where they're gonna make a panel's track.
Speaker 0: But what they want is people who normally do panels at nerdy conventions Sign us up for any of those that exist.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: They want to just do audio only because that's easier to start.
Speaker 0: Okay, so I'm trying to figure out.
Speaker 0: the problem is most of our panels We lied without the slides know like 40 40 games.
Speaker 0: You should play.
Speaker 0: it sounds easy, right?
Speaker 0: We don't fucking say the name of the game half the time because the slide is up.
Speaker 0: So I'm looking for panels.
Speaker 0: we've done where the slides.
Speaker 0: it's okay for someone to just hear the audio and be able to look at The slides but I don't need they can't need to see the slide to understand what we're talking about.
Speaker 1: I've also been thinking about doing this for a while even before everyone was sent home.
Speaker 1: I'm not sure if I should actually say my idea because then it would be shit talking.
Speaker 0: No, but I'm not saying anything.
Speaker 0: I'm trying to work on right now.
Speaker 1: No but the idea I've had for a while which you know, I guess has a chance of coming to fruition because it is lower effort than other ideas.
Speaker 1: is The thing we're good at is doing panels, right?
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: So why not just make panels and Just do them for YouTube at home.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and no one has to approve or reject our idea meaning we can No one can tell me not to do that panel.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I just come up with a panel.
Speaker 1: It could be doesn't it be an hour.
Speaker 1: It could be longer.
Speaker 1: It could be shorter.
Speaker 1: It could be any topic.
Speaker 1: It'd be anything even better.
Speaker 0: We can use the new YouTube live stream premier thing so we can do it with an online audience To have at least people reacting to it.
Speaker 1: Right, but I'm just saying like, you know I could just make some slides stand in front of the camera run the slides edit the slides into the video.
Speaker 0: Yep, right.
Speaker 1: I don't need to do it live and then Put it up and there you go.
Speaker 1: I did and I could do it.
Speaker 1: For example, we did it.
Speaker 1: We'll do a panel.
Speaker 0: I want to do the one we did.
Speaker 0: we already have one panel.
Speaker 0: We did that.
Speaker 0: we've never videoed anywhere.
Speaker 0: I have a recording audio recording of it that I gave to the patreon patrons only with slides But at the point it like for example We'll do a panel like how to win at games.
Speaker 1: I could take like just one slide from that panel.
Speaker 1: Right, like one way to win at games and do like up.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, I could do like positional heuristic the panel.
Speaker 1: It's ten minutes.
Speaker 1: Yeah and that's the video.
Speaker 0: we can we can do all that also a Lot of those what you just described are the panels that we used to do as part of those triple threat panels.
Speaker 0: We used to do a packs or we'd have three 20-minute panel ideas But we couldn't turn any one of them into an hour, right?
Speaker 0: That's like the perfect kind of content to do like this is.
Speaker 1: this is a good idea I think.
Speaker 0: to start well also this we should do Competitive versus casual because we already wrote that panel.
Speaker 0: We just haven't done it except at magfest once.
Speaker 1: I also want to point out we've had this idea of doing videos of how to win it board games.
Speaker 0: I saw someone seems to be trying to someone.
Speaker 1: an awesome group of people is already fucking doing it and I want to shout out To them.
Speaker 1: Let me just find out their name one sec Yep, and shoot me a link.
Speaker 1: It's show me how to win calm.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so go to show me how to win calm.
Speaker 1: They are making videos right Showing you how to win at board games.
Speaker 1: That is the idea that we had.
Speaker 1: they're doing it and executing on it.
Speaker 1: Yeah ahead of us props to them.
Speaker 1: That's awesome.
Speaker 0: we might also do it but I think our Demographic because I feel like the games we're gonna focus on.
Speaker 0: the problem is we can only actually do this for games.
Speaker 0: We've played enough to grok.
Speaker 0: Yep, and in the modern era, it's hard.
Speaker 0: We can't play like Maria 40 times like we did Puerto Rico.
Speaker 1: Yeah But anyway, there it is.
Speaker 1: If you're looking for that content and waiting for our slow shit talking asses to they're moving faster.
Speaker 1: Go someone else is already doing it.
Speaker 1: Go check them out.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Alright.
Speaker 0: Alright, so we're not talking about working from home.
Speaker 0: Cuz you're all sick of that shit.
Speaker 1: Have you done two episodes on that in 2009?
Speaker 1: We did telecommuting and in 2018 late 2018 we did work from home.
Speaker 1: So we're not doing that again.
Speaker 1: No matter how relevant it is.
Speaker 1: Go listen to the old episodes.
Speaker 1: They're up there.
Speaker 0: So when you're done looking at the bad screen, you're stuck at home.
Speaker 0: You're working from home.
Speaker 0: You've looked at the bad screen all day.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: You have two screens at home.
Speaker 1: Now you had a bad one and a good one and you by 45 rolls around.
Speaker 1: you close the bad screen For at a 40 I turn off the bad screen.
Speaker 0: But you don't always want to just look at the good screen Like.
Speaker 0: sometimes you want to like go hang out with your friends or like do the stuff you normally?
Speaker 1: yeah Can't because it's a bad time.
Speaker 0: So now you've got to not work from home with a good screen.
Speaker 0: You have a good screen still
Speaker 1: at home and you have to do not work things Right, and if you're not just a completely introverted person who's completely happy just hiding in your bed doing reading a book or playing Video games, how do you gonna replace your outside large social gathering biz?
Speaker 0: When you're stuck in the house, yep Now I do know a lot of a lot of introverted people online and pointed out that This is not nearly as hard for some people as this for others.
Speaker 0: obviously and very extroverted people are having a very hard time with This right now.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, I'm even getting antsy like I gotta hang out like I just get antsy cuz I didn't leave the house until.
Speaker 1: oh, I didn't leave that until now.
Speaker 1: I've been in my house since When I guess since oh god, oh no since I went to the restaurant after the food fell on the floor We went outside to pick up essentials from the grocery store.
Speaker 1: I know the grocery on the way home, then we go back in the home Yep, and we won't.
Speaker 0: we go for a walk every day around lunchtime because we're both working from home.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna do biking.
Speaker 0: Yep, but So if you're trapped inside and going crazy Like how do you how do you do it in the modern era?
Speaker 0: and the good news is it's both harder and easier now Than it's ever been but we've lost a lot of the even better ways that used to exist.
Speaker 0: So it's kind of fractured now.
Speaker 0: And I think I want to focus on the things that actually work today and not try to get into like the history like IRC is dead unless you're crazy like don't pretend the technologist man.
Speaker 1: The point is chat rooms.
Speaker 1: Don't really do it?
Speaker 1: No, I'm or even when I'm going out of the house.
Speaker 1: I'm already in a chat rooms all day.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like winter doesn't do it I'm already tweeting all day when I'm going out of house.
Speaker 0: It doesn't help like the only difference between me at work in the bed screen and me at home in the good screen Is that I'm not checking my discords and all my other things like constantly at work because I'm busy, right?
Speaker 0: But I still like see them right?
Speaker 1: So what you got to do is you got to replace, you know, your large social gathering, right?
Speaker 1: So one thing you can do is it's still okay to have a few people over your house That's not.
Speaker 0: if that's not really yeah read all the literature online like to households that are themselves.
Speaker 1: I came over to this house.
Speaker 0: Yep, quarantining can merge together and share that risk within their local group But like don't don't do that with too many people you can read online like the best practices for all this time, right?
Speaker 1: But uh, so you could get some board games going on that way, but number one board games.
Speaker 0: Tabletop simulator is pretty fucking good.
Speaker 0: Yeah works.
Speaker 0: It's good enough.
Speaker 1: I mean, it's not good But if you're got no other choice, it's gonna save you.
Speaker 0: Yeah Cuz here's the deal.
Speaker 0: tabletop simulator is basically a fixed physics engine with a bunch of like Boardgame specific things built in to make it easy to make tabletop games and it pretty much just works.
Speaker 1: And the interface is really bad.
Speaker 1: It's hard to figure out how to get it started But once it started and you're connected then you're good.
Speaker 0: It does kind of just work.
Speaker 0: it partly depends on you got to go find like games people have made Often of dubious legality the Steam Workshop.
Speaker 0: Yep But the one thing I'll say is if you happen to have a VR headset it.
Speaker 0: actually this is the one time Like the only time the UX in VR is way better than the UX on a desktop Like it.
Speaker 1: literally like you reach out You don't have to know what button to press to grab or put or want to roll some dice.
Speaker 0: grab them throw them They roll.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like it just works.
Speaker 0: want to play a card Where is it?
Speaker 1: How do you roll dice with the mouse?
Speaker 1: Like click on the dice and then I move.
Speaker 1: it's like you got to figure it out the buttons.
Speaker 1: But
Speaker 0: my real advice is if you have a friend who's kind of into tabletop simulator Get them to teach all your friends how to use it and like play a few games just to learn like you'll fuck it Up a few times
Speaker 1: right find someone who is gonna take the lead and be like, alright, I'm running this.
Speaker 1: Yep, right and then make it as easy as possible because you need these other people who are not say as technically savvy.
Speaker 1: This is the Monday show.
Speaker 1: You have to be the one the Monday geek nights listener who has not taken my advice to go do something else With your technical skills, you have to set it up and make it as easy as humanly possible For everyone else to get in on it in order to make it happen.
Speaker 0: You don't it won't happen Even if you're a jerk and you hate your friends like.
Speaker 0: this is enlightened self-interest.
Speaker 0: Imagine a board game person.
Speaker 0: You love train games.
Speaker 0: No one around you loves train games.
Speaker 0: You have a vested interest in making people around you want to play train games with you.
Speaker 0: It's the same thing if you're that TTS person.
Speaker 0: Make TTS easy for your friends and they will totally do it with you and strike now while the iron's hot, right?
Speaker 1: So now you got to think about the other things that you're doing at home, right?
Speaker 1: Find ways to digitally connect with other people doing the same thing, right?
Speaker 1: So if you're you know, you're introverted staying inside the house, you're reading a book.
Speaker 1: Don't just read the book and put it on the shelf.
Speaker 1: find other people who read in the book.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right.
Speaker 1: Maybe make a little book club action going on.
Speaker 1: I'll just maybe that you know have a little you know.
Speaker 1: Be like put on your schedule like use your online schedule with your friends and be like, alright Everyone's working at home until 5 At 6 o'clock today or 7 after dinner.
Speaker 1: We're gonna discuss chapters 1 & 2 of the book right?
Speaker 1: So now people actually feel obligated to read it.
Speaker 1: They'll do it while they're on their Kindle app obligate on their toilet.
Speaker 1: They'll read the chapter.
Speaker 0: This works real well with.
Speaker 1: they're not allowed to do anything else.
Speaker 0: any TV show you could watch like anything like you want to rewatch TNG just find other friends who will also want to watch.
Speaker 1: Make other people consume the same media at the same time so that you can discuss With them intentionally right so you're not sort of trapped in your own media landscape now.
Speaker 1: And also a lot of things these days have features where you can watch together.
Speaker 1: We're like, you'll all be watching at the same time while you have a voice chat open, right?
Speaker 0: I'm trying.
Speaker 1: so it was like it's like you're watching in the same room, even though you're watching in faraway rooms.
Speaker 0: So I'm trying a bunch of those out to figure out which ones kind of work the best and have the least like dodginess to Them yeah, and we'll post in the forum like some recommendations once I try them out, but I found one that was kind of crazy Totally illegal, but I was in VR chat on Sunday and someone made a room that was called the anime hangout room.
Speaker 1: They made it recently and they're just showing anime.
Speaker 0: so if you go into this room it's like an apartment and you can just kind of hang around in the room with this big screen on the wall and They have a library of bootleg anime full seasons of like recent stuff And you can just start it.
Speaker 0: so you and like 20 people can hang out in VR chat watching an anime But in a room interacting hmm.
Speaker 0: It's actually pretty cool and kind of just works like.
Speaker 1: I don't see why that wouldn't work.
Speaker 0: I hung out with some nerds, and I watched like 10 minutes of attack on Titan and it was weirdly Satisfying because it's not the same as like we're watching the show and then we talk about it.
Speaker 0: that serves one need.
Speaker 0: But you know that feeling of like you've got something on the TV but you're also kind of just hanging out and like riffing off each other like in person because like two people can walk to the back of the room and kind of talk and That talking is really quiet or even inaudible to people who are closer to the TV.
Speaker 0: because it's all proximity based VR chat is obviously only an option for people who have money or happen to already have a bunch of VR shit set up.
Speaker 1: you Can do VR chat with just your computer?
Speaker 0: Yeah, the VR chat desktop client actually is pretty good.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it works.
Speaker 1: I used it one time yeah.
Speaker 0: So I'm gonna explore setting up some hangout times in VR chat for people who want to hang out.
Speaker 0: hmm But basically find the tools that enable these things like tabletop simulator VR chat whatever of the ten watch anime with my friends in a semi-legal streaming manner and Use them, but like Scott said you have to be don't be the bystander you have to be the person who facilitates.
Speaker 0: Yeah, make it happen for your friends.
Speaker 1: one person has to take that on and make it happen right and all those since you Have you know if you're working from home?
Speaker 1: You'll have more spare time.
Speaker 1: at least for me It's like one to two hours a day.
Speaker 0: yeah for me I don't because my commute is like eight minutes.
Speaker 1: well I mean like if I bike to work It's what 40 something.
Speaker 0: yeah, it's so 40 minutes times to 80 minute But if I bike to work it takes 12 minutes.
Speaker 0: like I'm not really saving a lot of time.
Speaker 1: I save a lot of time.
Speaker 0: Emily walks to us.
Speaker 1: There's also time saved.
Speaker 1: not taking a shower not getting.
Speaker 0: You don't dress or take showers when you work from home.
Speaker 1: I put clothes on right before coming here, and I haven't showered in two or three days.
Speaker 0: So I did not shower this morning.
Speaker 1: Do I smell bad?
Speaker 0: you know I'm not gonna pretend I showered this morning.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna see.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna actually shave and shower when I get home to.
Speaker 0: in fact I was my plan because I was working all day.
Speaker 1: I didn't want to shower.
Speaker 1: I was I would have showered this morning cuz I felt dirty, but I was gonna shave my head tonight.
Speaker 0: So I still shower once a day But I don't have to shower right before work like normal.
Speaker 0: exactly the morning routine is a lot easier.
Speaker 1: a lot of time is saved Here and there yeah.
Speaker 1: And with that save time all those sort of higher effort things now become Doable.
Speaker 1: yeah, it's sort of like ah that board game that takes a lot of time to set up.
Speaker 0: I got time to set it up before people join TTS to play it with me right or that thing I want to cook for dinner.
Speaker 1: that takes an hour instead of 30 minutes.
Speaker 0: Oh, I can soak the beans this morning And they'll be ready when I want to you.
Speaker 1: I can marinate the meat as soon as I wake up and cook it for dinner.
Speaker 0: Right I can count the number of times I've marinated meat for the appropriate amount of time.
Speaker 1: on one hand right so I mean mostly for games But any other sort of.
Speaker 1: you know digital social thing that requires an advanced setup is now doable.
Speaker 0: Yep, right But I really are.
Speaker 1: you just have to be the one to do it all the hard parts and make it easy for the other People because they're not going to be able to do it and join it.
Speaker 0: yep, and even more It's not even if they're not capable of it.
Speaker 0: It's that you know.
Speaker 0: there's sort of a by much effort.
Speaker 0: But the bystander effect like if someone's hurt in a crowd.
Speaker 0: a lot of people will agree that person needs help and will call for.
Speaker 0: But if the whole crowd is just doing that it's easy for no one to actually call 9-1-1 like that's a thing that happens.
Speaker 1: so This advice if I if I see a thing whenever I see a thing like that going on It's like has anyone call 9-1-1.
Speaker 1: I go.
Speaker 1: I'm like you call 9-1-1 right.
Speaker 1: It's like as soon as I Gotta I'll often like bike past an accident of some kind, but that's only after I verified.
Speaker 1: okay This is definitely taking care of I am not needed.
Speaker 1: if it's not taking care of yet Yeah, then I stop and take care of it.
Speaker 0: Yep, even if there's like a pile of people I just I've stopped and verify and make sure yeah has someone at least called 9-1-1 like so It's not to that direness for social interactions yet.
Speaker 0: Maybe if we're stuck like this for six months.
Speaker 0: It'll get a little more dire.
Speaker 0: but Don't fall prey to the bystander effect.
Speaker 0: if you want this to happen and you see all your friends also wanted to happen like you're listening To this now just be the one and make it happen even if it's low effort.
Speaker 0: like.
Speaker 0: Discord is a great tool because discord streaming we talked about it the other day But now it's a good point to talking about it again.
Speaker 0: It just fucking works.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and it doesn't require fancy set up of OBS.
Speaker 1: You just push a button and it goes.
Speaker 0: Yep If you already and if you're if the thing you're streaming does desktop audio it just works.
Speaker 0: if you already can talk to people on Discord then that same talking setup just transfers to the stream.
Speaker 0: Like it's brilliant.
Speaker 0: Don't worry about privacy.
Speaker 0: It'll only stream to the people in your discord in that channel.
Speaker 1: There are other technologies though that you shouldn't discount right?
Speaker 1: So for example, I read a story just today or yesterday that Japanese elementary school held their graduation in Minecraft because they couldn't hold it anywhere else, right?
Speaker 1: So I guess they made a school auditorium in Minecraft and they all had.
Speaker 1: there was like a you know A green monster whatever the creeper on stage Graduating right.
Speaker 1: and I think what the lessons here are a Consider all possible technologies, you know software is that let people get together.
Speaker 1: Yeah that people already have and know how to use and are easy.
Speaker 1: But also Any event that is being canceled, right?
Speaker 1: You should find a way to replace it digitally Yep, even if you can't replace it fully.
Speaker 0: It's definitely give me an air sats version of that.
Speaker 1: I know right but whatever that way it's like, you know, if you don't have just use that thing, you know even if the replacement event is Basically not even remotely close to the actual event.
Speaker 1: it's replacing.
Speaker 1: use the existence of the original real world canceled event as The seed to actually plan and execute a replacement thing.
Speaker 1: So for example, right hockey's not happening, right?
Speaker 1: I'm seeing people in the hockey community doing two things so far.
Speaker 1: one They're getting together and playing the remainder of the season in NHL.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the video is gonna bring that up.
Speaker 0: if you didn't bring that up right Emily showed me that this morning.
Speaker 0: they're.
Speaker 1: also there's another group of people who are Simulating the rest of the season with spreadsheets game by game as they happen And then talking about him as if they happen.
Speaker 1: Yep, and even fantasy sports in them as if they had right.
Speaker 1: So That's right.
Speaker 1: They're using the.
Speaker 1: the games no longer exist the real ones.
Speaker 1: They're just taking that seed of the thing that was canceled to Instigate a replacement thing.
Speaker 1: Yep, right.
Speaker 1: So if you had a thing that was happening in your life, it could have been anything.
Speaker 1: It could have been a major event like a wedding or apartments.
Speaker 0: It's got a minor thing like your monthly dinner with the extended family, right?
Speaker 1: So whatever thing you had that was canceled replace that thing with a digital version of the thing.
Speaker 1: Yep So or something that is adjacent to that thing close get as close as do something that counts it.
Speaker 1: But anime Boston was canceled.
Speaker 1: do that.
Speaker 1: Just get some anime panels.
Speaker 1: post them online.
Speaker 1: What I see?
Speaker 1: artists alleys all over.
Speaker 1: people are going on Twitter.
Speaker 1: How can their artists alley emerge?
Speaker 1: David Peterson who can't go to the mouse guard artist?
Speaker 1: Yeah, he can't go to Was a Seattle Emerald City comic-con.
Speaker 1: Yep He's being twitch streaming and selling all kinds of merch and all kinds of biz.
Speaker 1: it's basically like he has an Artist alley booth running of him on his twitch channel.
Speaker 1: go check him out.
Speaker 1: And so many are.
Speaker 0: the artists are doing the same, but here's the key.
Speaker 0: You do don't feel like you have to be productive in these endeavors Like we're like we're gonna do a bunch of social stuff, but we're also aiming toward like.
Speaker 0: it doesn't be productive.
Speaker 0: It's just replacing hanging out that you've lost But like if you make this hanging out work just for like you and for friends hanging out Just hanging out.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean like.
Speaker 0: We always talk a lot.
Speaker 0: if we had tried to do this earlier in our lives like while we were still at our IT We'd probably more successful now, but we probably couldn't have made it Would we if we didn't be more successful in 15 years?
Speaker 1: We're getting more successful in 20 years.
Speaker 1: I think that you're saying five years from now will be more successful I think.
Speaker 0: I think what I'm saying is that there was a time when the iron was hotter to strike on some of this stuff.
Speaker 1: Maybe but if we had tried pretty sure we've been there every time the pad cast iron has been struck To do anything serious at our IT.
Speaker 0: instead of wasting all that time we could never have made anything we've ever made.
Speaker 0: The only reason we can make any of this is because we wasted all that time at our IT.
Speaker 0: That wasted time is what made me who I am.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we would not Times and learned how to talk about board game.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I mean I say wasted but it's not wasted It's that's what I played.
Speaker 1: battle broken into a conference room to play a battle tag.
Speaker 1: When would I have ever had been able to tell a story about breaking to a conference room to play battle day?
Speaker 0: Yeah, but no we would have been like, you know, our friends were like yo building sevens unlock.
Speaker 0: We're gonna play battle tech and we're like, no, no, no, we got to work on our podcast.
Speaker 0: So, uh But yeah, the tools are there.
Speaker 0: I wonder what do we do about old people and old friends like not like people who can't use this stuff?
Speaker 0: Well, I think you there are still ways like how do you how do you if those bridge that divide also?
Speaker 1: So, you know if someone's not super connected, right and you want to connect with them Maybe your parents or something, right?
Speaker 1: It's like you sort of have to like I said make it easy for them, right?
Speaker 1: So there are things they already have that they're likely not using.
Speaker 1: you just have to because hopefully They're bored or alone enough that you can instigate them into using them, right?
Speaker 1: So maybe instead of calling your parents FaceTime if they got on right Maybe you know, it's like maybe they got an Apple TV.
Speaker 1: I'm sure there's some Apple TV thing you can do that You just never bothered to do some feature in there to connect with them watch.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I have never used an Apple TV in what I know.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right, but whatever technology they've already got set up Right you go through the effort smart Monday listener technology person and figure out what they can already do that They're not doing right and do as much of it.
Speaker 1: You can on your end to get the other person in from their end, right?
Speaker 1: The best thing would be to do is I mean ideally you can set something up where you can send them a link to click On in a young man, right and the link will do everything.
Speaker 0: and honestly You might just have to take it where you can get it.
Speaker 0: Like you might end up having to make an SMS group chat with like all your relatives who don't understand how anything works.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm, that might be annoying but it will probably fill at least some of that social gap your head.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean for example, right?
Speaker 1: It's like maybe your parents are not cool They're not gonna get on a discord or even a Twitter, right?
Speaker 1: Maybe but they're probably all.
Speaker 0: my mom were like watches these streams and is on Twitter.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 1: Hi Rose mom Yeah, but your parents probably on Facebook.
Speaker 1: Grandma's probably on Facebook, right?
Speaker 0: I don't advocate using Facebook.
Speaker 0: Just delete that account.
Speaker 1: I'm saying they're there.
Speaker 1: you could go and figure out how to stream on Facebook and they'll fucking see it.
Speaker 1: No, they will.
Speaker 1: so there you can go, you know go to where they are All right, I hunger up.
Speaker 0: I to hunger and I gotta go all right.
Speaker 0: see you guys on Wednesday.
Speaker 1: See you on the internet.
Speaker 0: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Speaker 1: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 0: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 0: But unlike those other late shows It's actually recorded at night and the patreon patrons for this episode of geek nights are Alan Joyce Heidi McNichol Marty green.
Speaker 0: Yeah, just like a dude guys your topish and linky G You'll the key to my heart.
Speaker 0: I got in one little fight and my mom got scared.
Speaker 0: Clinton Walton J Bantz Ren from New Zealand Ryan parent rope and letter Nicholas Brando Chris midkiff Mac the thirst for hydrated Gannon dread Lily Tenebrae Chris Reimer Finn Sean Klein Tom is on shiver Von Harl and a bunch of other people who don't want me to say their names.
Speaker 0: and now I leave you with.
Speaker 0: Hey, do you want to feel so?
Speaker 1: Energetic try power thirst energy drinks for people who need gratuitous amounts of energy with all new flavors like chocolate Chocolate energy, it's like adding chocolate to an electrical store.
Speaker 1: Sound the alarm.
Speaker 1: You're gonna be uncomfortably energetic.
Speaker 0: What's that?
Speaker 0: You want strawberry?
Speaker 1: Well, how about raw berry made with lightning real lightning sports?
Speaker 1: Oh, you'll be good at them.
Speaker 1: It's an energy drink for men.
Speaker 1: These aren't your dad's puns.
Speaker 0: These are energy puns Turbo puns.
Speaker 0: Science energy science energy electrolytes turbo light power lights more lights that your body has room for.
Speaker 1: You'll be so fast.
Speaker 1: mother nature will be like slow.
Speaker 1: You'll be like fuck you and kick her in the face with your energy legs.
Speaker 1: You'll have so much energy energy Just running all the time.
Speaker 1: power running.
Speaker 1: power lifting.
Speaker 1: power sweeping power.
Speaker 1: dating.
Speaker 0: power eating.
Speaker 0: power laughing.
Speaker 0: power spawning babies.
Speaker 1: You'll have so many babies 400 babies.