Speaker 1: It's Monday October 26 2020.
Speaker 1: I'm rim.
Speaker 1: I'm Scott and this is geek nights.
Speaker 1: tonight We are talking about facial recognition technology.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: Tried to vote.
Speaker 1: I do you know voting's big this year.
Speaker 1: like a lot of people are voting who have never voted before a lot Of people are trying to vote early.
Speaker 1: a lot of people who were gonna mail a ballot aren't mailing a ballot because the post office I hope these people vote You know next year and the year after.
Speaker 0: yeah, well you're after that.
Speaker 1: It's tricky though because some of them have never voted before but a lot of them are also voting early and avoiding You know post office problems, but I figured New York City the first day of early voting.
Speaker 1: I wasn't going anywhere near that because I got a whole week where I can vote.
Speaker 0: well election is the thing about the early voting right is I?
Speaker 0: Finally, this is the first time during I think a major election that New York City State has had early voting because we passed it Thanks to our previous elections that where we didn't early vote we regular voted And we voted for people who may vote
Speaker 1: in election years that aren't leap years guys like come on.
Speaker 0: Yeah We voted that.
Speaker 0: those years we were able to get you know the early voting to happen in the first place.
Speaker 0: So normally the election day is a Tuesday, which is really stupid.
Speaker 0: That's what they wrote in the freaking Constitution.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: So then right people are fucking working on Tuesday, so as soon as early voting now you can vote on Saturday and Sunday.
Speaker 0: That's how people can turn out.
Speaker 0: they don't to go to fucking work.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I can vote right.
Speaker 1: especially Silver link to that talked about.
Speaker 1: what are the specific reasons Americans don't vote?
Speaker 1: and the number one reason across all Demographics was the wait in line to vote was more than an hour.
Speaker 0: Yeah, also People you know there is technically a law that your boss is like let you go vote on Tuesday.
Speaker 0: I don't do that work.
Speaker 0: well You know people don't have the balls to tell their boss that and then fight.
Speaker 0: and you're right.
Speaker 0: whatever they just go to work.
Speaker 0: Yeah More important than going to vote for them.
Speaker 0: so but I figured I wouldn't go on the first day because I figured that's usually the day When people I knew Saturday and Sunday were gonna be a complete trash fire.
Speaker 0: because you know for early voting Not only is this the only time you can vote on the weekend.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right the early voting in New York has fewer locations than actual election day.
Speaker 0: election day There's like tons of locations open because all these people who don't work on election day go to become poll workers Yeah, and that that way that enables them to open up more locations during the early voting.
Speaker 0: It's only the locations that the BOE has staff for that can work all those days.
Speaker 0: You know the old retired people and such.
Speaker 0: And so there's a lot less locations with a lot less hours.
Speaker 0: and because it's weekend This is the only time on the weekend less locations.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's gonna be a long line.
Speaker 1: Yep, so Saturday We got there.
Speaker 1: All right, right when it opened and the line we see a line like, okay, it doesn't look so bad It's socially distanced line.
Speaker 0: people really really really want to vote right now.
Speaker 1: So we walk down the line walk down the line keep walking down the line and then oh, there's the end of it.
Speaker 1: Nope, it's like a PAX line.
Speaker 1: It's around the corner and then around another corner and then and I then we realized it was like a four or five hour line And we're gonna vote a different day Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: So I what I did is I say I'm gonna vote early and often.
Speaker 0: I sent in the mail-in ballot long ago But oh, I'm gonna go a New York, right?
Speaker 0: So there were other people from other states who are my friends who were saying Oh New York is so dumb they don't open the absentee ballots till after and They talked about how someone showed up to vote in person who had received an absentee ballot in the mail At least according to the records, but they had not brought it with them to prove that they had not used it.
Speaker 0: Therefore they had to fill out a provisional, you know affidavit Ballot because you know as soon as that state receives ballots in the mail from voters They open them right away.
Speaker 1: New York doesn't open them till after the election Although no states open them in advance, which is a big problem.
Speaker 0: Well, some states do they're including my friends.
Speaker 1: Yeah, those states don't right.
Speaker 0: So not voting them till after is actually kind of good because it.
Speaker 0: the advantage is that I can now Vote by mail and then if I feel like voting in person, maybe I just changed my fucking mind.
Speaker 0: I don't know, right?
Speaker 0: Maybe I just want to make sure.
Speaker 0: maybe I not sure if I'll be able to vote in person So I send one in in case I can't.
Speaker 0: but then if I can I go and do that anyway.
Speaker 0: and what happens is when they go on the day after the election or the night or whatever they start opening the absentee ballots once The polls close and they see wait a minute.
Speaker 0: This is from Scott.
Speaker 0: Scott voted in person near his town near his house.
Speaker 0: We'll just throw this one in the trash.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but some states can't even do that.
Speaker 0: And maybe I'll get lucky and They won't throw it in the trash and I'll get to vote twice Once they crime I. They can't prove it because once they open that second envelope they because what they do is there's the there's the outside envelope.
Speaker 1: They got an admission right here live on geek nights.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they open that first day open the first envelope right and now now they're sitting at the second envelope Which is my name on it, right and those envelopes they've.
Speaker 0: don't open them, but they verify each one.
Speaker 0: So this is the part where they would say Oh this envelope says Scott on it and he voted at the school or whatever.
Speaker 0: or the old folks home Throw this out and they throw out the whole thing.
Speaker 0: Right if they open if they mess that up and they open that envelope and they throw up.
Speaker 0: then they throw out the envelope.
Speaker 0: This is Scott on it.
Speaker 0: Right now.
Speaker 0: They're left with an anonymous ballot.
Speaker 0: They gotta count it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right GG.
Speaker 0: I got to vote twice.
Speaker 0: maybe If they fuck up but legally I am allowed to both mail it in and then vote in person.
Speaker 1: so check your state laws.
Speaker 1: I'll just go.
Speaker 1: What check your state laws?
Speaker 1: Different cuz America is a really stupid country.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they explicitly allowed that in New York.
Speaker 0: So if I see that there's an opportunity to go vote in person and it's not crowded or anything and there's no line I'll go over and do it.
Speaker 0: And if no such opportunity presents itself, I already voted.
Speaker 1: The importance of this mode is not so much in New York cuz New York's gonna go blue no matter what but Kind of elections that got us early voting in the first place.
Speaker 1: Oh, but we have a sitting president who won't commit to the peaceful transfer of power and the Supreme Court has just been destroyed.
Speaker 1: so we're in a situation where if election night and the day after aren't a clear Biden victory then court cases and nonsense could actually overturn the election and cause a lot of Drama, the more votes get counted the day of the election the better Mmm, like.
Speaker 1: that's a really important thing, especially in certain states like Pennsylvania.
Speaker 1: that could determine the entire election Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: But yeah, so we're gonna go either like in the middle of a work day Like tomorrow like one day this week or they alternate the days like some days It opens at like 7 a.m.
Speaker 1: And closes at 4 and some days that opens is like 11 a.m.
Speaker 1: And closes like 8 p.m.
Speaker 0: Is that the poll workers can't work from 7 to 8 But they want to give some people who can go late an opportunity and some people can go early.
Speaker 1: and oh from what I heard The people have been stuck at the polling places every night for like four or five extra hours.
Speaker 1: because of how many people get in Line, they can't turn away.
Speaker 0: But if you went from 7 to 8 they'd be there from 7 to midnight instead of 10 to midnight or 7.
Speaker 1: You know that was always my strategy when I was a kid.
Speaker 1: We'd go to Cedar Point the roller coaster park and the park would close at 11.
Speaker 1: But all that meant was all the restaurants closed and all the lines don't let anyone else get in line.
Speaker 0: So what we would always do that was that mean that was that's you know, you were taking advantage of their policy But what they should what they should do is have the packs policy Which is it's six o'clock.
Speaker 0: a big wall of enforces just pushes everyone out immediately.
Speaker 1: the end Yeah, you gotta let people vote and if they're too slow to process voting.
Speaker 0: Yeah voting.
Speaker 0: Yes, but amusement park?
Speaker 0: Yeah, no, but if I ran the amusement park, I'd push you out But if I ran the voting I would not.
Speaker 1: it was so great though like me and all my friends would literally like get into a multi-hour line at 1059 with a pile of like chicken fingers and Mountain Dew and we would be the lat.
Speaker 1: we would try to be the last people in That line on purpose so we would be the last people walking out of the park at like whatever.
Speaker 0: just let everyone cut you.
Speaker 1: We would love anyone who came in after us.
Speaker 1: We'd always like cut.
Speaker 1: We were the last people in line having a chicken finger party.
Speaker 1: That was like a thing.
Speaker 0: I go for some chicken fingers right now.
Speaker 1: I actually could too.
Speaker 1: I'm pretty hungry.
Speaker 1: So there is actually some big news.
Speaker 1: It's not as big a news as some of you nerds are thinking but it is really big news.
Speaker 1: They have confirmed that there is water on the moon.
Speaker 1: We've suspected it for a long time.
Speaker 1: there's a lot of evidence of it, but they basically have Absolutely confirmed that there is significant amounts of water on the moon.
Speaker 0: If you collected all the water on the moon in a cup how big would the cup be?
Speaker 1: it'd be bigger than a cup now.
Speaker 0: It's like a swimming pool.
Speaker 1: Well, you can read the article to see all the details.
Speaker 1: But basically they found water in places.
Speaker 1: They didn't expect to find water and it seems to be protected.
Speaker 1: It's not a lot of water I think they said in those parts like on the sunny side of the moon like not on the poles There's the equivalent of a 12 ounce bottle of water per cubic meter of soil.
Speaker 0: not a ton big meter.
Speaker 1: 12 a Cubic yard is close enough.
Speaker 1: you can think of it.
Speaker 0: that and that's if you that's if you collect literally all the water which Is really hard to do even on earth right yeah?
Speaker 0: The water is basically trapped in like either dust particles or maybe like if I if I pull a plant out of the ground or Something that's got water in it right, but like can I extract a hundred percent of the water from that plant?
Speaker 0: It's pretty difficult.
Speaker 0: Well.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you can get pretty close.
Speaker 0: I can get a lot.
Speaker 0: I can get a lot, but you can't get all of it.
Speaker 1: You're not gonna get the full 12 ounces, but basically they found water in a lot of places around the moon and it implies that there might be a larger source of water near the poles and It's just cool that they actually like this was.
Speaker 1: this was saw I don't know decades and decades coming like the Soviets detected what they thought was water there in the late 70s But no one could ever prove it definitively until now.
Speaker 0: so it's hard to prove something.
Speaker 0: That's small and clear and you know yeah, also.
Speaker 1: It's not like we've sent anyone back to the moon to do more science.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we can only science it from with our more with our fancier technology.
Speaker 0: right the only.
Speaker 0: we've only explored the moon with you know 70s technology.
Speaker 1: yeah, basically and now we're scanning and analyzing it with 2000s technology, maybe some 2010s technology.
Speaker 1: Yep, so yeah, you can read the story like I'm not gonna like.
Speaker 1: that's the news.
Speaker 1: There's literally for real 100%.
Speaker 1: there is significant amounts of water on the moon, and that's actually pretty cool.
Speaker 0: Partly doesn't live up there that easily.
Speaker 1: There's a lot of things about space like things about black holes things about other Galaxies that are like quasars and things that we just think of.
Speaker 1: it's like common knowledge like oh, yeah We know that but a lot of things that are commonly understood and obvious about space We're only actually discovered in the last 30 or 40 years Like textbooks I had in elementary school did not have this information Mmm.
Speaker 0: Well.
Speaker 0: There's also just a lot of things.
Speaker 0: It's like you know we mostly know We're really really sure and then there'll be a news That's like it's a hundred percent or at least as not a hundred percent But ninety nine point nine percent confirmed like us confirmed as can be now.
Speaker 0: It's like aha, and it's like you know it's sort of a news But it sort of lacks its impact because you sort of already kind of knew.
Speaker 1: you know yeah But there's also a hindsight bias where you feel like you always knew it's like it didn't.
Speaker 1: our brains are real like And saying yeah, I always knew that.
Speaker 0: But if you asked me yesterday all right, let's take bets if you Is there water on the moon?
Speaker 0: I'd say water on the moon.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: No you got a bet on yes, or no You got no choice.
Speaker 0: I would have bet on yes I would have bet on yes, cuz I'd be like how many molecules counts one molecule of water?
Speaker 0: yes Yeah, Neil Armstrong like you know like a drop of water from his sweat got out or so if you ask me Say a decade ago are there white holes alongside black holes.
Speaker 1: I probably would have bet on yes, but we're increasingly leaning toward no.
Speaker 0: Yeah, all right.
Speaker 0: so a News I got here.
Speaker 0: That's pretty big going around the tech peoples But is largely understood sometimes blown out or under proportion right.
Speaker 0: so there is a tool called YouTube DL.
Speaker 0: it lets you download videos from YouTube a feature that is not an official YouTube feature, but According to whispers.
Speaker 0: I have heard from unnamed Unverified sources.
Speaker 0: It is I think Likely in my opinion that there are developers working at YouTube who intentionally?
Speaker 0: Design YouTube in such a way that it is not obvious That you can download things from YouTube because obviously they would never allow that.
Speaker 0: right, but it is always Possible if you are technologically sophisticated enough, and that is why a tool like YouTube DL Yeah, it is possible to create.
Speaker 0: it'll always be possible to create.
Speaker 1: I love always if I can see it I can records it right.
Speaker 0: There's always a hole.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna use OBS right now to record my screen.
Speaker 1: I could just record a YouTube video with OBS.
Speaker 0: I mean there's even.
Speaker 0: There's even just a hole just in the fact that you know while the video has to come to your computer and get decoded into Frames you could always grab it there because you're the administrator of your own computer.
Speaker 1: Yeah, also because it can't even rely on like private encryption keys and browsers because YouTube works on multiple browsers.
Speaker 0: right so it always be Possible, but it's slightly easier than it could be because of those developers that I have heard.
Speaker 0: rumors of that are unverified.
Speaker 0: so This tool YouTube DL exists.
Speaker 0: it is used by many people for Various reasons some legitimate some not legitimate some piracy.
Speaker 0: Yeah all of which I'm okay with personally, but the law.
Speaker 0: the law is not okay with some of them.
Speaker 1: Well the law is complicated.
Speaker 1: the RIAA is Against this.
Speaker 0: Understand this issue sufficiently right, but I'm saying it's some of the.
Speaker 0: some of these uses are illegal under some laws and some are not.
Speaker 0: so Yeah What happened is the source code of this tool YouTube DL is available on github because this is an open source project.
Speaker 0: github received a DMCA takedown request From the RAS you know and they were saying hey take down this YouTube DL.
Speaker 1: There are even was quote that the code is inherently illegal.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: so this is interesting because a right.
Speaker 0: it would not be under the normal DMCA.
Speaker 0: takedown notice.
Speaker 0: because YouTube DL the source code itself is not a copyright infringement.
Speaker 0: It's not like.
Speaker 0: there's some other tool that YouTube DL is a pirated copy of.
Speaker 0: yeah, right It's not.
Speaker 0: it's not like.
Speaker 0: it's a pirated Photoshop or something.
Speaker 0: It's a. it's a. it's a bread Unique you know on its own Freely licensed piece of software.
Speaker 0: so the code itself is not illegal.
Speaker 0: the argument The RA was making was that this is a tool for circumvention.
Speaker 0: right a copyright circumvention tool, but The DMCA is like hey you can't have DRM Circumventing tools.
Speaker 0: well YouTube DL isn't really circumventing a DRM.
Speaker 0: There isn't like a DRM on YouTube the way that like CSS is.
Speaker 1: I was about to bring up CSS DCSS.
Speaker 1: They had a better case on but that wasn't the RIAA.
Speaker 1: that was the MPAA.
Speaker 0: right You know YouTube DL is Sort of.
Speaker 0: you know YouTube isn't implementing a DRM to keep you from downloading videos.
Speaker 0: It's just not providing that as a feature.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so you're sort of you're saying I believe the lack of a download button a You know and you sort of adding one.
Speaker 1: I do believe that YouTube has language to the effect of we do not allow Downloads.
Speaker 0: that is something like that.
Speaker 0: But that would be a fight that would be a violation of between you and Google as a breach of contract.
Speaker 1: another lawyer That's between you and your god on your YouTube.
Speaker 0: You know user agreement right out, whatever.
Speaker 0: so So this takedown notice itself is questionable right on its on its.
Speaker 1: oh, I'm pretty confident not being a lawyer That however this would not hold up.
Speaker 1: a real lawyer actually wanted to wow this.
Speaker 0: well So here's here's some problems right.
Speaker 0: so so it's a positive and a negative problem.
Speaker 0: So the negative problem YouTube DL made a big boo-boo and that in their documentation They specifically cited examples of like.
Speaker 0: hey like.
Speaker 0: literally the examples in the documentation were like if you wanted to download some Taylor Swift Or some you know whatever.
Speaker 0: yeah, right like they.
Speaker 0: they used copyright infringement as an example in their Documentation of how to use YouTube DL basically admitting that they were you know a tool for illegal uses.
Speaker 0: They weren't like.
Speaker 0: hey if you want to download some Creative Commons licensed videos from YouTube But you just can't download them because you know YouTube doesn't have a download button like say some geek nights videos Yeah, which are all Creative Commons attribution only licensed.
Speaker 0: You know that wasn't their example.
Speaker 0: their example was use this for piracy right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, so that's a negative.
Speaker 0: So I think a non technologically sophisticated judge would see that as very bad.
Speaker 1: Yeah, even though they sell this is yeah, this feels more akin to lock picking tools.
Speaker 1: It is perfectly legal for me to own and carry lock picking tools.
Speaker 1: What is legal is to use them on someone else's property.
Speaker 0: right as long as you only pick locks you own you're all good.
Speaker 0: Yeah, anyway, thank you.
Speaker 0: lock picking law Yes So then the.
Speaker 0: the good part though is apparently this is really interesting There's apparently a bug in github right.
Speaker 0: so in github.
Speaker 0: You know you see a repository.
Speaker 0: What do you do you make?
Speaker 0: you want to contribute to it.
Speaker 0: you make a fork right.
Speaker 0: so it starts out as like Scott slash front row crew.
Speaker 0: rim makes a fork rim slash front row crew.
Speaker 0: he makes his own version of the source code.
Speaker 0: Then he submits a pull request to me and says hey, I made some changes.
Speaker 0: Here's the changes, please merge rim front row crew slash changes into Scott front row crew.
Speaker 0: you know main branch slash changes.
Speaker 0: Yeah, whatever slash main branch, and I can say yes or no.
Speaker 0: apparently it is a bug in github Where if you it's arguable whether it's a bug or who knows, but if you make a pull request It'll actually sort of it'll actually make a copy of that code onto the Sort of the the this the receiving repos You know area right?
Speaker 0: So like for example you might make a pull request to me and then delete your repo I'll still have the pull request you sent to me right?
Speaker 0: so it's sort of like a necessary thing in case you delete yourself.
Speaker 0: Yeah In case I wanted to keep that or something.
Speaker 0: so somebody made a pull request To the github because github has a repo that consists of every DMC a takedown notice that has been sent to github.
Speaker 0: So they sent a pull request to that DMC a github that wasn't merged But it contained the source code of youtube DL.
Speaker 0: Yes, so you can see you can go to github.com Slash DMC a or slash github slash DMC a you know to find this repo.
Speaker 0: And then if you you it won't be linked easily anywhere.
Speaker 0: It'll be hard to find but people are sharing the link.
Speaker 0: so you can go.
Speaker 0: It's like you go to github.com such github such DMC a to the repository of DMC a takedown notices the github has received and Poof there's the youtube DL source code.
Speaker 1: now even if it wasn't the like DCSS despite the fact that that one long integer was technically illegal.
Speaker 1: Somehow it was very easy to find that integer online.
Speaker 1: this code is going to be like that All right.
Speaker 0: Also the fact that the entire world has switched to.
Speaker 0: effectively the entire world has switched from SVN to get I don't know if people Realize that would distributed source code control software as opposed.
Speaker 0: We've talked about this in the past actually on geek nights.
Speaker 0: Go find those episodes.
Speaker 0: Every single clone of that repo has the entire history of the repo.
Speaker 0: if you get clone the Linux kernel You will have every version of the Linux kernel going back to the first version like on your computer.
Speaker 0: It takes forever to download the friggin thing.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so if you if you have ever cloned YouTube DL on to your local computer You have the code.
Speaker 0: no right.
Speaker 0: and so all these YouTube DL developers have all the code You can't really?
Speaker 0: you know taking it down off github.com doesn't really stop anything.
Speaker 0: And they can also file a counterclaim to get it put back up.
Speaker 0: so Nothing has changed on the YouTube side, so there's really no danger of us losing the YouTube DL functionality Yeah, which I rely on heavily All that you know.
Speaker 0: and even so there are other Git posting places including host it yourself, so it's like as long as the YouTube DL developers carry on their work Hosting their repo somewhere else
Speaker 1: as long as there's a discord somewhere server somewhere where people talk about and use a private repo This code will exist.
Speaker 0: So there's really nothing to get worried about here unless the YouTube GL developers decide to you know throw in the towel or something.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but even then what else?
Speaker 0: just someone else will just carry that or continue to work.
Speaker 0: Yes, as long as those rumored YouTube developers Don't make it much much more difficult to download things from YouTube, then we'll have some trouble.
Speaker 1: But on the other hand I can't see them being able to make it impossible because the frame It won't be impossible, but they could.
Speaker 0: they could make it extremely much more difficult than it is they could.
Speaker 1: It's not very and the current way things they could make it to where it's easier to use the analog hole.
Speaker 0: Yes It's not nearly as difficult as it could be.
Speaker 1: I guess what I would say is with this kind of copyright takedown The best case scenario for the people who are going after this kind of tool the best they could possibly achieve is to make the Thing they're trying to protect more of a pain in the ass than using the analog hole Because the analog hole will always exist no matter what and you can always Copy any media at a real-time playback rate.
Speaker 0: Yep, pretty much.
Speaker 1: But uh the EFF did respond to this and they said the thing they always say.
Speaker 1: they called the RA's notice disappointing and counterproductive Pretty much a sentiment echoed by activists who work in the fields of civil rights human rights and hate speech.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like I said, you know, there are many legitimate uses for YouTube DL.
Speaker 0: They're not copyright infringement and that should have been what the examples also notice.
Speaker 1: It's not the movie industry It's not videos.
Speaker 1: The.
Speaker 1: the people who went after this code are the music industry because they are arguing.
Speaker 1: we talked about this on our last gig nights Too.
Speaker 1: the RIA and the music industry is really thrashing right now.
Speaker 0: Generally, yeah, they're.
Speaker 0: they're really going after twitch as well, right?
Speaker 0: That's why twitch is all is bringing the hammer down a little bit.
Speaker 1: There's a reason why we've always hated the RIAA in particular because even though we do have to figure out a way to pay Musicians.
Speaker 1: the RIAA is basically never acted in good faith when it comes to copyright at any point in its existence Right.
Speaker 0: Well and at least in the twitch like YouTube does pay people In fact, it's sort of you know goes too far.
Speaker 0: Right, if I make a video and include a copyrighted song in my in my video then the YouTube policy is basically Okay, I use Rolling Stones right now and they come the Rolling Stones come and say hey used our song We're gonna put a claim on your video.
Speaker 0: your videos now showing ads and the Rolling Stones take all the money.
Speaker 0: It's like excuse me, right?
Speaker 0: You should get maybe a portion of the money from this video.
Speaker 0: But there's also the part that I made right.
Speaker 0: you're taking my money.
Speaker 1: My 20-minute video has one of minutes of your audio.
Speaker 1: you get two out of 20 of my revenue.
Speaker 0: Exactly, right some sort of.
Speaker 0: but no they just take everything which is bullshit right.
Speaker 0: and then on twitch.
Speaker 0: twitch It's you know.
Speaker 0: twitch is obviously, you know Don't think that because twitch is not completely capitulating.
Speaker 0: It's sort of covering for its streamers.
Speaker 1: now twitch is completely capitulating.
Speaker 0: No, it's not.
Speaker 0: It's it's sort of like it's sort of being evil both ways right.
Speaker 0: on the one hand They're like taking down people's videos just without even saying, you know, just like I'll take all this crap down.
Speaker 0: so, you know to get these people off our back, but on the other hand, it's like Twitch is has purchased music licenses, but it's only purchased Performance licenses which are the kind for playing music and like a restaurant, you know that kind of thing It's technically supposed to be part because you're synchronizing video and the music You're legally supposed to be purchasing sync licenses.
Speaker 0: I mean and then if it's a VOD mechanical licenses, right.
Speaker 0: so Twitch is not paying the Musicians, right?
Speaker 0: So YouTube steals all your money on the video creator and gives it to the musicians, right?
Speaker 0: It's almost too music friendly.
Speaker 0: Right?
Speaker 0: But meanwhile twitch is The opposite.
Speaker 0: it's like, okay They're they're.
Speaker 0: they're taking down streamers videos to make them upset Right and to sort of get the RA to go away a little bit.
Speaker 0: but they're also ripping off the music people not paying them.
Speaker 1: and this is at the intersection of.
Speaker 1: Someone buys a game but the game has music that is licensed within it.
Speaker 1: But do they have a right to stream that game or not?
Speaker 1: Like this is this whole area.
Speaker 0: the person who makes the game the person who makes the game doesn't care.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they're like, please stream Please stream because that is better marketing and gets me more sales than anything else I could spend marketing money on.
Speaker 0: in fact, I will give the streamer money to stream the game.
Speaker 1: I'm paying you to do this Yep, and you do see some more and more games are having completely original soundtracks to bypass this entire process Where the game itself like music came with the game and it's just part of that game.
Speaker 1: There's no separate music license.
Speaker 0: Anyway, the final story is if you didn't know that it's possible to download YouTube videos permanently I'll come to the party and you've got and you've got videos that might be taken down at some point or you're worried about not Being able to see them easily again.
Speaker 0: You should get the YouTube DL tool or a similar tool and download all your.
Speaker 1: be wary though If you get a similar tool from an untrusted source, and it's not source code.
Speaker 1: It's probably malware.
Speaker 0: Make sure you're getting some sort of legitimate.
Speaker 1: if you google for YouTube downloader You're gonna find a lot of malware.
Speaker 0: You are there's some out there.
Speaker 0: yet There's also some older un-maintained tools that don't work because YouTube changed yep since and they didn't maintain them.
Speaker 1: YouTube DL is actively main thing, but anyway things Of the day, so check this out.
Speaker 1: This is a two second video Looping in a tweet.
Speaker 1: That is my thing of the day, but what this video is is the surface of a comet Seen through a blizzard of dust ice and cosmic rays and a backdrop of stars.
Speaker 1: This is a fucking video of the surface of a comet.
Speaker 0: Holy shit Is it a comet?
Speaker 0: just a ball of ice?
Speaker 1: Yeah, and rocks it looks like wouldn't it wouldn't?
Speaker 0: it just look like a ice cube with rocks in it.
Speaker 1: It looks like a cliff face with rocks and a blizzard happening and snow.
Speaker 1: Okay, it's really cool.
Speaker 1: It's a goddamn comet.
Speaker 1: All right, I mean we've landed things on.
Speaker 1: comets like comets are neat.
Speaker 1: comets are probably where a lot of that water on the moon comes from - Yeah, anyway, that's all I got.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so I've been doing the bike to nowhere situation because it there's nowhere to go and the weather sucks now, right?
Speaker 0: So beat when you're doing the bike to nowhere.
Speaker 0: the bike to nowhere.
Speaker 0: software, right?
Speaker 0: You sort of can't avoid learning these new things like FTP.
Speaker 0: ever heard of FTP?
Speaker 0: not the file transfer protocol, but the other FTP.
Speaker 0: now It's functional threshold power.
Speaker 0: It's like the average wattage.
Speaker 0: You're capable of putting out in one hour.
Speaker 1: I've seen people talking about wattage hours stuff on blogs, but I don't care.
Speaker 0: So you bike as hard as you can for an hour.
Speaker 0: What's the average wattage you would put out over the hour?
Speaker 0: That's your FTP.
Speaker 0: Yeah, TSS.
Speaker 0: It's like this scoring system.
Speaker 0: They use it's not very complicated.
Speaker 0: Actually.
Speaker 0: It's a simple formula Which has to do with this has to.
Speaker 0: it's mostly based on wattage and length and time But it's basically a scoring system for how difficult a particular bike ride is.
Speaker 0: So it's like if it's a 200 TSS That's a really hard bike ride.
Speaker 0: But like a 50 is like alright you biked, you know.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so all this stuff.
Speaker 0: so I started going on YouTube to better understand what the hell this stuff meant and I found this channel this guy Dylan Johnson, so Dylan Johnson is a. I don't know if he's professional or not, but he is definitely a competitive Endurance mountain biker, right?
Speaker 0: So and he places highly so he's really good at it.
Speaker 1: endurance mountain biking is extremely difficult and painful.
Speaker 0: It actually looks to me like I would do that.
Speaker 0: then regular mountain biking cuz like regular mountain biking like, you know Downhill is like no.
Speaker 0: No, you're you mistake.
Speaker 1: Downhill is a separate subcategory of mountain biking.
Speaker 1: most people who say they're mountain bikers do not do downhill mountain biking Right, but it's like this looks way less scary.
Speaker 0: It just looks like hey you're biking a long way Which I do anyway.
Speaker 0: only it happens to be in the dirt and there might be some rocks and shit and you have a mountain bike Instead.
Speaker 1: that's most mountain biking.
Speaker 1: That's when I say I'm doing mountain biking.
Speaker 1: That's what I'm doing 90% of the time.
Speaker 0: That actually seems okay.
Speaker 0: But anyway So this guy does that very well and he is also I guess his profession is.
Speaker 0: he is a coach right athletic coach trainer person And he's got a YouTube channel where he talks about stuff.
Speaker 0: and normally when I search and try to find any Exercise health fitness wellness, you know, I even like the term wellness.
Speaker 0: if they say you they use the word wellness That's usually up flags.
Speaker 1: Nope right out of there.
Speaker 1: That's one step before homeopathy.
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 0: Whenever you see that kind of YouTube channel, you're like this is gonna be a bunch of woo bullshit, right?
Speaker 0: I can't.
Speaker 0: how do I know?
Speaker 0: I can trust what this guy's gonna say?
Speaker 0: Dylan Johnson has done the best job of convincing me.
Speaker 0: He knows what he's talking about because all his videos right are all about him reading every single study about the topic right and Saying well this one says this this one says that this one says this this one says that and this one says this.
Speaker 0: So in the end, what can we say is true to the best of human knowledge as of today?
Speaker 0: We don't know or this or the opposite of you know What you thought and he answers a lot of questions that are very relevant to any cyclist Who is even slightly more than non serious, even if you're not considering racing Like.
Speaker 0: I have no interest in racing.
Speaker 0: But he answers a lot of questions like are the clipless pedals more efficient than just?
Speaker 1: that's the one I'm looking at And the one I'm gonna watch after the show are is is what's the right seat height?
Speaker 0: What you know is it is it better be low high in the middle, right?
Speaker 0: How do you figure?
Speaker 1: Biking specifically because the thing I found about biking that I've not found with all a lot of the other sports I do is that biking people tend to always say there is a one true way to do a specific thing and There's never seems to be evidence to back that up.
Speaker 1: But it's like this very specific dogma about there like here's the rule on how to size your seat exactly to you for your bike.
Speaker 1: Do not do a lot of kids.
Speaker 0: Yes, there is a lot of Conventional wisdom in the cycling community and also a lot of just common sense.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's sort of two things that just make sense, right?
Speaker 0: and You know things you see you look at pro cyclists and you like Tour de France You see them doing something and you say well that must be the right way.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but now maybe not not always but maybe but maybe not right, you know, I saw video.
Speaker 0: Did I do that as a thing of the day?
Speaker 0: Like what's the best position to go to be in going down?
Speaker 1: Because we talked a lot when we did that show about Superman's the best position but don't do Superman right exactly so.
Speaker 0: but yeah, Dylan Johnson's channel is Incredible.
Speaker 0: I've learned a lot so far and I've only watched like a handful of the videos.
Speaker 0: I'm probably gonna watch all the ones relevant to myself and adjust accordingly.
Speaker 0: So yeah, if you if you bike at all and care about getting better at biking is a must watch channel.
Speaker 0: Good job, Dylan.
Speaker 1: I guess it's interesting that when I think about this like I run into that conventional wisdom and doctrine way more recycling than other sports I do specifically like.
Speaker 1: even skiing does not have this.
Speaker 1: like we ask a question of a ski instructor The answer is full of a lot of caveats and it depends and a lot of sort of like.
Speaker 1: this might work But it might not.
Speaker 1: let's try.
Speaker 1: but with cycling it's just always like put your seat at this height based on this formula.
Speaker 0: Well, there is.
Speaker 0: there is a formula which one's the right exactly.
Speaker 0: Dylan knows.
Speaker 1: he'll tell you so in the moment stuck at home.
Speaker 1: You can watch our panels on YouTube.
Speaker 1: join our discord I don't know.
Speaker 1: I Thought about fucking like vote.
Speaker 1: That's it.
Speaker 1: Just go fucking vote for Joe Biden or things are gonna get real bad in a hurry.
Speaker 0: or If you if you are eligible to vote in the United States of America and you do not vote for Joe Biden get the hell Out.
Speaker 0: Yep, and if you live in New York State You should vote for Joe Biden on the working families party line should to make to make the governor mad.
Speaker 0: It will can't?
Speaker 0: it will count the same.
Speaker 0: I promise.
Speaker 1: Yep It still counts for Joe Biden, but it pisses off Cuomo and all.
Speaker 1: good people hate him.
Speaker 1: Bad people hate him too, but so do good people.
Speaker 0: Same thing for the mayor.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Anyway, I Thought about reading a chapter of our book club.
Speaker 0: Oh so fancy of Genji, but instead I read a comic book.
Speaker 1: We're in a comic book.
Speaker 1: You know what I did I can't?
Speaker 1: I played a bunch of Star Wars and like made some food and went hiking.
Speaker 0: I made some food.
Speaker 0: I played some links of the past.
Speaker 1: problem is I like normally this.
Speaker 1: like this season when I'd go hiking I'd have a long train ride to and from the hiking that I would read books on.
Speaker 1: But now the only way to hike safely is to drive places.
Speaker 1: So I have to drive the whole time.
Speaker 0: I just hike to the hiking.
Speaker 1: That'd be like yeah, let me bike to Poughkeepsie to then bike to Albany.
Speaker 1: I Mean.
Speaker 1: I guess I could get.
Speaker 1: I could get the.
Speaker 1: probably I'd have to camp because to get all those mountains I would have to hike about 70 miles from Queens to get to those mountain trailheads.
Speaker 1: Three days two days if I'd like death marched it but really that's a three-day.
Speaker 0: I could bike 70 miles in like seven hours.
Speaker 1: Yeah, bike it.
Speaker 1: Let's see how far you can walk.
Speaker 1: Okay, how long they'll take you to walk.
Speaker 1: 70 miles Days.
Speaker 1: Yeah take about three days Three Days.
Speaker 1: if you're really fit and good at walking I'm good at walking.
Speaker 1: Are you really?
Speaker 1: we should test this?
Speaker 1: you want to go for a walk?
Speaker 0: My legs are long Therefore I'm good at walking.
Speaker 1: But yeah vote.
Speaker 1: Otherwise, like the next week is gonna be rough for a lot of people.
Speaker 1: So just be ready for that and We'll try to just keep doing geek nights until then and maybe at some point We'll have some downtime and actually read books again.
Speaker 0: my major concern these days is that Hockey will resume and for some reason they will allow people to go to hockey Before it is because then we have to sell all those tickets.
Speaker 1: because I'm not going to have a to sell right.
Speaker 0: they will have to sell all these tickets because Even though I said I would go as soon as I could I'm not gonna go if it's not that was assuming they wouldn't let Me go until it was safe.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right.
Speaker 0: So That's my.
Speaker 0: that's you know and for that to be my concern I'm doing pretty well.
Speaker 1: honestly though the way the news is trending I'm pretty sure COVID is gonna be like a wave worse than anything.
Speaker 1: We've seen up to this point.
Speaker 1: over the next few weeks That's gonna happen.
Speaker 1: Like things are looking pretty bad in most of the country I'll say the only saving grace for us personally Luckily is if we live in New York City Which except for one neighborhood is actually trending very well like one specific neighbor a couple couple couple neighborhoods.
Speaker 1: Only one neighborhood is the red zone.
Speaker 1: There are three yellow zones.
Speaker 0: Yeah, then one of the other ones is pretty big.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but that one big yellow zone is around the red zone.
Speaker 0: No, no, no, there's another one out by Q Gardens.
Speaker 1: That one's pretty big.
Speaker 0: It's like a second one.
Speaker 1: Anyway, anyway So, uh, let's get right into it.
Speaker 1: We talked about facial recognition off and out over the years, but we never really did a whole.
Speaker 0: she had some AI episodes.
Speaker 0: You've had some privacy episodes.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know things like that.
Speaker 0: But it's in the news so much and we don't have a lot of Monday ideas.
Speaker 0: So send your Monday ideas to us.
Speaker 0: cuz.
Speaker 0: Mondays for some reason are like slightly more popular than the other days even though They're the hardest to come up with ideas.
Speaker 1: Wednesdays are the least popular days.
Speaker 1: I think it's because we're the old men of anime at this point.
Speaker 0: Maybe it's because we just know more about Technology and gaming than we know about anime and that's why well We don't watch as much anime as we used to like.
Speaker 1: I basically only watch great shows.
Speaker 1: now though total aside Remember way back we're talking about how we should watch decadence because there's people keep talking about it.
Speaker 1: we watch the first two episodes, uh Yeah You're the whole first episode.
Speaker 1: You're like, alright, it's a show.
Speaker 1: Alright, I like it.
Speaker 1: Okay at the very end of the episode you like wait what.
Speaker 1: and then episode two.
Speaker 1: the show is not what it looks like Holy shit.
Speaker 1: It is not what it looks like.
Speaker 1: Okay, but I think it's specifically up your alley directly.
Speaker 0: you person Is there?
Speaker 0: is there a terrible secret?
Speaker 0: Oh is there and when you're there a train that is there a train that quietly goes out into the night and has a moral What a certain character looks like.
Speaker 1: you'll see what I mean, that's all I can say.
Speaker 0: a robot a cute robot.
Speaker 1: Okay, I can't.
Speaker 1: Everyone who's tried to get me to watch the show has said the same thing.
Speaker 1: I won't tell you anything about it.
Speaker 1: Just watch it.
Speaker 1: Do not read about it.
Speaker 0: Maybe I'll.
Speaker 0: where is it available?
Speaker 1: funimation and Hulu?
Speaker 0: I don't have either one of them.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we happen to have Hulu by accident.
Speaker 1: So we watch it on Hulu.
Speaker 1: No, I didn't know we had Hulu.
Speaker 1: Apparently we had Hulu.
Speaker 0: I Previously had Hulu before I had Netflix.
Speaker 0: I'm currently in Netflix mode.
Speaker 0: Once I get out of Netflix mode.
Speaker 0: I might go back to Hulu.
Speaker 1: yeah, it's hard though cuz Netflix has just got so much constant good stuff lately.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I did.
Speaker 0: I watched like that Michael Jordan documentary.
Speaker 0: That was good.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you can watch a keep.
Speaker 1: Oh Season 3 the third season is the last season anyway.
Speaker 1: facial recognition technology is a good topic because It is so illustrative of the tech transfer ethics concerns of technology.
Speaker 1: But unlike nuclear weapons, it's not like just killing people.
Speaker 1: There aren't that many.
Speaker 1: like peaceful uses for nuclear weapons.
Speaker 1: There were a few.
Speaker 1: there were terrible ideas, but there were a few.
Speaker 1: you can read about it You want.
Speaker 1: nuclear mining was a thing for a while.
Speaker 1: It was a terrible idea.
Speaker 0: That's a bad idea.
Speaker 1: Oh It was tested.
Speaker 1: It's a bad idea, but you don't say facial recognition It's one of those technologies.
Speaker 1: that one is unstoppable.
Speaker 1: We did.
Speaker 1: there is no way to get rid of this technology So you need cannot go back in the bottle.
Speaker 0: We know how to do it therefore and all you need to do it is a camera and a computer.
Speaker 0: You can buy those things off the shelf.
Speaker 0: Yep There is no putting the genie back in the bottle.
Speaker 0: It can be done and it will be done.
Speaker 1: if the world banned facial recognition technology the source code exists and just like YouTube DL people would use it on their own hardware and it would still happen.
Speaker 0: and Unlike, you know, if the world banned nuclear weapons, well, you could.
Speaker 0: there's only so much plutonium, you know, it can be regulated It can be detected with your counters.
Speaker 0: It could be well also do something about.
Speaker 1: almost no one on earth knows how to make a thermonuclear device Like that is there's.
Speaker 0: there are very easy.
Speaker 0: It is relatively easy ways to enforce that law and detect violators to stop people from using facial recognition.
Speaker 0: It's almost impossible because it's already in so many things And you have to ban like digital cameras which are being like there's mostly factories in the on earth Various places just like spewing out thousands of digital cameras a second.
Speaker 0: Like it's unstoppable You can't do anything about it.
Speaker 1: I just think of that old Bloom County strip randomly where they're making that illegal drug.
Speaker 1: It's a legal drug like opus and the crew are making it and the government just declares it illegal and they see the news and they Just yell like stop pouring the stuff Oliver like stop cut it off.
Speaker 0: But like they're literally there must be like a factory somewhere where they're just like, you know Like little tiny cell phone cameras like just coming out and like a flood like there's tons of them anyway,
Speaker 1: but also facial recognition has a huge number of Extremely beneficial uses
Speaker 0: and a huge
Speaker 1: number of extremely dangerous uses,
Speaker 0: right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, it bears mentioning that facial recognition is really just is not actually the technology?
Speaker 0: the technology is simply image Recognition.
Speaker 0: right is where you use machine learning to train a computer.
Speaker 0: you give it lots of data So images and you tell it hey, this is a cat.
Speaker 0: This is a cat.
Speaker 0: Here's a new image.
Speaker 0: You've never seen before.
Speaker 0: Is there a cat?
Speaker 0: and if so, where is the cat?
Speaker 0: and this is a software.
Speaker 0: You can this.
Speaker 0: instructions online like tutorials how to write that exact software yourself.
Speaker 0: You can write it if you want to make one to the text something right?
Speaker 0: All you need is the database of whatever it is.
Speaker 0: You want to detect so Human face.
Speaker 0: is simply that you're like detect human face, right?
Speaker 0: And then you go to the next step and you say okay you found human face right in this picture.
Speaker 0: You've counted them.
Speaker 0: Now here's a database of human faces which have names and phone numbers attached.
Speaker 0: find the phone numbers of all these faces Right, that's the step two.
Speaker 1: Yep Now even worse think about I could find the phone numbers of all the cats, but they don't have phones.
Speaker 1: humans are uniquely suited like we can identify other people very quickly and Unconsciously just by seeing their face like some people can.
Speaker 0: well, yeah Have a Disability like face blindness, which is a great reason for a positive use of facial recognition.
Speaker 1: Imagine Penn Jillette could wear a Google Glass and whenever someone walked up to him It showed them if he knows this person and what their name was.
Speaker 0: Right a face blind person with ARG that identified faces of that the person already knew and told them their names.
Speaker 0: Like that would even be useful for people who weren't face blind if used appropriately.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't remember any remember?
Speaker 1: Great that would be if people's names just appeared over there.
Speaker 1: I was in a panel at a PAX taking questions, right?
Speaker 1: or someone comes up to me And I they act like they know me and I have no idea who they are right, it's like if people who already did know me and had seen my face and knew my name.
Speaker 0: if only they could see my Face and instantly recall my name with a memory aid.
Speaker 0: Maybe they're maybe they aren't face blind, but their memory is just normal.
Speaker 0: like You didn't say bad you just said normal Yeah, or you know not not perfect as no one's is right or hardly anyone's is.
Speaker 0: that would be a great and good use of Technology, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, people would know.
Speaker 0: it would help people connect with each other What Facebook says they want to do.
Speaker 1: but it also makes this technology uniquely suited to identifying individual humans because the human brain like we are so we sort of evolved to where Specific cues in our faces can be rapidly parsed by our brains to remember who someone is meaning It doesn't take that much facial data for a computer to do the same thing.
Speaker 1: You only need a little bit of data from someone's face Right.
Speaker 0: a face is easy to find.
Speaker 1: It's got you know, mostly usually Humans are good at finding faces that don't even exist, right?
Speaker 0: It's a roughly circular Oval type shape.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there's a limited number of shapes and it has distinct features Right that are easy for this kind of computer software to find.
Speaker 0: and then it's also so Even though it's able to say it's easy to say that's a face.
Speaker 0: But then once you have the face cut out Faces are so unique and varied and detailed especially with high-resolution cameras It's easy to tell faces apart and say well, which face is it?
Speaker 0: It's like two different questions.
Speaker 0: It's actually two technologies at work, right one.
Speaker 0: So here's another one for step two.
Speaker 1: Here's a an example of how the exact same app even that use facial recognition could be used for great harm or great good Cuz.
Speaker 1: this is an app.
Speaker 1: I've always wanted.
Speaker 1: I even wrote like a document and RIT Describing this app is one of my classes.
Speaker 1: So I remember like I did a lot of research on facial recognition back in 2003 for my tech transfer class and The app I put together was basically I called it that guy.
Speaker 1: But what the app was?
Speaker 1: so you and your group of friends like our group of friends or like the geek nice listeners as a whole We all like friend each other in this app and say one of us of our group of friends
Speaker 0: encounter
Speaker 1: someone who is an abuser or a piece of shit like someone who is an annoying that guy at conventions or someone who is like just being misogynist and racist and terrible at conventions if I flag that person to say That person like like that person was racist to me at this con and that at another con Scott Meet someone and his Google s just pops up and says hey Scott.
Speaker 1: So, you know rim said this guy was a racist.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Now the only reason this is working is because me and rim already agreed.
Speaker 0: You know the fact that I friended rim on this service Yeah already means I trust his opinion and I'm only seeing the opinions of people.
Speaker 0: I trust I'm not just seeing data from randos exactly.
Speaker 1: So even in that context evil use exact same app.
Speaker 1: an Evil person who would say a stalker or a sexual abuser flags the faces of people who are easy marks or who have been abused successfully so that Friends in their shitty pickup artist Network could get a notification of hey this person you're talking to in a bar This is a person that this other pickup artist already fucked with.
Speaker 1: and here's the cheat sheet on how to pick them up.
Speaker 1: That's far right.
Speaker 0: same or exact same at or a way to detect like, you know People who are like, you know good at detecting them, right?
Speaker 0: So it's like, you know, maybe you're a criminal and you got all the cops faces, right?
Speaker 0: Maybe you're a protester and you got all the cops or maybe you're a cop and you got all the protesters faces or The criminals faces.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and this is be good.
Speaker 0: It could be bad.
Speaker 1: This is why there's so many serial killer on the loose.
Speaker 0: We have a video of the serial killer and now we're gonna use facial.
Speaker 0: It's an actual serial killer actual crime not bullshit, right?
Speaker 0: and now we're gonna use the facial recognition technology on all the security cameras and an alarm will go off if this if the serial killer is spotted anywhere in range of a camera and then we can go get Them to stop them from serial killing again, right?
Speaker 1: Oh, so I was actually looking something up because I remember seeing something about how the BCEC we're packs East is every year Had that system Remember when they put in that system that could figure out the number of unique people in the building based on like low-key facial recognition.
Speaker 1: the city of Boston has actually recently banned the use of facial recognition technology and I wonder what that will mean for the fire code counts at the BCEC.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I wonder I don't know about that system specifically.
Speaker 0: I know I heard rumors that it could count people but I don't know if it could like look up people but in China They absolutely have ones that can identify Individuals in a crowd basically cheat sheet.
Speaker 0: Where's Waldo?
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's literally what it is.
Speaker 0: No, they can take.
Speaker 1: how good could that technology be?
Speaker 1: a kid get ridiculously good.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I could get lost.
Speaker 1: I know I'm saying how good in terms of boons to society.
Speaker 1: a kid gets lost in a city or a giant convention center and Cameras are media like the kid is here highlight him give him give coordinates and follow him until someone can go find the kid and save them or The bank is robbed.
Speaker 0: we arrested this person.
Speaker 0: Oh, but then we checked the camera footage and we exonerated them.
Speaker 0: They were actually at this other location at the time of the bank robbery.
Speaker 1: Yep The problem the main problem is that generally when a technology is powerful like this The people who have more real-world power can leverage this technology more effectively Against people who wield less real-world power.
Speaker 1: What that means is that governments can use it more effectively than private citizens.
Speaker 1: Police can use it more effectively than private citizens.
Speaker 1: Generally Disadvantaged communities can use it less effectively than more privileged communities, right?
Speaker 1: So we'll exacerbate existing divides in society.
Speaker 0: We do have access to this technology.
Speaker 0: You can get it and just use it yourself for your own purposes.
Speaker 0: the problem is your data.
Speaker 0: will that your database of faces and Information about those faces will be severely limited?
Speaker 0: and in order to build up that database, right?
Speaker 0: It will require You know, you're not going to be able to build as good of one as the government who can put cameras all over the city.
Speaker 0: Yeah right and use use tax money to buy giant comp.
Speaker 1: or you could even see hackers like a lot of facial recognition software that is Made by like smaller companies or private individuals.
Speaker 1: They all train it using the same like generic data sets You can buy.
Speaker 1: meaning if you understand the biases in that data set you could possibly exploit Someone's implementation of facial recognition to paint a crime on someone else.
Speaker 0: That's actually a huge problem right?
Speaker 0: is that even people who do have you know, lots of data right advanced systems Those systems are often racist like you have a huge database But the database is all white people.
Speaker 0: or you know, let's say China.
Speaker 0: The Chinese database is almost entirely Chinese people, right?
Speaker 0: You know, so if I go over to China that system might you know?
Speaker 0: I imagine it would just be like unknown not Chinese person, right?
Speaker 0: or maybe they would take my photos when I Come to China and then they would put me in the database and that way they could find me.
Speaker 0: But it might have a hard time because it's heavily trained on Chinese people, right?
Speaker 0: So different facial structure.
Speaker 1: So some of the things that second do can day are things like from a data set find one person or find like.
Speaker 1: the people are most likely to be one particular person or like they're especially powerful when you focus them on a very Specific community like that's right now where the tech is the most powerful.
Speaker 1: the committee could be just you like Your face unlocks your phone.
Speaker 1: That's a community of one person.
Speaker 1: Or you and your like small group of friends like you use it as a like.
Speaker 1: I've already.
Speaker 1: you can buy Door locks that are electronic and some of them have the ability to like unlock your house based on just looking at your face.
Speaker 1: That's cool.
Speaker 0: One really another if you're talking about small uses, right?
Speaker 0: So your camera it Using the first part of the technology just find human faces.
Speaker 0: I don't care who they are, right?
Speaker 0: So you take a camera it finds faces and therefore Autofocus is really well because most of the time when you take a photo and the face in it You want to focus on the face because who wants photo of the tree, right?
Speaker 0: No, you take if you're taking a photo of the tree It wouldn't be a person in the photo right looking at the camera.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and then step two, right?
Speaker 0: This is also a really, you know completely Mundane but useful use of the technology.
Speaker 0: whose face is it?
Speaker 0: Automatically organize my photo collection based on who's in the photo now Forever my fucking old gx-1.
Speaker 1: I programmed in the names of a bunch of our friends and It'll tag the photos.
Speaker 1: I take with that thing with their names.
Speaker 0: Yeah, Lightroom Lightroom does it pretty much every photo app these days.
Speaker 0: does that right?
Speaker 0: It's like basic.
Speaker 0: It's like a standard feature.
Speaker 0: It's not even an advanced new feature.
Speaker 0: It's like Expected that you have this where it's like, okay find me photos.
Speaker 0: I've taken of Scott.
Speaker 0: Oh, here's all the photos in my library with my face in them.
Speaker 0: Yep I didn't have to.
Speaker 0: I didn't have to do any, you know, like tagging by hand, you know Like I used to have to do in the old days.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't even like I. increasingly I take a lot of photos.
Speaker 1: They generate a lot of video.
Speaker 1: I've increasingly stopped Bothering to fully and like add the metadata necessarily to find specific things in the future because it's not worth the effort.
Speaker 1: I'm sort of waiting and relying on technology like this to do that for me in the future.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I really wish people would apply because there's no reason technologically speaking.
Speaker 0: This couldn't be applied to audio, you know, you should be able to say that wave that mp3 is a geek nights episode, right?
Speaker 0: Yep, without having to put id3 tags on it It should just know it.
Speaker 0: might I know which episode or the topic?
Speaker 1: but it should be able to Commute and then Okay, so that doesn't narrow it down at all.
Speaker 0: No, it doesn't right, but you should be able to have one that's like oh, here's a song It's a just automatically tag the genre and possibly even the artist right if it doesn't and not base.
Speaker 0: You know the way most music things work is.
Speaker 0: they're looking at like, you know.
Speaker 0: They just have a database of the exact songs right like.
Speaker 0: oh, here's the M is exactly, you know, the song, you know a Beatles song.
Speaker 0: Oh, this is that exact song.
Speaker 0: It's it's my guitar gently weeps I know this song right, but what if it just didn't have a database of songs?
Speaker 0: it just had a database of you know singers and Musical styles and was saying oh that's a rock song and who do we hear?
Speaker 0: singing sounds like the Beatles and automatically tagged the music Library that way.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: There's no reason that couldn't exist right now if the database is large enough.
Speaker 1: Yep No actually getting to the database because one of the listeners Sam is actually posting a lot of good info in the stream right now Because he works in this space.
Speaker 0: But the data says if you're doing evil shit quit the job.
Speaker 1: And he seems like he's not doing evil shit because he's talking a lot about ethical concerns.
Speaker 0: Good and leak.
Speaker 1: that shit You know But evil think it's of what you just said.
Speaker 1: a lot of the more advanced uses of facial recognition Require machine learning of some kind meaning training data sets.
Speaker 1: The data sets encode the bias of society at the time The data set was collected and the biases of the people doing the collecting.
Speaker 1: We've told we've talked about that a lot on geek nights and it doubly applies here like The facial recognition software built into like my smartphone just fucking doesn't work as well on non-white faces.
Speaker 1: No, of course not like straight up because that's what.
Speaker 1: what do they train it on?
Speaker 0: they trained it on data sets that are mostly white Yeah, or they you know the people working in the office where they made the software, right?
Speaker 0: I think that's.
Speaker 0: that's an old story that they liked.
Speaker 0: it's true story, but they tell it a lot where it's not even facial recognition.
Speaker 0: it was like It was like a paper towel dispenser or soap dispenser where you put your hand in front of it And then the soap just comes out without you having to touch it.
Speaker 0: Yeah And all the people who worked in the in the engineering team that designed the hand Detector were white and then black people put their hand under it and the soap didn't come out and the paper towel didn't move.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right and it's like oops.
Speaker 1: Maybe you should have had some for you know employees but the racist the weird danger of facial recognition is that a lot of the most powerful things we could do with it for the benefit of society are also the most dangerous.
Speaker 1: and If we make the data sets more equitable and we make the core technology better, which is going to happen We actually enable those larger broader uses more readily.
Speaker 0: It's like yeah, let's put you know We wanted this to be less racist.
Speaker 0: Okay, add more black faces to the database All right now.
Speaker 0: equally good on the races and all the black people.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like Aha.
Speaker 0: So great.
Speaker 0: now the cops have an even better idea of who to go after.
Speaker 1: Thanks I don't know how like society is going to deal with the like the next generation of facial tech like 10 15 20 years from now when the some of the Examples we've talked about become like not only widespread but easy to implement.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think this technology is massively disruptive at least in countries where it's well and heavily Regulated.
Speaker 0: right the wrong large the corporations and government won't be using it for nefarious purposes.
Speaker 1: We live in America But I'm not even worried about the government using it so much as I'm worried about private companies using right reg.
Speaker 0: I don't regulate a well-regulated country, right?
Speaker 0: It'll be those Pete.
Speaker 0: the corporations and government won't be using it as much or in in ways that aren't you know Well controlled but there's nothing stopping the general public from using it and who knows what way.
Speaker 0: yeah As long as they you know, if they're technologically sophisticated So there will be you know, some sort of YouTube DL.
Speaker 0: ask right if you're in the know And you can set up your own fancy tech and you get this database from some Pirate Bay.
Speaker 0: then you're gonna have evil facial recognition technology and use it for evil and But also maybe use it for good.
Speaker 1: Yep, but I don't know like there is Really kick-ass to constrain the power of this technology except through government regulation and transparency Or Adversarial use of it.
Speaker 1: there have been a number of articles recently talking about cyberpunk and like you want to know what cyberpunk really is because basically The police and law enforcement America are already heavily using and abusing facial recognition.
Speaker 1: There's a whole like not to get into specifics.
Speaker 1: They're definitely using it.
Speaker 1: They're definitely abusing it.
Speaker 1: They're definitely targeting protesters with it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you were at a protest.
Speaker 0: All right, we took photos of everyone at the protest.
Speaker 0: We didn't do anything.
Speaker 0: and then we walk around town.
Speaker 0: People are just going to get groceries and then with facial recognition technology says oh that person in the grocery checkout aisle They they were at the protest last night and they were anti cop and then they go out to put the groceries in the car And then we get them and they're alone.
Speaker 0: All right, then we know it's them because we photo their face at the.
Speaker 0: you know Yeah, we captured everyone's face at the protest with our facial recognition technology.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but then that opened up the door to let's say we have good regulations and controls.
Speaker 1: So, all right the Baltimore Convention Center has their facial recognition thing that that keeps track of The fire code count and they use it if a kid gets lost to reunite them with their parents.
Speaker 1: That's all good.
Speaker 1: And let's say they even they even like don't use it on ethically Directly like the company just uses it for its purpose and that's all fine.
Speaker 1: One low paid employee who has access to that data could abuse it.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: That's right or leak it.
Speaker 1: Yep, leak it or abuse it.
Speaker 1: How many times does some cop get caught looking up an ex-girlfriend in a database to then go commit some crime?
Speaker 0: Yeah, something like that.
Speaker 0: Yep, but or you know, maybe there's somebody who's like you know like Trying to hide and that person Who controls the thing is like the evil person is trying to find them.
Speaker 0: or maybe you know, someone just breaks in right?
Speaker 0: It's like, you know, you know that the person you're you're a stalker and the person you're stalking You know is that is that a convention in the building and you break into the office and you use it and you find where?
Speaker 0: They are in the building, right?
Speaker 1: Otherwise you your chance of finding them are so small or you just call someone who works there and socially engineer them similar to how people's Sims get stolen all the time with cell phones Mm-hmm because a lot of people in the chain are not paid enough to care.
Speaker 0: Alright, so the last thing we should talk about which is pretty obvious and well-spoken on the internet But is that yeah, this technology is at least for the foreseeable future Somewhat actually easy to foil because it's not so advanced to the point where you can see through things.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: Wear a mask.
Speaker 0: You can use masks.
Speaker 0: You can just shield your face.
Speaker 0: You can use various kinds of makeup.
Speaker 1: No, so I have read numerous studies showing that that dazzling makeup has zero effects.
Speaker 0: That is not that maybe that specific but there are other kinds you can use though that makeup basically doesn't do anything.
Speaker 1: only cover and concealment does.
Speaker 0: Obviously that helps the most right but there there you can do.
Speaker 0: I'm not like not talking about like makeup like You know somewhat tame makeup.
Speaker 1: No No the extreme makeup seemed to have no effect either because some of the more on your face like some extra eyeballs that are like Realistic and shit.
Speaker 1: I saw a lot of papers talking about how that stuff's all trivially foiled.
Speaker 0: Maybe we'll say but I'm pretty sure a mask is a mask.
Speaker 0: Yeah Cameras can't see through things.
Speaker 0: I guess you can infrared cameras, but that's still not gonna give you the resolution that you need to really identify a face.
Speaker 1: Yeah I was reading right with earlier today because they get written ready for the show an article about using basically LIDAR and other technology from cameras to generate pseudo 3d models of faces as well as 2d and how that Drastically improves the quality.
Speaker 0: the new Pro iPhones have that at least.
Speaker 0: yeah I'm very surprised the new Pro iPhones are adding that and using it for autofocus When like a Canon DSLR doesn't have it and maybe it should.
Speaker 1: no Maybe it should.
Speaker 0: I have seen people selling systems third-party systems that you can basically attach to any manual lens Gears and it will use LIDAR to slowly and shittily Focus a manual focus lens automatically not too bad.
Speaker 0: There might be someone who needs that like you really need autofocus no matter how shitty it is.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you as and you care about like some ancient specialized manual only lens.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you care about it focusing accurately But you don't care and you care about focusing automatically and you don't care about money And you don't care about how much equipment you carry.
Speaker 0: Yeah But you don't care how slowly it autofocus is either.
Speaker 0: you're okay with that.
Speaker 0: then this is a good choice for you But that could develop into something much better as time goes on.
Speaker 1: now one direction this could go is You know that whole cyberpunk thing I was talking about.
Speaker 1: One way to control this kind of technology if it gets out of control is for organized Activists to aggressively use it against the entities that are oppressing them.
Speaker 1: case in point the recent groups of protesters Who have been cataloging police violence from videos and then using facial recognition to identify and document the specific?
Speaker 1: officers involved in the abuse.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: So you're hanging out and there's a bunch of cops coming and you're like, alright, those are all good cops.
Speaker 0: They have like this.
Speaker 0: many of us looks up their faces and looks up in the database and says here's how many?
Speaker 0: Violations of those cops have?
Speaker 0: how many times they've gotten in trouble for beating someone up?
Speaker 0: Oh zero zero zero zero.
Speaker 0: These are the four good cops in town.
Speaker 0: Okay You know the next one right.
Speaker 0: and then you come across another cop and it's like 20 and it's like whoop taking another street getting Away from that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, or even just as simple as all right.
Speaker 1: Some violence in the street.
Speaker 1: you hit the you have some video of it and you approve.
Speaker 1: Oh, that's the same cop who attacked this other person two days ago.
Speaker 1: attack this other person three days ago.
Speaker 0: or a bunch of undercover Cops ain't so undercover anymore.
Speaker 0: Yeah their face.
Speaker 0: It's like oh, there's a bunch of people coming to join our protest.
Speaker 0: Wait a minute.
Speaker 0: Those are cops and get them out of here.
Speaker 1: getting back to YouTube.
Speaker 1: GL kind of bringing this all together.
Speaker 1: that is the kind of tech activism that will be necessary if Governments don't step in and properly regulate these things in an equitable manner.
Speaker 1: That is the only way to.
Speaker 1: the only way to protect yourself from technology That's out of the genie bottle is to use the technology against the people who are using it against you.
Speaker 0: The last the last thing I think is one possible route that I hasn't I haven't seen explored much.
Speaker 0: is a Database poisoning right?
Speaker 0: It's like if they're collecting faces and failing and that's learning more faces, right?
Speaker 0: You know just somehow feed into the cameras lots of wrong or messed up or otherwise, you know faces Theoretically possible.
Speaker 1: I just don't know if it's practical but it is a thing I've thought about so I Have been doing a database poisoning experiment for most of my life since late middle school.
Speaker 1: uh-huh, I Put slightly wrong birthdays into everything I ever put my birthday into.
Speaker 1: that is not an official government record And what I found as time goes on Websites that I do not have accounts with or that I make a new account with like things that I interact with will sometimes Have my birthday somewhere or will send me a birthday thing Even though I didn't tell them my birthday and based on what birthday they
Speaker 0: say
Speaker 1: I can trace back to what database they got that data from
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: I haven't done much with it.
Speaker 1: It's just something I noticed over the years, but I was thinking of it because a couple weeks ago I remembered that my birthday and steam is from the year 1978 because that's the year I picked for that particular platform and Sither to the 1978 birth year has never shown up anywhere else.
Speaker 1: It's only in Steve.
Speaker 1: I Was just thinking about that the other day, but it's relevant to the whole database poisoning thing.
Speaker 0: Yeah, all right.
Speaker 0: So facial recognition is gonna be with us for the rest of our lives Cannot make it go as long as you have a face and a computer and a camera and the Cameras are connected to the computers.
Speaker 0: You're gonna have to learn to live with it somehow, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I recommend it.
Speaker 0: a good start extreme government regulation, which is happening already.
Speaker 0: So that's a good sign.
Speaker 1: Yep, extreme government regulation coupled with cyberpunk activism.
Speaker 1: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at front row crew comm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 1: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 1: But unlike those other late shows It's actually recorded at night and the patreon patrons for this episode of geek nights are Alan Joyce had McNichol Mardi Gras Nia Graham Finch.
Speaker 1: you hold the key to my heart.
Speaker 1: The license plate said fresh and it had dice in the mirror.
Speaker 1: Clinton Walton J Bats friend who's been from New Zealand Ryan parent Chris mint.
Speaker 1: give dread lily tenebrae just like a dude guy.
Speaker 1: Chris Reimer Finn chirping von Horrell and a bunch of people who do not want me to say their names.
Speaker 1: We'll see if Scott actually watches decadence yet, but uh, yeah you saw that bit in the stream.
Speaker 1: You should go check out that show and for right now.
Speaker 1: I leave you with.
Speaker 0: I'm such a loser My guts my guts.