Speaker 1: It's Thursday March 12th 2020.
Speaker 1: I'm rim.
Speaker 1: I'm Scott and this is geek nights tonight the Mandalorian.
Speaker 0: Let's do this All right, so my work is awesome work at least on my team because we can just work from home Sort of whenever and actually I work from home probably less than almost everyone else.
Speaker 1: Lot of my engineers work from home a lot But I rarely do since I'm a very visible position and I got to talk to my base.
Speaker 0: It's funny that actually the people who are more visible are out of the office more, huh?
Speaker 1: anyway But yeah, I'm also in a weird industry compared to like any other normal company.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: But yeah, I tend to only work from home like, you know, and when I got a bunch of chores piled up You know something where it's like, okay I work from home get my shit back in order like
Speaker 1: the super is gonna come do something and I want to like be home To let them in.
Speaker 0: but exactly right and it's like.
Speaker 0: that is you know, it's like, you know.
Speaker 0: Obviously you think I'll work from home every single day.
Speaker 0: That would be the best thing ever.
Speaker 1: But everyone I know who's done that has started to go crazy.
Speaker 0: I'm actually perfectly content to just work from home occasionally enough to have my shit together and like that's.
Speaker 0: you know I don't.
Speaker 0: actually I'm okay going to the office offices are.
Speaker 1: I wanted to work from home a lot more when I had a commute But now it takes me like 12 minutes to get to my desk.
Speaker 0: Yeah anyway from here.
Speaker 0: So but now they're like, oh my god virus, right and some people they're panicking too much And some people not panicking enough and too much is obviously better than not enough.
Speaker 0: But I don't see a lot of people getting it just right.
Speaker 1: too much is better than not enough.
Speaker 1: up to the point of I am Going to Mad Max that is that is too much.
Speaker 0: Yes, that is too much.
Speaker 0: You cannot personally Mad Max Maybe.
Speaker 0: so my company decided to do was not let anyone travel on business trips.
Speaker 0: Okay, sure.
Speaker 0: I'm on that.
Speaker 1: I'm not allowed to go to conferences until not going any business trips anyway.
Speaker 0: And to they're like, okay, we made sure everyone's VPN works in their computer.
Speaker 0: Let's try to work from home for two days to see how it goes.
Speaker 0: so Wednesday after I already left work, they sent an email saying hey work from home Thursday Friday.
Speaker 0: So this morning I got on the train and it went back because like if they didn't say don't come to work I would have I'd go in.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they didn't cancel hockey.
Speaker 0: I would have gone to hockey, right?
Speaker 0: But yeah, no, they're like, okay work from home Thursday Friday.
Speaker 0: So Michael not gonna argue with you Right, I might be willing to go to work, but I'm not gonna go.
Speaker 0: it's an empty office.
Speaker 0: But I had to go and get my work computer that I left at work.
Speaker 0: It's a lot of other people seem to carry their work laptops back and forth every day.
Speaker 1: No, no, no.
Speaker 0: I only carry it home.
Speaker 0: Like if you see at the end of the day my laptops not on the desk, that means I work at home tomorrow.
Speaker 1: It's interesting.
Speaker 1: a lot of people I know like not just my current job and in all the jobs I've ever had Don't have like good PCs or equipment at home.
Speaker 0: Like they need I'm not using.
Speaker 0: I'm not using my purse I had.
Speaker 0: do.
Speaker 0: I'm not using my personal computer for work.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if I'm working from home I do because I don't need remember the kind of job I do.
Speaker 1: I don't need like local files or anything.
Speaker 1: No, it's not about that.
Speaker 0: It's I'm not gonna use my hardware.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't I don't care for my works if they want it if they want me to have a good You know a computer at home to work on.
Speaker 0: Well, they should have bought me one.
Speaker 0: Yeah But I already bought me this one.
Speaker 0: So that's the one I'll use right?
Speaker 0: My computer would actually do the work a lot faster, but they didn't want to buy me a fancy work laptop.
Speaker 0: So I'm gonna do the work at the speed of the laptop that they have provided.
Speaker 0: That's you know, anyway, that's a separate issue.
Speaker 0: So this morning I went back to the work to get You know my laptop and bring it home.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I tried to go to TJ's which is across the street from my work.
Speaker 0: I'm there at like 9 a.m.
Speaker 0: And I'm like, you know what I'm going this TJ, right and I'm gonna get me some snacks And maybe I'll get some English muffin because they sell if you don't know Thomas English muffins at the grocery store usually overpriced when they're on sale There may be like $2.
Speaker 0: TJ's.
Speaker 0: English muffins are better and only like a dollar fifty at all time.
Speaker 0: Hell, yeah, that's right.
Speaker 0: So I was trying to get and then I wanted to maybe get some locks to put on there, right?
Speaker 0: They're sold out of locks Wow, and there was a usually that TJ, you know TJ's in Manhattan often have mega lines Right.
Speaker 0: This one rarely has the mega line.
Speaker 0: The line was wrapped like around the whole store.
Speaker 1: I find the most fascinating about this is like in Midtown Like I went to a random CVS just like to get a Red Bull they got everything like.
Speaker 1: it is no crowd there.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, there's a CVS right next door.
Speaker 0: They had everything.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like the people who are like panic buying thousands of rolls.
Speaker 0: I don't think people are Panic, some people are but I don't think most people are.
Speaker 0: I someone showed a photo of Astoria grocery store That was really crowded.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and You know the the idea that they were trying to get across.
Speaker 1: like I saw that photo It didn't look that much more crowded than normal.
Speaker 0: It was pretty crowded.
Speaker 0: But the point is People the idea they're trying to get across is like all people are panicking but I looked at people's carts and it was just like Cereal.
Speaker 0: Well, it's like normal shit and I'm like no no, no, no No, people are not going crazy cuz I'm virus and rushing and my you know, cleaning out the grocery store.
Speaker 0: It's simply that when people don't have to commute and spend eight hours in office.
Speaker 0: Oh my god They finally got time to take care of.
Speaker 0: their finally got time to cook.
Speaker 0: Maybe they could actually go to the grocery and buy ingredients to cook and not have to get delivery.
Speaker 0: That's why there's a crowd at the grocery store.
Speaker 0: Right if people could work from if everyone could work from home as much as I do The grocery store would just always be slightly more crowded than it is.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but it wouldn't need to be as open it like 2 in the morning like the Wegmans right to go to anyway.
Speaker 0: So on the way back on the train after I bailed from the TJ and had the laptop I'm on the train and the train stops at 34th Street and a smell funny smell.
Speaker 0: Oh and everything's.
Speaker 0: I look around.
Speaker 0: there's no stinky people It's not a crowded train.
Speaker 1: Go is it that does go?
Speaker 1: is it that bromine like disinfectant smell?
Speaker 0: No, the train was going in the opposite direction of commuting.
Speaker 0: So it wasn't crowded.
Speaker 0: No, um, and it's kind of hazy.
Speaker 0: And I look at oh and there's like a firefighter coming out of a haze.
Speaker 1: And it was basically they always talk about like track fire, dude I do know I've seen like 10 or 15 track fires at Queensborough Plaza in the time.
Speaker 0: Right, but this is an indoor underground track fire that filled that station with smoke.
Speaker 0: So I switched.
Speaker 0: another train comes in and that train this the the indicators aren't on telling me what letter it is.
Speaker 1: But you're just like I want to get out of this station, right?
Speaker 0: The train at the W I was on wasn't moving and I'm like, well that has to be NRQ It can't possibly be anything else.
Speaker 0: I get on it.
Speaker 1: It's all right for Street.
Speaker 1: I guess an R could.
Speaker 1: I think there's a way for an R to get.
Speaker 0: it would be on the same as the W So it would be behind us.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so I switch and then finally after I switch the W moves And you know how this smoke and there's like a firefighter walking around.
Speaker 0: it's all creepy the thing.
Speaker 1: But I the thing I love about New York is like that situation to a New Yorker is just slightly Notable and easily forgotten.
Speaker 0: right and then but they don't tell you about right now.
Speaker 0: They don't tell you which one is leaving next and then the queue moves that I'm on which I didn't realize there's a queue until It stopped.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you watch you now because now I don't want to be right I don't want to be on a queue.
Speaker 0: So luckily I was able to run across at 42nd Street to get back on the W because they stopped.
Speaker 0: they have big at the same Stops.
Speaker 0: Yep, and then I got home.
Speaker 0: But yeah, but there was a. it was a creepy scene at 34th Street because track fires real common But I don't encounter the track fire indoor.
Speaker 0: I've encountered the outside track fires occasionally But the indoor ones that filled the station with smoke and made it smell bad and had firefighters there are less frequent and You know, we were stuck in that station with the fire for a little while.
Speaker 0: Yeah So it was slightly more notable than you know.
Speaker 1: Like I've said before the creepiest thing that's ever happened to me on the subway other than the first time I saw a garbage train Before I knew those were a thing.
Speaker 0: Because it's why do you think garbage train?
Speaker 0: Where do you see track geometry?
Speaker 1: Oh my god that thing.
Speaker 1: because it's not like it's scary It's not like it's made out of a skeleton or blind you.
Speaker 1: It's more that if you've been in the city enough Like you just have this sense of you hear subway noise and you look to your right and a subway train comes in and then One time you hear the subway noise.
Speaker 1: They look to your right and something fucking else is there.
Speaker 1: Yeah, doesn't matter if it's scary It's just your brain like almost already shows you a subway.
Speaker 1: and then you get there and the brains like wait This doesn't map the fuck is that?
Speaker 1: and it takes your brain a while to figure it out.
Speaker 0: It's the x-ray.
Speaker 1: But the creepiest thing I ever encountered on the subway was still Hurricane Sandy when they just turned off the lights at every station On the way it was.
Speaker 1: so it was just silent.
Speaker 1: The train would stop the conductor would just walk out like lock a bunch of stuff Close a bunch of gates go into that little booth.
Speaker 1: If it was there all the lights would turn off one by one and then they'd get back on the train.
Speaker 1: They'd yell last call doors would close and then it was just pitch black outside of that train And we moved on to the next station.
Speaker 1: Mmm.
Speaker 1: It was a weirdly fun night that night.
Speaker 1: just because of that whole situation They're burning.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: You got any news?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I got some news.
Speaker 0: so Recently, there was some teasing tweets about a Super Mario Lego combo and that's pretty sexy news.
Speaker 0: It's like you go to Toys R Us when I'm a kid.
Speaker 0: And what did I buy?
Speaker 0: Nintendo games?
Speaker 0: Yeah Legos.
Speaker 0: Those are the two things that I bought.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So now finally after 20 magic cards, I buy magic cards.
Speaker 0: Sometimes not a Toys R Us.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I mean I didn't.
Speaker 1: I didn't buy them there At Toys R Us and Meijer.
Speaker 0: anyway after 20-plus something years Finally those things combining in an official capacity.
Speaker 0: That's a big news for a nerd But then they revealed what it is and what it is is actually pretty cool But something I have no interest in owning personally.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: If you have a kid you are obligated to buy them this.
Speaker 1: Oh my god, when I get of appropriate age when I was a kid This would have been like the best gift of that Christmas.
Speaker 0: Basically what is is a Duplo level kind of Lego.
Speaker 1: actually it's sort of in between Lego and Duplo and it's the pieces are Lego Conforming but the Mario pieces have like big blocky pieces.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but they interface with the regular Lego.
Speaker 1: you look at it You see what I mean, right?
Speaker 0: but anyway what it is?
Speaker 0: it's a Lego toy where Mario is electronic in some fashion and he any Interact a little screen on his chest and had a screen on his chest and he interacts with the other Lego pieces.
Speaker 0: So for example you put Mario on top of a goomba and he'll make a goomba stomping noise and like get some points Appearing on his chest.
Speaker 0: or like you'll put him near like a fire and he'll make that like whoa Noise of it when he got his feet get burned and his chest will show fire on it.
Speaker 0: or he'll put him near the flag Pole and it'll go And show the flag on his chest right.
Speaker 0: and it's sort of like you can make your own little Mario thing.
Speaker 0: That's interactive Between you know Mario and all the little little bits and that's a pretty great toy.
Speaker 0: But if you're an adult hoping for like, you know a Nintendo, I want a four thousand piece Mario.
Speaker 1: That's the size of a Death Star.
Speaker 0: Yeah, something like that or like a Koopa castle, you know thing where you open it up And you can put all and there's all sorts of things going on in there.
Speaker 1: That is not what they made Yep, but at the same time I'd like this is just such a phenomenal looking toy.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah over made this way.
Speaker 0: good I think everyone in any elementary school anywhere wants this.
Speaker 1: Oh my god This is I would put like if I ran like a doctor's office This would be one of the things that would just be in the waiting room.
Speaker 0: I think there's certain rules about what kind of toys are okay for like.
Speaker 0: the nut is a choking hazard So you can't put in doctors.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it depends on what level I guess and also sanitation.
Speaker 0: I mean There's a reason why every every every doctor and dentist has that toy where the the wires things across the wires of the wood.
Speaker 1: with The blocks you move along the wires.
Speaker 0: Yes now that toy.
Speaker 0: if you search for doctor's office toy on Google Images You will see the toy.
Speaker 1: Yep The orange wire was the best wire.
Speaker 1: Okay, that was a really long one.
Speaker 0: Okay, obviously the longest highest most complicated one was the best.
Speaker 1: I was the orange one.
Speaker 0: IIRC obviously some some other news.
Speaker 1: Uh, I don't know how many of you care about this, but remember geek nights.
Speaker 1: two nights ago I talked about the hero pools and overwatch.
Speaker 0: you're doing the same news twice in two geek night.
Speaker 1: All I'm gonna talk about.
Speaker 1: well cuz I I feel like I don't need to tell you that stuff shutting down.
Speaker 1: You should socially distance and like if your convention is canceled because of coronavirus like there's a reason they canceled it.
Speaker 1: Like don't get mad at the organizers.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like, you know, I if they canceled hockey if they didn't cancel hockey I would have gone.
Speaker 0: no, but they canceled it.
Speaker 1: So hockey is a hockey.
Speaker 1: audience is a much lower risk than a weekend-long convention for a lot of reasons I don't want to get into.
Speaker 1: it's bigger though a shorter duration shorter duration less interaction Fewer hotel stays.
Speaker 0: I still one person caught it like the wave.
Speaker 0: one person coughs in the prison to the left to coughs in the Person to the left.
Speaker 0: he coughs in the person then it makes a circle.
Speaker 0: that could happen in one period.
Speaker 1: but They just did the rotation and the next four heroes they pulled out.
Speaker 1: This will mean nothing to Scott, but they they pulled out Basically, like the four most important heroes just to see what the fuck happens.
Speaker 1: So the four most used one Reinhardt the big guy with the shield like the guy that like everyone uses to make a big Channing the four best people.
Speaker 1: Yeah Well, not the four best people but like for the most used ones.
Speaker 1: The other thing is that two of them are healers.
Speaker 1: There's two healers that are like super a big part of the meta and like people really worry about which healers.
Speaker 1: They basically remove the two best healers meaning you can use a shitty healer or no healer.
Speaker 1: Yeah, meaning well, you have to have two healers.
Speaker 1: You could have two shitty healers, but healers that are shitty Oh, right because they have the roll lock.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but good at other things.
Speaker 1: This shows the power of this feature Like the fact that the meta is so radically different now and just by saying you can't use these two healers.
Speaker 1: Now like which damaged guy do you play is way different.
Speaker 0: This gave me an idea right of a way to possibly evolve this idea to make it even better.
Speaker 0: Yeah Obviously if you have a bunch of choices in any game an asymmetric game and those choices are not all on the parade or frontier Right, if you there's no reason to ever use something in outside the parade or frontier unless you're dunking on someone who's worse.
Speaker 0: But I'm saying if you ban Options that are not on the frontier.
Speaker 0: You're changing nothing basically, right?
Speaker 0: It's only interesting to ban options on the frontier.
Speaker 0: Yep, because it's the only thing that will change what people play with them for moving the frontier, right?
Speaker 1: Instead of picking who to ban.
Speaker 1: It'll just ban whatever heroes are used the most or the most effective.
Speaker 0: I'm saying go even further than that.
Speaker 0: Yeah every hour Right figure out which hero of each category was most used.
Speaker 0: no, right and Ban that one.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right and that way it's obviously every single hero will be unbanned the next hour.
Speaker 0: So it's like okay.
Speaker 0: This guy's opie.
Speaker 0: He'll be available every other hour.
Speaker 1: Oh, this gives me an even better idea based on your better idea.
Speaker 1: Smash tournament right big weekend long full format smash tournament.
Speaker 1: But the way it works is if you win around with a hero with a player character, that's what Hearthstone did.
Speaker 1: Yeah You can never use that character again for the rest of the tournament.
Speaker 0: Hearthstone did that?
Speaker 0: Hearthstone did you had you bring X decks and you have to get a win with each one.
Speaker 0: I also did.
Speaker 0: you can play your decks as much as you want But as soon as one of your decks loses that one is dead and you have to play the remaining.
Speaker 1: But I want to see you like I win round one with Bowser I cannot pick Bowser again for the rest of the tournament.
Speaker 0: Fuck you What if during it This how about this?
Speaker 0: ready in a single match of overwatch?
Speaker 0: Oh, you join a match of overwatch.
Speaker 0: pick whoever the fuck you want, right?
Speaker 0: So who'd you say was this that's really strong?
Speaker 1: He'll don't say we're doing talent healers more.
Speaker 1: I'd be more.
Speaker 0: So you're more of the best healer, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, you start playing.
Speaker 0: you're dead.
Speaker 0: You're still stuck in the healer role, but I can't be more.
Speaker 0: ever is dead.
Speaker 0: You cannot pick more again this match.
Speaker 0: You have to pick a different healer.
Speaker 1: even better if you die and now you can't be any healer.
Speaker 1: Fuck you.
Speaker 0: Well, I think if you die, I think I think it would reset.
Speaker 1: yeah, well that's because that's what root does with the birds.
Speaker 1: if you decline like you go into turmoil four times and all your Leaders are dead.
Speaker 0: They all respond or you could have.
Speaker 0: you could either reset you could just be like you're fucked or you could be like Here, there's some base healer who's like just this like replacement player and like if you looks like Barney from half-life.
Speaker 0: Exactly you've lost you've lost.
Speaker 0: you've died with all of the real characters.
Speaker 0: You're now stuck on the generic healer guy no matter what role you're in.
Speaker 1: You just turn into Dan Hibiki.
Speaker 0: Yes, exactly Right, so they the only problem with this.
Speaker 0: I think it has a little bit of snowball enos.
Speaker 0: Oh, it definitely does but if you sort of mix it up, right so you kill the other team's healer But they kill your tank and it's you can sort of.
Speaker 0: it might not be a complete snowball for one side because you have teams.
Speaker 0: Yes, might be snowball per player if it's Depending.
Speaker 1: Well, you know what that's like in counter-strike good old gun game, you know.
Speaker 0: But the point is with that mode right you could then combine it with that sort of ban, right?
Speaker 0: So you could be like, okay, which heat healer was chosen in first Right in all these games and then you ban that one and then you have the reset.
Speaker 0: so it's okay.
Speaker 0: We banned the healer that keeps getting chosen first and will reset you.
Speaker 0: so you have to cycle through all of them.
Speaker 0: So you can't be good at a character.
Speaker 0: You have to be good at a whole class.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if you want to play over which is actually Bob That's kind of the direction overwatch is pushing in terms of.
Speaker 1: you can be you can play whatever you want.
Speaker 0: It's like.
Speaker 0: you don't have to be good at tank and healing and sniping Yep, but you have to pick one and be able to play any character.
Speaker 1: Yeah of that role and remember way back the other change they made.
Speaker 1: that was brilliant that I talked about a while ago.
Speaker 1: They rank you separately for each type.
Speaker 1: now So I have a rank in tank that's way higher than my rank in DPS.
Speaker 1: for obvious reasons I'm 38, right.
Speaker 0: Here's another thing you could do right which might not make players want to play is the problem.
Speaker 0: But instead of banning the one that's chosen the most we ban you from choosing the one you choose the most.
Speaker 0: So so you are a. you know, even let's say you are a big Danny Vicky guy.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like you can't play Dan.
Speaker 0: Too bad, you're too good with Dan.
Speaker 0: Yep, you can play the top meta guy.
Speaker 0: sure You think you have no practice with.
Speaker 0: basically is you get too good with the character?
Speaker 0: We force you off that character and onto another one.
Speaker 1: But what I like to is this all these types of things like what overwatch is doing and even the crazy stuff we suggested now They do a game design thing that I kind of like where instead of trying to balance your entire game forever.
Speaker 1: Just Mix up a bunch of stuff and then the game becomes.
Speaker 1: who figures out the new meta first?
Speaker 0: Well, that's the thing.
Speaker 0: is a meta?
Speaker 0: can a meta, you know matter how much you know It always takes time to form but it will change the game frequently enough.
Speaker 0: It cannot.
Speaker 0: you can prevent it from forming.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right.
Speaker 0: No, no one can evolve to adapt to an environment if the environment changes more faster than the rate of evolution.
Speaker 0: Yep,
Speaker 1: and If a degenerate strategy appears like think back to sports fucking awesome I want to watch the overwatch league match where the the disaster meta that appears from the hero bands ends up making a weird degenerate Nonsense situation because that is the anomalous thing that I love to see in a sports match like crazy shit happening.
Speaker 1: but anyway Things of the day what he got.
Speaker 0: Oh, so I discovered this very short animated film recently Thanks to reading a lot of internet.
Speaker 0: This is from.
Speaker 0: I get the feeling this is one of those short animations that would play before a movie.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'm not sure when it was exactly shown but it was Written directed and voiced by Mel Brooks, but there's other people involved.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you can check the credits, but it's mostly a Mel Brooks joint.
Speaker 0: It's called the critic has nothing to do with the other animated critic.
Speaker 1: I almost want to read out loud this description of it from the.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you can read it yourself, but it's only what.
Speaker 0: it's less than 10 minutes long.
Speaker 0: It's super short, right.
Speaker 0: three minutes long It's long.
Speaker 0: So this will be a very entertaining three minutes for anyone who has never heard of This or seen it before like me where I've seen pretty much everything Mel Brooks has ever created.
Speaker 0: Yeah, several times over yet.
Speaker 0: I hadn't seen this so that's got to be thing of the day worthy.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: I I'm not gonna say anything about it.
Speaker 1: Just watch it.
Speaker 1: In fact, I would say watch it before you even read the YouTube description.
Speaker 0: got three minutes, right?
Speaker 0: You're wasting your time.
Speaker 1: What are you doing?
Speaker 1: 24 seconds saying.
Speaker 0: what are you doing with your time?
Speaker 0: Listen to geek nights.
Speaker 0: No, you can.
Speaker 0: you can change that.
Speaker 1: So We've never made this a thing of the day.
Speaker 1: It's been around for a while like in various forms, but it's irrelevant to our main bit.
Speaker 1: this is just a YouTube video that is like 16 17 minutes long and is a collection of bloopers Failures and I feel like I've seen this before.
Speaker 1: I think I've seen parts of this before from like specials Like.
Speaker 1: I think I saw this in a documentary or parts of it, but it's from Star Wars a new hope.
Speaker 1: But some of it isn't even mistakes so much as it's the video that they were filming but with the audio from the soundstage or the set that includes like Some production assistant or even in some cases the director or an assistant director yelling at stormtroopers like walk faster faster faster
Speaker 0: I mean the all.
Speaker 0: the entire movie was dubbed over.
Speaker 0: Yeah, pretty much almost every scene in Star Wars the new hope as a DIs There's Almost everything in the entire original trilogy is dubbed over in post.
Speaker 1: In fact most action movies until like relatively recent times had a lot of ADR because good camera.
Speaker 0: But there was still audio recorded on set.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it just was when they went to post.
Speaker 0: They just got rid of that like some old movies.
Speaker 1: if you see these things It's great.
Speaker 1: Like you'll literally hear someone saying like pew pew pew and they shoot a gun sometimes Like you'll hear someone off-screen just yelling bang bang bang or especially like stunt actors need to communicate with each other.
Speaker 0: There's like a fight scene or anything like that, right?
Speaker 0: So they don't hurt each other.
Speaker 0: I was watching one from or they need to yell.
Speaker 0: timings like okay Like let's say there's like a motorcycle jump over it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that happens all the time and like James Bond movies, right?
Speaker 0: Then you know you hear people.
Speaker 0: it's like okay one two three.
Speaker 0: Okay go with the car and Now the motorcycle.
Speaker 0: timing, you know, you need instruction, right?
Speaker 0: This was just like because they're all collected and then in post all you hear is Right, you know some special effects or some shit.
Speaker 1: But just the fact that this is a whole bunch of them and a variety of those situations just all strung together It's pretty entertaining to watch.
Speaker 0: I mean Star Wars right a lightsaber fight.
Speaker 0: It's two people smacking wooden sticks together.
Speaker 0: These clacking noises also, right?
Speaker 0: They gotta replace those with the old, you know, electric razor and a metal bowl noise.
Speaker 1: You get Darth Vader's real voice, but like the actor thought he actually had to act.
Speaker 0: Yep, and you get a lot of outtakes 100 everyone knows this but a hundred percent of Darth Vader is dubbed over by James Earl Jones.
Speaker 0: Yes, but the actor who actually played Darth Any might know but can now currently actually act bring to mind and I want to say it's a name I know.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I know the name.
Speaker 0: I just can't say it right now, but there's a lot my brain is not good.
Speaker 1: there's that one scene where he chokes out a Rebellion.
Speaker 0: so giant dude, he died actually not too long.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they keep having to do retakes of him choking out this dude, and it's actually really funny.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna look it up cuz it's driving me nuts that I can't remember his name.
Speaker 0: Yep David Prowse.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's a guy.
Speaker 0: He's a no if you ever seen him outside the Darth Vader costume.
Speaker 0: He's enormous.
Speaker 1: Yeah in the metamoment he knows book club book the tale of Genji.
Speaker 1: I am Genji and a long Hanzo.
Speaker 1: Hanzo is not showing up yet.
Speaker 0: Nope Other things going on.
Speaker 0: obviously not any conventions until PAX West which has not yet been announced as canceled Yep, but we'll see how things go with the coronavirus.
Speaker 0: Also, we get a lot more free time with no hockey even to go to.
Speaker 1: So I'm gonna as things in New York slowly shut down.
Speaker 1: I think what we're gonna do is you're gonna see a lot of.
Speaker 0: yeah I got nothing to do except make content and I guess Zelda randomizer has like gone up to the top of the list of things right now.
Speaker 1: this weekend I'm gonna set up a Final Fantasy 4 free enterprise infrastructure, right?
Speaker 1: I'm gonna set it up.
Speaker 1: So if anyone is interested in trying out the Final Fantasy 4 randomizer I will be very patient with you because I need some people to play it this way if you want to play Zelda 3 Randomized in some way.
Speaker 0: come to the geek nights official semi official.
Speaker 1: I'll do score.
Speaker 1: I'll dig up a link to it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, uh, yeah, we got discord.
Speaker 0: you go to Twitter.
Speaker 0: We got to do two different YouTube channels that you should go to.
Speaker 0: we got Instagram.
Speaker 0: I don't remember to use enough.
Speaker 0: Yep, but it's there.
Speaker 1: It's it's I shut down the rimbler's.
Speaker 1: the rimbler's gone.
Speaker 0: Oh the rimbler.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 1: I also shut down.
Speaker 1: I forgot I had a tumblr whose sole purpose was.
Speaker 0: I think I actually have access to the geek nights YouTube channel that we don't use.
Speaker 0: Anyway, we have a lot of.
Speaker 0: Oh geek nice is now on Spotify if you want to listen to it there instead.
Speaker 0: Yep We got everything.
Speaker 1: we got stuff going on.
Speaker 0: I didn't delete the Facebook page and if you end up getting stuck at home with I probably should.
Speaker 1: We're gonna be playing a lot of video games and hanging out online.
Speaker 0: Yeah, now it's me.
Speaker 0: It's nerd time.
Speaker 0: Now.
Speaker 0: Everyone's stuck inside.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's nerd season.
Speaker 1: I'm dusting off the VR.
Speaker 0: Oh, the only thing that can stop me is is bike season which is coming.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: So that's good.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the thing is because once it's warm, the one thing coronavirus does not stop for me is running.
Speaker 0: I am I will bike regardless of any virus.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna get a virus while biking.
Speaker 1: in fact running is gonna be great because if if like all the places I run don't have People I don't have to deal with crowds of people blocking me and messing up my times.
Speaker 0: less cars.
Speaker 0: Yeah bikes.
Speaker 1: So otherwise, yeah stay tuned We got.
Speaker 1: no that the next possible Convention for us at this point is probably gonna be Pax West and none of us have the virus yet.
Speaker 0: So we're can still podcasts.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and even if rims was something like oh, I got the virus Well, I probably got it too.
Speaker 0: Yeah And if somehow he does and I don't we can just podcast over the internet or whatever.
Speaker 1: We.
Speaker 1: the only reason we don't podcast over the internet because it's kind of a pain in the ass But we can.
Speaker 0: we can.
Speaker 1: yeah, I'd have to.
Speaker 1: in fact, it's actually easier now that I got the new rig.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we could go to that if we had to yep.
Speaker 1: I don't think we'll have to for the foreseeable future.
Speaker 0: I do not either.
Speaker 1: Especially well anyway, so the Mandalorian.
Speaker 0: So if you don't know what the deal is, right.
Speaker 0: so Disney bought the Star Wars.
Speaker 0: They made a bunch of movies They made TV show and they brought out their Disney Plus streaming network and they want to compete with the Netflix and you know Everyone else the hoot.
Speaker 0: Well, I guess they own Hulu also.
Speaker 0: I don't know why they just don't.
Speaker 0: I thought they would just merge Hulu into Disney Plus But I guess they want to keep all the Disney branded content in the Disney Plus.
Speaker 0: We want all the other things they technically own but aren't Disney branded on the Hulu side.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so last night we pulled up Disney Plus and I saw a movie that struck.
Speaker 1: You know Sometimes you see something and suddenly your brain remembers something from your childhood that you look.
Speaker 0: poster looks familiar.
Speaker 1: The name rings No bells, so there's this Disney Plus movie called Perry Uh-huh, and it's a lot.
Speaker 1: It's basically a nature documentary with a narrative about this squirrel Mm-hmm, and I saw it when we were just scrolling through Disney Plus and I was like something that I've that some stern Powerful in my soul and we watched it.
Speaker 1: I'm not only do I remember this I am like 90% sure we had it on a VHS tape.
Speaker 0: I definitely didn't have it on VHS tape I'm not.
Speaker 0: I can't tell you whether I remember it or not because the poster is like that's a movie poster I've seen.
Speaker 0: yeah that name and that squirrel I do not remember.
Speaker 0: if I think about I know The only thing that I can think of is like Ricky Dickey whatever heavy.
Speaker 0: Was that a squirrel though?
Speaker 1: No, that was a mongoose a mongoose Scott Ricky.
Speaker 1: Tiki Tavi is not uncommon knowledge.
Speaker 0: No, it's not.
Speaker 0: but I'm saying like that I remember and that's what the squirrel brings to mind.
Speaker 0: Ah, no, I Definitely remember that.
Speaker 0: I didn't remember that whether Ricky D. He was a mongoose or a weasel or something, you know Wasn't a squirrel.
Speaker 1: Yeah, Ricky Dickey.
Speaker 1: Tavi was animated.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: I know that.
Speaker 0: Yep It was there was a snake and the funny.
Speaker 1: when I was a little kid I saw Ricky Dickey Tavi and then I didn't know what it was and it wasn't an internet to look it up and it took Me a long time to find out what like there was a book and all that.
Speaker 1: for some reason I kept asking adult.
Speaker 0: my memory knew my memory of Ricky Dickey there.
Speaker 0: I think there was a book.
Speaker 1: Yes There was a book.
Speaker 0: Yes I think my memory of it is seeing it in the public library in like the meeting room on a projector.
Speaker 0: but my memory of seeing it there includes a memory of having seen it previously like I Remember seeing it in the library and I remember remembering having already seen it But I don't remember where I had already seen it.
Speaker 0: I saw must have been from an even younger age when I had no memory.
Speaker 1: I saw the Chuck Jones cartoon on TV and then I remember like I asked my parents like what it was and they didn't know and like my teacher didn't like no one knew what it was and TV guy didn't say anything other than Chuck Jones Ricky Dickey Tavi.
Speaker 1: Okay, I didn't have anywhere to look it up.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 0: Anyway, uh That's it.
Speaker 0: Anyway, don't Disney Plus right?
Speaker 0: So Disney Plus wants people to sign up.
Speaker 0: So, of course they bring their best hottest property the Star War and they make a TV show.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and it's eight episodes.
Speaker 0: I thought it was more.
Speaker 0: I was wrong.
Speaker 0: Or today I found out it was eight.
Speaker 0: I thought I had watched.
Speaker 0: I watched four episodes at the time when there were only four episodes out.
Speaker 0: Didn't watch any more than that rim.
Speaker 0: watch the whole thing and I loved it.
Speaker 0: I really await the sequel and that was that wasn't.
Speaker 0: and then they came out with more and I didn't watch him and That was that.
Speaker 0: so I found out today.
Speaker 0: There were only eight episodes.
Speaker 0: I thought there were more.
Speaker 0: they're not long either So they're only like all.
Speaker 0: the first one I think is longer longer.
Speaker 0: It's like a typical TV show where you got to start off with the long episodes to build your whole thing.
Speaker 1: Well, also kind of like a lot of shorter, you know.
Speaker 1: You know like some anime like the first episode was a little longer and didn't have the opener.
Speaker 0: Well, yeah, they'll bleed in the first and last episode of a lot of anime.
Speaker 0: They'll bleed over into the credits and they won't have openers or closers or didn't show the closer over the anime to get those Extra seconds in there.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that was the side of the middle episodes.
Speaker 0: We'll have full openers full closers and be really short and cheaper.
Speaker 1: There were definitely some like late 90s anime where if you heard the closing music coming in too early Shit was about to go down.
Speaker 0: Well, I mean the ultimate anime for closing music is coming in while the show is still showing is Gundam seed.
Speaker 1: Yeah, go well for she did it every episode but Gundam seed when it did it That was the episode where you'd be like what?
Speaker 0: Because you'd because they would start playing it while characters is still talking.
Speaker 0: So people are talking or fighting in robots and you hear the song and you're just like fuck you.
Speaker 0: So you didn't realize that was over.
Speaker 0: it's like.
Speaker 0: it's like guess.
Speaker 0: it's like guess what?
Speaker 1: five seconds.
Speaker 1: So now let's back up a little bit - we were young and we saw Star Wars.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and in the background of a bunch of scenes, there was this character that people would say.
Speaker 1: Oh, that's Boba Fett.
Speaker 0: Yep, didn't?
Speaker 1: they didn't tell you shit about.
Speaker 0: Boba Fett was a better toy than a character.
Speaker 1: Here's what I here's what I knew about.
Speaker 1: That's Boba Fett the Mandalorian.
Speaker 0: Well, I mean, yeah, it's like that's Boba Fett.
Speaker 0: It's a dude in armor with a jetpack.
Speaker 1: What's a Boba Fett?
Speaker 1: Is that his name or his race?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I don't know What's a Mandalorian that is never explained.
Speaker 0: bounty hunting?
Speaker 0: Dude with guns and a jetpack and a grappling hook and he wants working with the Empire but not necessarily with the Empire.
Speaker 0: He's obviously some mercenary and he wants to just make money dangerous enough to where even Darth Vader will not give this dude shit.
Speaker 0: But for some reason even after capturing Han and bringing Han to Jabba and getting paid hung out with Jabba.
Speaker 0: Anyway, instead of leaving to find new work.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I always thought that was strange.
Speaker 1: Well, cuz we didn't.
Speaker 0: but then it was died like a chump Yeah, and then it's like I actually didn't pay that much attention.
Speaker 0: I knew Boba Fett right, but I didn't pay that much attention to Boba Fett when I was a kid.
Speaker 0: But later on like high school college Star Wars nerds were always like love it both of it.
Speaker 1: And I'm like family guy would make jokes about this like I never bet the Fett right.
Speaker 0: and it's like You mean that guy who was in the movie for two seconds?
Speaker 0: I'm like people cared a lot about this character.
Speaker 1: Which is the thing like that?
Speaker 0: what I did not care very much about?
Speaker 0: and usually I'm all about caring about the site the small Side character who doesn't get enough skill.
Speaker 1: Well like in Gosaraki, I'm all about the president of the United States, right?
Speaker 0: And it's like I'm okay.
Speaker 0: I'm Boba Fett both.
Speaker 0: That's cool, but I'm not a huge Boba Fett.
Speaker 1: It was partly I think that when I looked at the costumes like Boba Fett really stood out and I really like that.
Speaker 0: if you want to talk about cool side character I'm a. I'm a vix wedge side.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah vixen wedge.
Speaker 0: Give me those x-wings.
Speaker 1: I'm also a very like early venture brothers like 21 and 24 like two henchmen But anyway, I like the Rosencrantz and Guildenstern side characters.
Speaker 0: Obviously the fat man was mad popular though.
Speaker 0: So making any sort of new thing for the mass audience based on Mandalorians bounty hunters Boba Fett's y'all cetera Is gonna be a good sell and is an easy thing to do as a side story?
Speaker 1: And it's fertile ground doesn't?
Speaker 0: yeah It doesn't conflict with anything in the main movies.
Speaker 1: you have now and also you have not Established in the cinematic universe a significant cannon that you have to deal with.
Speaker 0: Yep And you've got an overabundance of now Non-canon that was formerly cannon to completely poach from.
Speaker 0: yeah, because mad nerds were all over that shit.
Speaker 1: Yep, so take all that.
Speaker 0: I don't even think that was the word Mandalorian even said in a Star Wars movie.
Speaker 1: I thought it's hard to see.
Speaker 1: this is the problem.
Speaker 0: It might have been in the in the ridge in the prequel trilogy.
Speaker 1: I feel like it was said because I knew the word But I don't know.
Speaker 0: I knew the word from nerds on the internet.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't.
Speaker 0: I don't think I knew the Someone out there who's watched the prequel series because it definitely wasn't said in episodes 4 5 6.
Speaker 0: Well, this is the thing said in episodes 1 2 or 3 nerds.
Speaker 0: Let us know.
Speaker 1: You know what?
Speaker 1: It's like.
Speaker 1: it's like when I first got into anime and I was in elementary school and like I couldn't find out about anime Like I'd see some anime but like there was no way to find out more about it.
Speaker 0: You googled that you wouldn't find too much.
Speaker 0: there wasn't Google.
Speaker 0: No There wasn't.
Speaker 1: and then there'd be the.
Speaker 1: it was the nerd in my middle school who knew a lot about anime Because he had lived in Japan for a long time and He would just like tell me things about anime that I like.
Speaker 1: like he told me shit about tenchi muyo And I was just like what the fuck always remember this.
Speaker 0: I'll always remember fourth grade.
Speaker 0: It was a Japanese exchange student, right and we were doing something.
Speaker 0: We're like we drew pictures of what we wanted for holiday gifts or something of all and he drew a Super Nintendo.
Speaker 0: Everyone else was like what the fuck?
Speaker 0: there ain't no such thing as Super Nintendo.
Speaker 0: Super Nintendo You're making shit up.
Speaker 0: and then that Japanese kid was definitely not Right, they knew what he knew.
Speaker 0: what was up, right?
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so Boba Fett has this like cultural cachet, but also the new Star Wars movies.
Speaker 1: I'm not saying good or bad or anything, but some people really like them.
Speaker 1: Some people really hate them.
Speaker 1: Some people don't care.
Speaker 0: I like them.
Speaker 0: I just don't like them as much as the original.
Speaker 1: I'm pretty much in that same boat.
Speaker 1: I don't hate them as much as the prequel trilogy But they're set what like 20 30 years after the trilogy that everyone knows and loves.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but the point is like I could watch original trilogy and I'll just be captured in it like a yep Oh my god.
Speaker 0: prequel trilogy.
Speaker 0: I'll try to turn it off.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right the new trilogy.
Speaker 0: I'll watch it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I would watch it again, but I could not be trapped by it.
Speaker 1: I could turn it off if I want but to this day like if you put up if if I see those twin suns rising Fuck I'm stuck here now until this movie ends.
Speaker 1: There's no way out.
Speaker 1: That's right.
Speaker 0: So that's hopefully The end of the movie was the new beginning.
Speaker 1: have a lot of stuff That's from a like a future of the Star Wars universe But the Mandalorian is basically set right like a couple years after Episode six.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: So like stormtrooper like instead of having like oh the stormtroopers It's like oh There's the general who's like leading a band of ex stormtroopers on this bullshit planet hiding from the New Republic.
Speaker 1: It's set in the same universe that I have the maximum nostalgia for the accoutrements of Mm-hmm, and I think they realize there's a terrible power there coupled with it's not spoilers at this point.
Speaker 1: The whole thing is he's protecting the child, which is basically a baby Yoda, right?
Speaker 0: So that's the thing.
Speaker 0: is they went in?
Speaker 1: if you were surprised by that?
Speaker 1: I really want to know how you avoided knowing that.
Speaker 0: Yeah They go in already.
Speaker 0: The show is like announcing that it's fanservice the show because it's Boba Fett the show.
Speaker 0: No, it's not the Fett man.
Speaker 0: You know what for Star Wars if it's set in like the direct and then some genius is like what fanservice thing Could we come up with to make people who don't care about a Boba Fett man, right?
Speaker 0: want to watch this show?
Speaker 1: and the answer is turns into lone wolf in color, like.
Speaker 0: I don't think they've told us exactly which Genius came up with a baby Yoda idea, but that's basically like whoever was like in a writers room and was like Baby Yoda.
Speaker 0: and they're just like here's a here's this briefcase full of money.
Speaker 0: you win Genius like the extent it's like, you know personally like it doesn't excite me personally that much like it's guy.
Speaker 1: It's cute I like it.
Speaker 1: Well, I like.
Speaker 1: I'm like the baby is a mural and dangerous, right?
Speaker 0: But the point is that I might not be a good guy.
Speaker 0: that idea is obvious.
Speaker 0: gold mine.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right in terms of oh obviously that will be the greatest hit in the Boba Fett.
Speaker 1: someone who never says a word and the entire universe just agrees as a badass despite not having any right.
Speaker 0: It's like.
Speaker 0: it's like a music producer.
Speaker 0: Here's a song.
Speaker 0: They might not like that song They might not play that song in their car more than a few times, but it's like.
Speaker 0: they know that's going platinum.
Speaker 0: Yep, that right.
Speaker 0: Here's a contract.
Speaker 0: Mr.
Speaker 0: Rock star.
Speaker 1: So we were at PAX East a little while ago and at PAX East there's acquisitions incorporated where the penny arcade people play Dungeons & Dragons with celebrity guests and just fun.
Speaker 1: and I was there like helping but manage the audience.
Speaker 1: They basically made the entire plot was basically the Mandalorian with a baby Something else baby Mike's character.
Speaker 1: Okay, Mike's character turned into a baby and the rest of characters had to like Mandalorian.
Speaker 1: that baby.
Speaker 0: so she's out.
Speaker 1: So The Mandalorian if I actually had to describe it it did like on a high level before we get into like some details and review.
Speaker 1: It gives me a lot of the feels that moments from the original Star Wars give me Sometimes and it gives me fan service and the fan.
Speaker 1: but the fan service is not.
Speaker 1: it doesn't cross that line where I cringe at It.
Speaker 1: like there's this one moment in a later episode Where it just does a venture brothers kind of thing or a vixen wedge kind of thing.
Speaker 1: It just costs to these two like dumbass Stormtroopers working for the bad guy and they're just sitting on speeder bikes outside of town and they they're just bored and they keep calling Back in like can we come back into town yet?
Speaker 1: And they're like no Darth whatever just like murdered.
Speaker 1: a bunch of people just hang tight and they're just like ends having this like mundane conversation.
Speaker 1: and one of them just kind of is bored and he's kind of pulls out his blaster and starts fucking with it and there's like This garbage in the distance and he just starts taking potshots at the garbage Just can't fucking hit it.
Speaker 1: And the other one starts kind of chuckling like that kind of stuff.
Speaker 1: like that's the line of.
Speaker 1: I like that kind of fan service.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so what the show is is it's actually just lone wolf and cub a serial Western Which is well just lone wolf income, but it's just So.
Speaker 1: it's actually more than that because I've seen the whole thing.
Speaker 1: every episode is Take the lone wolf and cub like basic like we have a lone wolf income situation and then make that episode an homage to a different Genre or milieu of cinema.
Speaker 1: like what episode is a full-on Western?
Speaker 1: one of them is a full-on heist movie.
Speaker 1: Like every one of them is a very different genre And the only thing that ties them together is the lone wolf and cub.
Speaker 1: One of them is very Kurosawa as opposed to like traditional American Western.
Speaker 1: Mmm I know you didn't like the Kurosawa one.
Speaker 0: I mean, it's basically right.
Speaker 0: So, you know when you go see a Star Wars movie, right?
Speaker 0: You're seeing right?
Speaker 0: Everything is like very grandiose Right and large like you like on Endor.
Speaker 1: There's like a thousand a TSTs like whatever there's everywhere, right?
Speaker 0: But I'm just saying like now
Speaker 1: see with 80 not
Speaker 0: just the content of what is happening story-wise being grand But the the production of it right the way it's shot, right the the kind of like wide You know terrain shots they have Right, you know even
Speaker 1: the stakes like we're waiting here to save an entire planet.
Speaker 0: right the loud score, right?
Speaker 0: It's like, you know trumpets like your door Star right, it's like they're there, you know, it's like ta-da.
Speaker 0: here comes the king.
Speaker 0: Star Wars is walking through right?
Speaker 0: Whereas this is sort of like, you know It's like.
Speaker 0: okay the actually the beginning couple episodes sort of have a lot of that going on Even though you're telling this smaller story about a few characters
Speaker 1: because it's not environmental storytelling but it's more the same
Speaker 0: way that cowboy bebop tells a story about just a few characters are in this bigger world where other stuff is Bigger than
Speaker 1: that.
Speaker 1: Well, like it doesn't tell you what the deal is with this like former Imperial guy No, but you can imply a lot about the universe.
Speaker 1: That's interesting without ruining it by being too specific, right?
Speaker 0: But the point is in those beginning episodes, even though you're still focusing on the small Set of characters in the smaller situation, right?
Speaker 0: You're still setting It's.
Speaker 0: it's those early episodes aren't doing the serial thing yet They're sort of the first two episodes are really sort of Setting up the.
Speaker 0: you know that Mandalorian, you know, baby situation.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that is gonna be carried through the other episodes.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and they do it pretty pretty well pretty succinct.
Speaker 0: So those early episodes I was actually kind of way into it, right?
Speaker 0: But then you know episode three a little bit and episode four completely Right.
Speaker 0: What ends up happening is okay.
Speaker 0: that big setup that we did right is now been reduced to this thread That is simply tying these independent episodes together.
Speaker 0: as you see these characters travel from Story to.
Speaker 1: so I would urge you because it's only eight episodes to watch the rest because I got stuff to do.
Speaker 1: After that episode four.
Speaker 1: it basically turns into resolve that plot and go deep.
Speaker 1: Oh, maybe it's not just fight an AT-AT in episode five.
Speaker 1: It actually is like like five is like a heist movie instead like totally different and that leads into like why the Mandalorians are Doing what they're doing and like it.
Speaker 1: it goes deep into the Imperial thing and answers a lot of questions.
Speaker 1: But like all the other someone way more important than Verna Herzog shows up with a lightsaber.
Speaker 0: Okay The other thing is like I said, not just content wise but also, you know Filming wise score wise, you know all that right?
Speaker 1: It's does it's not grand cuz I don't want it to be grand.
Speaker 1: I like this release.
Speaker 1: I love the idea of like like I like that AT-ST episode a lot because you zoom in and it's just here's some regular people and we're looking at an AT-ST like from the ground up in a zoomed in environment as opposed to here's the wide shot and there's A thousand AT-STs in a giant battle.
Speaker 0: Yeah, maybe I just thought it was sort of cheesy like Oh, I love monster in the woods is an AT-ST Like.
Speaker 0: I already saw that coming a mile away.
Speaker 1: I saw it coming too because it was a formula and it's Kurosawa esque movie But it's boring and lame.
Speaker 1: I wanted that because I really like watching like Good deep homages to other movies and the fact that
Speaker 0: I don't mind that it's not the fact that there's no mod It's just that it was sort of like a oh my like, okay I see we're doing
Speaker 1: it but I will say it's got.
Speaker 1: the other episodes are not like that.
Speaker 1: All right, like it does not do but all you know.
Speaker 0: But episode three like the second half was sort of you know winding down right and it's like.
Speaker 0: I still can't find words to describe It.
Speaker 0: that will let anyone accept my feelings but basically I don't accept your feelings.
Speaker 0: I know you don't but I think I'm sorry.
Speaker 1: episode six is the heist movie episode five is an American Western.
Speaker 0: Anyway, the point is every time I watch live-action American television of recent times and even actually older times too, right?
Speaker 0: There's sort of this feeling of like cheapness to it And I can't describe.
Speaker 0: that makes me not care.
Speaker 1: that is never sufficiently explain this to me.
Speaker 1: nor do I recognize this.
Speaker 0: I lack the English language to describe What is going on?
Speaker 0: But like, you know, if you watch a movie versus a TV show, there's like a clear difference in Something.
Speaker 1: you just you're just like the people and more who like to miss because the graphics you just want.
Speaker 0: Their movies old black and white movies that don't have this problem.
Speaker 0: But you ever all the shitty resolution.
Speaker 1: you have a problem with old black and white TV shows from that same era?
Speaker 0: I Don't know.
Speaker 0: I think you do.
Speaker 1: I think you do.
Speaker 0: it's just something about tell live-action television from the United States Especially recent of you United States television, right?
Speaker 0: Which I thought I started.
Speaker 0: I started getting this feeling around the time when like those HBO serials became like a big deal.
Speaker 0: I think you're just got like sopranos times.
Speaker 1: I think you're just old where it's like.
Speaker 1: I started watching those shows and people are all hype over them didn't wash like Oz.
Speaker 0: I did watched a few episodes and I was like I mean, you don't like Star Trek.
Speaker 0: You don't like mostly I never like Star Trek.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I know that's terrible.
Speaker 1: Yeah you not Star Trek.
Speaker 0: There are terrible Star Treks Like honestly if you're gonna know but the Star Trek that everyone loves with Picard next generation.
Speaker 0: now It has the same cheap feel that Mandalorian has.
Speaker 0: that makes me not want to watch it and I don't see that at all.
Speaker 1: But obviously the first two and a half seasons of TNG or garbage is don't watch him.
Speaker 0: Well, I don't know which ones I've watched.
Speaker 1: if you watch the phrase if there if there's this Beardless like shithead.
Speaker 1: Here's the first officer.
Speaker 1: It sucks.
Speaker 0: Once the guy definitely watch sums that had Borg in them.
Speaker 0: So, I don't know if that they were in the first season.
Speaker 1: There's some.
Speaker 1: There are not great board of Borg episodes and there are later great Borg episodes.
Speaker 0: The point is Mandalorian right started getting after the first two episodes which didn't really have it.
Speaker 0: Third fourth episode when I stopped watching started bringing in that feeling I get when I watch Live-action US television that I don't like and I just made me not want to watch anymore.
Speaker 1: I think you're just a weird curmudgeon because I don't see it.
Speaker 1: but there is a problem with the show that started in episode in the episode you didn't like and Then it doesn't happen for a while.
Speaker 1: But it does happen two more times in the show and what it is is circular dialogue.
Speaker 1: You know and the way I'll describe this, you know We're playing a burning wheel game and we us like two of us playing characters and like two NPCs Argue in a circle and Basically just keep saying the same things quick slightly.
Speaker 1: So over and over again But nothing gets resolved and eventually the game master is like listen fuckers and hence this dice and makes us roll to resolve it.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm the dialogue moves in a circle with characters basically just debating the same point repeatedly without moving anything forward multiple times before resolving it.
Speaker 1: and That happens in the episode that you didn't like where basically there's a bunch of characters talking And the camera basically goes from face to face to face to face.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, those are the words.
Speaker 0: Those are like the most those you seen.
Speaker 1: those can be great Except when they go to a face that basically just says the same fucking thing again And does not that dialogue serves no actual purpose Like it's almost like they're just padding out the scene.
Speaker 1: the game master meaning the director or the editor or someone should have just been like Yeah, let's just have the duel of wits guys.
Speaker 1: Come on.
Speaker 1: It also gives that in the last episode.
Speaker 1: There's like a really a second to last episode.
Speaker 1: last episode There's like a big like really important scene.
Speaker 1: It's egregious.
Speaker 1: there's a scene where the characters are debating whether or not to leave a certain character behind for plot reasons and they literally just Have the same conversation about this for like six minutes.
Speaker 1: Nothing gets revealed.
Speaker 1: No plot changes.
Speaker 1: No characters change nothing.
Speaker 1: It like an editor should have just cut that entire scene out and it would have showed a loss.
Speaker 1: nothing.
Speaker 1: and I think Circular dialogue is one thing.
Speaker 1: It's not the only thing.
Speaker 1: It's one thing that I think you bristle at even if you don't recognize it's happening.
Speaker 0: maybe The other thing is that really?
Speaker 0: That really like reminded me of like.
Speaker 0: I was getting flashbacks while I was watching the show.
Speaker 0: Yeah, isn't?
Speaker 0: I was a kid I actually liked.
Speaker 0: It was so.
Speaker 0: I liked him in the way that I like T man where once I learned better I realized like oh, why did I like that?
Speaker 0: That stuff is garbage, right?
Speaker 0: I liked a lot of these cheap adventure shows that were a thing for a while, right like young Indiana Jones?
Speaker 0: No, no, like that's a good.
Speaker 1: I remember that show being good.
Speaker 1: I have not seen even one second of footage from it in my adult life.
Speaker 0: I agree.
Speaker 1: Now shake that tree same cuz snakes are gonna buy out.
Speaker 0: the shows I'm talking about are the xena warrior princess princess.
Speaker 1: I never liked.
Speaker 0: you know, there was a Conan one Buffy.
Speaker 0: I didn't.
Speaker 0: I didn't watch Buffy.
Speaker 1: Buffy was not worth watching.
Speaker 0: But there was a Briscoe County jr I did not like.
Speaker 1: Briscoe County was always on when I was waiting to watch something else.
Speaker 0: It was 99 lives of blackjack savage.
Speaker 0: There was a. there's no one.
Speaker 1: that looked like a lot.
Speaker 0: It was a sin bad the sailor one.
Speaker 0: But basically these shows were on and like bad time slots.
Speaker 0: You could see the most often like weekend afternoons on Not the main broadcast channel, but like your local channel that was like it's showing syndicated shows.
Speaker 0: So like in New York, it would have been like 11 right or something like that Like your local like Connecticut channel as opposed to like actually NBC or some shit like that.
Speaker 0: And those shows right some of them, right?
Speaker 0: We're just sort of that episodic adventure with bad acting kind of thing Right, sort of like.
Speaker 0: those are basically a pure essence of the thing that I dislike right distilled and it's like 200 proof.
Speaker 1: Now I will say I get zero of those vibes from the Mandalorian except in that one circular scene I talked about.
Speaker 1: that was way too long.
Speaker 0: And you also see for example Briscoe County jr.
Speaker 0: And also blackjack savage as examples of I Don't know if you have much Briscoe County jr.
Speaker 0: Remember you said you didn't watch it.
Speaker 1: Well, I always saw like the last five minutes of it before the thing I wanted to.
Speaker 0: okay Okay But basically it was sort of X files II in the way that there was this main Secret from space plot that they'd barely address.
Speaker 0: that they barely address.
Speaker 0: So in Briscoe in X files It was always like what's up with the smoking man and that yeah, they find the ship.
Speaker 1: Ah, but that's that's the curse.
Speaker 1: I wanted to know about all that stuff for so long in the X files and then as soon as they showed it to me It was stupid and then I didn't care anymore exactly.
Speaker 0: but in Bristol County jr it was this ball this metal ball with like.
Speaker 0: that looked sort of like a I Don't know like you would take rods out of it.
Speaker 0: I guess they were trying to evoke a nuclear device of some kind.
Speaker 1: That's just the fucking plot of the venture brothers.
Speaker 0: Anyway, there's a ball.
Speaker 1: There's the orb.
Speaker 0: the orb Anyway, you can probably find pictures of it online And it would only show up occasionally and most episodes weren't about it.
Speaker 0: And when it was about it, it would sort of like oh dang it got away again.
Speaker 1: Okay, that orb looks way different from what I expected.
Speaker 0: yes, that's the thing that's like the main plot orb.
Speaker 0: That's the main plot of the show.
Speaker 0: Is that McGuffin?
Speaker 1: Did they ever explain what it is?
Speaker 0: I don't remember gonna find out what in the 90s Anyway, but in that same way the Mandalorian has this core plot of.
Speaker 0: what's the deal with the Mandalorians?
Speaker 0: what's deal with this baby, right and When?
Speaker 0: that you know?
Speaker 0: starting episode 3 and 4.
Speaker 1: never fucking explain it in at any point.
Speaker 0: No, the show got canceled.
Speaker 1: before then, uh, the orb gets destroyed Sure, and there are three orbs.
Speaker 0: Okay one gets destroyed.
Speaker 1: The other two are taken back to the future by someone.
Speaker 0: Okay, sure I guess there's time travel, you know, they make that terrible secret of space thin right while these other things happen, right?
Speaker 0: According to rim they unfin it, but I didn't see that far because I got bored and had better things to do.
Speaker 1: Yeah I did not see any thinning in the Mandalorian because it sort of gets thicker as it goes on As soon as this motherfucker shows up.
Speaker 0: I did not see that motherfucker that guy.
Speaker 1: so Werner Herzog is pretty fun.
Speaker 1: Like the role he plays this guy Is his boss?
Speaker 1: Okay, and he basically show rolls into town like in the second half of the show and he's like the fuck is going on.
Speaker 1: Did you fuck this up?
Speaker 1: Seriously?
Speaker 1: Fuck you.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: He's great.
Speaker 1: It's Moff Gideon.
Speaker 1: He's a moth.
Speaker 0: Oh It's a Star Wars.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it was some fanservice but Moff Gideon is I think my.
Speaker 0: that's only fanservice to nerds like us.
Speaker 0: You know what?
Speaker 0: I'm office.
Speaker 1: Yep He's an Imperial remnant commander and he is my favorite character in the Mandalorian.
Speaker 1: He doesn't even show up till episode 7.
Speaker 1: He literally just shows up.
Speaker 1: He comes down and he's like, what the fuck?
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know what?
Speaker 1: He's got with him.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: He's got some stormtroopers wearing black Fancy and they're actually good shots.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they either.
Speaker 0: those are the ones it's like a red guy.
Speaker 0: that's our gun.
Speaker 1: when we were kids both Was the coolest character in Star Wars knows the kid number two Episode when I saw those red stormtroopers.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah The way most people feel about Boba Fett is the way I felt about red storm as soon as I sold it.
Speaker 1: I remember I was like my uncle was the nerdiest person in my family and I was like what's up with those red stormtroopers?
Speaker 0: No one knows.
Speaker 1: he didn't know so he made up a bunch of shit.
Speaker 1: Okay, and it took me Way to go.
Speaker 1: uncle he's awesome uncle.
Speaker 0: That's the difference between a boomer uncle and a millennial uncle.
Speaker 0: boomer uncle will make up a bunch of bullshit.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right.
Speaker 0: Whereas a millennial uncle will actually tell you the truth because they googled a fuck ton about it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and they'll go on and on and on telling you everything there is to know about those red guys for real.
Speaker 1: I wanted to know the deal with those red guys so bad as a kid.
Speaker 1: Yep, but Yeah, that the month showing up is pretty great and it's only four more episodes.
Speaker 1: He shows up in episode seven if you want to see what his deal is.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but there's already gonna be a season two.
Speaker 1: I think we're season one ended without spoiling.
Speaker 1: It is gonna set up a pretty good season two.
Speaker 0: I wish they would make a Star Wars show.
Speaker 0: It's about space pilot and not about you know.
Speaker 1: Well, you know what?
Speaker 1: I'd like to see.
Speaker 0: I'd like to see as part of.
Speaker 0: it does feel like the people who are making this are sort of just like Sort of like just sort of like.
Speaker 0: it's there.
Speaker 0: it's like there.
Speaker 0: what's the word for it?
Speaker 0: Like their pet project like.
Speaker 0: no, we really want to make, you know an homage to Kurosawa.
Speaker 0: All right, let's just do it.
Speaker 0: Let's have like.
Speaker 0: they're having the fun making what they want to make as filmmakers.
Speaker 0: So find someone who really wants to make regardless of what Scott wants to see.
Speaker 1: so, you know what I want to see.
Speaker 1: now I'd like to see in with the same level of care that Mandalorian is getting.
Speaker 1: I want to see one a show That's about like one fucking TIE fighter pilot.
Speaker 1: I'd like to see one that is Our boy out in the Outer Rim.
Speaker 1: Okay, Vice Admiral Thrawn.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you're not gonna see that.
Speaker 1: I know someday.
Speaker 1: I think it'll happen.
Speaker 1: I'd like to see a Thrawn.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't know what else I really want to see.
Speaker 1: hmm What do you want?
Speaker 1: What do you want?
Speaker 1: That would be Mandalorian adjacent?
Speaker 1: Like the most fan service things Star Wars could give you personally me personally.
Speaker 1: Yeah Like if you got to direct what the what the pet project would have been for the people who ended up making the Mandalorian Vixen wedge like their whole lives.
Speaker 0: No, I would do.
Speaker 0: It would still be space battles because you gotta have space battle.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right, but we'd be focusing on.
Speaker 0: you know What's going on on one ship the way not in the way Star Trek though?
Speaker 0: Like Gundam seed made the way Gundam does but the main character right would not be a lame.
Speaker 0: Oh, you know blank Gundam character, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, like one of the Battlestar Galactica pilots.
Speaker 0: No, no, no the really the main character has to be one of those droids that has too much character That would normally be.
Speaker 0: is that would normally be a side character Killed quickly.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right like the one in.
Speaker 0: well the one in Mandalorian or the one in What's it called?
Speaker 1: All I'm gonna say is that droid comes back.
Speaker 0: I'm sure it does.
Speaker 1: also that droid the one you're talking about gives me mad return to Oz creepy voice.
Speaker 0: What's the Rogue?
Speaker 0: rogue, whatever the droid in that one also a cool.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, that guy like that droid a lot.
Speaker 0: Yeah, just take me a cool droid like that.
Speaker 0: That's the main character.
Speaker 0: make a Gundam setup where you're focusing on one ship.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like one Mon Calamari cruiser, right?
Speaker 0: Exactly right with a bunch of fighters right that I'll see the equivalent of the Gundams rise.
Speaker 0: You have this whole cast.
Speaker 0: that's on the one ship.
Speaker 0: It's like a Gundam not like a Star Trek Yeah, and but the main character has to be an awesome Hilarious character with a lot.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I like it and a droid and not some lame.
Speaker 1: Oh Well, you need three parts.
Speaker 1: You need the the ensemble cast of people to do the cuts to the faces when there's a space battle, correct?
Speaker 1: You need the character you described.
Speaker 1: is the real main character to like pull everything together?
Speaker 0: You need the evil Empire character in a mask.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: And then you need the Probably a Jedi.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, everyone need these new types are Jedi's obviously, of course.
Speaker 1: But then in the background of the ship you need the irresponsible captain Tyler.
Speaker 1: You're under arrest slash pat labore cast of idiots and side characters.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, we're just always in the background capering and fucking things up and getting drunk and causing trouble Yep, and then they need to be on a journey a slow journey from point a to point B Like they are in a Gundam or macross or whatever.
Speaker 0: We're like, okay We're leaving this planet and we have you know, the problem is they have warp drive and in Star Wars that fucks that all up.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the other thing you could do in Star Wars that would totally work.
Speaker 0: But actually I don't want it.
Speaker 0: cuz like I don't I don't need more of it is to do a Galaxy Express.
Speaker 0: There's some sort of.
Speaker 0: you're focusing on like, you know Couple mysterious people making a long journey and they basically go in hyperspace and then land on Star Wars planets and have moral Quandary.
Speaker 1: Right on Tatooine right when it's about to have it's like workers.
Speaker 0: They land on somewhere where the moral quandary and at the end of the episode they get back onto the space.
Speaker 0: So here's the question and it warps them to the next place.
Speaker 1: Are these two characters starting in the part of Star Wars?
Speaker 1: We know and going out to the Outer Rim?
Speaker 0: So it doesn't even matter just give more moral quandary.
Speaker 1: Are they out in the Outer Rim trying to come in to like meet Yoda not knowing that Yoda's dead?
Speaker 1: Everything's been destroyed?
Speaker 1: doesn't matter spoilers Yoda dies guys.
Speaker 1: Oh, no Yeah, also spoilers.
Speaker 1: We haven't seen the Mandalorian.
Speaker 1: That's not literally Yoda It's just the race that Yoda is.
Speaker 1: yeah, like obviously because it takes place after Episode six.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but what the other thing I really like about it and it comes out a lot more in the second half the show is You didn't see much of it yet.
Speaker 1: The baby is really powerful obvious.
Speaker 1: I saw that it's obvious and really dangerous and Not necessarily actually good like it might not know.
Speaker 0: it was just born.
Speaker 0: What does it know?
Speaker 1: Yeah, but it might not be okay for this baby to go where it's supposed to go in the end.
Speaker 0: Well, you can't?
Speaker 0: you don't know anything right?
Speaker 0: You know, you'll.
Speaker 1: Season one tells you a lot more.
Speaker 0: You don't know any.
Speaker 0: we don't know anything about Yoda's race.
Speaker 0: We don't know anything about right.
Speaker 0: We just know all right.
Speaker 0: It's a baby of Yoda's race Yeah, and it has mad strong with the force and does it even have parents?
Speaker 0: What does it think?
Speaker 0: What is it right?
Speaker 0: Does it candidate?
Speaker 0: it must have ideas is like I don't you know.
Speaker 0: The end of season one actually kind of explains what you can't really communicate in a way that the audience can understand.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think the baby of a real interesting in season two.
Speaker 1: Mmm, and I will watch season two when it comes out.
Speaker 0: I like you know if they follow the lone wolf and cub trend.
Speaker 0: right you think lone wolf and cub is this dude?
Speaker 0: I've read most of it.
Speaker 0: Yeah It's just episodic samurai stories, right?
Speaker 0: But it's like yeah, the kid is actually isn't just like this.
Speaker 0: You know baby in a carriage that he has to protect and keep it from getting killed like the kid You know at points fucking cuts people Oh kid goes out and does things even though it doesn't really talk a lot.
Speaker 0: Right, like the kid is actually like, you know a real deal that happens more and more in the second.
Speaker 0: It's like imagine imagine like a bear cub.
Speaker 0: that's like, you know, not just born but like been around a little bit But it's still a cub like, you know, I can hear that.
Speaker 0: is she gonna fuck you up?
Speaker 0: It's not a bear.
Speaker 0: it won't like maul you but it you don't want to go near it Right, and that's basically what the deal is, but I mean in the end like I really like Mandalorian I will watch season two as soon as it comes out.
Speaker 0: Mmm, and Yeah, it's a pretty good show.
Speaker 1: I do I enjoyed it more viscerally than I enjoyed the newer Star Wars movies But I don't think that I'm saying I did not like the new Star Wars movies.
Speaker 1: I think it's mostly that the Mandalorian is set closer to like the aesthetic of the first trilogy, which I like the most.
Speaker 1: I
Speaker 0: think the new movies at their best moments I liked a zillion times more than Mandalorian, but at their man moments, I'd liked less than Yeah,
Speaker 1: I can I can feel that like for that one of the movies like that casino thing was just real bad And that you should not been in the movie.
Speaker 1: and I would like that movie a lot more.
Speaker 0: Mmm part even in the casino part which was mostly man.
Speaker 1: It had it had a few moments.
Speaker 0: a few moments of the casino thing were not me Yeah, but 90% of the casino part was met.
Speaker 1: Yep, but there were some not met moments.
Speaker 0: I will give you that Yeah, Mandalorian better than casino not as good as space battle where they crash one ship in another ship.
Speaker 1: Yeah Yeah, but you know what?
Speaker 1: That's like.
Speaker 1: it's like, you know, we're doing a podcast.
Speaker 1: the audio.
Speaker 1: It's the difference between the root mean square volume and the peak volume.
Speaker 1: Yep, the new movies have really good peaks, but also a lot of really like low volume sections.
Speaker 1: Mmm episode 4 just has like a steady RMS from start to end.
Speaker 1: Yep This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at front row crew comm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 1: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night and the patreon patrons for this episode of geek nights are This new patron manager makes it hard for me to say these names So I got to keep fussing with it Alan Joyce, honey McNichol and Marty green.
Speaker 1: yeah, just like a dude guy chart obvious and linky G you hold the key to my heart.
Speaker 1: I got one little fight and my mom got scared.
Speaker 1: Clinton Walton J Bants run for New Zealand Ryan parent rope and Lander Nicholas Brando Chris midkiff Mac the thirst for hydrated Ganon dread Lily Tenebrae Chris Reimer Finn Sean Klein Thomas Han Shervin van Harl and a whole bunch of other people who don't want me to say their name.
Speaker 1: and now We are continuing our own interrupted geek nights and there won't be any cons to stop us anytime in the foreseeable future.
Speaker 1: I leave you with Something I can't believe.
Speaker 1: this is the first time we're hanging out.
Speaker 1: I mean, we know all the same people and we have so much in common.
Speaker 1: Do you mind if I take my shoes off?
Speaker 0: No, I mean this is a restaurant.
Speaker 1: So Okay, great.
Speaker 1: Uh, so What are you having?
Speaker 1: not for me?
Speaker 1: Thanks food is how they get you at these places.
Speaker 1: I brought my own meal.
Speaker 1: Um, what is that?
Speaker 1: Oh just some loose cream and napkin squeezings and ketchup water.
Speaker 1: I'm treating myself today So Wario never talks about you.
Speaker 1: I kind of see why he's just jealous of my girlfriend.
Speaker 1: That's half a toaster.
Speaker 1: Isn't she beautiful?
Speaker 0: Um, I should really be go.
Speaker 0: Oh god.
Speaker 0: What are you doing?
Speaker 0: Oh, excuse me.
Speaker 0: Did you want some?
Speaker 0: you know what?
Speaker 1: I just just remember I need to be Anywhere else?
Speaker 1: Oh, no, no, no get down get down what?
Speaker 1: Why my nemesis followed us here.
Speaker 1: Oh, he's such a weirdo.
Speaker 0: I thought I was your nemesis.
Speaker 0: I wish oh Hey, why Waluigi?