Speaker 1: It's Monday April 27th 2020.
Speaker 1: I'm rim.
Speaker 1: I'm Scott and this is geek nights.
Speaker 1: tonight We're talking about our TMP streaming and how we have set it up to record geek nights from home.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: So, uh Normally at the beginning of the show we have our little opening bit where we talk about stuff.
Speaker 1: There was we were doing which usually in the summer boils down to so I was biking somewhere and X happened or so I biked somewhere and Y happened, but we're not going anywhere doing anything.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but staying at home doing nothing I did.
Speaker 1: it was really nice on Saturday.
Speaker 1: So we biked down to Prospect Park and did a bunch of loops and came back.
Speaker 0: Mmm, there's a lot of people I see in the New York Internet communities and the common post people seem to be making is Hey, look at all these too many people outside, what are they doing?
Speaker 0: They got to go back inside and it's every single time the photo they post of too many people includes them.
Speaker 0: It's like everyone goes outside and takes a picture and says what are all these other people doing outside?
Speaker 0: I need to be out here.
Speaker 1: So biking some doing it, right?
Speaker 0: I've allowed to be out here.
Speaker 1: I think I realized what's going on.
Speaker 1: the problem even though there's no good solution to this is pedestrians.
Speaker 1: Because basically what's happening now that I've biked around in the city a whole bunch during this thing?
Speaker 1: The cyclists seem to be fine because they keep their distance.
Speaker 1: they're moving fast Like you're not next to anyone for more than like a half a second But the pedestrians.
Speaker 1: there's way more people out like if you go to any park anywhere any like walking path anything Especially along the rivers.
Speaker 1: There's more people that are normally out at this time of year like everybody's outside.
Speaker 1: I think they're getting stir-crazy, but they're all just walking and it's people who don't normally walk like they're not out there Normally like it's not that crowded.
Speaker 1: But now that everybody's going out to walk to get outside There's giant blobs of pedestrians everywhere making on crowded and dangerous situations.
Speaker 0: Well, a lot of other cities made the right move of basically closing roads or as we like to call it opening roads To people in the war on cars community.
Speaker 0: Yes Open the streets, right?
Speaker 0: You know, it's like Oakland is actually crazy.
Speaker 0: open the streets, you know, cuz it's like hey, there's not too many cars And people don't need to be driving.
Speaker 0: let's if we open the streets there's more room for people to walk so They could go not be near each other right and New York be mostly because of the mayor.
Speaker 0: You know, the City Council is like open the streets.
Speaker 0: I'm a kid, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, just open.
Speaker 0: Oh, they just the mayor of New York and the college like.
Speaker 1: there's an easy solution.
Speaker 0: Yeah, mostly the the mayor and the police have been hesitant to open the streets to give people more room.
Speaker 1: Well, cuz I might set a bad precedent.
Speaker 1: people might realize they like the streets being closed.
Speaker 0: Well, they do like the streets being open, but they're they're gonna you know, yeah today they announced they're gonna do something.
Speaker 1: But I know.
Speaker 1: but this is what actually happens I noticed.
Speaker 1: so if I go out of these parks I have to avoid like all the nice places to go because there's a million people clogging everything up.
Speaker 1: but because of that all the people who are running are Running in the bike paths and the bike lanes to get away from all the slow Pedestrians that are making it unsafe for them because if they just run they're also safe because they're not really next to anyone.
Speaker 0: Yeah, people are trying to dodge people more.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right, so they spread out and block the bike lanes.
Speaker 1: So the bikers now are stuck behind all the people see.
Speaker 0: normally I would just if I you know And I'm gonna when it gets warm.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna bike.
Speaker 0: I'll just bike away from the city to where it's not crowded.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right out in the middle of nowhere.
Speaker 0: The problem is if I buy too far I got to like take a train home and I want to do that And also little things like.
Speaker 1: I got to carry all the equipment I could possibly need.
Speaker 1: I got to carry all the food I could Need.
Speaker 1: I can't just do my old go-to of just stop at a restaurant.
Speaker 1: I need food.
Speaker 0: you can't stop at a restaurant But you could.
Speaker 0: there are places you can still stop like you know.
Speaker 0: yeah Depending on where you are Especially if you have someone with you right cuz you know wouldn't bike super close to the first in your with right But you could you know be like all right.
Speaker 0: you stand here with the bikes.
Speaker 0: I'll go in the grocery Yep, I'll get food.
Speaker 0: We'll sit here on these benches eat the food.
Speaker 1: yep I'm vaguely planning.
Speaker 1: some sit six feet apart and picnic and in like flushing or something later.
Speaker 0: I just can't.
Speaker 0: you just can't do like a group bike ride where you're like lined up right on top each other like you know Normally do.
Speaker 1: but something else happened That was sort of annoying.
Speaker 1: well other than the blobs of people because the blobs of people is annoying as they are.
Speaker 1: They're easy to avoid if you just don't go to the places that are very obviously going to be popular to those people like If you come in one street from the river ghost town.
Speaker 0: I just remember all kinds of things like you know smorgasburg.
Speaker 0: It's like rip.
Speaker 1: Oh my god.
Speaker 1: The Kent Avenue bike path is like jam-packed With slow people wobbling around to the point that I can't go over there like go take Bedford or something instead.
Speaker 1: Anyway, but so the thing I noticed is there's a lot of people biking who have clearly never biked before which on one hand is Good.
Speaker 1: it is people who are stir crazy, and they're going outside.
Speaker 1: They're getting on a city bike.
Speaker 1: But I witnessed like three different almost catastrophic accidents because there's a lot of people biking now Who have no idea how to bike?
Speaker 1: Yeah, like way more than normal.
Speaker 0: I mean people try to do things They don't know how to do all the time, and that's good.
Speaker 0: It's how you learn how to do things.
Speaker 1: But they're doing.
Speaker 1: it can be bad on a crowded street Almost having head-on collisions with other people who are also doing it on a public street.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm yep, that's that's how I do.
Speaker 1: yep, but there are way more of them than because usually this time of year There's like a few people are doing it, but I think it's just.
Speaker 1: people are getting stir-crazy They're going outside They're trying things they've never tried before.
Speaker 1: my only advice to you if you live in New York And you were listening to this and you've never biked before Get on a city bike and practice like on an empty street before you go to the really crowded bike path like.
Speaker 1: that's all I ask Mean.
Speaker 0: you know it's just the same thing we always talk about.
Speaker 0: is this people who you know actually You know do things and care about doing them well and want to learn right and try hard and pay attention Right.
Speaker 0: and then there's people who don't care.
Speaker 0: They're just like I'm riding a bike.
Speaker 0: well You know you can go faster if you learn how to use the gears.
Speaker 0: I don't want to learn anything right.
Speaker 1: They're wobbling around.
Speaker 0: they don't think it's a problem.
Speaker 0: They don't care about improving right.
Speaker 0: they've done all they want to do.
Speaker 0: Those are the two attitudes all right, and you know that attitude is the bad attitude.
Speaker 1: Yep And that is that is actually a big part of where geek nights came from and why we do the show is us being
Speaker 0: and every Everything I do even if it's not something I care too much about I'm always looking to do it better learn more about it Right try to improve efficiency quality Skill everything.
Speaker 1: how's that hadoken coming?
Speaker 0: I?
Speaker 0: mean I learned.
Speaker 0: So.
Speaker 1: Anyway So one news Scott's done more research on this than I have.
Speaker 1: I wasn't aware That this was a thing until recently because I just I haven't been paying attention to tech news And it's rare.
Speaker 1: there is tech news that actually matters to any pipeline.
Speaker 1: I own.
Speaker 0: So the deal is this is technology that's been around for a long time Yeah called SMR shingled magnetic recording.
Speaker 0: that happens inside of old-school.
Speaker 0: I mean They're not.
Speaker 0: it's weird that you call them old-school because everyone uses SSDs for everything nowadays.
Speaker 0: Yeah, magnetic drives still have a place because SSD capacity is not that big.
Speaker 1: yeah There's a reason why I have to one terabyte SSDs And then I also have to five terabyte magnetic disks.
Speaker 0: and Mike right so the magnetic disks have a technology in them So that they can have a technology them called SMR shingled magnetic recording.
Speaker 0: And it's called shingled because basically what happens is a lot like the shingles on the roof of a house Structurally right.
Speaker 0: so the read the the inside of the hard drive.
Speaker 0: You know you're spinning the platters And you have these heads that move back and forth and read and write The.
Speaker 0: just because of the way things are the physical size of the head that only does reading can be made Physically very small so you can read from a very tiny area.
Speaker 0: right.
Speaker 0: the head that does writing Has to be larger just because it has more parts or it's bigger.
Speaker 0: I don't understand why it just has to be right.
Speaker 0: So the result is that you could actually write.
Speaker 0: Let's say you write a one with with the right head, right?
Speaker 0: You've actually.
Speaker 0: what you've done is you've actually written two ones on top of each other Right and the read head could read from like only part of that area right.
Speaker 0: so if you're a clever and you wrote the you took the right head and you wrote down two ones at once and Then even though the right head is big you could just move it Less than its size.
Speaker 0: the motor that moves it is just as precise as the motor that moves the read head.
Speaker 1: This is the kind of crap that like old PC games would put copy protection on discs by writing stuff in a weird way to a floppy Right.
Speaker 0: so you could move the right head halfway up and then write a zero.
Speaker 0: so now in that spot where they used to be Two ones on top of each other is now a zero and then a one under it like shingles right.
Speaker 0: so you move the right Head up you know half ways each time and you can actually get increased.
Speaker 0: You know not it's not as precise as that.
Speaker 0: you couldn't get you know double your density But you.
Speaker 0: but you can get a large increase in storage capacity by using this technology.
Speaker 0: And it happens completely internal to the drive.
Speaker 0: so your computer Doesn't necessarily know about it or know or have to care about it that much.
Speaker 0: the hard drive Just does it.
Speaker 0: it reports that it has larger capacity.
Speaker 0: it uses caching You know technologies so that even though Writing is taking a longer amount of time to write your computer might not notice if you're not trying to write or read too much Because of caches and various things going on.
Speaker 0: and it kind of works.
Speaker 0: Now the obvious the problem.
Speaker 1: like we're not saying this technology is bad.
Speaker 1: the problem is that a Lot of hard drives are using this and not telling you and the way hard drive statistics tend to be reported Could easily hide Potentially catastrophic performance problems from you.
Speaker 0: well it doesn't hide it actually.
Speaker 0: it just you you your hard drive just doesn't work right.
Speaker 0: so what?
Speaker 0: What happens is back in the day?
Speaker 0: You know when they first introduced this technology you would go to buy hard drives and the hard drives had different labels on them like different branding In term.
Speaker 0: so they would be like Western Digital red black whatever and they were supposed to indicate different tiers of performance.
Speaker 0: And there would be like NAS hard drives and the.
Speaker 0: the SMR was used in what were usually labeled as like Archival drives.
Speaker 0: right like.
Speaker 0: buy these cheap large drives.
Speaker 0: They're for archival.
Speaker 0: they're not for like high read/write applications.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they're like real.
Speaker 0: the drive up read a lot.
Speaker 1: Maybe but you're not writing right.
Speaker 1: They're not suddenly.
Speaker 0: They're not unreliable.
Speaker 0: They're Danny right It's just you use this to fill up a data and then not access it too often.
Speaker 0: right and you could save money that way.
Speaker 0: And that's how they were marketed, but more recently they've been putting this technology into drives with different branding Like Western some Western Digital Reds even one model of Western Digital black has it Which is supposed to be like one of the higher performance models.
Speaker 1: actually I have to go check What because I have two blacks in my current computer that I bought a long time ago.
Speaker 1: I got a check.
Speaker 0: they might be SMRs right, but the point is is that you might know their SMR.
Speaker 0: because Number one some people are reporting like people are weirdos using ZFS.
Speaker 0: Yeah Are like hey my ZFS keeps kicking this drive out because it's it's timing out.
Speaker 0: unlike rights It kicks it out of the cluster all right.
Speaker 0: Other people are like they have drives in their NAS crash And then they replace them and the NAS refuses to use the SMR drive as a replacement.
Speaker 0: It's like no that one's.
Speaker 0: it's that drive is bad.
Speaker 0: I'm not yeah, I'm not repair I'm not repairing.
Speaker 1: on to that like I tried to write to it And it wasn't as performant as I expected.
Speaker 1: something's wrong with it right right.
Speaker 0: It's like the.
Speaker 0: because so You might not you know there are ways to tell like maybe a few ways to tell if the drive is SMR.
Speaker 0: But you know now basically because this is like a fiasco all the hard drive manufacturers I've sort of spill.
Speaker 0: I've you know come clean and be like okay these drives have them.
Speaker 0: these drives Don't?
Speaker 0: right?
Speaker 1: yeah, but the reason I'm mad about it like the real problem Is that the hard drive companies were really like.
Speaker 1: they knew that if they talked about this technology people would avoid those drives.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, right, so they say yeah The only people who are buying individual magnetic drives are people who know what they're buying.
Speaker 0: yep So look at nobody's buying individual magnetic hard drives in 2020. who isn't a nerd who knows about all the things on the label?
Speaker 1: Yep, so I don't have any customers issue these statements like all.
Speaker 1: right.
Speaker 1: Here's some of the drives where we might be using this technology.
Speaker 0: right.
Speaker 0: Seagate statement was like these NAS drives these Fox Pro whatever's iron something's.
Speaker 0: yeah these ones Definitely never have SMR.
Speaker 0: They are the ones that aren't.
Speaker 0: those might put these ones never have it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like you know because it's like.
Speaker 0: it's not a bad technology.
Speaker 0: It's just it crushes your performance.
Speaker 0: So if you're buying drives And you need lots of reading or writing like in your NAS that you're using a lot for example as opposed to your NAS That's asleep all day Then you need to know Right if using ZFS you need to know if you're.
Speaker 0: if you're NAS isn't going to accept the drive as a replacement.
Speaker 0: You need to know and not buy the wrong drive, so it's fine to have it out there.
Speaker 1: It's like okay product except this article the first article will link to.
Speaker 1: it actually points out something.
Speaker 1: this Technology does not actually let the manufacturers put more capacity in the drive so much as they're selling The same capacities.
Speaker 1: They're just.
Speaker 1: it may cost them less money to make them.
Speaker 1: They're saving themselves money, but they're not passing that on to us right?
Speaker 0: I thought that was interesting.
Speaker 0: is that you know one that they listed like oh, yeah The drives that are like big like the 10 terabyte one like that one's you know like normal CMR Which is like you know classical magnetic recording right?
Speaker 0: They're like yeah the two terabyte one the cheapo model.
Speaker 0: that one has SMR And I'm like wait a minute.
Speaker 0: wouldn't the 10 terabyte one have like You know six terabytes worth of platters, and then use SMR to get up to ten?
Speaker 0: It's like no no one's gonna because someone who buys a 10 terabyte drive is gonna pay the money.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so they went after the cheapo like the people are buying these one to four terabyte.
Speaker 0: You want to make that four terabyte the two terabyte four terabyte drive cheaper by using one or two three?
Speaker 0: Terabytes of platters.
Speaker 0: take a platter out right increase the capacity drop the price and compete on that low end.
Speaker 0: on the high end Right people are gonna a notice.
Speaker 0: be care more.
Speaker 0: see that performance problem will be Exacerbated when you have so much space on there right you know.
Speaker 0: even because like you think someone's buying a 10 terabyte drive Right the first thing that you know gonna.
Speaker 0: Do is try to fill it up with 10 terabytes of data.
Speaker 0: Yep, that's gonna.
Speaker 0: Take a long fucking ass time if it's got the shingle Emma, right?
Speaker 0: So they would notice it immediately.
Speaker 1: yeah, so this is like.
Speaker 1: This is a scandal like.
Speaker 1: this is not just like.
Speaker 1: oh Here's the technology people didn't understand.
Speaker 1: like.
Speaker 0: I consider this scandal among people who still care about magnetic drives.
Speaker 0: I imagine most listeners out there You know who aren't doing some sort of videos big storage application only have SSDs these days and don't give a crap though.
Speaker 1: I still run into a lot of people who only have spinning disks.
Speaker 0: That's strange.
Speaker 0: if you only have spinning disks you can at least buy.
Speaker 0: if not if you don't have any m2 slots in your computer Yeah, you can buy like I see.
Speaker 0: yeah a two and a half inch s ATA SSD And that those are way cheap these days because people like sort of don't care too much about those anymore.
Speaker 1: Yep You can get like a terabyte for not that much money.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you can get those way cheap these days especially the slower models and those will still be like lightning fast change like change your life.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like better than any other upgrade you can do to your PC is putting with putting your operating system And your most used applications onto an SSD instead of a magnetic.
Speaker 1: I think the people most likely to be burned by this.
Speaker 1: I think There's two very specific classes of people.
Speaker 1: class number one people who buy a low-end NAS like a to drive NAS Because they're smart and they like they're upgrading their game, but that's like they buy this NAS They just look for like what are some cheap for terabyte hard drives to stick in this thing?
Speaker 1: BAM SMR the NAS works like shit.
Speaker 1: They'll never know why right?
Speaker 0: I think the people who get burned are the people who are say who have lots of storage needs like Photo-video experts who aren't also computer experts, right?
Speaker 0: Like there's a lot of people who are like camera people and they have NASA's right, but they don't know too much about computer.
Speaker 1: They mostly just like well, those are the kind of people who are buying like drobos instead of buying like a real NAS.
Speaker 1: That's way better.
Speaker 0: exactly exactly that kind of person right who's got like a Mac and a drobo connected to it or something.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that person might got like 10 drives in there of 10 different sizes and you just try it in this hard drive work.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so my advice to you is if you understand what we just talked about make your own decisions.
Speaker 1: like SMR It probably has a use.
Speaker 0: just if next time you buy magnetic disks do some research to see if they have it or not and if you need it think About your application and whether it's gonna hurt you or not.
Speaker 0: And if you have any existing magnetic disks, just look up the model to make sure whether it has SMR or not.
Speaker 0: And you know, it's like I could look up.
Speaker 0: the only magnetic disks I really use like the ones in my NAS are the most recently purchased ones like they're working.
Speaker 0: So it's like.
Speaker 0: I guess if they have it, it's not a big deal.
Speaker 1: Yep I guess I just can't put my hands down when I'm not like when no one's accessing it Exactly, but I think the real thing is if you don't understand any of what we talked about Just never get an SMR drive unless it is dirt cheap.
Speaker 0: because and if you don't understand we talked about what you don't buy magnetic disks You probably don't need yeah But like it's 2020 the SMR drive versus the non SMR drive The price difference is not enough to even like like.
Speaker 1: that is not a compromise that is worth doing.
Speaker 1: you Just get a worse drive and you don't save a material amount of money.
Speaker 0: The hard drive manufacturer says yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah Boss saves money.
Speaker 0: You don't save money All right, so, uh, I just want to talk briefly geek bite about the new.
Speaker 0: What is the actual name of this product that iPad magic keyboard or something?
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, you got that thing.
Speaker 1: I haven't seen it.
Speaker 0: It's called magic keyboard for iPad Pro, right?
Speaker 0: So in the most recent iOS more recent iOS updates They they improved the support for pointing devices like mice and touch pads, right?
Speaker 0: So presumably you could use like a Bluetooth mouse or something, right?
Speaker 0: So when I got the iPad Pro Originally, you know, I wanted to get a hundred bucks.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah I could buy a laptop for 300 bucks and get change.
Speaker 0: You sure could.
Speaker 0: So The mat.
Speaker 0: so when I bought the iPad Pro the second because I had the original iPad Pro and then I switched to the newer one after that and The I bought a the original one that I had I had like a separate Bluetooth keyboard that I got.
Speaker 0: that was all cheap.
Speaker 0: Oh that I would put next to it.
Speaker 0: But that didn't work out too.
Speaker 0: Well, because it was really annoying to carry around a Bluetooth keyboard everywhere And like you wouldn't use it when it was a separate thing too often.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right That's why I still have a super thin traditional laptop that just rolls open and has a keyboard.
Speaker 0: So when I got the next iPad Pro, I bought the the keyboard that Apple made that goes with it the smart keyboard folio I think they call it which was actually okay.
Speaker 0: Like it wasn't great.
Speaker 0: It was like this, you know, the keyboard was kind of like these flat Mac keys, right?
Speaker 0: But it it worked and it was also a cover for the iPad and you could fold it back And hold your iPad like a normal iPad and you know, it was cool.
Speaker 0: the problem with it is that it was Fragile and it broke and I found a thread of people on the Apple support who had it break in the exact same way And basically when I connect it it says yeah unsupported accessory like it's an Apple made
Speaker 1: product
Speaker 0: And it broke after Apple care expired right so I couldn't do anything about it.
Speaker 0: So it became just like it became a keyboard a cover with a keyboard that occasionally worked.
Speaker 0: So There are these third-party keyboards you can get.
Speaker 0: that are also cases like Logitech make some and whatnot.
Speaker 0: But I've tried those in stores and like.
Speaker 0: they're like kind of meh, right?
Speaker 0: They're cheaper, but they're meh, right?
Speaker 0: They're like big and chunky and I kind of defeat the purpose like you might as you're right if you're getting one of those You might as well buy a laptop because even though they're cheaper They're not my laptop.
Speaker 1: My actual laptop is thinner than your iPad Pro plus this keyboard.
Speaker 0: I don't know about that.
Speaker 0: They're real.
Speaker 0: laptop is almost definitely slower than the iPad.
Speaker 0: the iPad is People don't realize because it's hard to directly.
Speaker 0: It's hard to directly compare.
Speaker 0: I think people are sleeping on this including Apple I think is sleeping on this.
Speaker 0: is that the CPUs that Apple is making the arm ones for the iOS devices are Insanely powerful.
Speaker 0: people don't realize it Like be an iPhone 7 or like, you know iPhone 8 is like faster than almost every Android phone, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, they're already on like iPhone 11 right with even newer CPUs Right.
Speaker 0: and the iPad Pro is like I think it might be like as fast as like super high-end Microsoft Surface Pro if not faster, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, they're just like ridiculous I saw of similar size has a pretty fast i7 in it Yeah, but has fans and it blows right.
Speaker 1: now if you it did Even if you push a fan that has only ever made noise once and the time it made noise was when as a test I Turned I tried to play overwatch on the laptop with all the settings turned up.
Speaker 0: point is iPad pros really strong?
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, you're paying up your.
Speaker 1: it's a real computer just without a real operating system, right?
Speaker 0: The price of the iPad Pro actually can you know considering what it does is actually sort of not as overpriced as other Apple products Like this keyboard which is ridiculously overpriced my laptop.
Speaker 1: I keep talking about cost over $2,000 like right.
Speaker 1: It's not like.
Speaker 1: yeah.
Speaker 0: So the keyboard is ridiculously overpriced.
Speaker 0: don't get it unless you have like money to set on fire.
Speaker 0: because Wow, is it overpriced?
Speaker 1: Yeah, three hundred dollars.
Speaker 0: You've spent on a keyboard for a tablet right exactly, but It's pretty nice like the actual like in terms of like a keyboard with the flat chiclet keys.
Speaker 0: It might be like the best keyboard of not mechanical keys That have had.
Speaker 0: it just doesn't have any F keys, but I guess in an iPad you don't need those.
Speaker 1: Oh, I also would need those on a laptop because I use F keys a lot.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Well, I pet iOS doesn't really need them.
Speaker 0: Yeah, what does it do on iOS?
Speaker 0: Yeah I guess if it's a Mac you need them, right?
Speaker 0: But iOS doesn't need F keys.
Speaker 0: also the trackpad the mad trackpad that's incorporated into the bottom of the keyboard.
Speaker 0: Was that part good?
Speaker 1: because I would pay $300 for that to be good.
Speaker 0: that is better than any trackpad on any laptop I've ever.
Speaker 1: the best trackpad I've ever touched on a lap.
Speaker 0: It's even better than like the I used to have the Apple Separate trackpad when I had a Mac at a job and this is better than that.
Speaker 1: The only show host I've ever liked and it was actually crazy good.
Speaker 1: the old Fujitsu lifebooks had this Amazing trackpad.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, that's this is even better than that.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Wow, really?
Speaker 0: I'd if you it's so good.
Speaker 1: All right, as soon as soon as quarantines over enough I want to touch that trackpad because it's so nice.
Speaker 1: I have never found a trackpad that even came close to that for jitsu lifebook trackpad, you know, it's.
Speaker 0: it's ridiculous.
Speaker 1: I don't imagine someone spent like a decade just designing the perfect trackpad at for jitsu.
Speaker 0: Yeah So the only the other than the obscene cost right which you shouldn't spend unless you have obscene Extra money.
Speaker 0: or you really need a keyboard on your iPad As head as a USB C port on it Which is cool because you can now get to USB C ports on your iPad Pro one for charging one for connecting stuff.
Speaker 0: But the one that's the one that's on the keyboard can pretty much only be used for charging.
Speaker 0: so if you want to say connect some devices maybe like a you know HDMI output thing you still need half the main one that one has to go on the iPad and the charging has to go on the Keyboard.
Speaker 1: Well, it makes sense.
Speaker 1: It's not like the keyboard has a USB C connection to the tablet.
Speaker 0: Right, exactly.
Speaker 0: The other thing is it's pretty cool to hinge.
Speaker 0: It's like the iPad sort of floats in the air and a magical Apple way.
Speaker 1: I'm looking at it on the stream right now Which is as much as I think this thing is overpriced.
Speaker 0: that looks pretty cool Right, and it actually completely works and is complete here.
Speaker 0: I'm holding it up on the YouTube, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, it totally works Right, it's not some right.
Speaker 0: it's completely legit that that part of it is completely Though that whole contraption is definitely thicker than my laptop.
Speaker 0: This is let me get my ruler.
Speaker 1: I don't have my laptop within length after the show.
Speaker 1: Let's measure.
Speaker 0: Okay, my ruler says The whole thing.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna write this down.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna go measure mine All right.
Speaker 0: Let me flip flat here And get a piece of paper.
Speaker 1: this is very important science.
Speaker 1: this is primary journalism.
Speaker 1: geek nights is doing.
Speaker 0: It's basically like it's a centimeter, but you have to add that little beginning.
Speaker 0: run on the ruler.
Speaker 0: Okay, so it's a. it's a centimeter plus the space on the ruler before the zero.
Speaker 1: Okay, so about a centimeter.
Speaker 0: So like let one and one between one and one and a half centimeters total the keyboard and the iPad Pro.
Speaker 1: I will post the.
Speaker 1: I will measure my laptop closed without any shenanigans and post that in the forum And we'll see because if my laptop is thinner than that.
Speaker 1: That's just really funny.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the keyboard also adds a lot of weight to the fit to the iPad.
Speaker 1: Well making it real you spend $300 to just turn it into a laptop.
Speaker 0: basically That's true because the other negative about it that I didn't realize is that you know when you use an iPad you kind of want To rotate horizontal vertical.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know you also get your magic pencil going on right?
Speaker 0: This thing doesn't rotate.
Speaker 0: You can't flip the keyboard to the back like you can With the folio.
Speaker 0: it pretty much just turns that.
Speaker 0: so basically if you want to on laptop you have to take the iPad out of The case noted okay you take the iPad out and now it's an iPad and then you put it back in and it's a laptop.
Speaker 0: so it's sort of like.
Speaker 0: it's sort of like the the surface Pro where the Monitor where the top comes out and the keyboard stays behind.
Speaker 0: It's a lot.
Speaker 0: it's a lot like that situation But yeah way overpriced.
Speaker 0: The problem is is like.
Speaker 0: It's like for what it is.
Speaker 0: It's overpriced, but it's like.
Speaker 0: There's no amount of money that you can spend on a other product.
Speaker 0: That is it's like every other keyboard You can get is not as is garbage much I want to make fun of you for buying this.
Speaker 1: That is kind of our philosophy of our life of by the cheapest thing or by the best thing never go in the middle.
Speaker 1: But sometimes the best thing is overpriced, but there is no alternative.
Speaker 0: Except that's exactly the situation here.
Speaker 0: is Apple has you.
Speaker 0: I think Apple knows they have you over a barrel.
Speaker 0: They're like man.
Speaker 0: No one's really making anything in this category.
Speaker 0: That's any.
Speaker 0: it's worth a shit.
Speaker 0: We can charge a fortune for ours.
Speaker 0: It's like.
Speaker 0: What are you gonna?
Speaker 0: Do buy something else?
Speaker 0: I Buy ours for way too much money or else go with some trash, right?
Speaker 0: It's like if you went to the store, and you were buying literal apples to eat right and it's like oh Yeah, there's a whole barrel full of rotten apples that are a penny each and there's one normal Apple.
Speaker 0: It's like well What's a normal Apple worth 50 cent?
Speaker 0: right a dollar maybe if you're you know in a you know if it's out of season?
Speaker 0: And it's really tasty.
Speaker 0: it's like and they're charging $100.
Speaker 0: It's like I paint $100 to one Apple.
Speaker 1: All the other ones are rotten.
Speaker 0: What are you gonna?
Speaker 0: Do not eat?
Speaker 1: I think the better analogy is airport pricing.
Speaker 1: That's what that thing costs when you're in the airport like that.
Speaker 1: you want it, and you're in the airport.
Speaker 0: That's it.
Speaker 0: But I am excited because something I've been asking for for 13 years Which is the ability to make iOS apps on an iOS device with Xcode for iOS.
Speaker 0: Right every computer that has a keyboard.
Speaker 0: pretty much you can make apps for it on the computer.
Speaker 0: You can make a Windows app on a Windows computer, huh, right you can make an OS X app on a Mac, right?
Speaker 0: Every computer ever has been able to program.
Speaker 0: almost every computer ever has had the ability to make apps for itself.
Speaker 0: Yep, that's kind of west is.
Speaker 1: that's one of those like very important concepts that if we ever lose that capability we've broken society.
Speaker 0: right iOS Doesn't have this, but the rumor is there is an Xcode for iOS.
Speaker 0: that might be a coming.
Speaker 0: We'll see.
Speaker 0: so if if that happens then this keyboard is totally worth $350.
Speaker 0: If not then it might not be.
Speaker 1: maybe wait on that, but anyway Things of the day, so I'll do mine first.
Speaker 1: cuz it's a I found a channel.
Speaker 1: I don't think I've linked to that.
Speaker 1: it's one of those things that I want.
Speaker 1: It's this real engineering channel, but this video is a 20-minute long Detailed explanation of how fucking insane the sr-71 blackbird was.
Speaker 0: we all know how insane it was.
Speaker 0: How much more can we learn about how insane it was this one actually?
Speaker 1: Explains a lot more like it sort of.
Speaker 1: it provides a lot of the foundation like ramjets.
Speaker 1: a lot of people know the word ramjet but don't really understand what a ramjet is and They only partially understand what it is.
Speaker 1: Well you might want to watch this video.
Speaker 0: I don't need to know that what it is I just need to.
Speaker 0: I just know that the blackbird had them and that's part of what made it all well.
Speaker 0: So the blackbird sides the way that it looks so cool.
Speaker 1: if the blackbird just had ramjets It would never be able to take off because ramjets don't work unless you're already going very fast.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm right the whole point of a ramjet is I'm still I'm super oversimplifying.
Speaker 1: The air intake is fast enough to self compress.
Speaker 0: Okay, okay going so fast.
Speaker 1: Yeah They can't even start running or provide any thrust unless you start them after you're already going extremely fast.
Speaker 0: You know it's like a lot of it's like F Formula One cars, right?
Speaker 0: It's like they have to heat them up, right?
Speaker 0: It's like the brakes don't work until they're hot.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but then you don't want to go too hot because they'll melt like a rail You can't stop gets launched with a like regular propellant to get it fast enough for the ramjet to kick in.
Speaker 1: Right, you know, but this video is just a really good like it's the right depth like it's just interesting that very fast machines Can't go slow.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I only go fast.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I do like.
Speaker 1: I like the videos in this genre.
Speaker 1: I actually like ones that are much more in depth Like I like them to be deeper than I can understand to force me to do research and engage.
Speaker 1: But what I appreciate about this video and what's my thing of the day?
Speaker 1: It's at a really good level of depth for most people to like really internalize how fucking insane the SR 71 Blackbird was without just being a facile two-minute check out this thing and without being a like hour-long nonsense fest that only me and two other people care about.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm Somebody got all right.
Speaker 0: So thing of the day.
Speaker 0: so way back I think I did a thing of the day or a news of some guy on YouTube Explaining, you know, like when Docker was more of a thing.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think it still is the thing I got a lot of Docker infrastructure.
Speaker 0: It's not it's less of a thing for me these days, but cuz it's still out there And I learned how it actually works.
Speaker 0: right the Linux kernel has these API's for Cgroups and other various things that allow you to make a container without making an actual virtual machine, right?
Speaker 0: You basically say hey all these processes are in this C group.
Speaker 0: They only get this much RAM between them.
Speaker 0: They can only have these permissions, right?
Speaker 0: They're sort of isolated over there.
Speaker 0: It's because Linux kernel added these API's and a guy I found a video of a guy explaining it and it was.
Speaker 0: I was Like, oh, that's how it fucking works.
Speaker 0: Why didn't you explain that Docker?
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Docker is just a wrapper that makes using those things easy.
Speaker 1: Yeah don't actually need to use Docker which is John general problem where a lot of technology in the last couple decades will Exist and be used.
Speaker 1: but most of the documentation that people have access to explains how to use it But doesn't explain why.
Speaker 1: so the people using it don't have a working mental model of what it's doing And then when it misbehaves they cannot troubleshoot it Exactly.
Speaker 0: So Docker is just a bunch of wrapper scripts around that to you know, make make using it easy.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we're not saying that's wrong.
Speaker 1: It should like.
Speaker 1: using that stuff natively would be a nightmare.
Speaker 1: The doctor did a good thing.
Speaker 1: It's yeah, if you use Docker, but don't know what doctors doing.
Speaker 0: However somebody named Julia Evans has produced the zine that you can purchase for $12 and get a PDF or Print it out or whatever Or you can pay like 170 dollars and get it for your whole company.
Speaker 0: Oh if everyone needs to learn it.
Speaker 0: And it's called how containers work and it's cute little cartoons.
Speaker 1: Oh, these look great.
Speaker 0: that completely explain in.
Speaker 0: You know language you can understand and graphics Containers seem weird because they are weird Exactly.
Speaker 0: And yeah, it teaches you about pivot root.
Speaker 0: It teaches about layers.
Speaker 0: It teaches you about I'll you know see groups the namespaces all that stuff that I learned in that video including extra stuff.
Speaker 0: I didn't know.
Speaker 0: And a handy like 20-something page zine.
Speaker 0: you'll learn better than you will from the YouTube video.
Speaker 0: This is really helpful And if you need to ever do anything involving a Linux container This might be the best documentation available.
Speaker 0: Is this cute cartoon zine?
Speaker 0: because I don't see any other.
Speaker 0: unless you want to like, you know read Linux kernel biz.
Speaker 0: This is this is your best shot out there.
Speaker 1: So this looks really good.
Speaker 1: I think I might actually buy.
Speaker 0: Yeah, where was this before when I was watching that YouTube video?
Speaker 1: That's the other thing that's annoying me lately is a lot of things will get implemented and the only documentation Including our ITMP server is a YouTube video.
Speaker 1: someone made like give me words.
Speaker 0: There are several.
Speaker 0: I have found several good how to make wire guard work things.
Speaker 1: There you go.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but not everything has that.
Speaker 1: there are thing even like.
Speaker 1: of all.
Speaker 1: Adobe is one of the few companies that has what I would call sufficient written documentation for their product.
Speaker 0: Adobe has like a whole I think like several teams of people that are like outreach people specifically pushing tutorials Like they have a tutorial app.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right Pushing out tutorials daily like tutorials learn Photoshop stuff.
Speaker 1: I'm talking about documentation.
Speaker 1: Like if you go into Adobe like audition and pick some crazy random filter that does something weird and you click on help There is a detailed and accurate explanation of exactly what all those parameters do.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, like yeah, Adobe definitely tries hard to push tutorials and Documentation For its users to help people learn their stuff, right?
Speaker 0: That's how they make their money.
Speaker 0: They want you to become a master of their stuff Right and then not want to switch to some other stuff.
Speaker 0: I mean it worked on me.
Speaker 0: I was you're one of those people who's afraid of learning something else.
Speaker 1: I would Probably I don't know what I do Like if I had to read like learn some other bullshit pipeline to make audio like.
Speaker 1: I've used Pro Tools.
Speaker 1: I've used a lot of those other tools.
Speaker 1: I don't like any of them, right?
Speaker 0: They don't.
Speaker 0: I also don't want you to bounce off their software by not being able to figure it out Right.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but lots of time and money into teaching more maybe more than any other big software company.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so in the meta moment, we're not really reading the tale of Hanzo right now because we're too busy Tale busy doing nothing.
Speaker 1: Uh However, once it gets warmer like give me a month I suspect when I go out biking in the evenings and on weekends I might just like stop in a park not of near any people under a tree and read Mm-hmm, in which case I might start reading the tale of Genji again.
Speaker 1: But to otherwise this matter by the other meta moments.
Speaker 1: while we are not doing any conventions for the foreseeable future I am continuing to take the reviews we have done of board games.
Speaker 1: Cut them out of their episodes.
Speaker 1: You don't have to hear me talk about like 20 minutes of being annoyed at slow people on their bikes.
Speaker 1: You can just hear the review of the thing and I got another one of those up.
Speaker 1: We reviewed a game that we played at PAX East which I think was 4,000 years ago at this point Called no return.
Speaker 1: That is a legit crazy good game And if you did not listen to our episode that was 58 minutes long where we reviewed this game and another game.
Speaker 1: You can watch this 10 minute YouTube video.
Speaker 1: That is just the review of this game and then buy this game because it's great and some odd.
Speaker 0: some technology meta.
Speaker 0: the new release of Ubuntu.
Speaker 0: Ubuntu The LTS release 2024 2020 which will be you know stable and supported till 2025 Just came out and I'm taking this opportunity to update all of geek night's Technology infrastructure so that I won't have to do it again for five years.
Speaker 0: Hopefully because this is the time I'm trapped inside I won't have to do it again when I could be outside.
Speaker 1: Generally we're actually you might have seen we've slowed down not just because we're not to conventions But we've slowed down a lot of our ancillary projects and that's because of all these infrastructure investments We're working on.
Speaker 0: so if you know that the point is if you notice downtime of any geek night's technology services.
Speaker 0: That's why and also if you notice improvement of any geek nice technology services.
Speaker 0: Those are coming as well.
Speaker 1: Yeah slowly But along those lines like go check out our forum and look around in there We're trying to update our like commit code of conduct for our community.
Speaker 1: We're doing a lot of stuff and you can be a part of a lot of these changes.
Speaker 1: Go poke around at all our places and look for the things we're asking for.
Speaker 1: one of the things I'll highlight.
Speaker 1: I'll mention this partly because our plan kind of got disrupted because of the quarantine so TBD on what the actual plan is.
Speaker 1: but if you were say Interested in contributing content to a zine that would be possibly distributed at gaming conventions in the future I'll hit us up.
Speaker 1: just if that sounds interesting to you at all.
Speaker 1: talk to us and we'll see what happens.
Speaker 1: Also keeping that vague because I don't know when and how we can do what we wanted to do in light of the current world.
Speaker 1: So I'm not gonna commit to anything more than what I just said.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the other thing is Alright, I've seen a lot of people running like online only conventions Which is a thing we could appear at.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: It's also a thing we could run but I'm too busy for that Doing that but I will.
Speaker 0: I'm not doing that but I will appear.
Speaker 0: if someone wants its nose of an online Convention that will let us appear at it.
Speaker 0: Let us know because I've seen some podcast ones and I've seen some.
Speaker 1: we were invited to join one that was gaming related But they were doing audio only panels and I went through every panel we've recorded.
Speaker 1: if you don't have the slides like they don't make any fucking sense because we Use those slides pretty heavily when we talk and we'll often not say things out loud that are on the slides.
Speaker 0: Exactly, we need the kind where it's like a webinar where everyone watches us or something.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if you want a live stream like I saw for example, some people were doing Relevant to the episode where we're about to do an RTMP.
Speaker 0: They were having a live stream and they would just.
Speaker 0: it was one channel.
Speaker 0: You'd sit there and watch and it was like you're sitting in a panel room and it would space Lee Import different streams to switch between the different people.
Speaker 1: So think of it this way because we're gonna make like panels and stuff on our own.
Speaker 1: But if there's an online conference like that.
Speaker 1: where you want us to talk about things we haven't talked about already.
Speaker 1: That is an inducement to get us to make a panel on that topic is to get us invited to appear on one of those things because we have a lot of time to write panels and Now is the time for us to do the panels
Speaker 0: and know where to do the panel.
Speaker 0: Yes, so no incentive to write one.
Speaker 1: but also we can do the kinds of content that is a little more adventurous or experimental or Difficult to get through the line on the kinds of conventions.
Speaker 1: We normally attend Exactly, so you can be self-interested in this.
Speaker 1: if you want us to talk about something that you think we'd be good at that We just have not talked about yet.
Speaker 1: So, uh, yeah Let us know.
Speaker 1: and also if you find any of these conferences that are awesome Post about it in the forum because I will gladly attend.
Speaker 0: on the good thing about ya.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the other good thing about these online conventions is maybe they'll just record.
Speaker 0: It's like I could attend them after.
Speaker 1: if the timings not good course recording It might be difficult for a lot of people which leads into what this show is about.
Speaker 1: So back in God 2007 or 8. we did a live stream of geek nights like on a couch in Beacon Right.
Speaker 0: We did that with a webcam plugged into a computer.
Speaker 1: in an era before like any streaming technology existed We used like you stream Right, exactly.
Speaker 0: We just webcam and computer.
Speaker 0: There was no stuff going on.
Speaker 1: We had halogen bulbs that were too hot Pointed at us.
Speaker 1: think it was a nightmare in 2013.
Speaker 1: We did a video or an episode on live-streaming video which is Completely out of date now because 2013 was a long time ago.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, so like that didn't know it as much back then.
Speaker 1: Yeah, what?
Speaker 1: not only do we not know as much but?
Speaker 1: Consumer level or prosumer level technology did not really exist in 2013.
Speaker 1: So it was hard to do a lot of this without professional equipment and even a lot of the professional equipment was not great back then.
Speaker 0: Fast forward definitely newer better technologies available for you today that are right.
Speaker 0: I remember back like even the capture cards that I had back then.
Speaker 0: Oh my god not support 1080p, dude.
Speaker 1: I had that.
Speaker 1: I tried to use that Aver TV USB to record a console and that's when I discovered that the latency on that thing was like eight seconds.
Speaker 0: Well I bought like that elgato for cheap at PAX.
Speaker 0: yeah, I also bought the totally.
Speaker 0: it totally crashed and stopped working.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that elgato just didn't fucking work like.
Speaker 1: I think I live stream successfully with it two or three times Yep, and now I've got this Aver one that works great.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I might end up getting the same one because well There's a newer model.
Speaker 0: get the newer one.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well the same kind of thing.
Speaker 1: because one thing I looked into now that we're getting into the main bit but I looked into HDMI capture cards, but I want a pro one cuz prosumer level stuff isn't that great.
Speaker 1: I want multi input, and I discovered the final limitation.
Speaker 1: for the first time in my life I hit a hardware limitation on the kind of workstation that I build.
Speaker 1: you know what you need a lot of for good HDMI input capture cards.
Speaker 1: PCIe lanes you know what most computers don't have a lot of PCIe lanes.
Speaker 1: Yep, if you don't know what a PCIe lane is I hope you're not trying to make Video hardware Right.
Speaker 0: okay, so here's the.
Speaker 0: is the deal right?
Speaker 0: so let's say you want to do some web streaming?
Speaker 0: Yeah, right you know twitch or YouTube?
Speaker 0: right well It's really easy to do because all you got to do is open OBS.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and learn how to use OBS.
Speaker 0: and what you do is you make a scene and in that scene you can incorporate all your Sources of video and audio.
Speaker 0: right you might have audio sources like your microphone.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you might have audio sources like some sound that's playing on your computer.
Speaker 1: I've dragged one of my OBS's into the stream, so you can see it.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna drag the second OBS into the stream so you can see it.
Speaker 0: right you might have other audio sources Like another friend with another microphone.
Speaker 0: you might have audio sources Video sources like capturing a video game that's playing on the computer.
Speaker 0: Yeah, webcam all sorts of things.
Speaker 0: right, but you can only stream things that you can capture.
Speaker 0: So basically anything you want to display and stream out to people.
Speaker 0: you need some way of getting that Video and audio data into that computer and the computer only has so many holes.
Speaker 0: So the holes you often end up using are the USB holes your webcam connects to USB.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right or not?
Speaker 0: even a hole just in the computer memory itself.
Speaker 0: your game is playing right.
Speaker 0: the the video of that game Is in a frame buffer.
Speaker 0: OBS can look at the images of that game right after it and like a webcam is just USB It'll just work the same.
Speaker 1: like that.
Speaker 1: that camera is just a webcam.
Speaker 1: There's literally nothing fancy going on.
Speaker 0: So let's say you want to stream your Nintendo switch right where your Nintendo switch is outside your computer.
Speaker 0: So what you need is need a capture card.
Speaker 0: the capture card is HDMI in and HDMI out Because you need to then display.
Speaker 0: you need to be able to see the game to play it, right?
Speaker 0: So you have HDMI in from the switch out to your TV so you can see the video game.
Speaker 0: So you can play and then USB out from the capture card Goes to the computer that runs OBS and you add that image to your scene on OBS and you stream and you're good to go.
Speaker 0: Yep, right the problem is is that when you want to do anything complicated, right?
Speaker 0: Suddenly you're in a situation where it's like you just can't do it.
Speaker 0: Let's say, you know, I'm here and rim is far away.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we want to be in the same.
Speaker 0: So, you know both our faces next to each other in the same stream.
Speaker 1: previously I had two webcams plugged into two USB ports pointed at each of our faces right all plugged into one PC.
Speaker 0: Let's say I got like a LAN party and even though everyone's in the same room There's too many computers, right and I can't plug in four capture cards on the same computer.
Speaker 0: It just doesn't work, right?
Speaker 0: I need some other way to get all of these different video and audio sources into a single OBS right To compose a single scene to stream it out to the world.
Speaker 0: How do you do this?
Speaker 0: Right?
Speaker 0: Well, this is technology called RTMP the real-time messaging protocol I believe and RTMP is actually what they used way back in the day to do live streams with Adobe Flash.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's it was invented by Adobe.
Speaker 0: It's open.
Speaker 0: It's like an open protocol.
Speaker 0: It's not a secret or anything.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there's a bunch of extensions to it, but you can't really use those in most cases Right.
Speaker 0: So in the earliest days of like watching like professional Streams like you know on the YouTube not YouTube, but like the internet you'd be like someone's doing a live stream of a thing.
Speaker 0: It's a special thing.
Speaker 1: They're probably go to their website software and they're probably right like a tricaster or something exactly.
Speaker 0: You'd go to their website.
Speaker 0: You'd be like you need flash.
Speaker 0: or there was also that Microsoft thing for a while that died And old Adobe like Adobe suites.
Speaker 1: you could just get that software.
Speaker 1: There's a lot of software that Adobe has gotten rid of over the years that managed some of this stuff, right?
Speaker 0: But yeah that all used this thing called RTMP.
Speaker 0: So what we've done nowadays is there are lots of alternatives to RTMP because honestly it's sort of a junky old protocol.
Speaker 1: I mean think of it this way.
Speaker 1: It's video right video streaming, but it uses TCP for some inexplicable reason.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's junky and old but for some it still works, right?
Speaker 0: It gets the job done.
Speaker 0: It handles HD.
Speaker 0: It handles everything, right?
Speaker 0: It's just junky and old.
Speaker 0: so there have been newer protocols that are better designed Or right they work and have additional features that may or may not matter to you.
Speaker 0: But RTMP works and there's a lot of support for it.
Speaker 0: So it's like you might as well just use it unless it doesn't work for you.
Speaker 1: Yes, I mean the default like if you want to stream something to like YouTube or Twitch It's literally just an RTMP destination with the stream key Exactly.
Speaker 0: So the way this works is you want to use RTMP and what you have to think of it is that You're replacing it.
Speaker 0: Imagine you had one computer to do the streaming and all your sources at HDMI cables.
Speaker 0: What you're doing is you're replacing the HDMI cable with a network connection Yep, and using RTMP.
Speaker 0: right Ethernet or Wi-Fi or cellular right is now Your HDMI cable is now a network cable instead.
Speaker 1: Yep, right.
Speaker 1: So what you do?
Speaker 1: so what Scott is doing is Scott is running OBS in his house And in his house, he's got a fancy microphone plugged in and OBS is just getting that audio.
Speaker 1: He's got a camera plugged in and OBS is getting that video.
Speaker 1: They are locally synced and he's sending me an RTMP stream.
Speaker 0: That is that audio in that video And that stream is now a source in RIMS OBS.
Speaker 0: Just like I have an OBS that I'm not streaming to YouTube I'm streaming to RIM and RIM is incorporating my stream into his stream as a source.
Speaker 0: So it's like I have a super long HDMI cable going all the way to RIMS house But we're just using a network cable instead.
Speaker 1: I pulled it all into the stream.
Speaker 1: So we've got an amazing ridiculous recursion here.
Speaker 1: But the problem is OBS for as good as it is Cannot just directly accept an RTMP stream like it's not a server, right?
Speaker 0: You'd have to open up like a port on your computer and it'd be weird.
Speaker 0: It's just OBS doesn't do that Yep.
Speaker 1: So what we've got in the middle of all that is an nginx server.
Speaker 1: if you're not familiar if we've done a show on nginx I feel like I don't know.
Speaker 1: nginx is a web server that sort of replaced Apache mostly just easier to use than Apache Because most of what Apache does it's not what anyone needs.
Speaker 0: Apache still out there.
Speaker 0: I still use it for some things.
Speaker 0: but yeah It's just a web server, but you can make extensions for it.
Speaker 0: And for some reason I don't understand the reason.
Speaker 0: instead of making like an RTMP server That's like a standalone product.
Speaker 0: right the most popular way to make an RTMP server for free is this nginx RTMP extension.
Speaker 0: So it's like everyone.
Speaker 1: like nginx is the thing.
Speaker 1: it's like node.
Speaker 1: everyone just uses it.
Speaker 1: anytime you want to proxy anything They'll just make an nginx module.
Speaker 1: Basically.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't know why it's sort of a hacky way to do it But again, it's junky but it somehow works.
Speaker 1: So I'm running an nginx server on my PC right now.
Speaker 1: I have opened ports and forwarding so Scott is streaming this to me via the RTMP protocol and this server Does almost nothing.
Speaker 1: it's using like 0.1 percent CPU because all it does is take that RTMP stream in and Make it available for me to pull via OBS.
Speaker 0: Yep, so here's is the thing that you know that there's a lot of these hidden advantages of using RTMP and an RTMP server for streaming that people.
Speaker 0: it's not immediately apparent, right?
Speaker 0: so the first thing is that the RTMP server like rim said doesn't take a lot of CPU because it's not doing encoding unless you Tell it to write.
Speaker 0: the final OBS is doing all the encoding and you know a transcoding of video Composing a scene to send to YouTube or whoever and that takes CPU power to do.
Speaker 0: But just taking streams and moving pushing bits along your only limitation is your bandwidth.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'm pushing out Megabit, right which is way more than necessary.
Speaker 1: Now Scott has sent me since we started doing this show 10 gigabytes of data and I have sent myself because I am my OBS Is not going to YouTube nor is my yeah.
Speaker 1: Accepting Scott my OBS is broadcasting to a local host port to this same RTMP server And I've sent myself 11 gigabytes of data so far.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: It's like I'm doing 1080p 60 FPS Right and YouTube or twitch.
Speaker 0: They only want six megabit.
Speaker 0: They don't want 20 20 is insane.
Speaker 0: They're like blah.
Speaker 0: they won't let you send them 20 even right?
Speaker 0: But because I'm sending you know 20 to rim.
Speaker 0: it doesn't take any of my CPU, right?
Speaker 0: It's really easy.
Speaker 0: Point at which we're using a lot of CPU is that final computer that does the encoding.
Speaker 0: everything else is just pushing crazy high quality.
Speaker 0: so Advantage one of doing it this way is that you could actually record each of these separate sources individually, right and that would only eat up your storage space.
Speaker 0: and Those individual recordings would be super high quality.
Speaker 0: if you only record that final encoded stream You're losing a lot of that original quality because it's all been encoded away in the compression.
Speaker 0: So by having all those individual source recordings, it's super high quality.
Speaker 0: You can now say later on make a YouTube video that you upload.
Speaker 0: that is ridiculously high quality higher quality than Recording of the stream.
Speaker 1: Yep, right and it also reduces recompression.
Speaker 1: just re-encoding Artifacts because I'm getting a very high quality stream from Scott that I'm then down mixing at the very end of the pipeline Right.
Speaker 0: Also, let's say you're doing PC games.
Speaker 0: Right, if you're streaming from the same computer that you're playing the PC game on directly to YouTube or Twitch.
Speaker 0: Well now the computer has to play the game, but your CPU also has to do the video encoding.
Speaker 0: Your CPU is doing double duty, right?
Speaker 0: So you're basically you push by you sending an RTMP stream to an RTMP server, right?
Speaker 0: That encoding is happening somewhere else either on a second computer or you can configure the RTMP server to sort of be To do to do the send but to twitch or YouTube or to multiple places.
Speaker 0: right and have it do the encoding And that's save your computer.
Speaker 0: This needs to use its CPU for playing doom eternal.
Speaker 0: Yeah can spend it playing doom eternal and use very small amount of CPU to just push bits of what's on your screen.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: Now if you have a real gaming PC like a serious one and you're just streaming your own game and things locally connected to it That's usually not a problem.
Speaker 1: It usually will not interfere with your game at all.
Speaker 0: If you're someone who really cares about like, you know Not losing any frames and having your whole CPU for the the game then it might matter, you know.
Speaker 0: Or if your CPUs weak and you want to do this anyway.
Speaker 0: Yeah There's one thing where you can get an internet server in the cloud To do it.
Speaker 1: the OBS is on the edge or sending a high bitrate Partly because that means there's less like compression it has to do.
Speaker 1: but we also set them to use pretty bullshitty Compression like don't spend a lot of time Mm-hmm, like don't spend a lot of resources doing better compression because compression gets better if you throw more CPU at it.
Speaker 1: and If you throw a less CPU at it, it just won't be as good but it'll be good enough for this.
Speaker 1: The high bitrate makes up for the lack of CPU resources, right?
Speaker 0: So now the other advantage you have here is that you know, let's say you're streaming on your local computer, right?
Speaker 0: Well, you know.
Speaker 0: now you got like, you know, you start your stream you stop your stream, right?
Speaker 0: You're trying to mess with things.
Speaker 0: you get to check your audio every time right.
Speaker 0: your stream always starts out weird, right?
Speaker 0: By having this edge OBS that's doing the final stream, right and all the other sources are sort of behind it.
Speaker 0: You can turn that one on right and your stream is live and it's not going anywhere.
Speaker 0: and all those other streams?
Speaker 0: You can test them out without having to show them to anyone.
Speaker 0: you can just open VLC If you have to.
Speaker 0: if you don't have any other way to do it, yep, and play one of those RTMP streams directly.
Speaker 0: It's like and you could just like watch me on the stream without streaming me to the internet See how it is See how it sounds see how it looks and then incorporate me into the scene once I'm ready.
Speaker 0: and then now your stream is way More professional because it's all.
Speaker 0: if you turns on you have a nice screen that says going live soon Doing all your testing behind the scenes right you update your you know, you switch your scene in OBS.
Speaker 0: You go live, right?
Speaker 0: let's say you have to go to the bathroom and you've got like a Mobile streaming setup with like.
Speaker 0: you're gonna stream directly from your iPhone, right and you don't want to hover it.
Speaker 0: Right, you can.
Speaker 0: you can actually do this the software for your phone iPhone or Android or iPad where you can just stream straight from?
Speaker 0: The phone either the phone camera or capturing what's on the screen of your phone.
Speaker 0: So what you do is your stream doesn't turn off right.
Speaker 0: you just change scenes.
Speaker 0: Well, you turn on your phone first you get it streaming you verify that it's working you switch scenes.
Speaker 0: now You know your stream hasn't gone off.
Speaker 0: people are watching on YouTube are still watching you but suddenly whoop It switches over to your phone and you're walking around with the phone.
Speaker 0: Right and it's super professional because your phone is streaming to the RTMP server your computer streaming to the RTMP server Right.
Speaker 0: your camera, maybe you got a separate camera.
Speaker 0: that's streaming to the RTMP server Right and then the central OBS is just switching between scenes and it's hiding all the inelegant Devices.
Speaker 0: turning on device turning off audio checks all those things are hidden because they're all being connected over the network.
Speaker 1: Yep, and the only drawback the only drawback at all Is this all told?
Speaker 1: this introduces significant latency in your streams?
Speaker 1: But at the very end that final OBS Whoever's managing that?
Speaker 1: one can just watch the streams and fucks with the encode delays to sync them up Right as long as visual sources are self synced, right?
Speaker 0: That final stream is gonna be delayed behind the real world like you're gonna be seeing things heavily delayed.
Speaker 0: It's like I might clap and you'll hear the clap 30 seconds later.
Speaker 0: Maybe something like that.
Speaker 1: that means
Speaker 0: as long as I'm in sync with the other things on the screen Right, if we're me and remember both playing a game as long as I'm not a minute ahead of rim It doesn't matter if we're both together at the same time and we're both a minute behind the real world.
Speaker 1: But what that means is I cannot use the stream Scott is sending to me to interact with Scott.
Speaker 1: So we have a separate out-of-band of all this.
Speaker 1: We have a discord voice chat is how we're actually talking to each other and audio quality through all of this Even if unless you are super professional and know what you're doing and have good hardware Gonna be pretty shitty for a lot of reasons.
Speaker 1: So you got to make sure that all the people in all your different destinations have like a good microphone good preamps all that stuff.
Speaker 0: Well, like I was saying the RTMP service can be configured to do recording Yeah, and encoding right.
Speaker 0: as a result that work.
Speaker 1: Scott's voice is being sent to discord direct to me with low latency.
Speaker 1: It's also being sent through RTMP with much higher latency Yep.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: So yeah, if you're doing any Moderately complicated streaming setup, right?
Speaker 0: I highly recommend Figuring this stuff out.
Speaker 0: It's not easy to do.
Speaker 1: but look the config file for my nginx If is under a hundred lines and most of that is white space and comments, right?
Speaker 0: You have to.
Speaker 0: still it's the documentation out there.
Speaker 0: There's a lot.
Speaker 0: it took me so long to set this up because there's so many different recommendations out there.
Speaker 0: Yeah so much conflicting info a lot of threat.
Speaker 0: you'll search online for help on this and you'll find threads that are super super old and Is like is this still the right info?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I still be using this.
Speaker 1: You'll learn.
Speaker 1: you'll learn some things along the way like for example, you know how when you stream to like YouTube or whatever There's that stream key that you have to set up.
Speaker 1: Now I know where that stream key is like where in the protocol that is used and it is stupid.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like super stupid.
Speaker 1: But you're gonna have to learn how all these things work Like why the RTMP URLs and your eyes like look the way that they do.
Speaker 1: But if you learn all of that, then you can be fluent in this real quick.
Speaker 1: It took me a couple hours of fucking with it to be a master.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: So yeah now there are.
Speaker 1: our quality is not perfect yet But that's just because I've not put the effort into a pipeline and because I'm literally running all of this on one PC.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if you're streaming games, so basically if your use cases are Combining multiple things together in one stream Offloading encoding to a different computer because you're using a lot of CPU on the computer to play games or something You've got mobile you just get multiple.
Speaker 0: you're switching between multiple different stream sources like living room bedroom outside the house.
Speaker 0: You got a stream that you know, maybe has different people, right?
Speaker 0: So it's like this you go to the geek nights channel It's me then it's rim then it's me again right switching back and forth.
Speaker 0: He's streaming right now.
Speaker 0: Yep, right?
Speaker 0: Anything fancy?
Speaker 0: this is the road you have to go down where you replace your HDMI cables with network cables or Wi-Fi And you end up Saving money because now you have to buy hardware.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right video capture devices are not cheap.
Speaker 0: Instead of buying a capture device you can just use a network cable, right?
Speaker 0: Why I was like I could take my iPad take an HDMI out into a capture device or the iPad could stream itself over Wi-Fi.
Speaker 0: So right.
Speaker 1: two last points there because there's some hardware I want to talk about.
Speaker 1: but point number one This is just a very useful trick for all of you.
Speaker 1: If you want to do this and you want to run multiple OBS's Make a copy of your whole OBS directory and just update the shortcut and add a - - portable to the command.
Speaker 1: That will run an OBS that state stores its own configuration locally and its own directory.
Speaker 1: So you have multiple OBS's with totally different configs all startable independently on one PC.
Speaker 1: That is that was not well documented, but I found it - you might think Why don't cameras just have RTMP?
Speaker 1: and the answer is expensive cameras do.
Speaker 0: Yep, you can buy like a $4,000 camcorder that actually does have RTMP.
Speaker 0: It has like a LAN hook.
Speaker 0: They can plug an ethernet cable into it and it could stream just on its own this camera just like boom.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and if you have enough money or you have a studio where you're streaming That's the kind of thing you want to buy.
Speaker 0: that's probably really good and convenient.
Speaker 0: But I gotta warn you we tried this out.
Speaker 1: There is hardware.
Speaker 1: You can just plug your kit like put on your camera with little antennas.
Speaker 1: that'll do this and like Scott said it's crazy expensive.
Speaker 1: There is cheaper hardware out there.
Speaker 1: This ICV company seems to make most of it and a lot of the other devices I've seen with other brand names look like they're This hardware with a different brand name on it Right.
Speaker 0: So like you could like I just said if you want to incorporate a device that has HDMI output but does not have Any sort of network output right and you don't want to buy a capture card or be tied down to.
Speaker 0: you know The physical wire right plugged into a computer somewhere.
Speaker 0: because think about it if you want to stream from a say a Nintendo switch Yeah, right You now need a computer to support that switch because the computer has to have the capture card plugged in with USB.
Speaker 1: Yeah, or here's my.
Speaker 1: you know, I want to do live video streams for like the rims rants on patreon on Fridays instead of like.
Speaker 1: I want to do a nice video thing.
Speaker 1: I want to set up in the living room.
Speaker 1: I have a nice backdrop.
Speaker 1: I can put my fancy camera.
Speaker 1: So if my camera has a device on it, that'll just stream our TMP.
Speaker 1: I just point it at the same server that we're using for geek nights and it just live streams.
Speaker 0: I don't need to run an HDMI cable.
Speaker 0: You won't need to have another computer with a capture card.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you can just have camera.
Speaker 0: go live with the camera.
Speaker 0: good to go.
Speaker 1: So here's the problem.
Speaker 1: Unless you spend a couple thousand dollars.
Speaker 1: These devices are complete and utter garbage.
Speaker 1: Holy shit, is this a piece of shit?
Speaker 0: there seems to be a big gulf between at the professional devices and the cheap ones Right.
Speaker 0: So the professional devices?
Speaker 0: I saw some out there that looked really good and obviously totally work.
Speaker 0: They do 1080p.
Speaker 0: They have strong CPUs that so they can encode the video properly.
Speaker 0: They have Wi-Fi.
Speaker 0: they have Ethernet.
Speaker 0: Some of them have LCD screens on them so you can preview the video that they're streaming up.
Speaker 0: They're very configurable.
Speaker 0: They have lots of features.
Speaker 0: They'll have like all kinds of audio inputs sometimes SDI inputs, you know multiple HDMI in and out A large battery packs the ability to be plugged into the wall all kinds of features That you need right, but those will be very expensive.
Speaker 1: So this bootleg one was like 170 on Alibaba.
Speaker 1: I wisely super cheap.
Speaker 1: I wisely chose to buy it on Amazon for 200 because Amazon is much easier to return things to.
Speaker 0: it's basically the cheapest one Right.
Speaker 0: So what is an HDMI?
Speaker 0: It's exactly what we want, right?
Speaker 0: It's a black box.
Speaker 1: It has a battery hole on the top so I can stick a battery in it.
Speaker 1: It's got two antenna.
Speaker 1: It'll connect to Wi-Fi.
Speaker 1: It has an Ethernet port so I could just plug a LAN cable into it.
Speaker 1: It's got an HDMI in bam.
Speaker 0: Perfect.
Speaker 0: So basically you can with that device you could turn anything that is HDMI output.
Speaker 0: It's like a camera right and it comes with a cold turn it into a live streaming camera.
Speaker 1: So I mounted to my camera plugged it in.
Speaker 1: when you power it on it just has a web interface.
Speaker 1: You connect directly to it.
Speaker 1: You can configure like four different sub streams.
Speaker 1: It'll stream to four different destinations Simultaneously.
Speaker 1: you set the bit rates it all just works and it kind of does all just work except It's tiny little bullshit.
Speaker 1: CPU hit a hundred percent immediately with one stream going to one destination.
Speaker 0: You couldn't even set what if you set the encoder to be like like we said, you know Don't try to compress the video to send all your bits.
Speaker 1: I tried every possible set of options.
Speaker 1: Nothing would make this thing work.
Speaker 1: I got it to a point where it didn't max out this.
Speaker 0: well it worked.
Speaker 0: It just worked crappily, right?
Speaker 0: Well video was low-quality.
Speaker 1: Well the video.
Speaker 1: when it was at a hundred percent the video would stutter to the point that it wasn't working.
Speaker 1: I got the CPU below a hundred a few times, but then the encoding quality was so bad, you know, like Really crap.
Speaker 0: What have you said?
Speaker 0: It's like 720p 30 like it couldn't.
Speaker 0: it couldn't keep up with that.
Speaker 1: No, I couldn't keep up with that.
Speaker 1: It just could not.
Speaker 0: that's like the minimum, right?
Speaker 1: Well, partly I can't output less than 1080p on the HDMI that comes out of my camera raw because no one has a use case for that Mmm, so like it won't do that which would be fine.
Speaker 1: This device should be able to handle that and it technically would stream video.
Speaker 1: But I think the encoding software is bullshitty because the RTMP server Couldn't auto detect the resolution of what it was outputting.
Speaker 1: like it works.
Speaker 1: when I consumed it in OBS But the RTMP server showed a weird resolution like it like something's wrong with the like the how it was encoding I didn't get to the point of wire sharking it to figure out what was wrong because I didn't care anymore.
Speaker 0: I've already mailed this thing back into that at a refund Yeah, but I think my solution is if I ever ever want to stream from on the go, right?
Speaker 0: I'm going to probably just stream from my phone.
Speaker 0: Yep, right?
Speaker 0: They'll be like phone.
Speaker 0: start streaming, right?
Speaker 1: By an HDMI input card to plug my camera into or I'm gonna buy like a multi-thousand dollar version of this from a company.
Speaker 1: That isn't bootleg nonsense.
Speaker 1: Oh good I gave it one star and I lit into how shitty this thing is.
Speaker 0: I feel like I would give something like that based on your description to star only because it did work.
Speaker 0: Right, like the web interface worked it did its thing.
Speaker 1: It was just really slow and but even if you get it working it encodes.
Speaker 1: It does not actually encode h.264 correctly Like the iframes are all messed up and like it has so many encoding artifacts and it it's weird what it's doing.
Speaker 1: I could not get it to behave deterministically.
Speaker 1: It also got so hot that it scalded me so I didn't trust it.
Speaker 1: Like literally I have a red burn on my wrist from bumping into it while I was testing it.
Speaker 0: So everyone out there it took me so long.
Speaker 0: if you're wondering how people doing these fancy streams This is how they're doing it, right?
Speaker 0: They're not using some sort of physical switcher in the real world like a professional?
Speaker 0: Yeah, no video people would do it I don't know.
Speaker 0: think about like the truck out behind the sports stadium Right where they're choosing which screens to play and they have a million cameras people who are live streaming on Twitch and YouTube.
Speaker 0: the way they're doing it is all the different cameras are streaming to a centralized RTMP server and then someone with a centralized OBS is Choosing which ones go live and that RTMP server is sort of replacing the truck that's behind the sports stadium And you're replacing the HDMI cables with RTMP streams.
Speaker 0: So it streams on streams on streams.
Speaker 0: I know that's the way it's done
Speaker 1: and frankly If you learn how to make that work Other than the underlying technology like the server you're using as opposed to say like hardware encoders and running real cables and stuff The reality is you'll learn like messing with OBS in that format Like you'll learn all the skills you need to work in one of those trucks.
Speaker 1: like it's the same pipeline It's just different on infrastructure to drive that pipeline.
Speaker 0: You can also get people who are streamers maybe popular ones who aren't good at technology to like pay you to help them out.
Speaker 0: Yep, because good lord people already in that industry, but there's still obviously room to move into that an industry.
Speaker 1: I've tried to watch a lot of people who are Ostensibly professionals in this space with their own live streams during the quarantine because a lot of professional entertainers are trying to live stream from home and Yeah, they don't know how to make any of this stuff work.
Speaker 0: No We only just learned it.
Speaker 1: Yep, but the point is it did not take long.
Speaker 1: RTMP is like not hard.
Speaker 1: You just have to understand all these sort of VIP.
Speaker 0: Well, you got to know TCP IP and you got to know all the stuff around streaming.
Speaker 1: Like you got to know how video works like on a basic level.
Speaker 1: You got to know how like encoders work on a basic level got to know how Microphones work on a basic level.
Speaker 1: like you need to have all these basic pieces and then you can use this technology To stitch them all together, which is the last mile.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: That's that's enough.
Speaker 0: I got any food.
Speaker 1: Yep, I also got any food.
Speaker 1: good times a lot of people in the stream.
Speaker 0: See you around.
Speaker 1: Yeah This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at front row crew comm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 1: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays and the comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 0: But unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night and the patreon patrons for this remote episode of geek nights are Alan Joyce, Heidi McNichol, Marty Green, you're just like a dude guy.
Speaker 1: chart option link.
Speaker 1: each you hold the key to my heart.
Speaker 1: I Begged and pleaded with her.
Speaker 1: day after day.
Speaker 1: Clinton Walton Jay Vance ran from New Zealand Ryan Perrin drooping ladder Nicholas Brando Chris midkiff thirst for high-graded Gannon dread Lily Tenebrae Chris Reimer Finn Sean Klein Thomas on sheriff of unhurled Sean Yeager and a whole bunch of people.
Speaker 1: Don't want me to say their names.
Speaker 1: Come to the forum.
Speaker 1: Tell us how the streams are going.
Speaker 1: We keep tweaking this pipeline bit by bit.
Speaker 1: We'll start sharing more Configs and options and if you have any questions about RTM be streaming will be more than happy to answer them.
Speaker 1: But for now, I leave you with Martina Sonal Sato.
Speaker 0: Hey, let's uh, Martina sonal Sato In vassal Partiziano For the movie.
Speaker 0: ah Hey, that's our that's our that's our child's own party.
Speaker 0: John.
Speaker 0: Oh, oh, that's me.
Speaker 0: Yeah He me sent.
Speaker 0: Say you move you.
Speaker 0: the parties are known.
Speaker 0: Vela chao vela chao vela chao chao chao.
Speaker 0: Say you more you.
Speaker 0: the parties are known to me.
Speaker 0: They'll be Separated.
Speaker 0: Separated.
Speaker 0: Sweet on Tanya.
Speaker 0: Vela chao vela chao vela chao chao chao.
Speaker 0: se pelire.
Speaker 0: Sweet on Tanya Soto go John.