Speaker 1: It's Thursday July 2nd 2020.
Speaker 1: I'm rim.
Speaker 1: I'm Scott and this is geek nights.
Speaker 1: tonight We're talking about those food subscription boxes that Millennials are so excited about.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: So something weird happened to me over the last few days like this.
Speaker 1: There was a minor drama.
Speaker 1: So Several a few days ago in the evening.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna cook something, right?
Speaker 1: so I I start some water boiling like on the stove like you do and I set the oven to preheat like you do and As the oven starts preheating the oven smells weird Not like gas.
Speaker 1: It does not smell like unburnt gas.
Speaker 1: So that's that is not.
Speaker 1: that is not something I would miss identify.
Speaker 0: I even go like in the oven that was burning.
Speaker 1: that was that was my first thought because I grew up in the Midwest and for those of you who don't know it is Weirdly common in the Midwest for people to store their bread and even sometimes other groceries in the oven.
Speaker 0: I do not do that or if I ever done that I don't think people do that except in the Midwest.
Speaker 1: but in the Midwest It's a.
Speaker 0: that's definitely a dumb idea or unless you never use your oven ever.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: So as a kid I just remembered anytime I was gonna use the oven I'd open it I take out like whatever bread was in there and then I'd preheat the oven.
Speaker 1: so to this day if you ever watched like As an adult this is so ingrained in my head for being a kid in the Midwest watch anytime I'm gonna preheat the oven.
Speaker 1: I hit preheat.
Speaker 1: I start it and then I open the oven.
Speaker 1: I look inside and then I close it again.
Speaker 1: It's just a habit that I'll never break.
Speaker 1: I don't store anything in my fucking oven because I'm not.
Speaker 0: I mean I before I use the oven I also open it to check inside to make sure the racks are in the correct position.
Speaker 0: Nah, true true was that I want to move them way after they heat up.
Speaker 1: But the inside of the oven smells really weird and night and it vaguely smells like either burning plastic or like really messed up food.
Speaker 1: Like I wasn't sure but it wasn't a super strong smell, but it was there.
Speaker 1: So I look around the oven like that I'd like did something fall off the pan the last time I was using the oven?
Speaker 1: like I didn't see any new Black marks or new garbage or anything in there.
Speaker 1: I fudged around a little.
Speaker 0: I even open the bottom door Like to check to see that the flame was something on top of the oven because sometimes when I use my oven it gets really Hot on top of the rain.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the heat comes up through the.
Speaker 1: you know, I checked up there, too.
Speaker 1: There was not a problem that I could see.
Speaker 1: I even open that little door though to check like what color was the flame?
Speaker 1: Inside the oven?
Speaker 1: because if the actual flame in the oven is not the the right orange or blue you're getting incomplete combustion Which is a big problem, but everything was fine there.
Speaker 1: So I just cooked with this weird smell.
Speaker 1: I didn't think about it.
Speaker 0: Wouldn't it make your food taste bad.
Speaker 0: It didn't like.
Speaker 1: it was fine.
Speaker 0: Okay I would not cook with a weird smell out of fear.
Speaker 1: It wasn't that strong of a smell and it got a little weaker like later after the oven was preheated.
Speaker 1: So I figured all right, I'll deal with that later.
Speaker 1: Like I got to clean the oven.
Speaker 1: Anyway, it's been a while.
Speaker 1: next day Emily's cooking and I'm in here like messing with stuff and she comes in.
Speaker 1: she's like the oven smells really weird Like this.
Speaker 1: the range smells really weird, but she was not using the oven.
Speaker 1: She was just using the cooktop.
Speaker 1: Okay, so I come out and sure enough it smells like the same weird smell that came out of the oven the previous day.
Speaker 1: It's now coming.
Speaker 1: It smells like it's coming out of the fire itself.
Speaker 1: on the top of the stove There's something in the gas.
Speaker 0: That wasn't good.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so at that point that's where it was a weird thing.
Speaker 1: And so I start googling around because it the best way I could describe the smell.
Speaker 1: Then when I really like this has happened two days in a row and it's not just the oven.
Speaker 1: This is weird I went from.
Speaker 1: I'll keep an eye on the situation to.
Speaker 1: I need to actively investigate the situation Because I don't like.
Speaker 1: this is something that I do not have knowledge of.
Speaker 1: so I googled for and this is where it was funny.
Speaker 1: I started googling for like kerosene smell from and Google recommended natural gas stove immediately And there's a million results for that exact question.
Speaker 0: People will say Google for like contaminated.
Speaker 1: Yes I mean I googled for all those sorts of things but everyone keep kept like a Vaguely kerosene or like bad propane or a smell in that class coming from a Gas a natural gas normal stove that previously never had a smell like that.
Speaker 1: and I found a million results mostly in places like Quora or like Yahoo!
Speaker 1: ask or reddit or stack exchanges where people were like Why is my oven smelling like this suddenly?
Speaker 1: and about half of them were?
Speaker 1: People bought a brand new oven and it smells like that for the first like month when you use it And then it just kind of stops smelling like that, but we've been using this same stove and oven for like 11 years.
Speaker 1: We've not replaced like the starter or anything in it like it.
Speaker 1: I don't use oven cleaner in it Like I don't use it.
Speaker 1: cleaning cycle done nothing weird to this thing.
Speaker 1: So the other reason most people say it has this smell is Something that I never even considered.
Speaker 1: so the stories all went the same way.
Speaker 1: The smell started happening and then when I scroll all the way down through the comments at the bottom the answer was I figured it out and it was always something like I painted my basement or I painted like a room in my house or I varnished my floors and My oven smelled like this.
Speaker 1: for like three weeks afterward I ended up finding some gas websites like gas company websites that had facts that even had things like.
Speaker 1: if you smell a smell like This here are the likely causes.
Speaker 1: and the first question they ask in those facts when you're trying to troubleshoot is have you painted or?
Speaker 1: Varnished anything in your house recently?
Speaker 0: did they paint in the hallway?
Speaker 1: Finally, they paid.
Speaker 1: the apartment next to us is empty and is currently being completely repainted.
Speaker 0: All right, you got to air it out.
Speaker 1: So apparently what happens is the paint smell was gone at this point like they're done painting that.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah But it's still.
Speaker 0: it's still around.
Speaker 1: it's around so it.
Speaker 1: apparently it hangs around for like a month and you'll never smell it or notice.
Speaker 1: but if you have Exposed open flames they will combust those particles that you can't smell and they will make this very specific kerosene esque odor.
Speaker 1: so because our neighbor's apartment was being painted our gas stove smells like kerosene and Probably will for another couple weeks.
Speaker 0: Why just open the windows and blow some fans?
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 1: So now I open though.
Speaker 1: I mean it's hot and don't you have that?
Speaker 0: you have an air filter thing, too.
Speaker 1: That air filter will not remove those types of things unless I put a different filter in it.
Speaker 1: That's expensive and that's not a common problem.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so we opened all the windows and the smell went down but it's still there and like it's lower and I guess I have to wait a couple weeks for it to completely dissipate.
Speaker 1: Okay, some people reported it took like two or three months But those people had done things like painted sealant over the walls of their entire basements Hmm.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that was so.
Speaker 1: if you ever have a gas stove that never smelled like kerosene before in one day It smells like kerosene.
Speaker 1: Did you paint your house recently?
Speaker 0: Did you paint anything?
Speaker 1: Yeah, did you paint something?
Speaker 1: I feel like the wrong Gundam kit could cause this problem.
Speaker 0: Yeah Well, the only the only open e type bit I have is that you know since going outside is kind of dangerous I don't do that too much right and I don't have to go to work in an office and not so I'm not biking there.
Speaker 0: You know, I've been riding the inside bike ever since my building reopened the guy.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the inside bike, you know, it's not that fun.
Speaker 0: But it's you know, it's more fun.
Speaker 1: No, but I've been forced myself.
Speaker 1: I've been biking outside every weekend instead and running outside avoiding people.
Speaker 0: So I biked on the the nowhere bike that go with the bike to nowhere like every day, you know for like You know, I guess six days a week except for there was one day.
Speaker 0: I guess I missed one day out of it was one week.
Speaker 0: I only did five days cuz I got really tired and I couldn't.
Speaker 0: I was like that happens.
Speaker 1: I mean, you know, I mean how crazy I'm about running.
Speaker 1: I don't run every day some days.
Speaker 1: I'm just like, you know what?
Speaker 1: I'm just gonna play video games and go to sleep.
Speaker 0: Oh, you know, I just figured it's like I'm not biking that much, right?
Speaker 0: It was I was used to bike every day almost every day anyway, so now today, you know they the guy I'm in the building got closed because You know virus right.
Speaker 0: and then they're like, okay, we're reopening it today.
Speaker 0: They send an email.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, the health department came and said they're gonna find us unless we close it.
Speaker 0: They closed it again.
Speaker 1: interesting.
Speaker 0: so And I guess tomorrow I'm gonna maybe try to just go outside and be like, well see what's it.
Speaker 1: I'm not sure what the rule there is because when I read the like the regulations that were passed in New York It seemed to imply that like those kinds of rules technically only applied to like commercial public.
Speaker 0: That's what I thought - this is an in the building gym Not a you know, yeah my building's gym has definitely not closed.
Speaker 1: I won't.
Speaker 1: I'm not using it one cuz it's small like it's basically just this atrium.
Speaker 1: But the rule their rule is basically you have to wear a mask while you're in there and only one person can be in there at a time.
Speaker 0: ours is just.
Speaker 0: it was open and Ours is basically.
Speaker 0: it's like it's an apartment where they just took the walls down.
Speaker 1: Oh, no, that's way worse.
Speaker 1: Ours is like like was made to be a gym room.
Speaker 0: It's a large.
Speaker 0: It was a large apartment where the walls were taking.
Speaker 0: there's a lot of stuff.
Speaker 0: ours is like this a dream in a sock.
Speaker 0: It's like an atrium connected to the building like a sauna and a bathroom in it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm a little jealous of that sauna.
Speaker 1: We don't got anything like that.
Speaker 0: I've never used it.
Speaker 0: I've never seen anyone use it.
Speaker 1: I would use it if you if I don't know how to use it.
Speaker 0: It's gonna use it properly.
Speaker 1: Uh, I I would gladly teach you if I could use your sauna.
Speaker 0: They say that no, I would let you come and teach me to use the sauna But there's actually a rule that visitors may not use.
Speaker 1: the guy Our jail building has that rule but I've often let people who visit us use our guy.
Speaker 1: I'm because they don't care.
Speaker 0: sure we could get away with it.
Speaker 0: But yeah, it has like a temperature setting and it's like what do I set it to?
Speaker 0: 100 200?
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, you don't want it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you could.
Speaker 1: you could possibly pass out and have a problem if you don't know what the head It's like.
Speaker 0: and then there's like, you know, it's got the little thing where you pour the water with from the bucket with.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you got to be careful with that.
Speaker 1: noobs will do things like pour splash a bunch of water on it And that is not what you want.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I know.
Speaker 0: So I think maybe I could just watch a YouTube video like how to sauna with some finish first.
Speaker 1: I'm sure there's some amazing finish video that is like here is how to sauna.
Speaker 1: that is funny and wrong and another one That is extremely correct.
Speaker 0: But the thing is I think their demo sauna would be much higher quality than the one.
Speaker 1: I am actually impressed that you have a real sauna because almost every apartment building I've ever seen in New York does not have a Real sauna.
Speaker 1: they have a hotel sauna that is designed to make sure that even idiots cannot hurt themselves Where you turn a dial.
Speaker 1: that is just a timer.
Speaker 1: You can't customize the temperature and there's no rocks.
Speaker 0: Oh, no No, this is a. this is like a little.
Speaker 0: it's like a little room made like the size of a small.
Speaker 0: that's good wood walls.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it wouldn't.
Speaker 0: I mean it's.
Speaker 0: it's like a door to get a glass door to get in there.
Speaker 0: So you can see what's going on in there.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and there's.
Speaker 0: there's two levels of wooden bench, right?
Speaker 0: There's like tier one and tier two and in the corner next to the door is I don't know if it's rocks But it's definitely the place where you can dump water.
Speaker 0: and on the outside next to the door is a little control panel where?
Speaker 0: You can set.
Speaker 1: you know, that's so nice.
Speaker 1: I will say what is it?
Speaker 0: But there it is.
Speaker 1: I uh once in my life III was party to and Smartly fled from before consequences occurred a sauna incidents.
Speaker 1: Well, our marching band was up in Canada for some competition.
Speaker 1: I don't remember what.
Speaker 1: so like 250 high schoolers are in this hotel in Canada and it had a sauna and the entire percussion group plus me and I like a couple trouble players.
Speaker 1: We're all in the sauna.
Speaker 1: I'll summarize the story an unnamed individual who is not me and not someone I was a fan of stood up walked over toward the rocks and Clearly was about to pee on them.
Speaker 1: Oh, I I Got the eye of the other trouble players with me.
Speaker 1: I was like we gotta get out of here and he was like what?
Speaker 1: well and I pointed he was like Oh shit, and we ran.
Speaker 1: I Don't know exactly how it went down But everyone inside started screaming and they could not all get out of the sauna because they blocked the door Falling over each other.
Speaker 1: It was chaos.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that person should be my advice to anyone out there.
Speaker 1: Do not pee on the sauna rocks trust or the electric fence.
Speaker 1: Yeah So in some news that may affect some of you many of you Actually a lot of you way more of you than I expected subscribe to my Twitter block list.
Speaker 1: Now my block list is not like.
Speaker 1: it's not a block list that I need to protect myself so much as I have added Groups of harassing accounts to it over the years to help my friends protect themselves like notably I created this thing way back when that whole Vic thing was going on and I wrote a Python script and used some Logic to find basically every shithead in that area of the internet and add them all to a block list that other people could subscribe to and a surprising number of people in the anime world Subscribed to it and those kids didn't realize that everyone they were trying to harass couldn't see them anymore.
Speaker 1: But block together the service I used to do this is shutting down and the main reason they're shutting down.
Speaker 1: Is that The technology they've deployed could probably have been done better like you and I if we made a similar service could have architected a lot Better.
Speaker 1: but also Twitter has locked down their API's to make it a giant pain in the ass to do anything like this.
Speaker 0: So I really don't understand.
Speaker 0: It's like Twitter, you know There's always been this pattern of businesses technology companies right where when they start out They're open source free.
Speaker 0: a guy Do something cool by being so open and so free.
Speaker 0: right people come to their platform and build upon it for free.
Speaker 0: Helping.
Speaker 0: it's like giving them free labor right.
Speaker 1: the Twitter API used to do a lot.
Speaker 0: It was used to do everything you could do on Twitter.
Speaker 0: You could do with the API And then they get big and then once people are big they're saying okay, we gotta lock it down.
Speaker 0: We got to charge money.
Speaker 0: We got to close things up, right?
Speaker 0: It's like Like.
Speaker 1: if you want to know what's wrong with you why there used to be a lot of really good Android Twitter clients And now there aren't any it's because Twitter removed all the features from the API necessary to make a good Twitter app.
Speaker 0: It's like you just did work to develop those features.
Speaker 0: Why would you delete them?
Speaker 0: Yeah, now like no one's gonna pay you for that feature.
Speaker 1: now you think why is Twitter doing this?
Speaker 1: Like.
Speaker 1: why is Twitter making it so hard to use the very simple API that just lets you block an account Like?
Speaker 1: why so, uh, I found this article from 2015 Where Twitter had implemented massive block features that they didn't have before.
Speaker 1: They implemented this whole thing where you can Import and export block list.
Speaker 1: so I could make a big block list of like all those big MiNONA fans and I could share it with all my friends and they could just import that block list.
Speaker 1: like Twitter started making Features that do the things that this block together thing did.
Speaker 1: so you might think okay I guess Twitter is trying to like run this themselves for some reason instead of letting someone else do all the work.
Speaker 1: Okay And they even shared this article talking about how sharing block lists will help you make Twitter safer Like.
Speaker 1: they highlighted it as a feature of Twitter to make Twitter a safer place, especially if people who get harassed Fast forward now to 2020.
Speaker 1: Twitter very recently like in the last couple months Removed the ability to import and export block lists.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm Twitter seems to have removed almost every safety feature that they implemented over the met last many years just in the last few months.
Speaker 1: Okay, I don't know why it seems insane.
Speaker 1: Twitter is even like they've throttled their API such that even that Chrome plug-in that you can click on some shitty Twitter account and Automatically block everyone who follows that account.
Speaker 1: They've throttled the API such that that thing doesn't work anymore either.
Speaker 1: Twitter is like aggressively going after features that make it easy for people to block Nazis and I don't know why.
Speaker 1: The only reason I bring this up on a Thursday is to make a more broad point.
Speaker 1: The problem with like harassment on the internet is not a technology problem.
Speaker 1: the tools to handle this are fairly trivial to make.
Speaker 1: the problem is that platforms actively prevent people from using these kinds of tools and Actively avoid just banning all the accounts that are the problem.
Speaker 1: like read it recently.
Speaker 1: They shut down all these awful subreddits.
Speaker 1: Why didn't they just ban literally every account that was in those subreddits?
Speaker 0: That's what I said.
Speaker 1: If the if the subreddit is bad enough to be banned then you should ban fucking everybody who used that thing ever.
Speaker 1: And sure, maybe there's a little bit of friendly fire.
Speaker 1: someone subscribe accident.
Speaker 1: I don't care.
Speaker 1: We already agreed as a society that blocking ninety nine point nine nine nine percent of all email is worth the trouble.
Speaker 1: like we all agree that we'd rather block every spam no matter what even if a Surprising percentage of valid emails get flagged to spam Why don't we just if you had a span ever had a G?
Speaker 0: if your Gmail spam filter, right?
Speaker 0: Never ever accidentally mark something as spam that wasn't spam, but occasionally a spam got through You would be upset.
Speaker 0: You'd be like what the fuck is a spam in my Gmail, right?
Speaker 0: So what Gmail does is it never lets us spit and there's never been a spam in my mailbox.
Speaker 0: Yep, right, but once in a blue moon a real email gets marked as spam Like once or twice like a quarter.
Speaker 1: that happens to me.
Speaker 0: and then people people it's like oh if they're expecting the email They check their spam filter and they find it and if they weren't Expecting the email then they don't miss it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, not a big deal.
Speaker 1: So these platforms like there are.
Speaker 0: someone asked me.
Speaker 0: if someone asked me on Twitter let's say I'd make a tweet and a thousand people at me right and it blocks all the Nazis adding me and It blocks a few nice ads that I would have liked to see
Speaker 1: like a nice person who happens to have Accidentally followed a Nazi bot.
Speaker 0: Let's say it's like well, I'm not gonna miss that at right.
Speaker 1: Well, what I'm not gonna miss.
Speaker 0: someone who got caught in friendly fire because they accidentally follow a Bob Their message is not so important that the fact that it was blocked is like a big deal, right?
Speaker 0: but if instead, you know all the good replies get through and I see them all but Two Nazis get through and I see two Nazi ads it's like that's not good Right.
Speaker 0: It's like we want more blocking pretty much everywhere, right?
Speaker 0: You should lock everything bad Even if it means blocking a couple good things and that we've already determined that that's the correct model.
Speaker 0: It's just few platforms other than email implement that model.
Speaker 1: So, uh, yep.
Speaker 1: I that's all I got to say about that.
Speaker 1: Like the problem is the people with power refuse to use their power Either because like I didn't I think there's a lot of reasons why some of them have like this false nobility.
Speaker 1: We're like they believe there's a higher purpose like some free speech thing but most of them it really just seems like they're in cahoots with shitty people or they're dependent upon shitty people and Like Twitter
Speaker 0: they care more about numbers and they believe that that will help their numbers.
Speaker 1: Yeah Well, like.
Speaker 1: I honestly think if Twitter actually blocked and banned all the bots and Nazis They'd lose like a third of the accounts on Twitter if not more.
Speaker 0: Well, if they if Twitter if you took all the number of Twitter accounts there are total right and you removed all the bad people and you removed all the inactive accounts and You removed all this the bot accounts.
Speaker 0: How many accounts would really be left?
Speaker 0: I mean, there's a lot of people.
Speaker 1: I think there's enough to have a thriving community and a great pleasure, but there's not enough to pay back those VCS.
Speaker 0: Is there enough to pay for all the employees of Twitter?
Speaker 0: It's like this huge company with a shit ton of employees, huh?
Speaker 1: Right, but how about this if you got rid of all those accounts and didn't and prevented them from rejoining?
Speaker 1: Maybe you need less infrastructure to stop just like how much infrastructure in Twitter is just passing Nazi bots retweeting each other at each other in a vacuum that no human ever sees.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you're uh, you know.
Speaker 0: if you're running just like a web server on the internet Right and you just put it out there and you don't have any sort of protections on it It's like you actually use a lot of CPUs and bandwidth just dealing with like random things on the internet Just like pinging your server and trying to connect your SSH or scraping your website and all this stuff.
Speaker 0: Right, if you just put a little filters on there and you block, you know some some naughty activities Right suddenly your web server is only doing the things you want it to do and you save a ton of money.
Speaker 1: Yeah All right But anyway It's Thursday.
Speaker 1: Not a ton of news because we don't need to talk about the news that you should all be following on your own.
Speaker 1: Black lives matter.
Speaker 1: do you fund the police like all that stuff is happening?
Speaker 1: Don't get don't come to us To get updates on that because we're two white guys.
Speaker 1: There are way better people to go to and if you're not following.
Speaker 0: That's a problem is from the same place that we're getting it from black people on Twitter.
Speaker 1: Yep, if you wouldn't hear about that stuff unless we talk about it.
Speaker 1: That's a big problem.
Speaker 1: So things of the day.
Speaker 1: What do you got?
Speaker 0: What do I have?
Speaker 0: I forget?
Speaker 0: Let me check.
Speaker 1: Let's get to the root of that problem.
Speaker 0: What was it the bootleg root?
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah So yeah bootleg.
Speaker 0: board games have been a problem for a while now partially because you know the the there are laws Regarding the intellectual property of board games are such that you can't control mechanics.
Speaker 1: Game mechanic is not really inherently copyrightable.
Speaker 1: So if I fully and if I design a game that is mechanically identical to a game that already exists I can sell that.
Speaker 1: they don't have any claim on those game mechanics.
Speaker 1: They can't say that they have a copyright on the way worker placement works in their game.
Speaker 0: You can only copyright copyright the artwork.
Speaker 0: You can copyright the text of your rule book.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know.
Speaker 0: so it's like I'd have to basically write the rules that are equivalently the same but not like copy their rule book.
Speaker 1: You have to do what a lot of high school kids do when they all plagiarize the same essay, right exactly but anyway.
Speaker 0: So, you know for what's been happening is there has been straight-up bootlegging which is where In places usually in China where board games are printed, right?
Speaker 0: Companies were printing out Direct copies of existing board games.
Speaker 0: like you would put in an order and say I want a thousand copies of my game and they would Make them and then some other factor would make a thousand copies of the game sometimes even the same factor.
Speaker 1: He just makes another thousand copies and sells them on the black market, right?
Speaker 0: But it's like it looks the same like exactly the same right.
Speaker 0: the same exact rules text, right?
Speaker 0: But like the quality would be lower right be shitty your cardboard right if the printing resolution be lower, right?
Speaker 0: But an untrained I would never be able to tell that right.
Speaker 0: only the only a nerd would know that was not an original You know copy of the game.
Speaker 0: And then they would flood the market with those.
Speaker 0: and like Amazon's you go like or anywhere else on the internet.
Speaker 0: so you go online and you're like I want to buy a copy of a carcass own and a carcass own shows up and It's a flimsy crappy carcass own that looks like a normal one And if you're not if you don't know better you just got hosed right cuz that money did not go to the correct company It should have.
Speaker 1: some people might like be like those anime fans who bought bootlegs on purpose because they were cheap.
Speaker 1: like that happens, too.
Speaker 0: But there's another level of bootlegging in the board game industry that goes on which is where The people are taking Chinese mostly as you can see in the examples in this at this link, right?
Speaker 0: The same exact game, but the same exact rules only translated into Chinese, right?
Speaker 0: So the game does not has not been licensed for the Chinese market.
Speaker 0: I think it's.
Speaker 0: you know It doesn't look like it has been right.
Speaker 0: And They redo the art they.
Speaker 0: they don't redo the rules or the mechanics it seems based on what it looks like.
Speaker 0: But they basically take the exact same game and reef redo all the art completely You know in their own style and translate it and then sell it in China.
Speaker 0: And it doesn't seem like they're paying licensing fees to the original creators.
Speaker 1: By the end Patrick leader even tweeted.
Speaker 1: He was like remember kids real copies of root have art lovingly made by Kyle Farron.
Speaker 0: Right it's like you know.
Speaker 0: you look at the the art they made though and some of it is a pretty astonishingly great.
Speaker 1: Yeah, some of it is just astonishing.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there's like a hive game where they've replaced all the bugs with like some fantasy warriors of some kind and instead of clacky tiles They've used little tiny cardboard hexes.
Speaker 0: That looks pretty bad, but yeah Here's a whole thread of that second variety of knockoff board game in which the games have been redone.
Speaker 0: It's pretty.
Speaker 0: it's pretty terrific to behold.
Speaker 0: Yeah, this doesn't happen just with board games.
Speaker 0: that happens pretty much with anything yep.
Speaker 1: So there was a meme that made the rounds a while ago if you didn't see it.
Speaker 1: It's a. it was the potion seller.
Speaker 1: It's a. there is an adventurer and the adventure It's one person doing the voice acting of the two characters.
Speaker 1: the adventurer wants to buy some potions from the potion seller and the potion Seller is warning the traveler that his potions are too strong and that he will not sell them to him.
Speaker 1: And it's just like a skit.
Speaker 1: It's okay funny, however People started doing the thing where they were remixing this meme and that started to get a lot of control.
Speaker 1: And it ended with this supreme work of art.
Speaker 1: someone took the audio from the potion seller.
Speaker 1: they Animated it in the style of Jojo's bizarre adventure Added music to it and turned it into a mini episode of Jojo's where a Jojo character is trying to buy potions from another Jojo character.
Speaker 1: it is too funny for this world and this entire dialogue is like burned into my soul at this point.
Speaker 0: Okay, I don't.
Speaker 0: if I have seen it I don't remember it.
Speaker 1: the potion seller meme is not.
Speaker 1: it did not seem to appear in our circles.
Speaker 1: It came to me by way of a friend of ours who was in our circles But also many many very very different online circles and the intersection of a burning wheel game brought this to my attention.
Speaker 1: Okay in the meta moment.
Speaker 1: We're stuck at home.
Speaker 1: There's a long weekend.
Speaker 1: You're lucky.
Speaker 1: We're doing a show today usually right before a holiday weekend.
Speaker 1: We'll bail.
Speaker 0: I got off work at 3 today.
Speaker 0: I didn't.
Speaker 1: I would have gone off at work 3 But there was a. there was an outage and I'm I'm the kind of manager person like if you've ever worked in like big iron IT, you know.
Speaker 1: when there's a problem there's like different classes of people who get involved.
Speaker 1: Like there's the person who desperately is trying not to get invited to the conference call that has a million people on it.
Speaker 1: There's the person actually fixing the problem that no one's actually talking to.
Speaker 1: for some reason There's all the salespeople who are on that conference call constantly asking for updates that no one gives them updates And then there's the person who eventually joins the conference call and as soon as they join everyone gets quiet and that Person asks for an update and then leaves.
Speaker 1: that last part is the role I usually serve in these conference calls, but That meant I had to keep doing a lot of work right up until we did the show.
Speaker 1: I couldn't I couldn't ease into the night for this long weekend Like I don't know if it's 459 right and my work says oh shit.
Speaker 0: Something's out.
Speaker 0: Can you help?
Speaker 0: I say?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'll give you exactly one minute of help.
Speaker 1: And then in the or in the case of today if at 259 I Work on I get paid enough to where I am willing to work a lot harder when that when the time comes.
Speaker 1: But if I but if that happened to all such there is no such time is there alright.
Speaker 1: So here's the question for you.
Speaker 1: Is there an amount of money?
Speaker 0: is There if they say if I said you have one more minute to and I'm gonna no longer work on this and they said we Will give you a million dollars.
Speaker 0: I say, okay.
Speaker 0: I'll work on this for another minute.
Speaker 1: So Yeah, check out our YouTube channels watch for our stuff.
Speaker 1: I'm working on things this weekend things you might be interested in.
Speaker 1: We're working on some panels for some online conventions working on a lot but Unfortunately, like we've worn before a lot of the projects we really want to work on are very hard to move forward when Scott And I cannot be in a room together.
Speaker 1: So we're making progress on things that do not require that.
Speaker 1: But the things that do not require that are much longer-term projects.
Speaker 1: where there's not a lot we can show you and we're very hesitant To talk about them because that will imply that we have done more work than we have up to this point.
Speaker 0: I've done some stuff that no one would notice.
Speaker 0: I upgraded the hardware of some of our servers.
Speaker 1: Ooh, this thing still works that you don't even know that I did that I set up and did some tests with my teleprompter and a paid streaming rig to do some other kinds of content.
Speaker 1: Okay So, uh, yeah, otherwise we will eventually read the tale of Genji, but But right now I don't have a lot of free time that I am stuck in subways or trains or transit.
Speaker 0: Like I feel like when I mostly read is when I'm flying taking trains somewhere I can't even go to the beach and do summer eating like but I weren't even go to a pool and do some reading.
Speaker 1: Yeah like if we could go to Sandy Hook like what we do this weekend you and me and a bunch of our friends would be Sandy Hook and I would lay there for about four hours reading the tale of Genji.
Speaker 1: Like that's what I would be doing tomorrow, but I can't nope Yep, so that's where we are.
Speaker 1: Wear masks.
Speaker 1: if you have to go outside Don't fly.
Speaker 1: if you can go outside.
Speaker 0: if you don't have to don't go anywhere if you don't have to.
Speaker 1: yeah I'm wrong.
Speaker 1: I'm going outside a lot, but I'm doing like long runs by myself.
Speaker 0: It sucks big time to not go outside But you know It sucks worse being anywhere other than New York.
Speaker 0: right now in America often you're long out and dying.
Speaker 0: I'll just stay inside and be sad rather than die because I'll be way more sad if I get covered.
Speaker 1: Yeah so One of the consequences of staying inside means that I subscribe to a lot more food boxes than I used to We were we subscribe to some of these things before.
Speaker 1: what we're talking about like the topic of the show is basically those things like Hello Fresh or Blue Apron or Misfits Market that are Variously.
Speaker 1: we will mail you like three or four meals with recipes on a weekly or monthly Basis or we will mail you groceries where you don't quite get to pick.
Speaker 1: We're not talking about just food delivery like fresh direct.
Speaker 1: We're not talking about.
Speaker 1: I can just put in an order for specific or fresh strike does have some meal delivery stuff They do but primarily I can pick exactly what I want for a specific delivery.
Speaker 1: We're talking about the ones where you don't a hundred percent get to pick.
Speaker 1: They're like a subscription very similar to those boxes of here's some clothes.
Speaker 1: Try the ones you want mail back the ones you don't want to keep.
Speaker 0: Well, I mean we spent a lot of time in this show berating rightly So various subscription boxes like the loot crate.
Speaker 0: the thing with the loot crate Here's some garbage.
Speaker 0: right.
Speaker 0: loot crate is we'll send you a box of mystery shit.
Speaker 0: You don't even know what you're buying your plate.
Speaker 1: I mean I solve the mystery.
Speaker 1: This is the stuff we literally couldn't sell for any amount of money and we're just trying to get it away Mailing it to getting you to buy it from us is way better than just throwing it in our dumpster that we actually have to Pay for
Speaker 0: and we can also charge people on both ends.
Speaker 0: They'll pay to put advertisements in our box.
Speaker 1: They're basically turning you into a dumpster that pays for garbage to be put into it.
Speaker 0: Yeah But the food boxes are a bit different right because a it's never a mystery.
Speaker 0: What's in there, right?
Speaker 0: B they're not dumping like the leftover food.
Speaker 0: They couldn't sell right like sort of Unsuspectingly.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right is like you're just buying food.
Speaker 0: We're like different channels.
Speaker 1: is food that like couldn't be sold?
Speaker 1: but that's what I signed up for.
Speaker 0: Send me the ugly tomatoes yeah, and The other thing is you the way those sites every single one of them I've used and I've used a few is Set up in such a way where they let you know well in advance Exactly what you're getting.
Speaker 0: you have a even though you don't have a complete freedom of choice, you know There's limitations.
Speaker 0: you do make choices of what you're gonna get and if you don't like the choices or if you have Some reason that you don't want a box even though it's a subscription you can it comes with.
Speaker 0: are you all weekly?
Speaker 0: You can just pick to skip any week you want, right?
Speaker 0: You can just like, you know I'm gonna skip 20 weeks in a row or you can just cancel it in any time Like I've clicked the cancel button.
Speaker 0: It just works immediately.
Speaker 0: It's like okay canceled.
Speaker 0: if you log back into our site We'll turn it back on right and every single one of them is is basically the same in that regard.
Speaker 0: I've never seen one that does it differently.
Speaker 0: Yep, so they're not fooling you.
Speaker 0: They're not tricking you into buying some garbage, right?
Speaker 0: They're just selling you food that you need regularly, which is something you need regularly.
Speaker 0: It's food.
Speaker 0: And they solve some problems for people that the grocery store does not solve Especially people who live in cities have small apartments don't have giant pantries Right don't have cars.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right.
Speaker 0: the or don't live with a lot of people with a big family, right?
Speaker 0: So the problems that they solve is the biggest one at least for me is food waste.
Speaker 0: If I want to make a recipe and that recipe involves say Swiss chard, right?
Speaker 0: I go to the grocery store.
Speaker 0: They got Swiss chard there.
Speaker 0: It's pretty nice.
Speaker 0: But there's a minimum amount you can buy.
Speaker 0: I can't buy like one leaf.
Speaker 0: Yep, right.
Speaker 0: I got to buy a bundle but then I get home and I'm making a recipe for one or two people and I use like two leafs and Unless I cook that same recipe several times which you know who wants to do that?
Speaker 0: or find like ten recipes that all use Swiss Chard and get sick of it, right?
Speaker 0: I just bought a whole bundle of chard even if the price was cheap and I'm gonna some of its gonna go bad and get Thrown out.
Speaker 0: there's like no avoiding it because I don't have a big family to eat a whole bundle, right?
Speaker 0: So when you order from these boxes, it's like, okay We're gonna send you a meal all prepared with the exact ingredients for that meal And if that meal needs one leaf in the box is one leaf.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's it Right, no food waste which is if it feels really good to not have food waste.
Speaker 0: The second thing they solve for you is meal planning which is like work, right?
Speaker 0: It's like let's say I was gonna go to the grocery and cook.
Speaker 0: I got to figure out what I'm gonna cook.
Speaker 0: I got to spend time planning.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well, there's two ways to go there either I have to plan and to go through this hassle like you're talking about which You know, I'm busy like I even during the quarantine.
Speaker 1: I don't have a lot of free time actually.
Speaker 0: But yeah It's like if we're talking about old shitty pre feminist society where there's like a person who stays home and that is their job.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right, then you can accomplish that.
Speaker 0: But if you're talking about a modern, you know egalitarian not shitty society, right?
Speaker 0: Well, I guess it's shitty that everyone has to work right?
Speaker 1: But yeah, but that's that's a different problem to solve, right?
Speaker 0: Regardless the point is nobody's at your house Spending all day meal planning as their job, right?
Speaker 0: So everyone's going to work or school or doing something productive that they want to do And no one wants to do the work of staying alive.
Speaker 0: So You pay them to do it for you.
Speaker 0: They think they say hey, here's some meals.
Speaker 0: We've planned them We provide you with the recipe and the exact ingredients.
Speaker 0: You don't have to go to the grocery store and figure out what to get or anything like that.
Speaker 1: Now being a better cook means you can buy groceries with less planning and still make good meals But one a lot of people like honestly do not have the time in their lives to learn to be a good cook.
Speaker 1: Like.
Speaker 1: that's a thing like we can't pretend that everyone has the time to become good cooks Like we have.
Speaker 1: I think I'm a pretty good cook at this point, but to If I do that and I know because I've seen this happen in my life like when we lived in Beacon or like during time periods in our lives when we were busy like really busy here like a Lot of cons if I don't plan meals and I do grocery shopping I can make a whole bunch of meals But I tend to default to a pretty narrow set of the kinds of meals that I am very comfortable making That I know intuitively that I don't need recipes for from a limited set of ingredients.
Speaker 1: So I don't tend to expand my horizons.
Speaker 1: I tend to make a lot of pastas and chilies and things like that.
Speaker 1: I don't tend to make something new.
Speaker 1: I don't try a new recipe.
Speaker 1: I just make something that I know is easy to make.
Speaker 1: So but what that leads to is that pre-covid because once the quarantine happened I have a lot of additional reasons that I'm using these food boxes.
Speaker 1: We're subscribed to way more now than we ever were but Blue apron was the one that I did first and what I found was that it almost served like a Cooking class in that as these recipes came in that like there'd be a lot of certain techniques that I would learn like how to cook a certain kind of spice a certain way Or like how to deal with a certain kind of vegetable that isn't like within your normal comfort zone.
Speaker 0: Every time that vegetable would show up in a box you deal with it pretty much the same way usually Yeah, and it's like oh well now I know how to cook that vegetable.
Speaker 1: Like I know how to make a Beckmell sauce.
Speaker 1: I don't need to like look up a recipe for that.
Speaker 1: or if I'm making a Complicated recipe that involves it kind of like we talk about with board games.
Speaker 1: if you learn how to play Yahtzee And you learn how to play Dominion learn how to play all these like sub games that are really complicated.
Speaker 1: game becomes much simpler These by following these recipes over time.
Speaker 1: It forced me to become a much better cook and I know how to cook a lot of things without looking at recipes.
Speaker 1: So I can look at a really complicated recipe now and I can just glaze over all the easy stuff like okay Make a sauce.
Speaker 1: Okay deal with it that and only focus on the unique part of the recipe or the construction of the final meal.
Speaker 1: Mmm, and that was anyway.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so the boxes are pretty good for all those reasons.
Speaker 0: the ways that they are bad is that they are expensive, right?
Speaker 0: You're losing money versus.
Speaker 1: yeah, this is way more expensive than buying all these things in a grocery store With the caveat that.
Speaker 1: the caveat though is if you buy all these things in a grocery store You're gonna throw a lot of it away.
Speaker 0: Anyway, right you would be going to.
Speaker 0: most of them are about $20 for a meal that feeds two people with two servings.
Speaker 0: So it's about ten dollars a serving for pretty much all the boxes from all the different companies.
Speaker 0: There's some differences in there, but it's generally ten dollars a serving.
Speaker 0: So that's like sort of.
Speaker 0: it's not quite go.
Speaker 0: It depends.
Speaker 1: It's a better deal for people like us who live in the city where groceries are just a lot more expensive.
Speaker 0: Right, it's like for me to go out to read it.
Speaker 0: go out and eat.
Speaker 0: right would be.
Speaker 0: I'd only be able to beat $10 a serving going out to a restaurant if I got some real shitty fast food.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like the diner is still a little more than $10 a person.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, but like any food that I would go out to eat that's not fast food.
Speaker 0: It's like not McDonald's not just some fried chicken or something from the greasies place palace fried chicken Anything that's not.
Speaker 0: that is gonna cost me more than ten bucks.
Speaker 0: So I'm still saving money versus eating out because I'm in the city.
Speaker 0: But if I didn't live in the city while then eating out for less than ten bucks is a lot easier Yeah, but also just the grocery stores.
Speaker 1: like meat is more expensive here than it is upstate.
Speaker 1: But yeah, I live in a suburb.
Speaker 0: if you live in a suburb the grocery store is cheaper.
Speaker 0: even so like yogurt It's like for me to get a single little yogurt cup is like one to two dollars in the suburbs It's.
Speaker 0: it'll be like, you know five yogurt cups for like 250.
Speaker 0: It's like it's so cheap.
Speaker 0: It's like holy shit.
Speaker 0: They're less than a dollar each right?
Speaker 0: It's such a deal.
Speaker 0: So the the food boxes are the same price no matter where you live so you can save money.
Speaker 1: Possibly or you know, it makes more economic sense based on your geography Yeah, and also based on your living circumstances because like Scott pointed out Cooking for one is a real.
Speaker 1: it's kind of like a one-bedroom apartment or a studio like a one-bedroom apartment versus two-bedroom Cooking for one versus cooking for literally any number of people other than one.
Speaker 1: It's like a whole different kind of cooking and the I think it's like one to more than two.
Speaker 1: true because cooking for one Very rarely when I live by myself would I ever make a side dish?
Speaker 1: I would basically just cook one thing Right.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean like most of these sort of for example, right when sometimes you get the food boxes There'll be a meal and most of the meals are two servings.
Speaker 0: So if you're only one person you're gonna make the two servings put one in the fridge and eat it later.
Speaker 0: Yep, right If you're two people, well, you can just eat it.
Speaker 0: All right, then it's just dinner.
Speaker 0: If you're more than two people well You know now you got but then you get the bigger.
Speaker 1: like some of these food services have things like.
Speaker 1: they have options that really Are tuned to people's lifestyles like we have we.
Speaker 1: there's one I saw that did a thing like you can choose a family Meal that serves three to five and has like bigger quantities and portions and more side dishes.
Speaker 0: For example, let's say one of the meals is just like some pasta.
Speaker 0: It's like well, that's real easy to eat one and put the other one in the fridge, right?
Speaker 0: But some of them are like, oh, it's a it's a it's a steak with a side salad and some vegetable.
Speaker 0: It's like well if that's a two sir If it's two servings of steak and a salad and a vegetables like I need the second person to be here I can't really put that in the fridge.
Speaker 0: Yep, right like I'm gonna make a salad and then eat half of it and put a half a salad in the fridge and it's like It's not great, right?
Speaker 0: You really need the two people to be there to choose that as a meal.
Speaker 0: Yeah box.
Speaker 0: so if the meals choices from that You know particular company are a lot like that then it's hard to do those as a single person.
Speaker 0: you need.
Speaker 1: you need a second Yep, but to get back to a positive one thing I noticed when I was making these a lot Is that if I try to cook elaborate meals?
Speaker 1: I tend to have to juggle a lot of things in the kitchen at the same time Like if we do a big Thanksgiving dinner like friendsgiving or something Any big meal I'm juggling a lot or if I attempt something different or new even if it's just the two of us I may end up using like three burners at the same time or something.
Speaker 1: Most of these services the recipes are very much designed to need either Just one pan just one pot or one pot and one pan.
Speaker 1: Like they're designed to where no part of the recipe will interfere with any other part of the recipe.
Speaker 1: Whereas someone who's not a great cook like me a long time ago if you just try to pick like oh Here's a recipe for some pasta.
Speaker 1: Here's a recipe for like some meat.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna make these two recipes.
Speaker 1: those two recipes might both need your oven with different temperatures at the same time.
Speaker 1: They might both need a pan and you only own one good pan.
Speaker 1: like you run into these race conditions that these meals hits avoid.
Speaker 0: Yeah, all right, so let's talk about the different services.
Speaker 0: Yeah that we've tried right.
Speaker 0: so the first one I did was blue apron because that was like sort of the first one maybe.
Speaker 1: yeah We both tried that one early on.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I used it for like the longest of all of them.
Speaker 0: The things I liked about it were that you actually did quite a bit of like cooking, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, they would usually.
Speaker 0: Sometimes it was nice that they would like make you cook, but sometimes it was annoying.
Speaker 0: It's like.
Speaker 0: it's like oh great Fucking Beckmell sauce.
Speaker 1: like there's a period where it was nothing but either lemon zest or Beckmell, right?
Speaker 0: It's like it.
Speaker 0: They'd send you a lemon and make you zest it and like alright.
Speaker 0: That's good.
Speaker 0: I get some nice fresh lemon zest instead of some lemon zest in a package.
Speaker 0: right yeah, but then they'd be like okay Here's some time.
Speaker 0: pick all the leaves off the time.
Speaker 0: It's like I don't want to do that.
Speaker 0: couldn't you have sent it pre-picked, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, so it blue apron makes you work a little harder.
Speaker 0: It also you know the blue aprons.
Speaker 0: When I was alone they were sort of coming in.
Speaker 0: I get they sort of changed because I mean originally when I did it.
Speaker 1: Well, they've changed a few times, and they changed in a big way when the quarantine started.
Speaker 0: Originally they forced me to do three meals minimum and as a single person doing three making three a week.
Speaker 0: It was like this pressure.
Speaker 0: It's like another box is coming with three more meals.
Speaker 0: cook cook cook.
Speaker 0: It's like oh guys like I didn't want to cook three times a week.
Speaker 0: Sometimes I did but sometimes I only want to do two.
Speaker 1: sometimes we finish the show and then you'd go home like we've.
Speaker 1: Emily I'll be like we're gonna eat out tonight.
Speaker 1: You'd be like I got like a bunch of blue aprons.
Speaker 1: I got a deal.
Speaker 0: I have to cook them because another box is coming.
Speaker 0: the pressure is on.
Speaker 0: I don't want to skip the next one that I won't have food next week, right?
Speaker 0: But then they changed it to let me do two boxes of food And that was way better because the pressure was like eased off.
Speaker 0: But yeah blue apron is nice.
Speaker 1: in that way It looks like they have an option now like you can pick an option of.
Speaker 1: hey I have a pressure cooker and they give you recipes tuned to the fact that you have one.
Speaker 0: of course all of the services Always let you choose your allergies or your tastes like yeah, send me fish.
Speaker 0: Don't send me any meat at all.
Speaker 0: Don't send me wheat.
Speaker 0: You know you're totally good.
Speaker 0: Don't send me dairy all that stuff.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they're all pretty good about that.
Speaker 1: The thing the thing I liked, but then stopped liking about blue apron early and when we canceled it We started up again, but we can't live for a long time was that after I'd used it for a long time I started seeing a lot of repeats of the recipes, and I wasn't learning anything new.
Speaker 0: yeah They have a certain.
Speaker 0: once you've cooked blue apron recipes You should know how blue apron recipes go and then you can make.
Speaker 0: you can like if you get another blue apron recipe like.
Speaker 0: yeah I've seen this technique, but yeah, I know what's about that nowadays.
Speaker 1: I make a lot of blue apron recipes without blue apron.
Speaker 1: I just I don't even look at the old recipe card They gave me.
Speaker 1: I'm just like I'm gonna make that lemon zest pasta gnocchi.
Speaker 1: I can make a lemon zest pasta gnocchi right the fuck now and just make it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like.
Speaker 0: I know what you're gonna.
Speaker 0: Do you're gonna make me Tell me to make a fucking pecmel sauce right every time the pecmel sauce because there was a period we're like isn't it bechamel?
Speaker 1: Yeah, it is.
Speaker 1: Anyway That was a thing so we were always made fun of it.
Speaker 1: like who the lemon zest arrived?
Speaker 0: Yeah, blue aprons added a new a new thing.
Speaker 0: I've recently turned it back on and they have our meal prep option which we just turned that on - I haven't gotten it yet.
Speaker 0: But it seems like what they're gonna Do is send me enough food to make eight servings of food that I can all put away in The fridge and save and then eat over the week after like a single big cooking session.
Speaker 1: from what I can tell we tried it.
Speaker 1: It's great.
Speaker 0: They basically looks like what they do is you make a bunch of different things and then you you mix them into different Combinations to get different meals even though you've only cooked like maybe five or six different items.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right.
Speaker 0: So it's like okay you made this pasta and you made this side.
Speaker 0: Well in and you've made this meat and you've made this other side.
Speaker 0: We'll go pasta side one pasta side two meat side one meat side two And now you've got four different.
Speaker 1: now part of that seems to be with kovat and the quarantine one.
Speaker 1: There were huge supply chain disruptions for a while.
Speaker 1: Like it was dicey getting certain kinds of food.
Speaker 1: It's sort of normalized now, but that was the thing.
Speaker 1: there was like a month where like I couldn't even get fresh direct deliveries like it was hard to get food and a lot of these services Actually stopped because they couldn't get their supplies either or they were running out of certain things.
Speaker 1: So I remember Blue Apron changed their recipes to simplify them a little bit.
Speaker 1: They started to like limit the number of like available recipes They'd even have and they started to like.
Speaker 1: I think that's part of why they moved to this system Because that's the kind of thing if you have a family in particular you're stuck inside.
Speaker 1: you got to cook almost every day.
Speaker 0: Anyway, right Well one thing that's something I did notice about Blue Apron is they would always tend to include at least one Tricky ingredient in all their recipes but never two at the same time.
Speaker 0: It was you never had two things to fuck with.
Speaker 0: it almost felt like a DRM kind of thing.
Speaker 0: I was like, hey if you try to go to the grocery to make this recipe you're gonna have to get like two tablespoons of cream of tartar.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I have cream.
Speaker 1: I mean I have cream of tartar too and a lot of people don't like.
Speaker 0: they'd be like yeah two tablespoons of verjuice little do.
Speaker 0: They know.
Speaker 0: I am overloaded with the very else But it's like.
Speaker 0: it's like.
Speaker 0: yeah, you're not gonna find that in grocery stores, right?
Speaker 0: So or at least not, you know, I mean it's easier for us.
Speaker 1: But like one of them came with ghee and that was really exciting.
Speaker 1: I know a lot of people do not have easy access to ghee.
Speaker 0: He is just clarified butter pretty much Yeah, but it's like, you know, you can make it too.
Speaker 0: But the point is is that yeah a lot of people in like suburban type Non-city places who don't have or don't have a giant grocery store with like an international aisle are gonna be missing an ingredient And if they don't know that they can substitute that ingredient or whatever It's like.
Speaker 0: yeah blue apron is sending you a tiny amount exactly the amount you need.
Speaker 0: You can't use that recipe on your own and you're gonna need to get it from blue apron again Because that ingredients hard for you to get.
Speaker 0: maybe you'll buy it online.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 1: so what I think blue apron did one we're tried that we're still doing now - is a Vegan recipes and they're honestly they are fantastic recipes.
Speaker 1: I okay.
Speaker 1: We've made some really good food.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna admit something though We got it not so much because we're trying to go vegan but because that's a really easy way to have to learn cooking skills that don't involve meat because one thing I've learned about cooking is I've cooked more and more is that a Meat can well well prepared meat can cover a lot of cooking mistakes in the other Aspects of a meal in a way that when you're cooking like a purely vegan recipe You really can't fuck anything up or it'll taste weird and it forces you to get better.
Speaker 1: But - it was a just an easy way to cut down our meat consumption.
Speaker 1: Like yeah, if we got some blue aprons like a two blue aprons and two purple carrots coming every week Guess what?
Speaker 1: We're gonna cook it.
Speaker 1: We're gonna eat half as much meat as we normally do.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So that's that's all you guys have our full carrot.
Speaker 1: Oh, it's.
Speaker 1: I mean, it's really good.
Speaker 1: But the one thing I will admit is that as I've been cooking those recipes increasingly I Will substitute the vegan butter the vegan mayonnaise all the like the vegan cheese For real cheese and real butter.
Speaker 0: because so what do you do with all the cheese and butter?
Speaker 1: They send you because that stuff tends to last forever.
Speaker 1: We keep it in the fridge usually and we'll use it in another recipe later or keep it as like an emergency supply Like here's the man.
Speaker 1: Here's some margarine.
Speaker 1: That'll never go bad, but I'm not gonna use it unless I'm forced to.
Speaker 1: Okay, but so the problem is the recipes taste a Thousand times better if you just substitute butter in for that vegan margarine.
Speaker 0: Like yeah, well, you're still not eating the meat.
Speaker 1: is the exactly like I made some vegan?
Speaker 0: It's not like.
Speaker 0: you know, all the other services do have vegetarian options.
Speaker 0: vegan up They all do.
Speaker 1: but like purple carrot is like particularly good.
Speaker 1: like the recipes are great.
Speaker 1: Like I made some vegan burgers the other day where I made the patties myself like shred some beets cook some rice Mush it all together in a blender.
Speaker 1: They were really good.
Speaker 1: but what they did not warn me about was that all the ways to make vegan burger patties are Extremely difficult to deal with in the kitchen and make a gigantic mess.
Speaker 0: Okay Another one we tried was home chef.
Speaker 0: Oh We tried home chef.
Speaker 0: we did it for quite a while after I Basically right after PAX East we signed up for it and then I cancelled it just like so like right as the quarantine was happening Right.
Speaker 0: It's like I didn't even.
Speaker 0: it wasn't even because of the quarantine.
Speaker 0: It was like hey after PAX East we're gonna be home and not have a schedule.
Speaker 0: Let's go get food boxes again.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: We'll try this one.
Speaker 0: We'll see how it goes.
Speaker 0: Oh, let's hold on to this.
Speaker 0: We signed up with a good timing home.
Speaker 0: Chef was Kind of like a little more sad than boo aprons.
Speaker 0: Some of the meals did taste really good But you were cooking a lot less for example one time.
Speaker 1: I tried a bunch of servers I don't remember the names where that's exactly what I was about to say.
Speaker 1: So we're you're heading me off here.
Speaker 0: Yeah, a lot of the ones they would send would be like oven ready And it was basically a tray with food in it and you would do some stuff and just put it in the oven take it Out and eat it, right?
Speaker 0: It's like yeah, that feels like TV dinner one time.
Speaker 0: They sent me one.
Speaker 0: I was this is the one I was most upset about is the one where they sent rice and Rather than blue apron they send you rice in a bag and they say make rice and I just put it my rice cooker.
Speaker 0: Yep, they sent this pre-cooked rice.
Speaker 1: That was like parboiled rice.
Speaker 0: you yeah It's like it was just like put it in a bowl with some water and microwave it and I was like, uh, I Just I didn't even make that.
Speaker 0: I just made rice.
Speaker 0: Like.
Speaker 0: that's awful.
Speaker 1: I feel like you know what?
Speaker 1: I've noticed some of these are Clearly aimed at people who live in like urban environments and some of these are definitely aimed at the suburbs.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the food was a little more bland didn't have those exciting ingredients that blue apron would send it that you couldn't get yourself.
Speaker 0: Sometimes the ingredient quality was a little low like they would send me a sad scallion and I would use my own scallion Right and throw their scallion away.
Speaker 0: but some of the resumes in there were pretty good and what you would do?
Speaker 0: there were a lot more choices than blue apron during the meal choosing part and What we just had to do is make sure that when we were choosing meals We didn't choose the ones that said like oven ready, right or didn't choose the ones that came with sad rice.
Speaker 0: We could avoid those and we could choose the ones that made us cook and we could choose the ones that you know Looked more flavorful.
Speaker 0: Mmm.
Speaker 0: Oh, wait, they're ones that they had.
Speaker 0: that were flatbreads.
Speaker 0: Obviously the problem with those is that you need two people there to eat them.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we I'm a big fan of the flatbread ones I've gotten because there's two of us the home chef.
Speaker 0: flatbreads were all like way good ones.
Speaker 0: I was into those.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like you cuz blue apron.
Speaker 0: I was like in flatbreads, but no the home chef flatbread ones were were quite good Like.
Speaker 0: I would just make those again like buy some.
Speaker 1: so all the other things we tried were have basically I have the same complaints Almost word-for-word that you just said.
Speaker 1: so assume a lot of the low-tier ones.
Speaker 1: It was kind of like that.
Speaker 1: one thing I noticed though across all of them even the blue apron and then I like the nice ones.
Speaker 1: I have not seen any of them have anything spicy and The like.
Speaker 1: it's the point of them all.
Speaker 0: blue apron always says like add as much of the red pepper As much of the hot sauce as you want and I would always add all of it and it was never a problem.
Speaker 1: I got I one time like they were like add as much of the red pepper as you want, but be careful It'll make it spicy.
Speaker 1: and they gave me this packet that had like 11 flakes of red pepper in it.
Speaker 0: yep, like it mattered but it wasn't spicy.
Speaker 1: but like Is it just that the kinds of people who buy these food boxes are so white that they can't handle like any amount of spice?
Speaker 1: Is this like pretty sure one of the Midwest pulling the one red pepper flake out with a tweezer?
Speaker 0: I'm confident that the customer base for these food boxes is almost entirely white.
Speaker 0: Yeah, because non white people don't need someone to tell them how to cook.
Speaker 0: they have, you know a culture of cooking, right?
Speaker 1: These are definitely aimed at a yuppie like urban demographic or like a particular kind of suburban demographic.
Speaker 0: And even though you know, I may be white but I'm a Jew and I have a culture of cooking in my family.
Speaker 0: Right the Jewish food that we cook, you know, the Jew meals of my family are meals for holidays and things, right?
Speaker 0: We don't have you know, the Jewish food to cook for every day, right?
Speaker 0: You know, it's it's like oh, there's a holiday All right.
Speaker 0: now the Jewish food comes out the chicken soups into the cookals and the breads.
Speaker 0: and but it's definitely like.
Speaker 1: a Common theme in all those food boxes is they will include spicy ingredients with a lot of warnings.
Speaker 1: But those spicy ingredients are not spicy like it was a we're talking less than the fire Salsa from a Taco Bell.
Speaker 0: It was either a home chef or a Sun basket Which is one that we've done recently that had a jalapeno in it the other one whole jalapeno.
Speaker 1: Lord Someone's gonna die.
Speaker 0: It's a hold on.
Speaker 0: so I cut up the hollow, you know It had all these warnings like, you know, clean your cutting board after you cut up the jalapeno.
Speaker 1: Oh When I clean board after I cut up like a habanero maybe so.
Speaker 0: so I Ignored that.
Speaker 0: I just cut the jalapeno and put it right and it was something really funny happened.
Speaker 0: Is that somehow the food wasn't spicy?
Speaker 0: obviously, right?
Speaker 0: The jalapeno wasn't spicy.
Speaker 0: Yeah somehow Like the capsaicin from the jalapeno must have getting concentrated somewhere Even though I wash my hands.
Speaker 0: It must have gotten like I think was under my fingernail or something and then I poked myself in the eye.
Speaker 1: somehow I've done that.
Speaker 1: I've done that.
Speaker 1: you know what gets me when I clean the seeds out of a pepper.
Speaker 1: Sometimes I'll just use my thumb like I'll pull it to pull them out with my thumb.
Speaker 0: It must have been something like that I've learned.
Speaker 1: I forced myself to do it with the spoon no matter what even though I want to do it with.
Speaker 0: the point is It wasn't spicy at all.
Speaker 0: Nothing was spicy.
Speaker 0: The only spice problem was me poking myself with spice in the eye, but see this is what we're talking about.
Speaker 1: They warn you to clean your cutting board cutting up a jalapeno like really that's the pepper you're afraid of.
Speaker 0: yep But yeah, the Sun basket is uh It's okay, right?
Speaker 0: I think the Some of the food from it was was kind of tasty.
Speaker 0: It makes you cook a little more.
Speaker 0: one of them actually made me cook too much, right?
Speaker 0: It was like I had to have like two pots and the oven going at the same time and that was like I wasn't happy About that.
Speaker 0: I was like, this is too much cooking.
Speaker 1: Yeah That's the cooking I do on a special occasion that's not the cooking I do on a Tuesday, right exactly?
Speaker 0: So that was kind of annoying.
Speaker 0: Quality was you know?
Speaker 1: I guess the last one I'll talk about is And we did this partly because you know Like I said, I couldn't get fresh direct deliveries for like a month when this whole thing started like it was hard to get groceries.
Speaker 1: But we were doing the misfits market which isn't food kits so much as we will send you a variety of Vegetables and fruits and things that are either damaged or difficult to sell in a grocery store because they're shaped weird or whatever and they're real cheap and We've just been using it as like.
Speaker 1: We get a whole bunch of vegetables and stuff every week and it supplements our food intake because we got to cook every goddamn day During kovat.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: I don't want to go out to grocery stores if I can avoid it.
Speaker 1: Fresh direct sells out of things like because there's supply chain issues.
Speaker 1: So we've diversified our ways to get food into our house And this was a good way to get a lot of vegetables that are perfectly fine for not a lot of money Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: I just always the thing with something like that is I always worry about the food waste and also the pressure.
Speaker 0: It's like okay.
Speaker 0: Here's what your random vegetables now.
Speaker 0: You got to cook with them.
Speaker 1: Go go to a degree like they show like here's the things that are available.
Speaker 1: You kind of look like I want some of those and some of those some of those.
Speaker 1: The good things just tend to disappear real quick.
Speaker 1: Like you got to jump on the site early.
Speaker 1: But the only thing that's been too much is and other people who have this service have pointed out the same thing We end up having a lot of beets and a lot of squash hanging around because those are the things we don't use right away.
Speaker 1: Yep, but those are also things that kind of last forever Like they're really bad.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So one last thing I want to talk about is, you know fresh direct We said is not a meal kit situation, right?
Speaker 0: It's a it's just grocery store online.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right and then they deliver the groceries that you pick specifically.
Speaker 0: It's like it's the same as going to the grocery store or Amazon.
Speaker 0: fresh same thing.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like it's it's my grocery store.
Speaker 1: I don't go to grocery stores.
Speaker 0: I go to fresh exactly what you want and they give you exactly what you want.
Speaker 0: But fresh direct does offer a meal kit that you can choose to buy.
Speaker 0: so we did buy one of those.
Speaker 0: It was like a chicken broccoli thing.
Speaker 0: I think yep, and I got to say it was the saddest I've heard that from other people.
Speaker 1: They're basically like they're the kind there's those.
Speaker 1: they're those pseudo TV dinners that like grocery stores sell in the suburbs.
Speaker 0: sometimes it was literally.
Speaker 0: I open up this box and inside is like a broccoli a Chicken and a rice and a sauce.
Speaker 0: Wow, and it's just like.
Speaker 0: I don't need to look at the instructions, but that's way sad.
Speaker 0: yeah, it's like way better like you open up, but if you open up a Blue apron.
Speaker 0: that was for chicken and broccoli, right?
Speaker 0: You would see a broccoli and a chicken, right?
Speaker 0: But you would not see a sauce in there to apply, right?
Speaker 1: Oh, you would see like here's some spices and things.
Speaker 1: you would see.
Speaker 0: you would see several ingredients with which to make the sauce Right together, right.
Speaker 0: and you would also see like, you know more stuff to put in there besides just broccoli rice chicken.
Speaker 0: There would be like other.
Speaker 0: it'd be like some peppery stuff some peppers to put in there Maybe like, you know some water chestnut.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they'll be like, you know, it would be more busy Right and more varied contrasting tastes.
Speaker 1: not so plain and sad Yeah I find with a place like fresh direct like the sweet spot for they'd also.
Speaker 0: they probably have you roast that broccoli and then put It in as opposed to just like steam the broccoli and make it real sad.
Speaker 1: steam broccoli is usually pretty sad Yeah, but like the middle ground.
Speaker 1: there is the thing about like a place like fresh direct.
Speaker 1: That's good is not those kids?
Speaker 1: because those kids are just those kids are the pits But they do have a lot of prepared food Like if I want to do a marinated pork chop or something like marinated meats and things like that.
Speaker 1: I can buy them in bags with their marinade like already done and just ready for your grocery store.
Speaker 0: has that exactly?
Speaker 1: it's the kind of thing a regular grocery store does.
Speaker 1: I Feel like that is a better option than getting a meal kit from most grocery stores.
Speaker 0: Sure, but yeah.
Speaker 0: So I guess the the final thing is you know If you are someone who doesn't live with a big Family where you can go to the grocery store load up on large quantities and eat it all Yeah, or you have a busy life and you don't can't spend time meal planning or you you have few people You don't want to do food waste
Speaker 1: Yeah, or honestly if you
Speaker 0: like you like cooking you have the time to cook at least a quick 20 minute 30 minute meal.
Speaker 0: You just don't want to do it necessarily every day.
Speaker 1: if you think you're a bad cook and you want to learn to get better You can almost treat it like a cooking class.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and you have the money to afford one of these things, right?
Speaker 0: Then I would highly recommend You know picking one of the.
Speaker 0: you know Try different ones because you can cancel them and skip them and all very easily get one box free.
Speaker 0: There's a lot of free sample boxes.
Speaker 0: You can get discount boxes.
Speaker 1: Oh if it's your first box Dude, you know how many of our friends we'd pass around like the code.
Speaker 1: like one of us tries the service The service gives us like here's codes to give ten of your friends a free trial.
Speaker 0: if you want any codes I have codes for tons of these things.
Speaker 0: I can send you one probably.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we just kept passed them around and everyone did like one.
Speaker 1: one free week of a box from a random service.
Speaker 0: Yeah, just try all of them.
Speaker 0: See if any of them work for you.
Speaker 0: if they don't okay cancel them and that's it.
Speaker 0: But yeah, they are.
Speaker 0: They might be good for you.
Speaker 0: They might help your life.
Speaker 0: They might increase, you know reduce your food waste and help you eat better and cook better possibly for a small fee.
Speaker 1: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at front row crew comm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 1: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 0: But unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night And the patreon patrons for this episode of geek nights are Alan Joyce, how do you mean it'll nickel a mardi grédia?
Speaker 1: Just like a dude guys are davish and Graham Finch.
Speaker 1: You hold the key to my heart.
Speaker 1: She gave me a kiss and she gave me my ticket.
Speaker 1: Clinton Walton J Bats friend from New Zealand Ryan Perrin Nicholas Brannagh Chris Mink if the thirst for hydrated Gannon dread lily tenebrae Chris Reimer Finn Sean Klein Shervin von Harl and a bunch of people who don't want me to say their names.
Speaker 1: long weekend We actually did a show today, I'm surprised.
Speaker 1: usually we tend to bail right before holiday, but not like we can go anywhere.
Speaker 1: but anyway We are live streaming the show again as you may have seen and I now leave you with an outtake from the very beginning of that stream.
Speaker 1: we just started to turn the show on.
Speaker 1: we were just about to record and Scott realized that his volume was way too low.
Speaker 1: He's got as a problem.
Speaker 1: There's a little preamplifier that Scott has at home with his rig and he just fucks with it.
Speaker 1: He just like if he's sitting near it He'll just fuck with it and move the volume slider around even though he denies that he does this.
Speaker 1: so uh Here's now take and see you guys next week.
Speaker 1: What did you do?
Speaker 1: Did you fiddle with the knob?
Speaker 1: I think you fiddled with the knob.
Speaker 1: we you caught yourself telling with the knob No, I accidentally fiddle.
Speaker 0: I Unconsciously fiddled with it before but I haven't touched it since you know the last episode.
Speaker 1: I am not confident that you have not touched it since then.
Speaker 0: It's like way back on the desk or it's why did you fiddle with it the other day?
Speaker 0: Well, I was just.
Speaker 1: you know Maybe in your sleep what I noticed.
Speaker 0: I noticed that I did it.
Speaker 0: How would I do it without noticing?
Speaker 1: I think you might have sleep fiddled like narrow.
Speaker 1: You just get up in the night.
Speaker 1: You wander over there You fiddle with it on night and then you go back to sleep.
Speaker 0: Should I put a piece of tape leg on it?
Speaker 1: I used to do that on the mixer.
Speaker 1: I actually taped the Pre-faders in the positions I'd calibrated them to for all our different microphones.
Speaker 0: I moved it like a millimeter.
Speaker 0: What did I move it in the wrong direction?
Speaker 0: Yeah Yeah, you got quieter.
Speaker 1: As long as it doesn't clip in your audition That sounded too loud.
Speaker 0: Yeah, obviously that's too loud.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I started streaming so the listener Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: All right, whatever it's it's it's good enough.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think we're good.
Speaker 1: Oh, wow, there's like four people watching.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: Wow, so many people.
Speaker 0: whoa four four Such a big number.
Speaker 0: Oh my god.
Speaker 1: It's more than zero.
Speaker 0: You're gonna become a YouTube partner with those big numbers and the single digits.
Speaker 1: I mean, I have more subscribers than dr.
Speaker 1: Disrespect All right, I think we're good to go.
Speaker 1: It's Thursday, July 2nd 2020.
Speaker 1: I'm rim.
Speaker 1: I'm Scott and this is geek nights tonight.