Speaker 0: It's Thursday January 30th 2020.
Speaker 0: I'm rim I'm Scott and this is geek nights.
Speaker 0: tonight We talk about getting rid of stuff, which is way harder than you think it is.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: So the weather's been a bit weird and I haven't actually gotten to ski this season until last weekend Which was bugging me to see while you can because eventually there won't be any more skiing anywhere.
Speaker 1: Yep, I guess you could ski on like Mountain big bars.
Speaker 0: Yeah Mount Olympus I'll just have to move further and further north as the world goes to shit.
Speaker 1: Is it north to Mars?
Speaker 0: But So it is finally cold enough.
Speaker 0: Like I'm gonna get some real skiing in the next several weekends I'm gonna try to ski every single weekend until I go to Japan on that trip assuming coronavirus doesn't prevent my trip to Japan Is?
Speaker 1: it is a. you know, not that I would ever ski right but is on Super Bowl Sunday.
Speaker 1: Is there more or less?
Speaker 0: It's the best fucking day.
Speaker 0: There's no ski.
Speaker 0: There's no.
Speaker 0: you go to a ski mountain.
Speaker 1: I think there are a lot of people would be like hey, we could like ski and yeah I just at like, you know five o'clock come into the lodge.
Speaker 0: Yeah They do but here's the thing.
Speaker 0: Those people they those are the kinds of people who tend to only ski a little bit.
Speaker 0: Anyway, like they go to the mountain they pay they're like hundred bucks for a ticket.
Speaker 0: They ski like four times and then they're done and then they sit in the bar and then they go out to Super Bowl.
Speaker 0: If you go ski, I'm so but the lodge is crazy busy.
Speaker 0: Yep Okay So if you go to scan Super Bowl weekend The only people actually skiing are people who care a lot about skiing and don't care that much about the Super Bowl.
Speaker 1: Oh, that's next week.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: Actually, it's in right Thursday, right?
Speaker 1: It's three days.
Speaker 0: So this week This weekend it is not next week.
Speaker 0: It isn't three days or next week.
Speaker 1: It is the next weekend.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: So, uh, I'm No, it is actually this weekend on next weekend This this week next one the one that's coming up next.
Speaker 0: Yeah this one.
Speaker 0: Yeah next one Yeah, so Scott if I say this Tuesday this Thursday, we're gonna do something.
Speaker 1: That's not today.
Speaker 0: All right, if I say this Friday, what day when does the thing happen?
Speaker 1: tomorrow?
Speaker 0: what if I say next Friday as tomorrow?
Speaker 0: also if I say next Friday today on Thursday, you literally would uh, Obstinately pretend that I meant tomorrow as opposed to the next Thursday like literally every English speaker would believe.
Speaker 1: there are lots of Inconsistencies in the English language.
Speaker 1: just because it is inconsistent doesn't mean it's wrong.
Speaker 1: flammable is in flammable.
Speaker 1: What's a country?
Speaker 0: but that's actually extremely consistent.
Speaker 1: No, it's not.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so, uh, you said you had some news but you said before the show that your news is all news.
Speaker 1: It is all news.
Speaker 0: So my my my supposition based on this cuz I don't know what you're about to say, I have no idea.
Speaker 0: Okay, but my guess is that I can sum up your summation of the news with a song.
Speaker 0: I don't you've ever heard this song.
Speaker 0: Have you ever heard the song called?
Speaker 0: Everybody knows shit's fucked.
Speaker 0: Well, I see even Paul Tyler.
Speaker 0: I mean you're close because the songs are Everybody knows shit's fucked.
Speaker 0: I don't give a good goddamn.
Speaker 0: Your uncle Sam is a motherfucker.
Speaker 0: fuck human beings fuck humanity.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there's a lot of songs like that.
Speaker 1: Yeah you can listen to Rage Against the Machine.
Speaker 0: you can listen to monster by Steppenwolf 60s and that song is 90% still true, you know I wish I'd read Steppenwolf without when I was younger as opposed to reading it as a geek night's book.
Speaker 1: You can read it again.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I already read it.
Speaker 0: I know it's deal but I Thought that book was about different things.
Speaker 1: Yeah I didn't know anything what it was about.
Speaker 1: I only knew Steppenwolf the band and I know that there was a book called Steppenwolf and I didn't know what relation there was between the two if any.
Speaker 0: yeah But I wish I'd known that when I was younger.
Speaker 1: Anyway now I know everything cuz I've been in it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the point is right.
Speaker 1: Yeah We've had this.
Speaker 1: everyone knows shit's fucked feeling for what like 15 to 20 years now mostly since December 2016.
Speaker 1: I mean that's you know more so right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, but I feel as if like January 2020 specifically Right, we are crossing a boundary.
Speaker 1: Yeah of fucking this.
Speaker 0: know we're crossing a boundary into like for one like not to harp on the whole Trump thing.
Speaker 0: But that feels like it made time slow down and I've been paying like.
Speaker 0: I already pay a lot of attention.
Speaker 0: Most people don't pay a lot of attention.
Speaker 0: Some people do.
Speaker 0: I pay you and I like we pay a lot But I'm paying even more attention and it's making time slow down and the more it slows down The more fucked up things I see in the matter I get and then I pay attention even more.
Speaker 1: But there's like an old saying like oh you couldn't you know, the life is stranger than fiction.
Speaker 1: you couldn't write this, right?
Speaker 1: I mean, but actually but life right now, right?
Speaker 1: Literally, I'd say you couldn't write this but actually we did write this.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but like me in the onion and in like that movie strange days are like every William Gibson novel.
Speaker 1: All right, let's list the things Right.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 1: It's like for the past 15 years.
Speaker 1: There's been general overhead of Fuck it miss.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know things like climate change We're just still around and still a problem right sort of like this background of yeah shit is bad But we are now in this month specifically have added all those things are still there right, but we have added this other layer of Relatively somewhat immediate fuck it
Speaker 0: miss.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Well, that's right.
Speaker 0: well, I think what it is is that multiple areas not just one area, but multiple areas have hit a Threshold like a crisis point whereby Depending on the results of things that will happen in our foreseeable future.
Speaker 1: There are radically different futures All right, so we have all sorts of presidential situations like right now.
Speaker 0: There's an impeachment.
Speaker 0: I'll have impeachment and election but we have a it's a scam impeachment trial We have.
Speaker 0: our government is literally trying to cover up crimes the president committed like that's not a joke Cartoonishly Corrupt people like they're from a movie, right?
Speaker 1: So you got that.
Speaker 1: all that going on if less in other countries to like breaks it is actually kind of real.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like it happened the EU said fine.
Speaker 0: Fuck it.
Speaker 0: Just fucking over with right.
Speaker 1: So that's so.
Speaker 1: if you're writing a novel from you're writing this cyberpunk novel from an American's perspective Like that's like a background thing happening.
Speaker 1: That'll come in later.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right.
Speaker 1: Okay, so then there's a horrible pandemic.
Speaker 1: That is a the World Health Organization said today.
Speaker 1: it is like a global public health emergency Right.
Speaker 1: That's not a thing that happened in my life.
Speaker 1: Maybe not handful of times I mean if ever ours happens.
Speaker 0: ours Was like the swine flu.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like that's there Flu being like a like lip specifically a global emergency though It wasn't.
Speaker 0: it wasn't as much of an emergency as coronavirus and SARS.
Speaker 0: right there have been margberg outbreaks and Ebola outbreaks There have been but this this one's moving pretty quick.
Speaker 1: Right?
Speaker 1: Anyway, so that's happening.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right I don't really have anything to say about it.
Speaker 0: Well, like here's just one example.
Speaker 0: You're probably even thinking of Because of our politics is so fucked up.
Speaker 0: Virginia actually became a democratic state like Democrats now control all the chambers of that state.
Speaker 0: So what did they do?
Speaker 0: they passed some?
Speaker 0: Extremely incremental minor gun control reform bills and Armed fascist militias literally marched on the Capitol and threatened civil war like that happened and it was only a footnote in the news.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's not a big enough news to qualify Literal brown shirts armed with AR like that's a tiny news.
Speaker 0: Yeah in 2020.
Speaker 0: Okay, that barely makes the news All right, so we have let's go Fire.
Speaker 0: there's a state legislature Legislator.
Speaker 1: keep focusing on too many government news.
Speaker 1: is I've already gone past all these government news.
Speaker 0: He's a literal terrorist.
Speaker 1: Yeah, whatever still in office.
Speaker 1: Let's take him out.
Speaker 1: Yeah, your news is our way tiny compared to the giant news.
Speaker 1: is Australia is literally on fire still probably I imagine.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 1: What else is a giant news right now?
Speaker 1: Oh, I mean, I guess it's it's not really of Significance word, you know the liberation of Hong Kong or the subjugation of Hong Kong, which is that that's not over not over.
Speaker 0: It's just not in the news anymore.
Speaker 0: This is the West right.
Speaker 1: not a significant thing in terms of the actual consequences of the event But in terms of the news worthiness right is like Kobe Bryant and his helicopter exploding.
Speaker 1: Yeah, got nothing to say about it, but it's still the kind of thing that in a cyberpunk novel.
Speaker 1: what happened, right?
Speaker 1: What else is going on?
Speaker 1: the Super Bowl is Sunday, oh who even cares?
Speaker 0: I Forgot when the super like.
Speaker 0: I didn't remember the Super Bowl existed.
Speaker 0: the last Super Bowl was a thousand years ago.
Speaker 1: The Tokyo Olympics are this year.
Speaker 0: There's Olympics.
Speaker 0: Yes I feel like I just saw some Olympics which are only significant because Akira exists.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right What is like there?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I can't even even remember all of the ridiculous things.
Speaker 0: So let's just back up a little bit.
Speaker 0: Don't forget that Russia just fucking like invaded Crimea and took it over.
Speaker 0: No one did anything about.
Speaker 1: that was a while ago.
Speaker 0: Yeah in a thousand and ten years ago that talking about things that are news like like this week.
Speaker 0: Yes Still ongoing.
Speaker 1: now sure There's just you know, the amount of insane More immediate things.
Speaker 0: Paul Paul and storm like got arrested protesting the fake impeachment trial in Washington like yesterday.
Speaker 0: Okay, whatever yeah, like there's people like in the Capitol like daily getting arrested protesting this now That started yesterday.
Speaker 0: that seems like you're only reading government news is now I'm just bringing those up because you didn't mention them.
Speaker 1: Government news is.
Speaker 1: those are small news.
Speaker 0: Yeah But the government news is aren't that small?
Speaker 0: because the government news is all lead to a global rise of fascism that threatens the very Fabric of human society.
Speaker 1: I think you're focusing too much on that.
Speaker 0: well, we don't defeat fascism.
Speaker 0: we can't even start looking at climate change and Climate change is the cause a lot of those other problems.
Speaker 0: We can't even look at global Catastrophes if we can't even get our own fucking house in order here.
Speaker 1: Look you're focused too much on where you are.
Speaker 1: I'm talking about like world news level shit.
Speaker 0: Yeah I think without the u.s.
Speaker 0: Descending into literal fascism will have a drastic consequence on the entire globe.
Speaker 1: pretty quick All right, the point is all right, right, you know focus on too many politics newses.
Speaker 1: Okay global Right news situation right with all the shit going down.
Speaker 1: It's like the the ever-present feeling of like, you know impending doom.
Speaker 1: Oh, I remember another one the The scientists with the doomsday clock.
Speaker 1: They said it was at like what it was like a minute.
Speaker 0: So they said it's like four days a clock, but they move it completely arbitrarily whenever they feel like it.
Speaker 1: it's yeah, but it's still.
Speaker 1: you know, it's still real.
Speaker 1: there's you know, the.
Speaker 0: The various arms treaties are basically going like well But again, the arms treaties are almost all collapsing specifically and solely because of Republicans in American politics.
Speaker 0: That's the only reason those arms treaties are failing.
Speaker 1: That is not the Republicans.
Speaker 1: Are you focusing so much or not?
Speaker 0: The real thing name what arms treaties like.
Speaker 1: what are you talking about?
Speaker 1: I forget the name of the nose is what the nuclear one is the landmine one.
Speaker 1: This is a lie, I don't remember the names of these things because we lost a bunch of every one article.
Speaker 1: that's like Oh, yeah, they've you know, we had this thing.
Speaker 1: That's like In this kind of place and they're basically now ignoring that.
Speaker 0: yeah all almost like literally all.
Speaker 0: But one or two of those treaty things that happened in the last few weeks were directly.
Speaker 0: the US government Just said fuck it and tore it up because we have the power to do that and no one else really does.
Speaker 1: anyway, the point is The general feeling that you always have shit is fucked.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it now like I'm almost like, you know, it is crossed the line to where it's like More than 0%.
Speaker 1: I could see for example The corona virus being like actually a zombie movie for real and society is destroyed.
Speaker 0: see but that's I don't.
Speaker 1: I don't think that's a. well I get large chance But that is my like.
Speaker 0: there is hardly magical thinking in the sense of because there are other bad things going on You and they are at a threshold crisis point.
Speaker 0: It's easy to see things that happen before under normal a similar situation two months ago if the virus came right?
Speaker 1: I would be like, you know You know, I wouldn't I wouldn't.
Speaker 1: and you said there's gonna be the pandemic that destroys the world.
Speaker 1: I'd be like, uh-huh Yeah, it's funny.
Speaker 1: Well now I only 99.99999 percent think that's funny.
Speaker 1: Uh-huh, right?
Speaker 1: Well, that is a significant move away from zero.
Speaker 0: Well thing is partly because 0.00001 is infinitely larger than zero partly Do is?
Speaker 0: I always look at this kind of news from the perspective of what could be done.
Speaker 0: Like is there something that could be done or not?
Speaker 0: Because some things you can't do anything about like if the Sun you can't do anything.
Speaker 0: Well, well you or like some local society or direct action like look at all the protests in France Which you didn't even mention.
Speaker 0: All right, uh, all I'm gonna say about that is Americans have to step up their like street action protest game.
Speaker 0: take a take a look at France.
Speaker 0: Direct action gets the good.
Speaker 1: someone brought up a really good point somewhere and that you know The people.
Speaker 0: all the earthquakes there have been some.
Speaker 0: there have been multiple terrifying earthquakes recently.
Speaker 1: I didn't hear about the earthquake.
Speaker 0: What really?
Speaker 0: Yeah, okay.
Speaker 1: That's a new one for me.
Speaker 1: but yeah That's the point This how can you do a news when basically there's just this giant pile of?
Speaker 0: you know Cloud has gotten a Significant shade darker and I think like the real takeaway from all this is that all the problems that are making the news So dire today have been simmering for many decades.
Speaker 1: as I'm saying is we were simmering and now we're boiling.
Speaker 1: Yep, not boiling over but we're boiling.
Speaker 1: but that means that boiling over used to be like yeah It's not gonna happen now.
Speaker 1: boiling over is like boiling over is.
Speaker 0: I'm not gonna just laugh it off But that that means we have to be we like the royal.
Speaker 0: we have to be ready in some circumstances like there have to be some lines that get crossed across all these various things.
Speaker 0: where Certain forms of direct action happen where jobs don't matter anymore Where you'd like protest real street protests happen something general strikes like well, you're not gonna go I'm not going to any protest if the protest has all everyone virus and gonna die.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm staying inside Protesting with my computer.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: I big for for my entire career weirdly like as a total aside like the job I've had at Every company I've worked for except the US government when I worked for the census that one time has and all my like piddly jobs in high school.
Speaker 0: and Like when I was at RIT one of my roles was part of risk assessment and one of my roles was always to document and Like maintain the things we do in the event of a global pandemic.
Speaker 0: like oddly specifically That was the thing I've been responsible for at a lot of companies.
Speaker 1: Why don't you make that your specialty instead of clock setting?
Speaker 0: Uh doesn't pay that much And I'm not responsible for it at my current job But I have to know a lot about how it would go.
Speaker 1: that is like here's a completely, you know Tangential point has nothing right but that you just reminded me of as just a general good life advice.
Speaker 1: Yeah There was this point where I was listening.
Speaker 1: lots of you know interviews with famous or not or at least significant people or people had Something in you know, yeah, right and you know people always ask the question How did how did you end up being whatever you are?
Speaker 1: that has more importance than whatever.
Speaker 1: I am just an interviewer, right?
Speaker 1: and At least half of the people the situation was basically they were doing normal life They went to school or something.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and they just ended up in a job.
Speaker 1: Right, you know, whatever their first job or something taking on a particular thing.
Speaker 1: I mean they just happened.
Speaker 1: It's like your first job and they assigned you to do this thing and then the next time someone needed someone to do that thing They were the guy or the person right.
Speaker 1: that was the expert on that thing And then now they're the globally important expert on the thing.
Speaker 0: I mean to a minor degree that happened to me with the fucking fixed protocol.
Speaker 0: I didn't.
Speaker 0: I never thought in my life.
Speaker 1: this is the thing I want to be like the dude about like I listened to an interview with the guy who managed the 9/11 victims compensation fund, right?
Speaker 1: He's like a lawyer and his job is there's a big pile of money.
Speaker 1: People are gonna come and make claims for the money because they were hurt in 9/11 and you decide how much money into and do To give it right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, and that's the job It's like.
Speaker 1: he's like.
Speaker 1: yeah There was some other fund and he was like.
Speaker 1: I was just like a lawyer out of law school and I got a sign.
Speaker 1: You know, I ended up just randomly having to manage that fund.
Speaker 1: and now I'm whenever anyone has a big compensation fund to give money Out to victims or sufferers for hurricanes or whatever.
Speaker 1: I'm like, he's like.
Speaker 1: he's Doug the guy.
Speaker 1: I forget his name.
Speaker 0: Well, you know, actually we know a lot of people are the guy of like tiny niche areas of things, right?
Speaker 1: I'm say but you know, that's so.
Speaker 1: anyone who's like, you know You hear all kinds of stories how to succeed in life or whatever bullshit, right?
Speaker 1: You know, but and people will say work hard or get lucky or it.
Speaker 1: but now the I guess it's sort of like this luck It's some because these are jobs anyone tells you about.
Speaker 0: guidance counselors aren't like.
Speaker 0: hey, this is the thing you could do But it's it's just.
Speaker 1: I think the advice is you know Get in a position where you do a thing and just become the expert on that thing and no one else is doing that thing.
Speaker 1: So now it's you.
Speaker 0: Yep, a Corollary to that.
Speaker 0: if you're in technology pick.
Speaker 0: don't pick an ancient technology But pick a technology that's past its prime but still in wide use.
Speaker 0: you will be employable forever.
Speaker 1: Right, if you look at like tech forums, you know and you'll see all the technologies people are talking about all the nerds like like rust or Dockers, you know, yeah No, no everyone's doing those things right.
Speaker 1: if you say if you're gonna get expert in Fortran, that's not gonna help you either.
Speaker 1: No, you have to do is you have to look at not the programming languages or the platforms But instead at like, you know protocols or some industry thing that you know modern and in wide use Right with protocol fixed protocol that kind of crowd.
Speaker 1: Those are you know, that's financial specifically But that's just well.
Speaker 0: capital markets account for like a third of all IT spending.
Speaker 0: so but I'm saying in other industries Yeah, like in in I'm in the music industry now, there's like CWR is a thing or you know, what logic signaling like Signaling truth at like yes and no and sending binary quote data in a verifiable way like train signal.
Speaker 1: I'm just saying get a job at a company that does a thing and do the computer stuff there And there's gonna be some protocol that you're gonna have to learn.
Speaker 1: It's like oh, yeah, our systems work on this standard or this, you know Whatever and just become the expert on that thing.
Speaker 0: and then Tracy points out for trend is still a thing.
Speaker 0: Yes, it is.
Speaker 0: I actually know some people who still have a job coding for trend is still a thing.
Speaker 1: But it's like if you like city won't become the king of fortress you sit at home like a nerd Learning for trend with your like mainframe emulator or whatever In your house, that's not really gonna get you, you know, some great position.
Speaker 1: You might be able to get a job with it.
Speaker 1: Maybe but it's not like.
Speaker 1: I don't think that's time well spent All right.
Speaker 0: Anyway, I think it's time for things of the day.
Speaker 0: what he got.
Speaker 1: so Nerds we like maps.
Speaker 1: Yeah I Remember you can always tell a good book if you open the book and the book starts with a map.
Speaker 1: prince of nothing Lord of the Rings every good book has a map in the front.
Speaker 0: I remember the first time we went to Seattle ever for the first packs we ever went to in 2008.
Speaker 0: We saw a map store and I was like, oh and we went in and there's all these stores still there.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and they're all these awesome maps.
Speaker 0: and then the next year we went back and I wanted to run this like burning wheel game about like Napoleonic era ship stuff.
Speaker 0: So I went in.
Speaker 0: I was like do you have any nautical charts?
Speaker 0: and the guy didn't have any.
Speaker 0: Cuz he mostly sells maps to.
Speaker 1: there's a giant map store.
Speaker 0: Yeah But he mostly sells like maps to tourists.
Speaker 0: But he got really excited that someone who wanted a weird map came into his store.
Speaker 0: cuz he was clearly a map nerd.
Speaker 1: Yeah, clearly you own a map store.
Speaker 1: You're a map now.
Speaker 0: He's living his dream.
Speaker 0: That's his best life.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so, you know make a lot of nerds like to draw maps.
Speaker 1: Yep, but You know, it's not so easy to get maps especially old ancient ones like if you look at like textbooks They'll be like tiny thumbnails.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you go online.
Speaker 1: You have to go to the library.
Speaker 1: You know only the fancy libraries would have some right.
Speaker 1: but here we haven't maybe the best online resource of useful nerdy maps Right.
Speaker 1: It is George the third's military maps.
Speaker 1: They uploaded a fuck ton of ultra high resolution scans of old European military maps, you're not gonna find the map I do.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you have to click it.
Speaker 1: There you go And they're there for free for you to use.
Speaker 1: No, man for your nerdy things and pretty much I clicked around it randomly.
Speaker 1: every single map that I clicked on was Amazing and would be very very useful for any kind of nerdy thing you want to do.
Speaker 1: You could pretty much take a map at random and like be like boom.
Speaker 1: This is the RPG map.
Speaker 1: Here's the town Here's the fort.
Speaker 1: Here's the right and just go with no planning.
Speaker 1: No thinking no nothing.
Speaker 1: except These are all real maps of real world.
Speaker 1: Mostly real Europe.
Speaker 1: During times of war like hundred-year war what?
Speaker 1: I don't know which wars but 30 years war.
Speaker 1: I think Europe Europe had too many wars for me to remember which ones.
Speaker 1: Definitely, you know not not in our anyone alive's lifetime, right?
Speaker 0: So speaking of the world being the part of a catastrophe.
Speaker 0: I saw a tweet going around.
Speaker 0: Am I gonna link to the tweet?
Speaker 0: I'm gonna link to the real website.
Speaker 0: But basically this Twitter account was like, oh my god, what's going on in Mali?
Speaker 0: Cuz Normal people when they travel on a country think about or know about yep So most people when they travel especially Americans don't think much about where they're going Like they do tourist research and they just go.
Speaker 0: But if you travel for business or you travel a lot or like you've lived in other places around the world Especially for American a really good thing to look at is the United States like Department of State.
Speaker 0: basically, like you trust you trust our current State Department, uh They have not messed this stuff up yet as far as I can tell.
Speaker 0: I won't try Depending on how things go over the rest of this year and early next year.
Speaker 0: I may not ever trust this website.
Speaker 1: I wonder like if you're say for example Chinese and you go to the Chinese State Department Equivalence website of where that say for a Chinese person with a Chinese passport to go It says for for work purposes at multiple companies.
Speaker 1: I've had access to independent research on this kind of travel like you know, but I want I don't want to see the independent truth.
Speaker 1: I want to know what our biases state.
Speaker 1: other countries are telling their own citizens about traveling.
Speaker 0: a lot of that It's just public.
Speaker 0: like this stuff is not right, but I can't read Chinese.
Speaker 0: Yeah, a lot of it's translated even on like Chinese websites.
Speaker 1: Okay, like for real I I don't know what website to go to like what I. I'd even know the name of the equivalent of the State Department in.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so, uh, I've learned a lot of these things mostly because I've used third-party like security firms who have given me information And that information tells me proper nouns to look forward to find even more fun things to read.
Speaker 0: But the tweet was going around.
Speaker 0: it was like, holy shit Don't go to Mali.
Speaker 0: So my thing of the day is I actually want to just link you to this really simple website where you can see for any country on earth, uh, I Don't know if the United States list itself.
Speaker 0: Actually, I've never looked for the United States on its own travel advisories But I do know that other countries List the United States as being a hazard for LGBT people, which yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah but the US Travel State Department stuff is pretty good.
Speaker 0: But the one that people were linking to was Mali and I read these things a lot.
Speaker 0: I've been to countries up to a level two like don't go here warning I have not been to a level three country But I have been.
Speaker 0: I've driven through on one occasion a zone that was designated as a level three Within a level two country and I had to have security with me.
Speaker 0: that was in Brazil a long time ago.
Speaker 0: But anyway, so there aren't many countries on the level four.
Speaker 0: But of all those countries in the level four the tweet that was going around was Mali is level four the highest level.
Speaker 1: There's no level five.
Speaker 0: No, there's no level five.
Speaker 0: There are global warnings, too.
Speaker 0: But basically level one is we're like whatever.
Speaker 1: well five is like the whole country is on.
Speaker 0: Yeah, level two is like be cautious like here are specific things to worry about.
Speaker 0: a lot of times It'll be like this kind of crime is happening in this area of this country.
Speaker 0: Level three is like please don't go here.
Speaker 0: level four is basically if you go here and you're an American The US government will not fucking help you if you get into trouble like you're on your own.
Speaker 0: Good luck.
Speaker 0: Have fun.
Speaker 0: but the Mali one this is the longest like warning I've ever seen from a country like longer than the one for like North Korea.
Speaker 1: and What's interesting you can you can describe the problem North Korea with very few words.
Speaker 1: Yeah, big problem doesn't need a lot of words.
Speaker 1: But
Speaker 0: what's interesting is the main value of this site in general is that it gives you Specific advice like don't go to ATMs in this part of this map Like they're very specific Like some of them will even list like here are the scams that are currently active as of a month ago in these regions.
Speaker 0: But the Mali one Item number one draft a will and designate appropriate insurance beneficiaries and powers of attorney.
Speaker 0: Discuss a plan with loved ones regarding care of can custody of children pets property belongings.
Speaker 0: Share important documents with your significant others.
Speaker 0: Like it basically says plan to not return why?
Speaker 1: What is the like?
Speaker 1: even if you were like, why would you?
Speaker 1: what's positive about going to Mali?
Speaker 0: I mean, I don't know a lot about Mali.
Speaker 1: I don't know anything about Mali.
Speaker 0: I've never seen One of these advisories that in my life that started with draft a will.
Speaker 0: like for real like that is the advice they give you.
Speaker 0: So anyway, did by thinking today.
Speaker 0: the travel advisories thing overall can be some interesting and fascinating reading And I if you're ever gonna travel somewhere I'd recommend looking at this.
Speaker 0: but especially if things don't go so well in the US over the next 12 months Recommend checking a non-us source for this information as well.
Speaker 0: And when I say non-us, I also mean non-british.
Speaker 0: So anyway in the meta moment, he knows book club book the tale of Genji.
Speaker 0: I'm reading it and steamrolling through it really hard to keep track of who's who other.
Speaker 1: that's why at the start of every chapter It says he has all the people in this chapter.
Speaker 0: I flip back to that section a lot.
Speaker 0: I'm glad But I know Genji is.
Speaker 0: I know when they're talking about Genji.
Speaker 0: Okay, good job.
Speaker 0: But yeah, we're reading the tale again.
Speaker 0: G at some point next month or two We're gonna do a checkpoint and we're gonna talk about some chunk of the tale of Genji Cuz.
Speaker 0: there's a lot to say about it.
Speaker 0: There's a. There's some awesome characters and so far Genji is like way near the bottom of characters.
Speaker 0: I actually care about.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah packs East is actually super soon.
Speaker 0: Oh god.
Speaker 1: Yeah early this year and we got a panel there.
Speaker 1: I think it's not a clickbait garbage panel.
Speaker 1: So maybe you could come to it or maybe you can just watch it on YouTube.
Speaker 0: Yep, we were slightly updating it, but it's basically the same panel.
Speaker 0: Take your fucking turn like go fast play games pop up up go go go.
Speaker 1: We did it a pack some plug But we'll do it at East but we'll tell us the different jokes.
Speaker 0: I changed.
Speaker 1: we got a badge, you know You can say hi to us.
Speaker 0: Well, we get a free badge anyway Because we're also enforcers and I encourage you if you like penny arcade expose as a whole I'd recommend at least once in your life.
Speaker 0: It doesn't matter which packs just pick a packs and Sign up to be an enforcer.
Speaker 1: to be this I mean if you go to a lot of paxes then you you know, why not enforce at one of them?
Speaker 1: But if you don't go to a lot of paxes if you go rarely don't waste like 30% of your packs Yeah, enforcing.
Speaker 1: but
Speaker 0: if you go to mold a lot of paxes enforce at least once because one it if you enjoy pax that is how you can make more pax experiences happen for more people and Enforcers are a big part of the reason why pax doesn't suck like most other conventions.
Speaker 1: Also there have less and less enforcers.
Speaker 1: They need more.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they're always looking for more.
Speaker 1: right now It's not like they don't have a. they don't have more people asking than they need.
Speaker 1: They need more.
Speaker 0: Yep But to even if you're just a selfish dick as long as you're not a jerk while you're enforcing and you're like a good person.
Speaker 0: Otherwise if you enforce you'll see a whole other side of the show and that is like worth the price of admission by itself Just to see what a giant convention like packs looks like from behind the scenes like from a logistic standpoint.
Speaker 0: Like that is an interesting experience And we will be there.
Speaker 0: We'll be enforcing.
Speaker 0: most of our friends will be enforcing at paxes.
Speaker 0: That's the one that we all took up the black for.
Speaker 0: I guess this took up the red because they color-coded it after those Early, no longer the black anywhere.
Speaker 0: Nope.
Speaker 1: I Remember when it was the black.
Speaker 0: only gray muzzles call it taking up the black.
Speaker 0: that was packs West.
Speaker 0: like earliest days like 2007 might have been the last black year.
Speaker 0: Yep otherwise Follow us on YouTube.
Speaker 0: follow us on Twitter.
Speaker 0: follow us everywhere.
Speaker 0: Check out the geek nights forum.
Speaker 0: We have Rev Massively stepped up the moderation of the geek nights forum and a lot of people have not been posting anymore Meaning a lot of you might be more inclined to post.
Speaker 1: Well, you know, this is just like the first step.
Speaker 1: I think we still have some ideas about how to Greatly reshape like the why the forum is even there.
Speaker 1: It's like, you know when there are so many other communication Platforms.
Speaker 0: this includes the fact that our way and elsewhere our website is a very 2005 looking ass website right now.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, right this reeks of when dig was popular.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but at least for the short term, it's like, you know, listen, you know arguments in a forum.
Speaker 1: That's what a forum is sort of for no matter what even if you say it's not for that.
Speaker 1: That's why I have it.
Speaker 1: if you're not gonna have discussions and arguments, right?
Speaker 1: But you know, we're just like listen we saw certain arguments, right?
Speaker 1: It's like we don't want people to not have them but it's like do you really need to have them here?
Speaker 1: You can have them on reddit.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right.
Speaker 1: It's like way back.
Speaker 1: I think we've been through this before the first time we've heard the same thing, right?
Speaker 0: It's like come on people bunch of people can argue about religion.
Speaker 0: We're just like look listen No one's ever allowed to argue about this again, unless you disprove the flies.
Speaker 0: we Eddie monster.
Speaker 0: Otherwise, there's no debate.
Speaker 0: do not talk about this and that made a big problem.
Speaker 0: go away.
Speaker 0: Also, if you don't like our forum just comment on all the other places.
Speaker 0: We are like.
Speaker 0: if you like our tweets and reply to them like we see that and so do other people who like the show.
Speaker 0: If you comment on our YouTube channels or watch the live streams like.
Speaker 0: there are 11 people just like chatting like during this live stream Right now, I don't know what they're doing.
Speaker 0: Are you too calm?
Speaker 1: I even made an account.
Speaker 1: There's a new you know, there's that there was vine and then there was tik-tok.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there's a new one.
Speaker 1: That's by the original vine.
Speaker 1: people called bite like by te.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 1: I made an account.
Speaker 1: I made an account on it.
Speaker 1: Some bites doesn't cost anything.
Speaker 1: Let me make a bite of rim podcasting.
Speaker 0: I'll make a bite of Scott making a bite of rim podcasting.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that'd be funny.
Speaker 1: Is rim podcasting right now?
Speaker 1: It's a bite.
Speaker 0: So, yeah meta stuff.
Speaker 0: Otherwise if you want us to appear at your convention or anything Email us but it's got to be big or fun because we go to a lot of conventions and most of them are packs.
Speaker 0: Isn't back fest right now?
Speaker 0: sadly Scott doesn't go to thank icon which I think is a shame because I love think icons are real good gaming.
Speaker 0: guy play a lot Of tabletop games there, but I'm gonna have to skip thank icon this year.
Speaker 0: So this will be the first thank icon in a long time where there will be no geek nights.
Speaker 0: But I will return the following year and I'm also highly likely even if Scott doesn't going to return To kinetic on and do a bunch of panels have fun.
Speaker 0: I will have fun.
Speaker 0: Okay, it'll be a good time All right.
Speaker 0: Getting rid of shit?
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 1: So we did a show about moving somewhat recently.
Speaker 1: as far as Thursday shows go at least Yeah, and one aspect of moving we may have talked about during that episode It's not exclusive to moving but it usually coincides with moving is getting rid of the shit.
Speaker 0: You don't want Yep, right and this was not a concern for most of my life for a bunch of reasons.
Speaker 0: one Lived in like Midwestern suburbs where everyone had like a garage in a basement at first.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I had like a house and I didn't have a lot of money to buy a lot of stuff And also I didn't own the house.
Speaker 0: my parents did right and My parents had this problem and it's not like I would be aware of that.
Speaker 0: like as a kid is just like go down to The basement like I didn't like there'd be a room full of shit and I just didn't ever go into that room.
Speaker 1: I didn't know I didn't care that it was attic was full of shit.
Speaker 1: I kind of wanted to go in the attic to look through all the shit I only cared was like my shit.
Speaker 1: So I didn't care at one point.
Speaker 0: like we had a pool table and the shit Like encroached into the area of the pool table and if God made heart made it hard to play pool.
Speaker 0: Then I cared a little bit and I like tried to get right tried to push all the shit back into the shit area.
Speaker 1: Right, you know.
Speaker 1: and then we move.
Speaker 1: even when we were in Beacon.
Speaker 1: It's like, okay We had a house that was way too big and we could fit tons and tons of stuff in there.
Speaker 0: We didn't own anything cuz we were in college for five years.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we didn't have a lot of stuff.
Speaker 0: We went out and bought a bunch of stuff.
Speaker 0: I think we've thrown away most of that stuff by this point.
Speaker 0: Yeah We saw that table though, oh god damn it.
Speaker 0: does anyone want that table?
Speaker 1: anyone want a kitchen table?
Speaker 1: Does anyone?
Speaker 0: are really nice wooden kitchen taste.
Speaker 1: not super nice, but it is a solid kitchen table before chair.
Speaker 0: It's real wood like nicely finished.
Speaker 1: It's like $500 like 15 years ago.
Speaker 0: Yeah It's a really nice table.
Speaker 1: It's a table anyway You know, it's not damaged really at all.
Speaker 0: Okay, so I just pulled up a bunch of pictures of us moving out of Beacon.
Speaker 1: Right, but point is when we moved right suddenly it's like I got all this shit.
Speaker 1: I want to get rid of this shit because I don't have a lot of room.
Speaker 1: I don't have a lot of space in the city.
Speaker 1: I want to get rid of stuff, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah And even if you're don't have even if you have tons of room having less stuff makes life easier Because you can get up and go.
Speaker 1: it's like the stuff even if you're not Literally carrying it like in your bag is like a burden on your ability to like be mobile.
Speaker 1: I can't suddenly like move to another state or go away for a long time You know because it's like I had to deal with all my stuff.
Speaker 1: I had to pay rent on the place where the stuff is.
Speaker 1: Even if I'm going like I want to take a trip for like several months Yeah I'm burdened by having to pay rent on this place with a bunch of stuff in it.
Speaker 0: No If I or
Speaker 1: move everything into storage and move it back
Speaker 0: out now if I owned a house and just was living there like semi permanently, I wouldn't think about this nearly as much because
Speaker 1: there is
Speaker 0: a Value to be had in accumulating stuff that is not negatively impacting your life because that stuff is valuable and useful if it ever comes up and otherwise doesn't negatively impact you.
Speaker 0: like You got some old skis you have a kid You can just give the kid the old skis.
Speaker 0: like save yourself some money like that kind of thing.
Speaker 0: But I've never been that way like even when I was in high school.
Speaker 0: Like I pretty much always assumed I wouldn't be living in the US at some point Like I'd always kind of planned to like move around live somewhere else see the world like fuck living in a house forever.
Speaker 0: So I've always had this idea that I wanted to have less stuff, but it didn't really become necessary to deal with immediately until now when I do.
Speaker 0: now I have like three closets in this entire apartment and even now I've been getting rid of shit at a like terrifying rate and Every time I do this every time I think I'm going to take this one area of my apartment and get rid of everything I don't need.
Speaker 0: I generate like 12 garbage bags worth of shit.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so I don't know how it's like.
Speaker 1: I managed to get rid of most of my shit, right?
Speaker 1: Now the prop thing is a. if you live in like a town and I guess a good town You can get rid of your shit pretty easily because you probably have a car, right?
Speaker 1: You can use the car put shit in it.
Speaker 0: Maria posted on like Craigslist and someone else who also owns a car will like Drive to your house and pick it up.
Speaker 1: Well, actually Craigslist isn't so great these days of all things.
Speaker 0: Oh, I've never successfully given something away on Craigslist.
Speaker 0: I gave up because I tried.
Speaker 0: I tried a whole bunch of people would respond asking questions so stupid that I refused to talk to them or Demanding ridiculous nonsense of me for the privilege of taking my shit that they wanted.
Speaker 1: I have given some way in Craigslist But more recently the thing that I've had the most success with is actually Facebook marketplace.
Speaker 1: Only good thing that Facebook has ever made.
Speaker 1: that's like actually good.
Speaker 1: It's like a better Craigslist than Craigslist.
Speaker 1: It totally works at least especially in New York City where there's a lot of people on it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and you give shit away and like even obscure shit.
Speaker 1: I tried to give away.
Speaker 1: people came and took it.
Speaker 1: so I Would make like.
Speaker 1: if you don't like Facebook, I would make like a bullshit Facebook account and only use Facebook marketplace.
Speaker 0: Yep, but I guess the tricky part is I've gotten rid of all the things that are easy to get rid of without a car.
Speaker 0: What I have left are things that I'm sure human will.
Speaker 0: on one hand there are things that I'm sure human could use But it's hard to find that human and my options are either Throw the thing away or put feels bad or put a lot of effort into it feels bad.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it feels bad to throw something out that you don't want, you know You're never gonna use again, but it's still perfectly good.
Speaker 0: Yep Like I have a whole bunch of high school textbooks that are still pretty good and you think I want to donate this.
Speaker 1: but actually donating things is sometimes easy and sometimes difficult.
Speaker 1: and what any?
Speaker 1: and the thing is the easiest places to donate are Places you don't want to.
Speaker 0: don't never give things to Salvation Army.
Speaker 0: They're a hate group.
Speaker 1: No, that's the worst.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like never.
Speaker 1: also I'd rather burn something than let the Salvation Army go like a gas station and there's like a big metal thing.
Speaker 1: That's like, you know donate stuff here.
Speaker 0: Oh, I remember when we found out those are scams.
Speaker 1: if you look at if you actually research it.
Speaker 1: There are maybe some that don't suck but the vast majority of them I've researched.
Speaker 1: like huh who actually owns that big metal can.
Speaker 1: where will the stuff go that I put in there?
Speaker 1: What will happen to it?
Speaker 1: who?
Speaker 1: I there was one.
Speaker 1: It was literally a cult Like not a cult in the same the way that I throw the word cult around to describe things even like Scientology Which also is a cult but like no the kind of cult that is like the Kool-Aid kind of cult.
Speaker 1: Yeah, super like, you know the kind of cult like that XX whatever that was upstaying.
Speaker 1: like.
Speaker 1: that kind of cult was making money off the Donated clothes somehow and if you put clothes in there, you're helping them and it's great.
Speaker 1: I'll do not put clothes in there.
Speaker 0: I also have a lot of like.
Speaker 0: the thing that's hardest to get rid of in New York is Furniture.
Speaker 0: Yeah, cuz I can't type furniture Can't easily be moved without disintegrating.
Speaker 1: I mean you can theoretically put stuff out on for the sanitation and but they'll throw it but they'll trash it.
Speaker 1: I've seen furniture out there.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but they'll trash it.
Speaker 0: I can't just take it all down and they'll just trash it.
Speaker 0: but I have like an armoire.
Speaker 0: It's a big armoire.
Speaker 0: I want to get rid of.
Speaker 0: it's nice.
Speaker 0: It's made out of wood.
Speaker 0: It's kind of beat up but like it's perfectly functional.
Speaker 0: I can imagine a poor family like wanting this in their house.
Speaker 0: But I would have to pay actually a lot for the privilege of someone of someone to come and pick it up and take it Independent of who I donated to.
Speaker 1: yeah, it's very annoying that it's like I don't have to schedule it during working hours.
Speaker 0: I have to like take a day off work sit here wait for this truck to show up that trucks gonna have to somehow like Park illegally on Crescent Street and then take this thing.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: Yep Crescent Street FYI is like the Street that goes to one of the most important bridges to Manhattan used to be able to park on the street in the back But that those days are over.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they put a building there.
Speaker 1: Yeah by parking lot.
Speaker 0: Yeah So I'm probably gonna just like.
Speaker 0: I'm getting to the point to where there's a bunch of things that I've been wanting to donate or give away for a while and Have been foiled enough to where I might just throw them away and just wash my hands.
Speaker 1: It's so annoying that we can't have this like arbitrage.
Speaker 1: there are people who basically have no money and Would really need stuff and there's no who have stuff and desperately want to get rid of it.
Speaker 1: But the logistics of getting the stuff from the person who doesn't want it to the person who could use it are so difficult.
Speaker 1: It's like you had to pay.
Speaker 1: it's like I had to pay to get rid of it.
Speaker 1: for that amount of money I could buy two new ones.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: The hardest one is technology.
Speaker 0: I had So many computer monitors that all worked.
Speaker 0: every one of them worked, but they were so obsolete that they were worthless Like no one wanted them.
Speaker 0: schools didn't want them.
Speaker 1: Recycling centers didn't want is a big problem these days with pianos.
Speaker 1: a lot of people have pianos From old in the day or whoever whatever and You can't get rid of a piano because no one wants one.
Speaker 1: you like donate to a school.
Speaker 1: the school's like we already got piano.
Speaker 0: Yeah, most schools have digital pianos now because digital pianos sound 90% the same like it doesn't matter for most use cases of a piano.
Speaker 0: They have more tools for like instruction They're easier for schools to use and they don't need tutors.
Speaker 1: I'm just saying real pianos the schools will have even if they don't have digital ones.
Speaker 1: They already have.
Speaker 0: They have all the real one right but a real piano is too much of a pain in the ass to maintain.
Speaker 1: It's really like you'll have this piano.
Speaker 1: you think oh, it's a very valuable expensive thing But it's like a diamond ring, right?
Speaker 1: But good.
Speaker 1: Well diamond rings not actually valuable.
Speaker 1: Well that you think it's valuable But it really is like the piano sort of is like if that same piano was in a piano store.
Speaker 1: Someone might actually come in and buy it for a large amount of money.
Speaker 1: But if you have the piano and are trying to sell it You will basically have to pay that amount of money to get rid of it.
Speaker 0: Pro tip if you need a piano or a Diamond ring buy one on the secondary market.
Speaker 0: You can get it for almost nothing.
Speaker 0: almost nothing ain't worth nothing Yep, but these computer monitors The only thing that saved me was that Scott had a computer like your monitor died.
Speaker 0: So I have.
Speaker 0: so I gave Scott one of the monitors.
Speaker 0: I put the other monitor in the living room as a monitor like around the corner like in the kitchen so I can watch stuff while I'm working on things.
Speaker 0: and That Samsung the last the sink master I have ended up just taking that to an electronics recycler.
Speaker 0: Yeah, no one wanted it.
Speaker 0: It's like once a year and they charged me 20 bucks to take it.
Speaker 1: in New York City the center of the world They have these safe disposal of old I.
Speaker 0: I biked over there the last time.
Speaker 0: I went like six times with a giant Backpack full of shit have a safe disposal event, which is what it's a special event.
Speaker 1: and they it's in the park.
Speaker 1: And well, it's in different places but it's only in each of the places one day a year.
Speaker 1: I think there's only like five days of the year total.
Speaker 1: Yeah And you can go there.
Speaker 0: gotta be a New York City resident.
Speaker 0: like if you drive in like they like make you prove where you Live.
Speaker 1: if you walk in they don't check.
Speaker 1: Yeah If you drive in they check to see where you're from right and you can bring pretty much fucking Anything.
Speaker 0: no questions that look.
Speaker 1: I just went to the website.
Speaker 0: that would normally.
Speaker 0: what do you got?
Speaker 0: batteries asbestos?
Speaker 0: Medical waste mercury.
Speaker 0: fuck it.
Speaker 1: Come on down literally like any of that dangerous shit.
Speaker 1: paint You know, whatever you got.
Speaker 1: electronics, you know.
Speaker 1: and Crazy light bulbs mystery chemical.
Speaker 0: if you bring it they will deal with it because the city would rather Like take on the burden of dealing with it in a safe way and you dump it down the drain.
Speaker 0: Yep, cuz if they didn't have this people would just dump it down the drain, right?
Speaker 1: You know some air conditioner or something any.
Speaker 1: you bring it to the safe disposal event Right, and they will take care of it for zero dollar.
Speaker 1: But this event only happens one day only within your at least within your neighborhood one day a year.
Speaker 1: if you drive There's a line of cars and they slowly go around Getting dropping off this stuff one at a time.
Speaker 1: you walk you can walk right in but you got a carrier shit if you're walking And if you don't.
Speaker 1: I used to live a lot closer to the park.
Speaker 1: now I live a few blocks further, but that makes a significant difference in how much stuff I can bring You know without like a hand truck or something.
Speaker 0: Oh, so I didn't realize this cuz I've never tried to throw one of these things away.
Speaker 0: There are three things they will not take.
Speaker 1: What will they not take?
Speaker 0: appliances?
Speaker 0: Okay, like you can't take a microwave Okay, air conditioner.
Speaker 1: You could take air conditioner.
Speaker 0: Uh, you keep odd so you can take nope.
Speaker 0: No air conditioners All right, dehumidifiers refrigerators.
Speaker 0: Okay, you can take Freon and things with Freon in them, but you can't take appliances that are Freon.
Speaker 0: Okay, and you can't take tires.
Speaker 1: Oh tires, of course, right?
Speaker 0: Those are the good luck.
Speaker 1: getting rid of a tire Get rid of tires is not easy.
Speaker 1: Yeah your best bet if you have tires is You know you think all.
Speaker 1: just you know.
Speaker 1: When you buy the tires make sure the tire place takes the old tires.
Speaker 0: now if you have a fridge if you call three one One they'll make an appointment.
Speaker 0: Just come take it from you.
Speaker 1: Yes fridges are like there's a special thing for fridges.
Speaker 1: I've seen fridges on like the side of the road when they usually have a sticker on them Like the doors have been torn off and I'm like there's a special way to throw out a fridge in the city.
Speaker 0: So I I'm not sure if this is true.
Speaker 0: I'm not gonna look it up But I'm pretty sure the only reason we have to take the doors off is because of a false scare that kids were hiding in Fridges and I don't know.
Speaker 1: but I've seen that some several times.
Speaker 0: But I don't think that actually happened that often.
Speaker 1: I don't think so either but I'm just saying.
Speaker 1: I've seen several instances of a fridge on the street Be waiting to be thrown out next to the trash with hope.
Speaker 1: there's one other rule special sticker on it and no doors.
Speaker 0: if you Multiple chemicals like mystery chemicals you're bringing you can bring them but don't mix them all together into one jug.
Speaker 1: You don't Yeah, I wanted to throw my ammonia baby.
Speaker 1: You want some ammonia bleach.
Speaker 1: I got some ammonia and I throw that out.
Speaker 0: So the other thing I gotta get rid of and I think I'm just gonna have to throw it away is I have the thing And someone actually had Tracy just mentioned here - uh, you and I both have this.
Speaker 0: we're nerds.
Speaker 0: We have a lot of technology.
Speaker 0: I have at least one of every possible fucking cable I could ever need for anything.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, I've got several of the every possible cable you could need for everything and you know what as on one hand Yeah, I could get rid of 90% of these right?
Speaker 0: No when I moved into this fucking apartment in 2009 I got FiOS.
Speaker 0: the only way to get the FiOS to the center of the apartment the computer room was with coax and But Verizon guy didn't have any coax and sure enough I had a coax cable in my bucket of cables.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and I was able to just plug it in.
Speaker 1: I recently when I moved I went through the cables and I got rid of many.
Speaker 1: but there are certain cables, right?
Speaker 1: It's like VGA cable.
Speaker 1: I still got one.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but you know what I got to.
Speaker 1: I had to.
Speaker 0: I got rid of one.
Speaker 0: You know, I got rid of all my DVI cables anything with DVI.
Speaker 1: I have one DVI cable.
Speaker 0: I took the plunge.
Speaker 0: I went to zero.
Speaker 0: Okay, and I think I'm gonna get rid all my VGA cables.
Speaker 1: I have one VGA and one DVI cable.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna get rid of my VGA long as the monitor still has an input.
Speaker 0: I still got the cable, but I have HDMI to HDMI.
Speaker 0: I have HDMI to micro HDMI.
Speaker 1: I have this.
Speaker 1: I have different.
Speaker 1: I have two different small HDM eyes One that oh, yeah the small one and then the smaller one, right?
Speaker 0: I have I have all of those.
Speaker 1: and then what happened is is newer devices Started like my camera used to have this weird mini or micro HDMI But then the newer camera just has full-size HDMI.
Speaker 0: all of all my cameras have regular as HDMI.
Speaker 1: now They're just like yeah, fuck it.
Speaker 0: So I might just get rid of all my non regular HDMI.
Speaker 1: You know, it's like I have power cables.
Speaker 1: never give her a power cable.
Speaker 0: I did because I actually did an inventory.
Speaker 0: I want you to guess how many Standard like PC like the three that goes into a power supply.
Speaker 0: How many of those you think I had in this apartment as of a month ago?
Speaker 1: 20? 31.
Speaker 1: Okay, that's too many.
Speaker 0: I got rid of all but I have six.
Speaker 1: I have like ten.
Speaker 1: I got just guessing.
Speaker 0: I kept six plus the ones that are plugged into devices.
Speaker 0: I'm using right now.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah The reason I had so many the mixer used one of those.
Speaker 0: they'll compress all that audio shit.
Speaker 0: also use that same form factor.
Speaker 1: The kind that I don't get rid of are the kind that are like two circles or a circle square with.
Speaker 0: I started get rid of those because I had Maybe tied a lot of them.
Speaker 0: So you know what I did.
Speaker 0: I got rid of all the ones that were Chinese bootlegs from when I bought Chinese bootleg batteries and they came with chargers and you can tell because the the that Specific kind of bootleg the prongs to plug into the outlet will be smooth with no indentations and no holes And they'll both be the same size 99% of the time.
Speaker 0: that is a like bootleg piece of crap cable.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: Why are there holes on the prongs of them?
Speaker 0: Partly to save metal and partly because depending on the outlet it helps hold it in better.
Speaker 0: No These days is pretty much just a mark of quality.
Speaker 0: like do people still make them the way they used to or they just make Some cheap shit.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: But yeah, I don't think what matters electricity.
Speaker 0: I can.
Speaker 0: I will look up to make sure there isn't something I'm missing here.
Speaker 1: Yeah Anyway, but yeah, the point is you want to get rid of shit.
Speaker 1: It's like you can call your friends.
Speaker 0: You can donate you can pay to have They fit those little bumps inside of the outlet that you don't think about and it's just.
Speaker 1: it's just a pain.
Speaker 1: Why is it hard to make stuff go away?
Speaker 1: That's why junk collector is a business.
Speaker 0: Well, here's the money.
Speaker 0: It's really easy to make things go away donating if you're crooked.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah I mean when I was a kid Alice's restaurant just illegal dumping.
Speaker 0: when I was a kid I think I was giving.
Speaker 0: I told the story once on gig nights, but back in like 2006 I think I can tell it again, but I'll tell a shortened version to graduate high school with a certified diploma because I grew up in Michigan and they just passed a law about this I had to Do a certain amount of community service Which fine.
Speaker 0: so I did a bunch of community service, but you could get a lot of it by Organizing a group go into a local park and picking up trash and like the city made it really easy to do So me and a bunch of friends were like, let's go to the park by the high school and pick up all the fucking trash.
Speaker 0: And like 20 of us were like, let's fucking do it.
Speaker 0: So we told the city we're gonna do it.
Speaker 0: So at the in the evening at 6 p.m The city was gonna send a truck to pick up all the garbage we collected.
Speaker 0: We collected enough garbage to where the city could not deal with it.
Speaker 0: We collected like I wanted.
Speaker 0: the pile was about 10 feet tall and 30 or 40 feet long and it included radiators barbed wire tires Barrels pieces of cars.
Speaker 0: We pulled an entire chassis of a car out of the woods into the collection area Like it was only the front of a chassis.
Speaker 0: It was like broken off and rusted.
Speaker 0: we pulled all this garbage out and the city was so mad they called the cops and the cops were like They were picking up garbage.
Speaker 0: They didn't break any law.
Speaker 0: You said you'd pick it up problems on you.
Speaker 0: that pile of rusting metal sat there for like a month before the city could figure Out what to do with it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's even hard for a city who is the people who collect the trash?
Speaker 1: Oh, you know depending right to get rid of stuff.
Speaker 0: a lot of it was barbed wire.
Speaker 0: We pulled so much like rusted ass old barbed wire out of the woods next to this park.
Speaker 0: But if you're crooked, yeah Just roll your car off into the woods file the vent off and walk away Like just dump that paint down the drain and I think a lot of people do that shit, which is a problem.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's a bit as long as you.
Speaker 1: if you're doing illegal dumping if it's in an Environmentally damaging illegal dumping I am against that.
Speaker 1: But if you are doing illegal dumping like put a rusty car on a wealthy person's lawn.
Speaker 1: I am okay with that.
Speaker 0: Well at one point we found a bunch of garbage that we were pretty sure.
Speaker 0: I hope this is me and a few friends.
Speaker 0: as a kid We were in the woods and we found all this garbage that we were pretty sure Was being dumped in the woods behind the property.
Speaker 0: the people lived like in front because we saw the posts that were on the.
Speaker 0: all This fencing they dumped back there were the same style as the post that were on the property.
Speaker 0: that looked nice and new.
Speaker 0: So in the middle of the night one time me and a friend of mine went into the woods Grabbed all that garbage and put it on their front porch.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: I hope it was their garbage.
Speaker 0: We're pretty sure it was okay.
Speaker 0: But even now like I don't want to just take this stuff downstairs because even if I dispose of it ethically It is just being thrown away when it could be used by someone theoretically.
Speaker 0: But at the same time in the end I Am NOT accruing more stupid shit.
Speaker 1: So if I get rid of all the shit, I think you know, they always talk about like, you know You know this recycling right recycling as we could do a whole episode of recycling.
Speaker 1: Reusing is always great, but we just talked about how hard it is to reuse.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: The best thing to do is reduce.
Speaker 1: stop buying so much shit in the first place.
Speaker 0: I don't buy things unless I need them specifically.
Speaker 1: I actually after I moved it to and I was buying a lot of stuff cuz I just moved for like maybe like a month For the past.
Speaker 1: like, you know, I get what.
Speaker 1: I went out and moved like September October.
Speaker 1: Since like this other than like, you know presents for people in December.
Speaker 1: I don't think I really bought much since December.
Speaker 1: like I basically have everything that I need.
Speaker 1: I don't need much more other than consumable goods like TP or You know Stuff like that.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: It's mostly disposables consumables or like like I bought some audio equipment cuz I upgraded the pipeline.
Speaker 1: Hey, I think I basically don't need anything right now.
Speaker 1: Like I have no needs whatsoever.
Speaker 1: Oh, I bought.
Speaker 0: uh, I had to buy a new pepper grinder because the crap you want I've had forever to stop working.
Speaker 1: Yeah, other than maintenance of the things I have to so that I don't have to replace them.
Speaker 1: I I'm pretty much like I don't.
Speaker 1: there's no kid I got.
Speaker 0: but that's why even if in the end some of this stuff I end up just taking downstairs and having the city dispose of It's a one-time deal.
Speaker 0: It's not like I'm gonna be throwing this Volume of crap away for the rest of my life constantly like certain people seem to do when they live in houses.
Speaker 0: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Speaker 1: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 0: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays and make comic Wednesdays and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: geek nights is recorded live with no studio And no audience, but unlike those other late shows It's actually recorded at night
Speaker 0: and the patreon patrons for this episode of geek nights are Greg alla rel enjoys having me nickel just like a dude guy sure college and link eg that the thirst for hydrated get in Christmas gift my state.
Speaker 0: calm J bad Sean Yeager Nicholas brand up you hold the key to my heart for two one creations.
Speaker 0: I got in one little fight and my mom got scared.
Speaker 0: Shervin van Harl Superboy Clinton Walton run from New Zealand Ryan parent rope and lender Finn dread Lily Tenebrae Sean Klein Chris Reimer Thomas on and a whole bunch of other people.
Speaker 0: so you might have seen I uploaded some patreon exclusive content.
Speaker 0: We did a brand new panel at magfest this year called competitive versus casual and unsolvable problem.
Speaker 0: We didn't video it.
Speaker 0: It was sort of a draft run.
Speaker 0: It was one of the.
Speaker 0: we often will try out a panel for the first time at a con.
Speaker 0: Maybe we video it.
Speaker 0: Maybe we don't because we weren't doing any other really new content.
Speaker 0: We decided just to not bother bringing all that crap to magfest and just have fun.
Speaker 0: But I did record.
Speaker 0: I was doing the panel with a slightly zoomed in like weird crop of the slides.
Speaker 0: You know BS on my laptop Just for like archival purposes.
Speaker 0: like I can look at it and kind of remember where jokes landed or didn't land or which slides Worked or which points seem to work.
Speaker 0: as we turn this into a full-on panel.
Speaker 0: We might do this panel for real.
Speaker 0: it like PAX West this year or maybe in another packs in the future.
Speaker 0: But right now doesn't exist anywhere on the internet Except in that one unlisted YouTube video that I linked to for the patrons login to patreon if you didn't see it.
Speaker 0: but anyway Now I leave you where.
Speaker 1: Sorry Jimmy without zinc for the rotary mechanism There are no telephones dear.
Speaker 0: God.
Speaker 0: What have I done?
Speaker 0: Think again Jimmy you see the firing pin in your gun was made of yep zinc.
Speaker 1: come back zinc.
Speaker 1: Come back zinc Cumber Z zinc z. what.
Speaker 0: oh It was all a dream Thank goodness.
Speaker 0: I still live in a world of telephones car batteries Handguns and many things made of zinc.