Speaker 0: It's Wednesday, February 19th, 2020.
Speaker 0: I'm rim.
Speaker 0: No Scott, and this is geek nights tonight.
Speaker 0: ride your wave Let's do this.
Speaker 0: Some of you who are watching the live stream might notice that we actually are recording this episode live on Thursday Because the movie was in theaters in the United States One night only and it happened to be last night on Wednesday when we normally would have recorded the show.
Speaker 1: So why couldn't it be Tuesday?
Speaker 1: Yeah, they clearly are not scheduling their theater showings around geek night.
Speaker 0: I feel like we need I need to send them a press release and a Notification like just see one night only.
Speaker 0: anime screenings must be on Tuesdays not be on Wednesdays.
Speaker 0: They must be on alternating Tuesdays.
Speaker 0: Yes, I can provide here.
Speaker 0: Here is the days you are allowed to schedule a one-night-only United States Subtitled anime screening, you know, maybe because I watched the movie an infinite number of times as a child and I still love it.
Speaker 0: But whenever I hear anyone say one night only all I can think of is the blues brothers.
Speaker 0: You're only thinking about that because they were advertising their other limited screenings Which I'm gonna go see the blues brothers in the theater because the blues brothers is one of those movies for me that is on That very rare list kind of talk about this a lot.
Speaker 0: There's like a handful of works of art like mostly movies TV that I can just watch any number of time.
Speaker 0: Like if I walk into someone's house and it's on TV I'll just start watching it until it ends.
Speaker 1: and then what if it's on repeat and it repeats before the credits roll?
Speaker 1: Yep, like it just immediately.
Speaker 1: as soon as the credits is just it just immediately starts again.
Speaker 0: Yep, like Empire Strikes Back.
Speaker 0: That'll do it to me the Blues Brothers.
Speaker 1: You'll just be trapped.
Speaker 1: Yep, right You don't need to make a pit trap.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you want to kill me and Scott in a dungeon.
Speaker 0: just have the matrix on on a random TV.
Speaker 1: in a dungeon You don't need to make like one of those Like a sarcophagus kind of shape thing with a lock on it.
Speaker 1: Oh, you don't need to do any kind of D&D like.
Speaker 1: you don't need like a rope Trap with it with a cake in it where your foot gets stuck and now you're hanging Like in return of the Jedi where they're hanging.
Speaker 1: and then the you ox God, you don't get any of those traps or like in this.
Speaker 0: you can.
Speaker 1: you see you can have an open.
Speaker 1: You can have an open field an open grass field With a giant projector and as long as you power the projector and keep playing movies that are in the right category back-to-back We will sit there and not leave as long as their food keeps coming and the weather doesn't get shitty.
Speaker 0: Oh Iron Monkey Iron Monkey does it to me?
Speaker 1: I'm just saying there's a. you know, you didn't see the the unedited Iron Monkey.
Speaker 0: No, I did not.
Speaker 0: that's I gotta correct that slightly edited.
Speaker 0: Yeah, okay.
Speaker 1: Okay Basically still the same movie.
Speaker 0: but uh, so I have a brief story, you know an opening bit from my life Cuz remember.
Speaker 0: well some time ago we had to go to the hospital because randomly this tertiary lamp that had a tempered glass top the top just exploded and showered us in like Broken glass at high velocity.
Speaker 0: It sounded like a bomb went off and that was a whole story.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so, uh Early this morning.
Speaker 1: I get only you could somehow say which he ignites.
Speaker 1: episode that was the opening bit for I could probably find it.
Speaker 0: I think I even said something about it in the show notes.
Speaker 0: You know, I can go look at my hospital records for when I went to the hospital.
Speaker 0: so, uh Anyway this morning.
Speaker 0: I'm showering and I hear a loud crash and then a bunch of Follow-up debris.
Speaker 0: noises happen while I'm showering.
Speaker 0: Okay It's loud enough to where it was either in our apartment and a problem or in someone else's apartment and a big problem.
Speaker 0: So I did what all good people do is I pause for a second.
Speaker 0: I just kept showering.
Speaker 0: cuz I'm gonna finish my shower and then go see what hell awaits me.
Speaker 1: It isn't screaming from people in your apartment.
Speaker 1: Yeah, where you need to call a 911 Yeah, or attend or something like that.
Speaker 1: Then you can continue with your shower.
Speaker 0: Yeah, no alarms going on but then there's a knock on the door and Emily just says hey So, you know my mirror exploded.
Speaker 0: Okay, which marry a lot of mirrors I bet quite a few mirrors the ones that came with the apartment and are built like the ones on the Medicine cabinets that are built into the fixtures in the apartment.
Speaker 1: So in the bathroom above the sink Yep, like there's a mirror on a medicine cabinet.
Speaker 0: Yep, and that the me the glass mirror part popped off and Exploded.
Speaker 1: so the mirror was not well attached to the cabinet.
Speaker 1: It was not that the cabinet door fell off It was at the.
Speaker 1: there's a mirror attached to the cabinet and that mirror popped off the front of the cabinet fell like hit the Sink, I imagine and shattered and now the second shattering you heard was against the ground.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: That was basically it.
Speaker 0: Now what's funny is last night.
Speaker 0: I remember cuz Emily was like weird.
Speaker 0: I was like what and she was like my Bathroom like medicine cabinet door just opened itself And she closed it and it was fine.
Speaker 0: I guess what happened is it must have like started to come off just enough.
Speaker 1: the weight the weight Distribution was and then it undid whatever magnet or thing.
Speaker 1: Yeah fastener.
Speaker 1: It has to keep itself closed.
Speaker 0: So today a magnet.
Speaker 0: I worked from home in the afternoon and the super and a bunch of people came to like deal with it.
Speaker 0: Cuz I explained to them what happened and they like didn't understand they were like that can't?
Speaker 0: what do you mean?
Speaker 0: So then they came in and one of them's like, oh And the supers like how the fuck did that happen?
Speaker 1: Well, we looked at.
Speaker 1: I saw the photo.
Speaker 1: I didn't go in there yet.
Speaker 0: mostly cuz I don't want to risk all fixed like it's completely.
Speaker 0: it's like nothing ever happened.
Speaker 1: I don't want to step on any glass though.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so I got a 99% way for you to step on the glass.
Speaker 1: So I'm still fine.
Speaker 1: point is in the photo you showed me I saw that beneath the mirror There were three patches.
Speaker 1: It looked like that mirror was held on with three spots of glue.
Speaker 1: Yeah vertically on the one the left side on the left side.
Speaker 1: not even like well distributed.
Speaker 1: They didn't even do like a. I would have done at least like a five like a D. You know the five.
Speaker 1: yeah lips on a d6 on the when you roll a five.
Speaker 1: Yeah Box with the X right or you could do nine.
Speaker 0: nine would be sensible right me don't use too much But I don't actually know what that was because this is like a thing made in a factory and pressed together Probably by a machine.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah, definitely the building.
Speaker 1: people didn't put that together.
Speaker 1: Yeah Unbox them and they attach them to the wall.
Speaker 0: So they put in a brand new door and everything because they're not gonna like try to replace like the mirror.
Speaker 1: I know they try to stick a new mirror on it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the first of all, they don't have a marriage is lying around but they probably have a spare cabinet liner.
Speaker 0: So then they went to all the other because there's four.
Speaker 0: there's four of these things in our apartment.
Speaker 0: They went to each one and like poked at it and they're like, yeah, okay I don't see any way this could happen to any of these other ones.
Speaker 1: my guess It was probably a combination of you know, humidity changes and hot cold change.
Speaker 0: Yeah coupled with manufacturing Contraction.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like cheap stuff.
Speaker 1: It's not like they put in the high.
Speaker 1: It's weird how when you get you know I mean obviously if you got a Super fancy rich wealthy person apartment, right?
Speaker 1: First of all, you're choosing your own Fixtures.
Speaker 0: Yeah, those apartments and condos tend to come with nothing.
Speaker 1: You're coming with an interior decorator and choosing your own shit.
Speaker 1: but most apartments even luxury ones right the fixtures that come with the apartment are Usually like not as cheap as hotel fixtures But not much better.
Speaker 1: like only like one because they're gonna get a lot more use than hotel fixtures But basically only one level.
Speaker 1: so I know I know you're someone who lives in like You know who doesn't have a lot of money and lives in some cheapy house in the suburbs or rural place.
Speaker 1: Your fixtures are actually probably pretty damn good compared to the ones in like a luxury Apartment in the city that costs like twice the mortgage
Speaker 0: and I think that part of that is just because like when I got this Apartment, I didn't even look at the whole apartment before I said yes and sign the lease because I was so desperate to find an apartment.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean I looked and it's like sometimes they'll splurge in the appliances like the stoves and fridges.
Speaker 0: this building.
Speaker 1: I heard of thing.
Speaker 0: this building splurged on.
Speaker 0: we are next to like seven subways, right?
Speaker 1: But it's like when you build a developer you build a building.
Speaker 1: you got you know As though maybe a hundred units or who knows how many fucking units in there?
Speaker 1: Yeah, right you got to put.
Speaker 0: I want to say there's a hundred and forty in our building, right?
Speaker 1: Is you got a?
Speaker 1: you want to put in all these?
Speaker 1: you got to buy whatever.
Speaker 1: you got to buy Stoves.
Speaker 1: you got to buy times that many units plus extras in case something goes wrong.
Speaker 1: And if it's something like like the heating units you got to buy two or three per apartment Right times the number of units and they've already replaced two of our units, right?
Speaker 1: It's like you're placing like a bulk ass order for like, you know hundreds of things.
Speaker 1: So how many bathroom cabinets are you buying?
Speaker 1: 500 bathroom cabinets?
Speaker 1: It's like you don't want to buy a bathroom cabinet that costs five hundred dollars because then you're spending $25,000 in bathroom cabinets you want to buy a $50 one?
Speaker 0: Yep, especially when in New York City someone like me is going to buy the apartment primarily because of its specific address You're not gonna say I'm not going to this apartment the cabinets cheap.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: Like the countertops is just for Micah like WTF Like now.
Speaker 0: don't care right?
Speaker 1: You can get one with less solid wood more poorly constructed.
Speaker 1: It's got to look nice.
Speaker 1: Yeah, doesn't matter.
Speaker 1: You know how someone's not gonna be like, oh man, you know this.
Speaker 1: You know this kitchen floor is kind of like a crappy kind of floor material.
Speaker 1: I'm moving in here.
Speaker 1: It's not the make or break factor.
Speaker 0: When they built the building because we moved in when it was built they ran fiber to every apartment from the Mimi room and and a bunch of other stuff.
Speaker 0: and the soundproofing in this building is like Terrifyingly effective.
Speaker 1: Well, yeah pretty much every building the new building the soundproofing is yeah I can play my trumpet in the middle of night.
Speaker 0: I can play DDR.
Speaker 0: I don't hear shit.
Speaker 0: You can only hear.
Speaker 1: I only heard shit.
Speaker 1: the only.
Speaker 1: I only hear shit from the hallway.
Speaker 1: You know the door is if you're right it's like oh you have an alcove But I just have a door right against an open room.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that would be way because you have that little tiny hallway entryway that blocks some of the Halloween.
Speaker 0: I actually picked this apartment partly because of the alcove and the like pseudo foyer.
Speaker 1: Well, also my door is right in front of the elevator and I've decided I'm gonna activity outside the door.
Speaker 0: as much as it pains me I'm gonna stop saying foyer because I realized something important foyer.
Speaker 0: the vast majority of mayor of Americans Have no idea what the fuck you're talking about.
Speaker 1: Oh, I thought you were gonna say that foyer had a racist Like.
Speaker 1: it's like.
Speaker 1: is there some history of the word foyer that it should not be?
Speaker 1: You
Speaker 0: know, that's that's a fair fear because I remember and I won't say the word but I remember an RIT when I was reading a book on bartending and it explained a certain kind of bar and Suddenly I realized that a very commonly used word was in fact a racial slur and I was like Scott Guess what's a racial slur?
Speaker 0: and you were like what?
Speaker 0: Oh Oh shit, and we both stopped saying that word.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm just the other day I was like I was.
Speaker 1: I'm not gonna talk about it is not that much to the opening.
Speaker 1: Yeah But I was.
Speaker 1: I've been I'm shopping to replace one of my shoe pairs of shoes and I was on a site and it's and there was a shoe and the name of the shoe was prison boot and I was not a hundred percent comfortable with the name of that shoe.
Speaker 0: Prison guard boot.
Speaker 1: No, I just it just said prison boot, huh?
Speaker 1: Like that was.
Speaker 1: you know, every company like names all those I mean, I guess it's a pretty like Nike will be like, this is the Nike free or this is the I run And this is the Adidas, you know, Stan Smith or whatever.
Speaker 1: Every shoe has a name, right?
Speaker 1: Well, they made this company named their shoe.
Speaker 1: This is the prison boot.
Speaker 0: I Don't know.
Speaker 0: I've never heard of the phrase prison boot before.
Speaker 0: Seems like it's a style of boot.
Speaker 1: It's the name of a specific boot model.
Speaker 0: Oh, it's a specific boot model from fry.
Speaker 0: I used to wear some fry boots.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 1: But yeah, I was like, that's not the greatest name.
Speaker 1: Yeah Probably change that name.
Speaker 0: So there's a whole bunch of news and geek bites and stuff.
Speaker 0: So we'll pick a few things first off kind of random aside, but we since we saw ride your wave last night We saw a bunch of trailers to a bunch of other animated features and apparently studio 4c has an anime movie That's already in theaters.
Speaker 0: We could go see it at the same theater in Astoria tonight if we wanted to.
Speaker 0: children of the sea Thus making a triptych of three water anime movies in recent memory.
Speaker 1: Have I seen children at the sea?
Speaker 0: No, it's brand new.
Speaker 0: Okay Like it came out in 2019 in May and in like a Tokyo premiere it later in June.
Speaker 0: It premiered in like the rest of Japan.
Speaker 0: It's only recently in the US and it's I think it's a G kids thing.
Speaker 0: Okay, but uh, it's about some kids who like one kid was raised by do gongs and there's water.
Speaker 1: Oh, I didn't see a trailer for that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you saw that trailer with me last night.
Speaker 0: We talked about this trailer.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 0: Do you not what?
Speaker 0: what happened last night?
Speaker 0: What's your name?
Speaker 0: What year is it Scott?
Speaker 1: Okay We watch this trailer last night.
Speaker 1: might have seen it at the previous Anime showing.
Speaker 1: I went to.
Speaker 0: it looks really good.
Speaker 0: The animation style looks different and beautiful.
Speaker 0: Apparently it's based on a manga.
Speaker 0: It's won some awards.
Speaker 0: Maybe I'll go see it this weekend.
Speaker 0: Hmm.
Speaker 0: It's just at the theater like right there.
Speaker 0: Uh, I don't know if it's good, but it looks like the kind of anime I would like.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm You got anything?
Speaker 1: Yeah, so we were watching some anime.
Speaker 1: We watched one episode of the show that was on crunchyroll and the show was called science fell in love.
Speaker 1: So I tried to prove it.
Speaker 1: And You know this show.
Speaker 1: I didn't know what it was about other than what I got a guess from the title.
Speaker 1: I guess it's based on a manga.
Speaker 1: looking at the cover of the manga I'm like, yeah, I guess the anime is a good at an accurate adaptation of the manga.
Speaker 1: What it's about is basically there are these scientists.
Speaker 1: I can't really tell what kind of scientists they are.
Speaker 1: I guess they're researchers at like a university.
Speaker 0: I guess I love scientists that it lays it layer some.
Speaker 0: They are some anime looking motherfuckers.
Speaker 1: It looks like they're researchers at a university.
Speaker 1: But basically at the very beginning of the show right is like, you know The dude is sitting at the computer doing work and then the girl who's got large boobs that are not I guess revealed though Yeah, but they're a large
Speaker 0: warning sign
Speaker 1: Yeah, and as a clearly, you know Sexual design.
Speaker 1: I guess the dude is supposed to be sexy - I guess there's a bear.
Speaker 1: I don't know anyway.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, this is the stuff.
Speaker 1: bear is a character.
Speaker 1: Okay, but I did not in episode one It's sort of like the mascot character.
Speaker 1: But anyway In the first episode she basic like.
Speaker 1: they're basically talking in a very Sort of that contrived Anime way right or like?
Speaker 1: they're real people don't talk this way.
Speaker 1: They're all like sort of like the way L talks and in Death Note, right?
Speaker 1: Only where L is doing detective logic talk they're doing science talk, right and that's the only way they ever talk.
Speaker 1: Alright, so, you know, they're talking science at each other and they're clearly have some you know belligerent attitudes towards each other.
Speaker 1: and then the girl is like Confesses that she loves the dude and the rest of the entire first episode is them Continuing to do their contrived science talk and attempting to experiment and prove and quantify love to determine if They're really in love or not.
Speaker 0: Empirically that sounds like it's very like see anime plot.
Speaker 1: that appears to be the plot of not just episode one But literally the entire show.
Speaker 1: and then there are other characters.
Speaker 1: Oh, I think the two dudes also go maybe but there was only one other Character in the first episode and that character was like a common-sense person.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so it's like they're both.
Speaker 1: You know the it's like other carry.
Speaker 1: all the side characters are all the straight men at least, you know The one straight characters and the two main characters are the messed up ones who are like science science science stuff, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah being weird Especially the dude the dude is the weirdest you get the idea that maybe the girl actually Understands and is just trying to you know, get with the dude anyway.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't know who this is for.
Speaker 1: I guess if you have this kind of particular science romance fantasy It's like.
Speaker 0: It's just like it seems.
Speaker 0: so describe it like it.
Speaker 0: Isn't that funny?
Speaker 0: It's not the worst.
Speaker 1: I guess it's funny to somebody I've seen.
Speaker 1: I've seen worse and I've seen better.
Speaker 0: So I don't really do it.
Speaker 1: No, it's a really You know formulaic kind of.
Speaker 1: you know Mass machine produced anime a court, right?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 0: See this is the kind of show that we've won.
Speaker 1: No it existed.
Speaker 1: now I know it does.
Speaker 0: Maybe we'll start when it like every now and then I watch like a one episode of a show to see if it's even worth Reviewing and if it's not.
Speaker 0: I usually just don't even say anything.
Speaker 1: This would have gotten probably like a bunch of Excitement and laughs at like an anime club showing.
Speaker 0: Yeah for younger people I would have died.
Speaker 0: this feels like the kind of thing I'd show an episode of at anime club, right?
Speaker 1: But yeah, no, no.
Speaker 0: All right, so some better news.
Speaker 0: Shira the princesses of power fourth season ended.
Speaker 1: It's four seasons now.
Speaker 0: Okay, it's real good.
Speaker 0: It's terrible secret of space plot precursor tech Like there's.
Speaker 0: I think you'll actually really like this show But I mean he-man.
Speaker 1: it's you know for as bad as he-man is right.
Speaker 1: he-man itself is about precursor tech like Did this castle come dude?
Speaker 0: if they did it a modern he-man remake in this style?
Speaker 1: I would be all about that right cuz like he-man like, you know, Prince whatever they live in like some fancy kind of future E castle somewhere else right.
Speaker 1: Castle Greyskull is like this weird thing for an ancient past.
Speaker 1: It's like a Stonehenge like.
Speaker 1: where the fuck did this come from?
Speaker 1: We don't understand it.
Speaker 1: It's like.
Speaker 0: so.
Speaker 0: I was a kid.
Speaker 0: I watched both Shira and he-man and I watched he-man.
Speaker 1: I don't remember.
Speaker 0: if I watch Shira there could not exceed the same universe.
Speaker 0: But yes, technically not because the planet she runs on like went to another dimension and there's stuff.
Speaker 1: Okay but the point is I didn't remember anything of them other than what the characters looked like from my childhood because I had toys and then and Fisto stanko her college at some point.
Speaker 0: I wanted our one he-man episode.
Speaker 1: I downloaded from a file sharing network.
Speaker 0: I think I dressed up as man-at-arms once for that.
Speaker 1: I remembered how bad and then I was like, oh this wasn't actually good.
Speaker 1: I just had nostalgia for this thing.
Speaker 1: I didn't remember.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'd stop caring about he-man forever.
Speaker 0: But all I'm gonna say I want to spoil anything but having seen all the she-ra there is to see As of now all four seasons that are out from the new Shira It just gets better and better and better and it is a fantastic show.
Speaker 1: Stop making it.
Speaker 0: It ended on a on a point where there will definitely be more.
Speaker 0: basically Grand Admiral Thrawn.
Speaker 0: Like the character is basically Thrawn Has now shown up and it's Star Wars terrible secret of space.
Speaker 0: The precursor technology has been explained.
Speaker 0: We know the deal with it.
Speaker 0: And now it's moving into like the final plot.
Speaker 1: is Admiral Thrawn the The old he-man bad guy or deck.
Speaker 1: Yeah, uh, I don't want to spoil got his name, but that's definitely him.
Speaker 0: It's calm.
Speaker 0: Yeah the skull looking guy who is the guy who's not Skeletor?
Speaker 0: He's actually sort of like who stole the baby from King Randor Princess Adora, right?
Speaker 1: He's basically sort of actually like above Skeletor and like evilness He's more competent than Skeletor.
Speaker 1: He's more evil than he's sort of like the Unicron to Skeletor as Megatron.
Speaker 0: So this gets into that in a Star Wars II kind of way and it's really interesting.
Speaker 1: He's sort of like the Emperor to Skeletor Darth Vader.
Speaker 0: So Hordak yeah, Hordak is like a full power level above Skeletor and in this show Hordak is Himself nothing more than a precursor boss to a square boss.
Speaker 0: That is like a mega Hordak Uh-huh, and the mega Hordak is the one hot and a brawny Okay, like this character.
Speaker 0: now that I've seen this character Holy shit How do they compare to?
Speaker 1: Sexy pirate man, uh I'd say 70%.
Speaker 0: Okay, 60 to 70%.
Speaker 0: Hordak himself is pretty hot too, but in a more like torture.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you get to see Hordak not in his suit.
Speaker 1: Hordak's hot and kind of sad, okay I'll be like saying like the Emperor is high like what?
Speaker 1: Basically the shriveled thing in a row.
Speaker 0: all the villains and She-Ra are hot Okay, and half of them joined.
Speaker 0: their redesigned but also original Hordak is not hot.
Speaker 0: Yes, this Hordak pretty hot.
Speaker 1: original Hordak is like clothes is like a like me like a pro wrestler body with a scary face.
Speaker 0: Oh, and there's a character double not in a good lucha way.
Speaker 0: double trouble is also pretty hot.
Speaker 0: Okay, I don't know what what I'm telling you about this show, but almost everyone is hot.
Speaker 0: You should watch the show.
Speaker 0: Okay So I also watched the first bit of Kipo in the age of Wonder Beasts, which is a never heard of this.
Speaker 0: I don't know how you didn't.
Speaker 1: this is what I hear of it.
Speaker 1: DreamWorks television Animated series that dream works only made movies.
Speaker 1: That's news to me too.
Speaker 0: That's Okay, it's on Netflix.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 0: It's very adventure.
Speaker 0: adventure time adjacent, but it's also kind of fallout adjacent.
Speaker 0: Adventure time is also fallout adjacent.
Speaker 0: So it makes a nice triangle there.
Speaker 0: It is plausible that this show basically like spiritually takes place in the intervening years between the apocalypse and adventure time and when adventure time to explore adventure time is a multi-universe universe so it could happen in an alternate adventure time universe that was simply not shown in.
Speaker 0: The plot is basically this it starts in media res.
Speaker 0: this girl Falls out of basically a vault into the post-apocalyptic world and she's totally cool like oh shit I gotta get back.
Speaker 1: You mean fallout vault not bank vault.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so she's like, oh shit How do I get back into my vault?
Speaker 1: Oh, it closed behind her.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: Yeah, sort of it's kind of.
Speaker 0: She doesn't know where it is.
Speaker 1: You can't get back in the vault and fought either.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so she wants to get back into the vault and she's in the outside world.
Speaker 0: She's like, oh, I didn't just die.
Speaker 0: maybe the outside world isn't so bad and it's full of dangerous monsters.
Speaker 0: and the thing I'll say that recommends the show the most is that the voice acting is like a Plus-plus voice acting.
Speaker 1: it's really good like it stands out above normal good voice.
Speaker 0: It stands out above normal good voice actor the voice actors.
Speaker 0: I didn't even look.
Speaker 0: Okay, I'm saving it cuz I feel like you should watch something like if they're so good.
Speaker 1: We should give them prop.
Speaker 0: I think we should.
Speaker 0: well, but we're gonna review the show for real.
Speaker 0: It's just a geek bite Am I?
Speaker 0: oh I will if you don't know.
Speaker 0: so last and least this is news, but We don't actually care about the news.
Speaker 0: We care about one Sentence in this news, right?
Speaker 1: So we we still like anime Boston the convention.
Speaker 0: It's it's in the top two Anime cons in the u.s Now we've been to I would I would argue.
Speaker 0: It's pretty safe.
Speaker 1: If you look at the schedule, if you look at the programming they bring the best guess.
Speaker 0: they really good Japanese.
Speaker 0: The way it's run its run staff are grades run relatively Well.
Speaker 1: compared to other cons.
Speaker 1: it is way up there in terms of anime con.
Speaker 1: goodness having been through it several times.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but I haven't been in quite a while.
Speaker 1: But When we went the biggest complaint wasn't something that had to do with the convention staff and the people running the con or anything.
Speaker 0: It was with the city of Boston, right?
Speaker 1: It was that the security at anime Boston was a huge hassle.
Speaker 1: Pax East also has this problem.
Speaker 0: But in anime Boston for a lot of reasons, we're not gonna get into it.
Speaker 0: It is.
Speaker 0: there are factors that make it Compounded to the point that it is an order of magnitude more a pain in the ass at anime Boston than at Pax East.
Speaker 1: However at anime Boston the behinds convention center We're only the first Pax East was held.
Speaker 1: then Pax East moved to a different convention center in the same city.
Speaker 1: But anime Boston is still held in the Heinz which is way too small Which is directly physically attached at the hip to a Sheraton Hotel.
Speaker 1: All right, so there is if you are wise a Quote secret entrance.
Speaker 1: if you go into the Sheraton Hotel and go up to like the third floor second or third floor It's the third floor near where the blood donating thing is.
Speaker 1: look for Hall C Where we're at least where it used to be.
Speaker 1: who knows where it is now?
Speaker 1: They always have a blood donation thing out of a Boston and there is.
Speaker 1: basically there's an entrance to the tiny Hallway and at the end of the tiny hidden hallway that feels like you're going nowhere.
Speaker 1: You're going like the back of a hotel ballroom or something.
Speaker 1: There's a door that goes right into the back of the artists alley of anime Boston and like most actually Smartly and greatly Kept a security guard there so that you could have your shit checked there and almost no one would use this entrance.
Speaker 0: It was super like it wasn't see there's no one knew about it.
Speaker 0: And even if you like until you get past it, it does not look like it will get you into the con, right?
Speaker 1: But yeah you could just go into the con that way instead of going out into the world and going in the main entrance or anything like That or waiting any line.
Speaker 1: so we would always use that entrance to go in and out of the con At all times and that would work as long as artists alley was still open.
Speaker 0: So enemy bosses move in the artist alley and the dealers were and making a whole bunch of very good-looking changes, right?
Speaker 1: So the changes they're making like they're explained why they're making them and they're for good reason, right?
Speaker 1: So the artists out of the dealers room, right?
Speaker 1: People want to like hang stuff from the ceiling and shit and the room where the dealers room currently is has a lower ceiling so they can't do ceiling hanging stuff and There's plenty of room.
Speaker 0: it's another credit to anime Boston just to like.
Speaker 1: They explain when they make big decisions like yeah If you want to look as an example if you're running any sort of organization and you're making a big change that might upset people This is how you make the press release to announce it.
Speaker 1: They fully explain not only what they're doing in great detail with not leaving any information out Yeah, but also their entire reasoning and explanation of why they're doing it without keeping any secrets.
Speaker 1: They're very open right but which is I approve of eight paragraphs in that there's final paragraph.
Speaker 0: there is a single sentence.
Speaker 0: quotes of final notes.
Speaker 0: The Heinz Halsey and made a very.
Speaker 1: the lead from the Sheraton third floor will now be Closed because the artist alley is now in a different place and now that secret entrance goes right into the dealers room.
Speaker 1: Well, you can't have people just come in in a dealers room at crazy-ass hours or directly from the hotel in a secret back entrance That opens up for shoplifting and all sorts of problems for the exhibitors.
Speaker 1: You can't be having that.
Speaker 1: so Because that's now dealers room area Rip secret entrance, which I I mean it sucks.
Speaker 0: But we've already kind of stopped going to anime Boston and as much as we loved it It was solely because of that.
Speaker 0: security like you write too much.
Speaker 1: But if we had still been going to anime Boston this might have been the reason.
Speaker 1: we might have been A very tiny broken straw.
Speaker 1: that not for most people people who you know, really
Speaker 0: reasonable people We're talking like us trying to lug like two giant cameras and a whole bunch of panel shit right for us
Speaker 1: Not by the secret entrance having to go in the main entrances with all their lines and having to go outside and then inside again.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that hassle would have been You know if we were still going.
Speaker 1: this announcement would make us no longer go even though Everything else having to do with this announcement is I think a smart correct move for them.
Speaker 1: Yeah, hundred percent just that one side effect is uh, you know, it's annoying and we we are intolerant.
Speaker 0: I mean if I'm walking toward lunch just like on a random day it like just in my daily life.
Speaker 0: if I walk if I go up to a place I want to eat lunch at and It looks like there's more than a 30 or 40 second line I'll just keep walking till I find a place that has a line under a minute.
Speaker 0: Like I won't wait any amount of time to eat food.
Speaker 0: Yep But anyway things of the day I did not know this gentleman existed.
Speaker 0: I don't know if I've even ever heard his name because as much as I was deep into music Like I don't pay attention to contemporary Conductors composers that much and any of that stuff.
Speaker 0: Yeah
Speaker 1: I go on Spotify and if I want to listen to classical music what I do is I find a classical song or composer that I would make
Speaker 0: a station
Speaker 1: and I right-click on and I say play song radio or play artist radio Yep, and then I don't look at what actually is playing even though I might recognize things that you know.
Speaker 1: show up.
Speaker 0: Yep, but There is a Dutch Baroque specialist named Peter Jen.
Speaker 1: all Dutch things of the day today.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I guess we didn't coordinate this Peter John Lucic and He is known for having a quote Singular conducting style.
Speaker 1: I have seen many conductors with singular conducting.
Speaker 1: I've never seen I think I have seen this one this.
Speaker 1: I have seen several.
Speaker 1: that seems to be a thing With conductors as some of them like to be, you know, sort of like how some baseball pitchers have a wild throwing motion.
Speaker 0: Yep, same guy.
Speaker 0: Oh, I as much as I hate watching baseball.
Speaker 0: I love watching weirdo pitchers.
Speaker 1: I always loved to ever play bases loaded for the NES.
Speaker 1: Almost every pitcher would throw.
Speaker 1: normally.
Speaker 1: some would throw sidearm, but then there would be a few that would throw crazy.
Speaker 0: Yeah But this guy's conducting style is amazing and Crazy, but what I want to point out because I actually am it's been a while But I took a lot of classes on conducting both orchestral conducting and field conducting.
Speaker 1: Like I'm a trained conductor This style of conduct is last time you conducted anything.
Speaker 0: I mean it's been.
Speaker 0: The last time I conducted anything was in the year.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean I had like CBR training like, you know 15 to 20 years ago, but I'm not gonna go and at one point I was you know a trained Whatever so I could still.
Speaker 1: I could still I would not make that claim today.
Speaker 0: I could easily conduct a marching arrangement.
Speaker 0: However, I do not have anything in a you
Speaker 1: believe you could
Speaker 0: I'm confident Your
Speaker 1: company partly
Speaker 0: because that style of conducting requires a lot less nuance and you don't even need to know the song Really to make it work compared to orchestral conducting Which I would need a lot of preparation to be able to do that in even like a baby's first competency.
Speaker 0: Well, you know the song first, but watching this guy one thing I will say he has This style as crazy as it looks like.
Speaker 0: I just want to say because I saw a lot of people in Twitter being like Does this actually hell like?
Speaker 0: could you actually use this guy?
Speaker 0: Yeah, you could conduct you could play to this guy.
Speaker 0: His ictus is like a plus and ictus is all you.
Speaker 0: you need ictus and form.
Speaker 0: That's it.
Speaker 0: That's all you need.
Speaker 0: You're a great conductor.
Speaker 1: What do you got me?
Speaker 0: Oh, let's talk about conducting more.
Speaker 1: No, we're good enough conducting.
Speaker 1: So another Dutch thing of the day There's the thing you may have heard of.
Speaker 1: it is the Dutch head wing headwind cycling championships and basically the way it works mustard shell deckering right in In.
Speaker 1: You know the Dutch land, right?
Speaker 1: They have this very long bridge that also serves as a sea.
Speaker 0: Well, it's the tangin wind feisten, right?
Speaker 1: It's a very long bridge that also serves as a seawall to keep from getting flooded, right?
Speaker 1: And there's also a bunch, you know It's a very windy place.
Speaker 1: and what they do is they set up this cycling championship For and they I think they actually I don't even think it has like a specific day in time.
Speaker 1: I think they like.
Speaker 1: they're like they.
Speaker 1: they're like they wait for like the windiest time and then they're like Okay, everyone they sent out the message like it's happening tomorrow.
Speaker 1: Let's go You know, it's like it's like a short notice kind of deal.
Speaker 1: I think I'm not sure.
Speaker 1: but anyway The way the competition works is everyone gets the same lame-ass normal one gear, you know every day's Bike you're not bringing like road bikes here.
Speaker 0: Yeah, because if I was gonna do this myself I would like I would basically bring a mountain bike with its tiny little baby gears, right and You have to bike straight into the super hard wind.
Speaker 1: Even though it's flat you're biking into some crazy wind.
Speaker 1: It's ridiculously difficult.
Speaker 0: I think you've made this a thing of the day like a decade ago.
Speaker 0: It's possible, but never had such high quality video explanation.
Speaker 1: Here's here's a great video of it the most recent one great explanation, you know, it's very short.
Speaker 1: You won't get bored watching this video.
Speaker 1: It's not.
Speaker 1: it's even not even ten minutes long I don't think right but it tells you everything.
Speaker 1: two minutes long You know, it tells you everything you need to know.
Speaker 0: amazing thing about.
Speaker 0: it is like they can't even get going, right?
Speaker 1: But I think I read a story that like this year They actually there was like a storm coming and they were like, hey everyone, come on cycling You know headwind cycling.
Speaker 1: and then it was too strong, huh?
Speaker 1: And they had to be like no no, it's too strong.
Speaker 1: I don't know if this was them trying again later or if this event somehow Ended right.
Speaker 1: It was cut short.
Speaker 0: And but yeah, see this is one of those things like.
Speaker 0: I love the idea of it But more importantly I love the idea of watching someone else struggle with this kind of problem.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I have zero.
Speaker 0: riding into the wind is one of my least favorite things on earth.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah I mean there was also a thing of the day very very long time ago.
Speaker 1: There's a competition in Pittsburgh.
Speaker 1: I don't know if it's a full bike race or just but there's.
Speaker 1: there's a basically.
Speaker 1: Oh, I think there might be a San Francisco one also where there's just like a ludicrously steep hill And I think it's like cobblestones - it's like fuck the fuck you Hill the worst possible Hill to bike up.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and I feel like that's another.
Speaker 0: and where the way to cheat is get a nice mountain bike and just go straight up.
Speaker 1: No pride, but it's like.
Speaker 1: but people are still just struggling to go the hill Zigzagging not moving falling over one of those mountain bikes were like.
Speaker 0: the front gear is tiny and the bag gear is huge and you're Just like.
Speaker 0: we can we can we can we can we can we can we get the whole way?
Speaker 1: Yeah, bring a special bike just to go up the hill.
Speaker 1: Even that it's like.
Speaker 1: even if you could you know Turn the crank right.
Speaker 1: you may say it's a lean like to go up that hill.
Speaker 1: You have to basically lean all the way over the front handle.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, when I was when I'm mountain biking me no suji.
Speaker 0: like when I'm mountain biking and I'm climbing a steep hill I'm basically standing forward like way over my handlebars.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah And the bikes below me and there's no seat.
Speaker 0: like you you hit a button to make the site disappear.
Speaker 1: That's the thing.
Speaker 1: is you all?
Speaker 1: you need that weight on the front other so you don't just flip over backwards Right, but you also you don't have any weight on the back.
Speaker 1: that pedaling ain't doing nothing.
Speaker 1: Yeah, pedaling a rear wheel in the air Get a bike that pedals the front wheel instead Unicycle That's not gonna get up a hill.
Speaker 0: No, I mean a normal bike but have the pedal pedal the front wheel two-wheel drive bike.
Speaker 1: Has that been made?
Speaker 0: Oh, I wonder if that's been made.
Speaker 0: I'll look that up later.
Speaker 1: So I think that might be dangerous in the meta moment.
Speaker 0: The geek does book.
Speaker 0: the book is the tale of Genji.
Speaker 0: I am continuing to learn how Kind of douchey Genji is.
Speaker 1: I just read all about Genji trying to hit on this lady and failing even though he's way hot.
Speaker 0: The more I read Genji.
Speaker 0: I don't know if it's just because I saw Urusei Yatsura and read it first and now I'm reading Genji or the other way around.
Speaker 0: But Genji reminds me of the main character from Urusei Yatsura.
Speaker 1: Like Genji's not stupid and failing at shit.
Speaker 0: That guy's actually not that stupid and when he fails it's not actually even his own fault And he's not even like ugly or anything.
Speaker 1: Genji doesn't have bad luck.
Speaker 1: Yeah Urusei Yatsura is about him having bad luck.
Speaker 1: Yeah, Genji doesn't have bad luck.
Speaker 0: Genji in fact has Astonishingly good luck, but Genji is born into luck is as lecherous as Ataru.
Speaker 1: No, he is lecherous.
Speaker 1: He is but it seems like all the men are lecherous true, but almost all of them I love like the scenes where like they talk about her actually seems while the Emperor has many ladies.
Speaker 1: Yeah, yeah, the Emperor is actually not really lecherous, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah compared compared to compare.
Speaker 0: Well compared to any other male character we interact with.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the ones who are like.
Speaker 1: yeah, I'm married to this lady.
Speaker 1: I was there with this other one.
Speaker 1: I let her go.
Speaker 1: I got this other one.
Speaker 0: It's like well, but like I finished a chapter then I like look at the notes again And it's like blah blah blah the implied attempted an affair between Genji and so and so and I'm like what I didn't even catch that one.
Speaker 0: Oh Otherwise we'll be live at PAX East which is coming up real quick next week.
Speaker 1: So today is Thursday, but this is a Wednesday episode.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right Friday Saturday Sunday Monday Tuesday Wednesday So less Wednesday, I'm doing a half day at work.
Speaker 1: I'm taking the train Doing a half day at work and go to Boston and then we'll be there until Sunday and then I guess Monday back to work.
Speaker 0: Basically our whole crew.
Speaker 0: I'm not going to work on Monday Mmm, I'm staying in Boston Monday night or Sunday night.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, but I'm you know, I'm still gonna come back home Monday morning.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'm not gonna come home and go straight to work.
Speaker 1: No, I'm gonna like work from home or whatever.
Speaker 0: Nah, I'll just take the day off.
Speaker 0: Not gonna waste a vacation day, but I guess I could work from home.
Speaker 0: We'll see how I do.
Speaker 0: I think I'm taking a later train home though.
Speaker 0: I'm taking like an 11 a.m.
Speaker 0: Train.
Speaker 1: I will quote work from home.
Speaker 0: Yeah But we will be on Saturday at 11 30 a.m.
Speaker 0: In the bumblebee theater, which seats over 600 people.
Speaker 0: We'll be saying we will be presenting a repeat panel with minor tweaks.
Speaker 0: take your fucking turn if you are listening to this you do not need to go to this panel because a Version that is 90% the same as what we're gonna do at PAX on PAX East is on YouTube already.
Speaker 1: But when we premiered this at PAX unplug Yeah, we're not even gonna bring video and record it to go on YouTube because it's already on YouTube.
Speaker 0: So but that doesn't mean if we deviate significantly or something funny happens.
Speaker 0: There will be no record of that.
Speaker 1: Oh, no, it's you're gonna waste an hour of your packs just in case like we make just in case like my pants fall down I'm teeny spontaneously make One joke that I didn't make it.
Speaker 0: But if you have a friend who perhaps should take their turn and you want to punish them Tell them to go to our panel and then at the end of the panel We're gonna tell everybody.
Speaker 0: you could have just watched this on YouTube.
Speaker 0: You just wasted an hour.
Speaker 0: So you will both punish them for not taking their turn and maybe maybe they will listen to us and start taking their turn.
Speaker 0: So ride your wave.
Speaker 1: All right, so we got another one.
Speaker 1: It seems like these days we just keep watching a lot of things from the same people Because you also is cranking out way too much content, right?
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: So here's the thing, right?
Speaker 1: If you look at the top anime directors, right?
Speaker 1: You got your Miyazaki Ghibli.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you got your hosted.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah Right.
Speaker 1: Oh, so those putting out one every three years Miyazaki and Ghibli are putting out one every century.
Speaker 1: Yeah How often it you know, but the point is Masaaki Yuasa and science Aru are cranking out not just TV shows but also movies at a shocking rate.
Speaker 1: So this movie came out in Japan months ago But finally made its way to the u.s.
Speaker 1: One night only in US theaters.
Speaker 1: some subtitles.
Speaker 1: Thanks to G kids, of course Yep, and I said, well, I guess I have to go see that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, even though we it feels like we just talked about walk on girl and also we've not that long ago Reviewed another movie that has a very very very similar.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, Lou over the wall, right?
Speaker 1: Also you awesome right and had the same producer is this right?
Speaker 1: There's Lou over the wall.
Speaker 1: walk on girl and this bang bang bang.
Speaker 1: It's like they're just.
Speaker 1: it feels like those movies are coming way too fast from from the studio Yep.
Speaker 0: And uh just to remind you before this because I want to go through some of these ping-pong the animation 2014 adventure time chain 2014 Space Dandy 2014 and then a gap because that's when they founded science Aru.
Speaker 0: and then night a short walk on girl.
Speaker 0: 2017 lower over the wall.
Speaker 0: Also 2017 Devilman crybirds baby 20 only.
Speaker 1: I think they only did one episode of space dandy, right?
Speaker 0: Director writer animation supervisor and storyboard for the episode slow and steady wins.
Speaker 1: It was like Adventure Time where there was one episode that totally insane that was by them.
Speaker 1: But you know, you also did like one crazy episode.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so this movie just the short version is.
Speaker 0: it is Absolutely worth seeing.
Speaker 0: it is a fantastic movie.
Speaker 0: It is extremely well executed and I have very few complaints about it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean there's nothing at the same time while that is all true.
Speaker 1: It's also not like oh my god It's the best movie ever.
Speaker 1: It's a legendary, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like.
Speaker 1: it's like Great, it's it's between good and great, right?
Speaker 1: But I guess maybe maybe it is great but not legendary great.
Speaker 0: What I would
Speaker 1: say is like regular great
Speaker 0: for what it is because the story it told was a relatively straightforward story Right, so
Speaker 1: I read the synopsis, right and this is not spoiler right for the movie at all because all this stuff happens Super early in the movie
Speaker 0: and also you can figure this out from the truth the teaser trailer,
Speaker 1: right?
Speaker 1: So this isn't the synopsis of the movie is okay.
Speaker 1: There's some you know, 20-somethings that live in like a beach town, right?
Speaker 0: Girls a pro surfer.
Speaker 1: the girls like a basically a pro surfer.
Speaker 1: the dude is a fireman They fall in love the dude dies and then it becomes a situation like that.
Speaker 1: You know movie ghosts with we'll be Goldberg and those other people right where the dudes a ghost at the pottery, right?
Speaker 0: I'm surprised that of all the headlining actors and actresses you might have said as ghosts, you know the movie with I was surprised you said would be Goldberg because that's a Recognizable person.
Speaker 1: the other the there's a. the main two people were just generic Hollywood hot people.
Speaker 1: I don't remember their names and I wouldn't recognize them on the street.
Speaker 1: Whoopi Goldberg is a recognizable unique individual.
Speaker 0: You don't remember who Patrick Swayze is.
Speaker 1: I know that's the name of a famous person.
Speaker 1: But if he walked into this room right now and said what is my name?
Speaker 1: I would say have no fucking clue.
Speaker 0: if Patrick Swayze he walked into this room right now Unless he looks radically different from old age or something.
Speaker 0: I would be like, wow, it's Patrick Swayze.
Speaker 1: I would say You're unusually hot person.
Speaker 1: Are you a Hollywood actor of some kind maybe?
Speaker 1: or you know famous person?
Speaker 1: Don't know your name and it's a. I'm Patrick Swayze.
Speaker 1: I'm like, I know that name.
Speaker 1: that is the name of a famous person.
Speaker 1: and then I'd say you were in things.
Speaker 1: What were you in ghost?
Speaker 1: Oh, I've seen that.
Speaker 0: Okay, but To put out like a broader again.
Speaker 0: The whole movie is just her sort of processing his death, basically Yes with a little bit of magical realism that does not necessarily need to be real It could just be in her head though There's a fun little nod at the end to make it clear there's a little bit of magic going on, but the movie is exactly what I expected it to be except The execution was so good that I actually want to bring it a lot of praise and point out a lot of very specific things.
Speaker 0: I think it did well, right?
Speaker 1: So usually the other Yuasa science saru works right are usually sort of you know Plot wise and character wise really out there and like crazy short walk-on girl I defy you.
Speaker 1: to summarize the events of that movie succinctly right to Tommy galaxy Which has the same characters basically is also it's just completely like out there kind of trippy and nutty Right devil man crybaby.
Speaker 1: That shit is fucked up and insane right now.
Speaker 1: This is really plot wise and character wise Much more in line with a very, you know down-to-earth kind of anime.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right more in line with a plot you would see from Hosoda though.
Speaker 0: But but what it really interested me is that there's actually a pretty good number of characters For how sort of zoomed in.
Speaker 0: some of them have almost no screen time, but the characters that get screen time are Surprisingly nuanced characters.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, and a lot of the things I thought oh, I guess I guess that's gonna happen.
Speaker 0: That person will date that person.
Speaker 0: None of those things happened.
Speaker 1: Oh everything I thought would happen happened.
Speaker 0: Well, the one thing I predicted very specifically was the sister and like her deal Yeah Pick that one up pretty early and I was glad that the other firemen did not date a different character.
Speaker 0: Yeah, because that's a direction a lot more pedestrian version of this movie would have gone.
Speaker 0: Well, that's wool Yeah, but the prod not the problem.
Speaker 0: But the interesting thing about this movie is that it's so soon after Lou over the wall and both this and Lou over
Speaker 1: the wall another completely crazy But
Speaker 0: they both in many ways tell a very similar story and they're both about using Water as a metaphor for the threshold of death and transformation
Speaker 1: central plots of both movies Even though one's a children's movie and one is you know a more adult.
Speaker 1: Yeah, not completely adult but a more adult romance movie and be like a teenage romance movie.
Speaker 1: Maybe how it right is that they're both about people dying at sea.
Speaker 1: Yep but it's like central to the.
Speaker 1: you know
Speaker 0: Lou over the wall was more about water and the mermaids were the metaphor for On one hand the ostensibly suicidal feelings of the main character coupled with like the processing of death coupled with the death of like ideas and culture and like the old way that town was and how things change as time goes on and The past dies eventually.
Speaker 0: This one is very literally the death of one person and the reverberations or dare I say the waves that person made both Metaphorically and literally in the world and how that affected the people around them.
Speaker 1: And then well also about the people riding those waves, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, the name of the movie comes.
Speaker 1: yeah, it's not really subtle with its message.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but it's a movie it's not to the point where you know.
Speaker 1: in sometimes there are movies where or any kind of storytelling medium where you know Their message is so sort of told so ham-fisted Lee and overtly that it's inelegant.
Speaker 1: right here.
Speaker 1: It is overt right to where they literally just spell it out.
Speaker 0: for you It's one of the rare movies that can get away with.
Speaker 0: saying the name of the movie doesn't sound stupid.
Speaker 1: It's like it's like, you know, you need to ride your wave to do that, right?
Speaker 1: But they do it in a way that doesn't feel you know, sort of you know tacked on or you know, like Uncomfortable, right?
Speaker 1: Like, you know, it feels like natural and it's just like oh, it's just not.
Speaker 1: it's you know It's like okay.
Speaker 1: You didn't really do this in an attacky way.
Speaker 1: You just did it in a way to where there's no way the audience can miss it.
Speaker 0: yep, but at the same time what I really appreciate about this movie is how Much it trusted the audience to notice things and how a lot of the subtle things that happen in the movie were not spelled out And it assumed that you would.
Speaker 1: well anime.
Speaker 1: anime does that a lot in general?
Speaker 1: Yeah, but in particular this one is at one point.
Speaker 1: There's a large time skip, right?
Speaker 1: Then there are several.
Speaker 1: you don't really know what happened in that time and it doesn't matter too much.
Speaker 1: But there are references or tiny flashbacks to things that it's not a super long time skip, but it's long enough.
Speaker 1: there are tiny flashbacks to events that happened in the time skip or Characters will reference things that happened in the time skip, but they didn't show you those things.
Speaker 1: So it's like, you know It's like if I went to rim and said hey Remember the time something happened.
Speaker 1: and the time something happened was not in the movie Yet.
Speaker 0: Yep, right.
Speaker 1: It happened during a time in the movie that got ignored, but it's still okay Right.
Speaker 1: It totally works.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: The other interesting thing is and it seems like this is a science Saru thing they hyper-researched like the details of the things they were portraying to the point that like there's a lot of very detailed long-running shots of firefighting techniques and firefighting equipment that is like Accurate to a shocking degree.
Speaker 0: the surfing is also extremely accurate.
Speaker 0: the life-saving techniques tiny little bits Like.
Speaker 0: there's two different scenes where someone like takes an unconscious person and flips them onto a surfboard or a raft, right?
Speaker 1: That's like.
Speaker 0: that's a technique you learn in life-saving right?
Speaker 1: Like I think because like I was saying this one is much more Grounded in the real world compared to their other works.
Speaker 1: right compared to say like loo over the wall, right?
Speaker 1: So therefore even though I'm sure they researched things for those other moves works as thoroughly Right say for example, I could there was like a bicycle episode of tatami galaxy.
Speaker 1: I'm sure that they researched bicycles for that.
Speaker 1: But because this is much more grounded in the real world the real world matching research shines through.
Speaker 1: It's like you can see that they put that work into it when you watch the movie Rather than whereas they might have done it for other things, but it's less visible and and you know obvious.
Speaker 0: It was weird for me cuz like I am a son of a fireman and I spent a lot of time around firefighting equipment as a kid and Part of my brain was like that part's accurate.
Speaker 0: That's a Japanese only thing.
Speaker 0: That's the.
Speaker 0: that's like this class of fire.
Speaker 1: How do you know?
Speaker 1: when we talk about anime?
Speaker 1: We talk a lot about at least on the judge anime show which will come back eventually guns.
Speaker 1: We talk about guns.
Speaker 1: It's like hey, you're reading some manga.
Speaker 1: You're watching some anime and that gun is just drawn in exquisite detail, right?
Speaker 1: It's like.
Speaker 1: well the person who made this clearly likes guns and it's clearly about the guns, right or the guns could be anything Right and it'll be the cars of the gun.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right.
Speaker 1: Well in this there are several guns in this movie, right?
Speaker 1: And I think the biggest one is coffee.
Speaker 1: coffee is the biggest gun in this movie.
Speaker 1: They're basically constantly drawing the process of making coffee and a fire.
Speaker 1: firefighting is also a gun yeah, but The detail in the drawing surfing and making amaranth.
Speaker 1: Yes the detail in the drawings An animation of people making coffee in cafes on the beach in their homes right is not only a So highly detailed and realistic right to sort of.
Speaker 1: you know Appeal to coffee fanboys who you know want to make coffee in a fancy way.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Well that co2 boom They're always doing it the exact same way every time they do it as like this, you know Repeated, you know imagery to tie, you know various scenes together because it it's subtle But it ties together.
Speaker 0: the like the interest in the topic of how to make this kind of coffee Having like spread from person to person in parallel to all the other ideas that spread like waves among these people affecting each other.
Speaker 1: Yep, yeah, cuz the dude who died was way into coffee.
Speaker 0: Yep, right.
Speaker 1: and then the everyone even after he's dead You see more coffee making than when he was a lot.
Speaker 0: But in terms of something that you clearly met a meta think right.
Speaker 1: yes people there's clearly one or more people at the studio Who are way into coffee and this coffee making process in particular also from the definitely inserted it because this coffee fan people at the Studio from the interview was.
Speaker 1: it could have been sir It could have been any.
Speaker 1: you know.
Speaker 0: on young Choi the producer they talked a lot about how much research Science are did for this movie in particular and how like they got surfing lessons and life-saving lessons I wouldn't be surprised if they like shadowed a fire department in a beach.
Speaker 1: I wouldn't be surprised that they went to several cafes.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right to watch them make coffee.
Speaker 0: And I guess like overall cuz like you just it's an anime movie.
Speaker 0: like just watch it.
Speaker 0: I'm not gonna explain the rest of the plot to you other than that.
Speaker 0: It is deeply satisfying.
Speaker 0: It's extremely well animated.
Speaker 0: It's beautiful.
Speaker 0: It'll hit you right in the feels.
Speaker 0: I cried a few times during it.
Speaker 1: I think the other thing is that you know like I was saying it's not so as crazy surreal and unrealistic as the other works by Yuasa.
Speaker 1: But he still manages to put in the trait his trademark art style Right all over it like you can tell immediately who made it.
Speaker 1: Yeah Even though it's so different in many ways because of the way the characters move the way the lines on the edge You know the characters don't like, you know whole hold their same like solid shape.
Speaker 1: Yeah Yeah, there's sort of stretchy a little bit and wiggly.
Speaker 1: you know, he always does a little bit of wiggliness and the lines on the edge of the characters are.
Speaker 1: It's almost like they're thicker and thinner at the same time because they're sort of you know, they move a little bit, right?
Speaker 1: They're not.
Speaker 0: Characters.
Speaker 0: all have like pretty unique or interesting walk cycles and like the way characters move is very tied to what they're about.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and then you know, of course the is trademark thing of sort of moving the.
Speaker 1: you know It's not a real camera, but the virtual camera perspective and all which is riding her bike, right?
Speaker 1: You know, he'll go he'll go low with wide angles or long crazy angle, right?
Speaker 1: All over the place the way he does in, you know a more a less realistic anime right, but he's still doing that.
Speaker 1: in this, you know story that is Mostly just real normal world stuff, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, but there's enough crazy stuff and magical stuff that like yeah, you couldn't make this live-action Even though it's like.
Speaker 1: so you can make like almost all of it live-action, right?
Speaker 1: But then they just you know, they make they go in an extra mile.
Speaker 1: It's like no just kidding.
Speaker 0: You could like the the ending scene of this movie like that the climax of the movie to make that without animation would be on.
Speaker 0: It would be a practical effects effort on the level of like back to the future - or Like a Star Wars.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it would not be you know doable.
Speaker 0: That is one hell of a climax - that was a good scene Yeah, so You know stretches your disbelief a little bit, but it's alright.
Speaker 0: I was totally down with the stretch of belief in that final scene.
Speaker 1: Just I was like, alright, I see what you're gonna do here Fine.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like in the interview when the producer was like, I'll go.
Speaker 0: you also explained What do you wanted to happen to the end and she was like what?
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like No, no, no, no when he storyboarded.
Speaker 1: She was like, oh That was also interesting in the interview.
Speaker 1: We learned that you know, it's like I always feel bad.
Speaker 1: You know when we talk about animes or mangas, right?
Speaker 1: Cuz a manga always like a one or two people get all the credits.
Speaker 1: when I know there were a ton of assistants aren't getting any Credit.
Speaker 1: Yeah an anime and movies this on TV shows.
Speaker 1: There's a ton of fucking people working on those things and we always just talk about like the one person, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah,
Speaker 1: but they she said in the post credit interview that like yeah You also draws a hundred percent of the storyboards themselves,
Speaker 0: which I think Satoshi kon was also that way right
Speaker 1: and it's like oh Okay, I guess I can pretty much give you the credit for this whole fucking thing.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, right as you know, obviously you you're not fully responsible for every aspect of it but in terms of you know, the the Overwhelming majority of the creative input was at your direction and from your mind You are the primary auteur of this work by far.
Speaker 1: But so I will give you most of the credit for that.
Speaker 0: but going further and I feel too bad But I felt this before.
Speaker 0: but now that we've done now that the track record is basically bat in a thousand.
Speaker 0: Science Saru is a really important ice force in anime.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah I still wonder if they're overworking their people.
Speaker 1: but more so, you know in the bad anime industry way.
Speaker 0: But on young made a really interesting have like less than a hundred people.
Speaker 0: They founded the studio basically to make that Adventure Time episode And then they made everything.
Speaker 0: but all the things they made The the rare in that they make both feature films and television.
Speaker 0: yeah, and she talked about how that's how they can have a development pipeline to give up-and-coming people in the animation industry the ability to like Try directing and try like like someone can like be the episode director for something and not like risk ruining a movie.
Speaker 1: Yeah, when you look at other anime studios the vast majority of them seem to either be in the TV business Or the movie business and sometimes video game cut.
Speaker 0: But by having both they're getting what the anime industry started to lose in Japan.
Speaker 0: If you look at all the greats we talked about and you look at like the works over their lives They all started as like key animation for episode 4 of like Gundam, right?
Speaker 1: But so, you know, I guess madhouse made movies and TV shows.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but it's like Ghibli only makes movies.
Speaker 1: Is there a Ghibli TV show?
Speaker 0: I haven't seen one but she specifically pointed out that they do it Because it lets them have the freedom to have their own internal development pipeline.
Speaker 1: It's like you're some new person or you're lower in the totem pole.
Speaker 1: We're not gonna let you make a movie, right?
Speaker 1: The movies are serious biz, but you can have a lot more creative input on the TV shows, right?
Speaker 1: I don't think you know.
Speaker 1: you also is hand drawing every storyboard for every TV episode.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'll trust someone else to draw a story so other people can express their ideas.
Speaker 1: You know something like a tatami galaxy or the new show that I watched.
Speaker 1: one episode of it I'm gonna watch.
Speaker 0: keep your hands off a Zukin.
Speaker 1: Yeah Keep your hands off a Zukin is their new show, right?
Speaker 1: and it's like there's a lot of opportunity for other creators in the studio to have a lot of creative input on those TV shows and Prove that they're good enough and maybe then work on a movie later.
Speaker 1: if they're you know, they stand out.
Speaker 1: But still they said there's less than 100 people working.
Speaker 1: They're making all this stuff.
Speaker 1: I don't know Doesn't sound like a.
Speaker 0: so they got another film coming called you know, it's supposed to premiere in 2021.
Speaker 0: It doesn't even have a Wikipedia page yet.
Speaker 0: Okay, so maybe they're taking a little break now.
Speaker 1: Is there any movie they made after?
Speaker 1: Ride your wave.
Speaker 0: not according to Wikipedia.
Speaker 1: Okay, and yeah TV shows they're making a ton, right?
Speaker 1: Yep So there you go.
Speaker 0: science are like just keep an eye on them.
Speaker 1: You see science or make anything.
Speaker 1: you should pretty much go see it.
Speaker 1: I haven't seen a bad thing that they've made.
Speaker 0: I feel like if we were younger and still like boisterous like kids going to anime cons We'd be doing that sofas dance around a con at least once.
Speaker 1: Oh the sofas dance replacing the naruto walk.
Speaker 1: Yeah Yeah, I gotta watch that again.
Speaker 1: So go see this movie.
Speaker 0: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at front row crew.com for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 0: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 1: But unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 0: It's actually recorded at night and the patreon patrons for this episode of geek nights are Alan Joyce, Heidi McNichol, Marty Gringa, JustLikeADudeGuy, Kjartavishan, Lynn Kieji, YouHoldTheKeyToMyHeart.
Speaker 0: I got in one little fight and my mom got scared.
Speaker 0: Clinton Walton, mystati.com, Jay Bantz, Ren from New Zealand, Ryan Perrin, Dropenlander, Nicholas Brandow, Chris Minkif, Mack, The Thirst for Hydrated Ganon, Dread, Lily Tenebrae, Chris Reimer, Finn, Sean Klein, Thomas Hahn, Shervin von Horl, and a bunch of other people who don't want me to say their names.
Speaker 0: And now I leave you with.
Speaker 0: Well, Mr.
Speaker 0: Burns had done it.
Speaker 0: the power plant had won it with Roger Clemens clucking all the while.
Speaker 0: Mike Sosa's tragic illness made us smile While Wade Boggs lay unconscious on the barroom tile.
Speaker 0: We're talking softball from Maine to San Diego Softball Manningley and Kenseko, Ken Griffey's grotesquely swollen jaw Steve Sax and his run-in with the law.
Speaker 0: We're talking Homer Ozzy and the Straw.