Speaker 0: It's Thursday March 26th 2020.
Speaker 0: I'm rim I'm Scott and this is geek nights.
Speaker 0: tonight We are talking about insurance because we are not experts in this field.
Speaker 0: Let's do this All right.
Speaker 0: So, uh try to avoid going to the grocery store like I'm doing it as little as I can like once a week go in With a list get everything to get out.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: Actually, it's a coincidence, right?
Speaker 1: So we used blue apron in the past to get meals delivered Yeah, and then I cancelled it when I moved and I was like, you know after PAX East I was like, you know What let's start up a new.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we're doing a bunch of delivery.
Speaker 1: We're doing and I was like we're doing the purple carrot.
Speaker 0: It's a vegan one and we're also doing this box of assorted ugly fruit.
Speaker 0: It's like stuff that grocery stores were gonna send back anyway, and they just give us.
Speaker 0: so it's like a bunch of tomatoes and celery and stuff.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so I was like, hey, why don't I try these other ones instead of blue apron, right?
Speaker 1: Let's see what they're about.
Speaker 1: I didn't want to try the which one was it.
Speaker 1: Hello fresh because Nothing, you know nothing to do with the service, but they advertise everywhere.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but they were.
Speaker 1: at one point they were marketing by harrat aggressively harassing people in the subway like they would come up to me Okay.
Speaker 1: Hey, hey, and that makes me like, alright.
Speaker 1: Well because you did that now, I'm not gonna patronize your business.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So I went and I googled and I found one.
Speaker 1: I'm like, oh, there's so many of these friggin things now It's crazy.
Speaker 1: how might how many there are?
Speaker 1: It's like picked one called home chef because it was highly rated.
Speaker 1: And then it's just and then we got locked inside after at that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, a lot of people must have started tried to start these after.
Speaker 0: well cuz fresh direct It's so hard to get a delivery slot that like they're completely overwhelmed.
Speaker 0: So a lot of people have been going to these other services like well anyone who lost their job.
Speaker 1: Why doesn't fresh direct, you know hire?
Speaker 1: Yeah, make some people to make deliveries, right?
Speaker 0: I think it might just get their supply chain too.
Speaker 1: Well, they also just don't have as many trucks, right?
Speaker 1: You get any more trucks?
Speaker 1: Yep to make more deliveries, but the interesting thing.
Speaker 0: So I wanted a delivery slot on fresh direct.
Speaker 0: But every time I checked all the slots for the next seven days were you know?
Speaker 1: Yeah, we we tried once or twice also and it's like I fuck it, but I am a member of the chef's table.
Speaker 0: So it's basically the rewards program.
Speaker 0: if you use it Basically, if you use it as your like primary or sole grocery store long enough, then they're just like, okay You're in our you're basically in our little rewards program.
Speaker 0: And all that means is instead of picking a time slot when you like finish a cart You can reserve a time slot in advance up to a week in advance And you can even reserve a recurring one Mm-hmm, but they're also allowed even in advance.
Speaker 0: I was just fucked.
Speaker 0: So last night I thought okay It's got a rollover.
Speaker 0: at some point the eighth day becomes the seventh day and appears there.
Speaker 1: Yeah, someone told me it was 6 a.m.
Speaker 1: I don't know if that's true or not.
Speaker 0: I don't think that's true.
Speaker 0: 6 a.m is when like the cutoff is for putting in orders for like Later orders that evening and there is a 6 a.m.
Speaker 0: Cut off for a bunch of things on fresh, right?
Speaker 0: But I don't think that's when the thing rolls.
Speaker 0: All right, so I thought okay I'll wait till midnight and I'll see if it rolls at midnight.
Speaker 0: and at midnight It's not that it rolled.
Speaker 0: It's that if you click to reserve It sits there forever and then times out and I think a million people are hitting a five Mmm.
Speaker 0: But basically I did discover that later in the day like around 1 p.m The slots appear suddenly, but they only appear for the chef's table.
Speaker 0: people first Fancy and then later that day they appear for everyone else and then the chef's table ones mostly seem to sell out within like an hour.
Speaker 1: Hmm.
Speaker 1: I mean the grocery store next to us still has pretty much everything that we need.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah food seller is completely stocked.
Speaker 1: Like I'm not other than like toilet paper and English muffins.
Speaker 1: They have everything.
Speaker 0: my food seller has plenty of toilet paper too.
Speaker 0: If you run low.
Speaker 1: Oh, they ran out of fresh basil.
Speaker 0: That was it, but I finally I just got lucky.
Speaker 1: I found the food seller has TP.
Speaker 0: Yeah Okay.
Speaker 0: All right, cool They basically are sold out of nothing Except if you go at certain times some things are not fully stocked because they I think they're stocking less frequently.
Speaker 0: So like when we were there last time they didn't have any fish, but they had everything else.
Speaker 0: the time before that They didn't have any non fish meat, but they had like literally everything else.
Speaker 0: Mmm, fresh direct has everything except they're completely sold out of toilet paper.
Speaker 0: Yeah, whatever.
Speaker 1: So, yeah, but yeah this home chef compared to the blue apron I have to say that on the one hand It's nice that the meals that I got were way Simpler and easier and faster to prepare who's kind of cool.
Speaker 0: That's a plus.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's a plus except Part of the reason they were easier to prepare is because they weren't like bad but they're just not as Fancy and good right like one of them.
Speaker 1: the worst thing You know, it's the old the biggest thing that like, you know it was actually like a negative check mark for me was that one of the recipes included rice and Usually when a blue apron includes rice, it's like alright, here's a packet of rice.
Speaker 1: cook it right and I put it in my rice cooker.
Speaker 1: This one had a sealed a vacuum sealed package of already cooked rice Parboiled rice fuck that.
Speaker 1: and you were supposed to Put it in a bowl with like a couple tablespoons of water and then microwave the bowl to get the rice up to Temperature.
Speaker 0: Oh, that is a sad sack TV dinner right there, right?
Speaker 1: And I couldn't even I mean it tasted fine, but it's like You just don't you forget.
Speaker 1: do that.
Speaker 1: Don't even send me the rice.
Speaker 1: I can just make my own rice.
Speaker 1: I don't need this.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we restarted Blue Apron because apparently what they did is they changed.
Speaker 0: they have fewer recipes now but it's recipes they can make much more easily in bulk.
Speaker 0: and Because we didn't get fresh direct We figured that would be a good way to start cooking real meals again without having to go out to the grocery store literally every week.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'll give the home chef another, you know a little while and then you know If it's.
Speaker 1: if it's man, maybe I'll go back to Blue Apron or maybe try another one.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's a whole bunch of them out there.
Speaker 0: I'm just trying whichever
Speaker 1: one could make a delivery happen I'll sign up for yep,
Speaker 0: because otherwise I just got to keep going to the grocery store, which I'd rather avoid if I could Alright, so, uh in the news there's a lot of news going on, but I discovered something that seemed like a joke and I kind of thought it was someone just making a joke, but then on Wikipedia I saw it and then I kept looking around and it seems totally legit.
Speaker 0: Apparently the first honorary member of the Harlem Globetrotters, you know, there's real members who actually perform But then there's honorary members.
Speaker 0: like when you get an honorary PhD, it doesn't mean you're a real doctor.
Speaker 0: It just means that the university wanted to recognize you in some way.
Speaker 0: so Apparently Henry Kissinger is an honorary member of the Harlem Globetrotters and was the first honorary member of the Harlem Globetrotters.
Speaker 1: I mean, why don't they revoke that?
Speaker 0: Right, like.
Speaker 0: I'm looking down this list of like the 10 notable Harlem Globetrotter like honorary people and the rest of the list is all great People.
Speaker 0: it's all like Bob Hope, Kareem Abdul-Jabbar, Whoopi Goldberg, Nelson Mandela.
Speaker 0: But hanging out right at number one is Henry Kissinger with and apparently he said something funny about it and Like one of the skittles in the bowl is poison.
Speaker 1: How many skittles do you eat?
Speaker 1: How many honorary Harlem Globetrotters will you will you eat?
Speaker 0: Of course at the same time if you've dropped your Jamaican beef patty into a pile of glass How much of that Jamaican beef patty will you risk eating?
Speaker 0: The answer was not zero.
Speaker 0: But uh, I do have a geek bite Emily and I. the other night we watched a movie we've been meaning to watch for a while Jojo rabbit, which Do you know anything about?
Speaker 1: I heard I heard that there was a movie called Jojo rabbit.
Speaker 1: I didn't I don't know nothing else.
Speaker 0: Treat it more like cinema.
Speaker 0: It's one of those like Oscar bait like very well done period made the movie Taika Waititi.
Speaker 0: Okay So the shtick of it, I don't know how to spoil anything.
Speaker 0: But if you put the trailers Sort of on one hand almost like give you the wrong idea of what this movie is about But on the other hand, they're actually very true to what the movie is.
Speaker 0: It's basically about a kid growing up with Hitler during Nazi, Germany.
Speaker 1: Why is it called Jojo rabbit?
Speaker 0: So what it really is is about a kid who is basically growing up as a child during World War two and He's a kid like he doesn't quite understand like everything and he's definitely bought into the propaganda.
Speaker 0: Like he's a member of the Hitler youth.
Speaker 0: He's totally into it and he has an imaginary friend like Hobbes and Calvin and Hobbes, but his imaginary friend is Hitler.
Speaker 1: His imaginary friend isn't Jojo rabbit.
Speaker 0: No, he is.
Speaker 0: His name is Jojo and The reason he is called Jojo rabbit is a plot point that I'm not gonna get into but it's the metaphor for the whole movie.
Speaker 0: But it's basically this kid with his imaginary friend Hitler traipsing around during World War two toward the end of the war and it is a Really really good movie and I hesitate to even really get into what it's really about and what the themes are.
Speaker 0: Other than that, you should watch it and I think everyone should see it be ready to cry a lot.
Speaker 1: I've seen almost every Nazi movie.
Speaker 0: There is this one's up there.
Speaker 0: This one deserves to be in the list of like Nazi movies.
Speaker 0: You need to see Uh-huh.
Speaker 0: All right Because it's it.
Speaker 0: it's hard to explain like the bits that are good about it without really spoiling main themes.
Speaker 0: But like it's Hitler and it's Hitler Hitler.
Speaker 0: But it's Hitler as imagined by a child who idolizes him having bought into the propaganda.
Speaker 0: Uh-huh, and it's just to Hitler's this like childhood imaginary friend.
Speaker 0: Let's go.
Speaker 0: Okay, it's an all-star cast.
Speaker 0: Like the the acting is amazing.
Speaker 0: The characters are great All right, whatever.
Speaker 1: Yeah What streaming service is it on?
Speaker 0: I just rent it.
Speaker 0: It came out recently.
Speaker 0: So I don't think it's on any streaming services.
Speaker 0: I rented it for $3 from Amazon Mmm, I've been using that option.
Speaker 1: You know more.
Speaker 0: yeah for a movie that I care to see like I want to see that I know is gonna be good.
Speaker 0: That's the option that it's guaranteed to be high quality.
Speaker 1: I don't have to fuss around on the high most even doing it for movies that I would might want to like rewatch Many times over the years.
Speaker 1: Mmm, right?
Speaker 1: So like Lord of the Rings movies I have on there.
Speaker 1: Yeah, cuz I don't have I wouldn't.
Speaker 1: during when everyone else is buying the DVD box sets.
Speaker 1: I refrained.
Speaker 1: Yep, so I don't have two statues of great.
Speaker 0: I still have those statues though.
Speaker 0: The hand is broken off of one of them.
Speaker 1: That's I guess appropriate.
Speaker 0: I Still have the hand.
Speaker 0: Yeah anyway But Jojo 100% a-plus movie.
Speaker 0: go see it.
Speaker 1: So back in the day We already did a geek nights episode about the Castlevania that is on Netflix.
Speaker 1: I think we only talked about season one at the time because we don't know in season one I don't know how many even episodes of season one that we saw But I did watch season two in its entirety when it came out.
Speaker 1: and season three came out I guess a few weeks ago maybe but I watched the first half of season three.
Speaker 1: So just to update anyone on that show if you only listen to that geek nights and wanted to know more I guess.
Speaker 1: So the second season kicks ass.
Speaker 1: It's a lot like, you know They're going into Dracula's castle and fighting and doing the biz and oh, yeah This is all these other characters that are hanging out with sort of like Dracula's Court of you know Helping people people that would be bosses that you would fight on the way to Dracula, you know And all that stuff.
Speaker 0: I remember people kept making fun of it in a good way.
Speaker 0: being like.
Speaker 0: it's basically like Castlevania 3.
Speaker 1: It's self-aware.
Speaker 1: So in the season three what you have is you've actually got like four different separate plot lines Going on that don't bump into each other at least not in the first five episodes.
Speaker 1: It's like clearly they're heading towards a snatch moment.
Speaker 1: All right, but to start out they're completely separate.
Speaker 1: So it's like the is a la card hanging out doing his thing with some new characters, right?
Speaker 1: completely separately.
Speaker 1: is Belmont and friend doing a thing in a creepy town with some priests that have obviously turned bad with some creepy thing going on in their church in the Like the first episode of Fullmetal Alchemist and and Saint Germain shows up there, which is a little right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, and then separately you have one of the characters from season two who is Captured by the ice queen vampire and is dragged back to the ice palace with the other three Vampire queens is like four vampire queens that run the ice palace and he's their prisoner.
Speaker 1: So that's like a plot line of what's going on in the ice palace.
Speaker 1: Yeah Right, and then the fourth plot line is one of the bad dudes who is like Dracula's helper in season two Was sort of during season two got like teleported far away.
Speaker 1: It's like the desert.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's presumably like Northern Africa.
Speaker 0: So what is he?
Speaker 0: just been walking back toward the plot the whole time?
Speaker 1: Yeah, right exactly.
Speaker 1: He's got like a. he's got like an army of beast men Night creatures because he's a bad dude and he got on a pirate ship.
Speaker 1: I guess not a pirate ship but like a cool Jamaican dude's ship.
Speaker 1: and the Jamaican dude brought him back to Genoa.
Speaker 1: Ah, he got off the be got off the boat in Genoa.
Speaker 1: So he's like on his way back with his army of Evil night creatures.
Speaker 0: I like an army of beast men because that just reminds me of slayers.
Speaker 1: So that's definitely my favorite plot.
Speaker 1: is the the evil beast guy and also the churchy one is kind of cliche But I'm into it.
Speaker 1: the ice princess one.
Speaker 1: I think could go ice print ice queen vampire one could go somewhere but it's a little man and The ala card in the woods.
Speaker 1: one is just like snooze time But at least that one doesn't take a lot of screen time.
Speaker 1: All four of those plot lines are gonna I guess converge at some point and everyone will be the party will get back together and They'll be action, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, we'll probably do a full review once we watch all of it.
Speaker 1: at this point cuz I'm watching all of it Like I'm not gonna I'm wondering how many seasons is gonna go for is like this third season can't be the final one the way.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they wrap all these four plot lines up in five episodes.
Speaker 1: I think it's a ten episode thing maybe and we've watched five.
Speaker 0: so Yeah, maybe maybe this is like the lead-up to the end and then there'll be one more season But I don't actually know.
Speaker 0: Actually, let's see number.
Speaker 0: does Wikipedia say anything.
Speaker 0: Nope.
Speaker 0: It only shows up through season three.
Speaker 0: Ah Doesn't say anything about a season four No idea.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 0: All right, cool All right.
Speaker 0: Anyway, it's time for things of the day.
Speaker 0: What do you got so?
Speaker 1: Uh What was my thing of the day?
Speaker 1: Ah, yes, everyone's trapped inside right not going out and including like famous people, right?
Speaker 1: So you're seeing lots of people are producing lots of content, you know.
Speaker 1: Posting things on you know creative endeavors.
Speaker 1: They're engaging in while they're trapped inside on the internet including famous people.
Speaker 1: So I've seen like, you know, and it's a wide range of famous people, right and and not famous people.
Speaker 1: People are getting more creative and putting more effort into posting things to like, you know share with everyone else, right?
Speaker 1: So like you just mentioned before the show Sir Patrick Stewart got CBS to let Picard be free even to people who aren't paying or the CBS streaming Tons of like.
Speaker 0: little game companies are releasing like their older games for free.
Speaker 0: So like bored kids have something to do, right?
Speaker 1: We?
Speaker 1: I just saw a video Lea's Anderson who I guess can't play hockey right now.
Speaker 1: he Just broke the record for wearing the most hockey jerseys at once.
Speaker 1: He's got nothing better to do Right, but one really interesting thing I saw was a noted astrophysicist Brian May Posted on posted on Instagram Demonstrating his guitar skills, right which?
Speaker 1: what is presumably his?
Speaker 1: the actual original You know red special guitar he made with his father and not some replica, I'm not expert enough to know.
Speaker 0: I mean, I would assume so if I had a homer bat like I would always use it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but I mean I have seen him Use not the original one before Yeah, but anyway.
Speaker 1: but you know You see when you look at a lot of guitar lessons online, right?
Speaker 1: Because I did guitar when I was in elementary school for a few years and then I tried to learn Relearn it once or twice, right?
Speaker 1: But you know, mostly you're learning like scales.
Speaker 1: You're learning chords, right, you know and You don't really see when you're taking guitar lessons how to do a guitar solo Right.
Speaker 1: It's like you just sort of get good enough to the point in which you can just go go wild improvisationally on your own, right?
Speaker 1: But here he is Showing you right with the getting his phone camera really close to the guitar twice, you know playing it slowly, right?
Speaker 1: Exactly how he plays the solo in the middle of noted song Bohemian Rhapsody.
Speaker 1: So this is like a really, you know interesting kind of thing that you don't?
Speaker 1: you don't see this, right?
Speaker 1: I've never seen a guitar lesson.
Speaker 1: I'm sure it's out there.
Speaker 1: Someone's gonna point to them, right?
Speaker 1: But I've never seen a guitar lesson that's like here's how to play the crazy solo that you know.
Speaker 0: Because like in high school we I literally get like there'd be clinics on like how to do improvisation and a lot of the Aspects of those clinics.
Speaker 0: they'd have us study and then recreate other people's Improvisational solos as practice and then we'd have to do our own solos over the same chord progressions, right?
Speaker 1: But here he's actually showing you like, you know the actual Technique.
Speaker 1: he's like.
Speaker 1: look, you know, I strum this note and but then I you know go on and off.
Speaker 1: I'm not actually strumming every note.
Speaker 1: Yeah this way in that way He's like.
Speaker 1: he's like even in such a brief Instagram video.
Speaker 1: It's actually way better at teaching Than a lot of other instructional videos I've seen.
Speaker 1: So if anyone cares about guitars Or astrophysics.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean you can read his thesis a survey of radial velocities in the zodiacal dust cloud from 2008.
Speaker 0: Yeah So my thing today real simple.
Speaker 0: This is I just found this.
Speaker 0: I don't even know where I found it.
Speaker 0: It's just this cute short animation.
Speaker 0: Dr.
Speaker 0: Mario is apparently doing a speedrun of his own game.
Speaker 0: Mario Luigi's timing him and he starts showing off and that's it.
Speaker 0: That's the whole video Dr.
Speaker 1: Mario.
Speaker 1: speedrunning is a thing a lot.
Speaker 1: I've seen a lot of people do it on Twitch.
Speaker 0: I mean, I remember my big moment of speedrunning.
Speaker 0: cuz like speedrunning has been a thing for a while But the one years ago I was thinking to myself
Speaker 1: Man
Speaker 0: I'd love to see a speedrun of like a 40-hour RPG and sure enough when I search for it I'd realize that there is a thriving community of people speedrunning like Final Fantasy 7 or some shit.
Speaker 1: Yeah Well speedrunning.
Speaker 1: Dr.
Speaker 1: Mario is interesting because you know, you're not going for score right?
Speaker 1: What you're trying to do is Beat it beat the levels with as few pieces as possible.
Speaker 1: right the less pieces used the less waiting there is.
Speaker 1: There's a little bit of RNG to add some excitement Especially toward.
Speaker 1: you're like about to clear the level and you might not get the piece you need.
Speaker 1: You've only got one color left for example.
Speaker 1: But there's also.
Speaker 1: you want to.
Speaker 1: you know, whenever you clear something if there's any pills that fall they go do do do do do And right and then you can't bring out your next pill until all the falling pieces have fallen.
Speaker 1: So you need to play in such a way that you reduce how far?
Speaker 1: Broken off pill pieces fall.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that just that just kills.
Speaker 1: Well, that just eats up your clock a whole bunch while you're waiting before you could bring out the next piece.
Speaker 1: So it's actually it's.
Speaker 1: it's pretty tough and pretty interesting way to play.
Speaker 1: Dr.
Speaker 0: Mario Yeah in the moment if you notice that we sound a little different that there's a little more pausing We talk over each other a little bit.
Speaker 0: This is the well the third time ever because apparently neither one of us remember that we did record geek nights Remotely once back in 2009 and somehow Luke remembered that even though neither one of us There's
Speaker 1: it only one episode
Speaker 0: one episode when you were already in your new apartment in the city And I was still sleeping at the Beacon House.
Speaker 0: okay during that like three-week period where we were like moving everything around and like finalizing our flight from upstate.
Speaker 0: so once in 2009 once two days ago and now today have we ever recorded geek nights remotely?
Speaker 0: it is More challenging than the normal show for a lot of reasons like the delay.
Speaker 0: While it's slight and while I it doesn't like you won't hear it in the show because I can slide things and edit it out.
Speaker 0: It does make it easier for us to talk over each other.
Speaker 0: It's harder to like key off a body language.
Speaker 0: We got to do some fucking body language.
Speaker 1: I don't see with my eyes closed Yeah, but I can see yours and with you facing away from me.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but you'll like shuffle a little bit like when I'm not when you're talking when you're saying a long thing I kind of lean back.
Speaker 0: I turn around and look at you.
Speaker 0: You don't see it cuz your eyes are closed.
Speaker 0: Nope Also just headphones like that's not as comfortable.
Speaker 0: I can't do the live stream as easily though.
Speaker 0: I might be able to start live streaming this again soon.
Speaker 0: I just didn't want to bother this week while we were testing.
Speaker 0: So yeah for the foreseeable future geek nights might sound a little weird and I just got to deal with it.
Speaker 0: It's this or nothing.
Speaker 1: Let's let's this weekend.
Speaker 1: We got nothing else to do.
Speaker 1: Let's figure out how to get to 2p one stream.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah, let's do it With video games maybe even also or anything.
Speaker 0: Yeah video versus two-player games.
Speaker 0: It'd be really good.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I just want to be able for us to both stream to a thing and for that thing to stream to the Internet.
Speaker 0: Yep, our combined video feeds because then we could play.
Speaker 0: we could play some games We could like just play counter-strike do a lot of stuff.
Speaker 0: Yeah on opposite teams.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we got time.
Speaker 0: Yeah we're gonna try to make a lot of content and stay tuned as soon as There might.
Speaker 0: there will hopefully be a point where even if the world still kind of locked down We can get together the two of us to do like in-person video.
Speaker 0: Because one thing we do want to do at some point is try to make this is warm enough to bite.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we can make panels.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we can in fact.
Speaker 0: and why they think the one conventions to go to?
Speaker 1: we just do panels without the convention and just put The panels on YouTube.
Speaker 0: Yep, but we can treat them like a panel which is very different for the way retreat Oh show like and we won't prepare restrictions.
Speaker 1: We won't have the restrictions on time We won't have.
Speaker 0: we should still force ourselves to go no more than an hour.
Speaker 0: I think.
Speaker 1: well, I mean I was thinking that we can do less than it.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, we can do an hour.
Speaker 0: We can do like we used to do at PAX is those 20-minute panels, which I love.
Speaker 1: We don't have to fill an hour and we can do whatever fucking topic we want.
Speaker 1: It doesn't have to fit the convention and no one approves or rejects it.
Speaker 0: We just do what we want Yep, and then you know what I'm gonna do once we.
Speaker 0: once we do this.
Speaker 0: I want to send them to.
Speaker 0: like y'all get all the packs.
Speaker 0: people be like look These are the panels that you have been rejecting all these years.
Speaker 0: when you want us to do the 40 games You must play for the eighth time.
Speaker 1: I could also like do some on my own or you know.
Speaker 1: So yeah, I'll probably still.
Speaker 1: I'll still make slides.
Speaker 0: Yep, but the main thing I'm gonna say it out loud on the show because I'm it's gonna force me to do it.
Speaker 0: My goal this weekend is to be able to stream with multiple camera angles myself playing DDR.
Speaker 0: Okay, I'm just gonna do DDR live streams.
Speaker 0: I got an idea how to do it and I'm gonna try it out and we'll see how it goes cuz.
Speaker 0: uh If I'm stuck inside for this long and it's gonna be like shitty and rainy all weekend I think I'm just playing DDR every day.
Speaker 0: Hmm the book club book is still the tale of Genji not the tale of Hanzo.
Speaker 0: We don't have a commute not pooping at work anymore.
Speaker 0: So I don't really have like Time to sit and read because as much as I could read I've actually been reading but I've been reading comics Which I didn't read as much.
Speaker 0: Yeah before I am also reading a comic that we'll do a show on next week.
Speaker 0: Oh good Yeah But I'm mostly playing video games and working out every video game season right now Like the other thing I'm doing this weekend and I'm not streaming it because Even my god computer cannot do VR in high quality and stream at the same time.
Speaker 1: You got to use daddy to computer.
Speaker 0: Yep I could use one computer if I turn the settings down but fuck that.
Speaker 1: Use one computer and the other computer has a capture card and does that right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, but then that's tricky with VR for a bunch of reasons.
Speaker 0: I don't want to get into right now.
Speaker 0: But yeah, it's doable It's just it's a pain in the ass But I'm gonna play through half-life Alex because every review says it's great.
Speaker 1: Yeah Any official.
Speaker 0: there was the one review of someone who played the whole game in one weekend and they were having hallucinations for weeks afterward Like real-world hallucinations from the VR world.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I feel like that edges into what happened to us when we first learned DDR And we'd like have those dreams of arrows at night like every night for weeks.
Speaker 0: So, yeah insurance.
Speaker 0: we don't know much about insurance, but we got opinions on it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we're not actuaries, right?
Speaker 1: We're not in the insurance industry.
Speaker 1: I know high-level stuff, but I think a lot of people just in general especially kids who don't learn this You know, no one ever taught me in school.
Speaker 1: So I presume no one else is learning in school like What insurance is how?
Speaker 0: Anything like and even I need a lot of people who are adults like where there is like.
Speaker 0: some insurance is stupid.
Speaker 0: Some insurance is bad.
Speaker 0: some insurance would be good But due to the lack of regulation or the lack of social safety nets is broken in some fundamental way.
Speaker 0: some insurance however is so cheap and so worth it and yet there are a lot of adults who don't buy it.
Speaker 0: like Imagine paying four dollars a month and you don't have to worry about like literally anything happening in your apartment Like you're just fine, right?
Speaker 1: So fundamentally what insurance is is gambling.
Speaker 1: you're betting right and there is some company that is betting the opposite of.
Speaker 1: You know what you're betting right.
Speaker 1: so it's like a casino, right?
Speaker 1: I bet the dice the roulette wheel is gonna come on zero zero and the casino is like I will definitely bet the opposite of that.
Speaker 0: But it's not quite gambling because there is a much more.
Speaker 0: a big component of insurance is the idea that you're distributing risk.
Speaker 0: The person who is providing insurance isn't directly betting that you yourself will not need to use the insurance.
Speaker 0: They're using data to show that.
Speaker 0: alright if we sell it to end people Odds are only n minus X people will need to use the insurance.
Speaker 0: So if we charge this much we can make a guaranteed profit of X?
Speaker 0: Well, I guess not X because I used X. we can make a guaranteed profit of Z while also providing insurance to all these people and being able to pay out anyone who has a problem.
Speaker 0: and then Often those insurance companies will then get another insurance company to cover what might happen if suddenly Everybody needs a pad all at once for some reason, right?
Speaker 1: So for example, let's say I have a you know You're betting that something bad will happen to you.
Speaker 1: right and in that way I'm placing that bet if nothing bad happens to you.
Speaker 1: Well, you lost some money, but nothing bad happened to you.
Speaker 1: Yeah, okay, but also bad.
Speaker 1: if the bad thing does happen Someone is gonna take a bunch of use a bunch of money and take corrective action To fix as much as possible the bad thing that happened to you.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well like you broke your arm in Australia and you had trip insurance.
Speaker 0: Mmm, I mean Australia has good health care.
Speaker 0: So it wasn't that important but still the insurance was like, alright Here's a giant pain in the ass is gonna happen to you and we are obligated by law to throw money at that problem.
Speaker 1: So let's say there's a risk you have in your life, you know, I'm going on a vacation.
Speaker 1: There's a bunch of risks involved with going on a vacation.
Speaker 1: What if I lose my luggage?
Speaker 0: Yeah, what if I get sick and can't go?
Speaker 0: what if?
Speaker 0: what if I get trapped?
Speaker 0: What if the player line shuts down while I'm there right?
Speaker 1: There's so many things that can go wrong on a vacation, right?
Speaker 1: So the insurance company is like they don't come to me like Scott and say hmm Scott We're gonna bet your vacations gonna go wrong because that would just be gambling for both of us.
Speaker 1: Like who knows?
Speaker 1: Yeah, they're not gonna make that bet but they do know.
Speaker 1: aha All right.
Speaker 1: Well with this list of things that can go wrong on a vacation What are the odds, you know, what percentage of people who go on vacation have one of these things happen to them, right?
Speaker 1: So it's like okay of a million people go on vacation 1% of them lose their luggage an average.
Speaker 1: it cost them about this much money to replace the lost luggage and solve their problem Right.
Speaker 1: So we want to charge them less than that amount individually, right?
Speaker 1: No one wants to.
Speaker 1: because if you if the purse individual person has to pay that amount to replace their luggage Well, it's like.
Speaker 1: well, why did I?
Speaker 1: I'm not gambling?
Speaker 1: because I could just save that money and fix the problem myself with the money.
Speaker 0: Yep, right like one way Mitigation.
Speaker 0: one way to mitigate risk is if I'm going on a trip I could set aside $40,000 as my emergency fund and not touch it till I get home from the vacation, right exactly.
Speaker 1: So you they need to figure out okay, how many people will have the problem?
Speaker 1: How much is it gonna cost on average?
Speaker 1: Yeah And then can we charge a large number of people a small amount of money?
Speaker 1: Less than the amount it costs to fix the problem for one of the people, right?
Speaker 1: Every individual person who's paying for the insurance is paying less than what it would cost to fix the problem for themselves.
Speaker 1: But total you add up all the little bits of money from all the people and you say, alright well all those little bits of money from all the people.
Speaker 1: only this percentage of people have the problem and that'll so and we can.
Speaker 1: So we lose that money to fix people's problems.
Speaker 1: But there's still money left over because so many people signed up for it and such a small percentage had the problem And we figured out exactly how much to charge where they're actuarial mess that we the insurance company make a bunch of money
Speaker 0: And even better they often because if it's a large insurance company They cannot use that data and use their Operational efficiency to make it cheaper for them to handle that kind of problem than any individual person could make it.
Speaker 0: so like they might have a relationship like a travel insurance company.
Speaker 0: a real one a good one probably has Relationships with most of the major airlines and they can like cut deals Like if you cancel your trip they work at work with Delta or whatever to put give those tickets to someone else and They actually cost them less to deal with the problem that it would cost you on your own.
Speaker 0: talking to the airline or the airline On their own without an insurance company managing this risk pool, right?
Speaker 1: You the negotiating power of one person is pretty weak against a giant airline, right?
Speaker 1: You go to the airline and something bad happens, right and you don't have insurance.
Speaker 1: So you just go and fight with them.
Speaker 1: You're like, I want the money back.
Speaker 1: They're like no Deal with it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you signed up for this flight.
Speaker 1: you you know, whatever right but the travel insurance company is like We have this many customers, right?
Speaker 1: We can you know, we have Bargaining clout with you.
Speaker 1: We're also a big company with a shit ton of money.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right airline You better do this for our customers and it's like oh, okay.
Speaker 1: So that means you know the cost to reschedule my flight on my own would be a thousand dollars But the insurance company has a with their bargaining power and negotiated the airline down.
Speaker 1: It's only five hundred dollars and I'm indirectly benefiting from that Discount bargaining power because the insurance company is taking care of the biz for me.
Speaker 1: Yeah I don't have to go in and negotiate with the airline myself.
Speaker 0: now on a high level the idea of distributed risk and insurance Is like yeah, I don't know how many of you might be stupid libertarians or something.
Speaker 0: It is a necessary part of modern society.
Speaker 0: There is a reason insurance the concept of insurance has existed for a long long time but at the same time We use insurance for a lot of things We really should be using something else for like for example health care.
Speaker 0: the fact that you have to have health insurance is ridiculous because Some kinds of insurance are purely optional.
Speaker 0: Like do I want to pay the seven dollars for insurance on my Amtrak to Rochester?
Speaker 0: Or do I my willing to eat the possibility that I might have to deal with some trouble on this trip?
Speaker 0: Like.
Speaker 0: that's a reasonable cost-benefit analysis that a person could make to decide if it's worth it.
Speaker 0: But no one should have to decide whether or not I think I'm gonna get sick in the next ten years.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's not a thing.
Speaker 1: You should be betting on.
Speaker 1: that's just a risk that should be eliminated completely.
Speaker 0: Yeah, insurance gonna happen.
Speaker 0: insurance should be one means of eliminating risk But we should not use it as the sole means of eliminating or mitigating risk.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean assurance is is best for things that will affect a small number of people right but could potentially Inflict a large number of people or likely or for things They're all.
Speaker 0: insurance is also good for things where an adult of sound minds can reasonably be expected to make a decision About whether or not they need this protection or are willing to assume that risk.
Speaker 0: Like there are some risks that we allowed.
Speaker 0: people like I I ski I am allowed to assume the risk of skiing.
Speaker 1: I am not allowed to assume the risk of fighting in a gladiatorial deathmatch Mm-hmm, except unless I'm on the barge Right, but the point is is that you know Even dangerous dangerous skiing a large percentage of the people who ski don't get hurt at all.
Speaker 1: Yeah but I but I can everyone who skis put in a little bit of money to cover the people who did get hurt skiing.
Speaker 1: the People who didn't get hurt wouldn't be losing that much and they would gain peace of mind Knowing that if they fell off the ski lift, they would be taken care of with money.
Speaker 0: The problem is what actually covers that is just people's health insurance.
Speaker 0: But there is a sort of form of interesting a hypothetical ski insurance.
Speaker 0: But you're closer to the mark than you realize because there is an implicit built-in ski insurance and especially at resorts And that is ski patrol.
Speaker 0: because basically to ski you need a lift ticket.
Speaker 0: That's the thing that allows you to go up the lift.
Speaker 0: A lot of resorts like you can hike up the mountain if you want then, you know what I got.
Speaker 0: You don't gotta pay or you gotta pay like 10 bucks for like a mountain pass But it takes all day to hike up the mountain.
Speaker 0: you ski down once now the sun's down you're done.
Speaker 0: So you pay for the lift ticket?
Speaker 0: The lift ticket doesn't just pay for like all the staff of the resort to make things work and all that stuff.
Speaker 0: It also pays for the support structures around ski patrol.
Speaker 0: and ski patrol are the people who are basically skiing all day But they're also EMTs and experts.
Speaker 0: They're the ones who will save you if you hurt yourself on the mountain And so effectively.
Speaker 0: and it's not just your lift ticket fees that pay for that.
Speaker 0: it's also a lot of skiers when they get older volunteer to be ski patrol to sort of like pay it forward and you basically have The system where if you go to any modern ski resort like anywhere in the world There will be people who will not charge you any money and will basically do everything they can to save you if you hurt yourself Or have a problem on the mountain, so we all pay in and then we all reduce our risk for everybody, right?
Speaker 1: But the point I was trying to make is that with the ski the theoretical ski insurance a lot of people never get Never file a claim.
Speaker 1: Yeah, never get paid out like look.
Speaker 0: I've been skiing for about 20 years, but I have health insurance.
Speaker 0: I've had two series.
Speaker 1: everyone gets paid out on health insurance.
Speaker 1: You are going you're a human being you're mortal.
Speaker 1: in some time in your life Every single person is going to be need to get paid out, right?
Speaker 1: So insurance is a good model for something where a small percentage of people in the in the pool Ever make a claim.
Speaker 1: if you have an insurance and everyone is posting is making a claim at some point That's not a thing that we should be using insurance to help out with.
Speaker 0: yeah exactly Which ties back into that idea that it can't.
Speaker 0: it has to be something that a person can reasonably Choose to accept that risk.
Speaker 0: and if we don't let me fight in a gladiatorial arena We wouldn't let.
Speaker 0: we shouldn't let me decide.
Speaker 0: I don't ever need to go to a doctor in my entire life Right?
Speaker 1: so some other things you know insurance from like the non.
Speaker 1: There's a consurances that people don't see when they're not a can because they're only consumers.
Speaker 1: right you're consumer.
Speaker 1: you see.
Speaker 1: car insurance?
Speaker 1: Yeah, right.
Speaker 0: renters insurance homeowners insurance.
Speaker 1: Right travelers insurance.
Speaker 1: We just talked about pet insurance recently.
Speaker 0: Yeah, my work started offering it, but then there's like like packs like conventions venue insurance event insurance There's all this like back-end insurance that has to exist for a lot of the things you do in your life to even be offered As services right.
Speaker 1: so it's like all right.
Speaker 1: I want to start a. you know a business.
Speaker 1: What's your business?
Speaker 1: I don't know a grocery store all right well I need insurance that is going to cover right.
Speaker 1: if Someone eats food in my store and gets sick and tries to sue me right which you're right Then I need this insurance to help me out.
Speaker 1: Yeah, to sort of cover my ass
Speaker 0: like I was you know happen like you know my last job Ibo's effectively like I did a lot of our risk assessment and one of the things I had to review was all the different kinds of insurance we have for some sock audits and things.
Speaker 0: and Like even a tiny company that has like 30 or 40 employees We had like five different types of insurance to cover all the kinds of crap that can happen in the kind of industry we were working in.
Speaker 1: and Because if any one of those five things happened, and you didn't have the insurance you would be boned yep.
Speaker 0: And it gets complicated like there's this concept of umbrella insurance and even like a tiny business like geek nights We could get umbrella insurance.
Speaker 0: It's basically insurance that covers Anything fucky that could happen that isn't specifically excluded and or specifically usually covered by other kinds of insurance.
Speaker 0: But then you get specific stuff like indemnity insurance or like.
Speaker 0: you can get insurance against what if some?
Speaker 0: what if an engineer?
Speaker 0: Pirate some code like steal some source code and puts it in your product and like no one noticed And then you get sued.
Speaker 0: you can get insurance for that specific thing All right, and then you just fight.
Speaker 1: You know you.
Speaker 1: if you didn't do it on purpose because your company like you know the thing that happened you were car.
Speaker 1: It wasn't your company's actual strategy.
Speaker 1: You know where you're supposed to get sued for that Just be like oh oops my bad settle out of court.
Speaker 1: the insurance money takes care of it yep.
Speaker 1: So I think the insurance that's in that category that most people are aware of is doctors malpractice insurance Yep, which is a form of indemnity insurance.
Speaker 1: Yes, it's like you're a doctor And it's like you're doing your best at doctoring and even if you follow all the best things as a doctor.
Speaker 1: It's like Medicines messy yep, and you know There's lawyers out there, and there's people who go to the doctor and if their experience isn't perfect They're gonna try to sue the doctor that equivalent exams are right and sometimes They're wrong.
Speaker 0: that equivalent exists for everything like one of the other one.
Speaker 0: I remember.
Speaker 0: I'm just looking at like old emails I said to remember the stuff.
Speaker 0: cuz I'm not I'm running.
Speaker 0: we are getting down to the depths of what I know about insurance, but Errors and omissions insurance is pretty fun too because that's basically the yeah if we fuck something up like sorry We're good work.
Speaker 0: It's not our big talk to those guys.
Speaker 0: They'll pay for it.
Speaker 1: the most fascinating insurance that I'm aware of is prize insurance, right?
Speaker 1: So let's say you want to run a contest or like a game show and you have like some huge jackpot or something right?
Speaker 1: But it's sometimes you have a guaranteed jackpot.
Speaker 1: That's like someone's gonna win the jackpot.
Speaker 1: It's these odds and you have some way to pay for it.
Speaker 1: But sometimes it's like you say you're running.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: freaking jeopardy.
Speaker 1: the TV show right.
Speaker 1: It's like most people per episode are only winning like thousands of dollars.
Speaker 1: right?
Speaker 1: you're a big TV show with big sponsors.
Speaker 1: You can pay for that.
Speaker 1: It's not a big deal right, but if you have like Small chance of the jackpot that could happen, but hardly ever happens probably won't happen right?
Speaker 1: you can get insurance Prize insurance right.
Speaker 1: a good example would be that Who wants to be a millionaire show?
Speaker 1: no?
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm pretty sure that show had insurance in case someone became a millionaire.
Speaker 1: right because most Contestants weren't gonna win a million dollars.
Speaker 1: most contestants We're just gonna win thousands or less.
Speaker 0: and it's still not really super gambling.
Speaker 0: because think about how that would work.
Speaker 0: the company that would Issue insurance to a game show like that would issue it to a lot of game shows Right and it also it wouldn't necessarily be the cheapest insurance.
Speaker 1: Yeah They would do the math and figure you can like that's.
Speaker 0: that's manually under written insurance.
Speaker 0: if you want to ensure something weird like what?
Speaker 0: Was that thing?
Speaker 0: we're gonna put this diamond on the front of an f1 car as a stone.
Speaker 1: Have you ever seen if you ever read the Mongo or watch the anime master Keaton?
Speaker 1: Where he's?
Speaker 1: he's an insurance inspect.
Speaker 0: also try gun fruit.
Speaker 0: Yeah, try gun and master Keaton are about the same thing.
Speaker 1: All right, they're my insurance inspector.
Speaker 1: He's working for Lloyd's of London, right?
Speaker 1: So someone filed an insurance claim and he goes out to make sure it's legit and not insurance fraud of some kind.
Speaker 1: Right and he ends up in crazy situations because these aren't normal everyday insurance claims Like big-deal crazy insurance claims, I'm like a famous painting got stolen or all, you know all kinds of nonsense.
Speaker 0: So other than health insurance Which is a topic that is way Beyond the scope of what we want to talk about in this show The insurance that I'm I've always been the most mad about in my entire life But for a lot of kind of complicated reasons is car insurance.
Speaker 0: That's the one I'm mad about because I'm what and it the rent Scott and I would talk about this a lot at RIT.
Speaker 1: Well when cars mattered more and we had less money to pay for insurance, yeah, I couldn't afford.
Speaker 1: now I don't have to pay car insurance.
Speaker 1: now I just don't have a car that has everything.
Speaker 0: and I just had like PLPD like I had the shittiest Possible insurance I could like.
Speaker 0: that was I was allowed to get on my car.
Speaker 0: But when it came to comes down to the reason I'm mad about car insurance, is that one?
Speaker 0: The fact that you can cause so much damage with a car to other things around you You should have to have some insurance to cover the damage you might cause.
Speaker 0: Like I feel like that's me recursively.
Speaker 1: I think we shouldn't require car insurance, but I also think that You shouldn't be allowed to drive unless you're like a fucking super expert incredible driver.
Speaker 0: Well, let's get it.
Speaker 1: Also, if you I also believe that if you fuck up driving even once even if you small fuck up driving I'm talking like you're driving and there's a red light and your car goes over the white line a little bit because you weren't perfect at Driving.
Speaker 1: banned from driving forever.
Speaker 0: You would be banned from driving then sure.
Speaker 1: That's fine.
Speaker 1: Not a super expert driver.
Speaker 1: And also, I think that if you are caught driving when you're not supposed to like you got banned from driving forever and you drive jail Fuck you.
Speaker 0: See I'm thinking more along the lines of the problem I have with car insurance.
Speaker 0: Was that all car accidents?
Speaker 0: Like well, ninety nine point nine nine nine percent of them.
Speaker 0: There's a tiny tiny like vanishingly small percentage of car accidents that are caused by Flukes of nature or you know force majeure Like a tree falls on your car.
Speaker 0: Yeah Like a tree that had no outward problems in clear sunny weather just like fucking falls over on your car while you're driving.
Speaker 0: What are you gonna do right?
Speaker 1: You're right You're driving down the road and something literally like just shoots out into the road from the side.
Speaker 1: Yeah, dear, but and you there's no way you could have seen it is impossible Yeah, and you weren't even speeding or anything.
Speaker 0: but most car accidents.
Speaker 0: It is there.
Speaker 0: it is very clear that one of the drivers caused that accident due to negligence.
Speaker 0: like exactly all the time There's almost always the negligent party and what I was always mad about as a kid Was I was in Michigan and I had to.
Speaker 0: I got my first car and I got car insurance And I learned about the concept of no fault insurance.
Speaker 0: on one hand It's good and that it prevents a situation where everybody's suing everyone all the time every time there's a car accident But on the other hand it removes
Speaker 1: the
Speaker 0: punishment or the it removes a way to punish or otherwise Force the consequences of a poor decision out of the person who made that poor decision Like someone who's a shitty driver and causes accidents.
Speaker 0: The only consequence to them really if they don't die in a car accident is that their insurance slowly costs more over time.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the other thing is that the whole car situation breaks into too many social justice areas.
Speaker 1: It's like oh, we're gonna start punishing drivers the way Scott just said.
Speaker 1: Okay, all the black people going to jail?
Speaker 1: Yeah like there's not or even just can't.
Speaker 0: what about like old people and people who have Disabilities where the car is the only way to get around because there's literally only one city Episode that's now insurance because there's only one city in America that has real mass transit.
Speaker 0: We happen to live in it like.
Speaker 0: But I'm just.
Speaker 0: I was mad as a kid about the fact that car Insurance did not force the person who was at fault to pay for all the damages.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean or at least cause their insurance to pay for all the damages.
Speaker 0: I didn't want my insurance to have to pay for someone else's damages if they hit me from behind.
Speaker 0: That's what I was mad about.
Speaker 1: It's it's a it's a. it's a double miscarriage of justice, right?
Speaker 1: On the one hand if we always correctly punish the person who's bad at driving Right, we will then cause because our society is car, right?
Speaker 1: Unless we fix that by winning the war on cars because we'll
Speaker 0: partly punish we
Speaker 1: think right unless we win the war on cars then as long right as long as you have a car culture if we if we Justifiably punish anyone who fucks up at driving that will be a miscarriage of social justice.
Speaker 0: Yep, like for example, we want everyone to be good We have to get rid of cars.
Speaker 0: most people in America even I mean a lot of people are bad drivers Even though there's no excuse.
Speaker 0: like a a lot of people got real driver's ed and learned how to drive They're just shitty drivers.
Speaker 0: But there's also a lot of people who probably just didn't have access to good driver's ed.
Speaker 0: Like if you go to a shitty school, it'll hurt like in the middle of nowhere.
Speaker 0: How are you gonna learn how to drive?
Speaker 0: Well, like how do you have time for that?
Speaker 0: Yeah, but you still need to drive much going on with the car department.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm at the insurance department Yeah, but I was mad.
Speaker 0: the thing I was mad about and I'm still kind of mad about it is the lack of significant consequences for the people who cause damage with their cars and the fact that Everyone has to have insurance and we kind of just paper it over by just having you know fault insurance and kind of.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so the the last insurance I want to talk about are these Insurances that I've looked into frequently, but never actually purchased.
Speaker 1: And so these are basically these niche Insurances for like specialties, right?
Speaker 1: So I looked at bicycle insurance.
Speaker 1: I've looked at camera insurance because our cameras aren't like mega expensive, but they're not mega cheap either.
Speaker 0: I paid for the insurance for my camera and that paid out dividend.
Speaker 1: You're just talking about the be like the warranty stuff, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah I'm talking about like an actual insurance plan with a premium that you keep paying yearly.
Speaker 0: I did look into one of those and the reason I didn't do it was very specific the cost of the like.
Speaker 0: I Forget what it was called.
Speaker 0: It wasn't because they had like a studio one for I forget even who I looked at.
Speaker 0: This was years ago.
Speaker 0: If you have a studio and your cameras tend to stay in the studio You can get a pretty cheap insurance that'll cover any accidents that happen to the cameras in the studio.
Speaker 0: But if you're carrying the camera around outside the studio, they wouldn't cover it.
Speaker 0: You have to go get a different kind of insurance.
Speaker 1: Yeah, yeah But I'm saying like these are specialty insurances for special kinds of expensive stuff you might have.
Speaker 1: Right, and the thing is it's like I kind of want bike insurance.
Speaker 1: I'm in New York City.
Speaker 1: My bikes aren't mega expensive.
Speaker 1: I've seen you know, but they're not super.
Speaker 0: but my renters insurance covers that my bike.
Speaker 1: It covers some things but doesn't cover everything.
Speaker 0: if my bike stolen it covers it.
Speaker 0: That's really the only thing I'm actually worried about.
Speaker 1: Sometimes depends on the exact circumstances and such right.
Speaker 1: but You know, so I was like, hey, why don't I get some extra bike insurance?
Speaker 1: That way I can like lock my bike up outside without even giving a shit.
Speaker 0: Ah, yeah Cuz that's you know, we didn't talk about this in the beginning.
Speaker 0: That's it's not just that you're mitigating your risk It's also that now it's something you don't have to worry about it.
Speaker 1: Right the people who buy insurance who don't file a claim are buying peace of mind.
Speaker 1: Yep, so I was trying to buy peace of mind to say oh if my bike gets stolen Whatever.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and because there were because normally if you get like I claimed on renters insurance once they give you the current value of The stuff you lost.
Speaker 1: so I had an old TV.
Speaker 1: It's like alright.
Speaker 1: Well, here's what the old TV is worth.
Speaker 1: You can't necessarily buy that same TV with that money.
Speaker 1: Yeah I've seen bike insurances that will give you what it costs to buy that bike when you bought it.
Speaker 1: So you would get your bike when it was new.
Speaker 1: you would not get like oh some depreciated value amount of money.
Speaker 0: But doesn't that create a perverse incentive to trash your own bike to get a new one?
Speaker 1: You don't commit insurance fraud or else the master Keaton will come after ya.
Speaker 1: but anyway, so I looked at that insurance and it was actually a good deal.
Speaker 1: if You were professional and you had super expensive bikes and you raced bikes my level of bike is like too Expensive to leave on the street but not expensive enough to be worth buying insurance.
Speaker 1: the same thing for my cameras, right?
Speaker 1: I'm not a TV station with a pile of expensive cameras.
Speaker 1: I have it like.
Speaker 1: I have more expensive cameras than the average person.
Speaker 1: So the camera insurance wasn't quite worth it.
Speaker 1: The premiums are too high.
Speaker 0: Yeah, my my most expensive camera is like three grand like okay that is not expensive by professional camera standards at all.
Speaker 0: and to like the Warranty insurance like the what do you bought it on Amazon like paying the hundred bucks or whatever was Way cheaper than the premiums on camera insurance, right?
Speaker 1: so that while the insurance company would be happy to have me join the insurance pool and help them pay for When a TV studio loses all its cameras and an earthquake you wouldn't get much out of it, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, if I had to file a claim it's like well I could have just taken the money I spent on premiums put it in a savings account even with no interest and Been able to buy all new camera stuff, right?
Speaker 1: So the premiums you're paying have to be small enough That you're pert that they're less than the amount of stuff you're protecting the only exotic insurance I ever actually got.
Speaker 0: but my parents got it.
Speaker 0: I didn't get it as a kid.
Speaker 0: I actually had an insurance policy specific to my fancy trumpet Mm-hmm because that was at the until I bought a car.
Speaker 0: that was the most expensive really cheap insurance though.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, it was.
Speaker 0: the premiums were like $15 a year.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah one of those It insured up to like $5,000 worth of trumpet related damages.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I've seen a lot of musical instrument insurance.
Speaker 1: It's especially because you know, some people have like, you know, not only is the musical instrument like their life leehood But it's irreplaceable Right.
Speaker 0: Some of them are irreplaceable and some of them aren't or some of them just I was watching a video recently on like how to repair a damaged violin.
Speaker 0: basically, the answer is there's a handful of people who are extremely skilled and cost basically an infinite amount of Money to even talk to right.
Speaker 1: So if you have a violin that needs one of those people you better have insurance.
Speaker 1: You'll pay for one of those people or be rich.
Speaker 1: Yeah, even if you're rich the insurance can make sense.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I guess the last insurance that people think about that's a little different is life insurance.
Speaker 0: Yep, I've got some life insurance.
Speaker 0: That's that's peace of mind for the people around you.
Speaker 0: But I don't want to get too deep into the weeds on this like right.
Speaker 1: The only thing with life insurance that makes it weird right is that you buy life insurance on Yourself, right?
Speaker 1: So normally all these other insurances you're paying to cancel out your own risk.
Speaker 1: And then when you file a claim you get money.
Speaker 1: with life insurance you're buying it you're betting that you will die and The payout goes to someone else.
Speaker 1: You're protecting someone else's risk in the case that something happens to you.
Speaker 1: No one else's.
Speaker 1: I'm not you know, you're not buying life insurance on me.
Speaker 1: I'm not buying life insurance on you, but maybe I should if you know.
Speaker 0: key though a company's.
Speaker 0: It's not that uncommon for companies to have life insurance on their key employees.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well companies buying insurance against the super valuable employee will often restrict that employee from engaging in different behaviors in their micro hoolick and the.
Speaker 0: You're not allowed to own a motorcycle clause.
Speaker 1: Well, I'm saying like professional athletes It's like they.
Speaker 1: often professional athletes won't obey the rules But you know the the sports team will be like in their contract with the player is like hey You can't do all these crazy things.
Speaker 1: You're not allowed or else we can void your contract.
Speaker 1: because You know, we put a lot of money into you right?
Speaker 1: Our team is riding on your human body.
Speaker 1: You're not allowed to put your human body in at these unnecessary risks.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right and maybe they'll have insurance to cover that.
Speaker 1: in case you know insurance.
Speaker 1: if the player gets her insurance If the player does something stupid and breaks the contract right protect We need protection because we just gave this guy a deal for 200 million dollars to play baseball.
Speaker 1: And if you can't throw the ball anymore, all right.
Speaker 1: Well, we're in deep shit.
Speaker 0: Alright, I think we killed enough time This weekend.
Speaker 1: I've got any more show ideas.
Speaker 1: Yeah end of in.
Speaker 0: I mean next week's easy.
Speaker 0: It's a. it's a Monday Wednesday There's actually.
Speaker 0: I got a lot of Monday stuff to talk about.
Speaker 1: How are you gonna do your tech news around news around up?
Speaker 0: It's time My body is ready.
Speaker 0: and then Wednesday, we're gonna review a manga.
Speaker 1: Yep All right, and yeah, come check us out on YouTube every streaming place discord twitch Twitter Everyone.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: All right This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Speaker 1: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 0: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 1: But unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 0: It's actually recorded at night And the current patreon patrons for geek nights this episode in particular are Alan Joyce Heidi McNichol and Marty gradient.
Speaker 0: just like a dude guy can art ovation linky G you hold the key to my heart.
Speaker 0: She said you're moving with your auntie and uncle in Bel Air.
Speaker 0: Clinton Walton J Bants ran from New Zealand Ryan parent rope and Lander Nicholas Britain now Chris midkiff the thirst for hydrated Ganon dread lily tenebrae Chris Reimer Finn Sean Klein Thomas on Shervin von Horrell and a whole bunch of other people who don't want me to say their names.
Speaker 0: This is much harder than it used to be because the if the name is more than like 20 characters I have to hover over it to actually see the full thing.
Speaker 0: It tripped me up a little on the Fresh Prince lyrics.
Speaker 0: anyway Now I leave you with.
Speaker 0: Well, mr.
Speaker 0: Burns had done it.
Speaker 0: the power plant had won it with Roger Clemens clucking all the while Mike Sosa's tragic illness made a smile While Wade Boggs lay unconscious on the barroom tile.
Speaker 0: we're talking softball From Maine to San Diego.
Speaker 0: talking softball Manningley and can say co Ken Griffey's grotesquely swollen jaw Steve Sachs and is running with the law.
Speaker 1: We're talking Homer Ozzie and the straw.