Speaker 1: It's Tuesday July 14th 2020.
Speaker 1: I'm rim I'm Scott and this is geek nights tonight.
Speaker 1: We were talking about console modding.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: So, uh, you know, I'm pretty particular about my phones my smartphones.
Speaker 1: I like them to be small but still full-featured like there are tiny Android phones, but those tiny Android phones are like Garbage phones.
Speaker 1: Yep, and there were small Android phones But the last one that anyone made as far as I can find that was worth a damn is the Sony Xperia zx1 or xz1.
Speaker 1: I just forget the order of those two letters.
Speaker 0: comes that is that is that running an unmodified Android?
Speaker 1: While it is not unmodified Android.
Speaker 1: the weird thing about Sony unlike all the other phone manufacturers that put their bullshit on there The Sony Android is 99% regular Android and stays up to date.
Speaker 0: Oh, so it's that you have the newest possible Android whatever the one that is.
Speaker 1: Yep, I'm very I'm very clear.
Speaker 1: I have Android 9 something right now.
Speaker 0: What's the newest Andrew?
Speaker 1: I don't know what the newest one is offhand.
Speaker 1: actually cuz I was just checking this stuff out.
Speaker 0: 11 your two versions behind.
Speaker 0: That's fine.
Speaker 1: I can live with that But does it not have 11?
Speaker 1: I think I can get it to 11.
Speaker 1: I'm fun.
Speaker 1: So the reason this comes up is my phone is multi multiple years old and finally running out of steam.
Speaker 1: Uh-huh, like the battery is starting to not last that long.
Speaker 1: but way back I bought a second copy of this phone.
Speaker 1: Yep, just in case to hold out and I'm pretty sure once that second one dies I'm just gonna go iPhone because there are no Android phones worth a shit after this.
Speaker 1: and in fact Sony their compact phones are now like So much bigger than this phone that it like they're bigger than an iPhone like that's their compact phone.
Speaker 1: Also, they have a weird bulbous back.
Speaker 1: So I'm a little annoyed by that.
Speaker 1: But here's the weird thing that happened.
Speaker 1: I got this other phone out.
Speaker 1: I start setting it up.
Speaker 1: It's obviously running like fucking Android 6 something and I got to run through a million upgrades and it's been churning and upgrading all day, but then I go to doubt to Restore my backup from my current phone to the second one.
Speaker 1: So I can have two phones that are basically identical and it won't see my backup.
Speaker 1: and I'm like, alright, what's going on?
Speaker 1: So then I just start setting it up without the backup because I don't there's nothing on my phone to back up.
Speaker 1: Everything's backed up like independently of the phone backup.
Speaker 1: I don't need data from my apps Yep.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: So I just started setting it up and it says swipe your fingerprint and I'm like There's no fingerprint sensor in this phone because my phone does not have a functional fingerprint sensor.
Speaker 1: When they release this phone the European models as far as I could tell had a fingerprint sensor But we're missing some LTE bands.
Speaker 1: the US specific version of the phone had all the LTE bands, but no fingerprint sensor.
Speaker 1: No one would explain why.
Speaker 1: the best anyone's guess is which I think is very plausible.
Speaker 1: Is that there is a patent on hiding the fingerprint sensor like inside of the power button and That patent seems to only matter in the US.
Speaker 1: So they basically released a version of the phone without the fingerprint sensor Only in the US and the whole rest of the world got the fingerprint sensor.
Speaker 1: Okay Turns out I have the second phone I bought is the European version of the phone and it has the fingerprint sensor.
Speaker 0: oops, so your backup phone is not a.
Speaker 1: But as far as I can tell it does have the bands that when I researched these models It said it wasn't supposed to have.
Speaker 1: So I dug into it a little deeper.
Speaker 1: My US phone also has a fingerprint sensor.
Speaker 1: There is US specific firmware that turns off the fingerprint sensor and hides it from the OS.
Speaker 1: Aha It's been in there the whole time.
Speaker 1: the hardware is there.
Speaker 1: that button that I thought was just a button for like four years is Actually a fingerprint sensor.
Speaker 0: How about that?
Speaker 1: So I wiped it because I'm just fucking with my phone anyway, and I put With the utility for me and I put the European firmware on.
Speaker 1: that fingerprint sensor works.
Speaker 1: Of course I can't tell if the missing LTE bands are working or not though, and I don't have a good way to test that.
Speaker 0: So yeah, see this is this is part of the like unseen advantages of iPhone, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, like iPhone 6s 6s from like four years ago gets the newest updates.
Speaker 0: the updates come automatically Right.
Speaker 0: everyone has with an iPhone has the newest version.
Speaker 0: You don't have to worry about any not having the newest one.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there is zero bullshit from carriers on the phone.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and because everyone's got an iPhone When it is necessary for like carrier firmware updates to happen to like adjust the radios They just show up automatically like once in a blue moon.
Speaker 0: They'll be like a message like there's a carrier update from Verizon push.
Speaker 0: Yes, I'll be like, yes, and then something happens and it's like okay and you can go into settings and check it Right and see what carrier, you know firmwares are in there whatever but you know That's how it is.
Speaker 1: Yep So right now both phones are cycling and like bit by bit after updating themselves back to the latest latest version of Android.
Speaker 0: and Since I'm in the house and I don't go outside that much It's like the phone is actually.
Speaker 0: it's like I was gonna buy the new iPhone.
Speaker 0: Presumably I was gonna consider it at least based on what had you know, what it contains?
Speaker 0: Yeah in September when this new I've I got hiccup suddenly.
Speaker 0: Yeah There's gonna be new iPhones in September I was considering upgrading cuz I got iPhone 7 where there's nothing wrong with it, but it is old, right?
Speaker 0: and It's like well now I barely use the phone.
Speaker 0: I'm inside all the time.
Speaker 0: I just use tablet.
Speaker 0: Yeah, or you know consider part of the reason I was thinking about upgrading it like.
Speaker 1: maybe I could wait till Reason I got the old phone out is because the new phone and the old phone not just cuz the batteries going low.
Speaker 1: It's not that I need it that much It's that I don't need to like have a SIM card in both phones.
Speaker 1: if I'm always in my apartment if I just want to Look at my phone like randomly around the house I could use either phone.
Speaker 1: the SIM card doesn't do anything for me unless I leave Wi-Fi mmm.
Speaker 1: Anyway, yep, so we'll see.
Speaker 1: now I'll just have two phones.
Speaker 1: But the clever thing I'm gonna do that's I've seen other people do I can get both of the phones to have the same totp for my Google stuff.
Speaker 1: So they can be backups for each other.
Speaker 1: I just scan the same barcode twice with two different phones when I set it up.
Speaker 0: Yeah, yeah, you can do that.
Speaker 0: Yep, so My strategy has been to print out the piece of paper with the backup codes on it.
Speaker 1: I do that as well.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and then I have a YubiKey for some things.
Speaker 1: But yeah, that was my phone Odyssey.
Speaker 1: I'm trying to figure out if there are any actual hardware differences between these two phones or if it's literally just they fucked up the firmware specifically in the US Probably the firmware.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: So in some gaming news Microsoft flight simulator on one I see some people who are like going crazy about this announcement and I see other people Who are this one's the last time there's been a Microsoft lights?
Speaker 1: Yeah, but I see a lot of other people especially a lot of younger gamers not understanding why people are going crazy about this update.
Speaker 0: Well, you got so in the 90s, right when people were first starting to get more powerful computers in their home.
Speaker 0: 386 is 486 is yeah Was like there was a lot of software That existed for PCs that tried to make PCs look powerful and impressive Sometimes by cheating and sometimes not by cheating right.
Speaker 0: so mist is like to see the biggest criminal.
Speaker 0: People don't know everything in.
Speaker 0: mist was pre-rendered.
Speaker 0: So they had big fancy computers.
Speaker 0: We're at the developers of mist right?
Speaker 0: They rendered all these 3d graphics and they created videos and they just put the videos on the CD-ROM Which had enough storage to hold the videos, right and then you would play mist.
Speaker 0: you'd like whoa.
Speaker 0: this game looks amazing.
Speaker 0: It's like your computer.
Speaker 0: graphics card isn't rendering shit.
Speaker 0: You're just watching videos that are look amazing.
Speaker 1: Well, wait, wait, wait, you just said graphics card.
Speaker 1: We didn't have graphics cards back then.
Speaker 0: Some people did.
Speaker 0: you could have had a voodoo card.
Speaker 1: My friend can got a voodoo card like early.
Speaker 1: I later I got a creative graphics blaster extreme.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I had the TNT too was.
Speaker 0: but anyway, the point is is that?
Speaker 0: Microsoft flight simulator right actually was Real-time rendering with your computer, right?
Speaker 0: It was basically a combination like tech demo to like sell PCs Right in the 90s along with being an actual flight simulator like but for consumers not for pilots.
Speaker 0: It was sort of like this in-between space right where it was more advanced than like incredibly basic, you know like it was Shockingly realistic and accurate for it wasn't?
Speaker 0: it wasn't like the kind that you could use act for actual pilot training.
Speaker 0: But if you it would sort of get you a lot of the way there right like if you played Microsoft flight simulator Seriously, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, you you could.
Speaker 0: actually if you were to then go to pilot school, you would know some stuff You wouldn't feel like you couldn't skip as well.
Speaker 1: I actually have an anecdote there.
Speaker 1: I've really practiced flight simulator to learn like how to fly a Cessna around and then I went and flew a Cessna and That actually like taught me most of what I needed to know.
Speaker 1: it didn't really teach me take off landing But it taught me like what all the instruments do and they were accurate and like how to do different kinds of turns and how?
Speaker 1: To use the control surfaces, right exactly.
Speaker 0: So They haven't made microsite flight simulator in a long time because you know tech demos aren't how you sell PCs anymore and People who care about flight simulating software isn't a large market necessarily and that software Especially in modern times is difficult and expensive to develop, right?
Speaker 0: so why would you make an expensive expensive software flight simulator and Sell it to not too many people, but they're doing it.
Speaker 0: So here it comes Like I said flight simulator a new version the first version.
Speaker 0: since I don't know when the previous version was I want to say there was all version in like I Gonna google it while you talk.
Speaker 1: Microsoft released a new simulator in February of 2012 called Microsoft flight designed to replace Microsoft flight simulator aimed at drawing new users in the flight sim walk.
Speaker 1: It was simpler and Incompatible with the old flight simulator in 2014.
Speaker 0: There was a Somebody else dovetail games made Microsoft flight simulator X steam edition Like someone else made it.
Speaker 0: You can write in prep.
Speaker 0: our 3d Microsoft flight simulator X was in 2006.
Speaker 1: We gotta read up on this because I was not expecting to ever talk about Microsoft flight simulator again in my life Except maybe in a panel on like the history of gaming.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the point is it's a big deal and it's come back.
Speaker 1: So yeah now they even if you don't care because as a kid, I love Microsoft flight simulator But I was a kid.
Speaker 1: I had nothing better to do I'd be perfectly happy to like fly for an hour just in a normal plane.
Speaker 1: Not really doing much.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Also, I think a lot of the people today who are very serious about flight simulating right Microsoft has been out of the game for So long, I don't know what they're.
Speaker 0: the last time I looked into this scene, which is admittedly many years ago I think people playing X plane.
Speaker 0: right.
Speaker 0: X plane was the thing.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah Right.
Speaker 0: It's like there's already.
Speaker 0: yeah X plane 11 flight simulator, right?
Speaker 0: It's like.
Speaker 0: that's what I think the nerds are playing.
Speaker 0: and it's like some people fly the planes.
Speaker 0: Some people pretend to be the air traffic controllers, right?
Speaker 0: It's like they basically have a whole flight network going on of nerds.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, the listener pointed out the last proper full world version was flight simulator 2006.
Speaker 1: Okay, that was the last Microsoft one 2006.
Speaker 1: God 14 years it is.
Speaker 1: it is a big news that they're doing it again after that If you don't care at all about flight simulators, here's why this is still really big news for you.
Speaker 1: It brings hot ass back to the table Because we were just talking about this in light of the Star Wars free-space shooter that's coming out from EA that we're cautiously Optimistic for it's EA so cautious is capitalized there.
Speaker 1: But there haven't been good joysticks except for very niche purposes for a long time.
Speaker 0: Well, they have been but it's Very niche purposes.
Speaker 1: most joysticks like ten years ago go want to buy a joystick online.
Speaker 1: Madcat's had some barely functional ones that fell apart or there were really expensive semi custom ones.
Speaker 1: There weren't a lot of good joysticks.
Speaker 1: unless you're willing to spend a lot of money and a lot of so I mean, I think there weren't there.
Speaker 0: they're good fight sticks for fighting fight sticks not flight sticks, right?
Speaker 0: It's like the.
Speaker 0: all the games the video the major video games where people would go out of their way to buy a controller For right are all mouse and keyboard gamepad or fighting stick.
Speaker 1: Yeah It was a weird nerd would have a hot ass setup, right?
Speaker 0: It's only.
Speaker 0: it's like a really niche.
Speaker 0: people who are willing to spend a lot of money are the only people who've been buying those For the past quite many so many years, right?
Speaker 1: Yep, but basically what I hot ass stands for hands-on throttle and stick.
Speaker 1: It's basically if you're flying a plane or something like especially a fighter jet or say a tie fighter You want bait.
Speaker 1: we have one hand on a joystick to control the plane and another hand on a throttle to control the throttle.
Speaker 1: like it's a very intuitive good user experience for controlling that kind of vehicle a Flying vehicle is.
Speaker 0: that is how you want to control it?
Speaker 0: Yep
Speaker 1: So if Microsoft flight simulator is coming out again for the first time in forever coupled with the Star Wars game coming I feel like it's time for there to be a mid range of hot ass or at least high-end Joysticks instead of just having the elite bespoke and on the other end literal garbage that falls apart immediately.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well, I mean logitech which I think owns or bought sci-tech at some point has somewhat recently Updated like the the the top-end Hot ass they have like the x56 or something.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I've got this shitty old like One yes thrust master which makes the sort of like military accurate ones.
Speaker 0: They're still in business so you can still shell out and get like flight stick.
Speaker 0: that looks exact and feels exactly like the ones in a real f-15 right.
Speaker 0: you can get those if you want.
Speaker 1: I If that Star Wars game is good I probably will get something like this but don't like a Thrust master hot ass that looks like that acts like an AC 10 warthogs controls like it's the same control surface or the same control 550 bucks yeah without the pedals
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm yep,
Speaker 1: but I'm kind of excited about this too Because if this kind of if this area starts to exist and that Star Wars game is good This is some of my favorite kinds of gaming.
Speaker 1: it also means that these peripherals like I want I always wanted to get foot pads like pedals, but the last few times I looked they either were crappy or Didn't really work with the kinds of games that like a lot of the games I wanted to use them with couldn't accept input for multiple devices.
Speaker 1: Like a lot of those problems have been solved over the years I think also the people being trapped inside around the world.
Speaker 0: I've seen a somewhat a resurgence as well in people buying a home like you know.
Speaker 0: virtual racing setups You know steering wheel like the penny arcade.
Speaker 1: guys are like deep into that racing now, right?
Speaker 0: It's like you know it's and it even because you know the real sport people have to are doing it that way.
Speaker 0: also Right is.
Speaker 0: they're all you know Some of the actual really Airbus now.
Speaker 1: They're not just making fighter jets.
Speaker 1: They released a an Airbus control scheme.
Speaker 0: Now if you want to do some commercial simulation, I mean Microsoft flight simulator Yeah, sure.
Speaker 0: So yeah, it's like the the home.
Speaker 0: You know people have enough space in their home Who are trapped there all the time.
Speaker 0: you know simulating the large vehicles that you cannot go out and ride for real?
Speaker 1: Which is extra fun because those are the kinds of things that were the realm of the arcade like.
Speaker 1: that was the main reason I?
Speaker 1: Still went to arcades once I had PCs and good consoles because there were Peripherals and controls in the arcade.
Speaker 0: I could not get at home right, but no one wants to buy an arcade.
Speaker 0: You know you some people want to buy an arcade.
Speaker 0: I do like the cost of an arcade machine that plays exactly one game and putting it in your house right versus Right.
Speaker 0: if you buy like a racing setup right with a wheel and pedals and three monitors right up there right and like something like that You can.
Speaker 1: actually there's more than one game.
Speaker 1: You might play with that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you can play several racing dude And it's cheaper, it's cheaper right.
Speaker 1: I watch someone playing Overwatch with one of those rigs.
Speaker 1: they were tracer, and they were just strafing and fighting with the wheel.
Speaker 0: Yep, they did terribly I'm sure they did.
Speaker 1: So uh yeah, I the problem is now.
Speaker 1: I still gotta wait till October.
Speaker 1: I'm not buying as much as I want like to buy a hot ass.
Speaker 1: I'm waiting until October like 20th because Star Wars squadrons comes out October 2nd And then we need to wait and see if it is worth it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, only if we play I'm gonna play Star Wars squadrons.
Speaker 0: if we I even play it at all.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna play it with mouse and keyboard and if we play it with a group consistently frequently the game stays alive And it's like becomes a serious regular thing.
Speaker 0: then I will consider buying.
Speaker 1: yeah I'm gonna use my mad cats v1 to try it out.
Speaker 0: I'll use a mouse and keyboard which drifts ever slowly to the bottom left.
Speaker 1: I realized when I tried to play.
Speaker 0: I'm sure you can adjust it.
Speaker 1: Uh no.
Speaker 1: I can't.
Speaker 1: this thing is.
Speaker 1: this thing is pretty old and pretty crap alright.
Speaker 1: So in some other news you're stuck inside right.
Speaker 1: well SGDQ is coming.
Speaker 1: They published this schedule starting Sunday August 16.
Speaker 0: SGDQ is usually held around 4th of July, but This year it's held a little later obviously and it's whole.
Speaker 0: It's all online.
Speaker 0: They're not going to congregate in a single location.
Speaker 0: But the good news is that while the event will be diminished in that way it will actually Oppositely be enriched because since the participants the speedrunners don't need to travel there.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right.
Speaker 1: I see some names.
Speaker 1: I haven't seen before.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that opens the door to a lot of excellent speedrunners who otherwise would not be able to be at GDQ because they would Have to travel there, which is a pain in the ass now.
Speaker 0: They can have speedrunners from anywhere in the world.
Speaker 0: There's a lot of people who are like oh, it's online.
Speaker 0: I guess I can submit my run now, right.
Speaker 0: And so if you look at the schedule that was just released.
Speaker 0: There's a lot of good shit on there.
Speaker 0: It's like virtual boy Wario land.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, this is like one of the best schedules.
Speaker 1: You know Elf on the Sega Master System.
Speaker 1: I love some awful games.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right, those are my favorite speakers also a big fan of mine.
Speaker 1: talk about this in a minute - quest for glory 1 But the VGA version not the unwatchable unplayable EGA version.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so if you're into the if you like to watch GDQ.
Speaker 0: You're gonna have a good time next month.
Speaker 1: power blade.
Speaker 1: I'm just scrolling through again.
Speaker 1: I keep miss power blades.
Speaker 1: nanny s game.
Speaker 1: That was pretty good.
Speaker 0: Never heard of it.
Speaker 1: Really Wow Can't believe you never played power blade.
Speaker 1: put it in emulator.
Speaker 1: It's worth you ten minutes of that.
Speaker 1: You'll see what the deal is and you'll probably like it.
Speaker 0: Okay Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: So in some other news shantay, uh, you know that the series of games I just realized there are more of those games than I thought there were but the gameboy color Version is getting re-released on a repro cart, but also on the switch.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so I haven't.
Speaker 0: actually I've never actually played a shantay game But what I know about them is like it's a series of platforming games that sort of has like this Underground popularity.
Speaker 0: it's like supposedly and I believe it.
Speaker 0: They're like really good platformers that just don't get the hype Proportional to their quality because they're just platforming game.
Speaker 0: I guess he constant low and have mostly right and have mostly been released on handheld platforms, right?
Speaker 0: So similar to like Golden Sun being a crazy good JRPG But not getting the attention of like a Final Fantasy because it's in the handheld realm, right?
Speaker 0: Even though it's sort of dead now.
Speaker 0: Yeah, has it had a new one released in forever, right?
Speaker 0: so but shantay is like they keep making more of them and they're releasing a new one soon and Along with this release of the new one They're re-releasing a lot of the old ones.
Speaker 0: So if you have it if you're like platforming games and you haven't been in the shantay scene I'm probably gonna go and check them out because I've heard so much about them.
Speaker 1: Yeah in another brief news.
Speaker 1: I'm just gonna highlight this.
Speaker 1: Like I said, I'm really big into the little quest for glory games.
Speaker 1: These are some of my favorite games of all time.
Speaker 1: I never noticed because I have them.
Speaker 1: I think I bought them somewhere a long time ago and I can play them in DOSBox.
Speaker 1: There's a package on Steam that packages all up and they just work with all the patches and bug fixes.
Speaker 1: The games are as Fully patched and playable as they possibly could have been on earth and it even supports the import and exporting of characters Between games because that required floppies.
Speaker 1: It was kind of a pain to make that work in DOSBox.
Speaker 1: They've made a launcher that makes that work to import and export characters between the games.
Speaker 0: So if you want to bring the key to you, I know that the standard pattern was similar to Actually golden Sun.
Speaker 0: Yeah, where you would beat you would beat quest for glory one then bring your character to two then beat the game and breeding It's a three.
Speaker 0: Yeah, could you go backwards and forward?
Speaker 0: Because the games take place in chronological order as you go Could you go forwards before you beat the game?
Speaker 0: Like can I play half of one and go to two?
Speaker 1: Nope, you beat one and eat.
Speaker 1: the end of each game Transports you or otherwise gives you access to the next place.
Speaker 0: Okay, so it's only the next place the game and go to the next one.
Speaker 0: You can't anything else.
Speaker 1: but there was a clever thing too where there's three classes.
Speaker 1: Like the game is baby.
Speaker 1: Each game is basically three games like the.
Speaker 1: if you pick fighter thief or wizard There's completely different things you can do like completely different stories.
Speaker 0: You change classes when you switch games.
Speaker 1: Uh, yes, but more importantly if you beat any of the games as a fight I can play one is wizard and play two is fighter.
Speaker 0: Transferring my character over.
Speaker 1: my favorite way to go is I'd start press for glory one as a thief But I you can.
Speaker 1: you have.
Speaker 1: you've set.
Speaker 1: you had skill points.
Speaker 1: in the beginning I gave myself magic like I open skills that you can open them at character creation, but not during the game.
Speaker 1: So I gave myself magic and some fighting skills so I could do everything And I just leveled myself up along the way.
Speaker 1: it took longer.
Speaker 1: I had to grind a little bit but I could literally do anything so I could do the thief quest But cast the open spell instead of picking the lock.
Speaker 1: Okay, but if you beat the game as a fighter You had the option to go through a trial in each of the games to become a paladin.
Speaker 1: See I had to play at least two of the games to be able to be the fourth class.
Speaker 0: Okay, these games are just like very different from all the other adventure games from that era like those scum games or Well, I guess I think they combined the sort of RPG freedom of like a Baldur's Gate or a JRPG.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but along with the point-and-click adventure puzzle solving of a monkey's island.
Speaker 1: Yeah, because a monkey island like there's one solution to the puzzle like those kinds of literally just a puzzle.
Speaker 0: This is puzzle plus RPG sort of like a step building visual novel kind of situation.
Speaker 0: exactly.
Speaker 1: It's a relatively unexplored genre still because not many games like it have ever been made even now.
Speaker 0: Well a lot of the step building.
Speaker 0: visual novels are straight-up visual novel.
Speaker 0: They don't have the.
Speaker 0: you know the point-and-click kind of thing exactly.
Speaker 1: So some blast little news Death Stranding.
Speaker 1: if you needed a reason to not have to buy a Playstation It's just on Steam now, you can just play it on a PC.
Speaker 0: Yeah, anyone who bought some console just to play some Hideo Kojima game well look at that.
Speaker 0: You could have just waited until today or what I got.
Speaker 0: I guess it.
Speaker 0: I don't know if today was the day or if it was yesterday or what it was recent.
Speaker 1: cuz people I saw I forgot This game cuz I wanted to play.
Speaker 0: it's like well.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like.
Speaker 0: you know this.
Speaker 0: This you know I understand this.
Speaker 0: exclusive games that people want to play all right, but there's so few of them.
Speaker 0: There's so few and if you just wait they eventually almost all make it to PC.
Speaker 0: And if they don't make it to PC you can emulate them eventually right it's like.
Speaker 0: so it's like.
Speaker 0: I don't see any Reason to buy a Playstation or Xbox right no matter.
Speaker 0: It's like.
Speaker 0: you know what game even if there is like a game on there that will never be available anywhere else.
Speaker 0: right it's like Okay, you don't need to play the game right now.
Speaker 0: You can wait and see.
Speaker 0: and if five ten years down the line.
Speaker 0: It still hasn't been ported.
Speaker 0: That's the only way to play it.
Speaker 0: well guess what now?
Speaker 0: PlayStation 4 or 5 is real cheap.
Speaker 0: You can play that game.
Speaker 0: No problem Why would you pay $500 whatever it cost to buy a PlayStation?
Speaker 0: because you need to play that game today immediately.
Speaker 0: the single-player game?
Speaker 0: But no multiplayer.
Speaker 0: no nothing.
Speaker 1: there is multiplayer interaction in this game.
Speaker 0: Oh, I was not aware of that.
Speaker 0: You know I don't think you know what death stranding is about at some Hideo Kojima game.
Speaker 0: We're like this like people walking around with like babies, and you shit.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 1: that is not wrong Kind of fuck.
Speaker 0: yeah, it's so kind of fucked up for Dale Kojima shit.
Speaker 1: That is also not wrong.
Speaker 1: It's some kind of fucked up Hideo Kojima shit with babies and walking around.
Speaker 0: yeah I see I know exactly what this is.
Speaker 0: that's all I need to know.
Speaker 0: I need to know nothing else.
Speaker 1: I feel like I'm not gonna play it today.
Speaker 1: I can I gonna buy it right now and play it, but I feel like once it starts getting cold.
Speaker 1: I'm still stuck inside because the pandemic Kind of game I can just play.
Speaker 1: cuz I could I can.
Speaker 0: I feel like if it was if it was a big steam Sale like if less than 15 bucks.
Speaker 0: I might play it.
Speaker 1: Maybe yes I feel like someday you'll be able to buy a game of the year edition of this for pretty cheap, but anyway things Of the day.
Speaker 1: what do you got?
Speaker 0: What do I have?
Speaker 0: oh yeah, so you know it's being at home, right?
Speaker 0: You know you get a lot more time to listen to music or whatever.
Speaker 0: So I've been.
Speaker 0: you know what I've been doing is not just you know eventually even Spotify you're right out of things to listen to Kind of right.
Speaker 0: so you know you go on twitch or whatever YouTube, and you know you find some DJs.
Speaker 0: and DJs are great because DJs are people who know a lot of music and They just play it.
Speaker 0: for you don't have to think you don't have to search you just push play.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you minimize them, and you're it's you get some great tune.
Speaker 1: I mean I've been doing that too just with like lo-fi beats or with There's a bunch of good future funk channels.
Speaker 1: that they're.
Speaker 0: they're semi live or they get you getting in the future fun game now Future funk.
Speaker 1: okay, I'm a little more fan of lo-fi beats.
Speaker 0: the point is You know just being a curious nerd.
Speaker 0: I've always been curious like hey You know all these DJs.
Speaker 0: They all have you know two or two tables and a microphone or they had.
Speaker 0: there was a time period where I know DJs recently Like Serato where they would have turntables, but it was like a magical digital record.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we were at Katsu count in the DJ I remember.
Speaker 1: he was explaining to us how it worked and it was really cool And we both got really interested in it.
Speaker 0: nowadays people just have.
Speaker 0: nowadays people just have DJ controllers, which are just plastic.
Speaker 0: There's just basically you know beat mania Right and then the computer does all the work.
Speaker 0: But the you still have a controller that looks like two turntables and a microphone and a mixer right?
Speaker 0: And I've always wondered just curious like I have no plans to ever be a DJ right I know that that is not a road I will go down if I were to purchase even an inexpensive DJ thing from some other Aspiring failed DJ who bought the stuff and decided not to use it and sell it.
Speaker 0: that
Speaker 1: is the best way to get most audio Equipment by the way
Speaker 0: that I would then also end up being the person that I purchased it from and be in selling it Right and not DJing anything, so I'm not going down that road, but I'm still curious How do you if you if I were to be DJ?
Speaker 0: How do you use that thing like what all those buttons do?
Speaker 0: What all those buttons do I?
Speaker 0: obviously I know that some of them do right just obvious I mean some of it's just a mixer like right.
Speaker 0: obviously I know all that.
Speaker 0: you know a lot of the parts But it's like if you were to be a DJ.
Speaker 0: like what buttons do you press what?
Speaker 0: how does it work right?
Speaker 0: So I went on YouTube and I tried to watch videos like how to DJ and a lot of the videos were crappy.
Speaker 0: Obviously right they were.
Speaker 0: they were the professors who were attempting to teach the way to DJ.
Speaker 0: We're not doing a very good job.
Speaker 0: I was able to learn a bit, but they did not go into detail right.
Speaker 0: I did not feel as if I've Learned how to do this.
Speaker 0: I could do it like.
Speaker 1: I feel like a lot of those people will say like Things like bead matching, but they never actually explain how the fuck you do that?
Speaker 0: Yeah They don't expect it.
Speaker 0: really explain in detail not leaving anything out right not telling you exactly what each button did When you would use them and why right.
Speaker 0: and then I found this guy.
Speaker 0: This YouTube channel is club ready DJ.
Speaker 0: I think right.
Speaker 0: and this guy.
Speaker 0: I don't know his name.
Speaker 1: He is selling his club ready DJ.
Speaker 0: Yeah, he's selling classes that he teaches you know so you could learn how to be.
Speaker 0: his focus is on obviously getting people Not just to learn how to DJ But it's like be good enough at DJing that you can go and work in the club right because that's the way to get good.
Speaker 1: Get low to your gigs in the area like that right.
Speaker 0: so you're.
Speaker 0: so his lesson plan is get you ready to go to the Club just like his name club ready DJ, and he sells classes that will help you learn this.
Speaker 0: But he has this YouTube channel, and I feel like wow this YouTube channel is so good.
Speaker 0: Why would you pay for the classes you learned?
Speaker 0: I learned everything for these free YouTube videos.
Speaker 0: Right and it's like these are the best DJ teaching videos, and I still have no plans to DJ.
Speaker 0: But now I feel like if I were had a gun to my head and someone threw a DJ controller in front of me Right that I would remember this guy, and he taught me well enough in a YouTube video so good at teaching That I could maybe not get shot.
Speaker 0: So if you are interested in DJing or are just curious how DJ stuff works like I was this is a great YouTube channel.
Speaker 0: Club ready DJ is an excellent YouTube teacher And if you want to teach something else and you want to make other instructional YouTube videos about some other topic You should learn from club ready DJ.
Speaker 0: I had to do that because he's great.
Speaker 1: All right, so y'all familiar with Rocket League.
Speaker 1: It's popular game.
Speaker 0: It's still alive.
Speaker 0: people still play it.
Speaker 1: from what I gather just I had some unrelated conversation with people.
Speaker 1: It seems to be pretty well agreed that Rocket League might have the most toxic player community on earth Apparently people I mean.
Speaker 0: when I played it it Sort of I mean it.
Speaker 0: there was toxicity when I played it when it was new in its first year of You know competitive play or whatever.
Speaker 0: But the toxicity mostly came at least when I was playing it.
Speaker 1: Who thought they were good, but they weren't right.
Speaker 0: yeah, or like you know.
Speaker 0: it's like yeah You'd be stuck in these low tier matches, and that'd be like some.
Speaker 0: you know the typical stuff right.
Speaker 1: oh I'm not bronze here I'm not brought here.
Speaker 1: as he descended
Speaker 0: I was I was under I was under the impression that over time since the game isn't so new anymore the only people still playing It which are still a lot of people right Where people who really cared about it and were good at it right and all the other people had sort of left for other games.
Speaker 0: And thus I had believed perhaps falsely the toxicity had decreased because it was pretty much like yeah The only people still playing Rocket League are pros who care about Rocket League.
Speaker 1: course you know.
Speaker 1: it's interesting if that happened though I don't know how Rocket League's tearing works, but in most like matchmaking tearing It's based more on a curve so that if it's all great players someone's still gonna be bronzed here.
Speaker 0: Maybe who knows.
Speaker 1: but anyway Rocket League Kind of already existed a long long time ago, and I have this video that is people in 1927 driving early shitty little cars that look kind of like Rocket League cars Driving around pushing a giant ball literally just playing Rocket League with real cars.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm it was push ball was a game that people were playing and in fact people still play today.
Speaker 1: I found a website with a bunch of photos of a group that plays push ball with cars like this today.
Speaker 0: Okay, like RC cars or no full-size cars.
Speaker 1: They're in these full-size really old looking cars Driving it around in a field model T. Yeah like model T. Looking cars with little cages around them, but no one's playing.
Speaker 0: They don't know it's doing it with like Toyota Corolla or whatever.
Speaker 1: that would be great.
Speaker 1: these do not look safe at all Okay, and they're driving them around at speed just trying to ram this ball into a net on either side of a field.
Speaker 0: I guess they don't have rockets though.
Speaker 0: They don't have rockets.
Speaker 1: No, I don't know what happens if you kill the other player because I know Rocket League has rules about that but there's video from people in 19 from 1927 people playing this.
Speaker 1: I Have to imagine that at least four people died anytime this game got played.
Speaker 1: this does not look cool Okay, but the reason I found this video is almost more fascinating.
Speaker 1: someone tweeted something and it was talking about sports being played like a hundred years ago, and it mentioned horse push ball and I was like what's horse push ball see now.
Speaker 0: so now this is interesting that you mentioned horse push ball because I Imagine that if there's a horse version of a sport the car version came later.
Speaker 0: Yeah So why is why would it be?
Speaker 0: Pushball and horse push ball?
Speaker 0: if there was a horse version shouldn't have the horse version be push ball and the car version would be car Push ball, so I went even deeper.
Speaker 1: the original game was just push ball in the late 1800s And it was humans imagine soccer.
Speaker 1: But there's one giant ball that's taller than any human and people just fucking have a fistfight over it until they push it into one of the goals.
Speaker 0: Alright, that's a sport.
Speaker 1: It's a real thing.
Speaker 1: It was popular.
Speaker 1: Apparently Yale University had their own variant called bladder ball Which was such a problem on campus that the police got involved and riots occurred on a regular basis Where basically every now and then someone would bring out the bladder this giant beach ball looking thing And then the students will just riot over like trying to steal it and push it into their own dorm or whatever like it was a thing.
Speaker 1: So yeah push ball was a human sport.
Speaker 1: people started playing it with horses Which does not look super safe, and then they started playing it in the 20s and 30s with cars.
Speaker 1: It seems like today the human version and the car version are the only versions that are still played.
Speaker 0: That's probably for the best.
Speaker 1: Yeah, cuz the horse version looks.
Speaker 1: I don't know how well they cared for the horses, but I worry a little bit about it.
Speaker 1: based on some of the footage I found Mmm.
Speaker 0: I do not ever want to worry about any animal in usage in sports.
Speaker 1: Yeah pretty much.
Speaker 1: But yeah, if you want to go play push ball It looks like there are people who are more than willing to endanger you for that purpose.
Speaker 1: Okay in the meta moment.
Speaker 1: We're stuck at home like we've been.
Speaker 1: nothing's really changed.
Speaker 1: I don't really have a significant update since the last time we talked.
Speaker 0: Yeah, PAX online is the next convention.
Speaker 1: There will be no PAX's this year because the state of Pennsylvania basically said nothing's happening this year, so no PAX unplugged which Obviously there wasn't gonna be a PAX unplugged Yeah, but now it's official.
Speaker 0: Yeah, PAX unplugged hasn't said it's official, but the state of Pennsylvania has made the point moot, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, there are no events for the next six months.
Speaker 0: Well.
Speaker 1: That's that and based on how things are going in, Texas I'm pretty I am not.
Speaker 1: I'm a hundred percent sure there will not be a PAX South.
Speaker 0: There won't be.
Speaker 0: there could be a magfest online.
Speaker 0: that might be interesting.
Speaker 1: yeah We'll see.
Speaker 0: maybe some maybe some other conventions that we have not gone to because There were you know physical this I think online Connecticut like already just happened like a tank came too quick for me to get ready for It.
Speaker 0: yeah, I don't know how many people watched it even a lot of online cops.
Speaker 1: They're not getting a lot of traction.
Speaker 1: But there's a few that are coming together that look like they're gonna put on a good show that we're gonna be at PAX online Virtual packs and we're gonna be at the virtual crunchyroll expo And we're trying to figure out what other online cons We want to do.
Speaker 1: if there is a virtual con that you want us at like email us.
Speaker 1: Like.
Speaker 1: email me.
Speaker 1: remember for recruit calm because I'm actively currently sorting out our virtual convention schedule for the rest of the year.
Speaker 0: Yeah, also in terms of online cons That I will attend but not be a speaker just be an attendee all right.
Speaker 1: Sing game devs of color.
Speaker 0: yeah the game devs of color is going online.
Speaker 0: They're usually in the summer around this time.
Speaker 0: I think if it was still scheduled submissions closed relatively recently.
Speaker 1: you press on me tweeting about it a whole bunch.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think it was like if there hasn't been a pandemic.
Speaker 0: it would have been like last week or a couple weeks ago.
Speaker 0: It would have been recent right or it would have been very close to this time.
Speaker 0: But I think they're making it in September or something the online version.
Speaker 1: I'm trying to fight because the Google likes to point at their old website here.
Speaker 1: We are 2020 expo September 19th online.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: so yeah It's gonna be around isn't that close to packs online time?
Speaker 1: it is close to packs online and also close to crunchyroll expo.
Speaker 1: Everyone's doing September.
Speaker 1: That's all right I don't know yet as far as I can see.
Speaker 0: of course you also mentioned as GDQ which is gonna be August some yep But it's also been devs of color.
Speaker 1: expo is notable in that the way every time we've gone.
Speaker 1: the panel content is fantastic.
Speaker 0: I mean in terms of the Quality to quantity ratio of panel content.
Speaker 0: I'd say it is probably the best of any con period.
Speaker 1: It's better than packs in terms of quality.
Speaker 0: Even if you go to magfest right we have like your mages content.
Speaker 0: You've got it diluted by so much You know not all the other not all not all the non mages.
Speaker 0: content at magfest is meh Yeah, this is a mess stuff But it's not come.
Speaker 1: but like these the talks at gdoc tend to be like the a-tier talks you see from other gaming cons.
Speaker 0: Exactly right whereas you know you go to say packs.
Speaker 0: It's like yeah There's a lot of industry garbage filling up the schedule all right, but game devs of color expo literally every talk is terrific.
Speaker 0: That's the whole schedule.
Speaker 0: There's like nothing to skip.
Speaker 0: you could just sit in there all day.
Speaker 0: Just the one two panel rooms.
Speaker 0: Just sit there.
Speaker 1: You don't got to do nothing else Alright, so I think we should get right into it.
Speaker 1: modding consoles is a thing Less of a thing for us than it used to be.
Speaker 1: at least it was Something that I didn't think I'd ever revisit again in my life.
Speaker 1: But as Scott's gonna talk about now.
Speaker 1: We have a lot of old gaming hardware that can actually just be made better With modern technology.
Speaker 0: so someone posted you know cold guy posted in our forum listener cold guy And he posted this video.
Speaker 0: we could link to the video.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, I'll pull it up.
Speaker 0: I think the video was an advertisement in disguise, but I guess it worked Recognized.
Speaker 0: I recognized it was an advertisement But basically they took it was about upgrading a Gameboy Advance right.
Speaker 0: Someone who makes Gameboy Advance retro modding products right sent all their products to this guy who has a YouTube channel And he made the YouTube guy made a video about upgrading his Gameboy Advance with all the products, and I said wow that's amazing I would like to do that as well, so I purchased all the same exact products And I upgraded my Gameboy.
Speaker 0: I had a Gameboy Advance sitting there unused.
Speaker 0: It's my original Gameboy Advance the very.
Speaker 0: I bought it on release day, but now it is no more it is now.
Speaker 0: It's motherboard has now been inserted into this other case right with a different screen attached and The battery is changed and a tiny tiny amplifier has been placed in between the motherboard and a replacement speaker.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, didn't you put?
Speaker 1: did you put the his filter in it, too?
Speaker 0: There's no real hissing noises.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I feel like this is something that only all like some people really care about it and no one else.
Speaker 0: No, I haven't really.
Speaker 0: I haven't really heard in.
Speaker 0: the audio is just.
Speaker 0: it sounds loud, and it sounds great.
Speaker 0: So I don't really.
Speaker 0: I haven't actually have to try the headphone hole.
Speaker 0: I'll do that after the show probably.
Speaker 0: But yeah, it's like I upgraded this Gameboy Advance to now the screen is an IPS screen.
Speaker 0: It's like any we're talking a screen as good as not a retina screen, but like think of an iPhone pre retina.
Speaker 0: That's the kind of screen that this Gameboy Advance has right.
Speaker 0: the brightness and the colors are just outstanding.
Speaker 0: You can actually control the brightness Which you couldn't do right.
Speaker 0: the volume because of the amplifier can go way louder out of the speaker.
Speaker 0: Which is great.
Speaker 0: And the battery has been replaced a rechargeable lithium ion battery with USB C. So no more double A's Just plug it into the wall.
Speaker 1: That's pretty exciting that part.
Speaker 0: and it's like it's a Gameboy Advance.
Speaker 0: so it can play GBA games and Gameboy color games and Gameboy Games, and if you get a flash cart, you know it can also play like NES games with an emulator Flash card.
Speaker 1: that everyone's just backing up games not pirating them.
Speaker 1: Just backing them up.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know.
Speaker 0: So yeah, it's like I had a DS light.
Speaker 0: and a DS light You know has a backlit screen has two screens and that can also play with a flash cart.
Speaker 0: right you know Gameboy Gameboy color NES and GBA games and DS games.
Speaker 0: Obviously this could do everything that the DS light can do except the DS games.
Speaker 0: right and the DS light could do SNES games and sort of Genesis games.
Speaker 0: But the resolution of the screen was too low.
Speaker 0: so it would like it would either stretch or cut off part of the SNES games.
Speaker 0: It wasn't great, and you know a DS has two screens But one screen of a DS is where you'd be playing most of these games and those screens would be One DS screen is smaller than one GBA screen physically right and the form factor is not as great.
Speaker 0: so like this upgraded GBA is Actually other than not being able to play DS games.
Speaker 0: Yeah, Super Nintendo games is like the best handheld right.
Speaker 0: it's like a mate You know.
Speaker 0: incredible right and if I could play it.
Speaker 0: if there's a game that I could play on this I'd rather play it on this than on a DS or through even 3ds if right.
Speaker 0: So that's pretty awesome, and you know.
Speaker 0: so I had to do some electronics.
Speaker 0: You know soldering and whatnot, but it was actually very forgiving right?
Speaker 0: I did a real shitty job of soldering and it still worked perfectly on the first try And also I didn't need to need to do the soldering right if you don't want the amplifier.
Speaker 0: That's actually the hardest part.
Speaker 0: you don't have to solder that you could just not do the amplifier Just keep the speaker.
Speaker 0: that came with the GBA the upgraded screen.
Speaker 0: You don't have to do any soldering unless you want the brightness controls, which is just three wires.
Speaker 0: It was very easy You know and putting it into the case the battery doesn't require any soldering at all.
Speaker 0: And putting it into the case is actually the hardest part.
Speaker 0: It's just a matter of screwdriver right, but it was a little tricky to get all the buttons and stuff You know lined up, especially the L&R buttons.
Speaker 0: They were a huge pain in the ass All right, but I did manage it and now I'm never opening this again.
Speaker 0: Yep, if it breaks well Well, it's funny.
Speaker 1: that's one difference between like mod.
Speaker 1: There's like.
Speaker 1: there's different levels of risk for modding because when I was really young we had a game gear and there was a mod That I'd read about on a BBS that people had talked about Where you would futz with the way the batteries work to give it a lot longer battery life Something to do with the fact that the LCD Only used like one or two of the batteries and all the rest of the batteries powered the rest of the machine.
Speaker 1: But the LCD batteries would burn out the fastest because of that backlight because that was ancient LCD technology.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 1: And there was a mod of like soldering and moving stuff around to get to put more batteries in just for the LCD.
Speaker 1: And if you did it that if you did that the whole thing would last like five or six hours on one set of batteries instead of like one or two, but I was a kid.
Speaker 1: I Theoretically could have made this mod based on these instructions.
Speaker 1: I downloaded from a BBS that I dialed into.
Speaker 1: however, I Could not afford to buy a new game gear if I fucked it up And if I told my parents that I cracked open the game gear and took a soldering iron to it and now it's broken They definitely would not have bought me a new one.
Speaker 1: The risk was so high compared to the reward that I was willing to just keep buying double-a batteries my entire childhood.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean what it comes down to is, you know, we have these pieces of hardware right computers game consoles, right and Even though time has gone on it's right is it's you know?
Speaker 0: newer hardware Doesn't run that old software.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but you later get this but they're not perfect.
Speaker 0: No, they're not.
Speaker 0: And there are like clone consoles you can get which are pretty cool.
Speaker 0: right that exists.
Speaker 0: But even so it's like okay.
Speaker 0: I'm just gonna buy basically a modern NES clone machine, right?
Speaker 0: It's like I have an NES right here.
Speaker 0: Why would I do that, right?
Speaker 0: It's like hey this NES is still perfectly good, right?
Speaker 0: But the problem is I can't hook it up to my TV because it doesn't have HDMI, right?
Speaker 0: Well, guess what?
Speaker 0: We have people make things so you can add HDMI to an NES.
Speaker 0: Why not go for it, right?
Speaker 0: You know, it's like oh you got a Commodore 64.
Speaker 0: Add HDMI output to it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know some kind of audio output that is easier to use.
Speaker 1: Well, you know speaking of the cold guy again way back Pat actually gave me and the Atari 2600 with the Video out mod.
Speaker 1: So it doesn't.
Speaker 0: yes the s-video out.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so it doesn't need RF Anything.
Speaker 1: so to this day like well, I guess now I can't have a party But we occasionally just turn on the 2600 and play outlaw on a modern TV with the actual hardware.
Speaker 0: Right when these things were new they were state-of-the-art technology.
Speaker 0: There was no upgrading to be done to it, right?
Speaker 0: It's like what are you gonna upgrade on your Nintendo switch, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like people change the plastic shells on them and stuff like that Like the old the original Game Boy, you can't see that screen for shit.
Speaker 1: No backlight in there.
Speaker 0: No, no, no.
Speaker 1: No, that's why it lasted so long compared to the game gear.
Speaker 0: Right, but it's like there's nothing to upgrade on a switch.
Speaker 0: You could just you could style it, right?
Speaker 0: You could maybe make controllers that are that are better if you need.
Speaker 0: maybe accessibility reasons or comfort reasons.
Speaker 1: Most people see style reasons.
Speaker 1: Most people seem to do on their switches cosmetic mods, like.
Speaker 1: they'll get custom controllers that look cool.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but if you want to go out and say upgrade the screen on your switch It's like what screen are you gonna get?
Speaker 0: There's no better screen.
Speaker 0: You can go buy.
Speaker 0: Yeah It's not like there's nothing that it's using.
Speaker 0: the best screen available for a Nintendo switch is already in the switch.
Speaker 0: right HDMI output.
Speaker 0: It's like it has HDMI output.
Speaker 0: What are you gonna do to it?
Speaker 0: It's like come on.
Speaker 0: But these older consoles not only can you upgrade a lot of especially the input output parts of them, right?
Speaker 0: You don't really you know You can also Was I said the input output parts.
Speaker 0: Yeah I are definitely the inter.
Speaker 1: you can also solve problems that were caused by the limitations of the state-of-the-art Technology of the time like the game gear.
Speaker 1: I've seen some mods But they seem a lot harder to pull off because that's older hardware.
Speaker 1: like way older hardware.
Speaker 1: You can replace the LCD with a new modern LCD display.
Speaker 1: that just works way better
Speaker 0: Yep, but what I was trying to say was Not only can you upgrade you know the input output parts with more modern stuff But when that technology was new when a game boy was new right if you opened it up That was actually complicated shit in there for the day.
Speaker 0: right.
Speaker 0: nowadays you open up a game boy and It's the inside is pedestrian.
Speaker 1: It's like you can look at the board and like see the traces and understand what's going on.
Speaker 1: There's not right.
Speaker 0: It's like it's not actually a complicated piece of electronics like when I open up this GBA.
Speaker 0: even the inside looked like an Electronics other than a few CPUs that had like you know some tiny surface mount stuff that like a machine might have to do.
Speaker 0: It's like the vast majority of the motherboard was like.
Speaker 0: oh that looks like an electronics project kit that I would do You know buy online and do for fun, right?
Speaker 1: You know the funniest was when I the only the console I modded first in my life when I actually was willing to do it was that ps1.
Speaker 1: I bought a ps1 and I want to put a mod chip in it.
Speaker 1: I remember I cracked it open.
Speaker 1: I was so worried like how I'm gonna get this mod chip in here.
Speaker 1: What if I fuck it up, but when I actually cracked it open, you know who's in there just like one really cheap looking green like but breadboard With some like really shoddy looking solders on it and a bunch of solid-state components and chips.
Speaker 1: And that was it.
Speaker 1: like it was just one little board.
Speaker 1: It was so simple that I almost laughed.
Speaker 0: Right, it's like the older stuff is simple enough to be worked on by an amateur, you know Hobbyist at home.
Speaker 0: right the new stuff.
Speaker 0: It's like a piece.
Speaker 0: I guess even you know PC motherboards.
Speaker 0: I guess even pretty much any x86 motherboard is too complicated to mess.
Speaker 1: Yeah I'm not gonna solder anything to my motherboard to overclock though.
Speaker 1: There were things people would do Along those lines to overclock chips back in the day, right?
Speaker 1: But I think the combination drawing the contact trace to remove the FSB limiter on an Athlon Yep.
Speaker 0: Yeah a combination of you know, the simplicity of the older devices relative to modern times, right.
Speaker 0: the the possibility of upgrading due to availability of superior components Right and also financially right.
Speaker 0: you can buy a pile of broken GBAs Right, like how many I bet you could go on eBay and probably buy GBAs with broken screens Right, oh, yeah cheap.
Speaker 0: deploy these mods and then just resell them and then just replace the screens on it with brand new amazing screens That you bought right and it's like, you know, it's actually.
Speaker 0: it's not that cheap though That's the thing you have to understand right?
Speaker 0: It's like okay, you know, you're buying a brand new amazing IPS screen.
Speaker 0: It's like that's not a cheap thing.
Speaker 0: It's like it's a brand new awesome part, right?
Speaker 0: So it's like the upgrading.
Speaker 0: It's not necessarily inexpensive You know, but it totally it totally works.
Speaker 1: What's cool is it can preserve some aspects of the experience of using old technology?
Speaker 1: Well at the same time modernizing or discarding some of the more negative aspects of that old technology.
Speaker 0: So it's still true to the game, but like the experience is better Yeah, we don't have to use a little worm lights on our GBAs, right if we all get awesome screens in them.
Speaker 1: I remember trying to play multi don't have to have batteries.
Speaker 1: I had the worm light and then I had the link cable plugged into the back of the worm light and it You'd even looked at it the wrong way the game would crash.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we don't have to have batteries dying because I put a lithium-ion battery in the double-a slot.
Speaker 0: Yeah All that kind of stuff.
Speaker 1: now that PlayStation mod I'm gonna admit fully at.
Speaker 0: the sole reason I put that PlayStation mod in was to pirate games like yeah See, that's the thing where I see even though the PlayStation at the time was a brand new PlayStation, right?
Speaker 0: Something that and it was you know, a modern technology at the time.
Speaker 0: I guess it was somewhat modern cuz ps2 was out already.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it was the ps1.
Speaker 1: So it was the re-release of the original PlayStation with the small form factor, right?
Speaker 0: But you know still that wasn't.
Speaker 0: as you know, you don't want a mod at the day at the time.
Speaker 0: nowadays You'd be like whatever right but back in the day modding that wasn't as careless as upgrading a GBA.
Speaker 0: Like if I broke this GBA, I'd be like, oh no, I'd buy another.
Speaker 1: I could not have afforded to buy another one.
Speaker 1: I did not have money, right?
Speaker 0: I have friends with who have just have spare GBAs lying around unused just like I do.
Speaker 0: I could have gotten more GBAs probably for next to nothing.
Speaker 0: right to try again.
Speaker 0: But yeah messing up that ps1 would have been not great But it made economic sense because the piracy possibilities made up for the risk of the mod ship.
Speaker 0: No, I remember my friend in high school.
Speaker 0: He had a PlayStation one that with a mod ship that he put in there and he would go to blockbuster rent games Copy him with his two blank CDs.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right and then return him and he was getting played.
Speaker 0: He basically had a huge binder in 1997 or 8 just like full of like hundreds of places.
Speaker 0: I knew a kid like that and that is partly why cuz he had a he was getting these games that cost 50 60 bucks For you know, three four dollars for a blockbuster rental.
Speaker 1: The thing is I'd never.
Speaker 1: when I got the ps1 my sole actual goal was to play dance dance revolution.
Speaker 0: You know nothing else.
Speaker 1: I needed a mod chip Even if I didn't want to pirate them because they were not released in the US.
Speaker 1: so I had to get Japanese Games that were region locked on the ps1 the mod chip would have also removed the region locking.
Speaker 1: however I then could not actually get a hold of legitimate copies of these games.
Speaker 1: not just But I could.
Speaker 0: yeah, they were very expensive even if you could find them.
Speaker 1: But right around then is when red octane came on the scene and did Netflix of PlayStation games and they had every international game.
Speaker 1: so we signed up for an account and Every week a DDR game came I copied it like I ripped the ISO out I mailed it back that day and I just got as many games I could for one month and I canceled red octane Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there's there's whole scenes of people out there now who are modding Various consoles for various purposes, right?
Speaker 0: There are people modding Consoles to help with speed running so they can like debug the console to see what's going on in there.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right.
Speaker 0: You've got people who are modding consoles for chiptunes purposes Right.
Speaker 0: so they can like, you know get their Gameboy to do better at you know Get some extra access to the synthesizer or whatever that kind of stuff You know, but basically that's just like people are getting.
Speaker 0: you know that the possibilities are out there.
Speaker 0: The stuff is available cheap and the technologies are available.
Speaker 0: Just like there's the the scene is Really cool.
Speaker 0: And if you have any interest in electronics, it's like, you know Like your game consoles as if you're a nerd or like your number one.
Speaker 0: They're like top tier electronics, right?
Speaker 0: So it's like you and you're doing like your little electronics projects right making like an LED blink.
Speaker 0: It's like that's not very exciting Right, but like dude upgrading a GBA suddenly is like whoa.
Speaker 0: That's like a whole new world like you're take your wet straight from crappy hobbyist electronics project with your soldering iron.
Speaker 0: Oh, I made an accumulator Right, and then you start doing game console shit.
Speaker 0: It's like now you can see you know The real the real biz.
Speaker 1: but I also think right now is a golden age for this that will never come again because we're at this point where All the consoles before that came before us.
Speaker 1: not all of them But like many of them like up to like the Gameboys Gameboy advances some of the Playstations like up to the ps2.
Speaker 1: maybe The electronics are simple enough for us to mess with pretty easily.
Speaker 1: the newer ones that are coming out I think are going to be a lot more difficult to mod effectively.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think that even when even when you know The switch is really old like.
Speaker 1: I don't think we're gonna be modding the switch there.
Speaker 0: I think even right even a 3ds right.
Speaker 0: I think it's like okay on a 3ds You could probably swap out the screen, but you think about Right.
Speaker 0: it's like you think about phones these days, right?
Speaker 0: It's like you know when it comes to cell phones cuz 3ds is about cell phone.
Speaker 0: I'm not gonna mod my old palm Smartphone so I can write a Nintendo switch is definitely cell phone level tech right in terms of you know Miniaturization level right touch.
Speaker 0: It's got a touchscreen.
Speaker 0: You know whatever is that the Peripherals?
Speaker 0: I think can still.
Speaker 0: there's still things to be done there replacing screens and messing with the audio messing with the inputs Right and the outputs yeah, but I think it'll be more Preservation and less for upgrade.
Speaker 0: the actual motherboards themselves like to mess with a switch Motherboard to mess with an iPhone motherboard.
Speaker 0: like people can fix your screen on your iPhone They can replace the battery on your iPhone.
Speaker 0: you can put a different speaker, or you know fix the camera.
Speaker 0: Maybe on your iPhone you can maybe mess with that right, but it's like you know to actually mess with anything on the board It's like that is too much.
Speaker 0: I think for anyone without some serious equipment and skills right It's.
Speaker 0: you know you're better off just making a new phone Doing that.
Speaker 1: but it's like that.
Speaker 1: we're just in this sweet spot now of the price versus availability versus access versus risk of messing with like These earlier eras of consoles in cool fun ways.
Speaker 0: And I think what's actually gonna happen as time goes on right like I said the newer The newer devices 3ds kind of forward are too complicated to mess with in a significant way Right and they don't have these glaring flaws that need to be improved either right that the older devices have.
Speaker 0: And What's gonna happen is even though now we can mod the old ones I think what will happen as time goes on is the old ones will become rarer Right they're gonna become rare and more expensive.
Speaker 0: so right now You could go and load up on game boys game boy colors game boy advances right all this sort of stuff And mod to your hearts can imagine
Speaker 1: being the person like 20 years from now Who rolls into like a mag fest and is like sets up the room of all right?
Speaker 1: Here's a room with 20 chairs and 20 of these ancient game boy advances that still work right?
Speaker 0: 20 years from now?
Speaker 0: how hard will it unless Nintendo or someone decides to remake them right which I think you know.
Speaker 0: that though There will be right is like there's a lot of people remaking old.
Speaker 0: like I said You know you can buy like clones of an NES of.
Speaker 0: you know a modern machine that plays NES cartridges right they make those, but you know to get an actual game boy 20 years from now I don't know how many how easy that'll be to get one right Considering it how many will be broken lost or modded right?
Speaker 0: So there are however people who are doing things such as like the raspberry like pi zero game boys Yeah, or basically you instead of buying it old game boy.
Speaker 0: What you do is you get a raspberry pi zero Which it's a
Speaker 1: lot like making a main cabinet, but making a main portable
Speaker 0: Exactly as you just make a game boy out of a different computer entirely with emulators on it right And that's also a road to go down.
Speaker 0: I don't think that will ever really go away.
Speaker 0: that actually only become easier as smaller computers get faster and more powerful, so That's I think the alternative.
Speaker 1: yeah So now's the time.
Speaker 1: if you want to like now is the time both because the pandemic and you're stuck inside and because of the availability.
Speaker 1: You'll want to try this out like do it now because much like PC overclocking The window where that made sense and was easy to do and worth it to do was pretty brief.
Speaker 0: And there's a lot if you're looking to not be creative and just sort of do existing stuff.
Speaker 0: There's lots of companies who are making all these upgrade products and selling them and making tricking people into making ads for them on their YouTube channels.
Speaker 1: but they come with like really good instructions like if you've never Soldered before like prac like poking some solder a little bit And then you probably be able to pull this off all over YouTube and all the websites that sell the products They want.
Speaker 0: they're not?
Speaker 0: they realize they can't sell it.
Speaker 0: you a screen Replacement for your GBA if they're not also giving you Instructions that make you feel like you're confident enough that you can install it yourself.
Speaker 0: right so and some of them are selling pre-modded ones But they charge an arm and a leg for that as they should.
Speaker 0: so go out there.
Speaker 0: And you know these companies.
Speaker 0: they have very limited runs on these products.
Speaker 0: It's like they'll make these things sell them They'll sell out then maybe they'll make some more.
Speaker 0: Maybe not right.
Speaker 0: Maybe they'll something better will come out.
Speaker 0: So you sort of have to stay on top of it and like order stuff as it becomes available And watch.
Speaker 0: you know these companies.
Speaker 0: I think they exist now.
Speaker 0: I think they're gonna eventually like the market for this stuff will go away.
Speaker 0: So it's sort of like you have to go.
Speaker 0: if you want to be a customer of any of these companies you got to go Find them now.
Speaker 0: So yeah use your use your Google skills you can find them.
Speaker 1: I think that's a fine show.
Speaker 1: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 0: be sure to visit our Website at front row crew comm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 1: remember geek nights is not one But four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 0: geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience But unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night and The patreon patrons for this episode of geek nights, which I still have to wait for this page to load Which is taking longer than I expected?
Speaker 1: I always record this live.
Speaker 1: I'm never gonna break that promise.
Speaker 1: meaning now.
Speaker 1: I'm stuck here.
Speaker 1: pattern here We go Alan Joyce Heidi McNichol Marty green.
Speaker 1: yeah Green is refreshing just like a dude guy.
Speaker 1: church option Graham Finch you hold the key to my heart.
Speaker 1: she gave me my kiss and she gave me my ticket.
Speaker 1: Clinton Walton J Bantz renter New Zealand Ryan Perrin Nicholas Brando Chris midkiff the thirst for hydrated Gannon dread Lily Tenebrae Chris Reimer Finn Sean Klein sure van Hollen a bunch of people who don't want me to say their names.
Speaker 1: Yeah, not much change since last week.
Speaker 1: stay tuned for a new tenor preview coming up soon because like I said we did work out a format that doesn't involve us having to synchronize a remote stream and We'll see how this format works.
Speaker 1: My backup plan if that doesn't work is I'm just gonna start making them myself because then I don't have to wait on Scott to schedule like his half of the video.
Speaker 1: So we'll see how that goes.
Speaker 1: but luckily these black rose episodes are pretty easy to do.
Speaker 1: They're the ones that I thought about the most in the past and I did dig out from when I the last time I started Pre-production.
Speaker 1: I had all the notes and I had some clips already pulled out.
Speaker 1: So I Should have a preview to show soon.
Speaker 1: I'm a little behind on that, but I think it's coming anyway.
Speaker 1: right now I'm gonna leave you with something that I doubt any of you will recognize Can't be gone Then she doesn't.