Speaker 1: It's Monday August 31st 2020.
Speaker 1: I'm rim.
Speaker 1: I'm Scott and this is geek nights tonight.
Speaker 1: We are talking about biometrics.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: it's uh, it's a tough time right now because Right around now.
Speaker 1: I mean year by year and all varies a little bit way to either be in Seattle About to fly to Seattle like this is the pecs time.
Speaker 0: It's pretty rare.
Speaker 0: You're gonna get a geek night's episode in August 31st, right like.
Speaker 0: probably You may be next year, but probably not the year after.
Speaker 1: hopefully This is when like all my calendar invites that I set to myself for like go to packs do things prepare slides Like they're all popping up in my feed up until this point the quarantine for all the trouble, you know it's not the best time like.
Speaker 1: I'd rather not have to be quarantined, but We haven't actually missed that many major Conventions or events because the summer is actually usually kind of our downtime.
Speaker 1: But we're now hitting the period where we would normally go to a major convention every month for like five months in a row sometimes multiple in a month and this is the point where I'm actually going to not have that happen.
Speaker 0: for the first time in since 2008 Yeah, we pretty much been doing the same You know, not, you know daily routine has changed and things like that.
Speaker 0: obviously but our Annual schedule, you know zoomed out the macro schedule has been pretty much the same for about ten years.
Speaker 0: Yeah until now.
Speaker 0: so There you go.
Speaker 1: Yep I'd like I had a dream the other night where I was just like We were on our way to PAX West and then I was like, oh shit What hotel are we in?
Speaker 1: and I couldn't remember and I didn't know what hotel we booked because we don't have a hotel We're not going to PAX West.
Speaker 1: I was like, I'm in the Sheridan or the Red Lion.
Speaker 1: Red Lion doesn't even exist anymore.
Speaker 1: What's going on?
Speaker 0: It's the motif.
Speaker 0: We're in the one that has the new PAX tabletop in it.
Speaker 1: That's where we usually are.
Speaker 0: That's what I have.
Speaker 0: one year We've been in it.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: That's where we would probably be again Probably yes.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So now now it's the weird time where there are things I'm missing that I would normally be doing.
Speaker 1: that are big things that are like Milestones of the year.
Speaker 1: PAX always ends summer for me and now there's no PAX.
Speaker 0: So either summer's gonna go on forever, which I'll take that Okay Yeah, but you know, I mean, it's just people have to get ready.
Speaker 0: I mean, even though it's been many months already, I think you know, it's like, okay.
Speaker 0: Everything's different.
Speaker 0: now People have to accept that like yeah On the other side is not gonna be going back to what you had before Not for a long time.
Speaker 0: At least I don't know.
Speaker 0: there isn't Like.
Speaker 0: some things will probably be able to return to the what they were right But the point is is that it's not like, you know, let's say we get past the virus and get past fascism somehow in 2020.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, it's not like.
Speaker 1: oh everything's fixed.
Speaker 0: 2022 is not gonna suddenly look like 2018 new or 24 or 2014 or you know any of the years of the past 10 years, right?
Speaker 0: It's gonna be.
Speaker 0: it's gonna be a different look.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right.
Speaker 0: You don't go get a makeover and come out.
Speaker 0: It's like oh, I'm getting a makeover right now, you know, looking bad looking good changing things up You know, whatever you don't come out on the other side looking exactly the same as you went in.
Speaker 0: Like that doesn't happen.
Speaker 1: Yep, some things whatever whatever your life situation is except that now yep, especially because where there's a long haul in the u.s.
Speaker 1: So Even like vaccines and things like there aren't gonna be a lot of cons next year.
Speaker 0: If any we'll see.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we'll see how it all goes.
Speaker 1: But there is a lot of tech news and we got to keep milking this Apple story because it's just growing and growing and stuff.
Speaker 0: So the first thing I got to say about the Apple story is obviously this brewing has only was sort of started at that Congressional hearing and only went up since right.
Speaker 0: and I got to say well Apple is obviously none of the companies involved here.
Speaker 0: good by the way.
Speaker 1: Yeah, nobody's nobody like clearly the right one.
Speaker 0: This is this is a bad guy battle here.
Speaker 0: This is like, you know, dr Doom and you know Lex Luthor punching it out.
Speaker 0: but the point is is that You know of all those four companies that were at that hearing right your Google your Facebook.
Speaker 0: Right your Amazon and your Apple, right?
Speaker 0: Apple is getting the the most blows here in the immediate aftermath, right?
Speaker 0: And why is that?
Speaker 0: Number one Apple has the most money of all those companies.
Speaker 0: What's Apple's I think as the biggest market cap ever in history of any company something some trillion.
Speaker 1: the entire like u.s Tech sector is bigger than many world like global regional economies right now Which let's not get into how the stock market doesn't reflect reality.
Speaker 1: but anyway, Apple got a lot of wealth and capital.
Speaker 0: Apple Apple is big right and also, right.
Speaker 0: Apple is philosophically At least on paper right the enemy of those other three companies, right?
Speaker 0: If you look at the four companies in the box, right?
Speaker 0: Apple is the one where the customer is the customer.
Speaker 1: Yeah Which doesn't always mean you're the right.
Speaker 1: good guy like Amazon treats the customer on a pedestal.
Speaker 0: get a row I was gonna say right.
Speaker 0: so a Google and Facebook the customer is the product right.
Speaker 0: on Amazon the customer is sort of the customer right but what Amazon does is they Exploit others in service of the customer while also taking the customers data to help it better exploit others.
Speaker 0: Apple right serves the customer but sees itself as a luxury service.
Speaker 0: So who do they exploit?
Speaker 0: also the customer.
Speaker 0: by making them pay.
Speaker 0: they make everyone they work with pay, right?
Speaker 0: It's like, you know instead of you know, taking your data and selling it or spying on you or any of those things, right?
Speaker 0: We're just gonna make everyone pay.
Speaker 0: developers pay customers overpay for my RAM.
Speaker 0: everyone pay money.
Speaker 0: right and You know will treat the customer nicely, but they don't treat anyone else nice just the cover That's and so because of that right that aligns the Google's and Facebook's of the world, you know against Apple.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right, especially since they have to operate on Apple's platform, right?
Speaker 0: So like I why does?
Speaker 1: Apple's platform is not the majority is not a monopoly.
Speaker 1: there are other platform Forms for smartphones and tablets and everything.
Speaker 1: but Apple basically has complete control over people who are fully into their Ecosystem.
Speaker 1: and the reality of the world is it's not easy for most people to switch ecosystems.
Speaker 0: no but if you think about it, right Apple doesn't Depend on Amazon.
Speaker 0: It's like they might use some Oz Computers or Google cloud compute or Microsoft Azure or stuff like that.
Speaker 0: They don't have those resources.
Speaker 0: I've heard like iCloud is hosted on those.
Speaker 0: possibly it's unknown But I've definitely heard stories that Apple hosts their iCloud on other clouds, but they're not dependent.
Speaker 0: They could just switch that up.
Speaker 0: They can do their own.
Speaker 0: They don't.
Speaker 0: they're not dependent on that, right?
Speaker 0: But so like no one has a hold on Apple No one can make Apple do anything that they don't want to do right, but Google's got to put Google Maps at iOS.
Speaker 0: Facebook's app is the numbers like the number one way to use Facebook.
Speaker 0: It's got to be on iOS If if Apple kicks Facebook out of the App Store Completely like the default Facebook app or the Facebook Messenger app or the Instagram app.
Speaker 0: It's like some people would leave iOS to go get an Android phone to get the Facebook app.
Speaker 1: I think a lot of people would use this as an excuse to say I guess I can't log into my Facebook account ever again.
Speaker 0: Oh, right But Facebook would be totally but Huge, it's true.
Speaker 1: I feel like to be real like real about it.
Speaker 1: I think Facebook would lose basically all of its non Dangerously crazy users and all of its young users and all that would be left would be like you and on conspiracies and anti-vaxxers.
Speaker 0: The point is is that Apple's got a hold on the other people they don't have and they got nothing on Apple.
Speaker 0: So that's why the battle rages.
Speaker 0: Okay, so what's the latest developments in the battle?
Speaker 0: So first?
Speaker 0: There was some shenanigans in with Apple's review process.
Speaker 0: Someone reviewing the WordPress app basically misunderstood it and misunderstood work the difference between WordPress the software and wordpress.com the site and There was some tussle.
Speaker 0: and then Apple said oops are bad and fixed it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so that's just a poor timing on.
Speaker 0: You know something that happens relatively often in the Apple, you know App Store approval process Especially and it goes unnoticed when it happens to smaller apps of Apple not understanding the what the app is and getting their own policies wrong because they've got a whole team of people doing reviews who aren't necessarily Even
Speaker 1: arguably.
Speaker 1: I've seen people make an argument that sometimes what Apple has done to them is Be purposefully obtuse as an excuse to not let an app in where there's some other reason they don't want that have to be in the store.
Speaker 0: sure so the It's just bad timing for them to get exposed on that thing.
Speaker 0: So what they've done is they now Apple came out I think today and they were like, okay, we got a new thing for our approval our App Store approval process, right?
Speaker 0: So they are making some effort to at least look better or do better.
Speaker 0: And what they're doing the changes they've made are that a if you're making just a bug fix patch like a small patch, right?
Speaker 0: They're just gonna let it go.
Speaker 0: if your apps already approved Right without holding you up and then if they happen to find something in your bug fix patch That they don't like that is not approved They'll get.
Speaker 0: they'll let your app stay up and basically make you fix it in your next, you know, your next go Right, so they're not gonna like because there's been a lot of times where people had bug fixes and they got held up or it's Like they're just fixing a bug and suddenly their apps out of the store and they're afraid to fix their bugs because you know Yeah,
Speaker 1: but a lot of that still resolve revolves around.
Speaker 1: What are the parameters where upon Apple will kick you out or force you to pay them the vig?
Speaker 0: So the second the second thing is they changed it.
Speaker 0: So There is now some sort of appeals a better appeals process or an unappeals process where there previously was none or whatever.
Speaker 0: So if you've got something That happened to you and you're not happy with the ruling you can appeal better I guess than before.
Speaker 0: we'll see.
Speaker 0: we'll wait for people to actually put in appeals and see what happens to them to figure out how well that's working.
Speaker 0: and the third thing is What was the third thing?
Speaker 1: Oh, so there was.
Speaker 0: they're going to take suggestions and like input from develop Apple developers Into what the rules should and should not be.
Speaker 0: so basically you can comment to Apple and say hey this rules bullshit.
Speaker 0: This rule is good.
Speaker 0: You should add this really should remove that rule.
Speaker 0: This rule is not clear, etc.
Speaker 1: What if they just see how that goes that are all just don't charge 30% for in-app purchase, right?
Speaker 0: Right?
Speaker 0: We'll see how that works, right?
Speaker 0: So the in-app purchases.
Speaker 0: so stories in that front and that front right.
Speaker 0: Facebook tried to put in a notice in their app To let users know that Apple was taking a 30% cut.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and that they could go to Facebook.
Speaker 0: they could go pay somewhere else and not through the app and deny Apple that money and pay the same price.
Speaker 0: Right and Apple was like no you can't tell users irrelevant information.
Speaker 1: Yeah quote irrelevant information.
Speaker 1: That is clearly a clause to let Apple quash anything.
Speaker 1: They don't like that.
Speaker 1: Anyone says in an app during the payment, right?
Speaker 0: That's a definitely an ambiguous rule.
Speaker 0: I'm sure you could go and find tons of apps with irrelevant information in them in their you eyes That are approved and Apple doesn't give a crap.
Speaker 0: That's definitely a vague arbitrarily, you know ambiguously Non-consistently enforced rule that Apple has in there so that for situations like this they can you know Have a rule.
Speaker 0: it's like oh, okay.
Speaker 0: We don't allow.
Speaker 0: you know this right?
Speaker 1: This is just
Speaker 0: like because this is just like all those laws that say Black people can't vote without actually writing down black people can't vote and you write something else like oh, yeah You can only register to vote on a Tuesday in the middle of the day in this part of town.
Speaker 1: You know what else?
Speaker 0: Where there's a bunch of white people with guns.
Speaker 1: there were a bunch of fights and there are still fights about.
Speaker 1: When can companies of various types?
Speaker 1: Include taxes and fees that they have to pay to other entities in their prices?
Speaker 1: They show you versus when do they have to be added after the fact?
Speaker 1: like some places there are laws that say you can't include the sales tax in a price you publish because they?
Speaker 1: the sales tax has to be Calculated after the fact to avoid the kinds of optics problems that state and local governments Don't want to deal with like weird laws and weird rules happen all the time.
Speaker 1: I remember as a kid Cedar Point the rollercoaster park got a special exemption from the state of Ohio to still collect sales tax But not say that they were collecting it and just include it in their prices, which was not allowed anywhere else in the States.
Speaker 1: Kind of like how some companies can say oh, we're charging you this fee.
Speaker 0: That sounds like not equal protection under the law to me.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well they applied it at like a county level.
Speaker 0: We're like Sandusky County has an example sounds like not equal protection under the law.
Speaker 0: to me.
Speaker 1: That equaled protection probably doesn't apply to a case like that.
Speaker 0: I mean, I know what the equal protection legally means right and that obviously Can arbitrarily regulate right commerce?
Speaker 0: I know that that is our.
Speaker 0: that is legal under the law as written and as you know enforced in the United States.
Speaker 0: But in principle the same laws should apply to everyone everywhere.
Speaker 0: and that's a case where it's like Oh, I live in a different place different law.
Speaker 0: All right, it's like oh, I'm in the next town over a different law I make more money.
Speaker 0: I'm allowed to trade these stocks, right?
Speaker 0: I'm a I'm an accredited investor.
Speaker 0: different laws for me, right and I I see all of those as in principle you know not.
Speaker 1: what I'm getting here is this is this is more the question of Providing that information is harmful to Apple's brand.
Speaker 1: but the information is true But Apple is banning this information from being shared in a place where it would be relevant by claiming it's irrelevant.
Speaker 1: This is this is a battle that has never been resolved pretty much anywhere right?
Speaker 0: the second battle that's going on Obviously the fortnight one the big one right.
Speaker 0: the current status is that on iOS you can still play fortnight But the developer account has been suspended so you can't download fortnight, but if you've already got it, you've already got it.
Speaker 0: So what that means is all the iOS fortnight players are stuck in the previous season of fortnight.
Speaker 1: I know enough about the kids to know that that basically means they don't have fortnight and are not getting updates.
Speaker 0: So it's sort of like a whole bunch of people playing Counter-strike source and then everyone else on all the other platform is playing counter-strike.
Speaker 0: go right, they all got the update but iOS isn't gonna get the updates for now.
Speaker 0: and but the the situation involving The unreal engine is still that you know if you're making games with unreal engine you can still get them on iOS.
Speaker 0: just epic Itself can't get their games out right yeah.
Speaker 0: So the argument that I want to make that I haven't seen anyone make right which seems really straightforward to me Which is why I don't know.
Speaker 0: there must be some reason that clearly that explains Why me not a lawyer or expert in any way has thought of this.
Speaker 0: yet corporate lawyers paid lots of money have not thought of It or at least not said it.
Speaker 0: there must be some reason because this seems so obvious.
Speaker 0: right.
Speaker 0: The Bose basic thing we learned about antitrust I even knew this as a kid from the Microsoft case was that if you got a monopoly in one area You can't use it to help yourself win and take over another market.
Speaker 0: Yeah Microsoft had monopoly on operating systems for peace, but already here's the problem.
Speaker 1: What's the market?
Speaker 1: is the market?
Speaker 0: I'll hold on.
Speaker 0: I got you I got no.
Speaker 0: no no I got you right.
Speaker 0: you can't use that to wedge yourself in and take over In the browser department.
Speaker 0: right that's what Microsoft got called out on right.
Speaker 0: so it seems pretty obvious to me.
Speaker 0: Right this whole 30% App Store thing that's going on right Instead of framing it as everyone has is like Apple taking a cut of your apps, right?
Speaker 0: But it actually is.
Speaker 0: is Apple is wedging out PayPal stripe Right payment cut Google pay.
Speaker 0: right you cannot use.
Speaker 0: if you've got an app in the Apple App Store You cannot sell.
Speaker 0: let's say you got a game that sells coins.
Speaker 1: I see where you're going with this.
Speaker 0: Here's that you can't use.
Speaker 0: you can't use PayPal to sell your coins in your game on the Apple App Store.
Speaker 0: You must use Apple pay.
Speaker 1: so if you go to a restaurant they can be like cash only.
Speaker 1: or we only accept Amex that's true, but the And arguably Might be monopolies because in that County there aren't in the other rows of that type.
Speaker 0: But that restaurant is not itself have a its own Restaurant pay and it does not control a significant portion of the restaurant market, but that Monopoly, what is the market?
Speaker 1: is the market?
Speaker 0: iPhone users or smart visa visa could not buy.
Speaker 0: if visa bought Several fast-food chains and made it so the only way to buy food at them is a visa that might fly.
Speaker 1: I actually that might.
Speaker 1: they might win that one Maybe.
Speaker 0: but like imagine if McDonald's and like they had a but they have to have a monopoly on fast food, right?
Speaker 0: so burger King and Taco Bell and McDonald's and Chipotle and Wendy's and every single almost every single fast food like more than half of it is owned by visa.
Speaker 1: Get the money from because Apple has Apple pay.
Speaker 1: But you still inject money into the Apple pay system from something else like a credit card.
Speaker 0: The point is I want to see right that.
Speaker 0: I think that you know, we should see PayPal stripe and all those payment processors should be the ones Complaining about Apple saying hey Developers want to you like our payment platforms But they can't use them in the Apple and their apps their native apps in the Apple App Store Right.
Speaker 0: Apple is pushing us out with their antitrust, right?
Speaker 1: I don't want to fly though because I think this is this is Apple running a store?
Speaker 1: Stores can use whatever payment things they would like to use but it's not.
Speaker 0: you're not paying You know, you're not buying the thing from Apple.
Speaker 0: You're buying the thing from the developer Yeah, but you're buying it for it to be a store Apple run marketplace.
Speaker 0: for it to be a store Apple would have to buy the app from the app developer and then Amazon goes straight past their sales and they take a cut.
Speaker 0: Yeah, okay You can't pay with a lot of not anything though River.
Speaker 1: oh, you can't use rim Co to pay that payment process Apple.
Speaker 0: if Amazon said the only way to buy anything on Amazon is with an Amazon credit card.
Speaker 0: I think that would be a little.
Speaker 1: ah Amazon there's a much better claim that they have a near monopoly on like online purchase, but they don't do that.
Speaker 0: You can use any old can use discover Processor.
Speaker 1: they're not taking a payment processing fee They're taking a. you're using our platform to host your app to download the app the infrastructure everything Like this is a can mark what
Speaker 0: they take what they're taking that fee on all Payments and they're making you process all payments through them and not it's
Speaker 1: for the purpose of them Collecting the cut that you have to agree to to sell stuff in their marketplace.
Speaker 0: You're welcome to not sell stuff in their marketplace But I think because it's as a side effect if it's you know anti-competitive against other payment processing Companies that could force Apple to adopt a different model, right?
Speaker 1: Apple could trivially say you can pay with any payment processor, but we take 30%.
Speaker 0: How would they do that?
Speaker 0: How would that be technologically possible?
Speaker 1: They've got paid.
Speaker 0: they my money is going from me directly to PayPal and then to the app.
Speaker 0: What they're?
Speaker 0: how is Apple gonna reach in if you're in our store?
Speaker 1: You can't directly sell stuff without going through our cash register Which actually is very common in farmers markets and art fairs and all sorts of things.
Speaker 0: No, it's still you know, there's something going on there.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm saying You that Apple has a monopoly except over people who choose to use Apple technology.
Speaker 0: But there's an argument you could make over the fact that you saw if you're a developer Right, it's like even though a lot of people use Android it's been shown, you know, numerically right.
Speaker 0: then Yeah You don't really make money selling like a game in the Android Google Play Store as much as you make money selling it on the Apple Store.
Speaker 0: It's like you sorta.
Speaker 0: if you want to make money selling mobile apps It's like yeah, the Apple App Store is where people pay for things the Google Play Store not so much.
Speaker 0: And that also has the sideloading thing going on there too, right?
Speaker 0: There's no.
Speaker 1: but is any amount of money Acceptable for the owner of the marketplace to extract from the system for the purpose of providing the marketplace which costs money to provide Right.
Speaker 0: Oh, I'd say like let's say you get to mark two farmers markets in town, right?
Speaker 0: And in one of them all the farmers make bank.
Speaker 0: for some reason that has all the customers Right that pay.
Speaker 0: the other one has a lot of foot traffic, but for some reason no one buys anything there Right or very little.
Speaker 0: and it's like They go to the big farmers market starts to crack down and do evil shit and they're like We don't have a monopoly.
Speaker 0: look at that.
Speaker 0: others farm farmers market and the farmers like we don't make any money in that market.
Speaker 1: There's also the problem of do the users care or not.
Speaker 1: Most people who don't play fortnight don't give a shit.
Speaker 0: Well for a fortnight for now, but there's a lot.
Speaker 0: there's a lot going on, right?
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, but I'm saying that I did.
Speaker 1: I think it'll be very difficult for Anyone to win against.
Speaker 0: it's just it's just.
Speaker 0: I mean, yeah, it's just an angle right that it's not been discussed, right?
Speaker 0: It's like, you know, I'm throwing on my armchair analysis.
Speaker 1: It's not like.
Speaker 1: I have special knowledge here.
Speaker 0: I didn't say.
Speaker 0: it seems like, you know, it seems like they're wedging out the payment processors, right?
Speaker 0: You gotta use Apple pay you anything else?
Speaker 1: I think that's a side effect like they don't care about the payment processors.
Speaker 1: Their only goal is if your thing is in our store.
Speaker 1: We want to cut of anything you bring.
Speaker 0: Well, I think what Apple actually believes is that you know is actually what they say Apple is.
Speaker 0: they they're very good at saying What they believe right?
Speaker 0: So they say it's like yeah, we want you to use Apple pay because it's more secure.
Speaker 0: It's safer It's a better experience for the customer.
Speaker 0: right and all those things are kind of true, right?
Speaker 0: And that's why they don't want you know PayPal in the App Store or whatever because it's like yeah There's some shenanigans suddenly Apple customers getting screwed over because something PayPal did right?
Speaker 0: They don't want that, right?
Speaker 0: But the side effect is you may or may not sort of be antitrusting out those competitors who aren't.
Speaker 1: but if that were a Real argument they would just let you use any payment processor.
Speaker 1: But they.
Speaker 1: the rule is you still have to pay Apple 30% of any transactions that happen in their store.
Speaker 0: But then you could just hide the transactions from Apple.
Speaker 1: But hiding the transactions is how Apple will then say you violated our rules and kick you out.
Speaker 0: And how could you how could they know you hid them you hit them?
Speaker 1: By going.
Speaker 1: if someone could download the app and try it.
Speaker 0: if I pay money to as I'm saying Technologically if I paid a PayPal you got an app.
Speaker 0: I buy coins in your app.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right.
Speaker 1: So I go to the with PayPal.
Speaker 0: Apple has no way to know how much money I gave you or that I even gave you money but that was part of my Terms of service.
Speaker 1: you got to pay me 30% of all those transactions or I kick everyone lies and pays you nothing.
Speaker 1: Yeah, then they kick them all out.
Speaker 1: That's what would happen.
Speaker 1: That's how.
Speaker 0: How would they know?
Speaker 0: you just say everyone would just say no one paid me.
Speaker 1: In situations like this Usually what happens is the company that suspects the problem will approach the companies that are the biggest likely offenders Demand an audit and if they don't comply kick them out of their marketplace.
Speaker 0: pretty sure Apple would rather.
Speaker 0: You know, it's a big difference between Apple having to do that.
Speaker 0: Also.
Speaker 1: All I ever do is have an And say oh look I can buy stuff through PayPal here.
Speaker 1: And if I do that, I will buy something.
Speaker 1: now.
Speaker 1: Look that company did not give us a 30%.
Speaker 0: The point is Apple having to do that to every single app and the billions of zillions of apps in the App Store and audit all of them versus Automatically collecting 30% without having to do anything.
Speaker 1: I guess is Apple obligated to create an in-app purchase ecosystem or not?
Speaker 1: They could just say no in-app purchases fuck you.
Speaker 0: and They could.
Speaker 0: they could say no app on the App Store is allowed to have in-app purchases.
Speaker 0: then they themselves would lose a shit ton of money because Everyone would lose money.
Speaker 1: Yeah, because really is most people don't actually buy or install.
Speaker 0: But it's not just the you know, it's not just the in-app purchases It's also.
Speaker 0: you buy a $10 app.
Speaker 0: seven dollars goes to the developer three dollars goes to Apple.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and even if the app has no in-app purchases after the initial $10, but the other thing is what if here's a hypothetical?
Speaker 1: What if without taking a significant chunk of all the in-app purchases the App Store itself is infeasible won't make enough money and Bet?
Speaker 1: the way for them to make money would just be to scale it back.
Speaker 1: Do less reviews of products let less things in just make it shittier.
Speaker 1: Like there's a lot of negative outcomes for everyone involved that could happen here.
Speaker 0: They could just have a different Model for it.
Speaker 0: that makes sense like hey You want to list an app in the App Store.
Speaker 0: if the app collects money is a freak because already if you have a free App right they all you have to do is pay to be an Apple developer.
Speaker 0: Yep, and then you can put your free all many free apps as you want, right?
Speaker 1: But most people only make free apps because they won't have in-app purchase.
Speaker 0: obviously most most apps in the App Store are free Which is what Apple also says.
Speaker 0: but if anyone makes an app that is not free in any way.
Speaker 0: Right?
Speaker 0: then you have to pay Apple a flat fee to list the app the listing fee.
Speaker 1: I don't think that would make enough money for Apple to even bother continuing with the marketplace.
Speaker 0: the app stores exist to sell.
Speaker 0: they Didn't even have the App Store in the first iPhone.
Speaker 0: the existence of the App Store makes Apple its money Via making people want to buy an iPhone.
Speaker 0: They should know.
Speaker 0: I'm actually clear We don't have data to show if that is the fact that they the fact that they make the 30% is Actually, it's like heart following the horse situation.
Speaker 1: Oh, but I would argue that that 30 that that 30% is probably critical and was probably though I don't know part of their business plan all along.
Speaker 0: No, no, no, I'm pretty it feels to me.
Speaker 0: I mean I was there alive at that time.
Speaker 0: That was a very different market - yeah Apple definitely I felt like at the beginning Caved in and a mate allowed the native apps by third-party developers, which they didn't want to do originally.
Speaker 0: They allowed it, you know with the intention that aha this will make people want to buy iPhones.
Speaker 0: Right the and the App Store is just a way to get people to buy.
Speaker 0: you know to make You know the phone desirable.
Speaker 0: and then it's like oh actually we're not making money on selling phones.
Speaker 0: People are just keeping their phones for a long time not upgrading them so much.
Speaker 0: We'll make our money on that.
Speaker 0: Oh, but the App Store look how much money it's making.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 1: Well, that's the money is I guess Yeah, but there's there's sort of the final.
Speaker 1: the real problem is still capitalism in that many problems always capital.
Speaker 1: But I'm saying many things like this Often what can happen in a market is the rent seekers are Actually using that rent to provide the service or to make it worthwhile to the people that own that company to bother provide Collecting plenty of extra rent.
Speaker 0: They could easily Charge way less rent.
Speaker 1: Ah, but if that would make them less profits, why bother?
Speaker 1: Why not just shut it all down?
Speaker 1: Like there's.
Speaker 0: there might be a because you're pretty because you're at least pretending to be less evil than the competitors.
Speaker 1: Ah, but fiduciary duty you are beholden to your shareholders To do the right thing for them not for society.
Speaker 0: They're already worth it.
Speaker 0: You already have the most valuable stock there is.
Speaker 0: I think you're doing well, right?
Speaker 1: But I'm just saying there's a. there are many things that if you strip away the monetization that late Capitalism has sort of thrust into those markets those products would just disappear in time.
Speaker 0: that logic by that logic Why doesn't an Apple shareholder complain and say hey, well, you should be charging 50% not 30?
Speaker 1: They do all the times shareholders Oftentimes activist shareholders will try to buy enough shares to force the company to be even more evil.
Speaker 1: That is the thing that happens.
Speaker 1: so if they don't have to listen to those even more evil shareholders they only don't have to listen to those more evil shareholders because smarter institutional investors hold on to enough of the stock to have enough of a majority.
Speaker 0: Is that if you if you can fend off a guy who says you should be charged in 50 instead of 30 Then you can fend off a guy who says you should be charged at 30 instead of 10?
Speaker 0: Maybe not because sometimes like if the profits aren't high gonna ask a judge to chart to determine the correct number You should be charging?
Speaker 0: Well me that what you're doing is legal in the first.
Speaker 1: now what it comes down to more Is that the company could just redirect strategically entirely?
Speaker 1: If something is not worth the hassle to maintain a high squeeze rate of the profits from that area.
Speaker 1: Also a lot of things like.
Speaker 1: here's a good example Facebook sucks.
Speaker 1: Facebook is evil.
Speaker 1: Facebook probably harmed America and the world in irreparable ways and Facebook should be destroyed.
Speaker 1: However nothing else Has the access that Facebook has especially in local hyper local even rural communities.
Speaker 1: So a lot of like left-wing activists organized on Facebook because without that tool There is no other way to reach a certain subset of the population.
Speaker 1: They need to reach.
Speaker 0: What do you do about that when the thing that's realize it because it's it's an essential tool.
Speaker 1: Ah, but there's a there gets even thornier problem Utility if you have the national social network.
Speaker 1: that could also get real bad in a hurry for a whole different set of reasons.
Speaker 0: That's a you know, that's the old.
Speaker 0: that's what you know, right-wing people say Oh, if the government owns it, then it's not free the the.
Speaker 0: if the government owns the printing press they will print.
Speaker 1: But would you trust our current government?
Speaker 1: Would you trust our current government with the social network?
Speaker 0: No, yeah.
Speaker 0: hence The point is like Twitter.
Speaker 1: Twitter is irreplaceable and Twitter also needs to be replaced because it's dangerous and broken.
Speaker 1: Mmm, there's no way to make a competitor to it in capitalism that could possibly succeed.
Speaker 1: In fact Twitter itself can't succeed.
Speaker 1: What you gonna do so in some other news.
Speaker 0: this is a very real go with news We're not.
Speaker 0: that news wasn't one more news.
Speaker 1: We can skip some of the other light ones, but this one is very tech news.
Speaker 1: This everyone kept talking to me about.
Speaker 1: this is a very rim news.
Speaker 1: this chrome feature and the DNS thing.
Speaker 1: Okay, I think we actually talk.
Speaker 0: Oh, we didn't talk about this.
Speaker 0: So about this?
Speaker 1: there is a thing that ISPs do that is evil and I think should be made illegal.
Speaker 1: Where the DNS server they give you.
Speaker 1: if you're not a smart tech person who knows how to avoid this If you type if you miss type a URL They'll take you to some other site.
Speaker 1: They'll give you a DNS result to that.
Speaker 1: Anyway, that takes some spam site, right?
Speaker 0: So you type into your browser Com which doesn't exist.
Speaker 0: No one's registered that domain or pointed it anywhere and what you should get as a response from the DNS server's system Right is no such domain NX, right?
Speaker 1: But there's this.
Speaker 1: this system is a hierarchy.
Speaker 0: It works this way for you're supposed to get an NX which is yeah You typed in a non-existent domain.
Speaker 0: It does not register the DNS system but instead your ISP will send you an IP address and say hey Here's the I or C name or whatever.
Speaker 0: Here's the address of that of that domain root.com.
Speaker 0: and you end up at a website that is run by Verizon or who knows.
Speaker 1: usually it has some ads on it, right?
Speaker 0: Usually it's got ads and search results or stuff and that your ISP is making money on that and tracking you and learning about you And such and such and they should not be allowed to do that.
Speaker 1: Yep, so chrome chromium had a pretty good feature where cleverly It's a way to detect if the environment you're in is do it.
Speaker 1: There's a lot more details.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna skip because this is a news that I don't want to go deep.
Speaker 1: There's a whole bunch of stuff about corporate domains and private DNS that I'm just gonna skip but basically What it does is it'll make up three random domains with like random top-level domains like bit of it a dot bit of that
Speaker 0: Right almost guaranteed that none of them will be real and registered so that when it looks for them It should see an X's, right?
Speaker 0: And if it happens to accidentally pick a real one the odds of there being like, you know more than two out of three Not and coming back with like a specific IP address.
Speaker 0: not right not likely.
Speaker 0: So that way they can find out if you're.
Speaker 0: you turn out you open your chrome browser and it's like aha.
Speaker 0: They know immediately if your ISP is shady or not and can act accordingly.
Speaker 1: So that'll actually work pretty well to detect if you are like using a hijacking shitty DNS like pretty good way.
Speaker 1: And then the browser can change its behavior when you make a typo or type something that probably isn't a domain name Into your like URL bar because the world decided that search and URLs are basically the same thing.
Speaker 1: now welcome to the your 2020.
Speaker 1: Yes, I have thoughts about that both that are nuanced that are beyond the scope of the show.
Speaker 1: But I lament the fact that DNS is not the strict tree hierarchy that it used to be.
Speaker 1: so the problem is Those requests.
Speaker 1: if the bride if the ISP is not doing something evil will basically go all the way up to the top of DNS and end up asking the Official hard coded.
Speaker 1: there aren't that many of them root servers of DNS.
Speaker 1: Hey, what the fuck is this top-level domain?
Speaker 1: Yep, and since this feature was launched Chromium has basically been D do s-ing the root of the entire DNS system.
Speaker 1: There's good graphs here.
Speaker 1: this kind of thing happens kind of often because people who come up with a very clever feature Don't fully understand the ramifications of how that feature will interact with Existing structures on the internet like DNS or and people are just it's.
Speaker 0: just if you write code for something like chromium And it gets deployed you have to realize your code is running on an enormous number of computers around the world Right?
Speaker 0: so things that don't matter or work perfectly in your local test right your test framework everything works great.
Speaker 0: You do not you do not.
Speaker 0: there's no way for you to test the ramifications of your code running on.
Speaker 1: you know every Windows PC yeah, or most of them and That's something that people who write code actually really need to think about.
Speaker 1: but usually the person writing any particular piece of code Doesn't necessarily have that broad and classical understanding of all the possible ramifications And the people deciding about the features may not like they may assume that the engineers will work these things out.
Speaker 1: There's not a good way to handle this right?
Speaker 0: you're also only thinking about.
Speaker 0: you know your Computers whatever you're working on right my you know.
Speaker 0: when I code at work I'm thinking about our work computers And I'm thinking about our users and their computers.
Speaker 0: right if there's some side effect for computers far away somewhere else I'm not thinking about those too much if I'm not directly interacting with them.
Speaker 0: But code on a computer somewhere it could affect code on computers everywhere and All the software of the world is not just one monolith that is written by one person.
Speaker 1: but I would say the real solution to this problem like the only reason chromium even added a feature like this is to try to get around a real problem of people's DNS servers Hijacking things they type in to serve them ads or otherwise spy on them.
Speaker 0: yep that Really.
Speaker 1: there is no technological solution to that problem short of nationalizing DNS.
Speaker 0: I think there is a solution to that problem.
Speaker 0: I think the solution.
Speaker 0: I think regulation is the solution.
Speaker 0: well That is one solution.
Speaker 0: I think the operating system should do something about it.
Speaker 0: right?
Speaker 0: the operating systems.
Speaker 0: You know OS X and Windows right.
Speaker 0: there's no reason that they couldn't just not X. when they do DHCP Right they could a right.
Speaker 0: they could collect right figure out which ISPs are good and bad.
Speaker 0: They could figure out when you install the OS or turn the computer on.
Speaker 1: they can figure out which Goes down a lot of the same paths that the solution We just talked about goes down, and then they clever solution at scale that may have unforeseen consequences.
Speaker 0: But it won't.
Speaker 0: it won't be pinging random things.
Speaker 0: They'll just build pretty quickly a database of which ISPs are good or bad.
Speaker 1: You know look at what gathering data on what URLs people are typing in on their like operating system level.
Speaker 1: No people would know not at all with that.
Speaker 0: They just look at your DHCP, and then they would say okay these you know.
Speaker 1: How do they know which I which which?
Speaker 1: DNS servers are bad especially if these are all ten dots inside of ISP.
Speaker 0: Can I know if you just type if you just type like IP config at a Windows computer?
Speaker 0: You can just see which ISP you have right.
Speaker 0: It's like.
Speaker 0: Oh, it's routing through.
Speaker 0: I do not want my operating system making decisions based on the information I have configured in my network settings.
Speaker 0: No not something that you if you configure something in your network settings, but I can DHCP use the DNS server pointed to that.
Speaker 1: don't ask question fault the default DHCP?
Speaker 0: No, if you put if you type in a DNS server, that's what you're using right.
Speaker 0: I'm saying 99% of people who don't type in anything.
Speaker 0: They just turn their computer on it don't touch the networking settings.
Speaker 0: Oh, I'm saying you should still.
Speaker 1: the operating system should still be obligated to trust whatever DNS ever comes back in that DHCP request.
Speaker 0: I'm saying it should only do that if you tell it to or if you're not on one of the.
Speaker 0: if you're on Some sort of.
Speaker 0: you know public ISP windows should never on a pay.
Speaker 1: I'm on.
Speaker 1: that is a bad solution to this.
Speaker 0: if you're on if you're on spectrum or FiOS or something and it's a known evil ISP it should switch your DNS server to be like Microsoft's DNS server.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that that would lead to an antitrust.
Speaker 1: Microsoft is hijacking your DNS request to their own private servers.
Speaker 0: Microsoft Sends you to Google's DNS server.
Speaker 0: It's not antitrust.
Speaker 0: They're sending you to someone else.
Speaker 0: Just someone that they trust.
Speaker 1: Yeah, who did that?
Speaker 0: That is a terrible idea.
Speaker 1: It's a great idea that that idea is very similar to the idea chromium has.
Speaker 1: that that is putting the logic to solve a problem way too low in the stack and making a lot of Assumptions for something that's going to be deployed.
Speaker 0: It's not gonna.
Speaker 0: it's not gonna make a zillion DNS requests that are unnecessary.
Speaker 1: I can imagine a lot of unforeseen consequences of that.
Speaker 1: I can imagine a lot of difficult to troubleshoot problems.
Speaker 1: I can imagine a lot of corporate networks.
Speaker 0: I don't think a corporate network wouldn't have.
Speaker 1: what if I want to go to those?
Speaker 1: What if I want to use my ISP DNS?
Speaker 1: I don't care about the hijacking.
Speaker 1: don't decide for me Don't don't send my request to Google.
Speaker 0: I don't trust Google too bad If you're if your only argument is the one that's in favor of the evil thing.
Speaker 0: We're trying to eliminate.
Speaker 1: No, I'm saying the operating systems network stack should be pure and specific.
Speaker 1: Don't overload your bullshit business logic into it.
Speaker 1: The network stack should not look at the ISP you connected to and make a judgment about whether or not to overwrite the DNS Setting that came back in a DHCP packet.
Speaker 0: I think it should.
Speaker 1: I think that is a terrible idea And I think the right solution is a great idea.
Speaker 0: It's much better than the chromium idea.
Speaker 1: Actually, I think the chromium one is a better solution because that's a piece of software.
Speaker 1: It's not the chromium ones.
Speaker 0: got to make all kinds of requests right and nonsense.
Speaker 1: Yes, but it doesn't mess with your network stack settings.
Speaker 1: What you propose will just lead.
Speaker 0: this is actually even better.
Speaker 0: This is actually.
Speaker 0: it's actually would actually solve more problems.
Speaker 0: because how many problems in non browsers are caused by Having shitty DNS?
Speaker 0: that sends you to weird things on bad domains.
Speaker 0: Now all your other apps would suddenly have good DNS operating system-wide.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'd still think that if only instead of only chromium having good DNS.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the problem is - I don't want anyone One to change what the network stack of the computer is.
Speaker 1: they should.
Speaker 0: they're cheap.
Speaker 0: you're changing.
Speaker 0: You are a person who's gonna type in your own DNS.
Speaker 0: For you nothing would happen.
Speaker 0: I Yeah, if there I am only assuming that if you're some customer who's on spectrum and you've never changed your network settings
Speaker 1: I don't want Windows to make any decision based on what ISP
Speaker 0: you don't but you know what it's better for a vast majority of People
Speaker 1: actually probably not most people are probably fine with those spam things because they just don't.
Speaker 0: Just don't know better.
Speaker 0: You'd be helping them out.
Speaker 1: Yeah, even though I don't want them I don't want a low-level systems to solve higher order problems.
Speaker 1: That is a recipe for disaster.
Speaker 0: That is it's not a low answer.
Speaker 0: solving it on the problem on the level that it is.
Speaker 1: If you want to frame it that way That's their set.
Speaker 0: your ISP is setting your DNS IP the IP address of your DNS server to a bad DNS server We're gonna set it to a good one solving the problem right at the spot where it's caused.
Speaker 1: I think a better solution would just to be to have a law saying that DNS servers that are used in public in public ISPs Cannot return results that are not.
Speaker 0: I don't think.
Speaker 0: you know, you're not gonna get a lot of that law ever.
Speaker 1: I mean We're not gonna do that law is more feasible than anything you proposed.
Speaker 1: Like if you have you proposed what you just said to Microsoft you'd be laughed out of the room.
Speaker 0: I don't think so.
Speaker 0: I think so they might be like, ooh, I think that would be a terrible idea.
Speaker 0: Google liked it.
Speaker 1: Google Trying to get you to use their DNS servers.
Speaker 1: They can collect a shit ton of data from you.
Speaker 0: Actually, I don't know if the Google public DNS actually collects.
Speaker 0: Think it doesn't collect users.
Speaker 0: It doesn't collect users specific data.
Speaker 1: No, but it collects what the crux what URLs are being queried.
Speaker 1: That's a huge.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they're looking at like.
Speaker 0: yeah, they're looking at like.
Speaker 0: who is which you are domains are the most queried and stuff.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it also does have enough metadata.
Speaker 1: Like.
Speaker 1: there's enough metadata there to figure out who's doing what pretty easily if they want it to.
Speaker 0: yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah What are you gonna use?
Speaker 0: open DNS law?
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's all that's broken in a different worse way.
Speaker 1: I guess my thinking is DNS and DHCP should be sacrosanct relatively straightforward Specifications.
Speaker 1: that made so some people.
Speaker 0: it forced me if people are using a non Sarcosynct DNS forced them to use a sarcosynct one.
Speaker 1: No because Google's not a sacrosanct one.
Speaker 0: Here's the is way you could do it.
Speaker 0: you could effectively make a list of known DNS servers that are evil and just block them all and be like not a lot right.
Speaker 1: and then most people's Windows Boxes just wouldn't work and they wouldn't know why.
Speaker 0: no because they would say hey You know your ISP is DNS server is on a list of banned DNS servers that behaves.
Speaker 1: and remember Netflix.
Speaker 1: Hey your eyes sucks.
Speaker 1: complain about it and how that didn't solve any problems and just confused people.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'm just saying yeah, you know if you're if you're so, you know picky, right?
Speaker 1: I'm just saying as a general piece of advice don't try to solve high order problems in low Level systems.
Speaker 1: that is I'm sorry.
Speaker 0: I see it as I'm solving the problem where it is.
Speaker 0: It's a problem of your DNS server IP address being set to a shitty one.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna set it to a good one.
Speaker 1: Okay?
Speaker 1: Anyway, the last thing we're not gonna talk about this in depth, but his little piece of news, uh Don't buy Elon Musk's brain implant and put no one's buying the brain and people want to.
Speaker 1: people are.
Speaker 0: people are in Just those are just sock puppet accounts or people that Ellen must give drugs to.
Speaker 1: I think there are people who want this and I All I will say, you know That's a self-solving problem.
Speaker 0: brain Brain interfaces should not be used until there are not mega corpse making them pretty much Until I can you know put together my own brain implant in my house Like I way I've put together a PC in my house.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right.
Speaker 0: and so you have a cyberpunk shop shop down in the corner next to the digital tattoo shop Zero, I see through anything, right?
Speaker 0: Don't go and get it any don't?
Speaker 0: like?
Speaker 0: I always said that I'm not gonna get brain implant 1.0 I'll probably get 2.0 or maybe even 3.0.
Speaker 0: But if Ellen Musk is making the brain implant, I'm not getting a million point.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, I'm not getting two million point.
Speaker 0: Oh but anyway things Of the day.
Speaker 0: so shit, what was my thing of the day?
Speaker 1: I'll do mine first.
Speaker 1: so this is a pretty cool article.
Speaker 1: I'm not.
Speaker 1: it is plausible, but I'm not going to say that it's true, but it may like it made the rounds news was talking about.
Speaker 1: It's an interesting story, but it's basically the story.
Speaker 1: It was published recently of Someone who claims to have worked at Apple and in the course of working for them helped probably the CIA make special iPods that had Hardware and software in them that could collect and hide data but appeared from all outward investigation to be a normal iPod
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Well what the actual story is more like people from the the government right the doe which is already like that's nuclear stuff.
Speaker 0: Apple didn't give permission for this.
Speaker 0: They probably wouldn't have ever right.
Speaker 0: these people basically snuck into getting jobs at Apple Developed it while working at Apple and then disappeared.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but we're told like there was.
Speaker 1: like you read the story like.
Speaker 1: I'm not gonna read this story to you but it basically tells the story of how this thing supposedly went down and There's a lot of plausible stuff in here and it's an interesting fascinating story, right?
Speaker 0: We obviously can't prove that true or false, right?
Speaker 0: There's no way to do that, right?
Speaker 0: Apple can't even prove it true or false.
Speaker 0: probably right, but it seems true.
Speaker 0: ish enough right to at least be worth Mentioning.
Speaker 1: it's all yep, and it's also like in terms of the details like worst case.
Speaker 1: It's just a really good story But the details are tracking with what I like just based on my own professional experience What I would need in a product like that.
Speaker 1: Like how would you do it?
Speaker 1: Like the details are pretty specific.
Speaker 1: So whoever wrote the story, even if it's false put a lot of thought into What would such a device actually need to be like in the real world?
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: It's basically like Either if like if it's.
Speaker 0: if it's true that it's true.
Speaker 0: if it's not true Someone did so much work writing this to make it, you know So as as you know believable and plausible as possible and that itself is worthy of giving them a read.
Speaker 1: Yep the only thing I don't think is plausible is the.
Speaker 1: the article speculates about what they were trying to spy on and I don't think it was a Geiger counter.
Speaker 1: Like.
Speaker 1: I can think of a lot of other SIG in type things that someone would want to do with a device like that To smuggle data in and out of a place possibly from sensors a Geiger counter.
Speaker 1: I think there were better ways to handle that but who knows I'm sure it's like.
Speaker 0: I'm sure the government already had Plenty of you know, tiny hidden Geiger counter things.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I wouldn't need an iPod one.
Speaker 1: Remember the key to an iPod is whatever it is hide in plain sight with a device that can be inspected pretty thoroughly and still not return anything like any like Deviant result.
Speaker 1: that would require further investigation.
Speaker 1: Yep, you find some yup.
Speaker 0: It's an iPod.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like and if I hide a tiny like micro micro SD card Somewhere on my body there are a lot of ways someone could find that.
Speaker 1: but if someone finds my iPod because I handed it to Them that's a very different situation.
Speaker 0: Yep, anyway, so my thing of the day is this little cute website Lord of the Manor dot IO and it's a little tiny Sim City ish kind of game right.
Speaker 0: you Collect some resources by building like you build like a little forest hut and the.
Speaker 0: then it starts chopping the wood in the nearby area.
Speaker 0: Then you get wood.
Speaker 0: then you can use the will to build the wood to build other buildings, right?
Speaker 0: Etc.
Speaker 0: The only buildings you can't build are the residential buildings that house your population.
Speaker 0: They just sort of appear.
Speaker 0: naturally as your.
Speaker 0: you know domain Increases in quality, you know houses will appear and upgrade and it's just a cute little sim game.
Speaker 0: It's not like the greatest game.
Speaker 0: It's not gonna occupy you for a long time Right, but it's thing of the day.
Speaker 0: because look someone made this in a browser.
Speaker 0: It runs in your browser and it's like it's this nice.
Speaker 0: They're still working on it.
Speaker 0: It's it's super speedy and responsive and it's like it could have been like a desktop app.
Speaker 0: You wouldn't even know.
Speaker 0: it's like wow, you did this in the in the web.
Speaker 0: It's like that's pretty freaking impressive.
Speaker 0: Wow Good job.
Speaker 0: I Played it.
Speaker 0: It only took me like hardly any time to upgrade everything to the max and get a huge pile of gold and jewelry and pretty much every resource available.
Speaker 0: So, you know, it's not gonna occupy your Time too much.
Speaker 1: I'm poking at it right now.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's a really good UI considering.
Speaker 0: Oh, I can.
Speaker 1: it is You know what it does, you know what makes me really pleased with this.
Speaker 1: I can zoom out to an appropriate level.
Speaker 1: so many games.
Speaker 1: Yeah, let me zoom out far enough.
Speaker 0: That's what I'm saying.
Speaker 0: Like you zoom in and zoom out with the scroll wheel super smooth.
Speaker 0: So, yeah, it's it's pretty pretty damn good.
Speaker 0: gives you some.
Speaker 0: you know, Euro board game kind of feels a little bit, right?
Speaker 0: But I think mostly it's just kind of inspiring.
Speaker 0: It's like yeah, you know imagine taking the async Websockets technology of like a jackbox or an adil a 18xx games and combining it with this kind of UI.
Speaker 0: That's the kind of game that you can make on the web right now.
Speaker 0: Not too not too much difficulty.
Speaker 0: You should try it.
Speaker 1: Yeah In the minute moment as we've said we'll be live on September 4th coming up real soon at the crunchyroll Expo With Jojo anime by its cover and also oh, that's sooner than I thought that's.
Speaker 0: that's in Friday September 18th.
Speaker 1: Where is the finish line?
Speaker 1: brand new lecture for our packs?
Speaker 1: We got some magfest stuff we're working on.
Speaker 1: we might be making our first ever appearance at magwest because It's all for sure.
Speaker 0: You don't have to go we don't have to go there.
Speaker 0: Yeah If there's any conventions far away Like magwest that we normally wouldn't go to ever because it's too far not worth it.
Speaker 0: We can go there now.
Speaker 1: So Yeah, you know stay tuned on all that.
Speaker 1: Otherwise like type geek nights into Google and find our stuff and hang out in our discord and watch our live streams.
Speaker 1: and We got videos.
Speaker 1: We got stuff.
Speaker 1: We're streaming.
Speaker 1: We're hanging out We're doing things during the quarantine and as winter comes we got to do more and more stuff indoors And we might be making more and more content.
Speaker 1: Cuz what else are we gonna do?
Speaker 0: Yep Yeah, and I might maybe we should read the book club book tale again.
Speaker 0: G at some point.
Speaker 1: Yep I'm trying to figure out at what point would I have enough free time to read books.
Speaker 0: cuz without community read some comic books yesterday.
Speaker 1: Well, like we keep saying without a commute like I don't have a lot of time to read because I keep saying this because I Think it's important for people to internalize The core.
Speaker 1: the kovat crisis does not mean you have to be like more Productive in your hobbies or your pursuits.
Speaker 1: Most people don't actually have any more free time now.
Speaker 1: They're just for.
Speaker 0: historically did.
Speaker 0: did previous pandemics were during the flu epidemic to the people who survived and didn't get the flu?
Speaker 0: Did they suddenly do a whole bunch of great stuff because they were at home all the time?
Speaker 0: Yeah, do I do?
Speaker 0: unemployed people have a lot of productivity?
Speaker 0: No, I can tell you the last time I was unemployed.
Speaker 1: I remember you what you you went from zero to 100 miles an hour at find new job.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like every waking hour into finding a better job.
Speaker 1: Not every waking hour, but I really put in like a work week worth of finding a better job.
Speaker 0: Yeah I tried to stream like, you know some.
Speaker 0: you stream maybe like once or twice or something in those days.
Speaker 0: cuz that's the time.
Speaker 0: it Was right.
Speaker 0: There's a different time you understand like the mid-2000s.
Speaker 0: I was unemployed for like a few weeks.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it was just like, you know Well, I'm gonna do a whole while I'm sitting here and I'm not looking for a job.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna do all kinds of shit.
Speaker 0: I did only a little bit of shit about as much as the little bit of shit.
Speaker 0: I'm doing now, right?
Speaker 0: So That's you know, if you're doing a little bit of extra shit, that's good enough.
Speaker 0: That's what you're getting.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like I'm spending a lot of time like I decided I'm gonna try to get like way ripped Like I'm working out a lot, but that takes away time from all the other things I could be doing.
Speaker 1: I don't have more free time.
Speaker 1: So just do not fall for the illusion of free time during this.
Speaker 1: You don't actually have more free time.
Speaker 1: You just have less options to spend that free time.
Speaker 1: So we actually talked for almost an hour already And the listener actually just pointed out another classic.
Speaker 1: This is like an old-school gig nights ribbon Scott argue through the news for 45 minutes and then are too hungry to do the main Bit, is that what the show is?
Speaker 0: cuz let's talk about some biometric of some kind You know, let's do the highest level of like.
Speaker 1: what are biometrics?
Speaker 1: and like the ramifications.
Speaker 0: so when people talk about biometrics They're usually talking about biometric authentication, which is stuff like fingerprint sensor.
Speaker 0: You know Apple face ID some sort of system where you're using your iris detector in a movie But those exist.
Speaker 0: kind of you know where you're trying to prove who you are to your computer to log in or prove who you are to the Computers that it opens the doors.
Speaker 0: you can go in the office.
Speaker 1: and that is one use of biometrics as one Biometrics, that's only biometric authentication right.
Speaker 0: biometrics as a whole is simply measuring human biology with computers.
Speaker 1: Biometric.
Speaker 0: yeah, your your heart rate sensor that you use their Fitbit.
Speaker 0: That's biometrics.
Speaker 1: Right, in fact the Wikipedia right here for the application of statistics to biology see bio statistics Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if you got some like device a breathalyzer For the fraudulently marketed by contour treatment see Peter Foster It's some scam problem.
Speaker 1: I guess there's a scam that was called biometrics or something.
Speaker 0: Anyway, probably You know, you could consider Like a baseballs, you know a speed gun used to track a baseball sort of biometric.
Speaker 1: It's great One step removed like it's an order.
Speaker 1: Yes, but it's capturing a holistic metric of a biological action.
Speaker 0: But if you aim it at Usain Bolt while he's running and doesn't have when he gets hopefully better from Kofi Then that would be a biometric.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so biometrics like I guess they are a very powerful tool like way more powerful than you might realize even if you're already afraid of like facial tracking like The power here is immense the danger here is immense But also the capabilities to better mankind are immense.
Speaker 1: This is a field that needs a lot of care and judgment and thought and guidance and ethics.
Speaker 0: Yep, it's like okay we can measure Hopefully most things about the human body.
Speaker 0: you can be completely measured and quantized in.
Speaker 0: you know Many many if not all aspects, right?
Speaker 0: Well, that's great for your health if you have a doctor who acts in good faith Because now we can figure out exactly what's wrong with you and fix it to the best of our ability?
Speaker 1: What if your doctor acts in bad faith to try to scam you or harm you in some way?
Speaker 1: What if your doctor is acting in good faith?
Speaker 1: But let's say the technology that underpins American health care is shitty and all that biometric data gets stolen By someone who isn't your doctor, even though your doctor is using it to help you.
Speaker 1: That data could be used by a third party to harm you immensely.
Speaker 0: Yep It's like, you know, let's say, you know, we talk about biometric authentication is being the one that gets the most attention, right?
Speaker 0: But it's like yeah It's like sometimes you want to prove exactly who you are and sometimes you don't want anyone to know who you are.
Speaker 0: But your biology is the one thing that you cannot yet escape, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, so if there is biometric authentication Someone who has access to it can always prove who you are.
Speaker 0: even in cases We don't want anyone to prove who you are And if the data is somehow messed up or the system is faulty It may become difficult or impossible to prove who you are when you want to prove who you are Here are.
Speaker 1: I have two examples.
Speaker 1: So one I worked as you know a long time ago.
Speaker 1: it look God That was a long time ago.
Speaker 1: I did project management and IT for hospitals So I had to wash my hands and then turn the page a lot.
Speaker 1: I washed my fingerprints off over time because of the chemicals I was using something that happens to nurses often.
Speaker 1: So I didn't have fingerprints.
Speaker 1: So the biometric systems that I used as part of the security infrastructure I interacted with either would not work because I did not have something that would recognize as a fingerprint in their system or Recognized a fingerprint that was so generic that fucking any finger would open it if I was using my own system.
Speaker 0: Well, yeah, it's like, you know, they register.
Speaker 0: some doctor who's rubbed his fingerprints off.
Speaker 0: He registers with a blank fingerprint.
Speaker 0: Now all the blank fingerprint people can get it.
Speaker 1: That's why while in the movies you often see single-factor biometric authentication.
Speaker 1: Here's the two real dangers of that one.
Speaker 1: What if someone steals that by like pulling your eye out like a spy and holding it in front of a cat?
Speaker 0: That's already happens in every cyberpunk story.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but that's a real fear.
Speaker 1: I have seen proofs of concept of sham eyes for retina scanners sham fingerprints sham Everything.
Speaker 1: if you don't even need to see.
Speaker 1: you don't need to cut someone's finger off Necessarily.
Speaker 1: just get their fingerprint and make a mold make it out of capacitive material that will feel like a finger put a little warmer In it like once someone has the data that comprises your biometric They have your biometric and can prove with that factor that they are you
Speaker 0: Alright, so let's you want to get really fun, right?
Speaker 0: Okay Hypothetical distant future, right?
Speaker 0: We have something that's the equivalent of a camera with a super zoom lens and anyone you aim it at.
Speaker 0: you can get their full DNA sequence right every single pair on the whole thing.
Speaker 0: It's like, you know, right like the full fucking thing you could.
Speaker 0: and then you can make you print out a clone body.
Speaker 0: It's so precise.
Speaker 1: I print out DNA evidence to obscure the crime.
Speaker 1: I just committed and pin it on someone else.
Speaker 0: Great You know all kinds of crazy shit going down there, right?
Speaker 1: So in authentication biometrics Must always be one of several factors though.
Speaker 1: I There I gotta point out right now as long as humans remain biological Technically in a pedantic and meaningless sense passwords are biometrics because you they're physically stored in your brain and Theoretically could be retrieved.
Speaker 1: There's an engram in your brain somewhere that has your password in it.
Speaker 1: There's a famous old Superman TV like episode I remember where someone is there's hostages and they're tied up and there's a donkey that can read minds.
Speaker 1: Let's not worry about why there's a donkey that can read minds.
Speaker 1: It's Superman And basically the one of the three people knows the past.
Speaker 1: but like the combination to a safe But you can't open.
Speaker 1: let them open the safe because there's like kryptonite in it and they're gonna use it to kill Superman like this All plot.
Speaker 0: Oh, no, so good.
Speaker 1: Basically the criminal brings in the donkey and they're like, I'll never say the password I'll never say the name of the combination and he's just like, all right Don't think about the combination to the safe.
Speaker 1: know whatever way you do don't think that number and then the donkey is just like 13 and they got the combination.
Speaker 0: Well, fuck you donkey.
Speaker 1: Yep But in terms of like free authentication like the other I did a recent one.
Speaker 1: This is something that happens to me today.
Speaker 1: And this is one of this is not the like far future Security problem or even the near future security problem.
Speaker 1: It's more the.
Speaker 1: it makes security more annoying for me.
Speaker 1: So I work for a fancy company where I have to use three-factor authentication to get into anything.
Speaker 1: So I've got a physical device That I need to have on me to be able to get in.
Speaker 1: that device has a fingerprint scanner on it.
Speaker 1: It also has a sensor so it can basically detect a light with a little camera on it.
Speaker 1: It does a lot of stuff But one of the things I do with it is I have to scan my fingerprint to turn it on and once it's on To get into certain systems I have to hold it up to my screen and that system after I enter my username and my password Flashes timecode data.
Speaker 1: that thus this device will then use with random seeds to generate a TOTP code.
Speaker 1: And I need to use all those things to log into a system.
Speaker 1: if I take a shower and I don't wait about an hour before I try to log in my fingers a little swollen up like from the water I can't finger purge.
Speaker 1: It doesn't fucking work.
Speaker 1: Can't log into anything.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: So I just when I wake up in the morning, I Log into the systems lock everything then I go take a shower then I get to work Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: I just wrote a fictional story, right?
Speaker 0: So you go.
Speaker 0: so there's Indiana Jones, right and he's Obviously Indiana Jones knows something right?
Speaker 0: He doesn't want the Nazis to know.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so he's what he's but he's got to get past the Nazis.
Speaker 0: So what he did is he recruited a bunch of people to dress up like Indiana Jones and that way the Nazis are gonna catch a bunch of fake Indiana Jones's and the real Indiana Jones is gonna make it past all the Nazis and deliver Right good play.
Speaker 0: Okay, so It's in a perfect sort of future, right?
Speaker 0: So the cost?
Speaker 0: the Indiana Jones clone people, right?
Speaker 0: They'll have the same face as Indiana Jones.
Speaker 0: So they get past the facial recognition system.
Speaker 0: They fool that right?
Speaker 0: It's You know the let's see.
Speaker 1: Well, there's Think they're Indiana Jones and they all try to steal the thing.
Speaker 0: Oh possibly but the point of the story right is like, you know.
Speaker 0: So they they capture some Indiana Jones's.
Speaker 0: they want to figure out which one's the real one, right?
Speaker 0: It's like something as simple as something that even exists today.
Speaker 0: forget for our future, right?
Speaker 0: Let's say the Nazis have the the Fitbit database and they know everyone's like heart rate zones.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they.
Speaker 0: they take some guns They point them at the end of Jones's they make them run on treadmills and they say who can who runs like Indiana Jones?
Speaker 1: It's like or you know I've seen systems where it would ask you and your friends to type a bunch of stuff and then if Any of you type anything it's pretty accurate at telling who typed it just based on your typing style.
Speaker 0: Yeah Or your walk it.
Speaker 0: you rim could put on the best Lupin the third costume in the world or Lupin could put on the best Lupin the third costume in the world.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and you could just see by the way he walks.
Speaker 0: Oh, that's her.
Speaker 1: Yep It's you know, it's no question.
Speaker 1: I have nothing.
Speaker 0: you that you could not fake it either There's nothing you could do.
Speaker 1: the way I move my hands and the way my head like Bob's as I walk has caused Numerous people to recognize me in VR before I introduced myself like oh, there's rim.
Speaker 1: This is literally happened to me.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but let's forget about credentials here.
Speaker 1: the other way this goes.
Speaker 1: biometrics also data about you facial recognition.
Speaker 1: now Listen old gig nights.
Speaker 1: We talked a lot about like powerful cool things You could do with facial recognition like but the killer app for Google glass.
Speaker 1: And of course, they're obvious.
Speaker 1: as we're about to talk about dangers of this.
Speaker 1: But if we forget the dangers first, here's the cool app.
Speaker 1: I always have a camera on.
Speaker 1: I got software.
Speaker 1: if I meet a piece of shit person like I made a Nazi I made a Republican I meet like some incel like dangerous person someone who's annoying and harassing people.
Speaker 1: I want to be able to flag them like that person's annoying So that my close personal friends if they ever encountered that person their camera will pop up a warning and say hey Rim said this person's a piece of shit.
Speaker 1: Cool cool feature.
Speaker 0: you could also have the opposite thing right.
Speaker 0: some shady dudes coming up to you on the street Normally run don't talk do not engage.
Speaker 0: But maybe it says rim verified.
Speaker 0: this person is cool person and I'm like, huh?
Speaker 0: Maybe all right I'll be like, oh, I know it was a listener and they just happen to recognize me and I was gonna run away Thanks to.
Speaker 0: thanks to this system that is not being used in an evil way You know, I was able to get a slightly more interesting morning by meeting a listener.
Speaker 1: Yep Now cool like that.
Speaker 1: that would be an awesome thing being able to share daint the information about dangerous people with my close friend network So that they could avoid situations like harassment at conventions.
Speaker 1: That's a killer app.
Speaker 1: However, that exact same technology is Like.
Speaker 1: you want to have super stalkers?
Speaker 1: That is how you have super stalkers.
Speaker 1: That is like you could track someone to the ends of the earth with that technology.
Speaker 0: Yep,
Speaker 1: because
Speaker 0: people some not some guy some piece-of-shit guy also buys it is walking down the street Right looking at people and he sees someone and it's like, you know His piece-of-shit friend labeled someone as
Speaker 1: an easy mark
Speaker 0: that as jw from Twitter that the crap Right and goes over and he starts something with someone else with someone he would have otherwise ignored.
Speaker 1: You know, all these fascist groups would enable everyone with.
Speaker 1: here are the biometrics of people we are targeting.
Speaker 1: if you see them You'll know those are the people to target like.
Speaker 1: that's kind of already happening and this would accelerate that.
Speaker 1: Yep, I don't know what to do about facial recognition And we haven't even.
Speaker 0: yeah We haven't even begun to discuss the fact that you know any of these systems that depend upon machine learning have been trained With.
Speaker 1: you know, basically racist data sets or you know Or to predict behavior or do other things are trained by data that will just Institutionalize encode the same institutional racism sexism and other problems that already exist in the systems.
Speaker 1: They're modeling
Speaker 0: and it's like even if you were to train the data sets on you know A good proportion of data from across the board right so that it would be equally good at detecting black faces and white faces and Chinese faces and you know, Iranian faces and whatever kind of faces Right, and it is equally good at detecting male and female faces and child faces and senior faces And all right, and if you removed somehow got a data set so large that it removed all Discrimination and it was equally good at you know doing things Suddenly that data set is so big that it's dangerous.
Speaker 1: yep, because that is to be used to find trends and those trends could be used to target individuals or groups of people who would Vulnerable to certain kinds of manipulation or attack and like what happened in the 2016 election but on the tiniest scale compared to what's coming.
Speaker 1: and the problem is facial recognition technology is Incredibly advanced already.
Speaker 1: the killer apps we talked about only aren't made in public because for the most part people have Recognized that they would be abused and misused to such a degree that the public can't be trusted with it.
Speaker 0: I could not think of any like public people who would with facial any facial recognition app Right that other than the one that people use which is sort your photo collection on your computer?
Speaker 1: Yeah, right, but like my old gx1 camera like it can't even output video on its own HDMI port Yet it has a library in it.
Speaker 1: Uh, I haven't updated a long time.
Speaker 1: I. I took pictures of all our friends like years and years ago with this dumb camera and I put names like to all of It flags every picture with oh, that's Scott.
Speaker 1: That's Emily.
Speaker 1: That's all these people I could take.
Speaker 0: but it's not.
Speaker 0: it's not.
Speaker 0: You're not accessing a date there.
Speaker 0: the database would be it's not the.
Speaker 0: I made my own Right, you made your own database, which is fine because it's gonna be small only for you.
Speaker 0: Not very harmful, right?
Speaker 0: Not being merged with the databases of all faces everywhere, right?
Speaker 0: It's just for your personal use, right?
Speaker 0: It's like what.
Speaker 0: what harm is there?
Speaker 0: and rim sorting his photos or having a camera that autofocus, but that's my data.
Speaker 1: I could share it.
Speaker 1: What if I drag a photo of someone I take into a reverse image search find other photos of that person and then use that To stock?
Speaker 1: well, it already happens.
Speaker 0: You could just do that with a camera that doesn't even have.
Speaker 1: yeah I'm saying that already happens.
Speaker 1: The technology is already out there, but we're not controlling it and we're not Like handling it.
Speaker 1: and the technology is getting so advanced that is asymmetric.
Speaker 1: governments and preg mega corporations have access to advanced facial recognition technology that I do not have To use to counter the effects they might have with it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but obviously it's like I was saying though.
Speaker 0: It's the.
Speaker 0: it's not actually the detection technology of saying.
Speaker 0: Oh, that's a human face, right?
Speaker 0: That's the most dangerous.
Speaker 0: It's simply the large databases the most dangerous, right?
Speaker 0: If you don't have the large databases, then all the other things are real.
Speaker 0: It's like oh, I have a machine that can read fingerprints.
Speaker 0: Yes, so does everybody.
Speaker 0: they're really cheap.
Speaker 0: You can just buy one but even without the large.
Speaker 0: But it's like I have a database of all fingerprints.
Speaker 1: Uh-oh Like you use a zoom lens to get good photos of one person you're making a database of one.
Speaker 1: What are the by facial biometrics of one person?
Speaker 1: but then you see that now with a database of biometric data?
Speaker 1: you compare that against a database of Cameras all over the world.
Speaker 1: dumb cameras video footage troll all of YouTube looking for where does that face appear?
Speaker 1: The biometric data itself is not even the primary danger.
Speaker 1: It's the database of data that you could overlay that biometric information on to ask that data questions That could not be asked of it previously at a scale that no human had ever imagined when the technology was developed.
Speaker 0: You could also learn things like, you know Say like you're an employer and you're collecting whatever biometric data you can on your employees and then you find out Oh this employee has a cancer.
Speaker 0: Yeah, maybe they don't even know it.
Speaker 1: Use a ring fit adventure or Fitbit.
Speaker 1: that's collecting a ton of biometrics.
Speaker 0: I don't think it's sending it to Nintendo now, but it get can collect data Sure, and sometimes it's on the SD card and your switch.
Speaker 0: Nintendo could collect it.
Speaker 1: I guess the most difficult thing is that It's not always obvious what data could be used for something in the future.
Speaker 1: Like it's not always a layperson.
Speaker 1: all kind of data is useful or not useful dangerous or not dangerous.
Speaker 1: All of it, yep, but like look at the difference a photo of your face extremely useful extremely dangerous trivial to obtain cannot be controlled Mm-hmm, but heart rate data could be controlled.
Speaker 1: But many people give that data away to a bunch of different sites.
Speaker 1: Like I give my heart rate data away to Strava I just get.
Speaker 1: I just use it like Strava has all my heart rate data.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm taking a risk there.
Speaker 1: theoretically I don't plan to use heart rate biometrics anytime soon But someone else might use it against me.
Speaker 1: But the real problem is these biometrics can't be.
Speaker 0: she also might use it for you right to help fitness.
Speaker 1: Yeah What if here's a detect heart disease?
Speaker 1: Yeah, what if somehow?
Speaker 1: They passed a law they passed all this data and they privately reached out to the 4 million Americans who have a rare heart condition That was detected by ring fit 5 in the year 2040.
Speaker 1: That would be an objective boon to society.
Speaker 0: But at the same time Apple says they're trying to do right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, but can we trust mega corporations or our current governments?
Speaker 0: No, that's the same.
Speaker 0: That's the same evil Apple.
Speaker 0: We talked about in the first hour of the show The same evil.
Speaker 0: Apple that did that thing is also trying to solve heart disease.
Speaker 1: So I guess because now I am hungry we've gone on over an hour.
Speaker 0: Okay, good, right.
Speaker 1: if you don't if you don't know a lot about biometrics what I'd actually recommend?
Speaker 1: Read the Wikipedia page we're linking to.
Speaker 1: it's not long.
Speaker 1: It's at the right level.
Speaker 1: Like I've been skimming it like this is at a level that you would understand.
Speaker 0: Are you saying that this whole episode of geek nights was you reading Wikipedia?
Speaker 0: saying the geek nights is two guys reading Wikipedia?
Speaker 0: I know anything.
Speaker 1: I mean I do the live stream.
Speaker 1: people can usually see what I'm looking at while I'm talking.
Speaker 1: Sometimes the listener will see me Geek nights to read Wikipedia.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we pick a random Wikipedia page and read it out loud to you.
Speaker 1: Actually the Wikipedia goes way deeper than we went we were mostly talking about might be useful for people who can't see.
Speaker 1: Yeah, did you see here?
Speaker 1: Here's something to end on total aside Did you see that dude who has been filling the Scots Wikipedia with made-up articles forever?
Speaker 0: I read something about.
Speaker 0: I read that like.
Speaker 1: That's it.
Speaker 0: I read a headline.
Speaker 0: I read a headline that said the Scots Wikipedia has mostly been written by a white guy.
Speaker 1: So it's supposed to be articles written in the Scots dialect partly to preserve that dialect and to make it more excessive.
Speaker 1: like there's a lot Of reasons why that's a good thing.
Speaker 1: But most of the articles are written by this like American dude who apparently was just writing articles with a fakie Bullshitty Scots accent like Uncle Scrooge McDuck.
Speaker 0: Yeah Glad II need the biometrics.
Speaker 0: watch out.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: It's basically like make a fake accent and just write articles in it.
Speaker 0: and Well, they could.
Speaker 0: at least they're all written by the same guy with the same account, yeah pretty easy to suss that one out.
Speaker 1: Yeah, this has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at front row crew comm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 1: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 0: But unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night And the patreon patrons for this episode of geek nights are Alan Joyce hiding McNichol Marty green.
Speaker 1: You just like a do gags or television Graham Finch.
Speaker 1: You hold the key to my heart.
Speaker 1: She gave me a kiss and she gave me my ticket.
Speaker 1: Clinton Walton J Bantz rain from New Zealand Ryan parent.
Speaker 1: It was Brando Chris midkiff the thirst for hydrated Gannon dread Lily Tenebrae Chris Reimer Finn Sean Klein sure about all and a bunch of people who don't want me to say their names.
Speaker 1: yeah, we uh, we got a new.
Speaker 1: we're gonna do a Shorter version of a panel that we've done before so it's gonna be like a best of highlights.
Speaker 1: real We're gonna see.
Speaker 1: we're working on this new panel for Meg West, but it's definitely something no one's ever seen before.
Speaker 1: We've never had to do this talk in like 20 to 25 minutes.
Speaker 1: So we're gonna come up with a new version of.
Speaker 1: it should be a fun time.
Speaker 1: Stay tuned for other conventions.
Speaker 1: We might be appearing at online.
Speaker 1: If you think you want us to appear at some convention that's happening online.
Speaker 1: Just let us know.
Speaker 1: worst case scenario We say no, we can't do it, but you never know.
Speaker 1: We might do it.
Speaker 1: But anyway for tonight.
Speaker 1: I'll leave you with.