Speaker 0: It's Wednesday January 22nd 2020.
Speaker 0: I'm rim.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott and this is geek nights.
Speaker 0: tonight We are talking about something that I can't believe we have never talked about on geek nights beat-ass Batman the animated series.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: so I moved into this building a decade ago and when I moved in the literal first thing I did was like walk around the apartment like look at stuff and the second thing I did was the Verizon FiOS to come install itself.
Speaker 1: That's right.
Speaker 1: So installed itself.
Speaker 0: Well someone came and back then like FiOS was a lot harder to get installed than it is now.
Speaker 0: They put this gigantic fucking box like in the wall of my apartment filled with like a giant battery and all this crap and all these things for like phone service that I didn't need and I've had the router that they gave me and that box just running as is for a decade.
Speaker 0: like I have this ancient ancient plan that's like 60 up 60 down and I randomly logged into the site the other day and just like looking at the account because occasionally I like log into accounts I have and make sure there's nothing new we're doing and They had a thing where I could basically get more speed because the plans are so different now from a decade ago.
Speaker 1: Our plan is like three or four hundred up and you know, like that.
Speaker 0: So I'm paying now like $25 a month less to get from 60 to 100.
Speaker 0: Mmm, and I think they incentivized it because They came and in the Mimi room in the building They like replaced a bunch of Verizon like shit down there and then they pulled that entire box out of my wall.
Speaker 0: And now in the giant compartment where that box was there's just one Tiny little o-nt just hanging out there with the fiber terminating in it.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I mean, that's ten years of advancement.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the new router they gave me actually works way better.
Speaker 1: That router looks enormous and doesn't look at all like the one I got.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, the router is enormous, but it has modern like really good Wi-Fi.
Speaker 0: The old router was real old.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean the one they gave me has really good Wi-Fi.
Speaker 1: I just don't like the The the UI when you go to its web interface.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the UI is not great.
Speaker 1: It has a surprising number of features, but not as many as you know, like a gear router.
Speaker 0: But I can do like full port forwarding.
Speaker 0: I could set up DMZ.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you can do all that kind of stuff I got routing rules DHCP configuration.
Speaker 1: It's just really hard and annoying to do anything like that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but so the funny thing is I learned something kind of sad about everyone in this building.
Speaker 0: Apparently I was the rising guy said I was literally the last person to have the old busted files Like ancient files shit.
Speaker 0: So when he came in he goes to replace it and he tries to put the router in the front closet Like by itself, there's no ethernet cables or anything over there.
Speaker 0: and I was like, whoa Whoa, no, no, no, no, no, no.
Speaker 0: No, you got to get that into my computer room like the last guy did and he's like well Do you have you think I run it over there?
Speaker 0: And of course I don't because this building There's no way to get ethernet over there because the cable path to get to my closet goes outside of my apartment into like building infrastructure Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: So basically I was like, oh I already got it set up and he comes in and he's like, oh you're using the coax Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: You'd I've never seen someone actually get that going.
Speaker 0: How'd you do it?
Speaker 0: And I thought back and I remembered something I'd forgotten when the first Verizon guy came ten years ago He went to set up all my crap and I was like I'm gonna cancel this unless you can get this thing into my computer room.
Speaker 0: Like I'm not using wireless only.
Speaker 0: this is 2010.
Speaker 0: It's a modern era.
Speaker 0: I want wired internet.
Speaker 0: So We start fucking around and there's all these ethernet like ports in our apartment.
Speaker 0: as far as we can tell.
Speaker 0: they just go to hell Like they don't go anywhere.
Speaker 1: But yeah, I see some right there.
Speaker 1: Those definitely look like they go to the telephone.
Speaker 0: Yeah, one's one's an rj-50 like a telephone and one's an rj-45.
Speaker 1: really is a cable in there.
Speaker 1: Yeah the top one does look a little bigger.
Speaker 0: so He gave me his toner and I like went around like trying to figure out where these cables go and they just go Nowhere, they go to the abyss.
Speaker 0: They're gone forever.
Speaker 0: But there is a coax network in my apartment that goes to every room.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's man.
Speaker 1: It's probably cuz time Warner was also in this building.
Speaker 1: I've seen.
Speaker 1: I've seen them in the lobby.
Speaker 0: That's for cable television and I toned it and one of the ports in the bedroom and the living room and the computer room Was also live in the front closet near the FiOS box.
Speaker 0: Mmm So I so I was like will this work?
Speaker 0: and he put a tight like he did a signal tester and he was like There's nothing else using it.
Speaker 0: I'm pretty sure there's a like an Unterminated coax cable in the basement of this building in the meet-me room just like plugged into nothing and that's where the other shitty service Would go if I use them.
Speaker 1: Well, yeah this what it is.
Speaker 1: if because I've seen in my previous Apartment, right?
Speaker 1: It was only Time Warner and basically what they have in the basement is this block, right?
Speaker 1: Oh that building had 12 apartments and in the block there were 12 Places to hook up cable that is and then there were 12 wires with stickers on them.
Speaker 1: that said which apartments they were?
Speaker 1: Yeah, and if you didn't pay they just unplugged your wire From the thing and then they it was in a metal box of the lock on it So you'd have to bust it open to give yourself cable.
Speaker 0: Yeah Our building is like a full-on meet-me room for all the equipment in there and they did there was there's already.
Speaker 1: This is in the laundry room.
Speaker 0: Yeah, this is like like in the basement of the building But they have they run fiber of a bunch of different types and coax and it looks like Ethernet, too every apartment mmm, so That's all set up now.
Speaker 1: My new apartment just has Ethernet in the wall and it just works.
Speaker 0: I didn't have to do anything Yep, but the guy was basically like seems like you know what you're doing.
Speaker 0: That's pretty clever using the coax And he was kind of excited about it.
Speaker 0: So we hooked it all up and it worked fine.
Speaker 1: So My internet wonder if because it's coax if it might be like your max if you want it So coax your max speed might be lower coax.
Speaker 0: My max speed is Around a hundred no matter what I do.
Speaker 1: See they try.
Speaker 1: you can buy like.
Speaker 1: we got what we chose the plan.
Speaker 1: That was like three or four hundred ish.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I could write that there was a higher plan.
Speaker 1: That was gigabit and it's like, you know, ten fifteen twenty, maybe twenty dollars on that.
Speaker 1: It's like with the speed.
Speaker 1: we've never used all that we've got with the three hundred four hundred.
Speaker 0: if I bought gigabit You know what I would do.
Speaker 0: I think we could know why I would sell.
Speaker 0: I would just be a fake like bootleg ISP and sell internet to everyone Our friends who live in the same building.
Speaker 1: they got the gigabit and I'm like why you're spending like a thousand dollars a year.
Speaker 0: Perspective we're streaming geek nights live right now.
Speaker 0: You know how much that's using six.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we're streaming.
Speaker 1: 1080p content up takes six six megabits per second.
Speaker 1: That's right.
Speaker 0: So I got a hundred now and I tested it and despite the coax being the limiter I get about 98 down reliably and I get about a hundred and forty up which is fascinating.
Speaker 0: But I think we did an ancient show about like wires and stuff.
Speaker 0: I think we explained coaxial cable and like why that is a limitation, but that's neither here nor there.
Speaker 0: I got a whole new digital pipeline for geek nights.
Speaker 0: I got all new internet.
Speaker 0: the computer rooms like nicely cleaned up.
Speaker 0: I got a brand new bed.
Speaker 0: I got a brand new armoire.
Speaker 0: This is the shit that you get excited about.
Speaker 1: it.
Speaker 1: all his money.
Speaker 1: Yeah, he's getting in line for that.
Speaker 1: Yo, he really went first class on the flight to to and from Pac South.
Speaker 1: Well, he's the one if you got.
Speaker 1: if anyone out there is setting up their guillotine.
Speaker 1: I got.
Speaker 0: you know This is not first class.
Speaker 0: Like you get a little room or a bed.
Speaker 0: This is The American domestic first-class meaning the seats slightly wider and they give you food cause way more money than in the back.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I did not pay that money.
Speaker 0: I got the upgrade on the way.
Speaker 0: They're three names.
Speaker 1: He did not pay all that money.
Speaker 0: Dude business travel gives you status on like every airline and they'll just give you free upgrades.
Speaker 0: the flight There was not sold out.
Speaker 0: So I got like trivial just free upgrade On the way back.
Speaker 0: the flight was definitely gonna sell out and was already pretty crowded.
Speaker 1: Amanda An empty seat next to her.
Speaker 1: so it was me only ninety nine point.
Speaker 1: nine nine nine percent sold out.
Speaker 0: So I was not willing to pay extra money for first class on a domestic flight because it would have been like several hundred Dollars, it's not worth it.
Speaker 0: The flight was our base right was only two or three hundred up But I have a shit ton of points and miles on Delta.
Speaker 0: So I spent miles to upgrade to first class which basically cost me almost nothing.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm I had to pay like a $20 fee To use the miles, but that also paid for the flight.
Speaker 0: so I got the flight free.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: So just the.
Speaker 0: if you fly a lot just try to always fly like the same airline and you'll just automatically get a bunch of free stuff anyway.
Speaker 0: So it's Wednesday.
Speaker 0: We're back.
Speaker 0: We're bad.
Speaker 0: We had a lot to talk about.
Speaker 0: Still can't believe we didn't talk about B tasks and we'll get to that.
Speaker 0: but there is a bunch of anime animation news.
Speaker 1: first off I didn't even know this movie was coming the me not until today cuz I was looking if you don't know Weathering with you.
Speaker 1: the new Makoto shinkai joint like just came out.
Speaker 1: It's currently in theaters in the u.s.
Speaker 0: It's breaking by his record.
Speaker 0: They had to.
Speaker 1: they had two nights.
Speaker 1: Well, that was a while ago.
Speaker 1: They had two nights of like fan preview screenings.
Speaker 1: And then after that it was just regular screenings, you know.
Speaker 1: So this is the Makoto shinkai who you know.
Speaker 1: did you know your name?
Speaker 1: and whatnot, right?
Speaker 1: Oh cloud, man.
Speaker 0: Please promise no early days, right?
Speaker 1: That's where we met him first.
Speaker 1: Anyway, uh This is new movie and It's I know we are weathering you.
Speaker 0: we'll talk about first.
Speaker 1: I've been trying to.
Speaker 1: I've been trying to like, you know Get everyone together to go see it and the movie theater here has been showing it but at weird times.
Speaker 1: So I'm just like I fuck it.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna see it tomorrow with or without anyone else.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'm Emily I already saw it.
Speaker 0: So we're good there.
Speaker 0: I Won't review it right now because we're obviously gonna review it on geek nights.
Speaker 0: But to give you a geek bite what I will say about it is that it is the most Makoto shinkai in terms of.
Speaker 1: I mean This is a guy who is just.
Speaker 1: he's like.
Speaker 1: he knows what his thing is and rather than like Try to go out of his box.
Speaker 1: He just goes more and more in his box.
Speaker 1: This was like, all right.
Speaker 1: Now we're gonna make it.
Speaker 1: every movie I've ever made is actually secretly about clouds.
Speaker 1: I'm just gonna make a movie weathering with you literally directly up in your face with the class.
Speaker 0: Yes, not to spoil anything, but it's kind of a lot of girl.
Speaker 0: It turns into a cloud.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's the most Makoto shinkai thing I've ever heard.
Speaker 0: also about climate change Yeah, you don't say and it's also about lovers separated by space and time.
Speaker 1: you mean everything.
Speaker 1: go to shinkai movie.
Speaker 1: that's about.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I will say I don't think it's his best movie.
Speaker 0: I think your name is a much better tighter movie.
Speaker 0: I enjoyed weathering with you a lot, but it has a few.
Speaker 1: Was there that one he made?
Speaker 1: that was real man.
Speaker 1: The one we saw at New York Comic Con.
Speaker 0: Oh children who.
Speaker 0: so it's funny.
Speaker 0: I was talking to Emily and I was like I think this is his worst movie after weathering with you like there's still a high bar But I think it's his worst one.
Speaker 0: and Emily was like, what about children who chase lost voices?
Speaker 1: Was not good?
Speaker 0: children who chase lost voices is basically just like an air sats Ghibli movie.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't know what the hell that thing.
Speaker 0: I remember seeing it and not getting And remove the environmental storytelling and replace it with a plot that goes nowhere.
Speaker 1: Maybe I should watch it again just to see what the hell is.
Speaker 0: it's pretty weathering with you.
Speaker 1: I put it in the same bucket as the the the Ghibli You know, oh the Ghibli.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we will not speak of Goro's bad movie.
Speaker 1: Yeah that one.
Speaker 0: But the one thing I'll say about weathering with you without spoiling anything that the two things that disappoint me is one.
Speaker 0: There's one reading of the movie that is about relationships.
Speaker 0: That's a pretty good like.
Speaker 0: there's a good message there.
Speaker 0: There's a good theme there.
Speaker 0: that's told pretty well to the story but there's a much more direct reading.
Speaker 0: that is Kind of a problematic message about climate change.
Speaker 0: now Maybe you shouldn't try that hard to try to stop it really like just live with it like weather it out Like it's hard to uh-huh.
Speaker 0: You'll see when you watch it.
Speaker 0: anyway, I mean with it it involves a gun.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: Well Japan, you know a gun is a big deal.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the guns a weirdly big deal.
Speaker 0: in the movie like Without the gun things don't work out that I did not expect him at this movie to have that gun.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so while I was you know arranging right, you know this movie I was like, well, you know my friends We can't see this anime movie together.
Speaker 1: We'll see it separately Yeah, but I'm sure there will be another anime movie soon for us to watch because they just keep coming right?
Speaker 0: Oh, and I went I just keep coming.
Speaker 1: Mamoru Hosoda has been reliably doing one movie every three years So he's not coming back till 2021.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right wolf walkers is coming this year.
Speaker 0: That's not oh fuck I forgot about that entirely.
Speaker 1: That's not anime, but whatever.
Speaker 0: I'm still into it.
Speaker 0: It's probably better than it Trigger BNA like we didn't know that much about it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there's so much in the pipeline and then suddenly you awesome Right.
Speaker 1: I suddenly look and I look at four kids who brings all the anime to the US and it's like boom You guess what new Masaaki was like next month.
Speaker 1: It's like you.
Speaker 1: Oh, he was just here.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like I feel like we just reviewed This movie.
Speaker 1: this guy is making too many damn movies.
Speaker 0: I mean look chill out, you know, you know.
Speaker 0: Oh, I don't even know what that's about is coming out in 2021.
Speaker 0: He's the director Japan sinks.
Speaker 0: He's doing an anime adaptation of Japan sinks.
Speaker 0: You got everything sinks about Japan, but Japan sinks.
Speaker 0: Apparently he's also directing.
Speaker 0: Keep your hands off a Zouken Super Shiro ride.
Speaker 0: your wave is the one we're about to talk about.
Speaker 0: devil man cryberry the crybaby the show Lu over the wall, which we just reviewed.
Speaker 0: 2017 also 2017 the night is short.
Speaker 0: walk on girl Which is one of my favorite goddamn anime movies ever right?
Speaker 1: So this guy's cranking out like to a year.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right Man it was.
Speaker 1: it was where his hosted is doing one every three, of course what hosted as late as Mirai?
Speaker 1: That was way good.
Speaker 0: Yeah, man We're living in a golden age of just anime and animation like this is good time to show Mirai, right?
Speaker 0: I don't think so.
Speaker 1: We saw it.
Speaker 0: Yeah I'll double check.
Speaker 1: you saw right with the in the weird architect house.
Speaker 0: Yeah, okay We uh, although we gotta look at all the anime we've seen that we just haven't in inexplicably if not reviewed like BTS.
Speaker 0: The first episode anyway, so ride your wave seems to also have themes of Water as metaphor for death and or transformation.
Speaker 1: Well, didn't the vampire dog movie also have that Lu over the wall.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah Lu over the wall.
Speaker 0: I feel like water was definitely a metaphor for death or loss.
Speaker 0: Maybe transition like.
Speaker 0: arguably this one seems like it's more about transition, but could also be about death and or loss.
Speaker 1: Who knows but this is coming to theaters next month, but February something I mean.
Speaker 0: All I'll say is that so far?
Speaker 0: Masaki Yuasa is basically patting a thousand with me and I'm just gonna keep riding this train as long as it goes trains gonna go Straight into the water.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: So in some other news, oh, yeah So long ago in the days when like vertical comics was like at their peak of bringing you over Tezuka mangas and all that biz, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, and and they were.
Speaker 1: they were the hot shit, you know You would see them at conventions all the time.
Speaker 1: I'd be like, hey They would ask people like hey, what manga do you want us to bring to the u.s?
Speaker 1: They would actually put out surveys to find out what manga's they fans in the know knew about because there's so many Yeah that we could bring over.
Speaker 1: obviously you just think the only rule was you couldn't mention any mangas that were obviously unavailable From like, you know shonen jump company Shueisha or whatever, right?
Speaker 1: But any other company was totally fine because they could license from them and I would always say hey we want to get st Young men that's the comic we want.
Speaker 1: bring that shit over in English.
Speaker 1: and they would always tell me because they were so honest and Cool, they'd be like look that one is like basically number one on our list as well.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right, but the problem is is the person who made it, you know, the actual creator is like.
Speaker 1: Right, they're very.
Speaker 1: they got issues, right?
Speaker 1: They don't want to.
Speaker 1: they don't want to let us do it.
Speaker 1: So it's we did.
Speaker 1: we can't do it.
Speaker 1: All right, so Lo behold look through the comic book catalog recently and there I see it Saint young men volume 1 and I ordered that shit and I got it.
Speaker 1: I'm about to read it.
Speaker 0: I didn't read it yet But I mean I've read it before mister who might be too young to have listened to us talk about this a long time ago.
Speaker 0: What is st.
Speaker 0: Young men about st.
Speaker 1: Young men?
Speaker 1: The name it's weird cuz like it's those.
Speaker 1: you hear the name and you're like, what the hell is that about?
Speaker 0: That sounds like generic.
Speaker 1: Then once you hear what it's about the name, it makes perfect sense.
Speaker 1: It is about Buddha literally Buddha.
Speaker 1: Yeah Buddha and literally Jesus Jesus Jesus Jesus Christ The crown of thorns.
Speaker 0: He's just wearing the crown of thorns all the time.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, they're young men in Japan Modern Tokyo.
Speaker 1: Well modern day is the time of the writing of the comic.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and they are roommates Yep, living out their life being tourists.
Speaker 1: I feel like I need to read taken everything taken a vacation from being gods or whatever.
Speaker 0: There are Saints living in Tokyo, Japan Buddha the enlightened one and Jesus son of God.
Speaker 0: Yeah After successfully bringing the previous century to the clothes to a close that you share an apartment in Tachikawa While enjoying some well-earned time off down on earth Buddha pinches pennies like a typical neighborhood housewife while Jesus is prone to making impulse buys.
Speaker 1: This comic is way good.
Speaker 0: I've seen like bits of it like scans lated and it was pretty funny.
Speaker 1: I read a chat few chapters of it way back.
Speaker 1: That's how I knew about it.
Speaker 1: But you know now finally it's coming out in print and I think actually a whole bunch of it is available if you do Kindle comics ology Chats like present day present time.
Speaker 1: But if you want the the actual physical versions legit in English available.
Speaker 1: volume 1 now volume 2 soon I'm into it.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: So in some other I would do a brief geek bite.
Speaker 0: cuz I like the dragon Prince.
Speaker 0: It's out and it's either done or the first arc is done and it'll get picked up for like a new arc.
Speaker 0: But the three seasons completed right we watch.
Speaker 1: I've only seen two season.
Speaker 1: So I watch the third season.
Speaker 0: third season is real good.
Speaker 0: It rushes a little bit in a few parts.
Speaker 0: But all I will say without spoiling anything is that the ending is really good.
Speaker 0: It wraps up enough to where.
Speaker 0: if there weren't more I'd be okay with that.
Speaker 1: So they they reveal the dead bird that everyone knows since episode one.
Speaker 0: So the dead bird does not get dealt with.
Speaker 1: well, fuck that then it can't end.
Speaker 1: Yeah I'm not because I don't know not because I need that reveal cuz I know But because I just need I need that to go somewhere.
Speaker 1: I need for anyone to Be like.
Speaker 1: see I told you.
Speaker 0: so yep I uh, but everything else resolves really well.
Speaker 0: the stuff that happens in the end is good.
Speaker 0: But the thing I'll point out in particular is that there's a romantic subplot that once it gets introduced They just fucking like me.
Speaker 0: I cuz I'm homie.
Speaker 0: We're done.
Speaker 0: They're dating.
Speaker 0: Let's go.
Speaker 0: Let's move on.
Speaker 0: It doesn't turn into a typical thing.
Speaker 0: It works.
Speaker 0: and two There's a big battle.
Speaker 0: in the last episode the battle is Really really well choreographed Better than any big fantasy battle I've seen in most animated shows ever.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm It's just.
Speaker 0: it's a. like the fight choreography of this battle
Speaker 1: cowboy bebop episode one or Like Lord of the Rings
Speaker 0: like
Speaker 1: III
Speaker 0: I would say that the fights at the end of some armies facing off has better Massive mass fighting fight choreography than any Lord of the Rings movie
Speaker 1: like five deadly venoms.
Speaker 0: Not that level.
Speaker 0: zoom down zoomed out level of like.
Speaker 0: there is a real battle and tactics and strategies and a shield wall Total war video games.
Speaker 0: Yeah like imagine one of those total war video games like.
Speaker 0: It avoids the problem of there's a big generic battle and a few main characters and stuff.
Speaker 0: Then they win.
Speaker 0: it really focuses on like the ebb and flow of a real battle in a very satisfying way.
Speaker 0: Like the battle stood out to me and it only has one silly kid thing I haven't auctioned shows up at one point in the battle.
Speaker 0: No gang so watch for that.
Speaker 0: But the show is deeply satisfying.
Speaker 0: if you're holding out like to decide if Dragon Prince was good before you watch it It is super worth episode on Dragon Prince already.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but now it's over.
Speaker 0: It's great things Of the day what he got for me.
Speaker 1: So when I was at mag fest I went and did something on the schedule.
Speaker 1: There was a little like a little tabletop game jam and it was only two hours.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, followed by a 90-minute play test and I was like damn that is not a large time investment for a four-day 24/7 con.
Speaker 1: no, right.
Speaker 1: I will go there and see what's up.
Speaker 1: So I went there sat at a table with three other nerds.
Speaker 1: We made a as much of a game as you could make in two hours is a good game You know, it wasn't the worst, right?
Speaker 1: Anyway, you know and then we sort of play tested one game.
Speaker 1: Maybe they played, you know, whatever You know, it was a slight.
Speaker 1: it was someone else's game that was slapped together in two hours.
Speaker 1: So funnily enough hard to figure out, you know What was going on without.
Speaker 0: I missed that session not because I didn't want to go but because I stopped to play someone's game.
Speaker 0: They were demoing their indie tabletop game in tabletop and they were also gonna go to the game jam.
Speaker 0: But they got so into teaching me the game that they were like.
Speaker 1: I want to skip the game jam so I can teach you this game anyway, so Afterwards, I was just chatting with one of the people I made a game with and I was like, you know Everyone has a nerdy thing.
Speaker 1: one guy who I made a game with was like a twitch streamer or something Right and everyone everyone has their thing, right?
Speaker 1: So the guy I was talking to he said yeah, I make this like video series, right?
Speaker 1: It's sort of like, you know, it's sort of like an SCA kind of deal, right?
Speaker 1: Basically, it's you know a live-action, you know fictional video series.
Speaker 1: That's you know, some fantasy fairytale kind of thing.
Speaker 1: It looks like you know, some SCA people recording a movie in the woods some larpers in the woods You know with a thing right and I was like, okay, so I had really low as expectations.
Speaker 1: Yeah Right from what amounts to SCA Larpers in the woods recording a short fictional video series not unwarranted, right?
Speaker 1: So I watch you know, the first episode.
Speaker 1: once I see that it's so short.
Speaker 1: I'm like, okay, whatever I got nothing to lose.
Speaker 1: This only has like a few hundred views.
Speaker 0: Maybe not even right on the 20th person to like it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, not a lot.
Speaker 1: All right, so I'm like, is this actually gonna be good?
Speaker 1: And you know what?
Speaker 1: It's not gonna blow your mind.
Speaker 0: with his goodness I was waiting for you to be like, it's amazing.
Speaker 1: No But it was vastly exceeding my extremely low expectation.
Speaker 1: All right, right like I kind of your new listeners coming from Scott.
Speaker 0: That is a weirdly high compliment.
Speaker 1: like I started I started watching it and I was like, huh?
Speaker 1: The acting isn't awful.
Speaker 1: It's like community theater level acting.
Speaker 1: maybe maybe a little better right.
Speaker 1: the videoing, you know, not the worst, right?
Speaker 1: You know, it's like there's nothing really mind-blowing about it, but it's like, okay, I can see what's happening.
Speaker 1: The audio sounds good.
Speaker 1: You know.
Speaker 1: the sets, you know are what they are.
Speaker 1: They look like some nerds left them together But and the actual fairy tale was you know, somewhat moderately compelling like I wanted to know what happened.
Speaker 1: All right, it's about this fair.
Speaker 1: You know This.
Speaker 1: this lady is on a you know Walking through the woods to visit her friend who lives in the woods house And she passes a fairy tied up to a tree in the woods and starts bargaining with it But not like a moron getting fooled by it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and that was pretty pretty good.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there you go It's tough because I feel like any magical creature I'd be easily tricked by because I just be hoping they teach me magic.
Speaker 1: This is basically yeah, it's like, you know It was like that common setup of magical creature in the woods trying to fool you.
Speaker 1: I mean, I'm not gonna listen.
Speaker 1: who's actually smart and won't be fooled by it?
Speaker 0: This is why our friend scojo has put me on his list of people who cannot ever be allowed to make a deal with Satan Devils of any kind because if I'm walking through the woods they bump into like some sort of like fantasy creature.
Speaker 0: That's like yo dog.
Speaker 0: I'll give you power if you help me out.
Speaker 0: I would probably help him out.
Speaker 1: So it's called far from the path a fairy tale web series.
Speaker 1: I've only watched segment one So I but I presume the further segments are similar in nature.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: All right, I'm game.
Speaker 0: So we were having a conversation I don't know if even if this was on geek nights or just in our life about Complicated rhythms in songs a little while ago and I mentioned that I just seen a really good video That's really recent where this dude David Bennett.
Speaker 0: It was a good YouTube channel Actually explains in detail with specific examples and they play songs.
Speaker 0: You can listen to it.
Speaker 0: what polyrhythm and complex rhythm really is means how it works why it's so hard for humans.
Speaker 1: Oh now that I see the image on your screen now, I understand why the fuck that problem is.
Speaker 0: Yeah Oh good lord.
Speaker 0: There's a great video where it shows trying to get a group of people one of them's gonna clap Rhythm a and one of them's gonna.
Speaker 1: that's the tiny box.
Speaker 1: Yeah polyrhythm be a tiny desk tiny desk Yeah anyway.
Speaker 0: so This but the cool thing is what it shows like.
Speaker 0: this is the stuff that I kind of miss when I didn't go into music Like as a profession, but what I used to study it that you think classical music is very like complicated But like popular music people kind of just sing and play unless it's electronic music.
Speaker 0: But
Speaker 1: even
Speaker 0: a lot of really pot like Zeppelin used polyrhythm more often than you realize like polyrhythm is actually more common in Popular music and rock and metal than it is in like classical or symphonic music Mm-hmm, and it's also in a lot of songs that you wouldn't know unless you were a music person you were listening for it.
Speaker 0: It also shows sometimes people write music naively like really good music, but they didn't study a lot of music theory.
Speaker 0: They just write something that sounds good and complicated.
Speaker 0: But then if you try to write the sheet music for that You gotta end up writing fucking polyrhythms.
Speaker 0: because they made something that cannot be expressed easily the way most music is expressed.
Speaker 1: Right because they weren't locked in with that mentality of notes.
Speaker 1: They just sort of played whatever with whatever tiring and rhythm and just sort of playing notes and it's like, okay Well now we have to take that.
Speaker 1: whatever notes they played, you know off rhythm and there, you know They mess they didn't place that you didn't keep the beat steady.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right Okay, well now write exactly what though what they played actually sounds good.
Speaker 1: We don't want to change it We don't want to cram it and fit it in the box of four four Oh, we're gonna use a 16 three times signature and right there we go.
Speaker 1: We ought to express it using this existing language of written music without inventing a new system that no one will ever understand.
Speaker 1: Yep, so we got to do crazy shit.
Speaker 0: So this video explains that in change the timing every measure.
Speaker 0: Yeah It's way worse than that.
Speaker 0: The funny thing is of like random aside if you ever run in like a busker in the street like anyone who's kind of Just like drumming around if you can pick out like natural or intuitive rhythms from polyrhythms or complex rhythms.
Speaker 0: That is how to tell if someone actually like has been trained in music or not because very rarely will someone who is just picking out music natively invent this kind of music.
Speaker 0: Mmm In the meta moment we are back freshly from PAX South 2020. the video of our panel will be on YouTube like this weekend.
Speaker 0: Also, we will link to.
Speaker 0: we've linked to video of the other similar panel that talks about 40 different games.
Speaker 0: We're linked to the slides from magfest.
Speaker 0: We did a panel on the real harm of games and it wasn't just me and Scott talking out of our butts.
Speaker 0: We had a doctor sitting next to us who made sure we weren't talking out of our butts and she was fantastic.
Speaker 0: And the slides from that panel with all the citations about how video games aren't bad except in the context probably of Gambling and loot boxes, which probably should be banned.
Speaker 0: those slides You can just click here and see the slides and all the citations and read all that research.
Speaker 0: We will be live pretty soon at PAX East 2020. it's like a month away and We'll be doing a repeat panel.
Speaker 0: So if you've seen it before you don't need to see us there at PAX East But it'll be all new to a lot of people.
Speaker 0: we were doing take your fucking turn which is a real fun panel to run.
Speaker 0: Otherwise the geek nights book club book is the tale of Genji.
Speaker 0: I'm reading through it.
Speaker 0: I feel like at some point before the end of the end of like the first quarter of the year We'll do a checkpoint episode on the tale of Genji.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: I got some things to say about Genji.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so leave it at that.
Speaker 0: So when I was a kid, I uh, I liked Batman but I didn't read Batman comics.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean so like I never read a Batman before you talk about before you talk about Batman, right?
Speaker 1: I just got to say I we just look to make sure we never did a show on this and we're surprised We hadn't done a show on it.
Speaker 1: But I think what we did do is maybe we did a show on like Cartoons.
Speaker 1: we watched when we were a kid and talked about this extensively.
Speaker 1: There is no way we have never mentioned this on geek nights before at best.
Speaker 0: We probably did like cartoons.
Speaker 0: We liked in middle school something like that.
Speaker 1: Anyway, this show is worthy of its own episode.
Speaker 1: So yeah when I was a kid much like rim, I didn't buy a Batman comic, but I watched the Batman movie.
Speaker 0: and Which one Michael Keaton?
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Well all the ones I think all the ones that came out during my the 90s Yeah, right, but the only ones I liked were the two Michael Keaton one.
Speaker 1: I like the Jim Carrey one.
Speaker 1: Okay, anyway, okay And the point is right did not is like the the one with Robin No, or the Arnold Schwarzenegger one.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah anyway The point is that you know, we ever get me kind of like that movie.
Speaker 1: You say what are your favorite things?
Speaker 1: Batman would never make the list?
Speaker 0: It was weird though because I liked Batman.
Speaker 0: I knew what Batman was, but I never consumed any Batman media.
Speaker 0: It's like until I saw Michael Keaton.
Speaker 1: Oh, I watched Adam West Batman before I watched this.
Speaker 0: Oh, I did see Adam West Batman, but I didn't my kid brain like that.
Speaker 0: I always treated that as a different Batman.
Speaker 1: Well, yeah, but the point is is that it was one of those things where it's like.
Speaker 1: I like this thing.
Speaker 1: I watched this thing.
Speaker 1: I didn't read Batman comics, but you know, I've read spider-man's or other things.
Speaker 0: I read x-men's.
Speaker 1: I wouldn't.
Speaker 1: if you ask me things that I liked it would never occur to me to mention it.
Speaker 0: You know, I would mention Batman.
Speaker 1: I would never.
Speaker 1: if I went to the Toys R Us to buy toys, I would never buy a Batman thing.
Speaker 0: Well people ask me what superhero things I liked.
Speaker 0: I would.
Speaker 0: I was a little kid.
Speaker 0: I would always say I like x-men and Batman like x-men and spider-man.
Speaker 1: Yep Batman I wouldn't mention it.
Speaker 1: But I sure as hell if Adam West Batman was on TV when I was a kid I would watch it and not want to stop watching it though one thing as a little kid It's totally inside.
Speaker 0: but Adam West Batman.
Speaker 0: when I saw the movie Much like with the project a co as a kid.
Speaker 0: I treated like a serious movie.
Speaker 0: I was like, oh shit that bomb.
Speaker 0: Oh, no.
Speaker 0: Oh, no, there's nuns.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: Like I did not get that.
Speaker 0: It was supposed to be a comedy.
Speaker 1: Yep Yep kid brain.
Speaker 1: anyway point is is that BTS Batman the animated series right was on like constantly on television.
Speaker 1: Yeah in the 90s and basically you get home from school.
Speaker 1: It would be on usually.
Speaker 1: it would be on like right before dinner.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I would I watched.
Speaker 1: it'd be like watch BTS BTS and eat food.
Speaker 0: I'm sure I've seen all or nearly all episodes of this multiple times.
Speaker 1: I'm sure I've seen close to all of them.
Speaker 0: Not seen.
Speaker 0: there's 85 episodes Okay.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it did get to a point on TV where I was watching syndication and I never was not seeing new episodes.
Speaker 1: Yeah, maybe one I missed but you know, who knows.
Speaker 1: anyway, so I would you know Purposefully go out of my way to watch other shows.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right.
Speaker 1: There were certain shows.
Speaker 1: It's like oh, I gotta see that, right?
Speaker 1: That's like, you know, I'm fighting to see those shows and if you ask me what I was into it Those are shows to be at like a Voltron right something like that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but if BTS is on And watched it, right?
Speaker 1: I was a little more be just sort of like.
Speaker 1: oh it's on.
Speaker 0: BTS is one of those shows that was in my schedule of.
Speaker 0: It's on at this time.
Speaker 0: I'm going to watch it.
Speaker 0: Or I would set my VCR to record that.
Speaker 0: my own VCR Like.
Speaker 0: I would record it and then watch it later if I couldn't watch it.
Speaker 1: He's like.
Speaker 1: I would watch it if it was on but it wasn't like.
Speaker 1: must watch right, but it's sort of like in hindsight.
Speaker 1: I like.
Speaker 1: I didn't realize how much I liked it just like every other Batman thing.
Speaker 1: I liked it so much without the self-awareness that that was a thing that I was into.
Speaker 1: So I wasn't taking actions to see more of it.
Speaker 1: Right because it wasn't conscious liking.
Speaker 1: but when it was there it would entrap me.
Speaker 0: But it tried.
Speaker 1: only later in life did I realize oh shit that thing was fucking great And I just didn't realize how great it was at the time.
Speaker 0: like I would say that it is the best incarnation of Batman in film or television.
Speaker 0: clearly like The the the best Batman movie is Mask of the Phantasm, which is the BTS movie.
Speaker 0: basically yep The best Batman show is BTS and the best Batman comic I guess is comic adaptation of BTS.
Speaker 1: yeah Yeah, but yeah, so this show if you don't know right It was pretty much as far as I can tell the first show to have that Animation style which was then later used on some other shows.
Speaker 1: I think there was a Superman that sort of had that.
Speaker 0: yep well remember well a bunch of the show was outsourced to anime studios.
Speaker 0: right and Especially watch the first episode again because I never saw the first episode until way later.
Speaker 0: But as it like when I was older when we were living in Beacon I just watched the first episode of it randomly.
Speaker 0: the first episode of it is some Anime feeling shit like right down to like the banter between characters.
Speaker 0: it feels so much like a 90s anime.
Speaker 0: But they outsourced a whole bunch of the animation to a bunch of studios including sunrise.
Speaker 0: There's a whole list of them.
Speaker 0: you can read Wikipedia about that kind of stuff.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but if you look like you know the main guys are like Bruce Timm Paul Dini Whatever.
Speaker 1: Bruce Timm is like the guy who was credited with like that art character design.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right, and if you look at the other stuff.
Speaker 1: He worked on like if you look for him It'll be like oh look a whole bunch of other stuff that looks like you know.
Speaker 0: BTS yep But why do we like this Batman so much like if we had to go a really high one?
Speaker 0: It isn't like the grim dark modern Batman that no one.
Speaker 1: But it was set in a you know retro future Visually dark right art deco Gotham City.
Speaker 0: now listen if there's things I like on this earth It's visually dark film noir style art deco like.
Speaker 1: it's already my jam right much Much like animes right?
Speaker 1: it did not you know Talk down to children and that did not dumb itself down.
Speaker 1: it you know.
Speaker 0: it was like yeah I'll be like it would.
Speaker 0: it wouldn't like a lot of people wouldn't get killed outright They just get poisoned or something, but it was still pretty dark, and there was a threat of death, right?
Speaker 1: It was still like an appropriate.
Speaker 1: You know for children's cartoon thing, but you know the storytelling wasn't?
Speaker 1: you know like?
Speaker 1: lame-o Kind of storytelling like you know Golden Age comic.
Speaker 0: there were a lot of twists there were ambiguous Characters.
Speaker 0: most of the villains in BTS were sympathetic like most of them.
Speaker 1: If you look at like you know.
Speaker 1: for if you look for another show Right that had the same kind of storytelling going on you don't see them really come until you know like a generation After with like say a samurai jack or something like that.
Speaker 1: yeah in terms of American You know kids TV shows with that kind of storytelling also had a lot of multi-episode arcs.
Speaker 0: it also built upon itself as time went up.
Speaker 1: It introduced characters to Batman's canon yep and many existing Batman characters who appeared were Significantly different and you know because they were new renditions.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it was almost like.
Speaker 1: not only were there new characters like Harley Quinn or whatever, but there were also remixes of existing characters that were sometimes Close to or nothing like the you know previous ones.
Speaker 0: This is my favorite Joker by far - yeah, it was just you know.
Speaker 1: It's just a crazy dude.
Speaker 0: How's the Mark Hamill?
Speaker 0: Though Nowadays like poison ivy was right and Batman was wrong to stop her and almost everything she tried to do.
Speaker 1: yeah Also, you know because it was a cartoon There was a more sort of like You know sort of supernatural Superpowered element cuz Batman doesn't have superpowers right now.
Speaker 1: his superpower in this show is money and being smart right but a lot of the villains Right if you want if you need a DC comic especially like say a Justice League.
Speaker 1: right the superpower people everywhere, right?
Speaker 1: You know it's ridiculous, but the ones in BTAS were all more.
Speaker 1: You know not outright.
Speaker 1: There was like.
Speaker 1: Superman doesn't show up in BTAS right.
Speaker 1: It's not in DC Universe.
Speaker 0: It's Batman only yeah Which is so hard why it's great.
Speaker 1: so when the villains have some kind of super thing going on.
Speaker 1: It's usually actually more of a sci-fi Kind of deal right?
Speaker 1: wasn't?
Speaker 1: like?
Speaker 1: I don't freeze science accident right I was in clay face also some kind of science thing yeah to face accident.
Speaker 1: Not that I know the real stories behind those in the quote canon stories of the original characters.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right, but then like Harley Quinn brand new character.
Speaker 1: Yep, but yeah There wasn't.
Speaker 1: you know a lot of any super powered people with like you know DC style Superman superpower that I remember.
Speaker 0: right There were some moments that edged into that.
Speaker 1: but usually There was definitely fantastical Non-real elements yeah, but most of it was sci-fi like the most memorable.
Speaker 1: there are two episodes I remember the most even this far late in my life when I haven't seen this show in forever Right.
Speaker 1: one of them was the one where Batman fights the ninja and the volcano.
Speaker 1: you remember that one?
Speaker 1: yeah Batman is praise and it was clearly an homage to likes old kung fu movies, right?
Speaker 1: It's like a lot of men is practicing like the touch of death on this dummy Oh my god.
Speaker 0: in his hotel room, and then he puts the armor played.
Speaker 0: yeah I remember I would I was the kid I remember that episode and he got hit with the touch.
Speaker 0: I was like oh shit Batman's dead.
Speaker 0: I was like really yes.
Speaker 1: He's fighting this ninja guy Hey on who's like volcano rocks right it likes floating in lava or whatever.
Speaker 0: But it also the show was really kind of brooding and atmospheric and I had a lot of like long Establishing shots and just like slow movement, and I did a lot of the things that I liked in anime at the time.
Speaker 1: The other episode that I remember at our deck two part.
Speaker 1: Oh of course.
Speaker 1: It's hard.
Speaker 1: Yeah, of course.
Speaker 0: It's hard I know you right.
Speaker 1: It's all about the this giant evil computer That's so big and is a lot like a giant vacuum tube computer But it actually is so powerful has an AI a real AI right and the computer can't even fucking move.
Speaker 1: It's just a giant computer.
Speaker 1: It's sort of like the computer in Evangelion right or the three computers in the Evangelion if they were just one computer yep, right?
Speaker 1: And somehow that's a villain in a Batman series, and it makes sense.
Speaker 1: That's a good set up, and then I think it was actually a set of episodes That was like a sequel.
Speaker 1: cuz Hardak was such a good good good idea.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'm pretty sure I came back.
Speaker 0: I feel like I gotta rewatch the show.
Speaker 0: just cuz I haven't seen most of these episodes since I was in like middle school.
Speaker 1: Yeah, of course.
Speaker 1: You know the song right.
Speaker 1: That's the Batman song.
Speaker 1: yep It wasn't.
Speaker 1: it wasn't originally the Batman song.
Speaker 1: right if you could play that song for someone on the street Who's never seen the show and say oh, what's this song?
Speaker 1: They're like oh, it's Batman.
Speaker 1: so I'm kind of like gee I wonder where the hell that came from?
Speaker 1: yep This show.
Speaker 1: it didn't exist.
Speaker 1: before this show.
Speaker 0: there's two Batman songs.
Speaker 0: There's the silly one and this one.
Speaker 0: there's one spider-man song.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the Batman song before this one That used to be the Batman song and all this show came around like if I was walking in the street And I heard you something that even just was the chord structure of the Batman song my brain would just say Batman.
Speaker 0: Yeah, where's Batman?
Speaker 0: that's right this Batman coming on.
Speaker 0: so the music was originally to Danny Elfman because that is who did the Tim Burton Michael Keaton.
Speaker 0: people are giving me shit on the stream.
Speaker 1: well cuz they this came.
Speaker 0: I don't call them the Tim Burton Batman movies.
Speaker 0: I called him the Michael Keaton Batman movies.
Speaker 1: anyway the point is yeah But I mean this was made around the same time as those right when did the first episode of B test came out?
Speaker 1: 92 Right.
Speaker 1: so at the time the Batman that was most in people's minds was the Tim Burton Batman Which was also a pretty good bet like and this came out.
Speaker 1: this was okay though.
Speaker 1: kids went to the movie to see Tim Burton Batman.
Speaker 1: we got to have.
Speaker 1: this is the cartoon has got to be close to that feel right.
Speaker 1: So that's why you got that.
Speaker 0: yep, but it's if I have this anecdote.
Speaker 0: I just remember when I was a kid because my parents when the Michael Keaton Batman movie was out my parents were like I don't Know if this is okay for the kids to see like.
Speaker 0: we should check it out.
Speaker 0: so my dad went to see it.
Speaker 0: He came home, and I remember my mom was like so uh How was it?
Speaker 0: and he was like it was dark and which makes sense, and she was like who?
Speaker 0: really well What if he was the kids like no no no like it's dark, but also like it's actually dark like I couldn't see a lot Of what was going on.
Speaker 1: yeah, it was dark.
Speaker 0: It was super.
Speaker 0: It was directly dark and metaphorically dark.
Speaker 1: It's like when you watch B test.
Speaker 1: It's like it's always night.
Speaker 1: It's basically rarely ever is Batman.
Speaker 1: I mean it happened sometimes, but rarely is Batman or any scene out in the sunlight during the day Maybe like at the end of an episode.
Speaker 1: It'll be like ah daylight to be like that.
Speaker 1: And you know the episodes over but most of the time they're either in a cave in a dark building Out in a dark street.
Speaker 1: It's just dark all the time.
Speaker 1: You know and everything around is dark.
Speaker 1: There aren't brightly colored flowers or anything except for contrast yep.
Speaker 0: So overall like this show holds up crazy.
Speaker 0: Well like if it came out today It would get a claim like it was.
Speaker 0: this was like Batman the animated series coming to Netflix, and it never existed before.
Speaker 0: and you'd like none of that.
Speaker 0: none of this existed.
Speaker 0: I think it would be one of the top shows right also.
Speaker 1: It's like you look at other You know adaptations of things into kids cartoon.
Speaker 1: You know and it's like they tend to do every other superhero Cartoon that I can think of that was a dad different comic book like there isn't a good spider-man cartoon.
Speaker 0: No like.
Speaker 1: is there a good Superman cartoon?
Speaker 1: It's like.
Speaker 0: I don't think there is the one Like this, but I remember watching a couple episodes and just not being in.
Speaker 1: yeah Even the other Batman cartoons like there's a Batman Beyond and stuff like that.
Speaker 1: It's like.
Speaker 1: there's so many of them.
Speaker 1: I think there's like maybe like a Justice League cartoon.
Speaker 1: I don't fucking know.
Speaker 0: there is one good x-men cartoon not the Fox one.
Speaker 0: that one was only good when I was a dumb kid.
Speaker 0: Not actually good.
Speaker 0: the point is there's so many but Wolverine in the x-men was actually like legit.
Speaker 1: good All right, there are many that are you know good or not so good, but there's none.
Speaker 1: even close to this level.
Speaker 1: This is like an extreme level of greatness that is like not been replicated ever.
Speaker 0: Beach-ass is the goat Batman like for real like.
Speaker 1: there might be an argument to even say like.
Speaker 1: would Batman even be a popular thing today?
Speaker 1: if be if not for these this cartoon I can it did Batman like have not been continued would not have carried its popularity forward.
Speaker 0: Yep, I feel like if beat as had not existed as a kid I would have.
Speaker 0: Batman would have just been Adam West to me.
Speaker 1: And I think if this had been a crabby cartoon that ended quickly and wasn't Resindicated and re-shone and so great and remembered where would Batman be now?
Speaker 1: would they have gone into that pool again?
Speaker 1: So frequently for all those other movies that carried it through today?
Speaker 0: But most of those movies like not to get on a change about Batman.
Speaker 0: most Batman movies aren't that great?
Speaker 1: So if it wasn't for this cartoon carrying it forward they weren't making those, you know It's like they made a bad movie and then they made another bad movie.
Speaker 1: Well because of this cartoon there were still Batman fans.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it was only those movies and then there was a first bat.
Speaker 1: bad movie would have been the end of it.
Speaker 0: I feel like I would.
Speaker 0: Batman would have been Adam West to me and then Michael Keaton and then after Michael Keaton I would have thought Batman was dumb.
Speaker 0: then I would have read Frank Miller's comic and they're really into it because that was good.
Speaker 0: But then I would have seen that every other Batman after that is just crying to like ouch Grimdark the Frank Miller Batman comic and then I wouldn't have been into it.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm So B TAS is the greatest Batman has ever been and possibly the greatest Batman ever will be And I feel like we shouldn't talk about mask of the phantasm because that deserves its own like.
Speaker 1: Maybe that is the.
Speaker 1: maybe we did do an episode of Master.
Speaker 0: the Phantom couldn't find it.
Speaker 0: I got.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna look for I'm gonna feel like we definitely did.
Speaker 1: Anyway, the point is, you know Batman is a character was like reinvented several times right?
Speaker 1: is the original detective II Batman Right, then you get the sort of Cartoony Silver Age Batman that you see in comics and also Adam West show Right, and then you get the Neil Adams Batman right who then gets even darker into the Frank Miller Batman, right?
Speaker 1: That man has been redone in different ways so many times Right, and it is still being redone.
Speaker 1: But you know those first few redoings were like major redoings, right?
Speaker 1: It was like they were trying to find what Batman should be and they sort of fell on deciding like okay Batman is like extra dark somewhere right James Bond sort of but also You know really creepy and messed up.
Speaker 1: It's somewhere in there Yeah, and that they sort of Batman I feel like has stayed in this one spot for a long time And hasn't moved a bunch and I would really like to see another Batman redoing, right?
Speaker 1: So it needs a new Take that's as wildly different from the current take as the.
Speaker 0: you know Adam West take was from the V test and there is precedent for that because spider-man into the spider-verse I Think is the best spider-man movie ever made.
Speaker 0: bar none Oh movie.
Speaker 1: Yeah, sure show thing is spider-man has actually lots of great spider-man coming.
Speaker 0: Yeah comics are more complex But other than comics I think the hint of the spider-verse is the best non comic spider-man that has ever been made.
Speaker 1: I mean any any video or TV because there's a lot of spider-man things but none of them are that great now.
Speaker 1: It's not a good one.
Speaker 0: I feel like you can reinvent Batman To get it away from its current state by just making Batman the animated series.
Speaker 0: There's make more in that style.
Speaker 0: don't even change anything.
Speaker 1: Oh, it's hard.
Speaker 1: It's hard to do.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right It's easy to be like I'll make more of the same but they can't and that's why you know This is.
Speaker 1: this is actually something I was thinking of the other day.
Speaker 1: Sort of looking end the show on this crazy thought, right?
Speaker 1: All right, so we've been watching lots and lots of link to the best randomizer, right?
Speaker 1: Why?
Speaker 1: why does that really?
Speaker 1: why are people playing these randomizers and keep playing them?
Speaker 1: It's because they want more of a thing.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right if there was a fin advance Wars randomizer That'd be the end of my.
Speaker 1: exactly.
Speaker 1: you want more of a thing and they're not making more of that thing right, so we found a way to To use technology to make more of the thing we want right.
Speaker 1: and it's like, you know You go to a restaurant and you eat steak.
Speaker 1: Well, you can always eat more steak because it's not like you're eating the exact same experience every time but when you watch a movie It's literally the exact same movie.
Speaker 1: every time you're rewatch B test.
Speaker 1: You're rewatching the same exact thing Pixel by pixel second by second.
Speaker 1: it doesn't change at all.
Speaker 1: So you run out eventually and it gets old and you can't get more right.
Speaker 1: that randomizer Allows you to get more linked to the past.
Speaker 0: Yeah, lots and lots more but it is diminishing.
Speaker 1: return the same way that you don't get bored of eating ice cream.
Speaker 1: You won't get bored playing, you know linked to the past randomizer because it's you're freshening it, right?
Speaker 1: it's not the same.
Speaker 1: every time as Technology advances we should be and the randomizer You should be able to develop right.
Speaker 1: you see lots of things now where it's like aha Used you know machine learning to read a bunch of books and then write a new book in the same style and it's kind of Silly and not there yet, right?
Speaker 1: There will I think in our lives?
Speaker 1: You know, you might probably won't get to download our brains into a computer or ghost in the shell or you know travel You know super far in space really fast or anything like that.
Speaker 1: but if we survive we should be able to develop a technology that can just spit out B test episodes that are legit and also new.
Speaker 0: I Await that day.
Speaker 0: Yeah, this has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Speaker 1: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 0: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows.
Speaker 0: sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays and make comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays Night's is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 1: But unlike those other late shows It's actually recorded at night and the geek nights patreon patrons.
Speaker 0: are Alan Joyce hiding behind a little just like a dude?
Speaker 0: guys art option link a G the thirst for hydrated Ganon Chris mink.
Speaker 0: if my state e.com J band Shawn Yeager Nicholas brand out you hold the Kray to my heart Or to one.
Speaker 0: creations started making trouble in my neighborhood Trevor Don't harl Superboy Clinton Walton Ren from New Zealand Ryan parent drew up and Lander Finn Dread Lily Tenebrae Sean Klein Chris Reimer and Thomas on.
Speaker 0: if anything sounds hinky about this episode of geek nights Like be sure to let me know.
Speaker 0: I threw a pretty primitive pipeline together Still playing around with this.
Speaker 0: This is a full digital pipeline.
Speaker 0: I have no analog compression.
Speaker 0: No inserts nothing anywhere.
Speaker 0: So I'm working from raw Microphone signals and I'm also Setting up some some sidechain stuff.
Speaker 0: I got a bus that's doing a more of a standard broadcast limiter and I'm trying to Bring the production time of a new episode of geek nights down from five minutes to about one minute Not counting the time it takes to record this bit.
Speaker 0: So yeah If anything sounds good bad weird give me some feedback on the audio in Particular and I'm gonna keep tweaking this pipeline and once it's good, we'll be good to go.
Speaker 0: I also want feedback on how the stream sounded if one of us was too loud or quiet or whatever.
Speaker 0: Since it's all digital.
Speaker 0: I can't rely on the analog compressor.
Speaker 0: I used to use for OBS.
Speaker 0: So I'm instead relying on the Kind of limited compression compression feature that is built into OBS.
Speaker 0: But anyway now I leave you with.
Speaker 1: It's October 31st, 2005.
Speaker 1: This is geek nights with rim and scope.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: Leeroy We should probably put leeroy in there whatever.
Speaker 1: Doo doo doo doo.
Speaker 1: No, I got before you start the news like doo doo doo doo doo doo, but not the noise.
Speaker 1: Doo doo me going.
Speaker 1: doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo.
Speaker 0: You want to do that originally?
Speaker 0: We're gonna have the So, uh, I guess we could do that or I could make that sound.
Speaker 1: I think this copyrighted or patented by whatever news will just make it something else.
Speaker 0: It's just Morse code.
Speaker 0: We'll make it say something geeky.