Speaker 0: It's Tuesday, January 14th, 2020.
Speaker 0: I'm Rem.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott.
Speaker 0: And this is Geek Nights.
Speaker 0: Tonight, the new hotness in trick-taking games, Nokosu Dice.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: We're almost at the end of the convention, the densest convention season we've had in modern Geek Nights history.
Speaker 1: Yeah, when's East like the right beginning of March or something?
Speaker 0: East is like the end of February, beginning of March, so we got like.
Speaker 0: We got a little bit of time after South, but Pac South is this weekend, and I think we're ready for it.
Speaker 0: I'm a little tired doing all these cons in a row.
Speaker 0: As much as I love cons, I needed like one more weekend in my life.
Speaker 0: Especially because like I'm tearing apart, like I'm buying all new furniture, and I'm like redoing bedrooms and all this nonsense.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: So, uh, our hiatus, as you know, is mostly over, but there might be a little bit of hiatus.
Speaker 0: You got any open-y bits?
Speaker 0: Anything happen to you in the last couple days?
Speaker 1: My shoulder has been hurting.
Speaker 1: My neck shoulder has been hurting for like a few months.
Speaker 1: I don't even remember when it started.
Speaker 0: Oh, a few months?
Speaker 0: I thought this was only like a few weeks.
Speaker 0: No.
Speaker 0: If I have a pain that lasts more than a week and I don't know what caused it, I go to a doctor like right away.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there was no thing that, it's not like something fell on me or I fell down.
Speaker 1: It just has been hurting.
Speaker 0: I mean, I know you and not to speculate on your health, but if I had to guess anything, it's your hunch.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: I feel like your hunch might be the problem.
Speaker 1: The hunch that hasn't been a problem ever.
Speaker 0: I feel like it will eventually be a problem.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so it's been hurting in a weird, it got, at one point it got really worse and then it got better, you know, better, but not all the way better and then worse again.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So everyone's like, go to the doctor, and I'm like, man, the doctor's just gonna be like, you're getting old, stuff hurts, whatever, just go to physical therapy or something.
Speaker 1: I don't care, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, physical therapy is awesome.
Speaker 1: I don't want to waste time with that.
Speaker 1: It works, it works really well.
Speaker 1: Yeah, whatever.
Speaker 1: I only want to go to a doctor.
Speaker 1: if they can tell me this is exactly the thing that is wrong, I have identified it.
Speaker 0: Here's the problem, you realize like almost no medicine works that way.
Speaker 1: Correct, which is why I'll just like, whatever, if you can't tell me what's wrong, then you can't possibly believe that you can fix it.
Speaker 0: No, but they can tell you what's likely wrong, they can give you likely options that will make it better.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so I finally go to the doctor because, you know, because I have a self-treated wound I can talk about, I'll show off my swollen finger in a minute.
Speaker 1: So he's just like, you know, it's like, he's like, oh, yeah, you got some kind of spasm.
Speaker 1: I'm like, okay, I'm like, shouldn't that mean the muscles moving on its own?
Speaker 1: He's like, no, that doesn't have to mean that.
Speaker 0: Usually in that kind of case, it means it like tenses up and doesn't let go.
Speaker 1: Yeah, something like that.
Speaker 0: Or it tenses up and like pushes a nerve.
Speaker 1: Yeah, something along those lines.
Speaker 0: I've had a lot of, I've had injuries that cause those kinds of things over the years.
Speaker 1: He's like, oh, I'll prescribe you these drugs or whatever.
Speaker 1: And I'm like, if it's just a pain killing drug, I'm like, I'm not in that serious pain that I need a pain killing drug.
Speaker 0: See, that's something I've never understood about you because if I'm in pain, I will just always take a painkiller right away because why have pain ever?
Speaker 0: But the point is- Why ever experience pain if you don't have to?
Speaker 1: The pain that I'm in is so minor, right, that it's not worth the trade-off of whatever.
Speaker 1: Like Tylenol messes up your liver, aspirin and the other ones mess up your stomach.
Speaker 0: Usually not, only if your stomach has other problems usually.
Speaker 1: I mean, my stomach's not the best stomach.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that is true.
Speaker 0: That is true.
Speaker 0: Well, I mean, I'll take like unbuffered aspirin, like fuck it and I'm fine, but not everyone has that luxury.
Speaker 1: The point is, you know, if pain is, I guess, I don't know if my pain tolerance is high, but like- Or you've just never experienced true pain.
Speaker 1: Well, I've experienced pain, but the point is, I feel like, you know, most of the pains I have, you know, have had are not so severe that there's any point in, you know, even this pain.
Speaker 1: It's been nagging and long, but it has only once been like, once did it get bad enough that I considered like a Tylenol.
Speaker 0: You have to worry, though, because if it's been around for a while, usually there's some underlying cause that isn't just like old men.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like, I want you to identify this cause.
Speaker 1: So, doctor said it's a spasm, right?
Speaker 1: I have no reason to disbelieve, right?
Speaker 1: You know, that's what the doctor said.
Speaker 1: So, you know, it's like, alright, take these drugs or whatever.
Speaker 1: So, I took them, and buggin' nothin' happened.
Speaker 1: Aren't like, you know, if you take, like, if you take a pain killing drug over the counter, do you feel effects in the short term?
Speaker 0: Yeah, like if I take an aspirin within an hour, whatever, like, pain I have is usually gone.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so he gave me basically what is the prescription equivalent of Aleve, I guess, stronger, or just more of it per pill.
Speaker 1: Alright.
Speaker 1: And it had no effect whatsoever.
Speaker 0: Well, maybe your spasm's bad, or you just probably gotta go back- It feels the same as it has.
Speaker 0: Yeah, maybe you should go in for a follow-up.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean, you know, I only went there, like, yesterday.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we'll give it a few weeks, but I- But, I mean, I'll, you know, I'll keep takin' it, but if nothin' happens- I'm just sayin', if I had to guess, it's the hunch.
Speaker 1: Well, the point is, either, you know, I'm not talkin' about this particular problem anymore, right?
Speaker 1: But, rather, you know, my skepticism of painkillers in general is that either I'm some kind of freak and they don't work on me at all, or they don't work, period, and there's placebos for everybody, I'm inclined to believe both of those things.
Speaker 0: Nah, but possibly what happens with some, depending on the situation, is a drug isn't actually tailored to that kind of pain, and you can take a different drug, or, for whatever reason, you have resistance, gotta take more of a drug.
Speaker 0: Like, for whatever reason, when I got my wisdom teeth out, it took more anesthesia than normal to put me down.
Speaker 1: I mean, you know, that is a painkiller that I use.
Speaker 1: It's usually a local anesthetic, right?
Speaker 1: The dentist.
Speaker 1: That's the kind of painkiller that I use.
Speaker 0: If I work out and I even just have, like, a headache, I'll just take an aspirin.
Speaker 1: But I was thinking, like, there have been, you know, I'd rarely get headaches, but, like, there was a time where I had a headache that was, you know, annoying enough to do something about it.
Speaker 1: I took a Tylenol or whatever, it didn't do fuckin' anything, I still had the headache, I feel like the Tylenol didn't do shit, and painkillers are a bunch of bullshit.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't know, when I take a Tylenol...
Speaker 1: Is it because I take them rarely that they don't, you know...
Speaker 0: No, there's not really a thing like that.
Speaker 1: I take them, like, you know, I can't even remember the literally, it must have been at least ten, maybe not even, when was the last time I took any painkilling drug, even over the counter, that wasn't a local anesthetic for at an office?
Speaker 1: I took some this morning, 'cause I did
Speaker 0: not break my finger, but I bruised it severely, and I've been self-treating, because with sports injuries, which it's like, sports injuries are like this one subset of injuries, where you almost all the time, if you can correctly identify, like, the problem yourself, unless it, like, gets out of certain bounds, like, very clear guardrails of when that's okay, there's literally nothing a doctor can do for you that you can't do on your own, as long as you know what to do.
Speaker 1: Well, the point is, I rarely take them, now, you know, this is the first time I've taken one in several, several years, and the fact that it did nothing leaves me being skeptical about its efficacy, at least on me.
Speaker 0: Well, I'm sorry, I think you need a higher dose, or go back to your doctor and say it didn't work.
Speaker 1: If I take all these drugs, and it doesn't work, I'm definitely gonna go back, and be like, hey, my arm still hurts, I took all these drugs, and at least the drugs were very inexpensive.
Speaker 0: I will bet you money.
Speaker 0: it's the hunch, in the end.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm, well, what are you gonna do?
Speaker 0: Yeah, 'cause I don't think it's an acute biking injury, because you can get a thing with, like, hunch shoulders from biking too much, but it's not biking season, you haven't biked much.
Speaker 0: So, uh, yeah, in some news, there's actually some pretty big gaming news, that, uh, it's one of those things where, in retrospect, a lot of people probably saw it coming, but no one specifically predicted it, but,
Speaker 1: basically- Well, I saw it coming, but then it took so long that I sort of forgot.
Speaker 0: But I didn't see, I didn't see Final Fantasy Flight Interactive just shutting down, I saw Fantasy Flight having a problem.
Speaker 0: I saw that, too.
Speaker 0: I don't feel like Fantasy Flight is a super healthy company, not that I don't know anything about their inner workings.
Speaker 1: I know about it.
Speaker 0: I mean, like, I don't know their corporate details, like, I don't know- I do.
Speaker 0: What do you know?
Speaker 1: So, Fantasy Flight was started by the guy who made fucking Twilight Imperial and everything.
Speaker 0: No, I'm talking, like, what's their revenue, what's their expenses- Oh, it's a private company, you don't know that.
Speaker 0: Uh, yeah, those are the things we can't know.
Speaker 1: Anyway, it was started by that guy, and by all accounts, based on reports from former employees, sites like Glassdoor, et cetera, it was a really toxic and shitty place to work.
Speaker 1: Uh, not in necessarily- I'm not saying not at all, right, but the reports I saw weren't about things, like, that you would expect in the modern times, like, sexism and harassment type things, but more like micromanaging and being stupid, making stupid decisions and those sorts of things.
Speaker 0: My only point is that we don't know the details.
Speaker 0: All we have are anecdotes from people who no longer work there, who have talked about it publicly or semi-publicly.
Speaker 0: Oh, people who did work there reported also, right?
Speaker 1: But you could see all of those reports about it just being a bad, you know, sort of culture, you could see those reflected in their games.
Speaker 1: For example, one notable incident in the Netrunner days, right, was there was a card that was clearly OP.
Speaker 1: Big time OP card, right?
Speaker 1: And the thing is, we know there are playtesters of this game, right?
Speaker 1: And even though they were supposed to not say they were playtesters and keep secrets, right, they wouldn't.
Speaker 1: We got lowdowns, right?
Speaker 1: And then you would see people's names in the credits and it's like, "Oh, yeah, I know that guy.
Speaker 1: He told me that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, okay,
Speaker 1: right.".
Speaker 1: But, uh, so people who will not be named, right, uh, would say things to the, you know, it would leak out in the community, "Oh, yeah, we playtested that card and all of us said that card was hella
Speaker 1: OP.".
Speaker 1: And it got changed during playtesting, but then when the card came out, printed in the final pack, it was back to its original thing.
Speaker 1: And the story that was told, right, unverified story that was told, was that, you know, I guess the game designers made decision X and then they, you know, the management was like, "You know, for some reason, wanted, you know, the card to be sexier and more
Speaker 1: powerful.".
Speaker 1: It's kind of micromanaging nonsense, right?
Speaker 1: And, you know, that's just a small thing if that even happened.
Speaker 1: But, you know, that matches the kind of thing, right, that you, and when you look at their games as a whole, right, as a company, they mostly produced, the games that they produced themselves, right, in-house, tend to not be this very few in-house games that are any good.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, like, to be perfectly clear, like, in terms of our taste in games, uh, if a game happens to be, like, published by Fantasy Flight, eh, fine, whatever.
Speaker 0: They do a good job with that.
Speaker 1: They focus mostly on theme and art, which they do actually a good job of, right, but the game mechanics are bad.
Speaker 1: The good games that they've published are games where someone else has made them and they've published it.
Speaker 1: Like, they're the publisher of Atticus and Euphrates, right?
Speaker 1: Or, games where, like Netrunner, where, yeah, the original game was made by someone else and then they brought it in and mixed it up a little bit.
Speaker 0: And slowly killed it.
Speaker 1: Right, like Netforge, Netrunner, Keyforge, yes, and slowly killed it, right?
Speaker 0: Keyforge was the fastest I went from "I am interested" to, like, halfway through my first and only play of Keyforge, I got bored.
Speaker 0: I was like, oh, oh.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but, you know, they did start back in the, remember, XCOM the board game?
Speaker 1: So, they started, you know, an interactive- We own that, don't we?
Speaker 1: I got rid of it.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 1: They started an interactive division, uh, to make software.
Speaker 1: Not that long ago, like, in- Around the time XCOM came out, and I thought that company was mostly gonna be making apps to accompany games, like, like Xcom.
Speaker 0: Yup.
Speaker 0: A link to Rock Paper Shotgun, they have a decent article about it, but basically in 2017, they founded Fantasy Flight Interactive, specifically to make digital versions of their own core and card games.
Speaker 1: Right, I think it was also to make things like the XCOM app.
Speaker 1: But anyway, the thing that they've been making and working the most on was a digital version of the Lord of the Rings, uh, LCG.
Speaker 0: Seems to be the only game they've released.
Speaker 1: Yes, I don't think it even finished, like, I don't know if it's still beta or incomplete or whatever.
Speaker 1: I never- And I also heard from people that it was a significant departure from the original card game.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Like, it wasn't exactly the same thing.
Speaker 0: But anyway- I didn't run into people who had positive opinions of it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, nobody really played it that much at all.
Speaker 1: It didn't, you know, even some of the minor, you know, like, you know, digital card games, it's like the top tier of digital card games has got to be like Magic Arena and Hearthstone.
Speaker 1: You go to the next level down and you got your Gwent's and those sorts of things.
Speaker 1: And I guess Duo List used to be a thing like that, maybe in the third tier.
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 1: This thing, I don't even know what tier it got to, but it wasn't even third.
Speaker 1: Well, 'cause like- Definitely below third.
Speaker 0: Lord of the Rings fandom is not at, say, a high watermark right now out in the world.
Speaker 0: Right, well then- And Hearthstone and other games exist, so unless this game brings something else to the table, it's a little too, little too late.
Speaker 1: Anyway, Fantasy Flight mostly made most of their money on licensed things, and they lost the Games Workshop license a while back.
Speaker 0: Yup.
Speaker 1: They lost the Netrunner license, which is what killed Netrunner, otherwise it would probably still be going.
Speaker 1: And mostly they've been leaning on the Star Wars license, but some of their Star Wars stuff is hit or miss, right?
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 1: So the Star Wars Destiny, like the dice game, they killed that today, which is after the layoff news, right?
Speaker 1: The original Star Wars LCG, I think, died a while ago.
Speaker 1: But I think X-Wing is really their big money maker, 'cause that thing keeps going, and you see those things everywhere.
Speaker 1: Even in Barnes and Noble, they got X-Wing.
Speaker 1: So a lot of people are playing X-Wing somewhere still.
Speaker 1: But anyway, so a while back, they got acquired by Asmodei, a much bigger game company, and we were like, "Oh, that's the end of
Speaker 1: them.".
Speaker 1: That's when I thought it was the end of them, right?
Speaker 1: They were just gonna be absorbed, and you know, I thought it was more of like a- Well, it was a- A higher- I think it was the things like get their licenses, you know, and that sort of thing, right?
Speaker 1: And then, you know, that head guy, the guy who actually I think was, you know, the Twilight Imperium guy or whatever, who I don't think was a positive impact, judging by the corporate culture stories, but I think he left, right?
Speaker 1: So it's like, "Okay, that seems like a positive
Speaker 1: move.".
Speaker 1: But yeah, since like those times, like those, you know, since the Netrunner times, like Netrunner ended, they got acquired, it's sort of been downhill, like you haven't seen, you know, good, big, positive news about them come out, like they haven't announced- you know, other than Keyforge- Well,
Speaker 0: what's also notable is you don't see a lot of negative- like you don't see people like complaining about a change in Keyforge or something.
Speaker 1: Well, no, no, what I'm saying is that- well, you're not paying too much attention to the Keyforge community, I'm not either.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So you don't know what they're saying in there.
Speaker 0: But usually you see that at least like fly by in social media.
Speaker 1: Right, but other than Keyforge, they haven't announced a new game, they haven't had another big success, like what else are they even doing, right?
Speaker 1: And now it's like, "Okay, we're laying people off, we got rid of the interactive thing that wasn't going anywhere, you know, we're ending the Star Wars dice
Speaker 1: game.".
Speaker 1: And it's like, "Oh yeah, that's totally expected.
Speaker 1: I saw that coming back when you got acquired/merged.
Speaker 1: Why is it taking this long?
Speaker 1: I thought they would work
Speaker 1: faster.".
Speaker 0: Okay, so in 2019, just by looking at Wikipedia, so I may be wrong, the only things they released were 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7 expansions to the X-Wing game.
Speaker 1: Yeah, okay.
Speaker 0: Or to Star Wars Legion.
Speaker 1: I told you that- oh, Legion's different.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so it's to Star Wars Legion, they released like a Landspeeder and an AT-ST and a Tauntaun Rider.
Speaker 1: Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Speaker 1: But anyway, miniatures have the biggest margins, they make a lot of money on them.
Speaker 1: But they also- people don't- I don't know how many people know, Fantasy Fight also makes RPGs, they have like this system, is it called Genesis or something?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: It's some kind of system that might as well be D&D as far as I know.
Speaker 1: I don't think it has a lot of, you know, I mean it's obviously not the same rules-wise, but I don't think it's meaningfully different.
Speaker 1: It's clearly not like an indie RPG where it's a storytelling thing, right?
Speaker 1: But they produce sort of like GURPS, right?
Speaker 1: They use that system for several games, you can get a Star Wars or a Cthulhu, you know, several different role-playing settings.
Speaker 0: I'll admit I've never even like looked at the mechanics or rules for these things.
Speaker 1: Yeah, nobody plays this thing, which is why they also pretty much shut that down.
Speaker 1: because, yeah, no one buys it or plays it.
Speaker 1: So what's really
Speaker 0: interesting, just like looking at these articles, is that one, it's very clear, like the stated mission of Fantasy Flight Interactive was not to make the Lord of the Rings game, it was to make digital versions of their physical games, which if they- The Lord
Speaker 1: of the Rings game is a digital version of one of their physical games.
Speaker 0: Well, yeah, but the game's plural.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they did one.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well, they did one, didn't seem to succeed with it, didn't do any more, but it also seems like this was shut down as part of just more general broad layoffs across the whole merch company.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it seemed like basically they're just like, "Okay, let's shut down all the stuff that isn't making any money, that's unpopular, and we'll just focus on the stuff that actually does make money.
Speaker 1: Everyone else get out of
Speaker 1: here.".
Speaker 1: Keep the keyforged rolling, keep the X-wing rolling, all these games we have that no one fucking plays, like these RPGs, get that shit out of here.
Speaker 1: Which means, okay, all you people who are working on those things, goodbye.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, so I never actually looked at this Lord of the Rings digital thing, but yeah, all these comments here are like, "It's mystifying that it chose to abandon both the original design and the business model of the tabletop Lord of the
Speaker 0: Rings.".
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: So arguably it wasn't actually an implementation of a physical game, they just made this different game that was similar.
Speaker 1: So... That's what I heard.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't know if I feel like this is just going to slowly fade away.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 0: Like, I don't know what's going to happen.
Speaker 0: Will Asmodee just slowly eat it, and it'll just disappear entirely?
Speaker 0: Like, what's going to happen?
Speaker 1: I have no idea.
Speaker 1: It's one of those, you know, it's like, it's usually, I think the one success of fantasy, well, I mean, the one thing that makes fantasy play different from other board game companies, right, is that, well, at least what I see in the community is, what's another board game company?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I mean, it's funny because I think mostly in terms of the names of designers, I actually don't care who publishes a game.
Speaker 1: Right, exactly.
Speaker 1: And that's the point, is that other, you know...
Speaker 0: Like, I think Andrés Zafar, I don't care who has the Puerto Rico license right now.
Speaker 1: Right, other game publishers usually don't have a fan, someone's not a fan of a publisher.
Speaker 1: They're usually a fan of a game or a designer, and they follow all the games a person makes, or they follow all the games in a series regardless of who makes and publishes them.
Speaker 0: Or the people who follow games that are based on an IP, based on the IP alone.
Speaker 0: They still don't care who made the game or even what the game is.
Speaker 1: But I actually know a lot of people who are, like, Fantasy Flight fans who are like, if Fantasy Flight makes a game, they're checking it out.
Speaker 1: Like, they're following the company.
Speaker 1: They go to the Fantasy Flight World, you know, game championships.
Speaker 0: I feel like I know of people like that, but I don't know people like that.
Speaker 1: Well, I know people like that because I was playing Netrunner.
Speaker 1: But it's like, there were people, like, they played Netrunner, and they were like, oh, Star Wars LCG, oh, Game of Thrones LCG, oh.
Speaker 1: And like, any time Fantasy Flight had a thing, like, they were into it, and they were, you know, not playing other companies' games as much.
Speaker 1: It was kind of like a thing.
Speaker 0: But meanwhile, people like us, we literally are like, what game is Cole Warrell going to release?
Speaker 0: Like, where is he?
Speaker 1: I was not interested in any Fantasy Flight game that wasn't Netrunner.
Speaker 1: That was developed by them.
Speaker 1: They published some games, like we said, Diggers and Euphrates.
Speaker 1: But games developed by them, there are almost none games developed in-house by them exclusively that I say are good.
Speaker 0: I guess the two takeaways are, big swaths of the tabletop industry globally are probably not doing that well right now.
Speaker 1: Well, you know, there's mad supply.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we've talked about this a bunch of times on the show.
Speaker 0: And two, I feel like if you care about tabletop games, you should focus on who is designing games as opposed to who is publishing games.
Speaker 1: But I think there are even people who are good designers.
Speaker 0: But then they work for, like, the design stable in a publisher.
Speaker 1: Right, when they worked at Fantasy Flight, they were stifled by that bad culture.
Speaker 1: So now who knows, maybe the layoffs can fix that culture problem.
Speaker 1: Well,
Speaker 0: one thing I've noticed, this is based on games I'm playing recently, but I feel like a lot of the designers, the games that are doing well lately, at least in our set, are the games that are designed primarily by designers who then either seek a publisher or partner with a publisher, as opposed to games that come out of a publisher or a studio that has a stable of designers that then release a game.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean, we also like games primarily for the mechanics of the game.
Speaker 1: We don't care if it's a fantasy or a Warhammer or a cyberpunk, even though cyberpunk is the best.
Speaker 1: We don't care about that too much, whereas Fantasy Flight as a company puts the theme first.
Speaker 1: And then mechanics are just like, yeah, slap whatever mechanics on this game, mostly.
Speaker 1: I mean, they care a little bit, but they notoriously had lots of problems writing rules and didn't fix those problems.
Speaker 1: They kept fucking up.
Speaker 1: It's like they didn't manage their competitive scene well, and they keep fucking it up.
Speaker 1: So it's like the things that you clearly, as a player of their games, you can see where their priorities lie, what you can see what they put effort into, and what they keep messing up and don't correct course on.
Speaker 1: Obviously, the only excuse is they don't care about that that much.
Speaker 1: That's why they keep messing it up, because they don't care to fix it.
Speaker 0: The other thing that I think might happen, but this is pure speculation.
Speaker 0: I don't have any knowledge of this.
Speaker 0: I wouldn't be surprised if companies like Hasbro start to work more toward making those licensed IP games that are one step above the monopoly dross that tends to get thrown out, but probably not even as good as Fantasy Flight.
Speaker 0: I feel like games that are a step or two better than the crap that usually gets IP associated with it will be just above the line to capture the majority of the "I want a game about Star Wars" market, or "I want a game about Doctor Who" or whatever property someone happens to care about.
Speaker 0: I feel like that is going to happen.
Speaker 0: You're going to see larger companies with stables of designers turning out IP-based games, and then you're going to see independent designers or designer studio or designer publisher coalitions.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean, Cryptozoic was all about making the IP-based games, but Fantasy Flight just has a completely different style from them.
Speaker 1: Actually, Cryptozoic games are probably actually worse than Fantasy Flight games.
Speaker 1: Cryptozoic is like take whatever generic game and slap a thing on it.
Speaker 1: Fantasy Flight, I think, is a little different.
Speaker 1: Usually, Fantasy Flight games more often try to make a competitive winning game and not just...
Speaker 0: Well, then you've got the third type of random kickstarted tabletop game that is just atrocious rules, and it's literally only a story and a theme.
Speaker 0: Well, anyway, there's a lot more to talk about here, but that's not what the show is about.
Speaker 0: So, in some other news, awesome games done quick happened.
Speaker 0: It was a good time.
Speaker 1: It's over.
Speaker 1: You'll have to wait until July for another one.
Speaker 0: Yep, I watched a few live, and I'm catching up on the YouTubes of the ones I missed.
Speaker 1: They've been slow to upload to YouTube, so I haven't been able to watch the ones I missed that I want to watch.
Speaker 0: I didn't watch the crowd control Zelda.
Speaker 1: I did watch that.
Speaker 1: That was quite excellent and surprising.
Speaker 1: I thought it would be a shit show, and it wasn't.
Speaker 0: But Super Metroid Impossible was A+.
Speaker 1: I didn't even know what it was.
Speaker 1: I was like, "What the hell is Super Metroid
Speaker 1: Impossible?".
Speaker 1: Neither did I. And I was very surprised by what it was.
Speaker 0: Yep, I think the moment when I realized I went from, "All right, this seems cool," to "Whoa," was when they go down to get the morph ball, and there's those spikes sitting there.
Speaker 0: And then the crowd was like, "Wait,
Speaker 0: whoa.".
Speaker 0: And it only gets crazier from there.
Speaker 0: The other one I enjoyed particularly was The Legend of the Mystical Ninja, because that game is actually just crazy good.
Speaker 1: I've seen speedruns of that before.
Speaker 1: The one I really want to watch that I wasn't able to watch was apparently some crazy shmup that only two people have ever beaten.
Speaker 1: So it's like, "Well, if you beat it and no one else can beat it, then that's a speedrun because no one else is faster than
Speaker 1: you.".
Speaker 0: It'd be like, "I'm number three in the
Speaker 0: world.".
Speaker 1: Right, you don't have to worry about any speedrunning strats.
Speaker 1: If you're the only one who can even beat the damn game, then congratulations, you're the fastest.
Speaker 1: Speedrunning only comes into play once everyone can beat the game, and then we have to do more to go faster.
Speaker 0: And in some last final news, Slay the Spire, as you know, we've talked about it before, is a fantastic single-player roguelike deck builder.
Speaker 0: that's on computers and the Switch.
Speaker 1: Hopefully it'll be on iOS soon.
Speaker 0: And I think the Switch is a better form factor.
Speaker 1: Nah.
Speaker 0: Because the controls are real good.
Speaker 0: You can play that game real fast.
Speaker 1: I can play it faster with my giant iPad, dragging cards onto the enemies.
Speaker 0: I guarantee touchscreen will be slower than the very intuitive and excellent UX of the two sticks.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't want to use any sticks.
Speaker 1: I play on the computer using the mouse.
Speaker 1: Why wouldn't I want to play using a...
Speaker 0: Have you played it on the Switch?
Speaker 1: No.
Speaker 1: Why would I buy it on the Switch?
Speaker 1: I already own it on Steam.
Speaker 0: Because I play it on the go.
Speaker 0: I love the game, but if I'm at home, I'm not going to sit here and play Slay the Spire.
Speaker 0: But if I'm on a train, I'll just play Slay the Spire all day.
Speaker 1: Anyway.
Speaker 0: So, the game is fantastic.
Speaker 0: It's had numerous expansions.
Speaker 0: It keeps getting bug fixes.
Speaker 0: There is a lot of content if you just want to keep playing the game.
Speaker 0: It keeps giving you more challenges and stuff.
Speaker 0: But, they've added a fourth character.
Speaker 0: This has been known for a while.
Speaker 0: The fourth character was coming.
Speaker 0: You can go read the cards.
Speaker 0: It's finally out of its early testing and now it's in a beta where you guys can play the beta and try this character out.
Speaker 1: No, it came out of beta today.
Speaker 1: What are you reading?
Speaker 0: I'm reading.
Speaker 0: this article is from September.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: The news is that this character is in beta.
Speaker 1: If you didn't play on the Switch...
Speaker 0: Because you couldn't play the beta on the Switch.
Speaker 1: If you weren't playing on the Switch and you played on Steam, then you could play the beta version.
Speaker 1: You would have had this character for quite a while now.
Speaker 0: There was a period when there were screenshots of the character and stuff, but it wasn't available in beta on Steam.
Speaker 1: It was released officially today, so stupid people playing a card game on the Switch, like Rym, can now play this.
Speaker 1: finally.
Speaker 1: Even though everyone else has been playing with this character for months on the PC.
Speaker 0: But, here's my warning.
Speaker 0: In a game like this, you don't want to play betas because they tweak the game a lot.
Speaker 1: I played beta for the time when I played it.
Speaker 1: I played beta and it was just fine.
Speaker 0: Have you seen all the changes they made to the game?
Speaker 0: How many cards were just broken and all this nonsense?
Speaker 1: There was never any major brokenness when I was playing beta.
Speaker 0: There was tons of brokenness.
Speaker 0: Have you ever looked at the release notes for this game?
Speaker 1: Yes, I played the beta for many months before you even played the game for the first time.
Speaker 1: And there was never any significant problems and no reason to go play the standard version.
Speaker 1: Everyone played on beta and everyone on PC still plays on beta.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 1: Also, there's another news.
Speaker 1: Is that The Root Guy, Cole Worley, and Letter Games, the people that published The Root?
Speaker 1: They've had this game coming for a while.
Speaker 0: Oh yeah, Oath.
Speaker 1: They had this game Oath that's been coming for a while.
Speaker 1: They've been posting developer blog posts telling you all about how they made the game.
Speaker 1: They've been doing Twitch streams and YouTube vids showing you how the game works.
Speaker 1: They've been all about telling everyone and showing it.
Speaker 1: It's exactly what I tell video game companies to do.
Speaker 1: Just be open.
Speaker 1: Show everything that's going on and that will make people more excited.
Speaker 1: It won't cost you sales.
Speaker 1: You don't have to keep everything a secret and reveal it at the last second like Apple.
Speaker 1: If Apple just told everyone this is the things we worked on today.
Speaker 1: every single day, people would be more excited.
Speaker 1: And here's proof, at least one example of proof, by being super open about everything that's going on with this game.
Speaker 1: People would be crazy excited to play it.
Speaker 1: And today the Kickstarter went live and it funded in like seven minutes.
Speaker 1: There's only one level you can kick, which is $90, but that gets you a ton, a ton of shit.
Speaker 1: And the game is a big ass game, totally worth $90.
Speaker 1: And the way this game works is it's sort of legacy, but not really sort of legacy, right?
Speaker 1: The legacy games we've had so far are games where you have to play a set number of times, preferably with the same exact people, same number of people.
Speaker 1: And you permanently change the game as you go on.
Speaker 1: And then the game is sort of done.
Speaker 1: The way Oath works is you bust it out and play it with one to six players.
Speaker 1: It has a starting configuration and then the game is over and someone wins.
Speaker 1: But then you put it back in the box in a particular way.
Speaker 1: And then when you set it up again, you set it up in a particular way.
Speaker 0: Because you've changed the world.
Speaker 1: And now you just have a different starting position for the next game, even if the next game only has one player or six players or four completely new players.
Speaker 1: You can also reset the game back to its original condition just by reordering some cards or whatever.
Speaker 1: You can learn the details if you watch some videos about it.
Speaker 1: I'm not going to explain them here.
Speaker 0: Or link.
Speaker 0: Because if you Google for Oath game, there's a different Kickstarter for this action MMORPG.
Speaker 1: This is the game.
Speaker 1: You can tell because it has root style art.
Speaker 1: You can't miss it.
Speaker 0: If you see something like action RPG look like MMO nonsense, that's not the game we're talking about.
Speaker 1: They're planning to deliver this game a year from now.
Speaker 1: I totally believe them.
Speaker 0: They're already at almost 500k.
Speaker 1: Yeah, my only concern is if, like root, there were various patches and expansions.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'm really glad I didn't buy root when it came out because they've made a ton of patches to the game.
Speaker 0: This is why you don't play games in beta.
Speaker 1: But I'm expecting this to not have that sort of thing and not need a 2.0.
Speaker 0: Well, because it doesn't need as much balance because it's a different thing.
Speaker 1: It's not right, so I'm like, alright, I'll buy this.
Speaker 1: If there's any expansions or things, I'm only going to get them if we play this a lot.
Speaker 1: But yeah, there you go.
Speaker 0: I'm pretty excited about it.
Speaker 1: Get on that Oath train.
Speaker 0: But anyway, it's time for... Things of the Day!
Speaker 0: So, Scott's got this video about Flushing.
Speaker 1: Yeah, not Flushing, New York.
Speaker 1: Queens.
Speaker 1: So, some company.
Speaker 1: What's the name of this company?
Speaker 0: The YouTube channel is Metacraft Het.
Speaker 1: Okay, some sort of company that makes things.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the high abuse Metacraft stainless steel toilet.
Speaker 1: Right, so this company, I guess, is a stainless steel works of some kind?
Speaker 1: I don't fucking know.
Speaker 1: But they made this toilet.
Speaker 0: A high abuse toilet.
Speaker 1: It is a toilet that can flush fucking anything without clogging.
Speaker 1: And in this video, they show you the various things they flush.
Speaker 0: Five pounds of gummy bears, a twelve inch chocolate long john, two and a half pounds of carrots, seven tampons with applicators.
Speaker 1: And wrappers.
Speaker 1: Right, this toilet flushes anything.
Speaker 1: My only concern is that, you know, they just hooked up this toilet to basically a water pipe and I guess some sort of bucket.
Speaker 1: If you look this up to the actual sewer system, right, obviously the sewer pipes are quite large and that won't be a problem.
Speaker 0: Well, sewer pipes by nature get larger the further in you go.
Speaker 1: Obviously, but the pipe that attaches directly to the toilet is at its, you know, least diameter.
Speaker 1: Lowest radius.
Speaker 1: If that pipe in your house, depending on your house, if the narrowest sewer pipe that connects directly to the output of the toilet is not wide enough, then, and you try to flush six hundred acorns, you might be in trouble no matter how hard the toilet pushes.
Speaker 1: So, I don't know if this is actually a realistic, real world use toilet.
Speaker 0: Well, I think it's just a demonstration to show the power of the toilet.
Speaker 1: Yes, the toilet is quite powerful.
Speaker 0: This is the toilet you put in like a prison.
Speaker 1: Sure.
Speaker 1: But yeah, it is quite amazing.
Speaker 1: It won't clog, which is, I guess, a really great feature.
Speaker 0: Oh, this great YouTube comment.
Speaker 0: This will be good if I ever crap out six hundred acorns.
Speaker 1: Right, yeah.
Speaker 1: My only, the only thing is, uh, who's crapping out six hundred acorns?
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: It's unnecessary.
Speaker 1: But I was surprised that I thought, oh, this probably uses like five gallons per flush or something crazy like that.
Speaker 1: No, it's actually only one point something gallon.
Speaker 1: So not only a little bit more than your average toilet or whatever.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: And I think if you modified this to have like the two different buttons, like the normal button and the crazy button, like a lot of toilets have these days, that then it could be reasonable.
Speaker 1: Like, oh, listen, I just peed and did a little poop.
Speaker 0: Small button.
Speaker 1: There's six hundred acorns in here.
Speaker 1: Large button.
Speaker 0: Now, I didn't look at this.
Speaker 0: I don't know if it has like a UNEC in it or if it relies on special sewage stuff.
Speaker 0: And it also doesn't have a tank.
Speaker 0: It needs like pressurized water, it looks like.
Speaker 1: Yeah, no, it's not a tank based thing.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: This is more like a public toilet, right, where you just push the lever and it goes with it.
Speaker 0: So my thing of the day is, you've probably seen a bunch of old timey footage of New York City from like 1911.
Speaker 1: I've seen this particular footage that you're showing.
Speaker 0: Well, you've seen some pieces of this footage because this was all cut together from a bunch of different archival sources.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I can't be sure I've seen all of it, but a lot of it looks very familiar.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: The problem is, if you watch archival footage, a lot of it looks familiar.
Speaker 1: This is only so much.
Speaker 0: But this is some very high quality footage of New York City.
Speaker 0: It's a trip around New York City from 1911.
Speaker 0: But they did something clever because a problem with looking at old time footage is that our brains look at it and it feels either unreal or it feels old timey.
Speaker 0: And it makes it hard to place it in the context of.
Speaker 0: that was a real place in color with real people living normal lives.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: There's the lack of color, but there's also the speed just because of the way old cameras work.
Speaker 0: It's flickery and stuttery and it's too fast and too slow and there's no sound.
Speaker 0: So what they did, it's a subtle change, but they stabilized it.
Speaker 0: They got rid of the flicker and they made it speed accurate.
Speaker 0: So it's at the actual speed of this day in 1911.
Speaker 0: And they added sound fully.
Speaker 0: That's like obviously not super realistic, but realistic enough.
Speaker 0: There's a little bit of a wooga.
Speaker 0: And I've never seen footage of like an old city with all those factors that makes it feel so relevant and real.
Speaker 0: And it is almost, it's so weird to watch it because like this one random thing I just got to.
Speaker 0: I know where that fence, that fence is the same fence as there today.
Speaker 0: And people sit there the same way.
Speaker 0: they sat there in 1911.
Speaker 0: The only difference is back then there was this elevated train that we got rid of.
Speaker 0: There's some cars around, but the cars are not faster than the horses.
Speaker 0: There's more horses than cars.
Speaker 0: And my favorite moment is many times you see the footage cut away suddenly.
Speaker 0: And right before it cuts away there's some kid who like walks over and sees the camera.
Speaker 0: And is clearly about to go fuck with the camera.
Speaker 1: Right, well I mean cameras are super relatively rare then.
Speaker 1: So the kid sees one and at a time when there's no video games.
Speaker 0: You see a lot of people look at it and are like, "Hey, ooh, camera,
Speaker 0: ah.".
Speaker 0: The other cool thing is you see a ferry go into a ferry terminal that we don't use anymore.
Speaker 0: But that you see anytime you ride in a ferry on the East River.
Speaker 0: This building here, you know this thing?
Speaker 1: Yeah, I know.
Speaker 0: Like it's not used anymore, but it looks literally the same now as it did then.
Speaker 0: I wouldn't be surprised if that same old...
Speaker 1: Wait another hundred years and people watch footage of us on YouTube right now talking.
Speaker 1: And they're like, "Wow, look at those old fashioned dudes
Speaker 1: podcasting.".
Speaker 0: Yeah, old timey dudes.
Speaker 0: Why do people use, what's that thing they're talking into?
Speaker 0: I wouldn't be surprised if this ladder's still there.
Speaker 0: In the meta moment, we've been at a lot of conventions.
Speaker 0: So check our YouTube channels for videos of some of the panels we've done.
Speaker 0: But this weekend we're going to PAX South.
Speaker 1: The Southern PAX.
Speaker 0: And at the Southern PAX on, when is our panel?
Speaker 0: Friday at 4 p.m.
Speaker 0: in the Bobcat Theater.
Speaker 0: We're doing an all new panel.
Speaker 0: We've done the 47 Club Games.
Speaker 0: It's 100% new.
Speaker 0: It is.
Speaker 0: I mean, you've seen the slides.
Speaker 1: It is not a new idea, so therefore it is not new.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 0: Anyway, it is.
Speaker 0: We've done this panel, the 40 Tabletop Games You Should Play.
Speaker 1: Wait, wait, you just said it's an all new panel.
Speaker 1: Then you just said we've done this panel.
Speaker 0: No, we've done this panel, the 40 Tabletop Games You Should Play, which is about if you want to understand what tabletop games are, and you want to be a broad-minded person who, it's not even all games we like.
Speaker 0: If you want to experience what tabletop has to offer, here are 40 games that will put you in 40 radically different directions.
Speaker 0: It's sort of like a list of.
Speaker 0: we think you should play all these games, have a broader understanding of games.
Speaker 0: This one does not include even one game from that list.
Speaker 0: Instead, it is.
Speaker 0: here are 41 games that we personally think you should play because they're neat for some specific reason.
Speaker 0: The rationale is, I mean, if you could submit panels, your panels never get accepted, so I don't know what to tell you.
Speaker 1: Yeah, because my panels are meaningful content and not just clickbait.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but you still put a clickbait title because that's the only way to get people in the room.
Speaker 1: Meaningful content is not so popular because people are anti-intellectual.
Speaker 0: I think this content is equally meaningful, though.
Speaker 1: No, I don't think so at all.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 1: I think this is like a BuzzFeed list garbage.
Speaker 0: So, you don't believe that anyone can ever give anyone a recommendation on what games they should play?
Speaker 0: Ever?
Speaker 1: I believe that this kind of content is low brow and low effort.
Speaker 0: That curated collections, like say, I don't know, First Look, have no value on this Earth?
Speaker 1: First Look has value in that.
Speaker 0: It's just a curated collection.
Speaker 0: It's just, here's six newish games you should play.
Speaker 1: The curation is not the value.
Speaker 1: The value is you cannot get these games.
Speaker 1: Here are games that you cannot otherwise play and are unavailable.
Speaker 0: I would argue that the curation is more the value because they don't bring the obviously crappy games to First Look.
Speaker 1: All right, so instead of First Look, what if they just had tables set up of all kinds of games?
Speaker 0: That would be fantastic.
Speaker 0: If there was an area that is set up the same way as First Look, but it wasn't new games, it's old games, but it's a curated collection of games that people should check out and learn and play with teachers.
Speaker 0: Would you ever go in that area to play a game?
Speaker 0: Hell yeah.
Speaker 1: I would not.
Speaker 1: There is no reason for me to go in that area.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: So you don't ever want anyone to recommend a game to you, apparently?
Speaker 1: I know what's good.
Speaker 0: Do you?
Speaker 1: I do.
Speaker 1: That's why you're listening to me.
Speaker 0: But you're the one who always tells people not to listen to you.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if you think there's no value in listening to me, go away.
Speaker 1: What are you doing here?
Speaker 1: By the fact that you're listening to this, that is an admission that what I have to say is something you believe in and is worth hearing, which means you believe I'm right just by listening.
Speaker 1: So if you don't believe that I'm right, go away.
Speaker 0: Okay, Old Man Scott.
Speaker 1: That's the only way to prove that I'm wrong is to not listen to me.
Speaker 1: Otherwise, you're admitting I'm worth listening to, and I know more than you.
Speaker 0: Anyway, moving on from Old Man Scott.
Speaker 0: We will also be at PAX East.
Speaker 0: It's going to be a good time.
Speaker 0: And this is the last episode we're ever going to record with...
Speaker 1: That's the last episode we're ever going to record.
Speaker 0: The old Mackie mixer that I bought in 2013 to replace an even older mixer that broke.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: So... Rem loves spending the money.
Speaker 0: No, I do not.
Speaker 1: It ain't broke.
Speaker 1: Don't fix it.
Speaker 0: Well, it is broke.
Speaker 0: The problem is...
Speaker 1: How broke is it?
Speaker 1: One... We're recording with it right now.
Speaker 1: How broke can it be?
Speaker 0: So, one of the preamps doesn't work anymore at all.
Speaker 1: Well, we're not using that one.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so I'm missing one.
Speaker 0: Two, the auxiliary bus is an analog pipeline, which kind of sucks.
Speaker 0: And, you know, I have to keep fussing with the OBS stream so the volume's equal.
Speaker 0: I got this giant compressor I want to get out of my house because I don't want analog pipelines anymore.
Speaker 0: The new one is tiny.
Speaker 0: The new one costs a third what the Mackie costs.
Speaker 0: And, holy shit, the preamps on this new thing are, like, night and day.
Speaker 0: And most importantly, the new thing?
Speaker 0: Dead at USB-C, meaning I can take the PCI Express FireWire card that barely works and sometimes crashes my computer.
Speaker 0: I will go from one legacy FireWire device in my life to FireWire does not exist in my life anymore.
Speaker 1: It is good to see that, thanks to USB-C, the audio companies are now producing a lot of USB-C audio equipment.
Speaker 0: Because 90% of USB audio devices can take, at most, two digital inputs, meaning they're literally worthless.
Speaker 1: It looks like you bought some kind of PreSonus thing.
Speaker 1: PreSonus is a real good brand.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I saw in the forum this company, Solid State, which has no relation to Ghost in the Shell, they're usually known for making, like, the enormous boards you see in music studios.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean, like, Mackie makes those, too.
Speaker 1: Right, but I'm saying, like, they're, like, one of the top makers of those.
Speaker 1: Like, you know, like, real music people are like, oh, yeah, that's a good one.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: They've made really tiny USB-C things that are, like, good for, like, two microphone, two headphone.
Speaker 1: It's like, if you're starting a podcast today, that thing is something you should check out.
Speaker 1: Like, that is, you know, real good.
Speaker 1: It's USB-C, two headphone, two microphone.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: What else do you need?
Speaker 1: Nothing.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: We need more microphones, because sometimes we have listeners on the show, or, like, we have guests on the show and stuff.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the one you bought is what, like, four, eight?
Speaker 0: It's four by default, but it has eight at input, so I could actually put, like, another eight onto it if I needed to.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 1: Oh, you can add on more, like, with another?
Speaker 0: I can add on more, yeah.
Speaker 1: Oh, okay.
Speaker 1: But, yeah, well, I mean...
Speaker 0: Because you can't use two different sound devices unless they are synced, and that is something that most people, like you listening, probably don't know what that is or how that works, and that is not worth learning.
Speaker 1: We don't need to talk about that now.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So, I'll be interesting to see what Geek Night sounds like, because I have to make a whole new pipeline, but I'm kind of excited, because...
Speaker 1: I'd be interested if anyone could tell blindly.
Speaker 0: Mostly, the only benefit will simply be that I will have...
Speaker 1: It takes up less room in your room.
Speaker 0: A lot less room in my room, good lord.
Speaker 0: It'll also use a lot less power.
Speaker 1: That's good.
Speaker 0: And it's small and USB-C, so if we do, like, a big video at Scott's house, or, like, on the field, I can just bring this and put a whole bunch of microphones for a video.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but we want to get the output into the camera to get the...
Speaker 0: There's a lot of really easy ways to do that.
Speaker 1: There's some desync between our mouths flapping.
Speaker 0: That is not a problem with modern equipment, and also, I have XLR in on my camcorder, which makes an easy sync.
Speaker 0: So, I'm real excited to set this up, because there will be zero analog... I can throw away my insert cables.
Speaker 0: If you don't know what an insert cable is, thank Satan.
Speaker 0: And in the last Metamoment, the Book Club book is The Tale of Genji.
Speaker 1: I am reading it.
Speaker 0: I'm also reading it.
Speaker 0: I am learning all the myriad ways that Genji's kind of a dick, and it's kind of... I don't know if I like Genji so far.
Speaker 0: I hope this is the tale of Genji being better.
Speaker 1: It's the tale of Genji, for sure.
Speaker 1: It's the only thing that is a tale about.
Speaker 0: There's three ways this could go.
Speaker 0: It's the tale of Genji being better, it's the tale of Genji being shitty to the end, or it's the tale of Genji getting his comeuppance.
Speaker 1: I think I remember, for being the first novel, I think it was more like a serial.
Speaker 1: I don't think there was an overarching plan from the start.
Speaker 1: It was written over such a long period.
Speaker 0: I hope Genji just dies a third of the way, too, and is never mentioned again, and it just keeps going.
Speaker 1: I get the feeling that there's people whose entire job is being a scholar of this book, but I get the feeling that it was just sort of made up as they went along.
Speaker 0: Kind of like how, when I first read, when I was young, The Count of Monte Cristo, I didn't know how it ended, and reading a really, really long serial can be pretty fun if you literally, honestly don't know where it's going.
Speaker 1: Well, also, from what I've heard, it doesn't necessarily end.
Speaker 1: It just sort of- Well, no, there's a chapter, spoilers, way late towards the end, like Genji is no more, and then there's a couple chapters of the people who are still around, like maybe his kids or something, I don't know.
Speaker 1: And then it ends abruptly, I guess, when the author died, or when we couldn't get any more, or I don't know.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: Something like that.
Speaker 0: I feel like it's just the one piece of its era.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well, it was also the first one.
Speaker 1: You can't be the one piece of your era if you're the first one.
Speaker 1: One piece is the tale of Genji of this era.
Speaker 1: So,
Speaker 0: as great as this game is, we don't have to talk about it that long, but we were at PAX Unplugged,
Speaker 1: and- Well, even before PAX Unplugged, a lot of the enforcers, you know, they scouted out at BGG Con, which was just- To make
Speaker 0: a curated collection to recommend to you what games to play?
Speaker 1: No, to get new games that are otherwise unattainable.
Speaker 1: They went to Essen and BGG Con, and the game they raved about that was new and unattainable was Nekosu Dice.
Speaker 0: So, first look at Unplugged- It was sitting there next to Goats and Goats.
Speaker 1: Right there, Goats and Goats.
Speaker 1: There it was.
Speaker 0: And I'm like- Oh yeah, Oats and Goats is the speedrunner.
Speaker 0: Goat and Goat is the goat game.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: So, I go and I'm like, well, that's the game.
Speaker 1: I can't play otherwise.
Speaker 1: Let's play it.
Speaker 1: And we read it, and oh yep, it is definitely the bomb.
Speaker 0: Then we played it, and it's telling.
Speaker 0: 'Cause I kept taking people over there and teaching it to them.
Speaker 0: I was sitting there teaching random people to play it at one point.
Speaker 0: I've never played a game in first look like that many times before.
Speaker 0: 'Cause usually I go to first look, I play a game- Usually it's hard to get into first look.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but once I play a game in first look, it's like, okay, I know the deal.
Speaker 0: And then I just buy the game or something.
Speaker 0: But there were a lot of other games I could've played at PAX.
Speaker 0: I kept going back over to play Nekosu Dice with different people.
Speaker 0: So, here's the pitch.
Speaker 0: It is a trick-taking card game.
Speaker 1: A lot like, you know, Euchre Hearts, Wizard, Bridge, one of those.
Speaker 0: So first, I'm gonna explain it very briefly, the way I would explain it to someone who knows trick-taking games.
Speaker 0: It's a trick-taking game with Trump.
Speaker 0: You bid on how many tricks you're gonna take, but there's a mechanism for that bidding.
Speaker 0: You have to follow suit.
Speaker 0: You don't have to, Trump, unless you want to.
Speaker 0: But, you get a hand of cards.
Speaker 0: And then you draft a bunch of dice, and the dice have the same set of suits as the cards.
Speaker 0: So, my hand might be the four of blue and the two of white and the three of yellow.
Speaker 0: And in front of me, I might have rolled a three of yellow and another three of yellow and a six of blue.
Speaker 1: The cards go-- And then when it comes around to my turn to play a card into the trick, I could play a card or a die.
Speaker 0: Scott leads a blue six.
Speaker 0: That's a die.
Speaker 0: I play a blue four.
Speaker 0: That's a card.
Speaker 0: Emily plays a blue two.
Speaker 0: That's a die.
Speaker 0: Like, that's the game.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Well, also, the cards go from one to seven.
Speaker 0: Zero to seven.
Speaker 1: Zero to seven.
Speaker 1: And the dice go-- And the dice go, obviously, one to six.
Speaker 1: So, if you roll out, if you've got a six yellow die in front of you, and you push it out, someone plays a yellow seven, it's like, well, no dice is going to beat that.
Speaker 0: So, here are the other thing, like, the final pieces of this.
Speaker 0: This is, like, the unique part of the game.
Speaker 1: Well, you've got to remember that "nokosu" in Japanese, I guess, means
Speaker 1: "leftover."
Speaker 1: It's all about the leftover dice, right?
Speaker 1: So, when you draft, you start by shaking up all the dice and spilling them out.
Speaker 0: You take a few away, and then you shake up the rest.
Speaker 1: Everyone starts with two random dice, but then you shake the rest.
Speaker 0: Well, not all the rest.
Speaker 0: You pull a few out, so it's a little different every time.
Speaker 1: You shake the rest that you're going to use, and everyone takes them one at a time in a draft, right?
Speaker 1: And the one that's left over is Trump.
Speaker 1: Whatever number and color that die is is Trump.
Speaker 1: So, if the blue three is left over, blue is Trump, and three is Trump.
Speaker 0: The best way to think of it is that all threes are now also blue.
Speaker 1: Yep, except for the blue three, which is now god tier.
Speaker 0: So, there are some games that have superior and inferior Trump.
Speaker 1: If you made a video game out of this, what you would do is, if Trump turned out to be blue three, suddenly all the blue cards and all the threes would turn gold, and the blue threes would turn crazy, right?
Speaker 1: Like on fire with sparkles, right?
Speaker 1: Because now they're all in the same suit together.
Speaker 1: So, even a yellow three would be in the same suit as a blue two, or a blue one, or a blue seven.
Speaker 0: Now, if you've played a lot of trick-taking games that have complex Trump, then this game, it's not a problem.
Speaker 0: We saw people who have not played games with complex or multifaceted Trumps before had trouble remembering that the twos were blue and the blues were two.
Speaker 1: I think I had a little, only a minor amount of trouble.
Speaker 0: It was funny.
Speaker 0: You would fuck it up, and then you would explain the rule to everyone, and then fuck it up again.
Speaker 1: I understand the rule perfectly.
Speaker 1: I blame it slightly because we played the original from the box, official Nekosi dice, and I only had a tiny bit of trouble.
Speaker 1: We only messed it up a little bit.
Speaker 0: Obviously, the game is- I made an AirSats version of this game out of some Shik'El cards and a bunch of dice.
Speaker 1: The game isn't out yet, right?
Speaker 1: Actually, there was a pre-order that sold out within a day.
Speaker 0: Now there's another pre-order.
Speaker 1: There's going to be another pre-order tomorrow.
Speaker 0: I'm getting in on it.
Speaker 1: We'll post the link for that pre-order for anybody if you can go fast enough.
Speaker 0: If it's not clear how excited we are, this game is a must-buy.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and it's going to be super cheap.
Speaker 1: But anyway, we played with Rims hacked together copy using whatever dice-.
Speaker 0: Now I know what you're about to say, but I looked at the pictures of the real cards and real dice and my copy.
Speaker 0: There is no material difference.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I can't tell you a specific difference between them.
Speaker 1: that was meaningful, but we did mess it up more with the put together copy than the original one.
Speaker 0: I think I figured out why.
Speaker 0: I was thinking about that a lot.
Speaker 1: When we were playing it in first look- I can't tell you why because it looks the same to me.
Speaker 0: When we were playing it in first look, we played it super slow because we had all just learned it.
Speaker 0: And every time we played it, we played it again super slow and everyone was paying 100% attention.
Speaker 0: And at MagFest, I just kept buzzing out on the table all the time.
Speaker 0: I played it like seven or eight times.
Speaker 0: You could be.
Speaker 1: Who knows?
Speaker 0: And I kept playing it with random groups of people, but we played it more like we play wizard or like normal games.
Speaker 0: Like people would get distracted or talk to each other.
Speaker 1: You deal out the cards, you get two random dice, you draft the rest of the dice.
Speaker 1: The last die.
Speaker 1: When you're drafting, there is an odd number of dice such that there is going to be one die left over after everyone is drafted.
Speaker 1: That die is the Trump die.
Speaker 1: Then you play the game and what happens is the leftover dice.
Speaker 0: So you've got five dice in front of you and a head of cards.
Speaker 1: You start taking tricks, right, as you would.
Speaker 1: a normal trick-taking game, must follow suit.
Speaker 1: So if I play blue, everyone has to play blue if they have it, otherwise they don't.
Speaker 1: And if you don't, you can play Trump unless Trump was led, in which case follow with Trump.
Speaker 1: If a lot of situations come up where you don't want to follow and you don't have a card to follow with, but you have a die to follow with.
Speaker 1: You have to follow with the die because a die is just a card in your hand.
Speaker 0: So if I see that Scott's got a yellow die and I'm worried that he might be de-suited, I know he's not de-suited in yellow.
Speaker 1: Well, if you know that blue is Trump and you see Rim has a bunch of blue dice in front of him, it's like, well, part of everyone's hand is just open, but only part of their hand is open.
Speaker 0: So here's the final magic that makes this work.
Speaker 1: So after you play, you keep taking tricks and eventually at some point, you, each player, will have one die left.
Speaker 1: You don't get to play that die.
Speaker 1: That die goes aside and now whatever the number value is on that die, regardless of color, is your bid.
Speaker 0: So if Scott has a six and a one in front of him and I play a card that forces him to play the six, his bid becomes one, which might totally fuck him.
Speaker 1: Right, so that bid is you're trying to win exactly that number of tricks.
Speaker 1: So if you're winning a lot of tricks, you want to have a die with a high value on it and not use that die.
Speaker 1: You want to set that die aside.
Speaker 1: Also, if you take more than six tricks, you can never be correct.
Speaker 0: Your maximum bid is six, but there are 15 tricks in a round.
Speaker 0: 14, 14.
Speaker 1: Before you start, after you draft, but before you start taking tricks, you can say, hold up, I want to bid zero, in which case you just pick one of your die and set it aside.
Speaker 1: And now you just play the turn normally and you're trying to take zero tricks, but obviously if you take even one, you've missed.
Speaker 0: So the game is not as punishing as Wizard because Wizard, you only get points if your bid was correct.
Speaker 1: When you play a game like Wizard, you need to be correct, but in Wizard you can bid any number, it's way easier.
Speaker 1: You need to be exactly correct, otherwise you lose points.
Speaker 1: Here, it's way harder to be exactly correct because you have less control over your bid, but if you fail to be exactly right, you still always get one point for trick you take.
Speaker 1: So it's like, okay, my bid was wrong, but guess what, I took 10 tricks, 10 points, that's pretty good.
Speaker 0: If you bid zero and get zero, you just get 10 points, but if you're the only one who is correct in your bid, you get a ton of bonus points.
Speaker 1: Right, I forget exactly how many.
Speaker 0: I think it's 30, 20, 10, 40, something like that.
Speaker 1: So you get 10 bonus points for bidding zero and being correct, on top of the points for being the only person who's correct.
Speaker 1: So if you bid zero and you're the only one who was right, you get a shit ton of points.
Speaker 0: If everyone's correct, they just get the tricks they took, so it's more like a traditional trick-taking game in that taking tricks can never hurt you too much.
Speaker 0: It just might deny you bonus points.
Speaker 0: It can't harm you.
Speaker 1: But the bonus points are so large that that's how to win.
Speaker 1: You're not going to win if you don't get the bonus points, unless everyone is so good that nobody ever gets bonus points.
Speaker 0: Or everybody always gets bonus points.
Speaker 1: Which means it's the same as everyone never getting bonus points.
Speaker 1: If no one ever gets bonus points, then it will just come down to who took the most tricks.
Speaker 0: There's one last nuance that makes the game work, because unlike a normal trick-taking game, there can be ties.
Speaker 0: The only other game that can have ties is wizard, or at least major trick-taking games, where multiple wizards get played.
Speaker 0: And wizard who ever played the first of those gets the trick.
Speaker 0: In this game, whoever, if there's a tie of what's winning the trick, the last card among the tied cards wins the trick.
Speaker 0: So if Scott plays a super high trump, and I tie his trump, and I go after him, I take it.
Speaker 0: It's easier to take tricks, it's harder to duck.
Speaker 1: Right, so there's a lot of difficult situations where, even though people's hands are half open, you just see their dice in front of them.
Speaker 0: More like a third open.
Speaker 0: You have five dice in front of you, and you have ten cards in your hand.
Speaker 1: Let's say blue is trump, and rim starts it off with a yellow too.
Speaker 1: And it's like, alright, I have no yellow, I'm de-suited in yellow, I'm going to play my trump.
Speaker 1: And then I look around the table, and I see the person next to me, just has like a fucking way more powerful trump just on their die, facing up.
Speaker 1: If it was wizard or some other trick-taking game, I would have just played my trump, like bam.
Speaker 1: But I can see a card, or a die at least, that beats my trump just right there.
Speaker 1: I can just see it, and it's like, well, I guess I'm not playing this.
Speaker 0: Yup, and because, the final piece.
Speaker 1: But it's like, well what are you going to do?
Speaker 1: It's like, you wait?
Speaker 1: It's like, yeah, it'll still be there, ready to beat you later.
Speaker 1: It's not like it's suddenly going to go, it's like you're going to wait for them to somehow use it before you use yours.
Speaker 0: It's like if you're playing wizard, and one person is just playing hand open, and you see the wizard sitting there the whole time.
Speaker 1: It's like, how are you going to beat it?
Speaker 1: You see it, that doesn't help you.
Speaker 1: It's like, yeah, you see it, can you beat it?
Speaker 1: No.
Speaker 0: And to make matters even more fun, the trump power order is, first, the item, the card or die, that matches both the color and the face value of the trump, is the super trump.
Speaker 1: Right, so yellow.
Speaker 0: We started calling it the bower, named after Euchre.
Speaker 1: But anyway, the blue three is trump, therefore there is one card that is the blue three, that is the strongest card.
Speaker 1: But there could be several other dice that are also blue threes, that are all equally strong.
Speaker 0: So after that, all the things that match the face value of trump, so all the threes, The yellow three, the green three, the red three, all the other threes, They're equally powered, and slightly less powerful than the one that matches both.
Speaker 1: So blue three is the strongest, yellow three, green three, red three are all equally strong to each other, but subservient to the almighty blue three.
Speaker 0: And then it's numbers down from there, so then the blue seven, blue six, blue five, blue four, blue two, blue one, blue zero.
Speaker 1: Anything that's blue that's not a three comes after that.
Speaker 0: So all these factors combined make this, like, one of the better trick taking games I have ever played.
Speaker 1: Oh yeah, there's just so much going on, you would have to play this for a hell of a long time, with any sort of mastery on it.
Speaker 0: And even if you start to master it.
Speaker 1: But even with the mastery, there's so much, not luck, right?
Speaker 1: There is a little bit of luck against the random dice you pull from the bag, the two random dice that are yours and yours alone for each round.
Speaker 1: But the draft, you just get such a different game every round, it's completely different what's going on.
Speaker 0: Yeah, imagine hearts with, like, drafting, like, whoa.
Speaker 1: Like, different crazy stuff happens each time, because your different colored dice come out, a different one is trump, a different person goes first.
Speaker 1: You know, you draft differently based on the cards and dice, because you already see your hand and your two starting dice before you start drafting.
Speaker 0: Yup.
Speaker 1: So that changes everything, so it's like, it's so fresh and does not get stale at all.
Speaker 0: Yup, and this is where credit to the designer, this is a Japanese game, Yusuke Matsumoto is the designer.
Speaker 0: Genius.
Speaker 0: And this game, I think, is going to open up a whole, I think a lot of people are going to start designing trick taking games, borrowing from this.
Speaker 0: Because my stupid brain had never considered just making dice and using them in a trick taking game like this.
Speaker 1: That's really the genius.
Speaker 1: mechanic is, yeah, the dice are also cards.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like, and this game is three or four player only, I feel like it really only works with four.
Speaker 1: I think, you know, I would also only play with four.
Speaker 1: Well, try it with three.
Speaker 1: Three could be okay.
Speaker 0: Because three player hearts is great.
Speaker 1: Yeah, two and five is right out.
Speaker 0: Yeah, not even allowed.
Speaker 1: No.
Speaker 0: But four player gives this game the opportunity to mod this game in the sense that I feel like you could very easily make this a partnership game and it would be great.
Speaker 1: It could, maybe.
Speaker 0: Because Wizard, as much as I love it, you can't easily make it a partnership game for a lot of reasons I don't have time to describe right now.
Speaker 1: I'd rather play a different game that is meant to be a partnership game.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I feel like this could work as a partnership game.
Speaker 0: I want to play with it.
Speaker 0: I think a lot of clever people are going to play this game once and go, "Oh,
Speaker 0: shit."
Speaker 0: And you're going to see a lot of games.
Speaker 1: You could literally just say, "All right, play the game normal four
Speaker 1: player.".
Speaker 1: And then you add your score to the person across from you and then there's only two teams.
Speaker 1: And that's the only change you make is, yeah, you're partners with a person across from you and you add your scores together at the end.
Speaker 1: So you could basically have, instead of a 25% chance of winning, you'd have a 50% chance of winning.
Speaker 0: But then you've got to also, to make it fun, ban Table Talk and...
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm happy to just play four player.
Speaker 1: I don't feel the need to mod anything.
Speaker 0: Well, I don't feel the need to mod anytime soon because I am nowhere near being a master of this game.
Speaker 0: Not even close.
Speaker 0: Obviously.
Speaker 0: Not that I'm even a master of Wizard.
Speaker 0: I think I'm near a master at, what, Hearts, Euchre, and the list drops off pretty quick after that when it comes to trick taking games.
Speaker 0: Moo still can't fucking play well.
Speaker 0: My skill in Moo is just random.
Speaker 1: I feel like there's no reason to play Moo if you have an Akosu Dice.
Speaker 0: Well, I think Moo brings different, more things.
Speaker 1: Moo is very, I'm not saying it's similar, right?
Speaker 1: It is very different and crazy.
Speaker 0: Moo has a more complex trump.
Speaker 0: Moo has a superior and an inferior trump.
Speaker 0: And Moo is a coalition game, but it's coalitions formed in the course of bidding.
Speaker 1: I'm aware, but the point is, in terms of, I'm in the mood to play a kind of meaty trick taking game and not just a sort of baby one.
Speaker 1: It's like, I'd always rather play Akosu Dice than Moo, so even though they're mechanically not equivalent and there's reasons for them both to exist, there's just no situation where I would feel like playing this kind of game and choose Moo over Akosu Dice.
Speaker 0: See, I would, but I'm way more into trick taking games than you are.
Speaker 1: I'm pretty into trick taking games.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you won't play Euchre with me.
Speaker 1: No, it's a stupid game.
Speaker 1: Euchre's fine.
Speaker 1: Why would I play Euchre when I can play Akosu Dice?
Speaker 0: You wanna play Wiz?
Speaker 1: No, it's a stupid game.
Speaker 1: I would rather play Akosu Dice than you.
Speaker 1: I would rather, but Akosu Dice is just better and it serves the same purpose.
Speaker 0: So, but I guess the real thing I would say is that...
Speaker 1: You're asking me to go eat at like, you know, McDonald's when it's like, but I have meat right here.
Speaker 1: I could make a delicious burger on the grill.
Speaker 1: Why would I go to McDonald's?
Speaker 0: No, McDonald's would be playing straight Wiz.
Speaker 1: I'm just saying, it's like there's no purpose even though, right?
Speaker 0: No, McDonald's would be playing Go Fish and calling it a trick taking game.
Speaker 1: You get the idea.
Speaker 0: But I guess in terms of trick taking games, Wizard is still the one to use to get your friends who have never played a trick taking game to try them out and realize they like them.
Speaker 1: Yeah, Akosu Dice is not an entry level, right?
Speaker 1: You need to understand too many different game thing.
Speaker 1: It's not that it's hard where it's pro gamers only.
Speaker 0: Good Lord, I taught this to someone who didn't know how trick taking games work.
Speaker 0: That is real fucking hard to do.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: It's just that you really, you know, if you want to be able to play this well and not be confused all the time, you know, you learn hearts.
Speaker 1: You need to understand just the concepts of drafting and taking.
Speaker 1: So it's like if you haven't played any drafting or trick taking games before, go play Sushi Go Seven Wonders, you know, Wizard Hearts.
Speaker 1: Yeah, go play those to learn.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: It's not.
Speaker 1: this isn't some advanced crazy game only for geniuses.
Speaker 1: It's just as the complete entry level can be confusing if you don't have the previous prerequisite knowledge.
Speaker 0: So if I had to say like the minefields or the moods I'm in to play trick taking games, if I want a very pure game, I'll still just go to Hearts.
Speaker 0: Hearts is my go to.
Speaker 0: That game is great.
Speaker 0: If I want an interesting experience that's really going to pull me in right now, no, Akosu Dice, because there's nothing like it.
Speaker 0: If I want an elevated partnership nonsense game, I'll play Moo.
Speaker 0: And if I just want any trick taking game, I'll default to Wizard because Wizard does take more players than Akosu Dice.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I guess that's the time to play.
Speaker 1: Wizard is if you have five or six people.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: And honestly, Wizard's not as fun with four players unless it's four people who are semi...
Speaker 1: Wizard is definitely the best with more players because it's fewer rounds.
Speaker 1: When you play Wizard with too few players, there's too many rounds.
Speaker 1: It takes too long.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: Now I do like that, but if I'm going to play Wizard with four players, I kind of want to play Hearts more because Hearts is more pure and despite... Hearts will go faster in the end for a lot of reasons.
Speaker 1: Hearts is way faster.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Well, unless someone won't take their turn, but that's a different problem.
Speaker 1: How could you not take your turn in Hearts?
Speaker 0: It's so simple.
Speaker 0: I've known some people.
Speaker 0: Well, when we played Hearts for money in middle school, some people would take a long time on their turn.
Speaker 0: We were playing for like pennies.
Speaker 0: We weren't high rollers.
Speaker 0: But Nokozu Dice, like I cannot stress enough, it was for us and for a lot of people in tabletop and first look like the breakout game of PAX Unplugged.
Speaker 0: I practically guarantee it's going to be in first.
Speaker 0: look at PAX South and you should go play it.
Speaker 1: I don't know if it will be, but we'll have our made up copy.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'll bring the Ersatz copy.
Speaker 1: The pre-order will not have arrived yet.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: This has been Geek Nights with Rim and Scott.
Speaker 0: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design, and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at FrontRowCrew.com for show notes, discussion news, and more.
Speaker 0: Remember, Geek Nights is not one, but four different shows.
Speaker 0: Sci-Tech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays, and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: Geek Nights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: Geek Nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 1: But unlike those other late shows...
Speaker 0: And the Patreon patrons for this episode of Geek Nights are... Why is the Patreon manager taking longer to load than it normally does?
Speaker 0: Oh, because they've changed the UI.
Speaker 0: I'll have to look at that later.
Speaker 0: As I said before, many times I never... Oh no.
Speaker 0: Maybe I have to read this a different way now.
Speaker 0: That's the mistake I made by starting this recording.
Speaker 0: I will never edit this piece.
Speaker 0: Here we go.
Speaker 0: Alan Joyce, Craig Oliver, Heidi McNichol, JustLikeADudeGuy, Kishore Thompson, Link Iji, Hydrated Gannon, Support Songkong, Chris, Midkiff, MyStacy.com, Jay Band, Sean Yeager, Nicholas Braddow, YouHoldTheQuayToMyHeart, 421 Creations, Started Making Trouble In My Neighborhood, Trevor Mutharl, Superboy, Clinton Walton, Remt from New Zealand, Ryan Perrin, Dropenlander, Finn, Dread Lily, Tenebrae, Sean Klein, Chris Reimer, Thomas Hahn, and like 40 other people who don't want me to say their names out loud.
Speaker 0: And now, this will be our last show before or after PAX South because we're flying to PAX on Thursday.
Speaker 0: We're not going to do a show from the plane.
Speaker 0: I leave you with testing one, two, three, four, five.
Speaker 0: It's Sunday, January 12, 2019.
Speaker 0: I'm Jim, and this is Geek Nights.
Speaker 0: Testing one, two, three, four, five.
Speaker 0: So testing one, two, three, four, five.
Speaker 0: Quieter talking.
Speaker 0: Right up against the mic.
Speaker 0: One, two, three, four, five, six, seven, eight, nine, ten.
Speaker 0: Testing one.
Speaker 0: It's Tuesday, January 13, 2020.
Speaker 0: I'm Ram, and this is Geek Nights.
Speaker 0: One, two, three, four, five.
Speaker 0: Testing one, two, three.