Speaker 1: It's Thursday, May 7th, 2020.
Speaker 1: I'm rim.
Speaker 1: I'm Scott and this is geek nights.
Speaker 1: tonight We're talking about playgrounds like child playgrounds.
Speaker 1: If you have any better ideas for a Thursday show you are welcome to send us those ideas on Twitter or geek nights a front recruit.
Speaker 1: ha ha Let's do this All right, what's been going on in your life by any opening?
Speaker 1: Any anecdotes to talk about in the show?
Speaker 1: any places you've been?
Speaker 1: good restaurants you've eaten at?
Speaker 1: perhaps a bike ride?
Speaker 0: No, none of that.
Speaker 0: so, you know that You know certain things.
Speaker 0: it's like we're not Completely out of things here, right?
Speaker 0: It's like if you need TP you can get TP.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, I just ordered a giant crate of TP from a restaurant supply company, right worst case You can get some low-quality stuff, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, like the grocery store has almost everything in stock still.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but one thing that you know, we can get but we can't get the good stuff is paper towel, right?
Speaker 1: Oh So that you know, I do have stuff to say because we way back bought some super organic compostable like easily degraded like environmentally friendly paper towel and It was so bad.
Speaker 1: It was unusable.
Speaker 1: Like if you got it wet, it just disintegrated into nothing.
Speaker 0: So yeah, we bought some paper towel.
Speaker 0: That was some shady ass brand and you could tell right out of the package that it was flimsy and thin.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I was going to pat dry some some meats, right?
Speaker 0: And the paper towel came apart and like disintegrated into the meat like a seasoning.
Speaker 0: So that happened with a soggy paper towels on my meats that I had to pick off with my fingers.
Speaker 1: I used a fork to like scrape it off because it was embedded in the meat.
Speaker 1: We might have used the same shitty toilet paper paper paper towel.
Speaker 0: You're using toilet paper.
Speaker 0: that explains why you're disintegrated.
Speaker 0: that explains all your problems.
Speaker 1: Yep It was that paper towel definitely paper towel.
Speaker 1: that paper towel was so bad really shitty that we put it aside bought entirely new paper towel and I kept it.
Speaker 1: the sole thing I Was gonna use it for was to like clean up grease spills when I'm working on my bike or something like that.
Speaker 1: Like.
Speaker 1: I was just gonna use it for like garbage tasks.
Speaker 1: But then this happened.
Speaker 1: and guess what paper towel I've been using in the kitchen off and on the shitty one.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you got to get some more of the good stuff because the shitty stuff is like it's just not working.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the worst thing is not like.
Speaker 0: that's like.
Speaker 0: it's a pretty first-world problem, obviously but it's still.
Speaker 0: it's like the difference between the good stuff and the not good stuff was More extreme than you would expect.
Speaker 0: I mean, it's notably different.
Speaker 1: I would believe that because it's not a matter of like, oh this one's nicer, but the environmentally friendly one is Nice enough but does the job?
Speaker 1: it's like it doesn't even do the job.
Speaker 1: You're better off having nothing, right?
Speaker 0: It's not like oh, yeah, I can get to work in a Honda Civic or a BMW.
Speaker 0: This is like imagine if you know a BMW drove and a Honda Civic like lost a wheel on the way to work.
Speaker 0: That's what this is.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Well, I could see you can use cheap toilet paper But the Wegmans one-ply doesn't really qualify as toilet paper.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's not great.
Speaker 1: I think at that point you're better off just taking a shower every time you Do your business and let's what if you're not at home?
Speaker 1: Uh Don't know what you do.
Speaker 1: then if your only option is when the Wegmans one-ply Use the underwear and bail That might be a better option Alright.
Speaker 1: So, uh, there is.
Speaker 1: there's a little bit of news.
Speaker 1: I think you had a news first about some HBO anime biz going on.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's not a huge news.
Speaker 0: But basically HBO max, which I guess is like HBO is the most confusing streaming service.
Speaker 0: I don't use any of their stuff, but they have like HBO go HBO now HBO max.
Speaker 0: It's like all these different services for people who are or are not paying for HBO on cable television.
Speaker 0: And I guess from what I understand I could be wrong about this because it's so confusing as the HBO max is basically, then Netflix competitor of HBO.
Speaker 0: I mean just pay for it.
Speaker 1: I'm not gonna lie HBO.
Speaker 1: Anything is a Yarr situation for me.
Speaker 0: Yeah, pretty much HBO match new streaming platform a twelve dollars a month, right?
Speaker 0: So the news is sort of a Wednesday news that HBO max is going to be Partnering with the crunchyroll and is going to include a handful of crunchyroll anime.
Speaker 0: Not all of them like 17 of them, right?
Speaker 0: But basically the 17 top ones.
Speaker 0: so it's like if you're the kind of person who is an anime nerd You need the crunchyroll because you're gonna be watching stuff that like normal people do not.
Speaker 0: yeah watch ever, right?
Speaker 0: But if you are a person who just watches an occasional anime, you know that the big ones right.
Speaker 0: Netflix has sort of been killing in that department.
Speaker 1: I mean Netflix has like all the great anime.
Speaker 1: They're out like you want to watch Beastars Like anything.
Speaker 0: well, that's a Netflix made anime, but they got like, you know, they got one punch man.
Speaker 0: They got I don't know for some reason.
Speaker 0: They don't have season 2 of one punch, man.
Speaker 0: They got that ghost in the shells.
Speaker 0: They got you know, a lot of the top animes.
Speaker 0: the evangelicals are on the Netflix Whether Netflix makes them or not, but HBO go or HBO max, whatever the hell It's gonna have the top crunchyroll ones.
Speaker 0: So now it's like ah, you know, it's like the Disney Plus.
Speaker 0: They don't have any animes on there, right?
Speaker 0: It's like a no anime zone Right Hulu, I think has a lot of animes actually.
Speaker 0: But that's basically I guess the reason Disney Plus doesn't because that's also a Disney thing Hulu, right?
Speaker 1: I This point what I pay for is Netflix crunchyroll Disney Plus and nothing else.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I mean, that's what I have right now - But we're not paying for the Disney Plus or really using it.
Speaker 1: We're using it cuz we have it for free watching like all the old Disney movies and randomly We watched this old Disney documentary about a squirrel.
Speaker 1: that was better than I expected.
Speaker 0: Okay, sure.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so yeah, if you're the kind of person who wants to watch HBO stuff right, this makes HBO max like something that you wouldn't think of as like, you know, like an actual Well, you think of it as like a tier below the Netflix of the Disney Plus in terms of like streaming services
Speaker 1: Which it is still a tier below like.
Speaker 0: let's not but it but it almost gets it there.
Speaker 1: It's almost like hey Well also remember HBO max is where the new Further adventure times are going to be.
Speaker 1: Oh, that's interesting adventure time distant lands for one hour long Specials.
Speaker 0: Well, I'm sure we can find those on the high seas somewhere.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah the special like.
Speaker 1: we haven't really paid attention to it because it was Intended to be released in 2020 and we don't actually know a lot about them.
Speaker 1: The only thing I remember that we knew I think we even talked about this is there are four episodes.
Speaker 1: They are called in order be mo obsidian wizard city and Together again and suppose all about that wizard city.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 0: Oh, oh this much.
Speaker 1: You know what the plot of that one is.
Speaker 1: peppermint butler goes to school to relearn magic Sounds good to me.
Speaker 1: I am down with that.
Speaker 1: Obsidian is princess bubblegum and Marceline meditate on their relationship on a mission.
Speaker 0: be mo You know, I have almost every adventure time comic.
Speaker 0: Have you read any of those?
Speaker 1: I read a bunch of them.
Speaker 1: Yeah The last one a quest reconnects Finn the human and Jake the dog.
Speaker 1: I guess they go their separate ways at some point and be mo be mo journeys to space.
Speaker 1: We know from the end of adventure time that be mo must come back from space at some point sure But I guess be mo goes to space.
Speaker 1: So, uh, yeah HBO max may have a little bit of a thing going on but this anime news in particular I think will be good for anime as a whole because I think and I see there are a lot of people who Kind of know of anime but are not really anime fans who have ended up watching things like Castlevania or Beastars just because it's on Netflix and Netflix like recommends it to them next to other stuff.
Speaker 1: I feel like HBO max will be a similar situation.
Speaker 1: I think you're gonna see a lot of people who will like bump into Fullmetal Alchemist be like Isn't that that anime thing and watch a little bit and get into it?
Speaker 0: Maybe I wonder if anyone will like start like discover anime from HBO max or Netflix.
Speaker 1: I mean, how did I just go to crunchyroll?
Speaker 1: Cuz how did I discover anime?
Speaker 1: like?
Speaker 1: literally just it was on the sci-fi network one day and I was like, what's this cartoon?
Speaker 0: Pretty much.
Speaker 1: Yeah people younger than us.
Speaker 1: It was just like on Cartoon Network like hey There's the regular cartoons and then there's this good cartoon every day at four o'clock for some reason.
Speaker 1: What's up with that?
Speaker 0: pretty sure people are though or these days are discovering it from internet.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but There are still a terrifying number of not that internet people Sure, so some other news.
Speaker 1: You know, we hate cars, but this the story is wouldn't would be funny if it wasn't so sad.
Speaker 1: So Philadelphia is Basically the poor.
Speaker 1: it one of the poorest large cities and I think it's the poorest and least funded large city in America.
Speaker 0: Like Philly is huge, but you got Detroit.
Speaker 0: God Philly's bigger than Detroit because Detroit collapse Sure, but you got places like, you know mobile, Alabama.
Speaker 1: Those are small cities.
Speaker 1: or relatively small city.
Speaker 1: Philly's actually a pretty huge city like in terms of population.
Speaker 1: There's a lot of things going on with the Philly.
Speaker 1: Philly is a big deal in that regard.
Speaker 1: Don't worry about shit all over Philly cuz.
Speaker 1: Philly's got some problems but Philly has Compared to if you would pretend New York City does not exist.
Speaker 1: Philly has one of the better mass transit systems in America.
Speaker 1: now again I have to stress that's that's like saying oh one of the least smelly diarrhea Is it if you get pooped on by like 10 really awful animals?
Speaker 1: But one of those animals is like relatively clean like a rabbit pooping on you is way preferable to like a cat pooping on you.
Speaker 1: But if the rabbit doesn't exist New York City being the rabbit then you've got your choice of many Terrifying animals to poop on you, but Philly pretending your doesn't exist pretty good transit system Like.
Speaker 1: they actually have a subway.
Speaker 1: They have a bunch of light rail They have a really extensive bus network and a lot of people use it.
Speaker 1: However, that transit system is going completely broke Right now like way worse than normal way worse than the MTA Makes sense.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but you want to know why.
Speaker 1: like the specific riding it No one's riding it, but that would be fine because it's got other forms of funding.
Speaker 1: In fact people riding it barely funds it.
Speaker 1: It's funding comes primarily from tolls on the Pennsylvania turnpike.
Speaker 1: because Philly and Pennsylvania Were actually smart they fund their transit system.
Speaker 1: that can't be funded by the local population because the local population is relatively poor per capita But the transit system is necessary.
Speaker 1: They tax cars to fund transit.
Speaker 1: However, because no one is driving on the Pennsylvania turnpike that now the transit system despite actually being used significantly by First-responders and critical workers has no money because it can't never
Speaker 0: understood why states it seems like every state does this right where they have Specific taxes tied to specific expenses.
Speaker 0: I feel like wouldn't it just make sense to have all taxes go into a common pile of money?
Speaker 0: I can.
Speaker 0: I would then be budgeted out.
Speaker 1: I can tell you exactly why that.
Speaker 1: the reason why what you just suggested is not the case anywhere in America anymore Nor is it the case pretty much anywhere in the world is because of specific corruption in the old that you know The term slush fund.
Speaker 1: just don't be fucking corrupt that you're talking to America.
Speaker 1: How hard is our Supreme Court just ruled that it is not technically illegal to be corrupt.
Speaker 1: That's just because we didn't make laws The convictions with the corruption law because the law wasn't enough to cover this exact Specific kind of corruption.
Speaker 1: the reason the law is not good enough the reason why every municipality in America will take specific tax dollars and say they can be only used for specific purposes is because every time Anywhere in America has ever had general funds The general funds are used to cause evil.
Speaker 1: every time hundred percent evil embezzlement.
Speaker 1: They'll just like cuz then you have like a mayor or a governor or like some city official who's corrupt.
Speaker 1: We'll just be like, yeah, I just won't fund the schools.
Speaker 1: Fuck you.
Speaker 0: No, you can't do that.
Speaker 0: There's a budget.
Speaker 0: you have to money from the general fund has.
Speaker 0: you has to be given out Proportionally to all of the things that are expensive.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so they just set the percentage to zero and there's no law that prevents them from doing that.
Speaker 0: No, the percentage should be set in law when you vote on the budget.
Speaker 1: Yeah Here's the other problem.
Speaker 1: you know all all the laws that get passed to force balance but battles budgets or to force minimum levels of funding.
Speaker 1: the reason those fail is because the municipalities are literally incapable of raising that much money and end up having constitutional crises like every time.
Speaker 0: and then The law should also say yeah, if you don't have enough money all taxes go up Proportionally equally on all things and that also doesn't work for a bunch of other reasons.
Speaker 0: Uh-huh.
Speaker 1: I think that does work Now because the taxes would have to go up specifically only on rich people or you end up driving people out of their town.
Speaker 0: In fact, I've seen situations Should be on rich people.
Speaker 1: Yeah but that's that would never pass because stupid people the only thing stupid people care about more than Themselves is making sure that rich people remain rich.
Speaker 1: well So yeah, Philly's transit system that cannot sell fund and the state refuses to fund.
Speaker 1: the state actually did fund by pet taxing cars But now because cars are gone the transit system that is actually still being used in crucial cannot actually be funded.
Speaker 1: Burma shave the aristocrats.
Speaker 1: So in another really brief news We talked about this on Tuesday that game Valorant the counter-strike II overwatch II like new game coming out from riot As we mentioned it has this dodgy anti-cheat software that is provided by Tencent, which is a giant Probably dodgy Chinese conglomerate.
Speaker 1: I don't want to get into all the reasons why I don't trust that company, but There are now a lot of confirmed reports of that malware and anti cheating software causing all sorts of chaos in people's PCs.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean that was from the start.
Speaker 0: people were saying that you know, this looks like trouble.
Speaker 0: and then afterwards There were several stories of trouble and I guess it's hard to tell which stories are real and which ones aren't Especially because you have people who don't know technology complaining about stuff.
Speaker 0: It could just be some dude installed it.
Speaker 0: then his computer exploded and he's like, oh you see it was the The Chinese government.
Speaker 1: remember remember when our neighbors when we were in college Called campus safety on us because they said we were hacking them because our IPX network frames were being picked up by their firewall.
Speaker 1: Sure, like that kind of shit happened.
Speaker 1: So here's an article that finally actually breaks down these specific Concerns and issues that people are raising about this software.
Speaker 1: so I'm probably not going to play Valorant or even try it despite the fact that the game actually looks okay, and I'm interested in it.
Speaker 0: I Wouldn't play it.
Speaker 0: I wouldn't play any right game.
Speaker 0: Well, it's right is basically in the market of.
Speaker 0: look at popular genres of game on PC and make one of those.
Speaker 0: Yeah, just apply their own stuff to it.
Speaker 0: It's like oh, we'll make a mo.
Speaker 0: There's a moba called dota out there.
Speaker 0: We'll make one.
Speaker 0: We'll call League of Legends.
Speaker 1: Oh and it ended up being more like the bigger one really, right?
Speaker 0: And now they're basically saying oh look, there's an auto chess.
Speaker 0: We'll make one of those.
Speaker 0: Oh, there's FPS.
Speaker 0: It's like any game that's out there.
Speaker 0: They're gonna make one of those.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but as a gamer is nothing original that they make.
Speaker 0: they don't do anything original at all.
Speaker 1: But I mean at the same time counter-strike kind of just action.
Speaker 1: quick too, but slower.
Speaker 0: Counter-strike was at least original in that.
Speaker 1: What about counter-strike source and then counter-strike go and then whatever the next counter-strike will be which is just other versions of counters.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like there wasn't a counter.
Speaker 0: It's like yeah.
Speaker 0: action quake had the die and wait thing.
Speaker 1: It also had the.
Speaker 0: it's like you one hit kills you Yes, but it was action quake was still pretty much every man for themselves deathmatch II kind of situation.
Speaker 1: No, there were two modes.
Speaker 0: The primary mode was five on five Yeah, but counter-strike had the DE and the CES and the you know, as well the oh my god AS or yes Yeah, and FY.
Speaker 0: That was there.
Speaker 1: Really, I mean I assumed FY stood for.
Speaker 1: fuck you Man we can.
Speaker 1: we even didn't.
Speaker 1: even we got into counter-strike on the tail end of AS missions continuing to exist.
Speaker 1: Yeah, pretty much all rig with some good times.
Speaker 1: So yeah Don't like be wary of Valorant even though the game actually looks like it might be good.
Speaker 1: I don't think you want to install it just yet.
Speaker 1: Let's wait and see how many people's computers get grossly violated and or catch on fire.
Speaker 1: but anyway things Of the day.
Speaker 1: What do you got?
Speaker 0: So way back in 1971 there was.
Speaker 0: there was not a.
Speaker 1: there was never in.
Speaker 0: Okay, whatever.
Speaker 0: there was a TV commercial for McDonald's.
Speaker 0: that was quite a production we should say.
Speaker 0: And not having been alive at the time.
Speaker 0: I did not see this commercial when it was on television.
Speaker 1: I've never seen this before until you sent me the link, right?
Speaker 0: I did not have a nostalgic memory for it as I do for many classic commercials that did air when I was still watching Television.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think my earliest like commercial memory is where's the beef?
Speaker 0: Yeah And this come is fabulous high production value for 1971 television commercial Apparently contains famous actors Anson Williams and John Amos who I don't know who they are.
Speaker 0: I had to google who they were.
Speaker 1: Oh, the first recommended video is Johnny.
Speaker 1: John Amos discusses the McDonald's grab a bucket And mob commercial.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but what's interesting is not only is it a singing?
Speaker 0: Dancing musical McDonald's commercial which is you know, pretty fabulous.
Speaker 0: It is also that it's not about the food.
Speaker 0: almost every McDonald's commercial or any food commercial you see these days right is always like You know doctored food photos and you know Get a McRib or a Big Mac or whatever, you know dollar menus and stuff like that, right?
Speaker 0: This is all about look how fucking clean McDonald's is well, or at least the McDonald's in the video is.
Speaker 0: I can
Speaker 1: give a little bit of context for that because the modern concept of fast food was evolving in that era and if you look at the history of Restaurants in the United States like and we've talked about this in cake nights before but like in eras before the 70s There really weren't restaurants that like people would go to the way we go to today.
Speaker 1: restaurants acted very differently in America a long time ago.
Speaker 1: prohibition kind of changed that.
Speaker 1: the evolution of fast food is like you could spend your life just studying the rise of fast food and The restaurant ecosystem that Existed in America in like the 50s and 60s and how broken and filthy and like messed up that ecosystem was.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean, it's funny if you watch like lots of old movies, right?
Speaker 0: The restaurants that people go to are almost always in hotels, right?
Speaker 0: They're hotel restaurants.
Speaker 0: this you don't see that.
Speaker 1: many stand-alone Old movies see three times the restaurants fancy fancy restaurant that may or may not be in a hotel diner or it's a bar.
Speaker 1: The only exception is it's like depending on the kind of piece it is.
Speaker 1: There might be like a local like family style place, but that's it.
Speaker 1: four kinds of restaurants.
Speaker 1: pretty much so in the vein of old Commercials my thing of the day.
Speaker 1: I found this video.
Speaker 1: It's a commercial for a roller coaster.
Speaker 1: It's from 1989.
Speaker 0: We were alive then.
Speaker 1: yeah It's what I have nostalgia for because it's a commercial for the Magnum XL 200 roller coaster That debuted in 1989 at Cedar Point.
Speaker 1: when I was a kid when this roller coaster was built It was probably.
Speaker 0: how did you see that commercial?
Speaker 0: I guess I guess you lived much closer to Cedar Point.
Speaker 1: So you realize when I was a kid, but that's kind of why I made this my thing of the day The entire like multi-state area around Cedar Point.
Speaker 1: if you lived anywhere in like, Wisconsin, Michigan, Ohio, Illinois Every year Before summer people would kind of wait for the Cedar Point commercial because every year Cedar Point would make a new commercial Like a high production value commercial and that commercial would reveal what the new roller coaster was because every year They made a new roller coaster.
Speaker 0: I guess there wasn't an internet to just find out Exactly.
Speaker 1: So like yeah, I remember like there'd be local news stories saying rumors are that after the Simpsons tomorrow We will get to see the first commercial of Cedar Point's new ride.
Speaker 1: We don't know what it is.
Speaker 1: Stay tuned to find out like.
Speaker 0: and none of those news reporters went to Cedar Point with like a camera.
Speaker 1: No, Cedar Point had like fucking security lockdowns.
Speaker 1: They treated a pretty big.
Speaker 0: you can see it from far away I'm sure yeah, but they would hard to hide a roller coaster it is true But they would put walls up.
Speaker 1: Well as far as long as they could during like the early construction they'd cover stuff in shrouds.
Speaker 1: They wouldn't tell anything about the name of the roller coaster.
Speaker 1: And also there wasn't really an internet like news agencies like really just didn't spoil it.
Speaker 1: They'd wait.
Speaker 1: we'd wait for the announcement.
Speaker 0: It was a. we had those two.
Speaker 0: what there was, you know, our commercials were for Six Flags Yeah, a Riverside or other places like that.
Speaker 0: and which rep which became Six Flags New England eventually when I bought it out And those commercials.
Speaker 0: they didn't have a new roller coaster every year.
Speaker 0: Well Cedar Point was crazy and weird like and the commercials that they did show for the specific rides Would be proportional like to the cost of the ride.
Speaker 0: So like when the Great American Scream Machine was made that you saw commercials for that thing for like several years Advertising Anymore as far as I'm aware like around March.
Speaker 1: It would just be like everyone in school like as a kid would be buzzing like Cedar Point commercials coming soon.
Speaker 1: What are they building?
Speaker 1: What's going on?
Speaker 1: Cuz every year they'd have a giant new ride and I remember was notable.
Speaker 1: there was one year was neither 94 or 95 where they didn't actually have a new ride and It was kind of like this weird local existential crisis.
Speaker 1: People were like a cedar point doing okay Why did they make another roller coaster?
Speaker 1: What's going on?
Speaker 1: But I rode this roller coaster when it came out because when it was riding any roller coasters now, nope But it was the tallest and fastest roller coaster in the world by a wide margin.
Speaker 1: like This roller coaster when it came out was a big deal and made international news.
Speaker 1: It took a long time for roller coasters to exceed what the Magnum was capable of.
Speaker 1: This was the first mega coaster, but it wasn't the first giga coaster.
Speaker 1: in the meta moment Not doing much trying to make more content like keep watching our youtubes follow our stuff.
Speaker 1: Join our discord.
Speaker 1: Things are hopping in there.
Speaker 1: Things are hopping more and more in there as I'm trying to remind people to actually go to it actually giving them the link When they ask me starting to try to hang out in there more.
Speaker 1: Forum still rocking.
Speaker 1: We're making content.
Speaker 1: I got my teleprompter set up.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna do something this weekend.
Speaker 0: I don't know if that are you really good to do something?
Speaker 1: I'm gonna do something, but it'll be relatively acid.
Speaker 1: Well, mostly I'm gonna record a bunch of stuff just to make to set up my pipeline to very quickly be able to.
Speaker 1: I'm trying to set up an area in the living room where we're storing stuff because it's not like we're gonna have anyone over anytime soon and Make it really easy to just sit down record a video like me to me talking video Like.
Speaker 1: I want to be able to do that with zero efforts.
Speaker 1: That's what I'm setting up this weekend.
Speaker 1: Mmm-hmm Because you know think about it.
Speaker 1: Imagine how different the things we produce would be if there was a building we could both just go to Like after work or anytime we wanted and there was just a studio and we could both just sit down Hit a button and just start doing something.
Speaker 0: There are places like that.
Speaker 0: You just pay money for.
Speaker 1: yeah, but I'm not paying money for that.
Speaker 1: I got time for that and money for you had to be able to go places exactly.
Speaker 1: So Yeah, I'm not.
Speaker 1: I don't need to have like anyone over to play board games.
Speaker 1: So the board game like kitchen table area is gonna be the.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna be able to talk with the teleprompter area And then maybe I'll just if anything if I upload anything, I'll just upload like my own random teleprompter testing.
Speaker 1: I'm not gonna actually make like a video video yet.
Speaker 1: Maybe I will.
Speaker 1: we'll see Beyond all right playgrounds playgrounds Occupied your idea.
Speaker 1: I mean, did you have a better idea?
Speaker 1: No, there we go.
Speaker 1: But the playground like the playground had this almost mythological and very important like place in my psyche when I was a kid because I couldn't get to playgrounds unless my parents took me to them and They always seemed far away and big and it was like a special deal to go to the playground.
Speaker 1: I always wanted to go to them Partly because they had to think kind of like the arcade even though I had video games at home.
Speaker 1: the arcade had games I couldn't have at home.
Speaker 1: I had toys at home.
Speaker 1: the playground had toys.
Speaker 1: I couldn't have at home, right?
Speaker 0: It's like you have a swing at home and then it's like you go to the playground and there's a fuck it.
Speaker 1: So yeah, the swing at the playground was like the swing.
Speaker 1: I could really hurt myself on his foot.
Speaker 1: I got a slide.
Speaker 0: you got a slide at home But at the playground they had like a giant slide or a spiral slide.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know some mega slide.
Speaker 0: It's like, you know, there's no way unless you were mega rich that you could have something that big and or dangerous at home.
Speaker 0: Yeah equal to what the playground had.
Speaker 0: But nowadays they don't make playgrounds like that anymore.
Speaker 0: I'm an old man.
Speaker 1: Some of the things that are gone Definitely should be gone.
Speaker 1: Those things were just death traps.
Speaker 1: some of the things that are gone.
Speaker 1: I see why they're gone But I want to see a modern Reimplementation of those things.
Speaker 1: like it's a mixed bag on what has come and gone in playgrounds over the years.
Speaker 1: Like I do appreciate the fact that there exists surfaces that will prevent Serious injuries when a child falls from a height.
Speaker 1: that did not.
Speaker 1: that rubbery stuff did not exist when we were kids No, so I usually either fell on sand or more often asphalt and I kind of hurt myself off in it.
Speaker 0: playgrounds or wood chips Or gravel the wood chips that always vaguely smelled like pee or just dirt and grass or sand.
Speaker 1: And we got to separate the school playground from the municipal playground though as a kid We often went to the school playground on weekends because there's no one there.
Speaker 1: It wasn't locked like the cops wouldn't stop us or anything.
Speaker 0: Well, there were certain features, right?
Speaker 0: So like I remember when I went to New York City playgrounds, they would often have like some sort of water feature.
Speaker 1: It's oh, yeah Yeah Like that was not a thing in like Detroit or the Sun like I know like that is a very New York thing to have That water feature in the playground, right?
Speaker 0: But the thing is even nowadays It's like you'd.
Speaker 0: the water features that the playgrounds have are sort of like little crapple sprinklers or something like that.
Speaker 0: Did you see the new?
Speaker 1: because they rebuilt all those playgrounds by the projects north of us like between us My apartment in your apartment along the water.
Speaker 1: There are some pretty big water features in there.
Speaker 0: now No, there are ones I remember like they had like mega like fountain type things or like almost wading pool type stuff Going on.
Speaker 1: Yeah Little bit of that going on in the new part of the playground.
Speaker 0: if you find some old playgrounds that haven't been remodeled Which are becoming fewer and fewer because City Council people love to yeah ribbons on playground.
Speaker 1: Someone told me a while ago that Highland Park like the last great wooden playground that I knew about was finally demolished.
Speaker 0: Yeah but like those If you can find one you can still see some like features that are there but disabled, right?
Speaker 0: There's no water flowing and no one turns it on.
Speaker 1: Yeah, even as a kid They were always like every play get our rent to it had like the features that were still in use But there were like the ruins of the old features Like I remember when I was really really young.
Speaker 1: there was one playground We'd always go to in Detroit and it had like stuff.
Speaker 1: But there were these metal posts with like in cement blocks that clearly were there to hold up like old Seesaws that were not there anymore and as a kid I was vaguely obsessed with like.
Speaker 1: what was there that I never got to play with?
Speaker 0: I Was always like Even at like my elementary school.
Speaker 0: right, it's like we go to the playground and There was pretty early on when I got there like kindergarten first grade They built like a new wooden thing.
Speaker 0: right that was you know, the wooden style castle kind of sit.
Speaker 1: Oh, that's the best the best possible furniture.
Speaker 0: It was one of the earlier ones though.
Speaker 0: So it wasn't that castle II.
Speaker 0: Yeah opposed to some later ones, right?
Speaker 0: It was the early model castle But they put it next to the old playgrounds.
Speaker 0: the old school playground With like just fucking swings and jungle gym seesaw, right?
Speaker 0: Was still there and then there was the new one and then there was a third one That was just like these exercise bits like pull-up bar Right like that sort of thing and not actually play like it wasn't fun.
Speaker 0: Yeah It was like all these exercise things and next to each one was like a board that told you how to exercise on.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, those are all around New York.
Speaker 1: Like those are still like a really common thing.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah boy, like you're an adult who wants to exercise.
Speaker 0: That's great.
Speaker 0: But as a kid When you're a kid is like god damn it, this isn't fun.
Speaker 0: I don't want this.
Speaker 1: It's like discovering that what you thought was a chocolate chip was a raisin.
Speaker 1: You're just like ah, okay.
Speaker 1: I love raisins though Yeah, but if you had the choice between a cookie with a raisin in it a cookie with a chocolate chip in it But not a raisin hater.
Speaker 1: So my favorite feature forever in playgrounds was always the giant wooden playscape like the big wooden castle thing.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but you know those.
Speaker 0: it's weird because it's like.
Speaker 0: it feels Like, you know because of how old I am it feels like that those were newer But actually, you know those.
Speaker 1: they were on the way out even when we were young.
Speaker 0: They started to come into existence when I was in elementary school and they started to fade Right when I wasn't like a school college.
Speaker 1: There was I think it was three mile park in Michigan Detroit and I remember as a kid.
Speaker 1: there was a big construction project and they built this three story.
Speaker 1: Well three kids story not three real stories like.
Speaker 1: it had three levels.
Speaker 1: That's how like giant it was.
Speaker 1: it was basically like it was a structure so big that you could get lost in it and I remember being like utterly dumbstruck the first time I saw it as a kid and my brother and I endeavored to.
Speaker 1: We were eventually found and brought home.
Speaker 1: But I love those things to the point that as an adult I would still play in them.
Speaker 1: I remember vampire tag Like.
Speaker 1: I miss those days.
Speaker 1: if there if there were a wooden playground like that in New York City today I would 100% get people together and play vampire tag in it like without any hesitation.
Speaker 0: The other thing is that like I think we've talked about this in the episode long ago, but like it's sesame place They had you know many things that were you know playground adjacent, right?
Speaker 0: So there was like this cargo net thing that existed that I think was torn down at some point because obviously there's no way that That's safe enough for anyone in the year 20.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I love those things.
Speaker 1: I had one at Cedar Point that we would always be all about Right.
Speaker 0: It was almost like, you know McDonald's play place on crack.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right just like extreme, right?
Speaker 0: It was like several stories tall tons of nets all over the place tubes You know, it was like, you know, I don't remember if they let adults in there.
Speaker 0: I think they did but it's like how did you get in there?
Speaker 0: There's such narrow tube ways and stuff.
Speaker 1: Yeah, Cedar Point had a place called I think it was King Arthur's something like Camelot something but it was on the roof of this other ball pit building and it was basically just a giant one of those with cargo nets everywhere and basically zero supervision.
Speaker 0: Yeah type sesame place cargo net into into Google image search and you'll see what I'm talking about.
Speaker 0: Yeah How crazy this thing was.
Speaker 1: so get this.
Speaker 1: I was googling for pictures of the old wooden place That's and I found a whole bunch of pictures that look Identical to the one we played vampire tag out at RIT and I learned something in All of New York like much of New York State other than New York City Almost every wooden structure and playgrounds was made by one company Leathers and associates in Ithaca.
Speaker 0: Yeah I mean that makes sense because when you went to different towns to see their different playgrounds They all looked pretty much the same and had the same pieces arranged in different ways.
Speaker 1: But Leathers was the company that made the one that was good for vampire tag Specifically and I thought I just looked at all these pictures of their play sets.
Speaker 1: They all look like Highland Park and they all look amazing.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so other than the giant structures Like what was your favorite thing in the playground?
Speaker 1: Like what was well, like what would you say is the top tier playground thing?
Speaker 0: Well, I mean it all depends right because it you know If you're if you like swing is a good swing, right a good swing But it's like if it's a shitty swing I don't care.
Speaker 0: so right.
Speaker 0: or it's like you have a good slide or a shitty slide, right?
Speaker 0: So it's like I don't prefer swing or a slide But I just if it's good then it's good.
Speaker 0: if it's not good.
Speaker 0: It's not good I think it might.
Speaker 1: my favorite feature like ever was large tire swing like the ones that were big.
Speaker 1: Mmm, you know, we have like a tire hanging from the roof because they felt more dangerous than they were and they required a moderate Amount of skill to not hurt yourself, but you wouldn't ever really hurt yourself too badly Unless they were installed badly like I remember as a kid like I love these tire swings.
Speaker 1: We even had one but we had some friends and they had a tire swing they'd made and their tire Swing was way too close to the trunk of the tree.
Speaker 1: It was hanging from.
Speaker 1: It was very easy to hit that trunk.
Speaker 0: Well, but also if you put it further away down the branch the branch might snap.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's got to be a real good tree to make that kind of tire swing.
Speaker 1: but and the playground?
Speaker 1: I did like the one that was like a tractor tire hanging sideways like hanging from three chains that would spin.
Speaker 1: mmm.
Speaker 1: Yeah, my mate my main go-to as a kid was to climb inside the tire and get someone else to spin it as fast as Possible.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: That's a that's a good one.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but yeah, that's the thing It's like.
Speaker 0: so rather than say like which feature was the best right?
Speaker 0: What makes a good one, right?
Speaker 0: What's a good slide from the bad slide, right?
Speaker 0: So for me the best slide is a slide You'll never find these days, which is the solid steel.
Speaker 0: heats up in the Sun will burn you slide.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but just Ridiculously tall.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: That was my favorite.
Speaker 1: That was my favorite thing by far.
Speaker 0: There was one that I don't know how ridiculously tall they actually were when I was a kid.
Speaker 0: right because I haven't seen any That's still standing back went to my memory.
Speaker 0: Is that the tall slides were fucking tall?
Speaker 1: There was a slide so tall in a playground.
Speaker 1: We used to go to in Detroit as a kid.
Speaker 1: I remember one point I looked up.
Speaker 1: apparently it was like 30 feet tall and it was notably tall like Like.
Speaker 1: people knew how tall it was because parents thought it was a problem and wanted to turn down.
Speaker 1: But it was tall enough to where the ladder to climb up to it was cage.
Speaker 1: So you couldn't get on the outside of it and fall off and there was a cage around the whole top Until you actually slid down the slide a little bit and then there was no more cage.
Speaker 0: I'm looking I'm looking at like some websites about dangerous old playgrounds and you can see how tall the slides were.
Speaker 0: and it's like Oh, yeah, they were as tall as I remember pretty like what you think.
Speaker 1: Oh, I was a kid.
Speaker 1: How tall could they have been?
Speaker 1: you go to his adult and you're like, I'm actually kind of afraid of that as an adult.
Speaker 0: Yeah as a kid, it wasn't a fry wasn't afraid of it at all.
Speaker 1: Yeah Some of the changes they've made make sense because as a kid we had a play set like we had one of those things.
Speaker 1: It's like two tees with monkey bars in the middle and like a thing hanging off of the ends like in our backyard Like that was our mini play set.
Speaker 1: But as a kid, I remember one day I just like climbed up on top of it and I stood up on the tee.
Speaker 1: So now I'm standing like almost 14 feet off the ground and I just jumps.
Speaker 1: I had like just I into the ground with no thought about why I was doing this or whether or not it was dangerous.
Speaker 0: Here's a picture of an old metal slide.
Speaker 0: It says on on sunny days without shade the metal slide could get up past 160 degrees.
Speaker 0: And here's a 35 foot tall spiral slide.
Speaker 1: Oh, I like the spiral side.
Speaker 1: The problem was the spiral slide.
Speaker 1: if you make it out of like modern safe materials Do you go too slow and they're actually not fun at all?
Speaker 1: If you make them out of metal while they're fine and fast they get so hot that they are dangerous Like I don't I do.
Speaker 1: I do not miss the fact that I multiple times got blister burns from slides.
Speaker 0: as a kid Like I was there and on them all the time.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think that was a problem, but there was this era where they started making slides out of plastic.
Speaker 1: But the plastic you'd slide really fast on it.
Speaker 1: but I remember the problem was that style slide.
Speaker 1: you would generate a Massive static charge by sliding down.
Speaker 1: and I remember one time as a kid.
Speaker 1: I was in like third grade We had one of these at the school.
Speaker 1: The school ended up getting rid of the slide because other kids kept hurting themselves on it the same way I did.
Speaker 1: I Slid down it and when I got to the bottom I went to stand up and my right arm touched a metal bolt that was like recessed in the slide holding it together And I got a static shock.
Speaker 1: so bad my entire arm went numb and I couldn't move it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it makes sense.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the school actually got rid of that slide.
Speaker 1: It only existed for like a month and then they got rid of it, but it was perhaps so fast.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think if you want to really talk about danger I mean maybe in just Anecdotally the one you see people hurting themselves with the most on the internet is the merry-go-round where you can freely.
Speaker 1: Those have to be banned solely because kids are too stupid to use them safely Like they don't understand how dangerous that actually is.
Speaker 0: Yeah It's like you spin it around as kids want to spin it as fast as possible and jump on.
Speaker 0: Yeah
Speaker 1: And the problem is if you get a kid who's smart enough to come up with a way to spin it faster But not smart enough to Understand the improve the increased danger of spinning it faster like turning a bike sideways and putting the wheel up against it We did that a few times.
Speaker 0: Well, I mean you can just deal with.
Speaker 0: you know The laws of physics.
Speaker 0: right is like if you can somehow increase the you know, you start with a large radius spinning, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, so you get the spin coming from the outside and then you get everyone to get towards the inside.
Speaker 1: Yep We did the same thing.
Speaker 0: or it's like even if you're just spinning alone on like say the tire swing that you just mentioned.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: It's like you stick your legs out you spin.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you tuck them in.
Speaker 1: We oh we had this kid Chris.
Speaker 1: I remember we were hanging out in the playground one day when we were kids and we Got the tire swings.
Speaker 1: We wound it up.
Speaker 1: We got a spinning so fast that it spun for a while and when it stopped spinning Chris was literally passed out in it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, makes sense.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like the blood just like went out.
Speaker 1: He's just like passed out.
Speaker 1: He was fine, but that that could have been a problem Theoretically could have been a lot of problems.
Speaker 0: and it's like, you know, I think oh, you know, we my whole life I was on these dangerous, you know survivor bias like we just got lucky.
Speaker 0: Well, it's not even survivor bias.
Speaker 0: It's like if I think back it's like yeah We survived.
Speaker 0: but it's like there are basically injuries and band-aid situations like on a daily basis.
Speaker 1: Yeah Like I remember like I think back to when I was in elementary school Like how many kids had broken arms like in any random class?
Speaker 1: I was in compared to how many kids have broken arms in any random elementary school class.
Speaker 0: today It's a safer time like yeah, it's like when I was in school there was as someone had a cast on at like all times.
Speaker 0: there was always some kid in the class of the cast that we could draw on and Seeing kids on the street.
Speaker 0: today I don't see a lot of cast like I remember in Because those kids are not out on the street because they can't they're having injury.
Speaker 1: But there were like five or six five or six kids broke their arm in My class in fifth grade during that one school year and all but one of those breakages were on the playground during school.
Speaker 1: But I think my favorite thing to do in the playground like my go-to was always the swings and Generally, I just tried to swing as high as possible and I was always chasing the.
Speaker 1: I want to go over the bar Like I was one of those kids who tried.
Speaker 0: you wanted to go over the bar.
Speaker 0: Okay I just I wanted to jump off the swing.
Speaker 1: So I did jump off the swing all the time.
Speaker 1: We'd go for distance We'd have distance competition.
Speaker 0: Oh, yes, that's actually.
Speaker 0: that's absolutely what we do.
Speaker 0: even at home We would go for distance.
Speaker 0: at home We went for distance.
Speaker 0: so much so like, you know The home playground the home swing set was concreted into the ground.
Speaker 0: Yep, but we would swing so hard that like some of the concrete Like jump like to do the same thing happened.
Speaker 1: We we started at the bottom like where the poles that held our first place set up Started to bend and deform and they were kind of broken and we had to replace it because we'd cause damage to it.
Speaker 1: No But yeah, and that we we have my brother and I and like we had at the playground We always had distance contests.
Speaker 1: a lot of kids hurt themselves with those distance contests not in the landing Like I don't think anyone ever like broke a bone on the landing.
Speaker 1: but multiple kids cut themselves badly because when they jumped they like didn't fully let go of the swing and would get caught in the Chain in some fashion.
Speaker 0: I think that was the real danger, right?
Speaker 0: It's like if you successfully jumped it's like you would go forward and as long as there wasn't anything out there for you to hit Besides ground.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you had a nice kid body.
Speaker 1: You could land pretty sure a kid body landing on grass Like.
Speaker 1: you were fine 99% of the time unless you got really lucky.
Speaker 0: but yeah if you if on your release if either you Didn't release enough or if your clothing got caught on the chains or anything like that, then you could be in trouble.
Speaker 1: I saw a lot of really bloody cuts because of that.
Speaker 1: I cut myself pretty badly a few times with that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think there were actually a lot of swing sets Even the dangerous ones.
Speaker 0: they put rubber coverings on the chains.
Speaker 0: Yeah prevent a lot of those types.
Speaker 1: my parents put those rubber coverings on the chains of our home swing set and they were always that Came with them.
Speaker 0: Oh, it just came that way out of the box.
Speaker 1: Not bad.
Speaker 1: The thing is that's a solvable problem.
Speaker 1: I remember the first time I saw in an anime that Japanese style swing set where instead of a chain It's like bars with chain links on the ends of them.
Speaker 0: That would be so much self issues.
Speaker 0: You just ropes.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the problem is the ropes.
Speaker 1: so many kids would get rope burns on their hands because they wouldn't quite let go on the jump.
Speaker 1: You know, it's better than a chain true But the ropes also would get damaged.
Speaker 1: I remember one day We don't know if anyone got hurt but one day we went out to recess and I remember one of the swings was broken.
Speaker 1: the rope had just like Broken at the top and snapped.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I just find it kind of funny how you know.
Speaker 0: It's like playground.
Speaker 0: the dangerous ones existed for a super long time, right?
Speaker 0: It's like our parents had playgrounds and they were kids right?
Speaker 0: Yep, and I don't know if their parents did or not.
Speaker 1: They did.
Speaker 1: I've been looking up some histories sure and so.
Speaker 0: but those adults right the generations before us Right, so boomers and older right as they got older Most of them didn't really have seemed to like recreate the playground in any way, right?
Speaker 0: It's like they would you know do other stuff, but it seems like our generation and younger.
Speaker 0: It's like what are people doing?
Speaker 0: They're rock climbing right?
Speaker 0: It's like what the hell is that?
Speaker 0: It's a fucking playground, right?
Speaker 0: It's like you fooling anybody.
Speaker 0: They're going to the ropes course.
Speaker 0: It's like what the fuck is that?
Speaker 0: Hey fooling anybody?
Speaker 0: That's a fucking playground for adult size, right?
Speaker 0: It's like who you fooling, right?
Speaker 1: So it's interesting that I don't know our generation in general of experiences matter more to us than things.
Speaker 0: I don't know if the people younger than us who had Who came after the wooden castle playground right into the land of the safe?
Speaker 0: But still potentially fun playground because they still see kids having fun on those.
Speaker 0: Yeah They must be good.
Speaker 1: the playground by Vernon Jackson near us.
Speaker 1: like if it wasn't it literally illegal for me to enter that playground I would go in there and play.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, that's if there is.
Speaker 0: the playgrounds weren't illegal for me to go in I would go in.
Speaker 1: yep.
Speaker 0: But yeah, the they're clearly having fun on those even though they appear much safer.
Speaker 0: this so there wasn't like, you know This imagined danger fun trade-off that I think is just not real.
Speaker 0: but I wonder if those kids on those will a Have that same Nostalgia and or even it whether it's a nostalgia or not, but have that desire for a playground when they're older Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: And also I wonder how many kids outside of cities where there's a lot of playgrounds how like as the playground Interest decreased because of internet like our kids still playgrounding How many suburban kids still have playground in their swing set?
Speaker 1: I mean, I do think back to when we were at Disney several years ago me and Emily for someone's wedding.
Speaker 1: And while we were there we were like we've ran into this family.
Speaker 1: we're kind of near them for a while and their kid had a like op tablet out and was watching a YouTube stream of someone playing Minecraft and gave zero fucks about Disney and was pissed the entire time that they couldn't just watch the stream and that they had to walk around Disney while they watched the stream.
Speaker 1: Uh-huh, I Just remember that as a moment pure Anecdote.
Speaker 1: it like I don't know because the playgrounds at least in New York completely full all the time except now obviously.
Speaker 1: Yeah Like the one in Vernon Jackie, you can't find a place.
Speaker 1: So I saw something interesting.
Speaker 1: I'm skimming through the Wikipedia to see if there's like anything any notable things about playgrounds.
Speaker 1: and there's this whole idea in like the research around playgrounds that one of the primary values of a playground for children is that Adults and parents Feel like they control the playground and thus and it feels like a place that's relatively safe for the kids.
Speaker 1: So they tend to get lax in their attention leaving the kids more unsupervised than the parents realize.
Speaker 1: but how simultaneously?
Speaker 1: That's actually the primary value.
Speaker 1: playgrounds have two children because it gives them less supervised time to explore boundaries more without Significantly increased risk with only slightly increased risk.
Speaker 1: and there's like real study around that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that seems accurate to me because when I was on the playground it definitely felt like, you know much like at the public pool.
Speaker 0: It's like yeah your parents bring you there They sit on the side and then you're in this Separate land and you almost forget they exist until they come to get.
Speaker 1: and then did you do the thing where you'd like seek out?
Speaker 1: Like you'd climb into the tiny area of the play set that really wasn't supposed to be a place to hang out But there'd be like ten kids hanging out in there for some reason Yep, or like there's the three trees like on the edge of the playground and like kids would just like cluster hiding inside of those Trees for some reason even though there's a giant field next to them.
Speaker 1: They're just ignoring that.
Speaker 0: one of the wooden ones had a feature that was just a bunch of tires as almost like a ramp and I guess the Idea was that you would climb up the tires to get to the top and then go over the bar and now you're in the playground.
Speaker 1: There's hiding inside the tires.
Speaker 0: people would just go underneath the tires and that's like a little fort area.
Speaker 0: So there's like a blanket fort situation.
Speaker 1: There's specific evidence that those tiny spaces and forts are like for whatever reasons.
Speaker 1: No one's 100% sure Why are crucial to that childhood development and like the way kids interact on playgrounds like you got a memory?
Speaker 0: That I don't know if it's real or not.
Speaker 0: Maybe my mom could confirm it.
Speaker 0: memory is that there was a tiny Children's clothing store somewhere in Connecticut that I would she would take me to to buy clothes in the mall.
Speaker 0: No, I stand alone like strip mall clothing store, okay, there's only children's clothing.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I have this memory.
Speaker 0: it could be false depending on what you say.
Speaker 1: I think I know the place you're talking about.
Speaker 1: I think it was.
Speaker 1: no you don't chain.
Speaker 0: Oh I get.
Speaker 0: I guess that could be possible.
Speaker 0: They didn't feel Cheney.
Speaker 0: It felt indeed anyway But my memory is that in the back of the clothing store There was basically next to the door for the bathroom Was like a mouse hole but big enough for a child to go through but not big enough for an adult to go through and You would go in that hole.
Speaker 0: and there was a room behind the store.
Speaker 0: No, it was like a carpeted room that had like I don't was there a television showing children's programming?
Speaker 0: Maybe but I definitely remember there being like, you know like a Fisher Price car and some toys and Some.
Speaker 0: it was like a. it was like a hidey secret kind of place and it felt like adults couldn't get in there Although I'm sure they could.
Speaker 1: yeah If so, there was something very similar in all the malls like this.
Speaker 1: there were multiple of these and I remembered as a kid.
Speaker 1: It was a children's clothing store that was in the mall and in the entrance There's like a normal entrance and there was this little mouse hole with carpet in it like just like so like next to it connecting the mall to the store next to the regular door and kids would always go crawling through the hole.
Speaker 1: or Kids would like wedge themselves in that hole like upside down and just play in the hole.
Speaker 1: and inside the store There's another little mouse hole that went into like this playroom that had like a tiny slide and a TV and like some kids toys And there were never adults in that tiny room.
Speaker 0: Mmm, it's similar to my yeah, possibly false memory.
Speaker 1: I'm trying to google a little bit.
Speaker 1: I can't figure out what the fuck this place was to even begin to find a picture to figure out if this was actually a chain that we both went to or My memory was not a chain.
Speaker 0: My memory was like a dark brown carpeted 70s 80s style room.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but this might really but part of the difference might be.
Speaker 1: I lived in an area That was very much more mall centric as opposed to strip malls.
Speaker 0: I live directly next to a mall Yeah, but this place was not in that mall.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the place I'm talking about was in the mall specifically Anyway, but it's like there's all these playground adjacent things.
Speaker 0: right McDonald's play place.
Speaker 0: even the McDonald's play places nowadays.
Speaker 0: They're like a bunch of tubes, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, like plastic tubes.
Speaker 0: I remember ones like when I was super young and I still went to McDonald's.
Speaker 0: there was one that was basically a giant Hamburger like it was on a stick.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there was one of those inside of Chuck E. Cheese's.
Speaker 0: You would go in the stick and climb up a ladder inside.
Speaker 1: I mean hit your head on it because it was really hard even as a tiny kid to navigate that thing.
Speaker 0: It would not be impossible for an adult to get in there.
Speaker 0: I don't know how they would.
Speaker 0: then you're inside like this basic UFO on a stick similar to like You know, I guess Corona Park right like a world.
Speaker 1: I Remember that exact that exact feature in the Chuck E. Cheese.
Speaker 1: Well, it wasn't a Chuck E. Cheese.
Speaker 1: I'm saying Chuck E. Cheese.
Speaker 1: It was actually a major magics, but I don't think anyone knows what that is Right, but I feel like there is a McDonald's with a play place.
Speaker 0: Actually in a story and by the subway, but and they actually redid it recently They totally renovated that play place.
Speaker 0: like these things still exist But I just don't feel they're that prevalent as they used to be.
Speaker 1: yeah Well the way fast-food places make money and the place like the way they interact with society has changed a lot.
Speaker 0: because well Oh here is a picture of it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's it's a It's like a. yeah, it's like a little stick and it looks like a hamburger with bars around.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right and then there's a. there's a little hat.
Speaker 0: So it looks like a policeman hamburger.
Speaker 0: I guess he's gonna catch the hamburgers.
Speaker 1: I forget that character's name.
Speaker 1: That was the character that would catch the hamburglar.
Speaker 1: that the way.
Speaker 1: an exact same thing at the McDonald's.
Speaker 1: and then the major magics Near us had the exact same toy that had clearly been repainted to not be McDonald's branded anymore.
Speaker 1: I don't know if they like bought it from a McDonald's that was renovating or something.
Speaker 1: Alrighty Alright, I think we've killed enough times.
Speaker 1: It's been an hour.
Speaker 1: I uh, I kind of wish I could play in playgrounds, but I understand why Playgrounds ban adults from going into them.
Speaker 1: because for every room and Scott who just want to go swing on the swings There are definitely some some other people who should not be in that playground.
Speaker 0: You should not be anywhere near that place exactly.
Speaker 1: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at front row crew comm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 1: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 0: But unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night and the patreon patrons for this episode of geek nights are Alan Joyce Heidi McNichol Mardi Gras just like a dude guy short option leaky G. You hold the key to my heart.
Speaker 1: But she packed my suitcase and sent me on my way.
Speaker 1: Clinton Walton Jay Vance Ren from New Zealand Ryan parent drew open-lander Nicholas Brando Sailor Vista the thirst for hydrated Gannon dread Lily Tenebrae Chris Reimer Finn Sean Klein Shervin von Horrell and a bunch of people who don't want me to say their names.
Speaker 1: and now I Leave you with Catchy snipe snipe Severus snipe snipe snipe Severus Snape Snape Severus snipe down the door snipe Severus snipe.
Speaker 1: Oh I Found the source of the ticking.
Speaker 1: it's a pipe bomb Voldemort Voldemort Voldemort.