Speaker 0: It's Monday June 22nd 2020.
Speaker 0: I'm rim.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott and this is geek nights tonight.
Speaker 0: We're talking about CICD.
Speaker 1: Let's do this alright, so When it comes to most political discussions out there that we at least I like to avoid on geek nights as much as is You know possible, right?
Speaker 0: Not that it's possible period but you know, yeah, all things are political all things all art all everything.
Speaker 1: I just you know when I say that I mean explicitly talking about, you know Politicians and and things that are actually happening in governments like right now or whatever, right?
Speaker 1: There's better place It's not.
Speaker 0: we're not trying to avoid like talking about Black Lives Matter.
Speaker 0: We're trying to avoid like the DNC is going to have these four delegates doing this thing on Tuesday, right?
Speaker 1: There are better places you can listen to get information on that than geek nights.
Speaker 1: But you know in most political discussions right even in other countries things are pretty You know two-sided.
Speaker 1: hey, you're for or against a person or a position or a platform, right?
Speaker 1: And you know, you tend to be pro or con and any particular thing.
Speaker 1: It's pretty rare to find something that People can agree on when they're far apart But if you're not paying attention to what's going on in New York because you're not from here Which would be understandable you might not know.
Speaker 1: And even though the mayor of New York is nominally a progressive Democrat
Speaker 0: And was more progressive than previous mayor's and was seen as a victory relative to them
Speaker 1: Right and was voted in like on a platform of going against stopping and frisking people He's like, all right, we're gonna put an end to that shit, right?
Speaker 1: He is hated by Everybody.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Well, it's funny cuz way back like I voted for.
Speaker 1: I thought he was good But there's no one else to vote.
Speaker 0: because in New York New York City The primary election for the Democrats is literally all that matters.
Speaker 0: Nothing else matters in this city.
Speaker 1: Whoever wins the Democratic primary then wins.
Speaker 1: Yeah, unless you're in a few weird places.
Speaker 0: But when de Blasio was elected conservatives hated him because of the progressive.
Speaker 1: they still hate.
Speaker 0: they say they don't.
Speaker 0: they still hate him but the cops Also hated him.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm like to the point the cops are also Republicans.
Speaker 0: Uh, yeah But cops specifically like police unions hated him way before this wave of protests.
Speaker 0: I'm talking years and years and years ago Like he gave speeches where police officers would all like in uniform turn their backs on him because he talked about slight changes to regulate police better.
Speaker 1: Anyway, the point is is that even the Democratic progressive lefty people hate him because he's not far left enough, right?
Speaker 0: He's not far left enough and despite the police already hating him.
Speaker 0: He still is unwilling to really go against the police.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so there's a huge article in New York magazine That just came out today and the cover for the article is actually really great.
Speaker 1: is what they did?
Speaker 1: is they posted the mayor's photo around the city like And they just let the photo?
Speaker 1: it was just a photo of him, right?
Speaker 1: They just put it out there and then they came back a while later and took photos of the posters to see what how they had Vandalized naturally And that and they use that to make their their cover image.
Speaker 1: But yeah, no one likes him.
Speaker 1: Basically, I don't know.
Speaker 0: he alienated the left because he's not progressive enough.
Speaker 0: He alienated the right because he's not evil.
Speaker 0: he alienated the cops because he's not evil.
Speaker 0: There's no one left in this city.
Speaker 1: This is article that explains in great detail how everyone came to hate him But there's a particular two paragraphs that I want to focus on.
Speaker 1: where he says I'll just read the two paragraphs.
Speaker 1: Okay So part of the problem longtime friends and aides say is that de Blasio is one of the few people in New York Not really on social media.
Speaker 1: until a few years ago He still used a flip phone.
Speaker 1: the images that bounce around the internet don't always reach the mayor Especially now that he's not surrounded by his usual coterie of AIDS.
Speaker 1: Even as some of his own staffers there to observe the demonstrators were kettled in with protesters and unable to escape He defended the NYPD and the strategy.
Speaker 1: He doesn't see the footage you and I are seeing on Twitter.
Speaker 1: He doesn't see the cops pepper-spraying protesters in the face or running over people says one former advisor.
Speaker 1: He is counting on the PD or some staffer to tell him what is going on And he doesn't get that.
Speaker 1: the world is watching this play out on their phones as it is happening.
Speaker 0: So I feel like using like not being able to use modern social media and technology is disqualifying for office.
Speaker 1: Alright, so this that's exactly what I want to point out.
Speaker 1: Is that a lot of this divide that we're seeing right?
Speaker 1: we talk about the divide along gender lines.
Speaker 1: Right, you know men are more likely to vote right than left.
Speaker 1: right about the line along age, which is Right wing wealthy people are more likely to be right wing and therefore they're wealthy So they live longer.
Speaker 1: therefore old people are more likely to vote right way because the left-wing, you know Old people didn't make it to be old because they were Right.
Speaker 1: you know Non white people are more likely to vote left and right for all the obvious reasons you can imagine Right and for all the ills of social media and the internet which are many and need to be repaired.
Speaker 1: Right, that does not mean that somebody you know, you should you know use it responsibly.
Speaker 1: You shouldn't use it like crazy and just sit on Twitter all day all night.
Speaker 0: We live in a society.
Speaker 0: situation like Twitter is a hell platform But it's kind of important and there's nothing else that replaces it.
Speaker 1: right, but that doesn't mean you should not use it at all.
Speaker 1: You should you know Unlike say alcohol, which has no positive health benefits whatsoever and will give you cancer, right?
Speaker 1: Being on Twitter for all of its negative things Which you should try to mitigate as much as you can by blocking using it responsibly, etc, etc.
Speaker 1: I don't want to emphasize that enough.
Speaker 1: avoiding harassment, right?
Speaker 1: You know.
Speaker 1: protecting your mental health first Right.
Speaker 1: you still as a human who participates in society, you know You need to be on there to some extent to see what's happening in the world, right?
Speaker 1: You know, you don't.
Speaker 1: obviously people who are like, I can't trust the media Different kind of right-wing nutjob craziness, right?
Speaker 1: That's a problem.
Speaker 1: But at the same time only getting your news through The mainstream media, you know CNN's MSNBC's New York Times is Washington Post's for as not Conspiracy not bullshit as they are They are not showing you the whole Picture like right now.
Speaker 0: if you watch Fox News You think Seattle has been like taken over by Mad Max villains.
Speaker 0: if you forget forget Fox News.
Speaker 0: but if you want to see it enter anything else that you might get the impression that the Protests are not happening as frequently as they were when in fact they're happening a lot more.
Speaker 1: if you go on Twitter You can see the tweet thread.
Speaker 1: That's like hundreds of videos of police harming people.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and you don't see that anywhere else, right?
Speaker 1: So and that's not some conspiracy nut thing right and some of those videos have different context.
Speaker 1: You can go watch them for yourself, right?
Speaker 1: You're not hearing some crazed ass commentator or whatever no matter how Legit or intelligent they may or may not be.
Speaker 1: you're just seeing the videos for yourself knowing what the you know Where the videos start and end?
Speaker 1: Imagining what could have happened before and after them with your reasonable mind, right knowing that you know there may be something missing there or not, but you're just seeing it as it is and You know, you're watching as much of it as you can tolerate watching and getting the real story, right?
Speaker 1: To some extent that you don't get anywhere else.
Speaker 0: But like I think why doesn't he just have someone or job?
Speaker 0: it is to be on social media and actually believe him Like I was saying to be.
Speaker 1: You know It's one thing to to participate in society and not have this information or not be tapped into the net.
Speaker 1: Right creates this divide of people who see what's going on and people who don't right?
Speaker 1: But for you to be governing people, right?
Speaker 1: It's like if you can't.
Speaker 1: even it becomes hard to communicate with someone when they don't have access to this.
Speaker 1: You know, if you're a person on the net, how do you even talk to someone who's not right?
Speaker 1: It's very difficult to when you're not even starting at the same base level of information.
Speaker 1: It's like in a conversation I can't transmit to you right the total sum of things I have absorbed from the internet and even like an hour.
Speaker 1: Right, it would take me longer than an hour to tell it to you What is?
Speaker 0: I saw an interaction online fuel last week people making fun of where someone tried to explain something that was going on with?
Speaker 0: Juggalos and the person was like what's a juggalo?
Speaker 0: and then they tried to explain more and then they're like what's the fur and you realize You can't explain anything.
Speaker 1: No, it's like if you're not tapped in you're literally like living in a different, you know world right mentally Societally informationally, right?
Speaker 1: So, you know that's creates the same divide in our society between you.
Speaker 1: know I guess you know, you might be trapped in a right-wing world on the internet, too.
Speaker 0: But yeah, well, here's the thing you want to dig into the real primary sources.
Speaker 0: But don't dig so deep that you hit the like right.
Speaker 1: the voltage wires Point is you're still even right-wing people who are nuts on the internet, right?
Speaker 1: Like Nazis on the internet are still living in a different world from right-wing old people who are not on the internet Right, like if you could imagine like some Nazi guy white supremacist to internets Right trying to talk to a right-wing Fox News watcher who doesn't internet and having the same problems We would have talking to a left-wing grandma who doesn't internet.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right, you know.
Speaker 1: They'd be trying to explain to them some stuff and they'd be like what the what.
Speaker 1: now, right?
Speaker 1: You know, there is needs a solution.
Speaker 0: anyone who's running for office should hire you or me to be their social media advisor.
Speaker 1: So just saying is that - if you're going to govern people Right, you know You if you're like this mayor you're having this this Even though you are ideologically aligned with some people, right?
Speaker 1: You can't even communicate with them because you're not seeing the same thing They're seeing.
Speaker 0: but also you're getting your information from people who have a vested interest in making sure you do not see everything, right?
Speaker 1: Well, but at the same time right if you let's say you had an internet e-mayor right who twittered a bunch Like an AOC type person, right?
Speaker 1: That person has.
Speaker 1: there's still people who don't internet who vote and it becomes hard to communicate with them.
Speaker 1: How do you you know if you can govern us?
Speaker 1: Well, like we'll say ah that person knows what's going on in the world.
Speaker 1: They're on the net they can govern.
Speaker 1: Well, but the people who don't internet now see that person is governing like a nut because they're governing based on all the stuff that Like what?
Speaker 1: How'd you come to that decision?
Speaker 0: Situation where they have a mayor's making decisions based on crazy talk or even just they have a mental model of the world.
Speaker 0: They see a leader do something that seems crazy to them because their model is so out of date.
Speaker 0: But if you actually go outside the model makes sense, but that disconnect is not able to be bridged by most people, right?
Speaker 1: So that the the TLDR is a Right as much as there's bad shit on the internet You'd need to be.
Speaker 1: you know being connected it to some extent in a in a healthy Manner is good because you can have the correct mental model of the of the world that were the society that we're living in.
Speaker 1: Right, but at the same time we need to solve the problem of being able to communicate between Because you know the problem.
Speaker 1: some of the other problems right that are dividing people can't be solved as easily right, you know.
Speaker 0: Fundamentally people who disagree on first principles cannot be reconciled.
Speaker 0: if someone right?
Speaker 0: How do I make use?
Speaker 0: slavery is good?
Speaker 0: Like there's nothing you can do.
Speaker 1: How do I make how do I tell you that you need to care about other people?
Speaker 1: I think is like right It's like.
Speaker 1: but if someone does care about other people and the problem is simply that they're not on the net and your your model of the World is different.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, if they disagree.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, that is still difficult to fix but not impossible.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but think about how crazy it is.
Speaker 0: We know I don't know what our first principles and we have disagreement on facts, right?
Speaker 1: So I don't know what the fix is But I know it can be fixed more easily.
Speaker 1: Then how do I make this person care about other human beings besides themselves?
Speaker 1: Yeah, which I don't which I don't think is as easily fixed what I would say technologically without This.
Speaker 1: so work on and It boys if you work on that you could get people like the mayor of New York.
Speaker 1: I I basically believe that like if he was on Twitter, he would be more progressive.
Speaker 0: But I think the real solution is to elect someone more like AOC in a place like New York Where there is no risk of a non.
Speaker 1: but I'm still to do that.
Speaker 1: You still need to solve this communications problem because that's what.
Speaker 0: oh, you got a lot Someone like that gone.
Speaker 0: dad be like look the other people voting for me aren't even reading this.
Speaker 0: guy's Just right.
Speaker 1: I know I see you But like to get elected you need to be able if you were on the net you need to be able to communicate with the non Net people that are constituents.
Speaker 0: part of that is the platforms need to change like this will do your rails.
Speaker 0: I don't want to move on but like look at the difference between What happens on Facebook lately in regard to all this and what happens on a platform like Twitter?
Speaker 0: They're both hell platforms.
Speaker 0: Like I'm not saying but also better, right?
Speaker 0: But somehow Twitter is being used as a true primary source for a lot of people and is getting information out in a way that a platform like Facebook is Reliably suppressing.
Speaker 1: but also if you look outside of politics, you know the the actual, you know political field.
Speaker 1: You look at just your everyday life, right and your interactions with other people who are not internet II, right?
Speaker 1: And it's like, you know people make you know People do stupid things and make mistakes and do horrible things.
Speaker 1: and or like don't recognize problems.
Speaker 1: And it's like you saw that on the internet last week.
Speaker 0: Well here look at look at nerds a gaming god like.
Speaker 0: they're like a very specific nerdy Almost prosaic example.
Speaker 0: There are nerds that go to conventions or online and they know what's going on And there are nerds who just show up to conventions not actually knowing anything about those conventions.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm somehow those two groups end up coexisting in a space but then there's conflict because they have fundamental disagreements on what those conventions are for or fundamental disagreements on facts Like no.
Speaker 0: PewDiePie is giving a talk at 9 a.m.
Speaker 0: Today not 9 a.m.
Speaker 0: Tomorrow.
Speaker 0: In some other brief news Tomorrow is the last day to vote in the New York City primary and like we just said primaries in New York matter Way more than the actual elections.
Speaker 0: I cannot stress enough if you live in New York You have to join the Democratic Party if you actually want to vote because nothing else you do in terms of voting will matter Except that primary unless you live in a very specific place.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's different but for the vast majority of New York, you know Yep, that's.
Speaker 0: and because we have mail-in voting I saw I went over to the post office to drop over our absentee ballots today because one of them came at like the last Possible second ton of people got their ballots in the mail today.
Speaker 0: I just want to remind you nerds Postmarks mean that the post office has to get your envelope Officially by the end of the day tomorrow or it doesn't count if you put it in a mailbox.
Speaker 0: It's not guaranteed to get that stamp.
Speaker 0: That means your vote counts.
Speaker 1: mine went in a mailbox.
Speaker 1: But it went in a mailbox several days ago and it went in a mailbox right in front of the post office.
Speaker 1: Yep Okay, I think it's okay.
Speaker 0: I went to the post office.
Speaker 0: Here's there's a secret that a lot of internetty people don't see.
Speaker 1: I think I'm alright.
Speaker 0: if you look inside any mailbox in America It actually says the schedule of when that mailbox gets picked up.
Speaker 1: But yes, that is true.
Speaker 1: But I often find that those schedules could lie.
Speaker 1: and the blue post office boxes?
Speaker 0: they tend not to.
Speaker 1: they tend not to.
Speaker 1: but all you know, the the I Often see this the mailboxes that are in weird out-of-the-way locations.
Speaker 1: Well a obviously have schedules posted on them that are less frequent.
Speaker 1: I've seen ones that are like you look at.
Speaker 1: it's like oh, it's mailbox in my neighborhood.
Speaker 1: You look at the sticker and it's like Saturday at 1 p.m Yep, right It's like that's the only time mail comes out of this.
Speaker 0: but I thought those things tend to be extremely accurate.
Speaker 1: The problem is they're accurate to a schedule that may not make sense to you Well, but also some I don't think they're that I've had times where they're not that accurate.
Speaker 1: And also the ones that are directly in front of the post office.
Speaker 1: Those are the ones where it's like, you know, yeah, those are definitely getting picked up.
Speaker 0: But when in doubt you can go to a post office and they will guarantee that it gets stamped with the correct date.
Speaker 0: yep, I hope none of you needed that little primer on how the post office works, but Anyway, so in some other news a Little like last week.
Speaker 0: I forget what day it happens.
Speaker 0: This was a hundred years ago at this point, but it bothered me enough where I want to talk about it today.
Speaker 0: a whole bunch of people Started talking about how there was a massive DDoS cyber-attack taken down cell networks to stop the protests and it was made up bullshit.
Speaker 0: But I saw like journalists talking about it I saw people who are otherwise intelligent talking about it.
Speaker 0: people kept talking about this like the cell networks are down and the two main threads of discussion were either it's something with to do with North Korea or it's something to do with I Was the thing or it has something to do with the protests and I had a few people even come at me when I posted very skeptically that it's probably just the same kind of routine outage that Happens all the time and for some reason like I don't know why people picked up on this and freaked out about it so much.
Speaker 0: but basically t-mobile head and outage someone in their network team like fucked up a circuit failed and Some percentage of t-mobile calls and text didn't go through for like a day and a half.
Speaker 0: That just happens.
Speaker 0: that happens all the time.
Speaker 0: that has happened in living recent memory and yet somehow the internet went crazy About this last week and I even saw news Reporting on like this massive outage that barely existed.
Speaker 1: I saw reporting that was like all cell networks in US are down and I'm like that doesn't seem right.
Speaker 1: I looked at my cell phone.
Speaker 1: I had five bars.
Speaker 1: I was like, nope That sounds wrong to me and also like if you're on the fact that I own I didn't see the article posted in enough.
Speaker 1: If that was true The it would have been posted many more places and up tweeted and it would have been a much bigger explosion.
Speaker 1: Well, I guess it would have been a much.
Speaker 1: I would have either seen a a lot more posts about it Or I would have seen a lot less activity because no one could post anything.
Speaker 0: Yep, but instead I just saw like Millions of people freaking out and even people we knew like we're posting it like in discord servers Like oh, there's this big outage.
Speaker 0: Is it?
Speaker 0: is it the protests?
Speaker 0: and I still can't figure out Why people freaked out about this particular outage?
Speaker 0: Like I cannot find the origin of everyone freaking out.
Speaker 0: So all I want to say about this, I'll link to the article that explains what happens one in The modern world.
Speaker 0: if you see one website talking about something do not believe that that is necessarily true until you see a separate website with real website not like my crazy right-wing nut job rant org and Website.
Speaker 0: that's not simply reiterating what the first website I was like, you know people always say we got to get two sources.
Speaker 0: but I also see a lot of people see something posted on like some like Dodgy news site like the post or something and then they'll point to a second source That is CNN reporting that the post said something that is not a second source.
Speaker 1: There's a lot of people who just like report and you read the article.
Speaker 1: it's like so-and-so reports and it's like wait I mean, I just it's like I'll read an article and then I'll read another article about the same thing.
Speaker 1: It's literally just another outlet reporting that the first place reported.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: So why is that even legal?
Speaker 0: I don't like.
Speaker 0: if you see news that seems big and crazy.
Speaker 0: Like wait a little bit and find another source.
Speaker 1: because right now also for something like that You can verify yourself like I did look at your phone.
Speaker 1: Yes, is it dead?
Speaker 1: No, well, then it's obviously something's fishy or even better.
Speaker 0: Remember we'd what scotch has said we were talking about like be connected.
Speaker 0: if you're using like social media and Twitter Like, you know, I'm in a lot of OPSEC circles.
Speaker 0: I follow a lot of people who are experts on networking and security.
Speaker 0: People like me and people like that will freak out online if something serious goes down.
Speaker 0: I noticed that no one in the OPSEC community No one in the internet like security community was freaking out at all.
Speaker 0: The odds of none of those people freaking out yet something serious going down are basically zero.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so the t-mobile outage was literally just like some network person had a bad day.
Speaker 0: nothing else happened.
Speaker 0: good lord All right.
Speaker 1: So today was an Apple day.
Speaker 1: It's the WWDC.
Speaker 1: they obviously couldn't hold a little Apple conference because Viruses would kill people so that was good.
Speaker 1: They made a video instead.
Speaker 1: They used a lot of drone footage.
Speaker 1: there were a lot of drones in the in the video.
Speaker 1: if you watched it as Predicted remember this is WWDC.
Speaker 1: So it's focused on developers, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah Pretty much almost everything they said was something we predicted including the huge announcement that they're gonna move away from Intel.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: They're using the exact same strategy.
Speaker 1: They used when they moved to Intel from power PC yep, of having both a a build Tool so you can recompile your apps into a universal binary that will run on both platforms As well as having an emulator type layer called Rosetta that will just run apps if it's the wrong of old style binary You know rolling it out slowly.
Speaker 1: over the course of a couple years They'll keep releasing OS X. that will work on both architectures and probably in a couple years.
Speaker 1: They're like, okay We're done with x86.
Speaker 1: You got to use You know our new Apple chips now right arm only Whatever.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so it's as it's.
Speaker 1: everything we said about it was you know We talked about it before and everything we said is still true?
Speaker 1: I don't think it's gonna be.
Speaker 1: I think it's be good for Apple because their chips are way fast.
Speaker 1: Yeah better.
Speaker 0: and and I'm pretty sure now that now that this is all sort of official in public Pretty sure Adobe is going to make arm builds at some point now.
Speaker 0: No, they said in the in the talk that well When Microsoft launched an arm laptop a while ago Adobe actually gave a statement saying we're gonna support arm and they just didn't.
Speaker 1: Well, see the difference here right?
Speaker 1: is Adobe already has apps for like iPad, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, so the main thing that they showed that I think was to Apple's advantage Which is like the seek.
Speaker 1: this is like the I guess the buried lead on this story, right?
Speaker 1: Is that it's like, okay You'll have the same kind of transition head last time.
Speaker 1: people will freak out about it too much Even though they shouldn't freak out about it at all.
Speaker 1: It's probably good for Apple long run.
Speaker 0: Apple's a much more ecosystem.
Speaker 0: There's less like consequences of this kind of thing.
Speaker 1: They showed They showed that the new OS X on the new chip right, you can just go to the App Store and install an iPhone or iPad app and Just run it, right?
Speaker 1: So it's like, okay What does Apple give a shit?
Speaker 1: even if they lose your your OS X app that you spent, you know, whatever you're done with Apple Now you don't want to port it to a new CP you are.
Speaker 1: you don't want to open up Xcode and recompile to a different target.
Speaker 1: It'll take you how long right an hour to fix the bug or whatever, right?
Speaker 1: You don't want to do that right too much work for you.
Speaker 1: It's like alright.
Speaker 1: Well anyone who wants to buy a Mac can now use all iPhone and all iPad software Which will just work because those are already on the same architectures.
Speaker 1: So and also on like plenty of apps They're not.
Speaker 1: they're gonna be sad without your app.
Speaker 0: But also unlike those arm laptops on Microsoft.
Speaker 0: I was talking about I These these devices seem like they will be powerful enough to be able to emulate in a way that those laptops couldn't.
Speaker 1: which will Imagine this will make Apple Laptops, right the most powerful Laptop available.
Speaker 0: I think it'll make them definitely powerful enough.
Speaker 1: with insane Life is what I guess you would have to discount like the crazy gaming ones that are huge and thick Yeah, right and have to be plugged in with a battery last five minutes.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but like other than those that way it would make.
Speaker 1: Apple laptops are probably going to be the the fastest and the strongest I don't know.
Speaker 1: I think the desktops are still gonna have problems because again Apple even.
Speaker 1: they said they focus on power efficiency.
Speaker 1: Right and they point it out like yeah desktop computers that aren't ours are so fast because why they don't give a shit about power Right?
Speaker 0: when I when I render a video on the PC under my desk It heats the room up so badly that the AC kicks in right within.
Speaker 1: a GPU has freaking three fans on it, right?
Speaker 1: It's like, you know, I do think though they are missing still.
Speaker 1: Is that what they should do?
Speaker 1: I don't know why they don't do this, right?
Speaker 1: You know what you should do.
Speaker 1: Yeah It's like okay.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you've conquered efficiency.
Speaker 1: great fantastic job, right?
Speaker 1: That's absolutely the right thing to be doing right.
Speaker 0: getting the most performance per because that's what most users actually care about.
Speaker 0: people like me are Not the majority for this kind of computer.
Speaker 1: in that big-ass Mac Pro you have right?
Speaker 1: You should use your same Efficient architecture that you have right.
Speaker 1: that gets so many more, you know so much more performance per watt.
Speaker 1: I just aren't cranking watch through it and just turn up the watts to the same number of watts.
Speaker 1: Intel is running right, you know?
Speaker 1: on that one machine on the Mac Pro just use the same architecture.
Speaker 1: You've got.
Speaker 1: put a cooler and turn up the watts on it and it's like ta-da.
Speaker 0: Well, you know what?
Speaker 0: There's definitely.
Speaker 0: there are people who are used servers.
Speaker 0: There's a balance between performance and efficiency.
Speaker 0: that is necessary because we have to not just waste energy, but laptops.
Speaker 0: Energy matters way more than performance 99% of the time.
Speaker 0: Workstations and gaming PCs are like the only two exceptions where power is all that matters.
Speaker 0: Nothing else matters.
Speaker 0: use as much electricity as you want, right?
Speaker 1: Exactly Anyway, so that's what's going on in that with the CPU department.
Speaker 1: smaller Apple newses.
Speaker 1: They're adding bike directions Apple Maps.
Speaker 1: Everyone in the bicycle community is basically of the opinion of better late than ever, but I'm sticking with Google Maps.
Speaker 0: Apple Maps has just been the worst option for as long as it's existed and that continues to be true.
Speaker 0: right.
Speaker 1: Apple has always talked about how their platform is the best for privacy and they pretty much focused on that during every single part of The keynote.
Speaker 1: they talked about how privacy goes with whatever it was including when they talked about the fact that Safari is now getting browser extensions and That's just more of the same thing Apple has been doing for its entire existence, which is Do something someone else has already done and do it maybe better.
Speaker 1: Maybe you're in a nicer design You know possibly but act like you invented it and now people start using it, right?
Speaker 1: You know, they came out with You know the Mac when other computers already had mice and gooeys and they acted like they invented the GUI, right?
Speaker 1: They came out with the iPad iPod when there were already other mp3 players.
Speaker 1: They came out with the iPhone when they're already other smartphones.
Speaker 1: They acted like they invented the smartphone, right?
Speaker 1: You know, they can't with the tablet.
Speaker 1: there had been tablets for a long time.
Speaker 1: They acted like they invented.
Speaker 1: that also Came out everything they've done From the small features like adding virtual desktops to OS X when Unix has had them forever to you know.
Speaker 1: coming out today.
Speaker 1: They showed the iPhone is gonna have widgets in the home screen.
Speaker 1: It's like dude.
Speaker 1: androids had that since like version 1.
Speaker 1: They act like they invented widgets on the home screen, which they're adding.
Speaker 1: You know things like picture-in-picture on Apple TV, right?
Speaker 1: It's like picture-in-picture has been around since like the 90s.
Speaker 0: Yeah My CR CRT television in the 90s had two tuners in it and had a picture-in-picture that you could even configure Where on the screen it sat and how big it was.
Speaker 0: and well and you can even configure it to have closed captioning Enabled but audio coming from the main one.
Speaker 1: Yes a lot of other small things and acting like they're new or a big deal simply because by you know For example being able to set your default web browser email client and iOS is gonna be a thing now.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and it's like.
Speaker 1: it's like Windows has had that since like Windows like at 95 98 It's like now it's a but because they've been holding back on it so long and people want it so bad.
Speaker 1: It's like oh, it's like a huge deal right to do something.
Speaker 1: That's should just be there without yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah, basically, there's all these announcements just boil down to.
Speaker 0: a lot of this was expected but now we got clarification or details.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the biggest thing is the non announcement which is like how come there still is an Xcode on iOS.
Speaker 1: You can't make an iPad or iPhone app on an iPad or iPhone.
Speaker 1: You need to get a Mac still Powerful enough like yeah now that the N has a keyboard if you have the seams and a mouse support.
Speaker 1: if you have the same CPU on a Mac and an iPad Why shouldn't an Xcode is running on that CPU?
Speaker 1: There's no reason.
Speaker 1: you know it's like you've got the iPad apps running on OS X. There is no reason that Xcode shouldn't run on iPad.
Speaker 1: They still didn't announce that despite it being rumored.
Speaker 1: It's bullshit.
Speaker 1: I'm not buying a Mac to make iPad apps, but if I could make iPad apps on my iPad I would right anyway.
Speaker 1: So that's bullshit, and then the final thing is we talked about the hey app email thing situation last Thursday.
Speaker 1: So go back to listen to that.
Speaker 1: yeah But hey modified their app in such a way they thought of a way to get it approved and Apple approved it.
Speaker 0: That was fast.
Speaker 1: what they did is they made it to where if you install the hey app without paying for hey You get a random bullshit Email account that will be turned off in a few days.
Speaker 1: That's basically completely useless, but you can like use the hey app and see how it works and stuff because you've got.
Speaker 1: You've got like a temporary bullshit account.
Speaker 1: That's useless right, but you can use the app and it does something.
Speaker 0: I wonder if part of them approving this solution was just to make this whole problem go away.
Speaker 1: I think part That's you know.
Speaker 1: there's definitely a lot of pressure on them.
Speaker 1: that seemed to have worked.
Speaker 1: plus You know you go to developer conference.
Speaker 1: you don't want to go in.
Speaker 1: you get.
Speaker 1: you got a bunch of angry developers.
Speaker 1: Right?
Speaker 1: you want to be able to say something to them right so?
Speaker 0: In the last news before we get into the main bit this also is gaming news But it's relevant to Monday for a bunch of reasons.
Speaker 0: mixer is being shut down by Microsoft and Basically merging into Facebook gaming.
Speaker 1: right so I don't know.
Speaker 1: a lot of people a didn't know about mixer.
Speaker 1: mixer was basically a twitch Competitor that had a lot of features and it actually was technologically probably the best of the games Streaming platform.
Speaker 0: like the penny.
Speaker 0: guys were using it a little bit And it did just a bunch of really neat stuff that I had
Speaker 1: a lot of you
Speaker 0: don't do had
Speaker 1: a lot of Interactive features that twitch you would have to like do development to get you know like twitch plays Pokemon those sort of interactive things.
Speaker 1: A lot of those are like built outside of twitch And then like plugged in via hacks and api's and through twitch chat and things like that Whereas mixer had that stuff built in from the get-go, so it was a good platform.
Speaker 1: People who did know that mixer existed a lot of them didn't know Microsoft owned it.
Speaker 1: I didn't know that originally.
Speaker 1: I learned it some months ago.
Speaker 1: Probably.
Speaker 0: I think like how did you not know that cuz we were?
Speaker 1: I knew it.
Speaker 1: I knew I knew it like last summer.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I feel I remember though I feel like it's knowledge that you and I and other people learned But was so unknown worthy that we just forget.
Speaker 0: and then well no It's like.
Speaker 1: I remember that I knew about mixer And then I was surprised that after I learned of mixers existence like early last year that I later learned Oh, Microsoft owns that.
Speaker 1: I didn't know that.
Speaker 1: I was surprised when I found that out.
Speaker 1: I just had that surprise long ago.
Speaker 1: Yeah, people now who now feel like I got that surprise at pecs south last year I don't know remember when I got it, but it was a long time ago.
Speaker 1: but the point is it was definitely 2018 or 19. the people now who are seeing mixer die are Surprised.
Speaker 1: they didn't know it existed or if they did know about mixer are now also receiving the Microsoft surprise.
Speaker 1: So what's happened?
Speaker 1: What's happening is?
Speaker 1: Everyone who had the exclusive mixer deals notably ninja have been freed from their deals given all their money, right?
Speaker 1: They're like totally set free like great there.
Speaker 1: They just made they're made out.
Speaker 1: They're like, whoo?
Speaker 1: Yeah Right like golden parachute for them.
Speaker 1: all of the other mixer partners the lower level ones are basically being handed the opportunity to go to Facebook gaming and Again base gaming right basically getting the same deal or a very similar deal to what they had it mixer.
Speaker 1: They're like.
Speaker 1: it's like don't you can continue your deal over there?
Speaker 1: Mixer itself is just gonna slowly shut down like end of July that you're just gonna turn it off.
Speaker 1: So it's not that it was unsuccessful.
Speaker 1: It just wasn't successful enough.
Speaker 1: and what you're getting is sort of again a sprint T Mobile kind of deal because I've talked about this before.
Speaker 0: but game stop idea or game spy IGN Right.
Speaker 1: the business model of the 21st century seems to be Make a company right.
Speaker 1: do what would normally beak in a normal time with normal antitrust regulation.
Speaker 1: be Considered to be predatory pricing.
Speaker 1: yeah to where you get lots of investment money from VC and other sources To run a business at a loss like say uber right get lots of customers because you're basically providing some insane Service at an insanely low price.
Speaker 1: That's like who wouldn't want to use uber?
Speaker 1: you get such cheap rides.
Speaker 1: It's such an amazing service.
Speaker 1: Yeah, cuz someone else like early twitch wait.
Speaker 0: I can just stream video to an infinite number of people for free, right?
Speaker 1: It's like you're getting this insane service for a low price.
Speaker 1: Why?
Speaker 1: because the business is losing money on it, but the business is cheating to stay alive sort of like a Ponzi scheme.
Speaker 1: But if you're not an investor you're not being Ponzi schemes, you're just getting a free service, so why not be a customer?
Speaker 1: It just benefits you to be a customer Yeah Like being a custom customer.
Speaker 1: Amazon just benefits you right even though they're doing evil on the side to make that a reality.
Speaker 1: Right so?
Speaker 1: and then you get so many customers because your business is just so insane and anyone operating in the same space Responsibly can't compete with that because they're trying to make a profit and stay in business and pay their.
Speaker 1: you know everyone fairly or whatever.
Speaker 1: So you then because you have this predatory pricing everyone else in the market dies.
Speaker 1: you don't have a monopoly.
Speaker 1: You're the only game in town right uber?
Speaker 1: We're the only car thing in town if we can beat everyone else right by cheating.
Speaker 1: And then once you're the only game in town you have a monopoly boom real prices.
Speaker 1: What's anyone gonna do about it?
Speaker 1: There's nowhere else to go right?
Speaker 1: so the same thing is happening.
Speaker 1: You're seeing it in the streaming space.
Speaker 1: where?
Speaker 1: YouTube Facebook gaming Twitch and mixer right we're all operating on the same.
Speaker 1: try to become a Monopoly business model.
Speaker 1: yeah, right anyone can stream here for free.
Speaker 1: We need to be the biggest platform and conquer the world right?
Speaker 1: Whatever?
Speaker 1: why wouldn't you stream with us right?
Speaker 1: And then you know if you find out you're not gonna achieve that monopoly that means it's not gonna work.
Speaker 0: right now.
Speaker 0: There's no future where you make money because you can't right.
Speaker 0: It's like you can't charge the people watching and you can't charge the people putting and you can't.
Speaker 1: your whole plan Your whole plan is to cheat to get a monopoly So that you can then raise prices.
Speaker 1: if you can never reach the monopoly you can never raise prices Which means you will just lose money forever.
Speaker 1: right if uber doesn't take over the entire space that it's in it Will just lose money forever.
Speaker 1: those investors it will just all the money They invested to make that you know acquire.
Speaker 1: those customers will just be lost.
Speaker 1: They'll never make the money back.
Speaker 1: so the monopoly must happen.
Speaker 1: mixer sees even though It's doing quite well for it is all things considered It's not number one, but it was doing quite.
Speaker 1: Well.
Speaker 1: It was a great platform All things considered you know even though there are now reports of racism as there are everywhere.
Speaker 1: yeah Good enough you know to make me not cry over.
Speaker 0: it seems like it was pretty egregious.
Speaker 1: at mixer right We got some racism and sex crimes going on over at twitch also alright, so you know no one's innocent in these world.
Speaker 1: Right you know kill them all.
Speaker 1: I say the point is that Because what is never going to be a monopoly You know they got the ninja deal.
Speaker 1: if that didn't make them the number one game in town nothing would.
Speaker 1: So if you're not gonna be number one well, we can't lose money forever.
Speaker 1: We got to shut it down.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so they wisely shut it down.
Speaker 1: You know they sort of.
Speaker 1: I think the mistake they made was surprising all the people with the shutdown.
Speaker 1: It's surprised pretty much everyone even their partners.
Speaker 1: They should have been better about communicating and telling people.
Speaker 0: Why bother?
Speaker 0: because most people don't even know it's Microsoft you.
Speaker 0: why bother?
Speaker 1: because to not be evil.
Speaker 0: But I'm saying from a capitalist corporate standpoint the right move is just - it stops working.
Speaker 0: That's it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it just disappears exactly anyway the the point is that They're doing a sprint t-mobile merger.
Speaker 1: right sprint t-mobile?
Speaker 1: neither one is the biggest game in town.
Speaker 1: They're not Verizon or AT&T right.
Speaker 1: so if you can't be number one you have to merge or go out of business.
Speaker 1: So they chose to merge with face merge slash go out of business with Facebook gaming To see.
Speaker 1: you know I guess Facebook can keep losing money longer to try to try to win the war.
Speaker 1: yeah We'll see.
Speaker 0: but anyway Things of the day, so I know you all many of you are fans of the Animal Crossing.
Speaker 0: I enjoy the Animal Crossing.
Speaker 0: It's a good game.
Speaker 0: But one of the aspects of Animal Crossing is that the characters talk in this pseudo nonsense But not completely nonsense language like they talk and it maps to the words that they're actually saying in the text in the game.
Speaker 0: But it's not a full language.
Speaker 0: It's like a Minimized cute language.
Speaker 0: so when characters sing like when KK Slider gives a concert he sings in that made-up language But he sings like a whole song.
Speaker 0: This is a band that does covers of KK Slider's music But they sing it in the Animal Crossing language.
Speaker 0: live All right, they also dress up like KK Slider in okay in a. It's not furry.
Speaker 0: This is not furry.
Speaker 0: This is I Don't know what this is.
Speaker 0: he didn't just watch it and you'll see.
Speaker 0: but this is expertly done All right.
Speaker 1: Well you may have seen a story going around the the webs or whatever about a crossword puzzle plagiarism Which is even though crossword puzzles themselves are not really there's sort of a trivial matter in the world the people who make crossword puzzles take plagiarism very seriously because crossword puzzles are Difficult to make.
Speaker 1: they're very time-consuming.
Speaker 0: a good crossword puzzle like that is on the level of designing a pretty good like small board game.
Speaker 0: Right right.
Speaker 1: so if you so and there's you know there's certain publications need crossword puzzles and pay out for them And they're actually worth quite a bit right?
Speaker 1: It's like a lot of people will buy like you know New York Times Sunday for that crossword puzzle, right?
Speaker 1: It's actually worth it to the New York Times to give the crossword maker a lot of money.
Speaker 1: Yeah especially if they write a good one the kind of good one that they expect to be in there right.
Speaker 1: so Crossword puzzle is still a big deal in the world and Crossword plagiarism is taken very seriously by people who make them right.
Speaker 1: So when someone discovers crossword plagiarism that's taken very seriously.
Speaker 1: so somebody The person in this video was just looking to do some studies of you know have fun Studying crossword puzzles right there.
Speaker 1: We're looking for plagiarism.
Speaker 1: They were just saying like hey I wonder what like you know it's probably a cool interesting data to look at.
Speaker 1: I'm a nerd right like.
Speaker 0: does someone use this one Clue?
Speaker 0: that's like really useful to fit into a weird.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the person right the person in this video looks like you know the most stereotypical computer science student And they tell a story about how they tried to collect a bunch of crossword puzzle data.
Speaker 1: They managed to get the data.
Speaker 1: They made a new file format for crossword puzzles.
Speaker 1: They put the day all the puzzles in that format And then they used your normal everyday Unix tools on that format like grep and cut and you know diff and they found Oh, oh, they just discovered plagiarism.
Speaker 1: that happened right like whoa And that became a big deal right for 15 seconds on the internet.
Speaker 1: But yeah this talk this person gave explains in great detail everything they did the genius file format.
Speaker 1: They came up with.
Speaker 1: but I think the Interesting thing is that this is at a convention I didn't know about what conference called CSV con which is like a convention for people who care about like data and So it's like you know.
Speaker 1: it's like CSV right cuz CSV.
Speaker 1: I assume it's about comma separated value.
Speaker 0: con Say that I have a 140 megabyte CSV file on my desktop right now.
Speaker 1: I know right I'm just you know.
Speaker 1: I want to go back and find other talks from this conference because this is the first I've heard of this.
Speaker 1: But this is a great one to start with even if you don't care about crossword puzzles.
Speaker 1: and also This conference is also partially the thing of the day right the fact this conference exists, so I'm gonna go check that out.
Speaker 1: And yeah, it's also great for Monday because you get a lot of technology going on.
Speaker 0: yeah in the meta moment We'll slowly read the tale of Genji, but working on other stuff right now We're working on panels for upcoming online conventions.
Speaker 0: some of you at least one of you has told us about some conventions that will be coming up that are online.
Speaker 0: if there's An online convention you think our brand like you want us to perform at you want us to do the weird panel you always wanted us to do that.
Speaker 0: we never did because like Normal physical conventions with their limited space don't want us to do our weird stuff like.
Speaker 0: now is the time to let us get weird Or let us get very hyper specific about the panel topics.
Speaker 0: We've always wanted to do Otherwise.
Speaker 0: follow me and Scott on YouTube.
Speaker 0: We're putting stuff out sometimes.
Speaker 0: We're just streaming games.
Speaker 0: I'll say I'll put a link to our discord Which is pretty rockin.
Speaker 0: Discords are a good place to hang out during all this cuz it's not like you're gonna hang out in person or at a con anytime soon.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I was I was just typing a bunch of stuff and not paying attention at a moment.
Speaker 1: any convention any talks.
Speaker 1: we we might give some talks for You know make record some videos that will be shown at online conventions.
Speaker 1: We got the packs online pretty much Yep, and then maybe we you know.
Speaker 1: if we have some talks that we want to give and no one accepts them Just give me.
Speaker 1: maybe I'll make the video anyway and put on YouTube.
Speaker 0: Well, I mean I did that you didn't want to do any Five Nights at Freddy's horror stuff.
Speaker 0: so years ago I just made my own like video essay panel and just put it up there and Kind of want to do the same thing.
Speaker 0: for another thing that again I'm not going to even mention what the topic is because until I make this panel, which is actually a lot of work I'm not gonna shit talk it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, not a chick talking anything I'm just saying that that is an idea I have that I may or may not do is to just you know It's like I'm good at writing panels and doing them.
Speaker 1: Maybe I'll just do it in front of this camera behind me over here.
Speaker 1: Yeah Maybe I won't.
Speaker 0: I mean the easiest thing to do is We'll get together at your apartment and we'll record panels in person together in front of a camera.
Speaker 1: When will it be safe to do this?
Speaker 0: Yeah, hopefully by September.
Speaker 0: Otherwise, it'll be a little bit difficult to put together that panel for packs online.
Speaker 1: Do a two box.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's tough though, I mean even now like there's a little bit of delay like we talk over each other It's just really hard to do like I just do what we could just do one people panels.
Speaker 1: I do want you do one.
Speaker 0: Oh we could do that, too.
Speaker 0: The problem is I got some one people panels I could do.
Speaker 0: that aren't the insane amount of effort of the one that I keep talking about.
Speaker 0: that I'm not gonna talk about because I really want to do it.
Speaker 0: It's such a good topic But I will.
Speaker 0: it'll literally take me like 30 or 40 hours to get together all the data and sources I need to actually make this panel and I don't know if I have it in me to actually do that All right.
Speaker 1: Well, let's move to the main bit because I'm hungry and I got shit to do.
Speaker 0: So CSCD You'll hear this what you'll hear this a lot.
Speaker 0: What does that actually mean?
Speaker 0: If you're not a nerd continuous integration and Continuous deployment or sometimes people say continuous delivery depending on the content.
Speaker 1: It's all the same thing.
Speaker 1: the core idea is that you're writing software right and You know back in the day the way software worked is.
Speaker 1: you would write the software you would put it on some floppy disks Or some shit, right?
Speaker 1: It's like you didn't have an internet to deliver your software.
Speaker 1: Yeah You would.
Speaker 1: you would put it on floppy disks or you ship those computers to a QA person who tests or cartridge Cartridges or chips or something, right?
Speaker 1: and then that was the final version and if you released a new version.
Speaker 1: you had to sell a new thing or You know, it's like that was it right?
Speaker 1: so it's like for example if you buy like a Super Nintendo cartridges, right?
Speaker 1: It's like you might have.
Speaker 1: you know, we talked about like Japanese 1.0 linked to the past.
Speaker 1: It's like well some Cartridges in Japan aren't 1.0 linked to the past.
Speaker 1: They're a newer version that doesn't have all those bugs in it, right?
Speaker 1: It's like, you know, they you wouldn't patch your software, right and even when patching came into existence, right?
Speaker 1: The patch has to be deployed.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it goes up on a server.
Speaker 1: You need some sort of automatic update thing.
Speaker 1: so Software was done and delivered.
Speaker 1: you had to like build software make it perfect Put it out into the world and then that's it right.
Speaker 1: patching was was very difficult And even if you could patch the patches themselves were sort of.
Speaker 1: that's it.
Speaker 1: You put them out and they're there now with the web Primarily right.
Speaker 1: the software people are running is not deployed to them.
Speaker 1: It's on a website.
Speaker 0: every time they reload they're reloading the software and it tends to not be a monolithic stack of Extremely siloed pipelines that don't interact with each other, right?
Speaker 1: It's not one exe right that is done and everything's in the exe.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like this your dad They're dad.
Speaker 1: every time they visit your web page They're downloading a ton of random stuff and they're hitting other APIs that are all over the internet.
Speaker 1: that are them Themselves.
Speaker 1: individual pieces of software Right and only the web browser itself is sort of a monolithic blob that is installed.
Speaker 1: Yeah and even so if you're writing Software right and your software is sitting on a server somewhere and everyone using the software is loading it from the server Every time they use it you can just update on the server that one copy of the software, right?
Speaker 1: You just update the one thing and now you've updated everyone.
Speaker 1: Everyone's always using the same copy of the software.
Speaker 1: It's like it's installed only once.
Speaker 1: imagine if we only installed Counter-strike on one computer and everyone in the world and that CPU on that computer was running everyone's game of counter-strike Right and you would just download right the graphics and you would send your your keyboard inputs now Like we're laughing.
Speaker 0: but that is literally how computers worked for a long time.
Speaker 1: So literally that's also how Google stadia works.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's literally.
Speaker 1: does that some computers that run the counter-strike or whatever game it is You just play right websites work is you're just downloading HTML's you download the JavaScript program it runs But the next time you visit that website the JavaScript program might be different and you download it again.
Speaker 1: Yeah, now if you're writing such a program You know, you don't need to like, you know.
Speaker 1: make deploying and updating the server this big event Right because you're not it's not permanently stamped in stone.
Speaker 1: if you make a mistake Right, you can just fix it and you fixed it for everyone.
Speaker 1: Of course you break it.
Speaker 1: you break it for everyone.
Speaker 1: That's the part we'll get into the most in a minute, right, but you can just update it in one place Frequently like you can just patch it constantly right?
Speaker 1: You can edit a web page while someone's visiting it They reload they get the update right away.
Speaker 1: You can just keep working on it constantly, right?
Speaker 0: You know, like we're playing for up to these these German like.
Speaker 0: well not German.
Speaker 0: We're playing these like weird train games on this website and literally like I'll take a turn and then like I hit f5 and they have deployed some new code to the server and the graphics look different and they fixed a bug.
Speaker 1: Like you're still in the middle of your game.
Speaker 1: Your game is not broken.
Speaker 1: Yep, you know.
Speaker 1: So this is great a great way to deploy your software because you can get patches out immediately There's no waiting and you don't need to like sit on this huge pile of updates right and then release them to the world like aha here are all the updates like look what Apple is doing with like.
Speaker 1: we just Talked about WDC.
Speaker 1: they're like here are all our updates for iOS whatever.
Speaker 0: that last part is really important because that's where like Management comes in of like large projects.
Speaker 0: because sure say Scott fixes a bunch of bugs.
Speaker 0: Say Scott fixes bugs and makes changes to something for a month and then deploys it and then all those other APIs and services Don't quite work right because of some decisions Scott made along the way maybe good decisions.
Speaker 0: Now a bunch of stuff is broken because no one tested the end-to-end workflow until Scott put his month worth of code out there.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so it's really good as a pro, you know developer right to be able to just constantly release your changes Like I don't even know why they still do, you know, imagine if you just got iOS updates like daily, you know Just.
Speaker 1: or they just happen without even realizing and you just constantly got new features.
Speaker 1: Just pop it up all the time all over the place.
Speaker 1: instead of here comes OS X. big sir we got big updates for you, right just what if OS X just constantly got better?
Speaker 1: as Apple developers worked?
Speaker 1: they finish a new feature and now suddenly everyone has it, right?
Speaker 1: So the Obviously the problem with this is that okay?
Speaker 1: Sure You're.
Speaker 1: you're just putting stuff out into the world as you do it.
Speaker 1: You're incrementally constantly updating the software.
Speaker 1: That's amazing.
Speaker 1: Right but You're not because you don't have this sort of big release event where you're like making CDs.
Speaker 1: If you're gonna know you're gonna make a CD and it's set in stone.
Speaker 1: You test that shit like crazy to make sure that what you put on that CD is perfect.
Speaker 0: Like you have a lockdown date We're like, alright, no more code submissions except critical bugs and then a massive QA project kicks off on its own.
Speaker 1: This is why you see with like Nintendo but especially back in the day in the cartridge times They would do tons.
Speaker 1: if you made a game Nintendo would do insane testing on it to make sure before they would let you sell your cartridges.
Speaker 1: Right with the Nintendo seal of quality or whatever.
Speaker 1: right because they don't want anyone putting games out there.
Speaker 1: They just don't work.
Speaker 0: But now like I make some tiny change like oh that words been misspelled for like a year.
Speaker 0: I'll just fix it.
Speaker 0: but two other API is just for whatever reason.
Speaker 0: that's a problem for them and you break everything.
Speaker 1: So you're not doing this huge big amazing Hardcore QA process before your release that you did back in the day because you can't be doing that ten times a day Right, what you need is some way to test.
Speaker 1: You still need to test though, right?
Speaker 1: If you don't test then you're just gonna be breaking your app ten times a day.
Speaker 1: or you're gonna like push out a patch.
Speaker 1: You break your website push out a different patch.
Speaker 1: It's still broken.
Speaker 1: push a different patch.
Speaker 1: all the customers are mad because everything's broken and then you finally fix it.
Speaker 1: So it's like what do you do every time you make a small update to your website?
Speaker 1: It's like you need to test still but you can't do some insane deep QA, right?
Speaker 1: You just need some way to test.
Speaker 1: and no you're not gonna break the website when you ten times a day and you
Speaker 0: need two fundamental kinds of testing the idea of unit testing like continuous unit testing and then Continuous integration testing which is the part we're really talking about because that's the part that makes this work,
Speaker 1: right?
Speaker 1: So what CI is is basically these platforms and services you can use and set up.
Speaker 1: that will You?
Speaker 1: basically the idea is that you use your version control, right and you make a pull request with git.
Speaker 1: Usually right is usually what you would do in the year 2020 You know and then or you'd you know, you'd merge into a branch or something like that.
Speaker 1: you push your new source code out there and This platform is looking at that source code and saying aha It's always watching and it sees aha somebody has written new source code.
Speaker 1: That is that they think is ready.
Speaker 1: Oh you think it's ready, right that that platform will go and take that source code To create a computing environment out of nothing that is identical as possible to the production environment, right?
Speaker 1: It'll make a new server.
Speaker 1: It will run the code that you just wrote and then run a battery of tests that you wrote.
Speaker 1: you wrote tests, right?
Speaker 1: tests And it will run all those tests against the code that you just wrote.
Speaker 1: now You should have been testing it yourself on your local computer before you made that push.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right, but there's still.
Speaker 1: Testing on your local computer is not the same as testing in production, right?
Speaker 1: So it's making an environment that's more true to production than your local development Environment is and will catch possibly errors and bugs that your local tests did not catch even though they might be the same exact test.
Speaker 0: and the important part is that environment will have Versions of hopefully also continuously integrated all the other services and API's and things that your code relies on.
Speaker 1: Even if you don't manage that code It can also run much more extensive tests than your local development environment can have right?
Speaker 1: So for example, maybe I write a little JavaScript form kind of thing, right?
Speaker 1: And I test it locally and I write a test and it totally works on my computer.
Speaker 1: It's great.
Speaker 1: So I push it out.
Speaker 1: I make a pull request and they say hey, I wrote this It should be added to the real the full project.
Speaker 1: It's a great new form that will help users out.
Speaker 1: Let's do it, right?
Speaker 1: So you push it out and the continuous integration thing comes along.
Speaker 1: it takes it and it tests it and then it tests it in Every single browser.
Speaker 1: Yeah, then it tests and then it tests it, you know on different versions of Linux Right and it tests it on different versions of Apache or whatever other.
Speaker 0: maybe it's a big iron Enterprise thing where not only will it run all these browser tests But it'll have other people who are using your API's.
Speaker 0: like maybe you have a federated model where you have a website But you also have API's Where they will hit those API's from like a hundred different kinds of endpoints to make sure that they all work, too.
Speaker 1: Maybe when you were testing local you were just testing the part you were working on.
Speaker 1: It's gonna run the full tests.
Speaker 1: So maybe you broke something that's far away from the code you wrote inadvertently.
Speaker 1: It's gonna catch if your tests are comprehensive enough, which they're never fully comprehensive But they should be good enough.
Speaker 1: right to prevent to me.
Speaker 1: You don't need them to be perfect.
Speaker 1: They'll never be perfect right but the tests just need to be thorough enough.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so that most of the time when you push to production nothing's broke.
Speaker 0: You want to know my hack?
Speaker 0: This is not a hack This is common knowledge but like a good secret.
Speaker 0: to get this going Come up with a good set of unit tests like very early and build them and obviously anytime you add new serious functionality Like make sure you build tests as part of that like you're not done until you've wrote tests for your own code
Speaker 1: But I know what I do.
Speaker 0: every time you find a bug like QA finds a bug or the testing finds a bug.
Speaker 0: That was a test for it.
Speaker 0: Yeah Make a test for the thing that was just fixed and you will naturally grow your unit tests over time with almost no effort.
Speaker 1: When I when I make tests, you know my test is I basically make a test.
Speaker 1: that just if I'm making a website Which is usually what I make websites, right?
Speaker 1: I just make a test that hits makes a sense of.
Speaker 1: basically I get to every single Endpoint every single possible URL and says did I get a 200 or did I get it right?
Speaker 0: That's a good smoke test.
Speaker 1: like it's either working or it's just just just hit every URL with an Appropriate request and say did I get a 200 or did I get what I was supposed to get, right?
Speaker 1: Maybe it's like a login page.
Speaker 1: So for a login page, I'll send a good login and a bad login.
Speaker 1: I'd like did the bad login get a 403, right?
Speaker 1: It's like just the most simple possible test for a website.
Speaker 1: just hit every URL check the response code, right?
Speaker 1: And if you get any 500s, that's a failure and then I'll start with that and then I'll just add more tests for you know That's a testing.
Speaker 1: All right testing is like a separate topic from the CI thing, right?
Speaker 0: But testing is like the core value of CI.
Speaker 0: is the test, right?
Speaker 1: Exactly.
Speaker 0: Otherwise, you just made a machine that breaks your code like you're gonna break things easily and quickly.
Speaker 1: Right, and you know, I've talked about testing before is like you still shouldn't go so crazy with the tests that writing Tests becomes too much work, right?
Speaker 1: You know, it's like you.
Speaker 1: you some people go create like they're super test driven development nuts, right?
Speaker 1: And it's like they spend so much time writing tests.
Speaker 1: It takes them like a week to make the simplest.
Speaker 1: I would say they wrote a hundred.
Speaker 0: that is fine.
Speaker 0: in Specific contexts where you're making medical software you are doing Engineering work, but medical software shouldn't be continuously deployed.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it should be continuously integrated in a test environment.
Speaker 1: Yes continuous deployment is not for things that matter.
Speaker 1: you don't to continuously deploy software to your satellite or your train signaling Right, exactly.
Speaker 1: You continuously deploy for things that matter less.
Speaker 1: Yeah And it's safe to you know.
Speaker 1: Only if you're basically saying I'm gonna put this small safety net of the automated tests and if anything can beat that I'm willing to let it deploy even if it's busted.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right if you're not willing to let something deploy that's even a little bit busted Which you shouldn't be for medical software train signaling satellites in space, you know Anything right.
Speaker 1: then you shouldn't be using continuous deployment, right?
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 0: Well depending on because deployment can CD gets into the idea of you'll have many layers of staged environment you could.
Speaker 1: you could have in those in those instances the continuous testing where I am at Lee tests before being merged and They just don't automatically deploy.
Speaker 0: Well, I get a previous company where we had like we had a continuous Only with no CD.
Speaker 0: We had a CI environment, but we also had CD to a beta environment.
Speaker 0: That was basically like a mirror image of production, but was like like it just like all the data in production There's monitoring software was copied over to this other environment.
Speaker 0: So one test could be written against that holistic environment and two people would notice if that environment broke.
Speaker 0: But so we could continuously deploy Beyond just the integration testing to catch more holistic issues, but there was no automated and also to production.
Speaker 0: But we did have a way and something had to be continuously deployed into that beta environment and at some point Someone would basically freeze it and say okay We're done deploying.
Speaker 0: That was the last commit.
Speaker 0: and then there's an automated process to deploy from beta to production.
Speaker 0: But that's when you start getting into enterprise software or big complex environments.
Speaker 0: but that's also where continuous integration really starts to shine because that's where Imagine everything's got talked about.
Speaker 0: is one team in a company that has like 400 different teams or multiple companies in a consortium that are sharing code or providing joint services or all sorts of nonsense like that?
Speaker 0: That's where your continuous deployment is often into a testbed Environment where all the other people you interact with have their own CI CD into that testbed environment.
Speaker 0: and then there's a meta level of hey Is the testbed working?
Speaker 0: because if you do something that breaks the testbed you would have broken it for Everybody in production if you deployed right?
Speaker 1: So yeah, that's that's actually what happens that like most of the places I worked where it's you you push your code, right?
Speaker 1: It passes the tests.
Speaker 1: then if you merge your code It'll go to like it'll actually be deployed but it'll be deployed to like a QA environment Yeah, and then to be deployed to a higher environment There'll be like another branch like a staging branch And if you what you'll do is you'll just go with like one click manually though, right?
Speaker 1: Intentionally someone will say I like what's on QA right now.
Speaker 1: It looks good, right?
Speaker 1: We're gonna merge that to staging and now when you when they do that merge Right the tests will and deployment will run.
Speaker 1: and now that code they just merged Will now be deployed onto the staging environment and then if they like that then they'll apply like a tag like git tag 2.0.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: I bet we made extensive use of that tagging especially because we might get something that's going all the way into prod But then we find a bug that's only serious for like one type of client or like one use case.
Speaker 0: We could continue to go into prod but we have a tag branch to fix the bug for a narrow patch We could release later, right?
Speaker 1: But it's like you make a tag and it's like if a tag appears Then that suddenly triggers the CD and it gets deployed to the production environment for real.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so it's like you're it's on.
Speaker 1: all these deployments are happening automatically.
Speaker 1: you don't need a human being to go and be like go to the servers and Push buttons to make the deploy if you're like.
Speaker 0: if you're like dragging binary files with win SCP or something like.
Speaker 1: That's what you did back in the day.
Speaker 1: It's like oh I got to deploy the code on.
Speaker 1: you know It's like I want to update my website.
Speaker 1: I guess I have to SSH to the server.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I copy copy my code to the server unzip my code on the server Restart, you know sudu Apache restart, right?
Speaker 0: I remember in ancient times the first time I encountered Jenkins was like wait so I can click deploy and It'll actually just deploy that.
Speaker 1: like that build you just automate all that parts all those parts just automatic They just happen, right?
Speaker 1: so all you need to do is through your version control and you know Testing is like a wall to keep things from going up to the no getting deployed.
Speaker 1: You can just do all that stuff.
Speaker 1: and now the greatest thing about this is that as a company It saves you a lot of time.
Speaker 1: You don't have to hire as many people like admin people, right?
Speaker 1: You just hire a devops person who you will pay less because you're evil.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's a set and the dev I find.
Speaker 0: in many industries devops gets paid more than engineering.
Speaker 1: now I'm not I'm not saying the devops person gets paid less than the admin person.
Speaker 1: I'm saying you would need a team of admin.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that is true, right.
Speaker 1: to do it You would need a team of admins.
Speaker 1: who to do like all these deployments and things, right?
Speaker 0: Well, like back before DevOps is a wise one.
Speaker 1: devops person will set up the CI and CD systems and maintain them And then that's it.
Speaker 0: Like when I worked at a broker-dealer a long time ago like our ops team did both the devops and like deployment stuff, but also the administration and The troubleshooting like we're all does in one team.
Speaker 0: But but what you just said that was also an environment where it was so long ago.
Speaker 0: I can talk about it in detail.
Speaker 0: This is the furthest extent I've ever seen of this.
Speaker 0: like environment staging Five levels is like the furthest you want to go unless you're working on the deadly stuff We just talked about.
Speaker 0: we had dev.
Speaker 0: dev was gate was the contract was dev is not Guaranteed to be stable.
Speaker 0: like do not rely on dev being stable.
Speaker 0: dev will break all the time.
Speaker 0: That's expected.
Speaker 0: Then we had QA one.
Speaker 0: someone's dev signed off saying yeah, this is good it would automatically just deploy to QA and QA could do whatever testing they wanted to do.
Speaker 0: then we had Beyond that we had a UAT of all.
Speaker 0: right now the users like the devops people will Deploy this in their environment and poke at it and make sure they understand it and they're happy with it.
Speaker 0: pre-prod which the sole purpose of pre-prod was to be a mirror image of production to make sure that it acted exactly Exactly the way production is supposed to act.
Speaker 0: and then finally production.
Speaker 0: it took us two weeks to deploy software But every step was automated along the way except the human parts of like hey Does the thing actually work?
Speaker 1: or hey verify like sign off that you actually looked at this before we went live Mm-hmm, and you know even for things that aren't on a server for example Right if you have some sort of auto update platform, right?
Speaker 1: So let's say you have a game on Steam for example.
Speaker 1: Right you could continue.
Speaker 1: you're working on your game.
Speaker 1: every time someone a developer on the game pushes something out it builds Right and it auto builds right you know.
Speaker 1: so you don't?
Speaker 1: the person at their computer doesn't need to like run the build and then Go take a drink.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right they push their code They keep they make a new branch And they work on something else and they'll get emails if that build failed and have to go fix it and fix that branch.
Speaker 0: My last place so everyone got an email.
Speaker 1: if someone broke the build okay sure but like you know that build is happening Automatically on some other server.
Speaker 1: you can just code code code focusing on your code Right not worrying about the building and the deploying when you're the developer right and then you know once you know if you're Sitting at the game studio.
Speaker 1: You're like.
Speaker 1: Oh, I like what I see and the dev build right now.
Speaker 1: I think that's word that has enough stuff in it that we should push that out to our Players.
Speaker 1: right so you push a button, and it will make up.
Speaker 1: It'll make a build and send it to steam and then everyone will get an auto update.
Speaker 1: Yeah Your new vert you write your.
Speaker 1: you write your update notes or your update notes for your iPad app or whatever it is goes to The App Store.
Speaker 1: right you wouldn't do it too frequently.
Speaker 1: You don't want updates every day But you do it.
Speaker 0: You know once a week once a month whenever Practical example overwatch right they have the real game.
Speaker 0: Everything scout just described.
Speaker 0: they also have up like a play a testing Instance of the game and you can tell your client I want to play on the test and they just continuously deploy like balance changes and tweaks there all the time.
Speaker 0: It's just like whatever are they experimenting with right now is just there.
Speaker 0: yep.
Speaker 1: So yeah, if you are developing software in 2020 right before You start if you're if you're planning on doing something that's going to be a project that is like small And we'll just like end mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: right you probably don't need to waste time setting this up Right.
Speaker 1: you need to if your project is going to be long-lived right.
Speaker 1: so a website You're going to keep maintaining even you know a small website I guess for as a web any website That's small enough you would just use Squarespace or a card or one of those auto website things.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like don't write a website unless you have a good or WordPress, right?
Speaker 1: We're talking about.
Speaker 1: we're talking about you write a website because you're making web application right developing something continually, right?
Speaker 1: Any?
Speaker 1: or a game that you're gonna not just release and move on to the next thing But you're gonna keep patching because you have players right.
Speaker 1: you know something with users That's always existing.
Speaker 1: that needs work.
Speaker 1: You should start by making a blank project that has nothing in it right.
Speaker 1: so like say you're making a website.
Speaker 1: You would just set up a blank website That's a blank page right and set up a server so that it continuously tests.
Speaker 1: It will run no tests at the start right, but it'll run the test runner And it'll say there are zero tests, and they all passed right and then Automatically deploy that to a server that will have a blank web page that you visit with your domain.
Speaker 1: you go to your website.
Speaker 1: There's a blank page there And you have that working to start with.
Speaker 1: as soon as you do that now working on the website will be so easy.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right.
Speaker 1: You'll just start working like all right.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna make my home page make a home page.
Speaker 1: you make it.
Speaker 1: Oh, it's on the server five And there's a test.
Speaker 1: you make it one test for it.
Speaker 1: This is does the home page load?
Speaker 1: so you and you you'll push and like the home page is on the server And it loads good.
Speaker 0: It feels just like an ancient times where I'd be like sitting there in VI like editing my web page.
Speaker 0: I write out the changes and then hit f5 on the browser that was pointed at the server I was on physically, but with appropriate layers of protection.
Speaker 1: Yep, all right, so let's briefly talk about some of the options you have for doing this right.
Speaker 1: so the thing that I've I guess I'm not really a fan Is the thing.
Speaker 1: is it for all of these choices out there and in that our circle CI or or GitHub actions or?
Speaker 1: Jenkins?
Speaker 0: yes Jenkins is the only one I'm deeply familiar with because I don't write code anymore.
Speaker 0: I haven't write code.
Speaker 1: get lab get lab includes one now.
Speaker 1: get lab get lab.
Speaker 1: I guess included one before get hub.
Speaker 1: Yeah, actually get lab CI.
Speaker 1: of all these options.
Speaker 1: I'm actually not a huge fan of any of.
Speaker 1: They're all sorted janky Right.
Speaker 1: the none of them are awesome and great and beautiful.
Speaker 0: Well Jenkins is pretty good once it's set up.
Speaker 1: But no no they all all of them seem to work well when set up.
Speaker 1: It's just the.
Speaker 1: setting them up is not great.
Speaker 1: Docker is always involved.
Speaker 1: YAML is usually involved.
Speaker 1: right.
Speaker 1: at least forget hub actions and circle CI.
Speaker 1: YAML is involved.
Speaker 1: So it's like none of them are great right?
Speaker 1: so you want to pick one that meets your needs right And it meets your pricing and your your whatever right.
Speaker 1: so you look at how much they cost.
Speaker 1: Look at whether you need your own hardware right.
Speaker 1: so Jenkins would be one that you're gonna use because you're setting it up on your Own hardware right and you're installing Jenkins, and you're configuring it And you have your own machines where the builds are gonna run.
Speaker 1: You know circle CI would be like you define these docker containers in these YAML files and then Circle CI is basically selling you their cloud servers, which are going to run your you know builds right?
Speaker 1: GitLab or get hub are the ones that they have.
Speaker 1: are sort of giving you the choice, right?
Speaker 1: It's like you know.
Speaker 1: you can install GitLab on your own servers Or you can pay for hosted GitLab you know and there's some amount of free service They'll give you.
Speaker 1: circle CI has an amount of free service They give you as well right, but you're basically.
Speaker 1: I think OZ also has some CI solutions.
Speaker 1: They have like OZ code deploy for the deploying part.
Speaker 1: I forget what they have for this the testing part.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't actually know offhand But I have seen people with the integration testing use AWS specifically to spin up like external environments That will hit your servers or whatever it is.
Speaker 0: you're hosting your full thing on From the outside like clients to do like full end-to-end testing yeah, and all is.
Speaker 1: the difference is when you get you and you use like a Solution like circle CI or get hub actions or GitLab actions with Docker right is they're getting their machines from somewhere else?
Speaker 1: Right like OZ?
Speaker 1: probably Right and they're spinning up your your your your docker containers or whatever.
Speaker 1: right when you use OZ For your stuff.
Speaker 1: right you could actually spin up an EC2 instance right run install your whole application On it test it and then turn off the delete the instance.
Speaker 1: right you can do shit like that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and that really depends on the scale or Google Cloud as well, right?
Speaker 1: So
Speaker 0: you if you're in college right now like you're like you're gonna start your career Learning one or two of these and like learning how to set this stuff up will make you Surprisingly invaluable because no one wants to deal with this crap just for
Speaker 1: however long these things have been around.
Speaker 1: The people just really don't.
Speaker 1: I think a because it's sort of a set it and forget it thing where people tend to work on It at the beginning and then not touch it again once it's there.
Speaker 0: I've been.
Speaker 0: I've been in instances where the jenkin builds failing and the problem is Jenkins but no one remembers how Jenkins was set up exactly or the?
Speaker 1: Now he said it and forget it.
Speaker 1: but like one person said it no I'll sit.
Speaker 0: oh yeah the person who had set up that Jenkins had retired and no one touched that Jenkins.
Speaker 0: They kept adding unit tests, but no one touched the Jenkins server.
Speaker 1: So it's like.
Speaker 1: the beauty of it is also the harm right?
Speaker 1: is that the people that it makes developers lives great because you just Focus on your code and this beautiful system takes care of the deploying and the testing and it's great.
Speaker 1: But if you ever have to mess with that it sucks.
Speaker 1: so learn How those things work.
Speaker 1: learn a few different ones.
Speaker 0: learn one of them in detail like you don't have to get expert at all of Them because every job you work will have a different thing.
Speaker 0: you're gonna have to learn.
Speaker 0: But right if you know like if you know Jenkins really well That will give you the tools to be able to learn any of these other things really well, right?
Speaker 1: But you know mostly it's that once even if you're doing a small product Project just for you all on your own, right?
Speaker 1: Having this set up to just deploy your little web app is gonna make you so much more productive Right that you're actually have a higher chance of actually delivering your product.
Speaker 1: right just psychologically speaking.
Speaker 1: Right because of you know not having to like test and deploy all the time.
Speaker 1: you can just zone in right write code and Do one feature at a time and each feature as you develop it will be automatically deployed And you're gonna get closer to that sort of like instant gratification.
Speaker 1: you got back in the day writing like with like logo or We're like you would see your application like come together like as you're writing it And I think for most programmers and developers.
Speaker 1: I know the psychology of that.
Speaker 1: you know Instant gratification of write code thing is better.
Speaker 1: right.
Speaker 1: you know having it immediately go out It's hugely beneficial.
Speaker 1: And
Speaker 0: if you end up working for like a big enterprise company or like you know these like work for a Microsoft Or one of these big companies with huge armies of people writing very complex stacks of code The reality is you've got to know your way around these types of environments and these types of tools Because while you can work without them in small projects like Scott said it makes you faster and makes you better and probably makes you Happier in a big project.
Speaker 0: It's impossible to make progress without this stuff.
Speaker 1: yep.
Speaker 1: So yeah like for you know I just set it up for you know the new I'm trying to fix front row crew comm.
Speaker 1: it needs a lot of work as it does.
Speaker 0: that website is old.
Speaker 1: It hasn't been updated in a zillion years right and every time I have to make a change to it Right like I think like what happened recently Oh Libsyn changed their FTP or something.
Speaker 1: yeah for the automatic episode uploading.
Speaker 0: I think the last change before that was you prevented me from accidentally uploading a wav file.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, something like that right.
Speaker 1: so for me to fix that because it's so old and unmaintained I have to like go SSH to the server and mess around.
Speaker 1: I have no way to test.
Speaker 1: I can have a local environment or anything right.
Speaker 1: so I'm basically setting up a blank website that auto Deploys so that it can make a blank front row crew comm Right out of nut and then once I have that and then from once I have that set up I'll be able to update front row crew comm beautifully going forward and also bring in developers You know to help with.
Speaker 1: you know other stuff right.
Speaker 1: you'll people get us push changes And they'll be tested and deployed if I you know if I merge them right.
Speaker 1: so It's.
Speaker 1: it's great even for tiny projects like a podcast website if you're writing it yourself Which you probably shouldn't.
Speaker 1: but that's what we did cuz.
Speaker 0: yeah well because we started Podcasting before.
Speaker 0: there were a lot of things that support started with WordPress.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but we still wrote code to glue it all together.
Speaker 1: We could have kept with WordPress forever.
Speaker 0: We didn't use lips and do website because it barely worked back then.
Speaker 1: no So yes, that's the basics of CI CD.
Speaker 1: if you want to know more just google it and read a ton of documentation.
Speaker 1: the documentation Sucks, I've been reading it for some of these things.
Speaker 1: But if you just just keep working at it until you get there ask for help.
Speaker 1: Support whatever you'll you'll you'll get there and the free versions of most of them are And more than enough for a small personal project.
Speaker 1: You're only gonna run into having to pay money like.
Speaker 1: I think one of them was like thousands of minutes a month of free Compute time and I did my test.
Speaker 1: my test take 30 seconds for me to make thousands of minutes in a month.
Speaker 1: You know how many patches I would have to write.
Speaker 1: It's like it's not gonna happen.
Speaker 1: so It's gonna be free for you unless you're a big project.
Speaker 0: All right This has been geek nights with rim and Scott.
Speaker 0: special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music catley for web design and brand Ok for the logos.
Speaker 1: be sure to visit our website at front row.
Speaker 1: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 0: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows It's actually recorded at night and the patreon patrons for this episode of geek nights are Alan Joyce I'm gonna kill just like a dude guy charge option.
Speaker 0: They're thirst for hydrated again and sailor vista shrimp on her old j-band scrap bench.
Speaker 0: But she packed my suitcase and set me on my way.
Speaker 0: Sean Klein you hold the key to my heart dread.
Speaker 0: lily tennenberry Chris midkiff Clinton Walton Finn Nicholas Brandau Ryan Perrin Ren from New Zealand Chris Reimer and a bunch of people who don't want me to Say their name, but now I leave you with You graciously, but gratuitously.
Speaker 1: Grasp some grass.
Speaker 1: the staff feels warm and almost alive in your hand Here an eerie voice in your head This I must first do the sacrifice of life for one of love.
Speaker 1: you find yourself letting go of the staff very quickly.
Speaker 0: I Am Nikolai.
Speaker 0: have you seen my honor honor.
Speaker 0: have you seen my honor?
Speaker 1: You tell the burger Meister about how you came here.
Speaker 1: Do you expect me to believe such a story that you could walk out of that cave alive?
Speaker 1: That the cave would be open?
Speaker 1: Tell me no more lies.
Speaker 1: Play mordavian style.
Speaker 1: They stare at you in astonishment.
Speaker 1: You say you are a hero.
Speaker 1: Well, we will judge you here by your actions rather than your words.
Speaker 1: Magic is a very dangerous thing.
Speaker 1: We do not trust those who use or are used by magic.
Speaker 1: Take certain you do not give us any more cause for alarm.
Speaker 0: I Am a farmer of pumpkins and corn and a person of great importance here and lovely mordavia.
Speaker 1: Listen, I'm telling you Igor's death must be avenged.
Speaker 1: Pleased to meet you.
Speaker 1: I'm Ivan an elephant herder.
Speaker 1: Unfortunately, there are no more elephants in mordavia.
Speaker 1: So Businesses kind of falling off a tad.
Speaker 1: Guy, is it just me?
Speaker 0: or is mordavia a wonderful place?
Speaker 1: How are you kidding?
Speaker 1: it's the greatest.
Speaker 1: there's many places to go things to see.
Speaker 1: are you kidding Right.
Speaker 1: Let's not forget that scenic cemetery to the east of town.
Speaker 1: Everyone here is nothing but grins real friendly.
Speaker 1: Yeah, except we don't know you we don't like strangers or anyone else.
Speaker 1: that's weird and doesn't belong.