Speaker 0: It's Wednesday April 1st 2020.
Speaker 0: I'm rim.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott and this is geek nights tonight.
Speaker 0: We're talking about the manga gambling apocalypse.
Speaker 1: Kaiji Let's do this.
Speaker 1: I was very happy that this year that the Internet.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the internet sucks day was mostly canceled and in the places where it was not canceled It was a decent mostly decent.
Speaker 1: The only the only fool like attempting to deceive people that I saw today that worked not on me, but on other people is someone posted like NHL salary cap is gonna likely be 74 million or whatever.
Speaker 1: it was like.
Speaker 1: it was like a low number Right and everyone's like oh no my tea every team is ruined.
Speaker 1: No, right because it's based on like, you know revenues or something, right?
Speaker 1: It's gonna be.
Speaker 1: But what they did is they took a tweet from like 2014 And they posted it and it's like hoping people wouldn't look at the date.
Speaker 1: So it was a tweet from a legit sports journalist saying this right That's well done not on April 1st, not in 2020.
Speaker 0: I Feel like it is posted.
Speaker 1: It's like read it as if it was new And some people didn't look at it.
Speaker 0: and we're like, oh the strategic ancient retweet will be mine.
Speaker 1: This is the thing that you like, you know made sense to be and you know, like you sort of knew was coming, right?
Speaker 1: It was extremely clever.
Speaker 0: We actually did a good one on geek nights once a long time ago Did we?
Speaker 0: we did a moderately elaborate one.
Speaker 0: what we did is We recorded and we recorded the show and then we recorded a bunch of extra dialogue Like first I record I made all this recording of like noise happening like far away from the microphone and we recorded a bit where you and I were talking about three or four specific forum users in the old geek nights forum and Acting as though we run those accounts and planning what flame war we were gonna start that weekend
Speaker 1: And
Speaker 0: I had that place.
Speaker 0: So the odd like.
Speaker 0: basically it sounds like we forgot to stop the record button and our outro music plays but you hear us like talking to each other in the background like Okay shows done whatever and then there's silence and noise for a while and then like five or six minutes later We've walk quote walk back into the room and start talking about.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'm gonna post his Killarney tonight.
Speaker 0: start a real fucking flame war.
Speaker 0: Let's go.
Speaker 0: Okay, I was the only good one we ever did.
Speaker 1: we got some people if you think that's good.
Speaker 0: Okay I think that's pretty funny.
Speaker 0: We fooled people and we did not just lie to them.
Speaker 0: We just we put something out there and people believed it and it was moderately low-key funny and then it ended.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I guess it didn't cause too much harm.
Speaker 0: now That's really Killarney's gone, but that's probably for the best Hmm.
Speaker 0: Wonder what that dude's still alive.
Speaker 1: I don't even know.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's a lot.
Speaker 1: There's a lot of people who listen to geek nights a long time ago.
Speaker 1: You know came in and out of the community and you know, you don't track.
Speaker 1: It's just some internet name.
Speaker 1: How many names are there on the internet?
Speaker 1: I don't hate people.
Speaker 1: It happens.
Speaker 0: Everybody was gaga.
Speaker 0: All right, all right, so there is actually big anime news like anime news.
Speaker 1: that's April not April Fool's.
Speaker 0: It's so big that when I saw the headline, I assumed it was an April Fool's joke, and now I'm just sad Right.
Speaker 1: So the past few Wednesday episodes of geek nights only animes we've talked about are ones from science are ooh and Masaaki wasa because
Speaker 0: their outputs been crazy and they're in a thousand because
Speaker 1: basically ever since Yuasa and do what's-her-name Choi and young started the science our studio back in the day They did their Adventure Time episode.
Speaker 1: They did a bunch of movies, right?
Speaker 1: By the way What's it called?
Speaker 1: Lou over the wall.
Speaker 1: That's right is on Netflix right now.
Speaker 0: Oh, oh, yeah If it anyway if it is the vampire dog one anyway.
Speaker 1: Um Ever since they started their output has been insane and among the best anime there is both in TV and Cinema, right?
Speaker 1: So and a lot of their stuff has just been coming out lately.
Speaker 1: Rapid-fire right.
Speaker 1: not because they did that much at once But because I guess sort of like the timing the way things worked out is like, you know They're new Isaac and TV series out now a movie They did ride your wave last year and but it came to the theaters recently, right?
Speaker 1: So it's like all their stuff is hitting it once but the news is that you wasa is retiring as president.
Speaker 1: So I guess he's not like gonna stay at these that he's like leaving the company.
Speaker 1: He's not like moving down to another position.
Speaker 0: Yep, it's more.
Speaker 0: It's almost like a rock.
Speaker 0: It's a robert ku situation.
Speaker 1: It's like he worked too hard and now he's like, alright I'm out.
Speaker 1: Peace.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna go take a rest and maybe work.
Speaker 1: He's not leaving the industry Right.
Speaker 1: Yes, just leaving the company and he'll do something else later.
Speaker 0: So on one hand I'm worried because he definitely in at least in some of their works did the like Ghibli style.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna like make all the storyboards myself by hand and I'm gonna do a hundred percent creative control of these bits.
Speaker 0: But on the other hand he and the studio built a really good Pipeline to elevate people and give that like raise them up in the anime industry in a very old-school manner Right, and it's like no one else is leaving right?
Speaker 1: So it's like, you know, so on the one hand it's like yeah they're most important creator who got all the credit directed all the big works and Drew all the storyboards by themselves is leaving.
Speaker 1: So there's some question as to what.
Speaker 1: they're not closing the studio So they're still working on stuff, right?
Speaker 1: The question is what can the remaining people produce without him?
Speaker 1: is creative input, right if he's doing if he's elsewhere?
Speaker 0: But one thing that could happen but this powerhouse studio We gotta watch is who are the key animators who have been doing a lot more key?
Speaker 0: Animation that are now gonna get there like early assistant director role.
Speaker 1: Yeah, who knows?
Speaker 1: You know, it's like on the one hand it could be a situation where what's the studio of the people who left Ghibli.
Speaker 0: Oh When they made witches flower, yeah, and it's kind of meh.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right air says Ghibli.
Speaker 1: so like is science.
Speaker 1: are?
Speaker 1: we're gonna now degrade and become a lot like a you know, a Bad version of its of its former self, right?
Speaker 1: or if they can maintain which I believe that they actually could You know just someone else drawing the storyboards, right?
Speaker 1: Then this could actually be viewed as a good thing because you also is not leaving the industry, right?
Speaker 1: so it's like if you're an artist right and you can make you're like a fountain that art comes out of right and You could go and just keep making your art on your own.
Speaker 1: But if you set other people up and make them artists and so that their fountains spit out all sorts of wonderful art You know by helping them out forming a studio, right and then you leave.
Speaker 1: Well, you're still a fountain of art.
Speaker 1: It's not like you suck now as long as he works on something somewhere.
Speaker 0: But also if you've created a structure that is conducive to creative people making good creative works Like if you built up.
Speaker 0: if you it's like if you're prime a pump.
Speaker 0: if you prime the pump and it starts pumping and you walk Away, it'll just keep pumping if you didn't and then you can go pump and then you can go pump another pump.
Speaker 1: They can't pump itself, right?
Speaker 1: So this could be a positive in which case where science sorrow will continue to do great and then he'll go do great somewhere else hopefully less vigorously And You know more more restfully, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, but yeah, we'll see how either one Goes and the future.
Speaker 1: and we still have you know, there's still plenty of works from them.
Speaker 1: Most of you probably haven't seen so yep.
Speaker 0: So speaking of keep your hands off a second Emily and I did watch it all the way to the end because it's only 12 Episodes.
Speaker 0: like it's a pretty short show.
Speaker 0: So we watched it to the end and the geek bite.
Speaker 0: I'm not gonna give a full like spoiler your final thoughts But spoilers.
Speaker 0: they make more anime.
Speaker 0: But the show not only continues to be good But it doubles down on all of its themes and also really gets into the characters backstories in a written nice Nuanced way.
Speaker 0: like the ending is just so satisfying and the end is basically they make a big animation and I'm not gonna spoil Like the things that happen as they make the animation.
Speaker 0: It's all great.
Speaker 0: a certain character solves a DVD distribution problem with a threat with threatening people with an angle grinder at one point.
Speaker 0: but The end is basically they make a longer form Animation.
Speaker 0: that's really heartfelt and really sad and it kind of blows up the world Mm-hmm, or at least it blows up the entire town in the metaphorical way of the show.
Speaker 0: Yep, like it changed it.
Speaker 0: It's very clear that the end was that that anime they made changed the entire town Even if they can't see it yet.
Speaker 0: So the show is a hundred percent worth watching to the end.
Speaker 0: It just gets better and better as it goes on.
Speaker 0: a plus beginning to end no breaks.
Speaker 1: All right Well, I finished watching that Castlevania season 3.
Speaker 1: Oh, I gotta get on that.
Speaker 1: So cuz I had only watched half of it.
Speaker 1: I think last time we had a Wednesday show, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, and then basically I you know that has these four plot lines going on with these four different sets of characters and four different places Even though some of them are on the move and some of them are sitting still.
Speaker 1: so I like snatch style.
Speaker 1: So what I thought was gonna happen is that like snatch all the characters are gonna physically Meet in one place via some means right.
Speaker 1: at least one of the plot lines had characters that were on the move via boat and walking right And some other ones might have had teleportation with magic.
Speaker 1: Who knows?
Speaker 1: But actually what happened was they didn't meet but instead they all had Climaxes in their individual plots Simultaneously in the timeline.
Speaker 1: So it's like at this exact point in time in the universe of the of Castlevania two of the storylines had met major sex scenes.
Speaker 1: Two of them had major war scenes at the same time and the end of the show is cutting between the two.
Speaker 1: It's like war sex.
Speaker 1: war sex back to war one.
Speaker 1: sex to War number two.
Speaker 1: sex number two.
Speaker 1: back to the beginning.
Speaker 1: Invested in this now, so that's what happens at the end of you know.
Speaker 1: Yes, three on Netflix.
Speaker 1: if you're into that you can go for it.
Speaker 0: I mean, I am deeply into that and I feel like I'm just.
Speaker 0: that's gonna be the next.
Speaker 1: it's obviously not safe.
Speaker 1: It's not safe for work.
Speaker 0: I Feel like my mom and dad will both like it.
Speaker 0: So I got my mom to watch it.
Speaker 1: probably my mom watched it.
Speaker 0: Yeah Cuz my mom was really into vampire hunter deed like that's.
Speaker 0: she got me to watch it.
Speaker 0: That was the first anime I ever saw cuz she made me watch it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, my mom loves harsh.
Speaker 0: Yeah So, uh in some other news, it looks like Viz is licensing the Super Mario Brothers manga mania.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't know if people know about this manga, but way way way back in the day Like way back.
Speaker 1: I was a book off which is where you buy the cheap used.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we're talking like early 90s Right, right, right.
Speaker 1: and I was in the book off looking for something to buy that was cheap.
Speaker 1: that maybe would be readable almost.
Speaker 1: So there was a Mario manga that was for kids.
Speaker 1: It was like Super Mario and I'm like and it was really cute.
Speaker 1: and I was like, oh well That's at least if I if I ever learned Japanese spoilers I didn't.
Speaker 1: I Could read that because it's for children and if not, I could at least understand what's going on because it's Mario.
Speaker 1: I know the characters and the pictures are cute.
Speaker 1: So and that's never good probably be published in the u.s.
Speaker 1: So I've had the volume one of that manga for a super long time And what do you know?
Speaker 1: this is bringing it over.
Speaker 0: if you don't this manga is actually been running Yeah since 1991 and Cora Cora comics is when it started and from anime news networking is the Shigaka kon published the 55th volume of it this year in January.
Speaker 1: Yep, it's still.
Speaker 1: it's just a Mario comic for kids that's been going for like ever.
Speaker 1: It's like if you're an elementary school kid and you're like Mario in Japan.
Speaker 1: You are well fed.
Speaker 0: It's just see it like the impression.
Speaker 0: I've read a bunch of Scandalations of like bits of it before and it's just cute and funny and like all the characters are great like peach is just hilarious Mario's grade.
Speaker 0: and yeah,
Speaker 1: yeah I'll probably I'm probably just gonna buy volume one in English to put it next to the Japanese volume one in English to be like Haha, and you know look at them together and you know, so apparently
Speaker 0: this is a compilation of Hand-picked stories from the Mario.
Speaker 1: Oh, it's not just.
Speaker 0: it's not just volume one.
Speaker 0: it looks like it's a hand-picked collection of the ones that were the funniest or the most popular or Cetera.
Speaker 1: Well, that's still worth that's still worth buying.
Speaker 1: But I think if you look at the actual volume one I have I think it's almost sort of like an origin story in many Ways a little bit not not completely, right?
Speaker 1: But it's sort of like I think they Yoshi hatches from an egg at one point.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like, you know, so you guess you're gonna miss out on that unless they choose that.
Speaker 0: they might choose that.
Speaker 1: Maybe who knows they got how many years of stuff to choose?
Speaker 1: So me your Mario and they I guess because you assume anyone reading it knows Mario.
Speaker 1: You don't need to have any of that, you know continued continuity.
Speaker 1: You could just pick random stuff.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you don't.
Speaker 0: you don't need to know the lore of the Super Mario verse to enjoy.
Speaker 1: if you buy this, you know Right.
Speaker 0: All you need to know is Mario's the red guy Luigi's the green guy and poop is the bad guy.
Speaker 1: Yep, Daisy's the princess.
Speaker 0: Yeah peaches the Francis and mushrooms are complicated But anyway things of the day.
Speaker 0: so speaking of anime and animation a lot of shows are gonna be on hiatus because the studios Can't necessarily have all their workers coming in.
Speaker 0: a lot of stuff is just delayed like across the board all over the world but adult swim just release like couple days ago.
Speaker 0: a Long short like this is almost six minutes long.
Speaker 0: It's a really it's Rick and Morty But it's basically Rick and Morty as lone wolf and cub.
Speaker 0: It's obviously done in like a what?
Speaker 0: It's a 3d CG kind of thing Like.
Speaker 0: it's not the level of animation of the show, but it's really well made Actually really good.
Speaker 0: Like I enjoyed this Quite a bit and I kind of combination is that it's basically just Rick is the lone wolf and Morty is the cub.
Speaker 1: Who out there besides like you knows both Rick and Morty and lone wolf and cub?
Speaker 0: I honestly think would argue that the majority of Rick and Morty fans who are not the shitty ones who hate the show now Do in fact know about both.
Speaker 0: the overlap is heavy.
Speaker 0: Aha, I love their shit out of Rick and Morty.
Speaker 0: I think it's a pretty great show and I've still to this day.
Speaker 0: I give props to the creators for recognizing that they had a toxic fan base and Specifically targeting the two seasons they made after that to drive that part of the fan base away.
Speaker 0: Mmm, like they made Rick the enemy they made him the shitty villain because you're not it's it's.
Speaker 0: you know It's kind of like what happened to Rick and Morty was kind of like what happened with Breaking Bad.
Speaker 0: Shitty people watch Breaking Bad and said Wow Walter.
Speaker 0: I want to be like him.
Speaker 0: He's the hero and Normal people watch it like wow, this is the story of a man becoming a complete piece of shit.
Speaker 1: Well, I think that's just a problem in all me.
Speaker 1: on all fictional media where whichever character is the main character Yeah, even kind of with them right whether they're bad or good and you can see that in Death Note Godfather, you know, whatever Right.
Speaker 1: It's like, you know they just because the person gets all the screen time and you you you get you feel closer to that person and Sympathize empathize with them regardless of whether they're good or bad or you're supposed to or not.
Speaker 1: And so I just generally You know, not that I create that much fiction, right?
Speaker 1: But if I did I would shy away from ever making the main character the bad character.
Speaker 0: No Unless it's about them.
Speaker 1: Basically, I'm saying you know, what should ever do that?
Speaker 1: I'm just saying, you know, it's it's a dangerous place to tread.
Speaker 0: Yep But like a house of cards did that like it gets her really on.
Speaker 0: you know The main guy's side Kevin Spacey for a while and then it there's a point where the show is just like you realize I'm the bad guy, right Right.
Speaker 0: I am the enemy and it actually handles that reasonably well until the show went off the rails and got stupid.
Speaker 0: but I can't actually blame the people who made that show because the show is based on house of cards is actually based on a BBC show from a long time ago about Parliament.
Speaker 0: They had to adapt it to American politics and the BBC show was apparently also Critically acclaimed and fantastic for a little while and then went off the rails and got stupid Uh-huh.
Speaker 0: So they went off there.
Speaker 0: They went off a different set of rails and also got stupid.
Speaker 1: Okay, somebody got.
Speaker 1: so my thing of the day we just talked about, you know, I see a good house a Good house.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we thought about science are overworking and such right?
Speaker 1: So you want to talk about overworking.
Speaker 1: you go back to the Tezuka days in 1963. here is a video of the studio They're making the actual Astro Boy in the 60s.
Speaker 1: I can see them drawing You know frames and cells that I have an episode that I have seen of the original Astro Boy.
Speaker 1: Yes, someone went in there and filmed them making the show.
Speaker 1: it's pretty crazy What's going on inside that animation studio when they didn't have computers or anything.
Speaker 1: And they're churning out, you know, crazy amounts of Astro Boy by hand, you know low quality high quantity I mean, it's all Japanese.
Speaker 1: I can't tell what they're saying.
Speaker 1: So it doesn't have subtitles.
Speaker 1: Maybe someone else can tell but you don't need it because the video footage alone is Pretty unbeatable.
Speaker 0: definitely a bootleg account because it has 48 subscribers.
Speaker 0: The logo just says guy next Yep, and this video has like less than a thousand views.
Speaker 1: Yeah, who cares?
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: This is super cool.
Speaker 0: I hope it stays up long enough for you guys to watch it.
Speaker 0: Yeah in the meta moment I didn't read Genji because I read Kaiji.
Speaker 0: As you know, we're not doing any conventions for the foreseeable future.
Speaker 0: We're recording the show remotely.
Speaker 0: So it'll sound a little weird.
Speaker 0: We're still tweaking the pipeline.
Speaker 0: Hopefully we can start live-streaming the show on YouTube again.
Speaker 0: I'm doing a test of a pipeline for that today And if that test works starting next week, you'll be able to watch the live stream again Which I know more of you look forward to than I expected.
Speaker 1: hmm The only other meta thing is that we do have a geek nights Discord.
Speaker 1: if you come to the geek nights forum where you should come Community dot front recruit calm or our you contact us via anyway You know, you could find the link.
Speaker 0: someone will give you the link or you'll find it in the forum.
Speaker 0: We'll put that one tiny barrier.
Speaker 1: Maybe I'll tweet it just now or something It's like, you know, but yeah, you can get into the geek night semi mostly official discord server And in that server there's a lot of streaming going on both by us and by other listeners because it's way easier to stream on discord to a Handful of people in a voice chat.
Speaker 1: if I go on twitch only a handful of people are gonna watch anyway.
Speaker 1: So why should I go through all the hassle of setting up twitch?
Speaker 1: I'll just go to discord and do it.
Speaker 1: You know, we'll still do some streamings on twitches and youtubes.
Speaker 1: You know for things that should be publicly broadcasted and are worth the hassle.
Speaker 1: But no if I'm just playing a video game at night, it's like why should I said I'm not a pro streamer No one not right.
Speaker 1: So why should I hassle?
Speaker 1: Yeah instead of twitch, but then discord is so easy Why not stream on discord to a couple listeners who happen to care?
Speaker 0: Yeah, you want to watch me just like playing a random Civ game for a little while Like I and it's and it's voice chat.
Speaker 1: So you're voice chatting with whoever is doing the streaming.
Speaker 1: So that's that's fun.
Speaker 0: Yeah and Also up since we're stuck alone in the quarantine Emily and I are gonna start rapidly producing more of our Disney theatrical animation.
Speaker 0: reviews were reviewing in depth every single Disney theatrical animation in release order.
Speaker 1: That's a lot.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: We just did and it's up on the patreon but free.
Speaker 0: You don't have to be a patreon patreon.
Speaker 0: You can just click on the link.
Speaker 0: You do not need to give us any money for this.
Speaker 0: but our fifth episode.
Speaker 0: we reviewed Fantasia and the one tidbit I'll give you.
Speaker 0: you know what the craziest thing about Fantasia was.
Speaker 1: I Mean there's a lot of crazy things about Fantasia.
Speaker 1: It was the first many many times.
Speaker 0: it was either the first or one of the very first.
Speaker 0: But it might actually be the first movie ever to record with multi-track audio.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I know that.
Speaker 0: Did you know that?
Speaker 0: Fantasize know that?
Speaker 0: how many tracks did they use?
Speaker 1: I don't know how many because it wasn't stereo.
Speaker 1: I just I just remember because I watched those like a Fantasia documentary.
Speaker 1: I watch I Think when Fantasia got re-released on VHS is when we bought it.
Speaker 1: Right, it was like, you know, it came out of the vault for a short time in the 90s I think and around that time.
Speaker 1: I don't know if was a TV special or maybe just an advertisement for Fantasia.
Speaker 1: But it basically, you know, there was some thing I watched that was like You know hyping up Fantasia and gave all sorts of background infos and to sound like that was Ridiculously groundbreaking.
Speaker 0: for what cuz?
Speaker 0: for one it was optical audio recording Before that was really a thing anywhere else.
Speaker 0: Like it was a pretty novel method of recording audio.
Speaker 0: They recorded nine tracks simultaneously.
Speaker 0: Geek nights did not have the capability to record nine tracks simultaneously until like five years ago.
Speaker 1: I mean, you know you think about all those movies that had original, you know synth, you know orchestral scores right.
Speaker 1: and then you know, like you watch Star Wars right and Star Wars they hire a symphony and they play Star Wars and then they go home and they take the recording and they attach it To the Star Wars.
Speaker 0: and the recording has a million different tracks because there's a bunch of mother's like a microphone on every horn.
Speaker 0: There's like a microphone for each section.
Speaker 0: There's a faraway microphone and a further away microphone.
Speaker 1: But the point is is that Fantasia is.
Speaker 1: what if that?
Speaker 1: Recording session right?
Speaker 1: was the movie?
Speaker 0: That's a Fantasia is except they Recorded it with a click track.
Speaker 0: That was the ninth track and then the animators used the click track to make sure they could time the animation so it would fit with the music Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: It was shocking technology technological advancement for that era.
Speaker 0: So let's get right into it, uh, we know I mean everyone knows about gambler kygee like even does everyone know about it?
Speaker 0: I mean, I feel like people who listen to geek nights at least know of that angle looking guy.
Speaker 0: Who's a gambler?
Speaker 1: So there's a the creator of this manga, right?
Speaker 1: Nobuyuki Fukumoto, right?
Speaker 1: So this person also created The other the mahjong thing, which is yeah G aka key.
Speaker 0: That's what yep aka key which looks right.
Speaker 0: so they have seen nerds confuse the two.
Speaker 0: cuz You did.
Speaker 0: the genre is angle looking dude who gambles in ridiculous games, that's it.
Speaker 1: that's the genre right, so basically there was.
Speaker 1: Akagi was the first one that I saw I think when the anime came out.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we reviewed it on geek nights and it had this unique visual style to it and it was about gambling and sort of like.
Speaker 1: You know not the way Hikaru no go is about go where it's sort of real.
Speaker 0: Oh my god, we reviewed Akagi and Gundam f91 in the same episode.
Speaker 1: Okay, what year was that?
Speaker 1: 2006. so in 2006 Akagi came out and I found out about this person because their art style was so distinctive and they were doing anime manga about gambling in sort of ridiculous shonen ways Right and it really stood out is kind of unique and it became a thing and some people are really into that thing and some People aren't right, but yeah this creator, right?
Speaker 1: No, buki Fukumoto makes basically tons and tons of stuff all in this very specific realm of Absolutely ridiculous mostly about gambling.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and that same art style where the chins are really pointy It almost looks like an episode of yo.
Speaker 1: Yeah, something like that, right?
Speaker 0: Yep So so we also live easily on geek nights Reviewed the show about tonogawa who was like the sub villain in Kaiji.
Speaker 1: right exactly, so we did.
Speaker 1: this is a side story that tells you the Backstory of this character tonogawa.
Speaker 0: Mr.
Speaker 0: Tonogawa middle management blues, right?
Speaker 1: So that was sort of like this ridiculous weird side anime.
Speaker 1: and because that came out I watched that and we did a show on it.
Speaker 1: And then I said wait, this is a side story of Kaiji Which I've never actually watched or read right?
Speaker 1: so when the Kaiji manga was listed for sale volume one I was like, alright, I'll just pick up volume one and see what the deal is, right?
Speaker 1: And then I'll.
Speaker 1: I've already seen some middle management blues.
Speaker 1: I can sort of connect the dots here, right and see what the deal is.
Speaker 1: So I got volume one of Kaiji.
Speaker 1: It seems to be a very large volume in English.
Speaker 1: I'm wonder if they're combining several Japanese volumes together to produce the one English one just to get things moving along.
Speaker 1: Not sure how long the actual manga is Right.
Speaker 1: the original one 71 volumes.
Speaker 1: Yes, so that they probably are combining Together to get them to fit into one, you know.
Speaker 1: So you don't have to buy 71 separate volumes because nobody in America will do that.
Speaker 0: So the thing I got to say and then we'll talk about like what this is actually about is as I read it.
Speaker 0: I read the first like fifth of this book and I was actually kind of into it Because it was moving pretty quick.
Speaker 0: Like this is one of those manga you can just read so fast.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah because there's the most manga you can read.
Speaker 0: so but this particular because the visuals don't really like.
Speaker 0: they're very simple and it's just the words.
Speaker 0: and like a guy looking and then a guy looking from a different angle a lot of just people yelling at each other and the narrator explaining what's going on and Right up until they explained the rules of the first game They were gonna play.
Speaker 0: I was actually kind of into it because it was moving so fast and they explained the rules Exactly.
Speaker 0: Like I really like it was a real game with real rules.
Speaker 0: They explained the rules.
Speaker 0: Well, it was an excellent example of teaching the rules to a board game.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm, and then my enjoyment of this manga and my desire to read more drops at a steady rate from that point forward until the end of this volume at which point I realized that I Literally never need to read more of this.
Speaker 1: I am a hundred percent agreeing.
Speaker 0: So little happens in this like inch and a half almost two inch thick book like I can summarize the entirety of this book in like a Minute if I had to write it's.
Speaker 1: that's the thing is like what's happening is actually good stuff.
Speaker 1: It's just happening too slowly.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's not enough of it, right?
Speaker 1: So it's like I care about the characters a little bit.
Speaker 1: I care about.
Speaker 1: the scenario is interesting.
Speaker 1: You know what's going on the mystery what this whole deal is.
Speaker 1: you can even though you can sort of figure it out.
Speaker 0: Yeah And if you watch Shona gawa even of two episodes in then that'll actually tell you exactly what I can't use them Gaka, what Kaiji is about right?
Speaker 0: Of course because that is literally the.
Speaker 0: the story of tona gawa is Here's the big bad villain who made this cruise ship and why?
Speaker 0: yep, and the answer is stupid.
Speaker 1: and how yeah How and why how and why?
Speaker 1: But
Speaker 0: like it spends like over a hundred pages Dealing with a character Figuring something out and slowly explaining it to two other characters Multiple times until they get it and the thing they are figuring out and spending these hundred plus pages describing is Hey, if people play all the rock cards and rock-paper-scissor Then suddenly all the scissor cards become a lot more powerful.
Speaker 0: Like that's it.
Speaker 0: That's that's it.
Speaker 0: That is literally hundred pages to explain that kind of concept.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so, you know, it starts out, you know, you get this poor guy Kaiji who likes to to.
Speaker 1: you know, Gamble or whatever.
Speaker 0: Well, no, he doesn't like to gamble.
Speaker 0: He doesn't gamble.
Speaker 0: He likes to deface Mercedes-Benz cars because he's a shit ass loser.
Speaker 1: Oh, right That shows it like I haven't read it in a while cuz I gave this to rim like weeks ago.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but yeah, so it's like I can't even remember that part cuz it was so brief Interesting like the.
Speaker 0: the intro is really good this piece of shit dude.
Speaker 0: It's just wandering around like being a piece of shit.
Speaker 0: He's he's got no money He's kind of a jerk and he Defaces all these Mercedes-Benz's because he's mad and jealous that people have them.
Speaker 1: and then he and his friend scams him Yep, and then he finds one that's particularly fancy.
Speaker 0: So he defaces the ever-living shit out of it.
Speaker 0: Then he goes home and he hangs their hood ornament.
Speaker 0: he stole on his door and someone knocks on the door and he's like oh fuck I can't let whoever that is see my Collection of Ben's ornaments.
Speaker 0: What if it's his car?
Speaker 0: totally is his car and the guy is like listen your other friend scammed you.
Speaker 0: you owe us an Insane amount of money and I'm a Yakuza and I'm gonna fuck you up.
Speaker 0: We should talk.
Speaker 0: and then Kaiji's like, oh, let's uh, let's go to a cafe.
Speaker 0: He was like fine follow me and they go down to his car and he's like, uh, so I got a flat tire Mm-hmm, and like this.
Speaker 0: stuff's all kind of like there's a fun thing going on, but then they get on a boat and just fucking Nothing happens after I.
Speaker 1: it's one of those scenario situations like nine doors nine.
Speaker 1: Whatever right is that there's some evil people who are for some reason running a cruise ship Where people who are down on their luck in some way right want to get on the cruise ship to you know And they're locked into the scenario, right?
Speaker 1: they can't escape where they have to play these games and win at these games and if they manage to do so and Succeed there's some huge prize at the end for them and they can escape their shitty lives and solve their problems.
Speaker 1: But it seems that there are horrifying and mysterious consequences for all the losers.
Speaker 1: Yep Like soundproof rooms where there's still screams coming out of them and there's some evil organization running the whole show And no one knows.
Speaker 1: you don't really start, you know, they don't tell you why or who or anything at least not in volume one.
Speaker 1: Yep, and the scenarios that they've set up for these players to play are Simple but interesting.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like the first game is literally rock-paper-scissors, but you know what the game they play.
Speaker 0: this rock-paper-scissors is Honestly a legit good game like it would be fun to play this at a convention in a panel room, right?
Speaker 1: You have a room full of people.
Speaker 1: Everyone is given an equal number of rock paper and scissors cards, right?
Speaker 1: You can't just throw whatever you want.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right if you go to a table and challenge someone you both play a card simultaneous.
Speaker 0: you both have to consent.
Speaker 1: Right you both have to consent to it.
Speaker 1: you flip your cards over you see who wins Right, and then you have also separately.
Speaker 1: you have money.
Speaker 0: You just have it.
Speaker 0: Well, it's like there's.
Speaker 0: it's a game mechanic That is this is actually the same game mechanic that train board games have in that at the start of the match You've got your three stars You've got your paper rock-scissors cards and then they let you take out a loan between what like 1 and 20 or 15 You can take.
Speaker 0: but you could take between 1 and 15 million yen like something like that like but the interest compounds every 10 minutes Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: So how much do you take out?
Speaker 0: Do you take out the smallest loan of the biggest loan?
Speaker 0: What's that money for?
Speaker 0: And I love the fact that the game master very succinctly explains the rules of paper rock-scissors.
Speaker 0: Like how are you gonna play the game?
Speaker 0: Because once you win once you play a match win or lose the cards that were used in the match are taken out of the game forever And at the end of the game anyone who has three or more stars lives.
Speaker 0: Anyone who has less than three stars or who still has even one card on them dies Right.
Speaker 1: So you have to get rid of all your cards right safely.
Speaker 1: So it's like you have if you start with you know, what they start with.
Speaker 1: three of each two of each something like that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I forget how many they start with some number of each.
Speaker 0: you have to get rid of the cards somehow Meaning you gotta play you gotta play the paper rock-scissors somehow.
Speaker 1: But they start to reveal as the game goes on is like basically like all the things they don't say Right are not rules.
Speaker 1: It's like oh I could just win a couple rock-paper-scissors get up to three stars And as long as I can find someone to take my cards, yep Right, or maybe I'll sell a star to someone for 10 million yen, right?
Speaker 1: Or maybe I'll trade a star for some cards.
Speaker 1: Yeah It's like oh, well that person lost a bunch and they're running out of cards I bet and I've won a bunch and I have cards.
Speaker 1: they need cards to play more rock-paper-scissors.
Speaker 0: I saw that guy play scissors like eight times.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna go over there assuming he's out of scissors, right and because your cards are limited You can't just throw whatever you want to throw, you know.
Speaker 1: So it's actually kind of an interesting scenario that they've come up with.
Speaker 1: Yeah That makes me interested to see how it plays out.
Speaker 1: But it plays out over such a long period of time.
Speaker 0: plays out over an inch of paper.
Speaker 1: They could have had this whole rock-paper-scissors Part of the ship because you know that there's gonna be other rooms with other games as the tournament goes on.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right This should have been one episode like one volume.
Speaker 0: is the rock-paper-scissors game done?
Speaker 1: You could have done two episodes for the rock-paper-scissors.
Speaker 0: True the first half and then the second half.
Speaker 0: after they figure out how fucked they are.
Speaker 1: Right exactly the first half where it's like the setup and the early play and then shit gets crazy.
Speaker 1: They figure things out and then it finishes, right?
Speaker 1: That's what you do with the rock-paper-scissors and you move on to the next game.
Speaker 1: Then this would have been like the great one of the great mangas.
Speaker 1: just you know, not great but like super fun.
Speaker 1: I would have bought volume 2.
Speaker 0: no questions asked right, but no It's just in slow motion.
Speaker 1: The pace is so slow.
Speaker 0: Characters will say the same thing to another character like four times in the span of ten pages.
Speaker 1: yeah, yeah, I'm very.
Speaker 0: the characters are dumb like they're dumb to the point that they keep like Re-explaining things to each other because they don't understand each other.
Speaker 0: I don't need to see that.
Speaker 0: I don't need to read that.
Speaker 0: you can skip that part.
Speaker 0: Yeah Like that's the part of the rpg where the game master is like, all right.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: All right Let's skip all that.
Speaker 0: roll the falsehood test.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so I don't think kaiji Became an.
Speaker 1: is it an anime also?
Speaker 0: There is a kaiji anime, but i'm pretty sure it takes place long after that cruise ship.
Speaker 1: You lose day by day gambling making small debt.
Speaker 0: yeah, look at what the first episode is.
Speaker 0: he's like escape from a work camp or something.
Speaker 1: uh-huh I know it looks like kaiji's automatic.
Speaker 1: I don't know how far they get in the yeah
Speaker 0: But like I can this manga unless you Have an infinite amount of patience to read an inch and a half two inch thick book At the end of which you don't even find out who wins rock paper scissors Because the last page is not them Doing the last rock paper scissors.
Speaker 0: It's not even close to being done.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it looks like the kaiji anime.
Speaker 1: Uh, that's listed here.
Speaker 1: Oh, there's ultimate survivor Right.
Speaker 1: Oh ultimate skull kaiji.
Speaker 1: ultimate survivor is 26 episodes and it seems like the rock paper scissors ends.
Speaker 1: uh At least yeah, it goes on for several episodes.
Speaker 0: Oh god At least initial d was always the the setup the get to the race The first part of the race the second part of the race.
Speaker 1: I can see here that in episode three They're definitely playing rock paper scissors and in episode nine.
Speaker 1: They are Still play episode eight and nine.
Speaker 1: They're still playing rock paper.
Speaker 1: Oh, no So And there's another anime kaiji against all rules.
Speaker 1: That's the one with the work camp.
Speaker 1: Um, yeah, I think that must take place after the first season.
Speaker 1: So i'm not sure which manga volumes those anime episodes line up to.
Speaker 1: I guess it would take less time to watch these two seasons of anime than to read all the manga.
Speaker 1: But who wants to watch?
Speaker 1: I just read a whole volume of rock paper scissors.
Speaker 1: I don't want to watch five episodes of rock paper scissors.
Speaker 0: It should be two episodes of rock paper scissors Yep, but also the worst part is uh, maybe this might be something that only applies to me and scott and like super like Heavy tabletop gamers, but uh I fully understood All the tricks they came up with.
Speaker 0: like.
Speaker 0: that's the kind of shit I had already thought of just by hearing the rules.
Speaker 1: like I thought of 90 of it at the start.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I thought about making the futures market buying cards from people But what?
Speaker 0: but at the same time it also they didn't.
Speaker 0: even there were better ways to handle this than they even handled it.
Speaker 0: yeah, like I don't want to get into it, but there's a lot of ways you could Safely progress through this game without taking the risk that these characters took.
Speaker 0: But I guess it makes sense because these characters are like canonically stupid.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think another part of it.
Speaker 1: Is that the?
Speaker 1: well kaiji is stupid but like he figures things out like he gets Yeah, he's just a step behind.
Speaker 0: It's like the one omega thought to be watched for.
Speaker 0: the one guy really sucked at rampart But started to figure it out as the match went on.
Speaker 1: right that's what kaiji is.
Speaker 1: He's a guy who figures things out as time goes on.
Speaker 1: but I think part of the problem is that there's none of the even Those characters you don't really identify with any of them or care.
Speaker 0: Nope, it's like kaiji.
Speaker 0: you're a piece of shit and there are a lot of better ways to handle your situation.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: They don't really Other than like.
Speaker 1: each character is really kind of thin.
Speaker 1: There's not a lot to their personality or backstory or anything to make you know or care about them.
Speaker 1: So it's really just all about the scenario itself.
Speaker 1: Yep, and that doesn't carry enough.
Speaker 0: nope, I Would.
Speaker 0: i've seen people like people.
Speaker 0: i've seen people run this scenario the rock paper scissors game in conventions before like in panel rooms.
Speaker 0: That's been a thing.
Speaker 0: It even got submitted to connecticut a few times.
Speaker 0: I forget if I ever scheduled it but uh Yeah, I I can't recommend this to anyone.
Speaker 1: Like I can recommend it if the if the the the because it's also sort of crazy, right?
Speaker 1: Scenario.
Speaker 0: but i'm just gonna read spoilers I'm just gonna go.
Speaker 0: well, actually I don't need to because I know the deal with the boat because I watched the beginning of mr tonogawa Exactly.
Speaker 0: Mr Tony if you are intrigued by this and you read this first volume of kaiji But you want to find out the end just go watch like the first three or four episodes of mr Tonogawa middle management blues and that will literally reveal everything you care about.
Speaker 0: Yep, pretty much and while the answer is stupid It's also pretty funny like what the bar.
Speaker 0: I actually I enjoy what this cruise ship actually is.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah That's what i'm saying is like what's actually going on is so crazy and sort of fun and ridiculous That it's like that genre of the ridiculous anime with the crazy stuff happening right is great.
Speaker 1: But if only This had the ridiculous things happening faster and more in less pages than it would be worth worth my time.
Speaker 0: Oh, there's a movie I don't remember what it was called like the test or something the exam.
Speaker 0: There's a movie that is this essentially but it's uh, i'm not gonna say it's good.
Speaker 0: I think it's just called exam.
Speaker 1: It's in the same genre as you know battle royale.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 0: The movie is called exam.
Speaker 0: It's from 2009.
Speaker 0: It's a low-budget film and it's this kind of scenario.
Speaker 0: It's like eight people are locked in a room and they have to take nine doors nine Whatever.
Speaker 1: we talk about these things all the time.
Speaker 1: There's these scenario based.
Speaker 1: Uh, what's the one we watched where the kids were like in it?
Speaker 1: They were people moved went to a village that was in the in the mountain or something.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right There's always these things but basically uh I would almost say if you're not sure if you want to deal with.
Speaker 1: Boca rana was technically sort of in that in that genre true, but it does have a lot else going on.
Speaker 1: Boca rana doesn't have the isolation that these other ones.
Speaker 0: Yeah, because exam is more like kaiji It is.
Speaker 0: these people are locked in one room for the entire movie.
Speaker 1: So I mean there's still.
Speaker 1: those are all in the scenario genre But this is in the more common isolated scenario where a group of people are trapped at a place and forced Into this complicated scenario with a bunch of made-up rules, right?
Speaker 0: I would almost say go watch the 2009 film exam And if you want to see a version of that movie that instead of being 101 minutes long Is a thousand and one minutes long but tells the same story then kaiji is the manga for you.
Speaker 1: I say just watch all the other things in that same isolated scenario genre that have faster pacing.
Speaker 1: and if you want to see ridiculous animes Watch different ones that are ridiculous that aren't this, you know one could argue that 12 angry men is in this genre.
Speaker 0: Uh sort of yeah, there is 12 people locked in a room with the scenario.
Speaker 0: They got to deal with Yeah, and no outside help No escape, but to solve the scenario.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but I think the difference is that in most of these scenario Um, they're real like they're really character driven but kaiji is actually scenario driven primarily right, and but it's also that they're um the the.
Speaker 1: the conflict is between The players who are trapped and the outside forces, uh, assailing them.
Speaker 0: Yeah, 12 angry men is not about jury nullification Right.
Speaker 1: No 12 angry men is about racism.
Speaker 1: Yep So, uh, but in 12 angry men the conflict is you know between you know It's more societal and ephemeral and also between the people that are trapped in there, right?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: The conflict is in a different spot even though it's still a scenario based situation.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I do not need to ever read more kaiji like good.
Speaker 0: No god I do.
Speaker 1: and I think I think that you know, well i'm not personally turned off by the unique art style.
Speaker 1: I know a lot of people that are yeah, i'm actually fine.
Speaker 0: I don't mind the art style at all.
Speaker 0: I just wish it moved faster.
Speaker 1: No, it's like you notice it a lot the first time you watch because it's so unique and different and kind of messed up.
Speaker 1: But once you you know, I stopped noticing it and stop, you know, it's okay.
Speaker 0: The only problem is I noticed that kaiji basically makes eight different faces and just rotates between them.
Speaker 0: Sure and it's it's like.
Speaker 0: he's concerned but sweating.
Speaker 0: he's angry but sweating.
Speaker 0: he's despairing but sweating he's Happy but sweating.
Speaker 0: and then there's another variant of all the same phases, but he's not sweating Like.
Speaker 1: that's it.
Speaker 0: Those are the only faces he makes Sure, and then he has one ultra despairing face.
Speaker 1: It's not you know, even though even though it does have a unique style which has its own merits.
Speaker 1: It is not a Masterpiece of drawing.
Speaker 0: No, it's not.
Speaker 1: that's not what you're reading this for.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I read this as fast as possible Like I just blew through it and it still was way too sparse for me to deal with.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna go just read spoilers on all the games they play and see if the rules are as good as this rock paper scissors.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah Definitely the imagination to come up with the rock paper scissors game alone gives me hope for the imagination of the the future.
Speaker 1: You know games that the players will be trapped in, you know.
Speaker 1: Hopefully there are more.
Speaker 1: the thing is I worry that they'll only be a few games right because yeah 4,000 episodes they play three games right if they would have come up with more games.
Speaker 1: They could have had less episodes per game.
Speaker 0: You know what we could do.
Speaker 0: We should.
Speaker 0: this is this is a pax panel that we could do during the quarantine when we got nothing better to do The kind of panel no one would accept.
Speaker 0: Let's make your own cruise gambling.
Speaker 0: No, let's read.
Speaker 0: Well, maybe that Let's just read the rules to all the games in kaiji and review them as games.
Speaker 0: Huh because I could do a full-on review of this, uh limited rock paper scissors a restricted rock rock paper scissors.
Speaker 1: It's a real game.
Speaker 1: I absolutely could.
Speaker 1: it's a good game.
Speaker 0: You could you could publish this and sell it and people would buy it and people would enjoy it.
Speaker 1: You could put kaiji art on it.
Speaker 0: Yeah I've seen people have have made those cards.
Speaker 0: Like i've seen those around at cons.
Speaker 1: Yeah, why not?
Speaker 1: All right, kaiji cosplayers.
Speaker 0: Yeah, i've seen kaiji cosplayers, but they might have been akagi cosplayers.
Speaker 0: I can't fucking tell.
Speaker 1: I can't tell either.
Speaker 0: All right, I think we're good.
Speaker 0: This has been geek nights with rim and scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to dj pretzel for the opening music cat lee for web design and brand.
Speaker 1: ok for the logos Be sure to visit our website at front row crew.com for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 0: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech mondays gaming tuesdays anime comic wednesdays and indiscriminate thursdays.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a creative commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 1: But unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 0: It's actually recorded at night And the patreon patrons for this episode of geek nights are alan joyce Heidi mcnickel marty gridia just like a dude guy chartavish and lindkey g. you hold the key to my heart.
Speaker 0: She said you're moving with your auntie and uncle in bel air clinton walton j bantz friend from new zealand ryan parent drew openlander nicholas brandow the thirst for hydrated ganon dread lily tenebrae Chris rimer
Speaker 1: finn
Speaker 0: sean klein thomas han sherwin von harl sean yager and a bunch of people who don't want me to say their name.
Speaker 0: uh, I Think the test live stream was successful.
Speaker 0: So there's a good chance.
Speaker 0: next tuesday when we do the next show you will see us live on youtube like usual.
Speaker 0: There just won't be a scot cam because I am unwilling to sort out a pipeline that will make that work.
Speaker 0: Uh, but anyway, uh, stay safe out there and now I leave you with a bunny.
Speaker 1: Looks like our long-eared friend is onto something bunnies love to dig.
Speaker 1: He's making a supreme effort.
Speaker 1: I think I can guess why.
Speaker 1: That's right.
Speaker 1: a carrot growing out here free and wild probably the result of a stray seed pooped out by a passing bird.
Speaker 1: What's this?
Speaker 1: there is?
Speaker 1: rustling in the bush could mean trouble.
Speaker 1: Mr.
Speaker 1: Bunny seems to think so.
Speaker 1: his sensitive whiskers quiver at the hint of imminent danger.
Speaker 1: Unfortunately for mr.
Speaker 1: Bunny, this is what nature is all about.
Speaker 0: It's a male deer.
Speaker 1: not a threat to mr.
Speaker 1: Bunny in the predatory sense, but still above him in the food chain.
Speaker 1: Mr.
Speaker 1: Bunny wishing to avoid an encounter hops away to safety.
Speaker 1: Wow, deers are jerks.
Speaker 1: Hey, man, you know, I can hear everything you say, right?
Speaker 0: What?
Speaker 0: No, I had no idea yeah, but you saw me leave the walkie-talkie and I left it on.
Speaker 0: you know that right?
Speaker 1: Hi dick.
Speaker 1: Hi beemo.