Speaker 0: It's Tuesday August 11th 2020.
Speaker 0: I'm rim.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott and this is geek nights.
Speaker 0: tonight We're gonna talk about the tabletop game modern art and how to win.
Speaker 0: It's because we are very good at it.
Speaker 1: Let's do this still.
Speaker 0: uh still stuck at home, but I've basically like I said I've been trying to really like up my Physical training and exercise.
Speaker 0: cuz going outside to exercise alone is like the one thing I can actually do.
Speaker 0: So Saturday ran half marathon Sunday biked a hundred miles and Monday my body was a little bit like yo dawg.
Speaker 1: You're almost 40 cool it Yeah, so who cares about that?
Speaker 1: The New York Rangers have won in some sort of miraculous twist of fate Despite the drop that should have cursed a sea cursed drop.
Speaker 1: Alright, so you got to understand how crazy this is, right?
Speaker 1: So in Earlier in the hockey season right there was a hockey game in which Carolina had to bring in a backup goalie not just the regular backup goalie But the emergency backup goalie who was a zamboni driver and they end up winning that game Right.
Speaker 1: the effect of that win on the standings is such that Right.
Speaker 1: if they had not won that game It is likely that you know some other team would have had the first overall draft pick.
Speaker 1: right that one game.
Speaker 0: Oh, there's so many so many like moments.
Speaker 0: But that one was the one I saw everyone talking about.
Speaker 1: if the season had continued in normal fashion and there was not some horrible Earth, you know shaking pandemic, right?
Speaker 1: The Rangers probably would have gone on to do You know too well this season to get that many lottery balls and end up with the first overall
Speaker 0: Like not out of the realm would have won the wild card race lost the first round of the playoffs and then right
Speaker 1: pretty much So.
Speaker 1: but instead what ended up happening is they did the lottery picks, right?
Speaker 1: But because they had these play-in games, right?
Speaker 1: You know into the for the play for the playoffs, which this is good game design talk to remember.
Speaker 0: They had to design how they're gonna do The like finish the end of the season to figure out who's actually in the playoffs with this weird format Like.
Speaker 0: yep, this was game design straight up.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so they came up with this format and the they it was randomly determined right that You know one of the eight teams That was going to lose in the play-in round ended up winning the first overall draft pick.
Speaker 1: Detroit got shoved down to like.
Speaker 0: Such a Detroit.
Speaker 0: if anyone needs good draft picks.
Speaker 0: It's Detroit right now.
Speaker 0: This is like the second dead wings era.
Speaker 1: Yeah Which is you know, I guess, you know it to prevent tanking right?
Speaker 0: This is this is what you do Yeah Cuz if they just said whoever came in last in the season got like the first pick The end of every NHL season would be a real.
Speaker 0: you'd see like the Sabres and the Red Wings like Refusing to score on each other and infinite overtimes.
Speaker 1: Yep I don't know at the players might be too proud to do that.
Speaker 0: I Feel like some teams would get to the point where enough they would not be too proud.
Speaker 1: Regardless, so it was randomly determined.
Speaker 1: So the odds of this or happening to begin with were very low.
Speaker 1: right that one of the eight teams was gonna end up with The first pick.
Speaker 1: not one of these, you know Teams that didn't what.
Speaker 1: the teams that didn't even make it to the play-in games the teams that just you know Stayed home and as soon as the virus hit we're just done for the season.
Speaker 1: those teams did not get the first overall pick.
Speaker 1: one of the eight teams had it and There's basically a one in eight chance like roll it You know take a d8 Say I'm gonna roll a one roll a one that and the first roll and that those are the odds 12.5% chance of any one team.
Speaker 0: Think of it like if they did a lottery But they hadn't sold the tickets yet.
Speaker 0: and then the lottery happened and we knew the winning ticket was in this one storm But we didn't know which ticket.
Speaker 1: so, you know, they took eight lottery.
Speaker 1: But after the eight teams after the eight play-in, you know series were done and the Rangers got swept Destroyed.
Speaker 1: it was embarrassing.
Speaker 0: It was a disaster.
Speaker 1: Disgraceful, right totally blown out, but it doesn't matter how much you lost you lost right?
Speaker 1: There were eight teams that lost right?
Speaker 1: There was Rangers Leafs Wild heart not hurricanes.
Speaker 1: They beat us.
Speaker 1: Yeah leaves wild a jets eat penguins penguins in there, right?
Speaker 1: Florida Panthers, right.
Speaker 1: any any one of these eight teams had an equal chance, right?
Speaker 1: Could you imagine if the like already still good penguins or Leafs got?
Speaker 1: it's like that would have been the worst thing ever, right?
Speaker 1: And so they go to do this lottery and since it's a simple d8 situation They don't have to do what they usually do with the book full of numbers.
Speaker 1: or you know different teams have different odds.
Speaker 1: It was just a one out of eight chance.
Speaker 1: They made eight special balls.
Speaker 1: that a team logos on them, right?
Speaker 1: They put the eight balls into a lottery ball machine and they picked one ball And if your team logo came out at the top, that was it.
Speaker 1: You got it, right?
Speaker 1: You don't got it.
Speaker 1: Well, you're picking somewhere between like, you know ninth and who knows where way down there I just googled Rangers ball dropped and what's up at the top is rigged trending on Twitter.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah No, so the dude he's got the dude from Ernst and Young right who is like prepared.
Speaker 1: You know the auditors who prepared these perfectly fair balls in the and the machine and everything, right?
Speaker 1: You know, they opens up the special case with the with the balls in it.
Speaker 1: It's a good case out.
Speaker 1: He takes the balls out one at a time.
Speaker 1: So the Commissioner can verify with his eyeball.
Speaker 0: I love his like stone face like he holds each one up like multiple angers angles to each camera.
Speaker 0: He doesn't react like the.
Speaker 0: I was just stone face.
Speaker 1: Yes He's showing showing the Commissioner of the balls and showing the whole world because it's on video.
Speaker 1: right each ball Right the whole thing.
Speaker 1: You can watch the video of the whole thing to see that no shenanigans happened Except he holds up each ball one at a time to verify before putting them into the slot, right?
Speaker 1: It takes out the Rangers ball.
Speaker 1: He drops it prematurely Prematurely drops the ball and I'm like, of course the one ball he prematurely drops is gonna be all right Of course.
Speaker 1: and then he takes it out again because the hasn't been visually verified.
Speaker 1: that puts it back in.
Speaker 1: So it's the only ball.
Speaker 1: he touches twice every other ball.
Speaker 1: He touches one time Right, and then if you watch it in slow motion, it's like you can see like the maple leafs ball like bumping our ball like up into the Right.
Speaker 1: I did not notice that You got to watch the slow-mo video, but it's like this one in eight chance.
Speaker 1: It's like and not the one ball that was touched twice ends up Miraculously being the one that gets the way sports goes.
Speaker 0: really fair lottery machine because we won the draft.
Speaker 0: now It was rigged but had we lost it.
Speaker 0: We would have been cursed.
Speaker 0: That's how they think.
Speaker 1: there were threads.
Speaker 1: There were threads online all week Basically showing how no matter which of the eight teams won you could easily make an argument for why it was rigged.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and they had.
Speaker 1: they had prepared copy pastas for all eight Of course in advance and then of course as soon as we won People went and found the Rangers copy pasta that was prepared in advance and started posting it, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, but now it's exciting cuz.
Speaker 0: now the real question is gonna be so we're gonna get up this first draft pick Don't?
Speaker 0: we have like.
Speaker 0: we have another first round pick too because of the trades.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so we have.
Speaker 1: so you need Carolina to lose quickly.
Speaker 1: they just destroyed us right which is good if they had.
Speaker 1: But We need care that we're gonna get Carolina's pick, right?
Speaker 1: So if Carolina wins at all, we're getting.
Speaker 1: we're picking last with that one right at least last in the first round.
Speaker 1: We're just still not.
Speaker 1: it's still first round Yeah, but we want them to lose like right away.
Speaker 1: that way that pick will be earlier right.
Speaker 0: So we'll see what this team looks like.
Speaker 0: cuz the Rangers are weird.
Speaker 0: They're like they were getting better and better over the course of the season.
Speaker 0: the season got cut short And then when they went into this play in they were bad again.
Speaker 0: But they got a little bit better over the course of those three terrible terrible games.
Speaker 0: Of course, I don't know if I'll even be hockey in 2021 like I feel like we might have to skip a year.
Speaker 0: We'll see how things go.
Speaker 0: So in some other gaming news There's a game out there.
Speaker 0: I have not played it like full disclosure.
Speaker 0: I don't know if I will based on what other people have been saying about it.
Speaker 0: That is it's okay, but it's not great.
Speaker 0: but Fall guys has been moderately popular because it's like an online game that a bunch of people can play.
Speaker 0: It's really accessible really simple and I saw a lot.
Speaker 1: I just watched some video of this game or some streams of it.
Speaker 1: You can see what it's all about.
Speaker 1: pretty it's pretty straightforward and it does look pretty fun.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it looks it looks.
Speaker 1: I just I just don't know if I'm gonna get into it.
Speaker 0: Well, the thing is be too late.
Speaker 0: I feel like fall guys would be way more fun at a convention or on a couch with a whole bunch of people Like among friends.
Speaker 1: the thing is it's like a battle royale.
Speaker 1: We need like a hundred people.
Speaker 1: I don't think it'd be fun with like ten people.
Speaker 1: I don't know The probably a hundred people kind of situation.
Speaker 0: Yeah Well imagine like a room.
Speaker 0: it like a PAX where everyone in the room or a theater like everyone in the main theaters just play In this game.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they'll.
Speaker 1: probably they could do something like that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but it's a magic conventions doing that.
Speaker 0: the game seems to have gotten more popular than anyone expected.
Speaker 0: So it doesn't have.
Speaker 0: despite being an online game where people are ostensibly competing to win like ortho game.
Speaker 0: It is not like set up to have things like.
Speaker 0: you can't report other players for things.
Speaker 1: I didn't know about that.
Speaker 0: Yeah like it doesn't have a lot of the things that games like this would normally have and one of the things that does not have is Any way to prevent cheating and people are cheating like crazy in this.
Speaker 1: Well, so the first thing.
Speaker 1: so when this game came out the first thing I heard about it was that they had the usual Going live on the first day and their internet their multiplayer two servers are failing.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that was the first story I heard about this game.
Speaker 1: the second story I heard about this game Is that streamers are streaming it like crazy.
Speaker 1: come look at it?
Speaker 1: And I went and looked at it and saw that it actually looked kind of fun.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right and so forth.
Speaker 0: I earmarked it as I play this at some point.
Speaker 1: Yeah the third thing I heard about it was that some people were basically Trolling.
Speaker 1: so they'll be like races in the game and it's like as long as you get you know Make the cut in the race you go to the next round and you're not eliminated, right?
Speaker 1: So people will race and if they finish early enough will stop at the finish line Turn around and just like interfere with other players.
Speaker 1: That's cool.
Speaker 1: I like that and then when they're getting closer to the cut will turn around and cross the finish line.
Speaker 1: So there's a lot of trolling kind of griefing behavior involved going on in the game, which is good and bad.
Speaker 0: Yep It's more good than bad in a game like this because this is not a like Mario Kart Fox-only final destination situation like turn off all the items.
Speaker 1: also It can still be kind of frustrating depending on the specifics.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but this game is also like super loose control like like barely able to control your character game.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and then the last thing I heard about it as rim said is that apparently cheating is now rampant in this game.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like some of it's just like glitches like you can start people can start running before the gun goes off.
Speaker 0: people can just teleport To the end.
Speaker 0: I watched one streamer who was like way ahead of the pack and like really excited.
Speaker 0: There's this whole thing going on and then he gets to the end and there's like three people Already there who had teleported to the end at the start of the match and we're just waiting for someone to see before they went over the finish line.
Speaker 1: Yep, so So yeah, I probably you know, it's it's I think the core does idea of this game that you know as it was designed.
Speaker 1: It's like very very clever, you know, it's so basic.
Speaker 1: It obviously didn't take.
Speaker 1: you know, I mean, I'm sure it wasn't like.
Speaker 1: I'm not saying it was super easy to make this game Right, but relatively speaking.
Speaker 1: It didn't.
Speaker 1: it wasn't a triple-a budget super long difficult development, right?
Speaker 1: It's you know, it's a pretty relatively straightforward game, right?
Speaker 1: But you know such ingenious and unique.
Speaker 1: They're the first ones to combine the battle royale with sort of like the monkey ball plus sort of the overwah Overcooked kind of a little bit right is like sometimes his teamwork involved.
Speaker 1: It's like, okay We're gonna split you all into teams and each team has to push a ball through an obstacle course.
Speaker 1: a little bit of Marvel Madness.
Speaker 0: People were complaining.
Speaker 0: There's one minigame that was very hard and people were really mad about that one and never wanted to see it.
Speaker 1: Yeah Regardless, you know, it's it's unique combination.
Speaker 1: I like it.
Speaker 1: I like the concept.
Speaker 1: It's just.
Speaker 1: you know, this is problem after problem after problem.
Speaker 1: Clearly something here part of which part of which is caused by you know not lack of polish in the game itself and part of which is caused by Two more people playing it than they expected sort of what happened to zoom.
Speaker 1: Yeah, where it's like, oh we have shitty software.
Speaker 1: Oh, no, too many people are using the shitty software.
Speaker 1: It has broken under the weight of user So it actually hits teams top five.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's what I'm saying.
Speaker 0: It's broken under, you know, here's a question for you users What do you think is above?
Speaker 0: fall guys on Steam right now, I'm not looking at it right now.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like.
Speaker 0: well if you had to guess I'm just curious if you're on tapped in that cuz hop games on Steam.
Speaker 0: I am.
Speaker 1: I'm looking at the list always up there.
Speaker 1: Don't it?
Speaker 1: Who's usually?
Speaker 0: yes go Dota 2.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 1: I got two.
Speaker 1: I'm that's doing pretty good.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: There's only two more.
Speaker 1: It's only two more.
Speaker 0: the fifth the fourth one.
Speaker 0: I did not.
Speaker 0: I would never imagined in a million years GTA 5.
Speaker 0: Oh I didn't think that many people were playing that.
Speaker 1: Oh, this has to be like an online multiplayer game.
Speaker 1: Yeah I don't know.
Speaker 1: I give up.
Speaker 0: It's pub G.
Speaker 1: Oh Dad, that makes yep.
Speaker 0: That's the obvious one.
Speaker 0: via GTA 5.
Speaker 0: I did not but as I apparently there is no way to report anyone for cheating.
Speaker 0: Nor does the company have like any resources to do anything about the cheating?
Speaker 0: What they're?
Speaker 0: they ask people like oh if you see a cheater come into our discord and tell us that ain't gonna fly No Like I said, it's fallen under the weight of more users than expect.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so I think it's gonna be a flash in the pan and die pretty quick.
Speaker 0: So I don't think I'm right.
Speaker 1: I don't know if it'll.
Speaker 1: I don't know if it'll die, you know I think when you have that maybe it'll from the all sales to a steady.
Speaker 1: You can boost yourself up right with all that money like zoom has right?
Speaker 0: I think the problem part of the problem This
Speaker 1: is the thing is right is this see we're the kind of people right where if we came up with this idea Right, we would foresee all of these problems and Foreseeing those problems
Speaker 0: decide not to make the game We
Speaker 1: would either decide not to make it or decide not to release it until we've solved all the problems.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: And then we would not release and we'd get beaten by this kind of but by actual fog.
Speaker 0: We would have made the same mistakes that video ball made.
Speaker 1: I think right and I think this is what happens With pretty much all not just video games, right but all successful multiplayer software.
Speaker 1: You look at you know, things like friggin Twitter and Facebook and you know, pretty much everything right Google, right?
Speaker 1: and it's like.
Speaker 1: people are always complaining about these things.
Speaker 1: and it's like because they have all these problems.
Speaker 1: and it's like Yeah, because the way to succeed is to release a thing that gets the job done But it's full of problems.
Speaker 1: if you solve all the problems before you put your product out there You'll never put your product out there and you'll never be the winner, right.
Speaker 1: and then it people.
Speaker 1: Yeah, no one's complaining about your perfect product that never got released and took ten years and that's just.
Speaker 1: it's a software problem.
Speaker 1: So I feel like there is something here though I don't think there's a way to make a price off a piece of software with a Incredibly large number of users.
Speaker 0: now that is a unique constraint.
Speaker 1: that is problem that public users right not private business users, but like public users that is Simultaneously doesn't have people complaining about it and also successful.
Speaker 0: So yeah, you can read the details here But I don't know if I'll be playing this because it seems like the skill cap is very low and the game is kind of Just ran to me really.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's the kind of game.
Speaker 1: It is.
Speaker 1: It's like a fun party kind of situation.
Speaker 0: I feel like what the game I want is basically WarioWare.
Speaker 0: this Like.
Speaker 0: I want massively online WarioWare.
Speaker 0: like 10,000 people are doing that dancing game in the old GameCube WarioWare Until eventually one person's left go.
Speaker 0: make it now somehow how I foresee all these problems with it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think people are gonna cheat and grief at that.
Speaker 1: What are you gonna do about it?
Speaker 0: I'd let him grief.
Speaker 0: I just wouldn't let him cheat.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Well, I feel like it looks like some of the cheating here is like Exploits.
Speaker 0: some of it might be fucking with API is like I. I don't know.
Speaker 0: I haven't looked into it that much I don't care that much but I think this could have been handled a lot better.
Speaker 0: But again the game did well.
Speaker 0: It's popular.
Speaker 0: It's still popular.
Speaker 0: People are still playing it despite the cheaters.
Speaker 0: So you got any news?
Speaker 1: Do I have a news?
Speaker 1: Yeah, so there's a lot of news coming out and like the board game land Because you know all the board game conventions didn't happen Right and Gen cons and things like that would be around this time.
Speaker 1: So because of that right there's instead all the new people still making board games, right?
Speaker 1: The the virus doesn't prevent board game development.
Speaker 1: In fact, it probably speeds it up.
Speaker 1: You have more time to sit at home and work on their board games Or tabletop RPGs or whatever it is, you know tabletop stuff in general.
Speaker 1: so There's plenty there.
Speaker 1: I you know, there were some video game news as I saw but that was I didn't know enough about them To really talk about them, but plenty of tabletop news.
Speaker 1: and one that really caught my eye Right was this announcement of a new dune board game, you know Because the existing dune board games kind of legendary and infamous in various ways.
Speaker 1: We talked about it on the show before But here's a new dune board game.
Speaker 1: That is the has the official dune license dune theme right which other Like, you know has not been available for other games that recently.
Speaker 1: But It's not anything like the old dune game.
Speaker 1: It is instead a deck building worker placement game made by the people who made clank Which is maybe one of the better deck building games.
Speaker 1: That's not dominion because they're most of the deck building games that aren't dominion or poop Yeah, so usually when you see a deck builder and it's not dominion you're like, eh
Speaker 0: Yeah, maybe if the deck building is like a minor component of another game like slay the spire
Speaker 1: Yep, but Regardless, there's a dune themed right board game coming out that is a worker placement game and a deck builder, which is I guess you know a Combo of two things that are like peanut butter and jelly.
Speaker 0: here is literally all that we know about it.
Speaker 0: Do you want the entire power of the universe?
Speaker 0: and then it says deck building these worker placement talk about spice, right?
Speaker 0: Yep, deck building meets worker placement in a new board game of galactic struggle.
Speaker 0: That's it.
Speaker 0: There's always a video trailer and it's 30 seconds long.
Speaker 0: That's all it says.
Speaker 1: right and dire wolf digital who is maybe the best company at making You know digital editions of board games they make they're making the roots digital root digital edition.
Speaker 1: They made the yellow and yanxi digital edition, which is he works fine.
Speaker 1: Perper, you know has very few issues.
Speaker 1: It's not perfect, but it's pretty damn close to it.
Speaker 1: And they're involved in this game.
Speaker 1: so If you like dune if you like deck building or worker placement if you like clank, right.
Speaker 0: if you like clank the game That's all I can imagine is because clank is all about go into the dungeon like that old infiltration game steal loot get out Before everyone else or get out and hope you don't die like a push.
Speaker 1: This game is probably gonna be about making a deck that gets you the most spice before the game ends.
Speaker 0: The whole premise of clank is like clank is every time you make noises The Dragons more likely to wake up and kill everybody.
Speaker 0: kind of like how we know the Russian kind of like that worm Yeah, or like in the filtration you set off the alarm too many times cops show up.
Speaker 0: So in this game, I feel like the clank is literally walk without rhythm.
Speaker 0: So you don't attract the worm.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's probably what it's gonna be.
Speaker 0: I could feel that I could feel that real hard.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so this this is promised.
Speaker 1: keep your eye on it.
Speaker 0: Well, like storm and worm cards are like curses too many.
Speaker 0: call pair in your hand and then bullshit happens.
Speaker 1: I'm cautiously put a worker you put a worker to go gather water or whatever.
Speaker 0: Yeah, as long as I can be the Harkonnen in some capacity Why you gotta be so bad?
Speaker 1: like I'm always bad I can't.
Speaker 0: you'd be good cuz I'm not cuz I win.
Speaker 0: when I play Harkonnen I tend to win dune.
Speaker 1: Yeah, cuz you're bad.
Speaker 0: yeah Look, yeah, what do you got?
Speaker 0: You got four treachery cards.
Speaker 0: I got eight.
Speaker 0: like what?
Speaker 0: Oh, you have a traitor.
Speaker 0: How many traders do you think I have?
Speaker 0: So in some other news as you know pecs Online is happening because pecs is are basically not happening for the foreseeable future.
Speaker 0: And I just want to remind everyone that pecs online is a real thing and it is 24 by 9 meaning It's gonna go 24/7 for 9 days.
Speaker 0: I and Scott and a lot of our friends and I hope many of you will do the same.
Speaker 0: I'm not gonna take like a whole week off work But I'm going to like make a point of going online Going into these spaces and playing like online games with people during this packs watching panels doing stuff.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean there's been a lot of online conventions so far and I've not really Participated too much in them.
Speaker 1: I've watched a couple panels from some of them like after the fact Like that but like I haven't like gone and like Attended in whatever that means for an internet convention.
Speaker 1: I just been doing my own things, you know.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well, you know like we kind of say a lot especially when we're doing like pre-show stuff or in the meta moment.
Speaker 0: For people like us where our jobs are just remote like we don't actually have any more free time now than we did before like Literally, nothing is different except we can't do some things we want to do.
Speaker 0: But we didn't have enough time to do everything even before that.
Speaker 0: So there is no more free time.
Speaker 0: There's just more hassle and work that we're still doing.
Speaker 0: So I'm not actually playing more games despite not going to work every day But I'm pretty excited about packs online.
Speaker 0: we are doing a panel at it so stay tuned.
Speaker 0: We'll talk about that more in the meta moment.
Speaker 1: Uh Isn't this the meta moment now?
Speaker 0: We're still doing news.
Speaker 1: Oh Okay, I thought this is the meta moment.
Speaker 0: No, should I move into the better moment?
Speaker 0: You want to talk about Luigi's penis?
Speaker 1: That's a huh.
Speaker 0: So about Luigi's penis if you want Kotaku I was looking for like gaming news that I had something to say about and I saw a headline and They got me.
Speaker 0: I was like, you know what?
Speaker 0: I want to see how thorough this article is because the article was titled it's from two years ago and they like resurfaced it.
Speaker 0: Bowser is only four feet tall Judging by Luigi's penis.
Speaker 1: This isn't your thing of the day.
Speaker 1: This is still news.
Speaker 1: It's news.
Speaker 0: I'm saying it's news because hey, it's not news.
Speaker 1: You said it was two years old.
Speaker 0: It's uh, we don't do breaking news.
Speaker 0: We do commentary.
Speaker 0: This is commentary on news Basically news at all.
Speaker 1: if
Speaker 0: you look at this article It compares like the size of Luigi's bulge in this promotional image to the length of standard tennis rackets and other characters And they do a bunch of math and they figure out how tall Bowser is and it's way more Thorough than it had any right to be.
Speaker 0: if any of you if you are the original listener of geek nights You may remember a term that I don't think I've even said out loud in a decade But Gandalf's girthing when you argue about the physical reality of something completely made up for no reason.
Speaker 0: so this article is pretty thorough and they make this argument that Bowser is about exactly four feet tall and The first comment in this article actually ruins the whole thing Completely ruins this entire theory with one sentence Bowser canonically has the ability to change size.
Speaker 1: That's true.
Speaker 0: so much for that and I would argue that Luigi at least in the context of this article probably also has the power to change size.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's eats a mushroom.
Speaker 1: Hey changes sighs.
Speaker 1: I'd also like to ruin the whole article by saying that Penises canonically have the ability to change size.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's what I was getting at with you.
Speaker 0: You went to the mushroom I was getting at.
Speaker 0: the unit of measure that they're using for this can itself change size much like Luigi and much like Bowser.
Speaker 0: Yeah Yeah, that article just popped up promoted in my feed and I popped up a. yeah, just just popped up.
Speaker 0: grew larger Mm-hmm hit a brick.
Speaker 0: anyway, it's time for things Of the day.
Speaker 0: So what do you have?
Speaker 1: What did I have?
Speaker 1: Let me remember by clicking FYI.
Speaker 1: Alright, so I don't know if we did this as thing of the day or news previously.
Speaker 1: This might be a rerun in which case oops.
Speaker 1: I tried to search my own website to see if this is a rerun.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know hard that is when you've been doing a podcast for 15 years.
Speaker 1: Well, and I have the shitty search functionality.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we never rebuilt it.
Speaker 1: I'm rebuilding it now.
Speaker 1: Uh-huh.
Speaker 1: Stay tuned coming along regardless.
Speaker 1: So when we play counter-strike back in the day, right?
Speaker 1: We're talking like, you know counters like go did not exist, right?
Speaker 1: It was it was counter-strike and those counters like source and that was it, right?
Speaker 1: We actually played a lot before counter-strike source even exists.
Speaker 0: I was playing in the betas.
Speaker 0: I was playing before the p90 was introduced and I remember when they introduced the p90.
Speaker 0: it was way too powerful And that was a problem 20 years ago 20 years ago playing counter-strike.
Speaker 1: Goddamn, we're old.
Speaker 1: We had we ran our own little counter-strike server on my old desktop.
Speaker 1: Yeah in the apartment in the apartment there and on our counter a little counter-strike server, right?
Speaker 1: You know, it wasn't actually that powerful a computer.
Speaker 1: So if we had too many People on it it sort of was laggy.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and if we ran a map that was too big that was a problem.
Speaker 1: So I really want to run CS thunder, but that didn't work out too.
Speaker 0: Well, right?
Speaker 0: Ah CS thunder the best counter-strike map ever made exactly.
Speaker 1: So what we did is we ran a certain you want to serve to be popular also, right?
Speaker 1: So we ran a server that ran one map and one map only and that map was FYI squirreled.
Speaker 0: No counter-strike map.
Speaker 0: naming conventions would be like CS underscore something or DE Underscore something or if you're old enough as or es escape.
Speaker 1: Yeah, remember jail and that don't have first, right?
Speaker 1: So those first two letters would tell you what kind of map it was was.
Speaker 1: what was the goal of the map?
Speaker 0: Yeah, like.
Speaker 0: is it a demolition?
Speaker 1: hostages?
Speaker 1: Yeah, escorting the VIP out of the thing, right?
Speaker 1: but FYI people say it stood for a fight yard, or I don't know.
Speaker 1: Fuck you.
Speaker 0: I always understood for fuck you.
Speaker 1: I don't know what the hell it stood for.
Speaker 1: I never thought about it.
Speaker 1: I just knew that FYI means you spawn you pick up guns off the ground that are near your feet.
Speaker 0: They're just laying lined up like you look down.
Speaker 0: There's like an m4 You look up.
Speaker 1: someone else is also looking at is a tiny little like tic-tac-toe board Basically with three rows across and one row in the middle one horizontal, you know thing in the middle perfectly symmetrical.
Speaker 1: You're not perfectly symmetrical.
Speaker 1: There's some obstacles and crates and walls to hide behind a little.
Speaker 1: there's a tiny by zone In the center if you can get to the middle of the map where the most vulnerable position You could spend your money.
Speaker 1: You couldn't spend it where you spawned but you could spend it in the middle if you could get there and then that's how you Get grenades and stuff.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I get the joy of this map.
Speaker 0: The most important part was it's so tiny.
Speaker 0: when you spawn and the game's like, okay ready and then it starts You can see the other team like you can like.
Speaker 0: sometimes like I'll be looking at a terrorist and I'm a counter-terrorist.
Speaker 0: We're both looking at each other and the map hasn't started yet.
Speaker 0: Like I've got my mouse just on his head Like ready to click.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but what if he's standing on a sniper rifle and you're standing on like a pistol?
Speaker 0: Well, then we'll see what happens.
Speaker 0: But you would sometimes get killed in less than a second.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it was very fun.
Speaker 1: It was and it was you wouldn't care even though in counter-strike when you die You don't come back to the next round, but the rounds are so quick.
Speaker 1: It was so fast It was so fun.
Speaker 1: You know, you it was.
Speaker 1: you could just sit there playing ice world forever If the round went on longer than a minute.
Speaker 0: that was like an epic match and usually it was two people sneaking Very carefully, which was usually fun enough to watch to where I wasn't bothered at all that I was dead.
Speaker 1: Nope, not at all.
Speaker 0: or that was like, you know what it is If you're that person who's left a lot so far boy, but you also know everyone's watching you waiting for you to fuck up.
Speaker 0: Yeah, this was like the McDonald's of counter-strike maps.
Speaker 0: This was just like garbage that I was just shoving it in my face.
Speaker 0: I probably played 20 or 30 hours in this map that one year.
Speaker 0: We were running that server.
Speaker 1: So these two articles I read them a long time ago but I guess I either forgot to make them news thing of the day or I did and this is a rerun.
Speaker 1: but the journalists here at rock paper shotgun went out and They wrote all about this map and they did a forensic Investigation of the digital files that composed the map to try to figure out who made this thing Right why it was named what it was made why they made it the way they made it pretty much everything And they found out.
Speaker 1: You know basically as much information as we can find out, you know using Research methods about the history of this map and why it exists and where it came from.
Speaker 1: And if that's fascinating is someone who played it a lot.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so my thing of the day I use this channel once before so I basically can never use it again as my thing of the day now because I'm using it twice but this was too good.
Speaker 0: So this channel called tasting history is this dude and he will recreate Ancient and historic recipes of food like show you the process talk about the history God do like real research and then as faithfully as possible Recreate an ancient dish and then eat it.
Speaker 0: live usually for the first time on camera and talk about it.
Speaker 0: Well, not live recorded on well recorded but live to tape like you.
Speaker 0: record like that is his legit first reaction to this ancient food Right.
Speaker 1: So some food.
Speaker 1: the only video I saw from this guy's he made some old Roman condiment.
Speaker 1: That's basically a fish oil.
Speaker 1: Yeah That is like supposedly was like the best condiment that Romans had.
Speaker 1: It was just salty fish oil, basically Yeah, and he tried to make it and he made the best approximation He could given his resources.
Speaker 1: and he ate it and it.
Speaker 1: yeah, it tasted like salty fish oil.
Speaker 0: So this one is much more fascinating.
Speaker 0: This is basically Kiki on is a healing potion from pre-grease like this is the drink described in the Odyssey and the Iliad that heroes would drink and Based on historical sources.
Speaker 0: It's actually shockingly consistent throughout all of history.
Speaker 0: What Kiki on is made of?
Speaker 0: So he made Kiki on.
Speaker 0: uh, oh does it describe here?
Speaker 0: It's basically this mixture of red wine Barley meal goat cheese and honey, and it look makes this like purplish looking.
Speaker 0: It's not like.
Speaker 0: it's like a cross between a beverage and a yogurt.
Speaker 0: It's almost like a milkshake.
Speaker 1: Mmm, it looks delicious.
Speaker 0: Just like look at me.
Speaker 1: Oh cheese and honey is already a good combo.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's a known modern, you know, I guess also ancient right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, that is a food that is eaten widely today, right?
Speaker 0: the other two things Barley meal and I like barley a lot.
Speaker 1: barley meals really good Yeah, but I mean barley meal plus the.
Speaker 1: I mean, I guess that kind of works.
Speaker 1: That's similar to like, you know, I wouldn't use barley meal.
Speaker 1: I'd use maybe like a oatmeal.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like you have a yogurt you have a yogurt with some granola and some fruit, right?
Speaker 1: That's like it's a breakfast.
Speaker 0: get some groats put some honey and goat cheese in it.
Speaker 0: All right now we're talking That's some food.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you're just using goat cheese instead of like another yogurt in there, right?
Speaker 0: And then red wine like I really like red wine.
Speaker 1: I like using red wine instead of fruit.
Speaker 1: So it's yeah, basically it's like an ancient sort of combo that's similar to like a breakfast cup.
Speaker 0: so the first thing I want to point out is one of the top comments on this YouTube video is Trojans hate this.
Speaker 0: try this one drink that Achilles drinks every day.
Speaker 0: But Watch the video.
Speaker 0: I'm not gonna reveal Whether or like what this drink actually tastes like or if it's good or bad or anything Because this video is good like the history is really good.
Speaker 0: But then you get to the point where he actually has it and tries it and that is when this video becomes a S tier.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think that I would just opt for Your Greek yogurt or some other yogurt fruit fresh fruit, you know granola and What's the last thing honey?
Speaker 1: Honey?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I was particularly into this cuz I'm on honey.
Speaker 1: I can't keep.
Speaker 0: I'm on a Minogue.
Speaker 0: I've always been like weirdly into Minnow in history and Recently, I've been more of a Mycenaean fan.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah Yeah, you like the much later later degenerate societies that came after My stands.
Speaker 0: neat but I've recently been learning more about cycladian cultures like prima no and stuff and it's all just very pretty cyclopean.
Speaker 0: But yeah, basically the TLDR of that is the Greeks you think you know, like Athens and Sparta.
Speaker 0: They were basically like.
Speaker 1: they kind of migrated into the ruins of like multiple older civilizations and kind of just took their stuff Mm-hmm, but basically basically it's you know, you read fantasy stories that talk about like, you know Lost Lemuria or Atlantis, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah like that and it's like okay the Lemuria and Atlantis probably were not real, right?
Speaker 1: but there were civilizations before Greek civilization like Minoans and Cyclopeans and Mycenaeans and that were real even crazier.
Speaker 0: I was gonna talk about this and we're learning more about them all the time.
Speaker 0: I got a thing in the day.
Speaker 0: Some crazy ancient ruins from them from the cycladian and the Minoan era were Discovered and have been excavated since 2018.
Speaker 0: There's actually been updates in that field like big ones.
Speaker 0: So, yeah met a moment.
Speaker 0: we're gonna be live at the crunchyroll Expo with an all-new judge anime by its cover.
Speaker 0: We took that old old old panel.
Speaker 0: We did once at an anime Boston We turned it for a while into a YouTube show that Scott and I were doing.
Speaker 0: We kind of stopped doing it because it's a pain in the ass to make and not that many of you were watching it after The first few.
Speaker 1: also also there's a powerful pandemic.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the pandemic makes it extra hard to make that show.
Speaker 0: So we kind of paused it for a lot of reasons.
Speaker 0: But we brought back the panel version that we did once an anime Boston Cleaned it up made it more to our modern sensibilities like wrote better jokes And we're doing that at the crunchyroll Expo.
Speaker 0: as soon as I know when it will premiere.
Speaker 0: then I'll let you know and obviously It was recorded live to tape like we recorded it in advance.
Speaker 0: but we'll be in a voiled chat and you'll be able to ask you questions like during the panel and React to us or make fun of us or whatever it is You're gonna do.
Speaker 0: we're also gonna be live at the penny arcade Expo online and we are doing a brand new panel.
Speaker 0: Scott's working primarily on this one and it's sort of a tangent from other panels we've done.
Speaker 0: It's like a topic that we'd age into and talk about a little bit, but we'd always then move on to something else.
Speaker 0: So Scott basically does the right turn and we're going deep into.
Speaker 0: when should games ends?
Speaker 0: How do they end?
Speaker 0: Why do they're gonna?
Speaker 1: you're gonna design a game any kind of game.
Speaker 1: you need to write in your rule book, right?
Speaker 1: The game ends when this happens.
Speaker 1: Well, how do you write that rule that one specific rule?
Speaker 1: How do you write it?
Speaker 1: And when it?
Speaker 1: what is a good thing to write and what is a bad thing to write?
Speaker 0: Yep, where is the finish line?
Speaker 1: or a video game or a sport or I guess has to be a multiplayer game where there's winning?
Speaker 0: We're talking about ortho games.
Speaker 0: We're not talking about when should Final Fantasy 7 end.
Speaker 0: Yeah, when should Death Stranding?
Speaker 0: and we're talking about like when should chess end?
Speaker 0: So Friday September 18th at 2 p.m.
Speaker 0: Pacific time But since you know, normally we just say 2 p.m.
Speaker 0: Because like we're at PAX Pacific time That's 5 p.m.
Speaker 0: Eastern Daylight Time on the PAX 3 channel.
Speaker 0: It'll be live to tape.
Speaker 0: We're gonna record it live and then it'll be aired by PAX.
Speaker 0: But we'll be in a chat room like ready to answer questions and stuff.
Speaker 1: We're gonna want packs of Video file and they're gonna play it.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: We could be in the chat room while it's playing.
Speaker 0: basically We could stream it to them live like we have the capability.
Speaker 0: but this is way easier especially because here we would we probably would have streamed it actually live if we were in the same room together.
Speaker 0: But it's such a pain in the ass to do that right now.
Speaker 0: So we got to keep all our options open.
Speaker 0: So stay tuned.
Speaker 0: I'm looking forward to PAX online.
Speaker 0: Otherwise book club book.
Speaker 0: We're not really reading right now.
Speaker 0: We're too busy working on other stuff.
Speaker 0: Emily and I reviewed Salados Amigos and I'm gonna post for the patrons our review of the horniest movie Disney ever made Donald Duck in the Three Caballeros.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna post that review for the patrons first because we can't actually post that one publicly yet Because in the series we're doing the reviews in chronological order.
Speaker 0: We have to make it through victory through air power first, which was technically made between Salados Amigos and the Three Caballeros, but I cannot stress enough to you how utterly fucking horny Donald Duck is in the Three Caballeros like to a degree that is unnerving to my adult sensibilities.
Speaker 0: I wonder what my parents thought about the fact that me and my little brother were obsessed with this movie and would watch it on loop as children.
Speaker 0: You got anything any meta Any meta.
Speaker 1: you should come on to the.
Speaker 1: if you are have an internet connection which I'm sure you do you should use that internet connection and find all of the various spaces that we occupy on the internet and Spend the correct amount of time in those spaces and spend more time in other places.
Speaker 1: But we exist anywhere you look on the internet.
Speaker 1: We are there somehow.
Speaker 0: Yep, our discord channels happen.
Speaker 0: We got a forum where people are posting stuff like YouTube channels.
Speaker 0: Just follow all our stuff.
Speaker 0: Honestly, just google the word gig nights.
Speaker 0: You'll see a ton of crap.
Speaker 0: Like we're past the error We're gonna have to give you a bunch of links.
Speaker 0: You can find us.
Speaker 0: We uh, we've got a lot of Google juice on the gig nights brand from 15 years of podcasting Yep.
Speaker 0: Oh, why do I have a notification in board game geek?
Speaker 0: Oh, they're live streaming some Gen Con stuff.
Speaker 0: Okay Anyway, we are tonight gonna talk about a game.
Speaker 0: pretty sure we reviewed this on gig nice a long long Are you sure we did a very long time ago, but what we're gonna talk about?
Speaker 0: Search trying this out.
Speaker 0: We haven't played a lot of new games.
Speaker 0: I just I'm playing overwatch cuz that's what I'm doing.
Speaker 0: so we figured we take a game that we know very well and we think we're very good at and we've played a lot.
Speaker 0: and Without playing it again and doing some analysis We want to try to talk about like legit how to be good at this game Kind of like those panel we did on how to be good at Puerto Rico or how to be good at Carcassonne.
Speaker 0: We want to do it for another game.
Speaker 1: Yep, so if you don't know how to play the game modern art by Rainer Knizia We are not going to teach you how to play that game.
Speaker 1: We're assuming you know how to play that game already and before you listen to this podcast You should go and read the rules to that game.
Speaker 1: If you haven't played the game You should probably play it a few times because otherwise why do you need to know how to win a game?
Speaker 1: You don't know how to the rules to or have never played before.
Speaker 0: Yep, but the gist of this game The reason I think we want to pick this one.
Speaker 0: It's a bidding game.
Speaker 0: Like the whole game is run auctions for other players to buy stuff from you or Bid in auctions that other players are running and whoever has the most money at the end of the game wins.
Speaker 0: You can also bid on your the things yours yourself auctioning off Yep, and there's multiple kinds of auctions like bidding and auctions is the primary thing in this game.
Speaker 1: That's all you do in this game.
Speaker 1: Yeah is run auctions and bid in auctions of various types, right?
Speaker 1: So to win this game you not only have to basically your decision points in this game are a on your turn You're going to choose a card from your hand and auction it off.
Speaker 1: You're going to right.
Speaker 1: you need to choose the right one.
Speaker 1: The second thing your second decision point in the game is regardless of who is auctioning off what you need to figure out how much you are willing to pay for it and Bid that amount.
Speaker 1: so you need those two things, right?
Speaker 1: Yep, and the rest of the game just sort of takes care of itself.
Speaker 1: make those two decisions wisely and you are good to go Yep, so the fascinating thing about bidding games.
Speaker 0: we talk about this a lot in panels lately to bidding and auctioning and valuation.
Speaker 0: humans are just like Fred are naturally bad at this like people are so bad at it like If you like if you play Monopoly with kids It'll be random like it doesn't like someone will win because Monopoly is random.
Speaker 0: if you play Monopoly and you actually use the bidding rules Against kids you'll probably beat them because kids will bid like a thousand dollars on boardwalk and then not have any money and go bankrupt Immediately.
Speaker 0: people just is all can't do it.
Speaker 1: This is also why our human society has gone away from markets with bartering and Towards price tags on things in stores.
Speaker 0: one of many reasons, but one of many reasons.
Speaker 1: but in the days of bartering it's like bartering became a skill that pretty much everyone had to have or someone in your family or your group had to be good at it or Regardless of how hard you worked or whatever you how
Speaker 0: many nails is a fair price for two chicken eggs
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: So imagine you have a farm where you grow a corn or something and you bring your corn to market.
Speaker 1: if you're bad at Selling figuring out the right price at which to sell the corn you get ripped off You.
Speaker 1: just everyone else in the market is like hey loading up on cheap corn and you go home and you're starving and you can't.
Speaker 1: You know the other thing.
Speaker 1: we're not starving.
Speaker 1: you got corn, but you got nothing else, right?
Speaker 1: You know, you can't.
Speaker 1: you got nothing didn't get enough other things in exchange for the corn, you know You'd not enough clothes not enough meats soaps, whatever you needed, right?
Speaker 1: And you know vice versa.
Speaker 1: maybe someone's really good at bargaining, you know, they don't have as much stuff, right?
Speaker 1: They their farm didn't output, you know They got one cow, but they bring that cow to market and they managed to go home with all the corn from the.
Speaker 1: you know The person who's not good at bargaining how they're living pretty great and there's literally that's where people exchange their goods.
Speaker 1: There's no other goods exchange.
Speaker 1: That's like your only option.
Speaker 1: Yeah magic beans You're not good.
Speaker 1: So if you the point I'm trying to make is that if you're not good at this game modern art and you cannot become good At it you would have lived a very shitty life in the ancient times when there were open-air markets for and no monies
Speaker 0: Yep,
Speaker 1: and everything was bartered.
Speaker 0: so first things first.
Speaker 0: the main thing you have to be able to keep in your head to be good at this game is to be able to figure out the maximum possible value a painting could have.
Speaker 0: because remember after a round ends the Paintings based on how many of them were bought by players and are out in front of people.
Speaker 0: The what the top three pay out some money and the whole point of the game is to get more money than the other players.
Speaker 0: So there is literally never ever a reason in this game to bid more money for a painting than it could Possibly be worth at that one single moments, right?
Speaker 0: So you can look at the chair is no clever strategy that does anything different from that.
Speaker 0: not one, right?
Speaker 1: So it basically it's the more popular paintings right end up being worth more money Right.
Speaker 1: and there's a chart on the side of the board that shows you the rankings of popularity at the end of each round.
Speaker 1: So you can look over there and say aha It's let's say it's round two and you know that the Carl Gitter paintings were the most popular in round one.
Speaker 1: Well that is now increase the value of all Carl Gitter paintings from here to the end of time Right, and maybe the van Gogh's are the.
Speaker 1: is van Gogh one of them.
Speaker 0: I forget I mean, it's all fake names.
Speaker 0: if you play it depend.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it depends on which set you have like some people print their own copies of modern art and have different artworks in them.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but you know Carl Gitter and light metal.
Speaker 1: Oh light metal.
Speaker 1: that's one.
Speaker 1: So let's say light metal was super unpopular in round one, right?
Speaker 1: Well, you know that now the maximum value of light metal is now lower right over, you know Cuz even if light metal is maximum popularity for the rest of the game, right?
Speaker 1: It's the.
Speaker 1: you know that the maximum total value is now less by however many it is.
Speaker 1: I forget.
Speaker 0: Yeah There's a limited number of cards of each type of painting So you have to just keep a count of how many of those cards have been played already and how many do you have in?
Speaker 0: Your hand and how many more cards will you draw over the course of the game that might give you another?
Speaker 0: painting of that type Mm-hmm the paintings that break ties toward themselves.
Speaker 0: There are fewer of them as well and you just have to take all that into account.
Speaker 0: But the thing I see people mess up the most is that once the round is over Like whichever painting had the most out everyone sells those paintings for $30.
Speaker 0: each second place is $20.
Speaker 0: third place is $10.
Speaker 0: Everything else is nothing meaning bidding more than $30 in the first round on anything is 100% pointless.
Speaker 0: that just loses you points for nothing.
Speaker 0: bidding 29 Probably not a good idea But it is plausible that there might be a reason to do it.
Speaker 0: that one dollar profit might make sense.
Speaker 0: But bidding 30 or more especially bidding more than 30 31. yet I see people do it so often even when when Scott and I pointed out to people at the table and tell them Literally bidding this amount of money will only lose you points.
Speaker 0: Here is mathematical proof.
Speaker 0: They will let it for ride.
Speaker 0: Anyway, they'll say no.
Speaker 0: No, I want I still want to go with my bid.
Speaker 1: So this leads into two other things right.
Speaker 1: number one You're on your turn right.
Speaker 1: the first decision point which of the things in my hand do I put up for auction?
Speaker 1: Right, whatever you choose is affecting the popularity You are making.
Speaker 1: if you auction off a green painting a Carl getter you are making Carl getters worth more at that moment.
Speaker 1: So if you have a bunch of Carl getters in front of you Even if the Carl getter you are about to auction if you don't if you're not the one who buys it, that's fine.
Speaker 1: You have just increased the value of the two Carl getters.
Speaker 1: You've already got because you've made it more popular.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right.
Speaker 1: so if you see someone else with like a whole bunch of light metals already in front of them because they've already bought them and Previous auctions that round.
Speaker 1: you probably don't want to put a light metal out there Right because now you're just not.
Speaker 1: even if that person doesn't win this third light metal Someone else buys it for even if they buy it for like a dollar, right?
Speaker 1: Whatever you just gave that other person more value their light.
Speaker 0: They're gonna sell their light metals for more but consequently other players will bid more for your light metal.
Speaker 1: Yes, because if you're desperate you put something up for auction and you buy it yourself your money goes to the bank, right?
Speaker 1: So you better be.
Speaker 1: you know If you're gonna buy something from yourself you better make sure that you're paying less enough that the profit of selling it is worthwhile.
Speaker 1: if Most of the time when you put something up for auction what you want is you want another player to buy it from you at a high price because if you buy something from the Bank, even with a big margin on your sale, right?
Speaker 1: All that does is raise your score, right?
Speaker 1: It gives you money.
Speaker 1: That's it.
Speaker 1: Everyone else stays flat.
Speaker 1: if I can get someone else to buy something from me Especially someone who's ahead of me, right?
Speaker 1: Rim is in the first place that I'm in second place.
Speaker 1: If I can get rim to buy something from me for a dollar.
Speaker 1: That's the same as getting two dollars because rim has gone down one and I've gone up one.
Speaker 1: I have to end the game with the most money.
Speaker 1: I don't care.
Speaker 1: You know how much of the most help what the differences between me in first place and rim and second.
Speaker 1: as long as it's a difference I'm gonna win.
Speaker 0: that is the mistake.
Speaker 0: like mistake number two I see a lot of people making this game is exactly that they will buy their own paintings way more often than is warranted.
Speaker 0: That is usually not a good idea to buy your own painting unless like the situation where I've bought my own painting is Let's say it's the second round never in the first round and I got a bunch of light metal in my hand.
Speaker 0: maybe I auction off a light metal and Someone buys it and pays me some amount of money.
Speaker 0: Then or maybe I maybe I buy my own painting.
Speaker 0: if I buy my own painting That's probably because I have more light metals in my hand to play.
Speaker 0: So I buy my own painting low because there's no light metals out yet.
Speaker 0: People don't think light metals that valuable.
Speaker 0: They don't bid it up that high.
Speaker 0: I buy it for a relatively low price from the bank, then I immediately when I have the auction up again I auction off another light metal.
Speaker 0: So I've primed the market.
Speaker 0: now people are gonna pay me Big for that second light metal and I'm also gonna get the margin of.
Speaker 0: I got a light metal for cheap.
Speaker 1: Yep, so you got to think about this.
Speaker 1: if I'm let's say I'm selling a light metal to rim for $10, right?
Speaker 1: That's a $20 gain for me.
Speaker 1: Assuming rim is ahead of me.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right.
Speaker 0: That's a good assumption Right.
Speaker 1: So if that if that light metal comes around to me and I can bid on it, right?
Speaker 1: I have to be bidding such that I'm paying $20 less than the end value of the light metal, right?
Speaker 1: So if I think the light metal is gonna sell at the end of the round for 40 if rims gonna pay 10 Then if I have to pay more, I guess everyone was paying Yeah, if rims gonna pay me 10 Then and I can pay 20 for it
Speaker 0: that's
Speaker 1: I guess paying 20 would be better.
Speaker 1: That would be equal right.
Speaker 1: me paying 24 from myself is equal to rim buying it from.
Speaker 0: I feel like the math part of this Would be easier if we actually had like a whiteboard.
Speaker 1: well people But actually not because rim is gonna then sell it for 40.
Speaker 1: Yeah at a $30 profit, right?
Speaker 1: So you had to.
Speaker 1: it's a basic calculate.
Speaker 1: They're paying me this much and getting this much profit.
Speaker 1: add those two numbers together and compare it to the number I'm paying.
Speaker 1: first the number I'm getting right and see what the difference is.
Speaker 1: now
Speaker 0: honestly another sort of a better point there is Remember the compounding because in the first round like 30 is the most something can be worth But the second round the third round if a painting keeps showing up in The top three then all of the previous Showings add up so you can have a painting that is worth 60 or 90 like you can have a painting that's worth a ton Later in the game, so You don't really want to go too hard.
Speaker 0: bid too much in the first round because the profits are kept.
Speaker 0: $30 is the most money.
Speaker 0: any painting could be sold for no matter what.
Speaker 0: but in the second round 60 is the most something could be sold.
Speaker 0: for the third round 90 is the most something could be sold for.
Speaker 0: so Hold on to the auction types that are more powerful Especially the double auction for second third fourth round.
Speaker 0: don't waste good auctions in the first round.
Speaker 0: That's something that trips people up a lot because to play a painting whatever painting you play you are stuck with the kind of auction that that painting has on the card and some of the auctions are better or worse for you depending on the Situation on the table,
Speaker 1: right?
Speaker 1: So let's talk about the different kinds of auctions when to play them and how to bid in them effectively.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right open auction is the least risky for everyone and tends to arrive at the most precise value and have the least profit.
Speaker 1: Right, so the open auction is what is where it goes?
Speaker 1: that everyone just keeps bidding whatever they want.
Speaker 0: Do I hear one?
Speaker 0: do I hear two going once going twice?
Speaker 0: I hear three.
Speaker 0: Do I hear ten?
Speaker 0: I'm gonna be living my own painting going once going twice going three times sold to the idiot, right?
Speaker 1: So this is a very good auction.
Speaker 1: it to play because play early in the game Because you're gonna get very close to the real value.
Speaker 1: It's sort of like an information finding auction, right?
Speaker 1: It's like you're learning the value how other.
Speaker 1: how much do other players believe this is worth, right?
Speaker 0: Think of it.
Speaker 0: like every time another player bids like raises the bid they've revealed more information to you.
Speaker 0: You're gonna get so many touch points with the other players than this auction.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you're gonna.
Speaker 1: this is really about learning not about making.
Speaker 1: you're not gonna make big money when you do an open auction.
Speaker 1: Right, you don't want to.
Speaker 1: you know You don't want to do one of those towards the end of the game.
Speaker 1: You want to do them early in the game, right?
Speaker 0: How you do today?
Speaker 0: because if you do toward the end of the game It'll only pan out.
Speaker 0: if you're like auctioning off a super valuable painting near the end But you're just gonna get the maximum possible reasonable profit Like it's just gonna write auctioning off something early in the game with an open auction.
Speaker 1: Not only do you get its value It's like okay.
Speaker 1: I get about what it's worth, right?
Speaker 1: Because it's such a precise auction, but you're gonna.
Speaker 1: that information is is non quantifiable Value that you're also getting and the earlier you get that the more powerful it is like.
Speaker 0: first for example Say to an open information is useless at the end of the game.
Speaker 0: Let's say to an open auction on a Carl Gitter like arbitrarily early in the game nothing's out yet and Scott and Joey Jojo Kind of have a little bidding war with each other like push like back and forth.
Speaker 1: He must have hands full of Carl getters up the wazoo.
Speaker 1: Yeah Like they know Carl Gitter is gonna be real popular.
Speaker 0: one of them wants to play a Carl Gitter Next to extract more value because it'll the bid will go a lot higher once people know If you're bidding in those auctions.
Speaker 0: My advice to you this is psychological.
Speaker 0: like this is a strategy that does not work on people like us But it will work on other people.
Speaker 0: if you know the value you're willing to bid.
Speaker 0: Don't be like bid up and get into bidding wars.
Speaker 0: just let everyone else bid for a while reveal as little information as possible and only enter the bidding if you still want it.
Speaker 0: and The other players appear to be faltering off and the bid looks like it's about to lock down And they're below your number.
Speaker 1: yeah Don't reveal your high number for no You know.
Speaker 1: if they go over right like if I bid 20 and someone out bids me right.
Speaker 0: don't be like I'm out.
Speaker 0: Just don't say anything right.
Speaker 1: well Let's say 20 is the most I'm willing to pay.
Speaker 1: right if I bid 20 and someone else bids 21 22.
Speaker 1: I just revealed information, and I got nothing out of it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I should wait, and if it gets to 19, and it's looking slow It looks like 20 is gonna be a winner.
Speaker 1: Then I'll say 20, but if it looks like 20 is gonna be a loser.
Speaker 1: people are quickly going 18 19 right and I'm like Oh, this is gonna.
Speaker 1: Go past 20.
Speaker 1: Don't bother saying 20.
Speaker 1: Just let it go to 21 22.
Speaker 1: Let it go.
Speaker 0: Yep, if you say even one number and another player does not outbid you you made a mistake.
Speaker 1: Yep, all right, so the next kind of auction is the once-around auction.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you put it out.
Speaker 1: everyone bids in a circle They have one shot, and then it ends up and you get the final say so this is a great auction when you are Pretty sure you want to be able to buy something yourself.
Speaker 1: Yep, right you there's a high margin on it because When you do this kind of auction no one can stop you from buying it yourself.
Speaker 0: Yep You always get the last choice and the only person who can stop you is the person before you by themselves Bidding way too much money, which they're going to give to you.
Speaker 1: Yep if anyone else bids over your number with the once-around auction you're gonna make bank on that.
Speaker 1: so okay sure I'll take it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and if it gets back to you.
Speaker 1: Well you get what you wanted.
Speaker 1: This was something you wanted to buy yourself And you have the power to do so.
Speaker 1: no one else was able to pay enough to make it.
Speaker 1: You know worth your while to take their money.
Speaker 1: Or maybe the person bidding who has the high bid is someone who's like in last place.
Speaker 1: So taking their money isn't as good as taking you know your money right.
Speaker 1: so yeah Then you just take it yourself.
Speaker 1: no one can stop you.
Speaker 1: and the best thing is that if you?
Speaker 1: Don't play a bid if you just take someone else's money in this auction.
Speaker 1: You don't have to reveal any information.
Speaker 1: Yep, even better to say what you were going to bid you.
Speaker 1: just everyone else reveals information to you.
Speaker 1: they reveal whether they were willing to bid more than the prior player and then At the end you can just say okay I'll take someone's money and don't reveal your valuation of that guy.
Speaker 0: and because they only get one shot they have to say The higher number if they actually want it like they can't play any game.
Speaker 0: They have to be like 17.
Speaker 1: they have to say that they say pass which means their numbers below the current number.
Speaker 0: yep Right uh there's also.
Speaker 0: This is very opportunistic.
Speaker 0: This is a good one to use if you have a very high value painting And you just want to have the maximum choice in how that painting get like how that all goes down.
Speaker 0: The bonus of this one is that if no one if everyone passes you just get it for free.
Speaker 0: I've seen it happen Mm-hmm sometimes that sucks in that you'll get basically get nothing for a painting that will be worth nothing.
Speaker 0: But that's that's how the game plays out.
Speaker 0: usually if you do that like I will occasionally do a once-around For a painting that is not likely to be worth anything in the current round.
Speaker 0: But I have a lot of that painting for later rounds and especially if it's the painting that has there's more of that painting.
Speaker 0: Like.
Speaker 0: they're not as rare.
Speaker 0: I'm trying to thin the pool a little bit, but then be able to bust out later in the game.
Speaker 0: But that's a very opportunistic and nuanced play that would require a little more like a whiteboard to show you why I would do this in detail.
Speaker 1: Alright the next kind of auction is the closed fist auction.
Speaker 0: This is the auction that traps players who have no idea what they're doing.
Speaker 1: Alright.
Speaker 1: So the closed fist auction is the auction where players don't have any information to go on.
Speaker 1: you put money in your fist you put Your fist out there everyone reveals their fists Simultaneously and whoever's got the most money wins it.
Speaker 1: so you get information from everyone after the auctions over But you have no idea what to bid during the og.
Speaker 1: yup, so it's up to each player to be good at Evaluating the true value of the painting.
Speaker 1: right because they've got one shot to pick a number put their fist out and open it And that's it.
Speaker 1: so it's great for trapping players who overvalue things into giving you a lot of money And it's especially great for paintings that you don't want to take at all.
Speaker 1: Yeah Because you could.
Speaker 1: just you can put it out there with a bit of zero Get information sell the painting and get a lot of money from someone else.
Speaker 0: Yep, uh This is the one where players make the most mistakes.
Speaker 0: people Weirdly like panic or have trouble with this kind of auction in particular in all games where this exists the closed fist reveal.
Speaker 0: I just watch people play Objectively incorrect bids all the time and fresh fish in any game.
Speaker 0: So my advice to you is if you are struggling with a game like modern art Whenever the hidden auction happens bid less than you think you should Because that will hurt you less than bidding more than you should have.
Speaker 1: Yep, it'll reveal less information about your evaluation if you win with that lower price.
Speaker 1: That's also great.
Speaker 1: You paid less for it And if you get outbid, well someone else paid too much right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, okay Fix price is kind of the weakest auction because you after you're the only one who has to reveal information You have to pick the price.
Speaker 0: You better be right.
Speaker 0: I see people make mistakes here.
Speaker 0: Usually they set the price way too low because they're hoping to buy it themselves.
Speaker 0: But if the price is actually too low someone else is going to buy the painting a hundred percent Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: It's the one that I will use if I'm playing a painting like let's say there's two Carl getters out but it's very early and there's also two of some other things out and I'm holding on to more.
Speaker 0: like I don't have any more Carl getters in my hand and I suspect based on the information I've gained From auctions that there aren't a lot of Carl getters left in people's hands Meaning or the player who has a bunch of Carl getters won't get a chance to do another auction before the round ends in that I might put out a bullshit painting that I know is not gonna be worth nothing.
Speaker 0: with a fixed price low enough to try to trick someone into thinking they can salvage it because they have Sussed out the information state of the game worse than me.
Speaker 0: I'm putting people in a predicament hoping to trick them.
Speaker 0: Otherwise, I'm playing a fixed price auction because I'm forced to because you don't get a choice sometimes in your hand.
Speaker 1: Yep Yeah, yeah, the fixed price auction is really a test of your own skill.
Speaker 1: How good is your valuation of it?
Speaker 1: Did you nail the exact right price?
Speaker 1: that puts all the other players in a tough spot of choosing whether to buy it from you?
Speaker 1: Or not such that you don't care who ends up buying it whether it's you or someone else.
Speaker 1: You're happy with the result no matter what because you're so good at picking that number and this is sort of what separates the pros From the schmoes.
Speaker 1: right?
Speaker 1: if you can use the fixed price auction and set that price exactly, right?
Speaker 1: You're well on your way to winning the game But that's also very difficult to do.
Speaker 1: So why bother doing it when other action types are more advantageous?
Speaker 1: All right, you do it when you have to and when you do do it try to do it very well.
Speaker 1: So you got to do all that math of saying?
Speaker 1: All right, if they buy it at this price, I'll be happy.
Speaker 1: if they buy it at this price I'll be happy if they buy to this price.
Speaker 1: I'll be happy if I have to buy it at this price, then I won't be upset.
Speaker 1: Okay, that's an okay price to put it out at.
Speaker 0: yeah Yeah Also do not play the fixed price auction.
Speaker 0: Even if it's a painting you want to get out there if you don't have a lot of money in behind your shield because you can't bid more than you have.
Speaker 1: and Well, that's that's something else.
Speaker 1: That's a more general strategy right is?
Speaker 1: you can't bid money You don't have.
Speaker 1: so if you keep buying your own paintings, you will run out of money.
Speaker 1: You must sell paintings to other people for a lot of money.
Speaker 0: Yeah, don't wait for the end of the round money.
Speaker 1: That's gonna be too late Right, I guess this sort of is a little tangent, right?
Speaker 1: But if you think about going to an actual auction right in the real world, right?
Speaker 1: Let's say you go to like Sotheby's or whatever and there's auctions going on for famous shit, right?
Speaker 1: Some collectibles nonsense and there's some rich dudes there, right?
Speaker 1: Good luck getting the good shit against the rich dudes, right?
Speaker 1: Because you know, something might be worth a million dollars.
Speaker 1: You only got a thousand.
Speaker 1: a rich dude can now walk away with that for a thousand and one because You don't have the million to bid them up to what it's the true worth, right, you know The same way thing works in modern art.
Speaker 1: if you don't have a lot of money if something's worth 50 bucks And you've only got 20.
Speaker 1: Well, someone's gonna get it for 21 and Nothing you could do about it.
Speaker 1: so you need to look at your own coffers and try to sell things to other players at high prices because Increasing your own funds if you're sitting at the table with a bunch of chips in front of you Even if you are weak in paintings.
Speaker 1: You don't have a lot of paintings in front of you, right?
Speaker 1: Because you've been selling them, but you got chips.
Speaker 1: you can dominate in the later rounds easily because no one else has ships.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you're gonna be able to buy a lot of stuff way below value Even though everyone else was paying accurate values in the current round.
Speaker 1: They were paying them all to you.
Speaker 0: So the double auction is the whole game.
Speaker 0: if you play with skilled players, that is literally the whole game.
Speaker 0: There is almost no reason to ever play a double auction in the first round.
Speaker 1: No, no unless they're literally.
Speaker 1: I've just a handful of double auctions by some bad and
Speaker 0: honestly I won't even play him in the second round Unless I'm doing it specifically to get two of a painting out Either to force the round to end and cause a weird outcome that denies someone else a whole bunch of money Like I force a painting that my rival has three of into being fourth place and getting nothing But that I lose out too because I don't get to auction anything off like the round just ends.
Speaker 0: That's a play that's highly situational.
Speaker 0: You got to be good at math and know that the math will work out or I'm gonna get two out to force something to Four to guarantee that it's gonna be at least in second place.
Speaker 0: I Mean, but it could fall into third place with the.
Speaker 0: you know The whole precedence order and the tie break.
Speaker 0: but you get my point.
Speaker 0: the double auction is the big play.
Speaker 0: It's gonna make one more paint one type of painting way more valuable in a hurry.
Speaker 0: So my first advice is if someone else plays a double auction for one type of painting and then you Have one of those left in your hand a good thing to do is put that up for auction Immediately when you get a chance again especially if you go right after that double auction because people are gonna be pumped up.
Speaker 0: that double auction basically Guaranteed that paintings worth cash and now you're gonna be able to collect some of that cash by selling yet another one.
Speaker 0: Definitely don't buy your own painting in that situation.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm the double auction.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I really can't see good reasons to play them in the first round like ever.
Speaker 1: no because the value of people have less money Right and the values of things are unknown and lower, right?
Speaker 0: You don't have that history of like Carl Gitter being worth 30 20 30 the first three rounds.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so but you know in later rounds it's like okay How much are you gonna pay for two of something in the first round?
Speaker 1: It's like Not much.
Speaker 1: if you just hold that stuff in your hand until later rounds.
Speaker 1: It's like well two of that suddenly two of that painting you can sell it to someone else for a whole bunch.
Speaker 1: Yep It's pretty straightforward.
Speaker 1: You're selling two at once.
Speaker 0: so like in a package deal Playing a double auction early in a round will cement that painting is likely to pay out.
Speaker 0: playing it later in a round is Likely to give you a big payout.
Speaker 1: Now remember the double auction that the method is One card has a doubler on it.
Speaker 1: right you're putting it with another painting and you're using the auction method of the second painting.
Speaker 1: That's the rule right?
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: That's the rule remember.
Speaker 1: It's the rule.
Speaker 0: It's it's a long time fiddly stuff around getting a painting for free and all that.
Speaker 0: But that never really happens among skilled.
Speaker 1: you do not want to do a double auction with the fixed price.
Speaker 1: Oh, no, that's that's not a good idea because good luck picking the exact right price.
Speaker 1: That's gonna rake in the dough You don't?
Speaker 1: you know, you want to use you know, pretty much any of the other types.
Speaker 0: But really the once-around is really good with it because it gives you the final power over that.
Speaker 0: Basically with once around and a double auction if the table Under values the painting you're just gonna get it like you're gonna get such a deal I'm gonna get two paintings cheap.
Speaker 0: Yep, if the table over values it you're gonna get a big payout.
Speaker 0: You pretty much win no matter what like.
Speaker 0: that's just always a good situation.
Speaker 0: Yep, the only time you did net it won't work out is if the painting type you're doubling is Like at zero and other paintings are all already at three or four.
Speaker 0: Then you're gonna waste your double auction.
Speaker 1: Yeah doubler on the open auction pretty good Yeah, right doubler on the closed fist is sort of a gamble.
Speaker 1: right.
Speaker 1: somebody, you know, everyone might bid, you know Poorly, right.
Speaker 1: and you end up, you know putting out.
Speaker 1: look like what number you putting out there, right?
Speaker 1: You don't want to put out a number to where like, you know, if you put out, you know say 30. someone else puts 29.
Speaker 1: It's like I'd rather what I had there 29.
Speaker 1: Why did I do you know to decide you valued?
Speaker 0: That's when I look at card counting.
Speaker 0: How many of each painting have I seen?
Speaker 0: how many are left in the deck?
Speaker 0: Like that's where you have to make the call because remember the historical values are all added.
Speaker 0: But if a painting doesn't at least make third place, none of that matters.
Speaker 0: It's worth nothing that round.
Speaker 0: So if something if Carl Gitter when 30 30 30 and you're in the fourth round you might think oh Double I'll put out a double Carl Gitter as the first auction that'll pay out.
Speaker 0: big People might count the cards and realize Carl Gitter can't even get into third place Because one person has the rest of the getters in their hand.
Speaker 0: They're not gonna play them and all the rest of them were already played to cause those three 30s to happen in the first three rounds.
Speaker 0: Play it.
Speaker 0: that's like the final mistake that sophomore players of this game will make.
Speaker 0: they will forget that a painting is running out and Cannot place in the final round.
Speaker 1: It's like oh this painting has been so popular the whole game.
Speaker 1: It's worth a fortune Yeah, but there's none left.
Speaker 1: people have bought them all.
Speaker 1: there's no van goes left in the world.
Speaker 1: They've already been sold.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's gonna be super unpopular these days simply because there's no you know, it's like everyone's holding their van.
Speaker 1: goes no one selling?
Speaker 0: Yep It's only valuable if enough of them will be played before the end of the round to make it place at least third.
Speaker 0: So you have to figure out what are the odds?
Speaker 0: It'll be it'll place at all.
Speaker 0: and once you figure out those odds Then you can use that and the maximum payout to figure out how much you should bid Generally bid higher
Speaker 1: on that
Speaker 0: if you are losing bid lower on that if you are winning The nuances if you can convince the players beating you to bid on it
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: so the final thing you need to win a modern art is Luck because there is some luck in when you're drawing paintings, right?
Speaker 1: It's like you might end up drawing And like the final rounds like a whole bunch of cards and all those cards are Unvaluable paintings that aren't gonna rank.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: No one's cared about them the whole game and They all have shitty auction types on.
Speaker 0: so I get a whole.
Speaker 1: because remember you start with a set of cards and you draw Three fixed auctions for Carl Gitter and Carl Gitter hasn't ranked in any round so far and it's the last round.
Speaker 1: Yeah, fantastic.
Speaker 0: Oh, well, or like I remember like I remember this game we played of it This was it like an early paxies.
Speaker 0: I like I remember the moment because at no point in the entire game did I draw a double auction not once Not one turns out.
Speaker 0: you cannot win this game if that happens to you unless multiple other players are very bad at this game.
Speaker 0: But this was a table of like powerful people.
Speaker 0: So there was literally nothing I could do.
Speaker 0: there was just no way to win.
Speaker 0: double auctions are just.
Speaker 0: they're so powerful if nothing else.
Speaker 0: Make sure you are very careful with the double auctions you play.
Speaker 0: that is the key to victory.
Speaker 0: Once you get past the basics of don't bid more than something could be worth.
Speaker 1: All right, so you're playing the right auctions.
Speaker 1: You're choosing the right paintings.
Speaker 1: You're bidding the right amounts.
Speaker 1: You're participating in the auctions properly.
Speaker 1: Oh, that's what we didn't talk about right?
Speaker 1: So you're not the seller in the auction, right?
Speaker 1: You're the buyer.
Speaker 1: Ah Someone does the different kind of auctions, right?
Speaker 1: How much do you bid on?
Speaker 0: Here's my simple heuristic number one I will bid more if the person I am buying from sucks at the game or is not likely to beat me, right?
Speaker 1: It's the opposite of what we said before someone's buying from you.
Speaker 1: They're going down and you're going up right.
Speaker 1: you buy from someone.
Speaker 1: you are helping that player whose current turn it is.
Speaker 1: So don't just look at the painting that they're selling and how much it's worth think about who that is.
Speaker 1: It's like Oh rim is selling.
Speaker 1: I'm willing to pay less when rim is selling then when Joey Jojo is selling.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right if that they might sell the same painting in the same auction type.
Speaker 1: But if rim is the seller I'd rather have my money go to Joey Jojo's, you know bank account than rims bank account.
Speaker 1: All right, so I'll pay.
Speaker 1: I'll bid less in the rim selling auctions.
Speaker 1: So that doesn't matter what type of auction it is, yeah, right it's just who is it right?
Speaker 1: try You don't know exactly where you rank in the game overall But you can get a pretty good idea because just how much money you have and how much your paintings plus the paintings You've already bought are worth, right?
Speaker 1: So, I mean like you I guess you could track it perfectly if you're some kind of genius or you worked really hard But you could just sort of you know, get a feel for it, right?
Speaker 1: You know, you see some of the pile of chips.
Speaker 1: don't buy paintings from them for too much money.
Speaker 1: Make them buy their own paintings to empty their pile of chips, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know see someone else who has got barely any chips.
Speaker 1: Yeah buy their paintings from them.
Speaker 1: They'll have to won't be able to outbid you.
Speaker 1: you'll be able to buy them cheap and give money to someone who's not ahead of You.
Speaker 0: also you can Game people who are bad at this game a little bit and trick them into buying from you especially with the fixed price Mm-hmm, like look at the turn order.
Speaker 0: if a weak player is sitting to your left You can put the party if you can figure out a price that feels low But you know isn't?
Speaker 0: you can often trick them into buying something that there's no one else will talk.
Speaker 1: table talk You know talk about psychology.
Speaker 1: table talk is not banned in this game.
Speaker 1: You can be like, oh you can get you act like you're that guy that you know The smooth talker and the ancient barter.
Speaker 0: I got a handful of getters right here.
Speaker 0: Don't even try to make get her anything but like it's getters gonna be number one thirty points guaranteed.
Speaker 1: Right and just you know, try to mess with people right to get them to bid over under right.
Speaker 1: basically make any mistake whatsoever.
Speaker 1: It's just gonna benefit you right.
Speaker 1: just get people to not do all the things we just told you to do.
Speaker 0: Yep The other thing I'll do is something that I just tend to look for the painting that places Every round but is not in first every round like ideally something that's like 10 in the first round 20 in the second round 10 or 20 in the third round.
Speaker 0: if I have enough of that in my hand I will save and try actively to make it number one in the third round not to get those paintings But to get everyone else to buy them from me Because I know there'll be a lot of them and if they're in my hand Then I can put them out.
Speaker 0: people bid them up.
Speaker 0: Someone else will probably try to ride that train.
Speaker 0: put out at least one and I'll be able to buy one.
Speaker 0: to also capitalize on Both sides now.
Speaker 0: I'm winning on both sides of the transactions and That's a pretty good way to win this game.
Speaker 1: like so when you're right.
Speaker 1: So when you're participating in an auction as a buyer, right pick your number.
Speaker 1: right taking into account Not just the value of the painting but also who you're buying it from.
Speaker 1: right reveal as little information as possible.
Speaker 1: Right if it's an open auction like we said I think earlier.
Speaker 1: right bid when if it seems like your number is gonna be a winning number based on other people's behavior.
Speaker 1: and If not, don't reveal your number.
Speaker 1: just let someone else win it because they're out bidding you.
Speaker 1: Anyway, you didn't have to reveal anything.
Speaker 1: if it's once around say your number if it comes to you on the once around.
Speaker 1: if it's already Over you pass, right?
Speaker 1: If it's a fixed price?
Speaker 1: if the price is lower than the price that's in your mind buy it.
Speaker 1: Otherwise, don't All right, if it's double auction right try to pay less.
Speaker 1: figuring out the true value is hard.
Speaker 0: So the lag.
Speaker 1: if it's a closed fist put your number in your hand put it out and reveal it.
Speaker 0: Yep, like this the last piece of advice I have is if you're auctioning off a painting or you don't care that much Like especially like an open auction for something that's kind of middling and may or may not place and you don't really care that much Like you're just playing it to get out of your hand or whatever.
Speaker 0: Whenever a decision is kind of arbitrary like that try to play a painting.
Speaker 0: that makes it more likely that someone who's doing better than You will get screwed Like if Scott's got three getters in front of him and nothing else has been played.
Speaker 0: auction off a non getter Like yeah, put out some garbo lighting.
Speaker 0: fixed price something.
Speaker 1: You're affecting the value of the already sold paintings no matter which painting you put out there.
Speaker 1: Right, so even if you know you make a good deal right on what you paid and what you sold.
Speaker 1: versus the value of the Painting that you're selling or buying You're affecting the values of the other paintings as well.
Speaker 1: Which gives or takes away money from other players of a losing player.
Speaker 1: has a bunch of getters in front of them.
Speaker 1: play a getter May get her more valuable.
Speaker 1: That's losing.
Speaker 1: player will get money.
Speaker 1: Who cares right?
Speaker 1: if rim is winning and has a bunch of getters?
Speaker 1: do not play getters.
Speaker 1: They're just going to make rim.
Speaker 1: or is existing getters worth more?
Speaker 1: don't play them at all.
Speaker 1: Just hold on to them.
Speaker 1: Even if someone old pays for them Even if someone over pays you for them and you profit rim is also profiting even if he doesn't buy or sell them.
Speaker 1: It just sits there watching you trade them with someone else.
Speaker 1: Alright, don't let that happen.
Speaker 0: See what I realize, you know, what other game we could have done this with the listener pointed out I'm an array.
Speaker 0: We are both raised.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we could do.
Speaker 1: I'm an array.
Speaker 0: I'm an array.
Speaker 0: I think I could get to the point of like.
Speaker 0: here are set plays.
Speaker 0: this game is like super dialed in
Speaker 1: yep, pretty much
Speaker 0: partly because we played it enough to where like Literally, the only determiner of who wins when we play Amun Ray with our set of people is the randomness of what cards get drawn Because everything else like people play properly optimally.
Speaker 1: I can tell you this that in Amun Ray and also power grid I have a very similar heuristic because those games Modern art is just bidding power grid and mom and ray have bidding right in an auction Followed by a phases where you need to spend your money on resources.
Speaker 1: Yeah So an Amun Ray you're buying pyramids and farmers and in power grid you're buying houses and you're buying resources.
Speaker 0: I'm trying to end my.
Speaker 0: I'm trying to end my Operating building area phase with no more money like dollar tight, right?
Speaker 1: So what I do?
Speaker 1: in those games?
Speaker 1: my heuristic is generally, okay.
Speaker 1: Let me figure out how much money in power grid I need to buy all the fuel I need And all the houses I want to buy and I'll subtract that mentally from my money pool Right and the rest of the money I'm willing to bid on.
Speaker 1: if there's a power plant I want I will spend all the rest of the money on it up to right obviously Hopefully not all of it but up to that much right?
Speaker 1: It's like this is the money I need to buy resources.
Speaker 1: I'm willing to spend all the rest and the same thing on Amun Ray.
Speaker 1: It's like alright, I need this much money for pyramids I need this much money for cards.
Speaker 1: I need this much money for farmers.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna have this much money left over if I buy everything I want.
Speaker 1: I'll have $20 left over.
Speaker 1: All right Well, I'll sacrifice $20 to the gods, right?
Speaker 1: That's I don't need it for next round to our god Right or negative.
Speaker 1: I'll nay I'll spend everything I have to negative the gods if I wanted to go the other way.
Speaker 0: because that's one thing I like about sumer.
Speaker 0: Is the the?
Speaker 0: because there's a big bidding component in sumer.
Speaker 0: It's very mule like on the switch, but You can always bid an infinite amount of money if you're willing to spend victory points once you run out of cash.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's pretty fun.
Speaker 0: That's real fun and sometimes it's the right idea, but that is the kind of mechanic much like the auctions in modern art that will cause a poor or Mathematically deficient player to make a very bad decision and destroy themselves in the first round.
Speaker 1: Alright, so I think hope that helps people win at modern art and also other bidding games Gives you something to think about.
Speaker 1: it's a good game I think to do this with on a podcast because it's not.
Speaker 1: there's no like visual elements to modern art.
Speaker 1: It's not like a chess where you have to see the the board.
Speaker 0: I think the only thing that would have that we could do if we made this with a video.
Speaker 1: There's an actual math.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I do the actual math.
Speaker 1: or even like much.
Speaker 0: Is it gonna be worth show like a table and show like here's a situation?
Speaker 0: What do you do?
Speaker 0: Like here's what I would do exactly if the board look like there is a packs unplugged again.
Speaker 1: Why don't we do learn and win modern art?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'm 100% down for that because it got reprinted a bunch of times.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we don't like the reprints, but I like the terrible art from the first one.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well I don't know if the one you have is even the first one.
Speaker 1: There's probably older ones, but it's been again.
Speaker 1: It's been printed many times.
Speaker 1: There's also lots of print and play editions.
Speaker 1: Yeah, obviously you should be buying a copy of a game that you want But you know buy it and then if you like different art, maybe you know make also print one, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah But yeah, there's also modern art the card game which is slightly different.
Speaker 1: I haven't played it But it I believe it is more portable.
Speaker 1: So maybe try that one.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 0: modern art is in a tiny tiny box.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but you won't have if you're playing or playing the car or something true the or on a train.
Speaker 1: Yeah, not having the chips I guess would be an improvement.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I haven't played the card game.
Speaker 1: I just know that it's a version.
Speaker 1: It's only cards.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: So that's the thing.
Speaker 0: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott.
Speaker 0: special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and brand.
Speaker 1: Ok for the logos be sure to visit our website at front row.
Speaker 1: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 0: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 1: But unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 0: It's actually recorded at night And the patreon patrons for this episode of geek nights are Alan Joyce Heidi McNichol Marty greenia just like a dude guy chart a vision Graham Finch.
Speaker 0: You hold the key to my heart.
Speaker 0: She gave me a kiss and then she gave me my ticket.
Speaker 0: Clinton Walton J Bantz Ren from New Zealand Ryan Perrin Nicholas Brandau Chris midkiff the thirst for hydrated Ganon dread Lily Tenebrae Chris Reimer Finn Sean Klein Shervin vulnerable and a whole bunch of people who do not want me to say their names.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna post this week for you and only you the patrons for now our Review of horny Donald Duck's adventures through Central and South America the three copy arrows Until we get our victory through airpower review together Which is gonna take us a little longer because we did all the duck shows in one go.
Speaker 0: We're spending a lot of time recording panels for upcoming online cons.
Speaker 0: That's why we didn't do shows last week.
Speaker 0: We might have some disruptions to the show in the next week or two while we get together our pecs panel or potentially pecs panels.
Speaker 0: But uh, we'll cross that bridge after we burn it.
Speaker 0: Anyway, now I leave you with.
Speaker 0: Let him go boneface.
Speaker 0: We'll take those children.
Speaker 1: no, I'll take those children.
Speaker 0: That's right Skeletor.
Speaker 1: I figured you'd show up here when you two are finished.
Speaker 0: We'll take the children now hand them over.
Speaker 0: Horde-prime will know who's number one.
Speaker 0: Good aim you hit yourself.
Speaker 0: I Take those goody-goods not a freaking help at Hordak.
Speaker 0: better get back children orko.
Speaker 1: go with them, right?
Speaker 0: You're not delivering them to hard prime.
Speaker 0: Forget it he man.
Speaker 0: The little fools are delivering themselves to our prime.
Speaker 0: What is it?
Speaker 0: It's hard prime.
Speaker 0: Come on, Shira.
Speaker 1: We must stop him.
Speaker 1: robots get them.
Speaker 1: Hang on orko, we're on our way.