Speaker 1: It's Wednesday, September 16th, 2020.
Speaker 1: I'm rim.
Speaker 1: I'm Scott and this is geek nights.
Speaker 1: tonight We are talking about the fantastic wolf walkers.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: So we had a like I think I alluded to in the closing bits in the last episode.
Speaker 1: Literally minutes after we finished recording geek nights the preamp in Scott's audio device died like it exploded or something.
Speaker 0: We're pretty sure that we're pretty.
Speaker 0: we are pretty sure.
Speaker 0: That is the most likely scenario right.
Speaker 0: so you know when we're recording the podcast together We have like a mixer or a device with two inputs And that's we're good to go right.
Speaker 0: so for me to record the podcast on my own You know to use a microphone with XLR.
Speaker 0: you obviously can't just plug that into your computer.
Speaker 0: I've never seen a computer with an XLR input You need.
Speaker 1: I saw a sound card for an old case that had XLR inputs in the like five and a quarter inch like Five-and-a-half inch opening bay in the front.
Speaker 0: oh Sure sure.
Speaker 0: so the device I've had for six years for thing for scenarios like this is this thing which you can see if you're Watching the stream, but if you're not it doesn't matter.
Speaker 0: It's the sure X to you.
Speaker 0: sure the same people who make the sure microphones, right?
Speaker 1: Yes, I'm 57 you 58.
Speaker 0: yeah, literally the letter X the number two the letter you.
Speaker 0: it Literally is XLR to USB.
Speaker 0: it is a tiny rod.
Speaker 0: You can fit in your fist one end of it as XLR one end of it is USB and all it does is You know there's a monitor.
Speaker 0: There's a headphone hole on the sides.
Speaker 0: you could listen to it if you want.
Speaker 0: you can actually use it as a sound card and listen.
Speaker 0: also There's a knob for adjusting the gain on the microphone.
Speaker 0: There's a knob for the volume of the monitoring and there's a knob to switch between when you're monitoring How much volume you want to hear from the computer side and how much volume you want to hear from your own voice, right?
Speaker 0: Or whatever instrument you're playing or whatever.
Speaker 0: and then there's a button for phantom power.
Speaker 0: That's all it is.
Speaker 0: It literally has no other feature whatsoever.
Speaker 0: It's really solidly built.
Speaker 0: it worked for six years and I'm 90% sure that this is the broken part because I tried it on a different computer With a different USB cable and a different microphone and it still didn't work, right?
Speaker 0: So we tried all that replaced all the other pieces.
Speaker 0: the microphones obviously working because I'm using it right now.
Speaker 0: That's not the broken part.
Speaker 0: The computer is working.
Speaker 0: I'm using that right now.
Speaker 0: That's not the broken part.
Speaker 0: So what it was happening is if you plug this into a computer, right?
Speaker 0: It detects it.
Speaker 0: The computer doesn't know anything's wrong.
Speaker 0: The computer is like, hey, there it is.
Speaker 0: We're good to go.
Speaker 0: But there's a little light an LED that can turn on green or red.
Speaker 0: that indicates that you know Volume is coming through right that sound is coming from the XLR side and it's red when the sound is too hot and That light no longer turns on.
Speaker 0: when you plug headphones in the monitor, you don't hear anything anymore.
Speaker 0: and Even though the computer detects it perfectly if you look in the windows You know recording devices the you know, the level meter basically never moves ever So pretty sure.
Speaker 0: the preamp and this just died after six years.
Speaker 0: So I had to go buy something new and I had to buy my second choice because my first choice Was not available for a rush, you know quick shipment.
Speaker 0: It was out of stock everywhere and it won't be here.
Speaker 0: Even my first second choice won't be here till tomorrow.
Speaker 0: So we'll see how that works and if we have to do anything, so there you go.
Speaker 0: So yeah, I don't know if they still make the sure X to you or if they still sell it.
Speaker 0: Should you buy it?
Speaker 0: I recommend buying it only if you really really need a small USB XLR interface.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and you and you expect it to last for six years if you're sitting at a desk or You're in any sort of that kind of scenario where you don't really need it to be this small.
Speaker 0: Pay the extra money and get you know.
Speaker 0: One of the ones I was looking at a pre-sonus one this scarlet focus, right one.
Speaker 0: And is this a moto one?
Speaker 0: you can google and you'll see.
Speaker 1: all of them are apparently like a plus devices Really like it comes down to what you're using them for.
Speaker 1: like I you I'm a really dedicated personas But I also set up really complex pipelines using their software.
Speaker 1: Scott doesn't need any of that crap.
Speaker 0: The personas one looked great.
Speaker 0: I just I ordered the focus right one because it was way smaller.
Speaker 1: not sure X to you small Yeah, but yeah My audio interface is like why it's like a rack amount thing that I got in a little rack down here And it was.
Speaker 0: it was well reviewed.
Speaker 0: So we'll see.
Speaker 0: but the moto one actually looked the nicest.
Speaker 0: It was just out of stock everywhere.
Speaker 1: Yeah But yeah These are the trials and tribulations of like having to record podcasts and make panels and everything remotely during kovat.
Speaker 1: We'll be doing this for probably at least six more months.
Speaker 1: Maybe a year.
Speaker 0: So here I am using the panel set up for this show because I don't have any other way to use this microphone Which is good news to the recording yet another panel soon that you'll be able to see at Superman.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I had to it's coincidence.
Speaker 0: I had to set up this anyway, so why not?
Speaker 1: Yeah So in some actual anime news, you probably know if you've listened to geek nights at all Though I don't think I've mentioned this show in a long time doesn't really come up and casual conversation.
Speaker 1: But probably one of my favorite anime and all of my life is Irresponsible Captain Tyler.
Speaker 0: I'm just an anime that only old anime nerds like us even know exists.
Speaker 1: I found out about it before it even got released in the US.
Speaker 1: I was like into it.
Speaker 0: I found out about it at anime club.
Speaker 1: I watched a fan sub of the first episode and I was like really excited.
Speaker 1: I bought like the VHS's as it came out.
Speaker 1: It took a long time to come out But I didn't see the end of it.
Speaker 1: as much as I loved this show I couldn't get past like the first seven or eight episodes.
Speaker 1: I want to say it was like in high school and then we got to RIT.
Speaker 1: eventually at some point I Realized wait, I could just watch the rest of that show that I liked.
Speaker 1: It's all the anime club library and we watched it all eventually.
Speaker 1: and the movie - yeah And there's a bunch of OAV episodes and all this stuff.
Speaker 1: There's a newer version of it like a series - maybe I'll give it a rewatch.
Speaker 0: I think it's cuz.
Speaker 0: I basically remember almost nothing.
Speaker 0: I remember the core concept and an alien girl.
Speaker 0: It's a.
Speaker 1: it's definitely in my top 10 of anime.
Speaker 1: I've liked in my entire life.
Speaker 1: Yeah hard to get it disappeared from streaming sites I want to say a while ago Like I have DVDs of it and that seems to be the only legit way I could watch it really.
Speaker 1: but somehow this show Like many other shows that have gotten a re-release in recent history It's getting a collector's ultra edition blu-ray release meaning
Speaker 0: I can write stuff Yep,
Speaker 1: so meaning I can buy those blu-rays rip them and then get rid of those blu-rays because I don't want them But
Speaker 0: gonna or wait for someone else to rip them and download.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but the point is This show if you've never watched it figure out a way to watch it Even if you're not invested enough to get this.
Speaker 1: like ultra collector's edition this and master Keaton Are possibly the most underrated Anime in Western fandom ever in terms of number of people who have watched them Versus how good they actually are.
Speaker 0: there are better shows Right.
Speaker 0: So master Keaton is basically really awesome Japanese, dude Except he's all humble and acts like he's not that as good as he is.
Speaker 0: Is that right?
Speaker 0: So it'd be like, you know, imagine if like Clark Kent didn't transform into Superman.
Speaker 0: He just like lifted a car occasionally and was like, yeah, I'm not so great He's a little bit like right like Keaton's a little bit like Matlock a little bit, right Irresponsible.
Speaker 0: captain Tyler is a complete like, you know doofus, right?
Speaker 1: Or is it all a brilliant?
Speaker 0: Transcendent being it's a complete doofus who messes everything up, but somehow succeeds Despite being a doofus.
Speaker 0: and you're supposed the whole point is that you can't tell.
Speaker 0: is He pretending to be a doofus and is a secret genius or just so lucky That his doofus ness manages to succeed despite, you know what he's doing.
Speaker 0: It just stumbles into success, right?
Speaker 0: It's not an inspector gadget situation where there's like penny is actually making the success happen, right?
Speaker 0: Imagine if inspector gadget just succeeded without penny and brain being there.
Speaker 0: That's what.
Speaker 0: that's what irresponsible captain Tyler is.
Speaker 1: But it asked it builds and builds and builds and as funny as it is like it's primarily a comedy.
Speaker 1: It also has that thing that we love like tank police.
Speaker 1: has this to Dominion tank police or a Pat LeBourre Where there's a gang of idiots who are sort of like friends with or working with the main character and they're just doing their idiot Shit in the background all the time.
Speaker 1: I love that in anime.
Speaker 0: So that's those are the.
Speaker 0: that's captain Tyler's coming back.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so other big news right discotheque media who is a come a US anime distribution publishing production company, I don't know which one they count as They often put out the good old Animes right.
Speaker 0: the license rescues the re releases that kind of stuff, right?
Speaker 0: So like if you told me pick one US anime, you know Distributing publishing company and you can have their library and but you can't have any other anime from any other the US companies Just go tech every time.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right.
Speaker 0: So since there's a lack of anime conventions or lack of anime conventions to go to in person.
Speaker 0: Right what they did is rather than attend an online anime con They just did their own panel on their own right.
Speaker 0: they had some technical difficulties.
Speaker 0: Did their own.
Speaker 1: We have technical difficulties trying to make this stuff happen.
Speaker 0: Yeah they just did their own broadcast to announce all their shit on their own all at once and You don't need to watch that broadcast because they did a Twitter thread where they broke went down and broke down Everything they announced in the panel.
Speaker 0: they live tweeted themselves, right?
Speaker 0: So you could I just read the Twitter thread to see the live tweets and I got all the info.
Speaker 1: I scroll down a little bit.
Speaker 1: I see Rosa Versailles.
Speaker 0: There's some hot shit announcements in here.
Speaker 0: right.
Speaker 0: most of them are bure announcements But it doesn't matter because even if you don't care about getting plastic discs, like we don't want plastic discs it means that all of these shows are going to be legally available in high quality or Illegally available in high quality from somewhere, right?
Speaker 0: So Rosa Versailles which was on crunchyroll and I don't think is anymore that coming out bure.
Speaker 0: So that will be available again.
Speaker 0: How'd you may know it Bo?
Speaker 0: right awesome show that I don't think people watched.
Speaker 0: if you want to see a guy punch a bear In the face, right?
Speaker 0: There you go People who like the whatever giant robo this that like gin ray side thing, right?
Speaker 0: They're bringing that back.
Speaker 1: Yes, you can show I forgot all about again.
Speaker 1: She can.
Speaker 0: Is that even?
Speaker 0: I don't even see that on the list.
Speaker 1: Oh, no, I'm scrolling through their thread.
Speaker 1: That is a fan replying to them at the bottom of their thread.
Speaker 1: Never mind.
Speaker 0: Okay It's a show we completely forgot about right coming back in.
Speaker 0: not HD right SD blu-rays.
Speaker 0: Big big Lupin announcements, right?
Speaker 0: So they got Lupin the third Tokyo crisis.
Speaker 0: That's one of those Lupin movies.
Speaker 0: I think one of it.
Speaker 0: I think it's one of the newer ones.
Speaker 0: I don't know if I've seen it.
Speaker 1: I forget which one that is right.
Speaker 0: the Probably best new Lupin TV series the Fujiko Minae.
Speaker 0: right which funimation had and then Ended.
Speaker 0: they didn't renew it.
Speaker 0: So here comes discotheque.
Speaker 0: Just pick it right back up.
Speaker 0: It'll be available again.
Speaker 1: You fell off the Lupin the third train.
Speaker 1: Which that show the Fujiko Minae.
Speaker 1: Lupin basically starts a new era of a plus Lupin.
Speaker 0: Yep, what's interesting?
Speaker 0: Is that some of these funimation and other licensed rescue ones they're doing.
Speaker 0: they guess they purchased the rights to that Like the dub, but they're not dubbing it.
Speaker 0: They're like getting the dub funimation did and just putting it on there.
Speaker 1: That's the right way to go.
Speaker 1: You don't need to do a new dub.
Speaker 1: a lot of these We're just like.
Speaker 0: I assume they're paying funimation for that right in some way.
Speaker 0: All right, but yeah, why not?
Speaker 0: Big one project a co I don't think has been available.
Speaker 1: the third anyway I ever ever saw in my entire life in the 90s after vampire hunter d and robot carnival.
Speaker 0: Yep, other than that.
Speaker 0: There's some other ones you could you know that we don't care as much about like symphogear g Devilman.
Speaker 0: lady, I guess that's going to guy right?
Speaker 0: Yeah submarine super 99 Genosyber ninjas sent sent she topic cog, whatever these other shows are.
Speaker 0: There's a case closed in there.
Speaker 0: These are the shows I've seen but I don't really ever need to see again, but they announced 15 things at their special Discotheque only panel.
Speaker 0: so big-time anime releases coming in the u.s.
Speaker 1: Pretty good Tell you know we live in a golden age of access to good animation right now for everything else is going wrong with the world.
Speaker 1: We've got animation but anyway Things of the day.
Speaker 1: What do you got?
Speaker 0: So tying right in to my news, right?
Speaker 0: I mentioned that Discotheque is bringing back the project a co on booray and they bragged during their panel About how well sort of bragging.
Speaker 0: but they're like listen project a co.
Speaker 0: we're bringing this back.
Speaker 0: We can't get the Masters.
Speaker 0: the Masters are lost to space and time not uncommon in old anime.
Speaker 0: How are we gonna release project a co on booray in high quality when the Masters are just not available, right?
Speaker 0: They're gone.
Speaker 0: We just can't get them.
Speaker 0: It's not like what.
Speaker 0: no one will sell them to us.
Speaker 0: It's like no one has them.
Speaker 0: They're just poof, right?
Speaker 0: So what they done is they have this device apparently that I learned about.
Speaker 0: It's like a homebrew device.
Speaker 0: You can buy it or even make one called the domes de duplicator.
Speaker 0: and What the domes de duplicator is?
Speaker 0: it looks like an Arduino with two things stacked on top of it.
Speaker 0: I'm not sure exactly if it is an Arduino or not but what it does is you get a laserdisc player,
Speaker 1: right and
Speaker 0: Then you attach it to the laserdisc player in such a way that you bypass Most of the hardware that is internal to the laserdisc player and you're basically reading the signal from the laser in the laserdisc player like directly and you're recording it out to a real modern computer and Saving that signal in a file.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: It's raw RF Right.
Speaker 0: So you're taking this raw RF signal that and you managed to by not running it through all that other laserdisc hardware and Like into a you know, who knows what kind of device?
Speaker 0: That signal didn't get interfered with in any analog way, right?
Speaker 0: It's like you got the digital readout from a laser and you just record it.
Speaker 0: No analog interference in between right and now that it's in a file on a computer.
Speaker 0: What you do to it is really clever is Rather, it's still an un decoded signal.
Speaker 0: You can't watch it Right.
Speaker 0: What you do is you create a laserdisc player in software.
Speaker 0: you write Software that is a laserdisc player to then translate that that, you know raw read from the laser into Video that can be used and then made a booray out of eventually, right?
Speaker 0: so they can take the project a co laserdisc that they get from somewhere right which I guess they have and Get the best possible reading of that laserdisc.
Speaker 1: Yeah Now this article doesn't use that to make booray doesn't explain this but as best I will assume based on my knowledge of RF.
Speaker 1: What's going on here is the way RF works.
Speaker 1: is it's literally like radio frequency like the same kind of signals You send over the errors in the old days.
Speaker 1: and what it does is it encodes both chroma and luma together into one signal and It's an analog signal.
Speaker 1: Well not like an art like a wav file like it almost looks like a wav file in essence.
Speaker 1: and what you do if you ever heard of a comb filter is you basically use a Fancy version of an equalizer to say this part of the signal is the chroma.
Speaker 1: This part of the signal is the luma and like split them apart.
Speaker 1: But to do that in real time with analog signals using analog equipment.
Speaker 1: these filters are not a hundred percent.
Speaker 1: There's a lot of room for error.
Speaker 1: chroma and luma can kind of bleed into each other And that wasn't a big deal when you're outputting the signal to a TV.
Speaker 0: now I also don't know enough about how laser discs work, right?
Speaker 1: It's just RF like, you know, like RF is RF.
Speaker 0: They just take RF and but it's it's still.
Speaker 0: it's the same as like a CD, right?
Speaker 0: It's still.
Speaker 1: you know That's on the laser disc but the data we get off is effectively a raw RF signal Isn't it?
Speaker 0: It's a laser disc is zeros and ones though, right?
Speaker 1: There's more in there that I'm obviously skipping but what you get the problem is at least I think it is.
Speaker 1: I could be wrong so I Can link to a video that actually explains this.
Speaker 1: that will do it much better than me because my knowledge of this is Weakening because RF is not relevant to the modern world except in cases like.
Speaker 0: what is it?
Speaker 0: This is really cool Right and it you know, let me tie my news and my thing of the day together into one item like that.
Speaker 1: So as a kid, I remember my uncle had a chip that he was trying to like futz with and what the chip would do?
Speaker 1: It was a better comb filter that would better separate luma and chroma.
Speaker 1: So if you plugged like an Atari into it you get a crisper signal But that was a long time.
Speaker 1: point
Speaker 0: is if you've got a laser disc and you want to read that laser disc out And you don't want to use your laser disc player anymore and you want to get the best possible quality You can you can buy or construct this domes de duplicator set it up and it'll be a lot of work But you'll basically get a perfect rip of your laser disc.
Speaker 1: Yep It can't get better quality than the laser disc signal But it can get as good as you could have possibly gotten better than any lasers player ever could have in the wild.
Speaker 1: Yes So my thing of the day I'm not that much of a mountain biker these days.
Speaker 1: Like I tend to go like twice a year at best.
Speaker 1: Now I'm not really doing it at all for obvious reasons.
Speaker 1: But the thing about mountain biking compared to skiing is that I learned to ski From professionals who taught me a lot of techniques jargon words for things theory, etc.
Speaker 1: but I learned mountain biking by being a dumb kid and somehow Surviving just learning it on my own and watching other people and trying to copy them.
Speaker 1: this video which our friend Luke posted in the geek Nice forum recently is a really good mountain biking video because it's not just awesome mountain bikers shredding down a mountain Like a highlights reel.
Speaker 1: it's super long and super slow and it's basically two dudes one of whom's a pro one of whom is not as good Trying a trail over and over again analyzing like what they did and basically explaining the craft and technique of how to approach that trail safely like how to do it like When to hit the apex and all the different kinds of things to do using all the jargon mountain bikers do and I don't see many videos like this for either skiing or mountain biking where Basically pros speak in the language of their craft and address the problem and then attack the problem.
Speaker 1: I know long video like this is just really cool to me because I didn't actually know a lot of this jargon.
Speaker 1: But I think I understand it all because I learned it intuitively and I wonder what people I try to teach skiing think When I use jargon that I assume they understand that they might not necessarily understand.
Speaker 1: It's just.
Speaker 1: I thought this is a really fascinating video and I haven't seen a video like this quite as good and actually Interesting as this partly because yeah the lines they're taking like the trails They're working on are I believe the technical term for this is fucking insane.
Speaker 1: These are not trails I would be comfortable doing in most circumstances.
Speaker 0: Yeah, on the one hand, you know when people just speak in their jargon of the pros, right?
Speaker 0: It's kind of disappointing because it's like damn.
Speaker 0: I can't learn from that right?
Speaker 0: I'm still not a pro yet.
Speaker 0: But on the other hand, I'm always disappointed especially with like sports interviews.
Speaker 0: It's like they'll interview some athlete after a game and they'd be like both teams played hard, right?
Speaker 1: It's like the pucks in to speak.
Speaker 0: It's like.
Speaker 0: but if you go to practice and like we're able to listen to the coach and the players talking to each other It's like just talk like that when someone comes to interview you after the game be like, oh, yeah and that play I didn't do this and that and this other thing and you know, this is why I messed up on the wrong defensive Whatever, you know it's like talk like that and that will even if I don't fully understand it and I can't I'm not able to like learn to Be you from that.
Speaker 0: it is much more interesting to listen to and more entertaining and informative.
Speaker 0: Then the boring, you know Not giving you the information.
Speaker 1: Yeah Kind of talk with this video because it's one person who's way better like sort of guiding someone.
Speaker 1: through this You can start to learn and intuit a lot of that jargon.
Speaker 1: because you watch the pro do and you're like wow That looks really easy.
Speaker 1: Then he explains what he's gonna do.
Speaker 1: then you watch the other guy do it and even the non-expert you're like, wow He didn't do it as well.
Speaker 1: What's different?
Speaker 1: and then the guy starts.
Speaker 0: does he get hurt?
Speaker 1: No, no one really gets hurt.
Speaker 1: This is so.
Speaker 0: if no one gets hurt then I consider that a success.
Speaker 0: Well, that's like who cares.
Speaker 1: Here's the example.
Speaker 1: like skiing is the same way.
Speaker 1: I could get down a double black diamond trail without dying many many many many years ago like I was able to do that like pretty early on because You can take it real slow and careful and boring or like scoop down on your fun.
Speaker 0: That seems like the way you should always be doing it.
Speaker 0: That's boring.
Speaker 1: I only do that when I'm like Luring a trail to figure out if I want to.
Speaker 1: like go hard on it or not.
Speaker 1: Like learn a trail first then go take the lift back up then ski it fast cuz now I know what to expect.
Speaker 0: But how about just don't do that second part?
Speaker 1: That second part is all I'm after.
Speaker 1: That's all I want Right.
Speaker 0: So you did.
Speaker 0: I could do it without dying but doing it with dying.
Speaker 0: That's what I'm after dying part.
Speaker 1: but like you build that flow state you learn those skills and this video just shows like a nice progression of that and It just really makes me want to get outside and go mountain biking skiing again instead of being cooped up.
Speaker 1: Good God in the meta moment.
Speaker 1: the geek nights book club book has been the tale of Hanjo tale of Genji since forever and We're not really first novel in human history ever.
Speaker 1: I'm hoping we just don't have time to read right now Like we're actually really busy.
Speaker 0: I've been I kept.
Speaker 0: I actually have like an urge to read fantasy novel and a little bit But I it's like every time I go to do it.
Speaker 0: I don't yep, and then I'm like I should read the tale of Genji.
Speaker 0: That's what I should be reading.
Speaker 0: I don't.
Speaker 0: I do something else.
Speaker 0: So better to have time.
Speaker 1: maybe in the winter we'll get to it.
Speaker 1: Otherwise, we're gonna be live on Friday coming up real soon at the penny arcade Expo online.
Speaker 1: Well live to tape with our brand new panel.
Speaker 1: Where is the finish line?
Speaker 1: Friday 2 p.m.
Speaker 1: Pacific time in on the PAX 3 channel in the goose theater?
Speaker 1: And I cannot stress this enough.
Speaker 1: We will be in the discord answering questions.
Speaker 1: when in the last 15 years at a goddamn convention Have we taken questions from the crowd?
Speaker 1: at a panel you will not likely get opportunities like this again.
Speaker 0: I Mean you could just ask us questions any old time by any other communication mechanism like a Twitter DM or coming to our discord or?
Speaker 0: Email or our forum or it's like we're available for questions.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we're just not available for questions at our panel.
Speaker 1: I kind of blame right like because I busy.
Speaker 1: we're busy and like I'm dealing with other stuff and we don't always respond to like.
Speaker 1: When people fans interact with us like when a lot of you at me and I don't always respond I'm actually trying to respond.
Speaker 0: more depends what you what you message me with.
Speaker 0: right if you message me with something that's you know Worse a response or you know, it's like yeah that I'm gonna reply.
Speaker 0: if you just send me like, you know.
Speaker 0: Hey check this out.
Speaker 0: Here's a link.
Speaker 0: It's like, alright Okay, you sent me something.
Speaker 0: maybe I'm 90% chance.
Speaker 0: I saw it already.
Speaker 0: Maybe I didn't might be cool But it's like I'm not gonna say anything.
Speaker 0: Let me say thanks.
Speaker 1: But also we're hanging out more and more in the geek nights FRC discord.
Speaker 1: We're also hanging out at other places online.
Speaker 1: We're streaming stuff.
Speaker 0: We're doing things follow us around on the internet and hang out Because we're also going to tomorrow record a panel that will be shown at magwest.
Speaker 0: It'll be a 30-minute panel 25 minutes.
Speaker 0: Oh my god.
Speaker 0: It's a repeat panel of Play dirty to win but it's cut obviously in more than half.
Speaker 0: So you can just watch the old longer version.
Speaker 1: Well, the old log one is gonna be better because the old longer one is like.
Speaker 1: here's the technique to win.
Speaker 1: Here's a lot of explanation in detail.
Speaker 1: This one is gonna be like do a B C and D You will win and we're not gonna give you a lot of the theory.
Speaker 1: and why stuff?
Speaker 0: Yep now a convention we will not be appearing at other than as a virtual attendees is this weekend Saturday and Sunday.
Speaker 0: the game developers of color expo.
Speaker 0: this full schedule went live today and let me tell you That is some kind of schedule.
Speaker 0: Honestly packs online schedule looks like poop compared to that schedule You see has always had a plus panel content.
Speaker 0: Go right now cuz now is the time right?
Speaker 0: I see it right.
Speaker 0: put it on.
Speaker 0: if you don't do it right now write it on your to-do list right now That by Friday go.
Speaker 0: I think you got to buy a ticket or like get it and box Right.
Speaker 0: get the game developer of color expo.
Speaker 0: go through that schedule.
Speaker 0: add that shit to your calendar, right?
Speaker 0: It is gonna be probably the best online convention.
Speaker 0: It is for games in terms of an online gaming convention where you want to see panels Right and learn things.
Speaker 0: This is gonna be like number one, but by far.
Speaker 0: so there you go.
Speaker 1: So get this.
Speaker 1: the ticket is ten bucks by default.
Speaker 1: However, there is a low-income ticket that is five bucks if you are really strapped for cash.
Speaker 0: Yep, they've always had that.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: I guess I never noticed an event.
Speaker 0: Yeah for the in-person events They've always had a you know, sort of.
Speaker 0: I'm poor but I want to go anyway.
Speaker 1: addition Yeah, so this is a fantastic con is definitely worth your while.
Speaker 1: All right, let's get right into it because this movie is fantastic.
Speaker 1: It just came out.
Speaker 1: We just watched it.
Speaker 1: We want to talk about it.
Speaker 0: All right, so quick background background info right.
Speaker 0: so years ago I don't remember what year and I don't care the secret of Kells movie came out and we're like, whoa.
Speaker 0: And then a high quality full-length Animated motion feature that isn't from Japan or Korea or the United States Irish France.
Speaker 0: It's Irish.
Speaker 0: It's like.
Speaker 0: I've never seen an Irish animation before let alone an Irish animation That is a full-length movie of 90 minutes that is looking so damn good, right?
Speaker 0: We watched it.
Speaker 0: We're like, wow, that was terrific.
Speaker 0: It wasn't perfect, but it was amazing Right.
Speaker 0: and then few years go by they come along with some friggin song of the sea and we're like, whoa We didn't think they could do better, but they did.
Speaker 0: somehow they did right.
Speaker 0: Meanwhile while they were working on those two things they did some other stuff, right?
Speaker 0: Those two were directed by Tom Moore, but they had like Nora to me it had all these people.
Speaker 0: They did some puffin rock.
Speaker 0: They did some breadwinner another.
Speaker 0: we did an episode on that.
Speaker 0: I'm pretty sure I think so.
Speaker 0: Right cart cartoon saloon.
Speaker 0: Just cranking out the hits like no misses.
Speaker 0: We're talking like Satoshi.
Speaker 0: come right Satoshi khan level almost just no misses right.
Speaker 0: even Miyazaki has misses, right?
Speaker 0: So years ago right around the time of song of the sea shortly thereafter, right?
Speaker 0: We knew the next one they're working on was wolf walkers and based on the teaser imagery.
Speaker 0: We saw we're like, that's the one.
Speaker 1: Oh, we were we didn't do it.
Speaker 1: We're just like we're gonna see this day one.
Speaker 1: No matter like what?
Speaker 0: We didn't think you could beat song of the sea, but I can tell right now.
Speaker 0: That's the one that's it.
Speaker 0: It's like, you know, they did one two three and the third time is like boom the home run, right?
Speaker 0: Not that the others weren't home runs.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: This was the Grand Slam.
Speaker 1: Haha.
Speaker 0: So we knew that in advance, right?
Speaker 0: So comes along a little while ago, I think we talked about this also on the show.
Speaker 0: Oh Wolf walkers is coming real soon.
Speaker 0: But guess what Apple TV plus exclusive and we're like, no No, I don't want to pay for Apple TV plus.
Speaker 0: It's five bucks a month and you can get a seven day free trial.
Speaker 0: But I don't want to have to do that to watch this thing, right?
Speaker 0: Supposedly Tom Moore told me himself on Twitter.
Speaker 0: You'll be able to just buy it on iTunes.
Speaker 0: So it's because Apple funded the movie, right?
Speaker 0: So, you know, yeah G kids has still licensed to the movie in the US just like, you know, they have for all the past ones.
Speaker 1: Yep, so whatever theaters are existing and safe I'm sure you'll be able to see it as a theater.
Speaker 0: if there is a Theater that is safe to go to that you can go to.
Speaker 0: it may be showing there at some point also.
Speaker 0: Presumably they'll release a bure at some point.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right, but in terms of digital It's gonna be Apple exclusive for most of the world for quite some time though.
Speaker 1: We watch it I don't know.
Speaker 1: I don't know if it's over yet, but we actually watched it.
Speaker 0: You could it is over in a few days.
Speaker 0: I think you've got about four days left.
Speaker 1: Toronto International Film Festival has the premiere of this movie.
Speaker 1: So if you pay for access to it You can just stream this movie directly from the Toronto International Film Festival in really really high quality.
Speaker 0: It's silver lining of a global pandemic As if it's really not even much of a line and considering how horrible pandemic is obviously right but We would not have been able to go to the Toronto International Film Festival had this.
Speaker 0: nothing wrong gone in the world, right?
Speaker 0: However, because it's online you can pay 19 Canadian dollars and you'll be able to watch this movie for a 12-hour window I think from the time you first press play and or if the film festival ends whichever happens first.
Speaker 0: So that is how we saw it and that is how we are reporting to you on what we saw.
Speaker 0: we watched the whole movie.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well, we won't spoil anything at least for a while.
Speaker 1: We'll warn before we start spoiling but This movie is a 100% must-see.
Speaker 1: Like I'm not gonna just go watch it.
Speaker 1: Don't wait for us to tell you to watch this movie.
Speaker 0: We predicted and we were right.
Speaker 1: I mean, I'm so say it's the best movie cartoon saloons ever put out possibly.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's up it's I think it's tied I think maybe with song of the sea.
Speaker 0: a little different anyway It's still for me.
Speaker 0: That's like oh, I'm tied with song of the sea.
Speaker 1: Yeah, though the tricky part is like I have to go watch breadwinner again, cuz that movie is real good - oh, that's so good.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, so just brief plot summary, right?
Speaker 0: You're in Ireland
Speaker 1: Kilkenny specifically
Speaker 0: Yep, the place where cartoon saloon is located in the real world and it's you know The times where the English were coming all up in Ireland's business, right Irish people weren't too happy on that and you know They're trying to you know, build out the area around the town, you know, civilize it and obviously the woods are not too happy about it.
Speaker 0: So you got a little uh, you know a little environmental story, right?
Speaker 0: What was that one?
Speaker 0: What Fern Gully?
Speaker 0: No, a little bit of Fern Gully there is.
Speaker 1: That is technically an apt comparison.
Speaker 0: I'm not gonna lie Not Fern Gully is a piece of shit compared to this movie.
Speaker 0: but the point stand.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there's a little bit of Fern Gully story going on, right?
Speaker 0: But this is sort of a lives in the town.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they can't clear the woods because there's wolves in the woods and they keep biting people and scaring people off, right?
Speaker 0: This girl from England and her dad obviously her mom is who knows where probably dead.
Speaker 0: They are living in this town.
Speaker 0: The dad's job is to hunt the wolves right so that they can clear the woods.
Speaker 0: The girl wants to go on an adventure and haunt wolves with her dad.
Speaker 0: The dad is like no you're gonna get eaten by a wolf.
Speaker 0: It's probably not a good idea.
Speaker 0: You're really tiny right and the girl meets You know the wolf walker the magic people in the woods Right and things progress from there as you would imagine in a children's movie.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: It is beautiful It is the music is good.
Speaker 1: The story is good.
Speaker 1: It's pretty.
Speaker 1: It's actually kind of like.
Speaker 1: the situation is more complex than Scott described because remember this was during Like the Oliver Cromwell area and if you know anything about how that government interacted with the island of Ireland Then you can see why the Lord Protector is the villain of this movie.
Speaker 1: But there's an interesting dynamic.
Speaker 1: on one hand the two made deal.
Speaker 1: the father and the daughter who have moved to Ireland.
Speaker 1: They're English the English are colonizers and subjugators of Ireland but simultaneously the townspeople are also themselves sort of colonizers and Quote, you know, I'm using this as a pejorative word in this case.
Speaker 1: I would be very clear civilizers of the previously existing populations and There's a dynamic of townspeople are sort of against the previous people the wolves but also against the English.
Speaker 1: the English are like everybody's against everybody and It's sort of a complex situation.
Speaker 1: and even still the father and the daughter have clearly come to Ireland to start a new life or to escape something like they are.
Speaker 1: they're not necessarily by choice But that's the life they have.
Speaker 1: like they got their hustle.
Speaker 1: They got.
Speaker 0: the girl is obviously happier in England.
Speaker 0: Yeah, she's not happy about coming here, right?
Speaker 0: So she's also You know, the dad was coming, you know for his own reasons, right but you know The girl is trying to you know, find a way to you know, either get back to England But she doesn't try it at that.
Speaker 0: But to you know find a new life for herself and in you know, find a way to enjoy, you know Her situation right instead of you know getting stuck.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know happy but simultaneously she wants to be like her dad.
Speaker 1: So she wants to be a wolf hunter just like her dad and she goes out into the woods Like hunt the wolves and kill the wolves and oh she meets a wolf and turns out the wolves are pretty cool.
Speaker 1: And there we go.
Speaker 1: Here's a movie Yep.
Speaker 0: So this movie does have the common kids movie trope of the adult that won't listen to the kid, right?
Speaker 0: Which is understandable because she's trying to tell her dad that like fairy tales are real and he's like, yeah, whatever It's like I got this is serious.
Speaker 0: You're gonna get bitten.
Speaker 0: No, don't go out in the woods But it's one of those ones where it's like.
Speaker 0: yeah, if you had just listened to me right this would have been all sort.
Speaker 0: It's.
Speaker 0: that's a little bit frustrating right because as a movie watcher It's like it's weird.
Speaker 0: and now on the one hand you're like just listen to the kid Ah, but on the other hand, you're like, wait a minute If if the kid was coming up and telling me that I'd be like, uh-huh.
Speaker 0: Yeah Yeah, because obviously in the real world fairy tales aren't real but I know they're real only because I'm watching a movie.
Speaker 1: Yep, but what I will say cuz we.
Speaker 1: I want to talk about the movie in depth which requires spoilers and I cannot stress enough.
Speaker 1: just go see this movie, but the movie has a very satisfying arc and it moves pretty quick like it it doesn't that is.
Speaker 0: one thing I've Noticed between this one and their previous ones is that I felt like you know Not that the pacing in Secret of Kells or Song of the Sea was bad or wrong in any way necessarily But it was definitely Sort of a little slower had a little bit more breathing room in there during certain parts of the the narrative Whereas wolf walkers, I don't think has any breathing room.
Speaker 0: It's like they it's not.
Speaker 0: it's only 90 minutes, which is normal movie length Right, but these days a lot of movies are going two hours, but in those 90 minutes, they pack it in tight But it doesn't feel rushed at any point, right?
Speaker 0: It's like they figured out the exact saturation point of you know, how much they could cram into every you know second of animation.
Speaker 0: and they're like, okay, that's how much we're gonna do.
Speaker 0: and they just did it at that pace throughout the Whole thing and it just keeps moving.
Speaker 1: Yeah And then it's over it moves past Where a movie that followed the troops of this kind of story likely would.
Speaker 1: that's one thing I will say.
Speaker 0: It's like you would think the climax and the ending will be at this point in the story.
Speaker 0: It's like nope It's actually further down the road right because they're moving.
Speaker 0: at a nice clip they get further.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think if they had you know, it was I wonder is it like, you know Cuz Apple paid for this right and clearly it wouldn't have happened had they or not anyone else done it, right?
Speaker 0: Netflix could have paid for it, right?
Speaker 0: But if no one paid it wasn't happening, right?
Speaker 0: They needed.
Speaker 1: I mean it was very hard to get secretive Kells made.
Speaker 1: part of the reason why secretive Kells Obvious kind of just Peters out at the end was the difficulty in funding that movie.
Speaker 0: Yep, so I mean, you know secretive Kells and song of the sea basically on that reputation from those is what you know Convinced someone like an apple to pay for this and more
Speaker 1: importantly to let Tom Moore and cartoon saloon Do what they will with the movie like
Speaker 0: yep be
Speaker 1: a little bit.
Speaker 0: I wonder Yes, I wonder if there had been less budget constraints Like let's say they just had more money right would they?
Speaker 0: and they didn't have to care, you know.
Speaker 0: Would they have preferred it to be two hours and spread it out a little more?
Speaker 0: But I think actually maybe this is one of those cases where they were actually helped by with by the constraints on their creativity Right.
Speaker 0: I think the 90 minutes worked.
Speaker 0: Well, it's actually.
Speaker 1: it's actually a hundred minutes.
Speaker 0: Oh Ten more minute ten more minute.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: so one other thing I'll say before we get into spoiler territory is that the animation is Utterly beautiful, but also there's definitely a form as function Situation in this movie where the way it's animated and we went to.
Speaker 1: we also attended the NS the NSC film festival online Where we got to see a an explanation of this which is the reason we know this.
Speaker 0: they told it to us.
Speaker 1: But it's apparent when you watch it to town scenes and forest scenes are animated in fairly radically different styles and both are animated in the way you might Expect cartoon saloon movies in this sort of triptych or trilogy to be animated.
Speaker 1: that combined Visual storytelling is huge.
Speaker 1: in this movie.
Speaker 1: A lot of things are not said out loud.
Speaker 1: you figure them out because you see it Or just feel it.
Speaker 0: you can't even if you don't can't Directly pick it out.
Speaker 0: It's like if someone says it you'd be like, oh, that's obvious, right?
Speaker 0: So for example when you're in town or town characters, right are drawn with straighter lines, right?
Speaker 0: The Lord Protector is like a box.
Speaker 0: Yeah, pretty much right.
Speaker 0: and the Lines around the characters and around the things in town or the town objects, right?
Speaker 0: So a wagon or you know a crossbow right are thick solid You know clear lines and the the colors are contained within the lines, right?
Speaker 0: So everything townie is very rigid and straight and the color palette for everything in town is very cold gray Right blue, you know.
Speaker 1: There's also a lot of boxes like characters are often shown like especially the the main girl Behind windows behind bars Surrounded and boxed in by things and that even like later in the movie when some soldiers leave the town.
Speaker 1: It was a very interesting stylistic choice because when they go out into the woods to do a thing They put on helmets that basically put a grid over their own faces as they go out into the woods.
Speaker 0: They make a lot of good use in the movie of the portcullis in the town.
Speaker 0: I love a good portcullis, right?
Speaker 0: There's a great scene where there's actually a few scenes where they show the portcullis.
Speaker 0: from a direct side view I like cross-section and this character is on the left on the town side and characters on the right on the outside the town side.
Speaker 0: And so the contrast is like split right down the middle of the frame precisely There was.
Speaker 0: so is that obviously out in the woods the colors are completely different palette green brown red.
Speaker 1: very You know warm lines are a little soft like characters.
Speaker 0: hair is Yep, all the lot.
Speaker 0: the coloring in the lot doesn't stay in the lines.
Speaker 0: Like the color will sort of go outside the lines a bit.
Speaker 0: The lines will be thinner and sketch here more like with a pencil then with a pen.
Speaker 0: Everything is hella curvy and round.
Speaker 0: Everything is round outside the town right curves and roundness No, straight lines anywhere.
Speaker 0: the trees and everything are really hyper exaggerated, right?
Speaker 0: Like they've not realistic but good enough, right?
Speaker 0: Until you know It's a tree and you can you just get a completely different feeling in in both places and you can see in the main character.
Speaker 0: Right is like as she becomes, you know less townie.
Speaker 0: You'll see like they draw her right.
Speaker 0: It's like oh her colors are coming outside her lines Right as she's a little bit less townie and you'll see that transition happens visually as well as narratively
Speaker 1: And I Think we want to spoil some things beyond this point because I actually want to talk about specific moments and scenes in the movie.
Speaker 0: It's a kid's movie.
Speaker 0: It's hard to talk about too much without spoiling.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but I cannot stress again Don't wait for Oz like just go see this movie go into it without knowing anything more about it.
Speaker 1: that we've already said.
Speaker 0: I'm Expecting you to be listening to this not because you need someone to tell you whether it's good or not before you see it But because you've already seen it and you just want to vicariously hear people talk about it and go yeah Yeah, that's the purpose of this podcast, right?
Speaker 0: So if you have if you're at if you're hearing my voice now and you haven't seen the movie what's wrong with you?
Speaker 1: So spoilers.
Speaker 1: the one thing that I was actually surprised by was that both parents survived.
Speaker 1: I was so ready for at least one if not both of them to not make it and the movie Oh, yeah, really really set me up for that.
Speaker 0: I The mom and then it's like, you know, and they really dragged that mom survives question out quite a bit, right?
Speaker 0: And then the dad one I was like, whoa.
Speaker 0: Oh, you go.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: It's like wow.
Speaker 0: I didn't see her.
Speaker 1: I was like a hundred percent sure he was going down and especially because very early in the movie you have that scene where you know, he's setting the traps and Like the girl almost steps in the track check out check offs bear trap.
Speaker 1: Oh my god, but after you see those traps Throughout the entire film the camera will cut two shots of people's feet walking and running briefly and Every time I almost winced like is this gonna be Chekhov's trap?
Speaker 1: I was actually pretty sure that either the mom the dad or Oliver Cromwell We're gonna die in a trap or that one of the two girls was gonna get caught in a trap And that was gonna be a plot point.
Speaker 1: I'm kind of glad that didn't happen, but that actually really ratcheted up the tension on certain scenes.
Speaker 1: But at the same time the movie did.
Speaker 1: it wasn't just like a false Chekhov's gun because there are scenes where Robin is running through the woods and the wolf girl she's like Knows about the traps clearly and the traps are like not a problem for her But she like.
Speaker 0: traps are.
Speaker 0: the traps are a plot point But no one ever you you I expected someone to get snared in one It'd be a big deal and that never happened.
Speaker 0: people
Speaker 1: get snared in a less horrific trap than the bear trap But there's a like the girl at one point just throws like casually Trek Trips the trap right in front of Robin while she's blindfolded So she doesn't step into it which I think was a very subtle way to show How in tune with the forest the wolves are and how they like.
Speaker 1: the traps are not actually a threat to them They're not but they're more dangerous to the humans who were laying them than they are to these Characters.
Speaker 1: in the context of this film which sets up the power of the wolves and the wolf walkers later on Like that's the subtle storytelling.
Speaker 0: Right, usually it's situated, you know Like a fern gully.
Speaker 0: right.
Speaker 0: the situation when you is that the humans are so impossibly strong with their guns and their fire Right that the woods doesn't stand a chance and the woods has to like rally or you know level up somehow to You know do something or even get away, right?
Speaker 0: Whereas here it's like the wolves are clearly a plus number one.
Speaker 0: The humans have nothing on them even with their guns and there's also many scenes where they're trying to shoot wolves and they can't hit.
Speaker 0: Shit for shit like stormtroopers.
Speaker 0: They're like pew pew pew pew pew with our shitty muskets and they can't.
Speaker 0: they can't hit anything.
Speaker 0: pistol No can't hit.
Speaker 0: It's like the wolves.
Speaker 0: just own the humans.
Speaker 0: They're just better in every way from the start and they know it.
Speaker 1: Right, well because the movie definitely has a very clear point of view like a lot of movies with this kind of story would try To make a point of oh, there has to be understanding and like the city and the town coexist.
Speaker 0: Whatever the movie definitely is saying the forest life is superior full stop Yep, and also that you know the wolves interestingly enough.
Speaker 0: They don't want usually this kind of story.
Speaker 0: It's like the wolves want to stop the humans from chopping down the forest, right?
Speaker 0: It's like no actually what's happened here is all the other wolves have left, right?
Speaker 0: It's like okay humans You can have this one.
Speaker 0: We'll go to a different one, right?
Speaker 0: We're gonna leave But because of the situation right with the mom This one pack is still there and as soon as they rescue the mom and resolve everything then they leave.
Speaker 1: that leads to another like big surprise that I thought was wonderful and A minor spoiler for inglorious bastards if you didn't see it because it's a similar type of situation weirdly enough.
Speaker 1: But the movie actually just has a straight-up happy ending like everyone makes it But the fact that they kill Oliver Cromwell that does not obviously happen in the real world.
Speaker 0: Oliver Oliver Cromwell, I mean he is cast as Simon McBurney as Lord Protector Oliver Cromwell.
Speaker 0: Oh, did because they never say Oliver Cromwell out loud in the movie, but you say it's in the credits.
Speaker 0: You saw it.
Speaker 1: It's it.
Speaker 1: the Wikipedia lists the credit as Simon McDurnie.
Speaker 1: Okay, Lord Protector Oliver Cromwell.
Speaker 0: Okay, because it's like if you know anything about Oliver Cromwell you 100% know that's all.
Speaker 1: yeah genocide and subjugation of Ireland the puritanical nonsense like the English as colonizers and oppressors.
Speaker 0: But if you're a if you're a kid, they don't say the words Oliver Cromwell in the dialogue even one time.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So it's sort of like that thing where adults or really smart kids who know history or maybe Irish kids who have learned this probably I imagine better than any other kids, right?
Speaker 0: They would know right?
Speaker 0: What's the the extra layer, right?
Speaker 1: That's going on there, but there's like Yeah, there's the moment where he dies though and when I get back to that because that involves another thing That's how Oliver Cromwell really died.
Speaker 1: Yeah, Oliver Cromwell was not bitten by a wolf and dropped into a pit of spikes.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but that's this movie the whole time.
Speaker 1: if you know history like you're thinking about like the English prevail in many ways in the real world and continue to commit their atrocities and like the history of Ireland is something you should learn about if you don't know about it, but in Inglorious Basterds the whole movie is all these people are trying to kill Hitler and you watching the movie think But I know Hitler like doesn't get assassinated.
Speaker 1: How is this like?
Speaker 1: how does it?
Speaker 1: where does this movie go wrong?
Speaker 1: and the end of Inglorious Basterds is no this is an alternate Timeline.
Speaker 1: they fucking killed Hitler.
Speaker 1: everybody succeeded This movie.
Speaker 1: similarly the happy ending just the for the family Leaving on their own off into the woods clearly happy clearly free.
Speaker 1: They've escaped the English.
Speaker 1: like it's an Abjectly 100% happy ending.
Speaker 1: escaping the city was the right choice for everyone.
Speaker 1: It's very refreshing to see a movie that has such a strong Note to end on like that just the scene where the four of them are in the cart.
Speaker 1: The dad is clearly.
Speaker 1: I Think it's heavily implied that him and The other mom have now formed a relationship of some kind the way they are interacting.
Speaker 0: The two girls and also the two the two daughters are clearly, you know, they're.
Speaker 0: it's like it, you know.
Speaker 0: on the one hand You usually when a movie like avoids being explicitly gay.
Speaker 0: when it's trying to be gay You usually want to call them out for not being you know explicit and trying to sort of.
Speaker 0: you know Work both sides right like that, but you know, these characters are too young.
Speaker 0: So I think that's kind of okay.
Speaker 1: it was both a coming-of-age story an escape from oppression story and a Coming-out story or an awakening story for these characters especially when you watch Robin and her progression and her like getting curious and Interacting with the wolf girl and changing herself as she realizes things about herself.
Speaker 1: Which gets into the third thing I love about this movie.
Speaker 1: when a character gets some magic.
Speaker 1: They just use it There's like well, I'm magic now.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna magic.
Speaker 1: I Hate it.
Speaker 0: There's no characters get magic and don't use it intelligently in any media Or don't use it to the fullest extent of its power.
Speaker 0: Yep The only way the only way in which there is any holding back on power in this movie is I think obviously because it's a children's Movie.
Speaker 0: the wolves in the action scenes, which are really well animated Did not at any point just like mall someone right.
Speaker 0: so it's like there were some times where like, you know It's like if it wasn't a kids movie that wolf could have just like tore open that dude's neck with his teeth And that would have been it right.
Speaker 0: and they they don't do that, but they do everything else, right?
Speaker 0: So And I just chalked that up to not wanting to show someone's intestines getting Don't show goring and mauling of people in a children's movie, but the movie Appropriate.
Speaker 1: it set up the rules of magic Partly by explanation but mostly by again visual storytelling.
Speaker 1: the bite marks.
Speaker 1: check out his bite mark on the dad.
Speaker 0: They just you just what they no point.
Speaker 0: was there a scene where someone explains what wolf walking does, right?
Speaker 0: I guess there was.
Speaker 1: it's like there's a little bit of like when we're asleep.
Speaker 0: It's a very short one.
Speaker 0: Actually.
Speaker 0: Yeah, she's like.
Speaker 0: She's like yeah when I go to sleep I'm a wolf and then I wake up in the morning and that's it.
Speaker 0: That's like all.
Speaker 1: that's all the explanation you get and like oh don't bite people or they'll turn into a wolf walker But the fact that biting someone turns them into a wolf walker is used twice.
Speaker 1: the mom like the dad gets bitten Possibly on purpose like that.
Speaker 1: That's just that's part of the movie.
Speaker 1: Yeah And I love that cuz that sets up the scene at the end with the Lord Protector where he is bitten.
Speaker 1: the magic is there.
Speaker 1: It is very clear that the healing magic could have saved him.
Speaker 1: He would have become a wolf walker and he explicitly chooses death rather than becoming like the wolf walkers.
Speaker 1: Fuck him.
Speaker 0: Yeah, he's a bad guy, but I like that.
Speaker 1: he chose his own death.
Speaker 1: I think they would have saved him.
Speaker 1: He chose this which very much sets up the One-note portrayal of that character and I think the one note of him really fits what this movie is.
Speaker 1: My only complaint about him like if I have any critique of this movie, there is one thing that happened a few too many times.
Speaker 1: Cromwell would tell the dead to do something.
Speaker 1: the dad wouldn't do it.
Speaker 1: Cromwell would then say well you fucked up.
Speaker 1: now If you fuck up one more time You're fucked.
Speaker 1: and then there really wouldn't be that many consequences for him.
Speaker 1: and that just kept happening over and over.
Speaker 0: eventually like he eventually made him like a foot soldier instead of a hunter and then He was still right there like doing the hunting job in the foot soldier costume, basically like that dialogue of.
Speaker 1: Here are consequences and then they're not really followed up on directly.
Speaker 1: happened a few too many times.
Speaker 0: I feel like this is I think once or twice extra.
Speaker 0: I agree.
Speaker 0: Yeah So the movie does have but I think because it's so speedy and jam-packed There wasn't a lot of time.
Speaker 0: screen time for side characters, right?
Speaker 1: Like a really good character the guy in the see look at something like an Aladdin Right.
Speaker 0: an Aladdin gives quite a bit of time to like, you know, Iago the bird right or a poo the monkey Right or whatever, right?
Speaker 0: This doesn't give so much time to anyone other than the four main character, you know Even the mom right the mom the dad the two girls and Cromwell.
Speaker 0: pretty much no one else is on.
Speaker 0: I mean really me.
Speaker 1: all the wolves together are almost like one character.
Speaker 1: all the non wolf walker wolves.
Speaker 0: They're just like this spin on speed.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they're just a fluid mass of undifferentiated wolves I like.
Speaker 0: the only other characters are like the the scullery maid who talks for like a minute maybe not even right and Fair child work his prayer.
Speaker 0: the old man in the stocks is like the best.
Speaker 0: He's awesome.
Speaker 0: Well, cuz he's interesting also doesn't have a lot of time.
Speaker 1: he like this.
Speaker 1: is this again the movie really subtly addresses like the cycles of Subjugation and oppression colonizer and colonized in that he like that.
Speaker 1: he almost represents the villagers.
Speaker 1: They fear the wolves and want to like tear use the forest to enrich themselves and better their lives.
Speaker 1: So they're at odds with the wolves But at the same time they are also at odds with the English.
Speaker 1: but the English are at odds with the wolves and the English like so they're sort of dependent upon each other in this triangle of Dependency and animosity and subjugation and oppression.
Speaker 1: You don't see something that nuanced in a movie like this that often usually it's all the good guys Here are the bad guys, but also visually speaking right the old man in the stocks, right?
Speaker 0: He's on the one hand a villager.
Speaker 0: He's drawn with the solid lines that are colored in right on the inside, but his character design is very round.
Speaker 0: He's got a round jolly kind of Santa Claus ish kind of look and feel to him, right?
Speaker 1: You know even in the stocks, he's like Like oh the wolves are scary, but then he's like yeah, but a wolf saved me.
Speaker 1: so Maybe they're alright.
Speaker 1: and then where the wolves come to fuck up the English.
Speaker 1: He's like fucking go wolves get him get him.
Speaker 0: Yeah, exactly.
Speaker 0: So it's like because he has that wolf woods alliance that he's drawn with a rounder shape to him.
Speaker 0: but yeah, there's also a couple other good like Fun animation bits going on.
Speaker 0: there's like a funny donkey right the bird.
Speaker 0: the bird is awesome.
Speaker 1: the sheep The chaos of sheep was one of my favorite animated scenes other than running.
Speaker 0: chaos of sheep was good.
Speaker 0: Also the wolves.
Speaker 0: sometimes the wolves are in a swarmy pack similar to what Miyazaki like Beautiful like if you look at in Nausicaa and Princess Mononoke are the two biggest examples.
Speaker 0: But Miyazaki does this a lot where they'll be like a swarm or a blob of something Spirited away when the sprites are all in a big blob, right.
Speaker 0: or you know The the water is crashing around in the inn and stuff like that, right?
Speaker 0: It's like he does that kind of thing.
Speaker 0: The wolves will sometimes do that blob movement where the pack is just in a blob, right?
Speaker 0: But then sometimes they'll all like line up rigidly in a grid, right?
Speaker 1: Healing magic tapestry or illumination where they're two-dimensional like they form like almost a painting Yeah, or a scene you'd watch the movie to see.
Speaker 1: it's really hard to explain this without some visual aid But the move cartoon saloon in general with these three movies has used perspective a to great effect.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm That's the one.
Speaker 0: last thing is the.
Speaker 0: there are a lot of common Visual tropes they use between all three movies.
Speaker 0: The one that I stands out the most to me is that when they're showing the town like from far away like zoomed out It the town is drawn almost Cartographically, right and you'll see this in Secret of Kells.
Speaker 0: It's.
Speaker 0: the town is drawn like it's on a map, right and you'll even see scenes like a little character is walking onto the map Right and then it'll zoom into the town in store Song of the sea right?
Speaker 0: You'll like.
Speaker 0: they'll show the island as like two-dimensional from far away, right?
Speaker 0: It's like a little house on top of a rock, right?
Speaker 0: And here when the town is shown from far away It's like a rectangle right well of walls filled with little tiny houses right and like, you know a game.
Speaker 0: And then only when they zoom in further do they get away from that sort of Style.
Speaker 0: so it's like there's a lot of like common Things between all three movies, but that's that's like the most visible one, right?
Speaker 0: It's like oh when they show the town and zoom out they draw it like it's a map.
Speaker 1: Now and I know even as I a little while ago said to the effect of you know critiquing the The circular discussion between the punishment of the dad from Cromwell and how he's still there almost went on too many times.
Speaker 1: at the same time The dad was dependent upon the Lord Protector for his livelihood.
Speaker 1: Like he didn't have all that he even if he had other options He did not realize it and he may not have even from the beginning is clearly not liking the Lord Protector.
Speaker 0: He's just sort of resigned to the fact that he has to do this.
Speaker 1: he has no choice and the right this to survive almost turns into a Will.
Speaker 1: you follow me this far.
Speaker 1: is how about this far?
Speaker 1: How about this far?
Speaker 1: and he keeps every step he takes?
Speaker 1: he has to be more like the suppressor to be in his good graces for his own livelihood.
Speaker 1: and You see his struggle to break out of that cycle because attempting to break out of that cycle might just mean him and his daughter Die
Speaker 0: Yep, so he finally does break out right and it's the scene where he does break out is great because he's like he's doing all This stuff right trying to just you know caring about his livelihood even though he doesn't like what he has to do.
Speaker 0: Right because he wants to protect his daughter.
Speaker 0: right and then right He's like he's are.
Speaker 0: he's finally actually arguing with with his daughter a little bit and not just ignoring her and saying shut up Right.
Speaker 0: and he's like, you know I don't want you to end up in a cage.
Speaker 0: and the movie has had so much cage imagery in it.
Speaker 0: the port Cullises the gates on the faces of the soldiers the mom wolf in a cage It's just in cages.
Speaker 0: all over this movie right in the house is a cage.
Speaker 1: the windows everything That seems like a bolt of lightning in the movie, right?
Speaker 0: And then she's like, well, I already am in a cage, right?
Speaker 0: She's like I'm imprisoned in this house in this town with walls.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right It's like, you know the whole start the big very beginning of the movie is I want to get out of the house I want to leave town and I'm not allowed to write and immediately leaves town.
Speaker 0: And that's when the dad realizes I think like oops
Speaker 1: but also the dad when the dad becomes a wolf to Like because he gives his daughter when she says that like she is a wolf and she is basically decided I am going to live with the wolves regardless of what you do like.
Speaker 1: she has made her choice.
Speaker 0: We done see you town sucks.
Speaker 0: And oh and there's those those kids in town the bullies who have a cage.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they're toy that they they bring with them everywhere.
Speaker 0: right the town bully kids.
Speaker 1: Yep Which the allegory of the scene where she is Robin is trying to protect the wolf girl Just like her dad is trying trying to protect her and she basically tricks those kids into locking the wolf girl up in a cage During a pivotal scene.
Speaker 1: and then yeah that's sort of where
Speaker 0: she on
Speaker 1: one hand understands why her dad is coming from and also understands what the right thing to do like that scene is like her character transformation and then her saying I was already in a cage is Her like revealing of that and like the final decision.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's that's the climax of the movie.
Speaker 0: And right after that is pretty much just resolution.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right Of okay, everyone's on this these sides now everyone's figured out their shit, but now we're gonna kill the big bag.
Speaker 1: I also I like how the like it when she turns into a wolf like that.
Speaker 1: Magic is also very like.
Speaker 1: the rules of magic are very well Like she becomes a wolf literally and the consequences of her literally being a wolf are immediate and direct.
Speaker 1: Oh They also do this like the dad goes upstairs and there's a wolf Like what the fuck.
Speaker 0: My favorite episode of Samurai Jack is the one where there's the three art is there's no void.
Speaker 0: There's no dialogue.
Speaker 0: There's the three archers on the tower and Samurai Jack is trying to get up there to go to the.
Speaker 0: well Yeah, I was thinking that the whole time Samurai Jack can't beat the the archers, right?
Speaker 0: They're too dangerous.
Speaker 0: So he ends up like training and closing his eyes and learning to hear the arrows instead of seeing them Which makes no sense because the speed of light is faster than the speed of sound.
Speaker 0: but ignore that.
Speaker 0: Yeah But like In that Samurai Jack episode they do this thing where the screen is black, right?
Speaker 0: suggesting to you that set that Jack has his eyes closed and then they begin drawing single objects and playing that.
Speaker 0: the sounds that go With those objects to illustrate how Jack is has his can't see.
Speaker 0: he's intentionally blindfolded himself But he can see the world through hearing right as these objects appear Drawn at a different art style and this movie does the same thing.
Speaker 0: is like you're a wolf now and they draw everything To suggest to you.
Speaker 0: This is how the wolf sees the world.
Speaker 0: Smells are now drawn.
Speaker 0: It's like they draw the smells.
Speaker 1: that is such a beautiful scene.
Speaker 0: any Vibrations that go through the floor.
Speaker 0: they draw them right to illustrate and get across the point that yeah The wolf has these enhanced senses and sees the world this way and the human sees the world this way, right?
Speaker 1: Which you then is used to great effect both for that amazing running with a wolf scene where the like Robin Embraces being a wolf like like that's it.
Speaker 1: She's a wolf now.
Speaker 1: Well simultaneously when the dad becomes a wolf and he starts to experience these things but without any help or friendship or context Like he doesn't understand what's happening at first.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: He's just suddenly a wolf like oops not But it was set up.
Speaker 1: we the viewer Understand it because of how Robin experienced it and it's also it's portrayed so well like our words cannot do it justice.
Speaker 1: You just have to see it All right.
Speaker 0: So this review is probably you could have watched most of the movie by now, right?
Speaker 0: Hopefully you have seen it already And it wasn't just spoiled for you horribly.
Speaker 0: not that I care about spoilers, but other people do so, you know I have to go eat food now.
Speaker 1: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Speaker 0: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 1: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 0: But unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night And the patreon patrons for this episode of geek nights are allot joyce.
Speaker 1: Heidi McNichol Marty green You're just like a dude guy char tovish and Graham Finch.
Speaker 1: You hold the key to my heart.
Speaker 1: There was a dude looked like a cop standing there with my name out Clinton Walton Jay Vance run from New Zealand Ryan Perrin Nicholas Brando Chris midkiff dread Lily Tenebrae Chris Reimer Finn Shervin Von Harl and a bunch of people who do not want me to say their names and now We're using a weird pipelines until Scott gets this new audio device curtains and panels tonight And a lot in the hopper that we can't really talk about yet.
Speaker 1: Some of its a little weird, but some of it's pretty fun.
Speaker 1: But anyway now I leave you with.
Speaker 1: So I was to spend with you.
Speaker 1: so go and part of your cute little pussycat knows.
Speaker 1: Pussycat pussycat.
Speaker 0: I love you.
Speaker 0: Yes You any pussycat knows What's new?
Speaker 1: Pussycat pussycat so thrilling and so willing to care for you.
Speaker 0: But you got eyes pussycat pussycat.
Speaker 0: I love you.