Speaker 0: It's Wednesday March 31st 2021.
Speaker 0: I'm rim I'm Scott and this is geek nights.
Speaker 0: tonight We're reviewing a classic cartoon called the Simpsons.
Speaker 0: Let's do this Up, so uh I'm gonna get my vaccine finally on Saturday.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean we became eligible.
Speaker 1: They told us in advance we'd be eligible on Tuesday.
Speaker 1: start right so we couldn't make appointments till Tuesday.
Speaker 0: If I can make an appointment like Monday night of course I couldn't.
Speaker 0: and then okay at 759 59 on Tuesday every site that I was using at least updated and immediately started working.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean on the one hand as expected there weren't any appointments available.
Speaker 0: really unless you went far away right from where we are I did end up deciding to go to Staten Island So I didn't know.
Speaker 1: good luck with that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I decided to just be patient.
Speaker 1: I'm just like oh, I'll just wait until you know why I'm not gonna sit here reloading all day wasting my time.
Speaker 1: I only got one life to live.
Speaker 1: I'll just wait until I can get one easily with just like a click.
Speaker 1: You know there's just plenty.
Speaker 1: yeah pick one.
Speaker 1: I'll wait until that time.
Speaker 1: you know that time would come right.
Speaker 1: so I was only checking like you know once twice a day like wake up check it right go to check it Go to bed right see if they're just in case.
Speaker 1: you know most of the day You know I looked at I think once in the middle of the day, and it was like nope nothing no Early
Speaker 0: on I checked a lot But it was clear that it wasn't gonna happen like one would appear and it like wasn't worth it.
Speaker 0: So I basically what I just.
Speaker 1: I do want to congratulate Whoever's running a lot of these sites such as turbo vax the official, New York City site all these sites.
Speaker 1: There were some problems.
Speaker 1: for example at one point the official, New York City dot-gov site Said like city field available you click on it you fill out the form and then when you finish the form It's like actually just kidding low.
Speaker 0: Yeah So I did learn something about that.
Speaker 0: the reason that was happening is that if a lot of people once you fill out That form once if you change like if you go back or click on a different link from turbo vax It makes you fill the form out again and again.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well you can.
Speaker 1: I think on.
Speaker 1: the people are saying this tricks to Real simple.
Speaker 0: if you just stay on the page and just change the date or the zip code.
Speaker 0: It'll just immediately refresh and keep everything regardless.
Speaker 1: the point is is that there.
Speaker 1: I want to say of course There's no appointments right.
Speaker 1: There's just supply and demand.
Speaker 0: well Comment a Millions and millions of quote very online people.
Speaker 0: suddenly we're trying to get access right.
Speaker 1: But all of these websites that I tried the various ones that were out there They were all fast and up right.
Speaker 1: so take a lesson people such as Blizzard right Going down when you get when you get crushed inventions where the artist alley application crashes slack slack on January 4th right.
Speaker 1: take notice.
Speaker 1: You know something.
Speaker 0: Wedges went on sale and literally every adult in New York City was trying to get them at the same time.
Speaker 1: Right exactly.
Speaker 1: so good job keeping the the site up even though of course the inventory was down, right?
Speaker 0: It's like they're like people are.
Speaker 0: if you're if you're patient and persistent you're gonna get one soon.
Speaker 1: It looks like yeah, so what happened to me was you know my doctor long ago, right is you know it's NYU doctor, right?
Speaker 1: They have all kinds of apps and stuff.
Speaker 1: They're very you know modern right and they they just send a message to all the patients.
Speaker 1: And it was just like hey stop calling us right we got shit to do.
Speaker 1: You're not getting.
Speaker 1: we'll let you know right where you know.
Speaker 1: they talked about all the stuff.
Speaker 1: They're doing.
Speaker 1: I know you'll know Right.
Speaker 1: they were testing the vaccines themselves to see which ones they liked better and doing all kinds of all kinds of stuff.
Speaker 1: They're like.
Speaker 1: we'll text you.
Speaker 1: so of course Tuesday like the middle of the day.
Speaker 1: I actually they texted me.
Speaker 1: They're like you're eligible now, right?
Speaker 1: I didn't ask them any.
Speaker 1: I never communicated with them.
Speaker 1: once I'm just in the system as a patient and they said here's the link and it was a link to go to in my doctor's Official app.
Speaker 1: right they had a whole section for make an appointment, and they they're like here's all our locations.
Speaker 1: Right you know choose the ones you're willing to go to.
Speaker 1: so I clicked all and then I click the Long Island ones to deselect them.
Speaker 1: continue Right Yeah, and Tuesday there were appointments on Long Island you know and then by the end of Tuesday there weren't any left.
Speaker 1: some people took All those.
Speaker 1: so I was just like okay, cuz I only checked it twice this morning.
Speaker 1: You know I finished my little inside bike of the morning right my pretend commute To my my work which I can see from the bike two feet away And I just go over to my computer before I take a shower, and I just press ctrl R one time.
Speaker 1: Just one time ctrl R for a reload on my doctor's page And I see a bunch of green boxes, and it's not only is it not Long Island it's the doctor's office that I go to.
Speaker 1: and Just like a full set of times for all pretty much all day Saturday pick any time you want.
Speaker 1: so I just click 10 a.m.
Speaker 1: And I clicked ok and they're like ok you have appointment 10 a.m.
Speaker 1: And then it texted me later in the day like you're coming at Saturday at 10 a.m.. Right.
Speaker 1: I'm like all right And I just patiently waited.
Speaker 1: I didn't waste my time reloading all day or anything like that and so I'm gonna go on Saturday.
Speaker 0: It's exciting that it's all working and we're getting shots and arms pretty quick which leads us You know it's a Wednesday animation day to a very relevant news that bridges what we just talked about and what?
Speaker 0: So there is an anime convention.
Speaker 0: a Couple days ago and all he said was something like you're gonna be mad, and I was like.
Speaker 1: I told Telling Amanda this and I was like there's an anime conventions gonna happen, and she's like oh no But I'm like it's worse than that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so It's oh, it's worse worse than that sack.
Speaker 0: It's extreme worse Sacramento, but sack anime.
Speaker 0: I dug into it a little more.
Speaker 0: this con is a history of doing bad shit like they invite That other cons won't invite like whatever.
Speaker 1: I didn't.
Speaker 1: I denounce.
Speaker 1: Oh sack anime There.
Speaker 0: I only denounced two things in the world Scott in any civilization game and sack anime.
Speaker 0: So here's how egregious this is why opposite of endorse denounce.
Speaker 0: so sack anime is happening this weekend Like crap.
Speaker 0: April 1st and seconds.
Speaker 1: have you looked at a kovat graph?
Speaker 1: It's going up people way up.
Speaker 0: This ain't like New York City, this is a place where it's upper upper up yep - it is happening at the convention center.
Speaker 0: that was Giving vaccines out and the vaccines are all gonna be paused so the fucking anime con can happen.
Speaker 0: uh-huh Three this anime con Should not be allowed to happen because per the rules of the region the place It's in you can't have conventions in the convention center.
Speaker 0: But you know what you're allowed to have in the convention center.
Speaker 1: swap meets There's all they have.
Speaker 1: there's a rule that you can have swap meets at half capacity right.
Speaker 0: so they're having classified their convention as a swap meet yep, and Multiple people reply because I tweeted about this.
Speaker 0: then I had to mute it because it got read like did.
Speaker 0: this thread is like still Going on Twitter because people are mad about it as they should be.
Speaker 0: but it's even worse than that.
Speaker 0: Apparently according to numerous sources this con was planned during Covid like.
Speaker 0: this was not like.
Speaker 0: they planned this five years ago, and they had to do something.
Speaker 0: It was planned during kovat and they classified as a swap meet on purpose to make sure it happens.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so never go to this con.
Speaker 0: Yes Evil people this is not.
Speaker 0: not that it's excusable But it is not the case of a con was forced to run or go bankrupt.
Speaker 0: It was a case of this con actively tried to run During a pandemic.
Speaker 1: for all that we can tell.
Speaker 1: that is true.
Speaker 1: right there may it may not be true But as far as the information available to us reported by reputable real news websites That at least appear to be real news websites that appears to be the case.
Speaker 1: therefore that means In summary anyone who is running sack anime the staff the board of that con whoever it's organized owner president Whatever right those are people who think it is okay to literally risk human lives Just to have an anime con and get together and cosplay for a weekend.
Speaker 1: right.
Speaker 1: they would literally not Exaggerating like take a person who is alive and just murder them Right in order to have a convention, and then a person is dead.
Speaker 1: They're okay with that.
Speaker 1: I mean even one person would be too many and they're potentially risking many people.
Speaker 1: yep, so they're just evil bad people And fuck their con.
Speaker 0: yeah, we've said this before.
Speaker 0: but even if a con was you know forced to run like one of those situations We've talked about The whole purpose of making an LLC is to limit your liability.
Speaker 0: It's right there.
Speaker 0: in the name limited liability company.
Speaker 0: if your choices run your con or your LLC goes bankrupt You're morally obligated to let your LLC go bankrupt.
Speaker 0: because guess what you can just make a new LLC and get the same staff and just start your fucking con again like in a couple years.
Speaker 0: like it'll be fine.
Speaker 0: Yep, yep, so yeah fuck everyone involved in the management and planning of sack anime And also do not go to sack anime.
Speaker 0: You don't say Who is even going?
Speaker 1: Like that like people who properly believe the same thing as the people who run the con believe Which is that it is okay to risk human lives just to be.
Speaker 0: That was like you're gonna be mad and he sends this link and I click on the link and I was mad.
Speaker 0: But as I read the rest of the article.
Speaker 0: I just got more mad and madder.
Speaker 0: It was Homer mad in bed face by the time I got to the bottom.
Speaker 1: Yep, so there you go.
Speaker 1: Waste any more breath on such trash people.
Speaker 0: Yep in some other news that is Complex and behind the scenes, but it's like it'll be interesting to see the real like what's going on here.
Speaker 0: Bandai Namco actually announced recently like this month a big re-shuffling of all their subsidiaries.
Speaker 0: Because remember you think oh Bandai Bandai is a holding company and there are a lot of like subsidiary companies under that.
Speaker 0: That's how a lot of.
Speaker 1: yeah, you got sure you got Dragon Balls.
Speaker 1: Yeah getting poke a nap.
Speaker 1: Oh, come on There's a lock it there's a lot there Pac Man's there's a lot of stuff.
Speaker 0: so they have rejiggered a lot of that together and consolidated and there's I don't I there.
Speaker 0: we might be able to infer some things about the state of That industry like that fandom industry based on this because the reason they gave They're mostly focusing on the u.s.
Speaker 0: France and China like subsidiaries in those three places in light of Re-evaluating the direction of the company's plan in light of expected changes in quote customers lifestyles and sense of value.
Speaker 0: Like there's a something Predicately caused them to make these changes, but they're basically merging everything into three units.
Speaker 0: They're gonna have one unit that is entertainment, which is basically like toys and hobbies and network and all that stuff.
Speaker 0: one That's like IP production which is merging other visual like like TV stuff and their music stuff together and they're like IP units.
Speaker 0: and then a third unit the Amusement unit which I'm pretty sure is just the gaming stuff Mmm, and that's all we know.
Speaker 0: that is anime news it that doesn't sound super exciting.
Speaker 1: I'd probably go check out see what the gunpla communities are saying right because you know Bandai makes all the gunplas
Speaker 0: Yep, the day that like where a fan will care is either this consolidation might also come along with some Business line that that fan cares about not being prioritized or being shut down.
Speaker 0: that often happens in mergers or new ones appearing.
Speaker 0: Yep, new ones appear.
Speaker 0: one could be revitalized.
Speaker 0: That's been dead as part of a like a play.
Speaker 1: There's a lot you think things might become accessible or inaccessible in different places in the world.
Speaker 0: There might be more cross work like the visual and music production units and the IP units might like do stuff That was difficult to do before because they want to cross things that were previously managed by two separate subsidiaries.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: All we all we can say for sure.
Speaker 1: Is that something I know it's so we know it's like Oh Tekken.
Speaker 1: We know so little right is basically Something related to some of the stuff that Bandai does in some way will likely change in the nearish future.
Speaker 1: Yep, that's it.
Speaker 1: That's how little we know but it's still What it.
Speaker 1: the news is not that the thing has changed yet So you can't write.
Speaker 1: the news is keep an eyeball in that direction.
Speaker 1: Wait for it.
Speaker 1: That's the news.
Speaker 0: So I'll talk about penguin drum.
Speaker 1: Oh, okay.
Speaker 1: Yeah, just a tiny news, right?
Speaker 0: So ten years ago God damn I still haven't even watched it Ikuhara the Utena guy.
Speaker 1: right, you know, everyone knows Kuniko Ikuhara in this anime creator Created this TV anime called penguin drum that we didn't watch right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm sure you know the the bear one was good right and people said I watched a few episodes of the the newer one The couple one that was also for good.
Speaker 1: What little I watched that the couple one was good anyway.
Speaker 1: But yeah penguin drum For a show that's ten years old that you thought was like a show that you know Like most anime happens ends and then fades from consciousness.
Speaker 1: They are coming out with a compilation movie of penguin drum ten years after its original release.
Speaker 1: for some reason I guess there must be some value or money behind it or something That's interesting and cool in case maybe that might become.
Speaker 1: you know Usually I'm not huge on compilation movies, you know, even people who say like, you know, those original Gundam compilation movies.
Speaker 1: I watched the three movies instead of watching the original Gundam series, which can drag a bit I personally.
Speaker 1: we just watch the original Gundam series.
Speaker 1: I got time for that, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, because I say that neither one of us watched penguin drum.
Speaker 1: That's true So it's.
Speaker 1: but the point is as someone who I think that's why there might be some appeal in the compilation movie.
Speaker 1: It's like oh, well, I didn't watch it, but it's like watch this compilation movie.
Speaker 1: Oh, well, if I had watched it, I'd probably be like man who needs a compilation movie.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I've never in my life seen something.
Speaker 0: and then later when a compilation movie came out said hot.
Speaker 0: Damn I really got to get on top of that
Speaker 1: Exactly, but when you haven't seen it and you know, you're not, you know
Speaker 0: There's gonna be a ghost in the shell movie and I get real pumped and then I find out it's a compilation movie and my Interest drops back to zero.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but it's like oh maybe I'll what.
Speaker 1: maybe you'll be worth watching the compilation movie penguin drum instead of watching the real thing.
Speaker 1: Who knows it's coming.
Speaker 1: And that's I think the most fascinating thing is not that the compilation movie will be good bad worth watching or not?
Speaker 1: It's that penguin drum as a franchise and a property isn't dead, you know It's still.
Speaker 0: if they I if they made a new tenor compilation movie.
Speaker 0: I would actually be how could you just could you?
Speaker 1: You might have to make three like the Gundam ones.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that might work.
Speaker 0: antenna one dot one one one dot one All right, so his isn't is?
Speaker 1: today is a Trans visibility day.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, so let's.
Speaker 1: so let's check this news right very relevant news.
Speaker 1: So when it comes to wiki's write this Wikipedia, everyone knows Wikipedia and The thing with Wikipedia is that they will cover a wide variety of topics.
Speaker 1: But Wikipedia refuses to go super in-depth on narrow topics right even You know because there are some things in the world that there is just so much information on right like, you know Pokemon, let's say right, but you don't have.
Speaker 1: they don't put all the Pokemon info on Wikipedia, right?
Speaker 1: Just like you don't put everything there is to know about Turtles in the encyclopedia Britannica.
Speaker 1: Does that even still exist?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 0: Well with this it's especially things that are Fictional Especially yes, like there are.
Speaker 1: that's why we asked for like every kind of boat, but that's a very yes But they don't go into, you know, super detail, right?
Speaker 1: So that's why we have things like Bulbapedia to give you all the Pokemon information.
Speaker 1: Yeah And there's a website fandom.
Speaker 1: Is it just fandom?
Speaker 1: calm but it's.
Speaker 1: they run Wikis about all the you know for all the different major fandoms including the famously pun named Wikipedia which has all the Star Wars information about literally everything Star Wars ever right is catalogued on the Wikipedia.
Speaker 1: Because obviously that is so much information that Wikipedia doesn't need to be hosting.
Speaker 1: And what happened is they had a policy.
Speaker 1: is that the trans Related part right?
Speaker 1: They had policies on there that were like look, you know, someone may have you know transgendered right and have a new name and You know regardless of how you feel about that, right?
Speaker 1: They want.
Speaker 1: their policy was to use the names of people that were in the credits of the thing.
Speaker 1: so if there was a comic book a Star Wars comic book and they were making a page about it and The writer was a transgender person and their name at the time of writing the book was different from their name Now they were gonna use the the dead name, right which is bad for a lot of reasons
Speaker 0: And even worse they choose to die on this hill for a while.
Speaker 1: yes, but has the very very tiny Somewhat barely understandable reason of like, you know Someone might look up the person because they have the comic right and if they didn't have the dead name up there You wouldn't find the person.
Speaker 0: well Meanwhile, we could Wikipedia or IMDB actually has a handles that very well and that they will have a page for each person And it has their real like.
Speaker 0: whatever name they go by is the name there That is their real name only ever appear in a separate class of for a specific film Credited as X for data integrity purposes, right?
Speaker 1: I mean and the way you know to give a good example right is like, you know, someone like sting, right?
Speaker 1: I bet if I go to IMDB I haven't done this so I'm just guessing.
Speaker 1: but I'm willing to bet if you go to IMDB and look for sting is It?
Speaker 1: the name is gonna be sting and is like his real name?
Speaker 1: right quote real legal name, you know, was it?
Speaker 1: is it like?
Speaker 1: What is it forget?
Speaker 1: It's something really like sounds dorky like har, you know Looking it up right now.
Speaker 1: It's gordon.
Speaker 1: I think it's gory.
Speaker 0: Go Steve go Steve Borden Steve Borden.
Speaker 0: Okay, so he orton it was.
Speaker 0: oh he is listed.
Speaker 0: Oh, no, that's a wrestler.
Speaker 0: Never mind.
Speaker 1: Okay The point is right is like Gordon's by staying Matthew some nerd it was going is listed as Sting in IMDB and exactly but it lists for each thing.
Speaker 0: He's in what he's credited as there but the name that is his name associated with his like page is just staying.
Speaker 1: Exactly, right.
Speaker 1: I'm pretty sure that Gordon whatever is his legal name, right?
Speaker 0: Well, they do it better.
Speaker 0: They also said like they point out they don't even say it's his legal neighbor Whatever.
Speaker 0: they just say he was born with that name.
Speaker 1: Yeah, okay.
Speaker 1: Sure good.
Speaker 1: That's fine.
Speaker 0: There's a lot of nuance how to handle these situations But Wikipedia was taking a right arbitrary hard line.
Speaker 0: That was harmful for no good reason, right?
Speaker 1: So here's the.
Speaker 1: here's the the why.
Speaker 1: Wikipedia itself was bad, but the end result of the whole situation ended up good.
Speaker 1: So what Wikipedia was doing is they were putting it up for a vote using their existing processes, right?
Speaker 0: Seen in Shattered Earth trilogy where someone puts up a vote similar to this and someone can't Yeah Blows it up and says you don't get to vote on who counts as people.
Speaker 1: That's right trans rights or human rights.
Speaker 1: You can't have votes on human rights, right?
Speaker 1: It's like, you know, it is it.
Speaker 1: as a Jew There's one Jew right in a room and it's like alright, let's have a vote and should we kill the Jews?
Speaker 1: It's like.
Speaker 1: that's not how it works right.
Speaker 0: you vote on things like should taxes be four point one percent or four point three percent?
Speaker 1: Exactly, right.
Speaker 1: So this is why you know in democracy you took my majority rules minority, right?
Speaker 1: See we vote on things but anything that is the right of minorities.
Speaker 1: You can't vote on that.
Speaker 1: It just is right.
Speaker 1: deal with it.
Speaker 1: so Fandom, you know the Wikipedia was going about things all the wrong way voting on human rights, which they shouldn't be doing and Luckily I don't know if all just luckily but goodly Fandom the Overarching, you know service that runs and hosts all these wikis.
Speaker 1: They're the technology platform that all the wikis on fandom are governed individually.
Speaker 1: But fandom itself, you know runs the servers so they have a terms of service for any wookie for a wookie For any of the wikis that they host right?
Speaker 1: And so the even though the wikis might vote on their own internal, you know governance issues they're still beholden to fandom itself.
Speaker 1: and Fandom came through and was like look You can't vote on this Because you know having all these dead names is violating our terms of service.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right of not respect to human rights.
Speaker 1: So shove it Wikipedia, right?
Speaker 1: Your your voting is over right.
Speaker 1: get those dead names out of here, right?
Speaker 1: And that also applies to all the other wikis hosted by fandom, which is a very good news.
Speaker 1: you can read.
Speaker 1: this gizmodo article gives you a Hundred percent of the details on this story if you really want all the details and all the history because there is a lot of history going down Here with Wikipedia and such.
Speaker 1: all the details have been Thoroughly documented by journalists and so you don't need to hear them from my mouth Because I didn't read all of them.
Speaker 1: I just read enough to tell you the news.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: Ah, yeah I am.
Speaker 0: DB has another interesting policy.
Speaker 0: That's good.
Speaker 0: Even if you like if you're if you have if your birth name is not credited anywhere They will not like.
Speaker 0: if you want it gone They will remove it because there's no relevance to their database to that.
Speaker 1: I agree.
Speaker 1: That's also a good policy.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it seemed to have a pretty good policy here.
Speaker 0: now that I'm digging through it Mmm, so in some other news before we get to our main bit this is relevant.
Speaker 0: It's not really news but it's a recent article and I don't want to go too in-depth on it because we're gonna probably spend a lot of time talking about The Simpsons.
Speaker 0: but You can guess why I bring this up.
Speaker 0: This is an article on CBR about why king of the hill Which was very popular at the time of his cancellation was canceled.
Speaker 0: It's not a bunch of huge new insights Like this is not a lot of new information But it talks a lot about why a popular Fox show might be canceled while executive changes at the network.
Speaker 1: That's usually what the story is.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but there's also like.
Speaker 1: that's what killed Disney Afternoon.
Speaker 0: We learned that Yeah, but sometimes it's also things around like the creative staff either out of ideas or like geek nights Yeah, yeah, or maybe like they think the show like did what it needed to do.
Speaker 0: They want to move on to something else.
Speaker 0: There's a lot of reasons for this kind of thing.
Speaker 0: Fox has never Officially given a reason for this one so we can only speculate.
Speaker 0: but the art do?
Speaker 1: they give reasons regularly or Sometimes no obligation.
Speaker 0: sometimes shows get canceled and an explicit official reason is given like ratings were expectations.
Speaker 0: Sometimes no reason is given.
Speaker 0: the only thing we know for sure Objectively is that the time slot that king of the hill was in was taken over by the Cleveland Show.
Speaker 0: Okay But It's very interesting that the Simpsons is still going.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know all I have to say about king of the hill is like I didn't really watch it.
Speaker 1: It was one of those shows that I would always see starting or ending before or after other shows and then change the channel away.
Speaker 1: But in more recent years, right?
Speaker 1: I have I know people who are appreciators of it.
Speaker 0: It is like really low-key funny shows, but I didn't watch it.
Speaker 1: So I don't have an opinion of like whether I didn't like it or dislike it.
Speaker 1: I just didn't watch it.
Speaker 1: So But seeing other people's appreciation of it adjacent to me right and people like spreading memes from it I'm like my now current thought on it is like, huh?
Speaker 1: There was probably something good there that I didn't see cuz I didn't watch it.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: That's my feeling on that.
Speaker 0: Watch all of it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm not gonna go.
Speaker 1: I'm not gonna do that.
Speaker 1: But that's what my talk.
Speaker 0: Hill Set later, but same care queen of the queen of the valley Like.
Speaker 0: I think all the characters will be 15 years older.
Speaker 1: Okay, whatever.
Speaker 0: I don't know we'll see but I was.
Speaker 0: oh I was a big like.
Speaker 0: our family was a big fan of Mike judge Like even from the early Beavis and butthead days.
Speaker 0: So when a king of the hill was announced we were all on board and honestly king of the hill is one of the funnier like American prime time cartoons there ever was.
Speaker 0: Hmm it's no first ten seasons of Simpsons, but it's definitely a solid show.
Speaker 0: You wanna talk about Keanu Reeves ultra-violent comic.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 1: I forgot.
Speaker 1: So this is sort of a geek bite and sort of a news right, so There was a comic book listed in the comic book order form called berserker with some vowels removed.
Speaker 0: It will not hit you like a truck.
Speaker 1: However, yes, people are making all sorts of berserker jokes, right?
Speaker 1: But I it caught my eye Because on the the credits right in the cover were two names that I recognized Matt Kintz, right?
Speaker 1: Which you know is a great comic writers written things like MCND, right and the spy spy thing.
Speaker 1: What was it called?
Speaker 1: I have it on the shelf and it's not turning around to look at it.
Speaker 1: anyway, I like the comics I've read that have been written by Matt Kint and Keanu Reeves the famous person that you even I know who that is bench sitting guy, right.
Speaker 1: So you see Keanu Reeves name on a front of a comic book.
Speaker 1: It's like did he actually write this comic book?
Speaker 1: and on the cover of the comic book is an illustration of Keanu Reeves You know wearing guns and shit like.
Speaker 1: he's ready for the typical movie that he's typecast to play in.
Speaker 1: Okay, so I go and I'm like, well, I guess I'm ordering that comic book.
Speaker 1: I'm like, give me send me volume one.
Speaker 1: I want to.
Speaker 1: I want to read it, right?
Speaker 1: I'll see what the hell's in it if he actually wrote it.
Speaker 1: And I read volume one not volume one, you know the first floppy issue, right?
Speaker 1: And in that book it was Keanu Reeves is is basically this immortal dude Who can't die sort of Wolverine esque, you know he gets gets really beat up and shot and and destroyed and they he goes back to this lab and they can sort of fix him and He's out doing wars and stuff.
Speaker 1: But also he's like a zillion years old right like caveman old and that's sort of the plot.
Speaker 1: and Not long after I get this first, you know issue and read it and see what the deal is There's announced like yeah, they're making like, you know animation of it and every.
Speaker 1: it's like the license it right and I'm like Already.
Speaker 1: the first issue just came out, right?
Speaker 1: so sometimes we see things where a comic is like 10 years old before it gets adapted like invincible.
Speaker 1: and Sometimes we see things.
Speaker 1: It's like yeah one floppy comic comes out.
Speaker 1: They're like up licensed.
Speaker 1: Yeah adaptations.
Speaker 1: They're coming.
Speaker 1: Let's go comics.
Speaker 0: A lot of geek nights comics have become one of the biggest like Floats to see if something can be turned into an animation or a movie.
Speaker 1: I mean, that's that's been true for like 15 to 20 years already.
Speaker 0: Yes, that's why we bring it up a lot on geek nights.
Speaker 1: But I'm saying is like.
Speaker 1: that's why I still read comics and don't watch a lot of TV.
Speaker 1: Just get the original biz.
Speaker 1: why you know something so strong that is inspiring someone to invest money in it, right?
Speaker 1: Whether that thing they the adaptation they want to make happens or not a mouse guard The original thing must have some incredible strength.
Speaker 1: that's worth checking out.
Speaker 1: Just constantly read comics and you won't need to bother with the other stuff.
Speaker 1: but yeah, if you are a fan of the Works of Keanu Reeves in which he has typecast as action, dude such as John wicks matrix, etc.
Speaker 1: You will probably enjoy this because that's what the fuck it is.
Speaker 1: And if you're not then you're not.
Speaker 1: so ignore it.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: And last before we get into things the day and everything I know I've mentioned this every every other Wednesday or so.
Speaker 0: But great pretender all I'm gonna say is now that I've seen everything but the last arc.
Speaker 0: People are sleeping on this show.
Speaker 0: I cannot understand.
Speaker 1: I was gonna watch it.
Speaker 1: We would have done a show in it today had I watched it.
Speaker 0: I just.
Speaker 0: and why more anime?
Speaker 0: people are not talking about this show?
Speaker 0: This is not a cowboy bebop like how we bebop is an s-rank show But right now having seen all but the last arc.
Speaker 0: this is an a-minus show and Depending on how the last arc goes which appears to be like now, you know all these characters.
Speaker 0: now It's gonna get like more serious.
Speaker 0: Like here's the here's the real meat.
Speaker 0: like here's the story like how kobe bebop did to a degree This.
Speaker 0: this could easily be an a anime in the end.
Speaker 0: hmm Me so many times and but it's just.
Speaker 0: it's so weird that I see almost no one talking about the show.
Speaker 1: Well, I just just a very quick note.
Speaker 1: Also working.
Speaker 1: I'm continuing at least to watch.
Speaker 0: volt is five and much more than rim has Ten episodes in but I feel I'm based on what you said to me.
Speaker 0: I gotta go deep.
Speaker 1: We're on episode 20 something and The every episode except for like the dog episode which is just like a random monster of the week episode.
Speaker 1: Other than that one episode every episode like Something happens they push.
Speaker 1: the status quo does not stay still like they are pushing hard.
Speaker 1: It is quite interesting to see a super robot toy selling show that keeps going right?
Speaker 1: Doesn't let up.
Speaker 0: so, you know things of the day.
Speaker 0: so My favorite character in Adventure Time is actually LSP in terms like.
Speaker 0: there's something Hilarious about that character and that voice and everything.
Speaker 1: but LSP is definitely a top five.
Speaker 1: I don't know there might there might be enough characters, but you know way up there highly ranked.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like LSP is right up there with like Marceline and Princess Bubblegum and like there's I actually you know I put all.
Speaker 1: I'm a person who likes weird side characters because they're more interesting.
Speaker 1: Even you know, even when main characters do have interesting things about them which Adventure Time all the main characters obviously do they always have.
Speaker 1: they're always a little less out there right than side characters because you do you need to use them more often if They're out there that they run out of material and don't work.
Speaker 1: But the out there ness of side characters always makes me like them more Even though you don't see them often, but I know I like this character a lot.
Speaker 0: But I know Scott is particularly a fan of the choose goose.
Speaker 1: I think choose goose might be the number one as like prismo cosmic owl choose goose.
Speaker 0: And it's very telling because now this is out of date.
Speaker 0: it only gets up through Elements which is near the end of Adventure Time, but there have been some appearances post that that are not in this video.
Speaker 0: This is all of Adventure Time up through the end of elements, but only when choose goose is visible.
Speaker 0: Yep, not even if he's talking he has to be on screen or it doesn't count.
Speaker 0: it is two minutes and 35 seconds long.
Speaker 1: they took all the frames in which choose goose was on screen and Cut those frames out and pasted them in order, and that's it favorite bit.
Speaker 0: with shoes I mean the thing we quote the most is the armor thing.
Speaker 0: But yep my favorite thing with him ever is when Finn buys that cursed sword And he goes back to choose good because you didn't buy it.
Speaker 0: for me the fuck like he's pissed at.
Speaker 1: he's like What are you doing?
Speaker 1: Yeah?
Speaker 1: He's angry cuz like they went to another store.
Speaker 1: He's like.
Speaker 1: I know you went to go shop at the grass, huh, huh?
Speaker 1: Yeah a bunch of jerks Thought you were loyal customers of the choose goose.
Speaker 1: Now you're.
Speaker 1: now you're coming to me for help.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, just so mad.
Speaker 1: So the thing I like about choose goose is that choose goose is simultaneously silly looking.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's just like this floppy goose thing though.
Speaker 0: We know canonically he can walk.
Speaker 0: We didn't learn that until Right.
Speaker 1: well yeah, but he's just floppy looking.
Speaker 1: yeah He is a merchant which is totally cool in a fantasy universe selling cool stuff right being.
Speaker 1: that's always everyone loves You know shot item shops, right?
Speaker 1: He's actually.
Speaker 1: he rhymes in a silly way talks in a funny way But it otherwise is perfectly confident intelligent not foolish.
Speaker 1: You know he's just a quality merchant doing merchant biz right.
Speaker 1: He's not like doesn't have any issues You know just going about his biz mm-hmm, so what you got?
Speaker 1: So what do I have?
Speaker 1: so?
Speaker 1: The NWHL after having to suspend their season with their failed bubble in Lake Placid Which was the she went away.
Speaker 0: people were watching that stuff.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it was on Twitch and everything you know they were.
Speaker 1: They've managed to come back and finish it.
Speaker 1: they basically finished it by just having you know a one weekend deal right a little semi-finals finals kind of thing and They managed to get that broadcast on NBC Sports Which was exciting?
Speaker 1: But it also meant that you couldn't watch it on Twitch in the United States.
Speaker 1: if you're in other countries.
Speaker 1: It was still on Twitch, but in doubt US twitch region blocks.
Speaker 1: you could use a VPN I guess but if you're in the US you had to use NBC Sports to watch it.
Speaker 1: the champions the Isabel Cup champions of 2021 is Boston because Boston needs more sports Whatever.
Speaker 1: Regardless It was still glad to see that they managed to finish it and didn't just cancel the whole thing.
Speaker 1: And I'm sure that next year There's you know there's been talk of like adding a team from Montreal so that'll bring them up to.
Speaker 1: you know even more teams.
Speaker 1: Seven teams would that be seven teams, but yeah, it'll be a lot more exciting And they'll hopefully have a real ish season next time not plagued by plague Yeah, so to somewhat celebrate this this person What is their name on Twitter?
Speaker 0: Adam Stevens color-filled.
Speaker 1: madam Stevens color-filled mind on Twitter.
Speaker 1: took because there obviously is not an NWHL video game Although there should be all right.
Speaker 1: took NHL 21 EA Sports and where you can Customize your teams and your rosters and your jerseys and every right you can customize.
Speaker 1: That's how they every a sports game.
Speaker 1: lets you do that these days, and he basically set up the whole NWHL Right jerseys player rosters everything inside of NHL 2021 and I think that's pretty awesome.
Speaker 1: And there's a whole Twitter thread they posted with all the screenshots and descriptions of the whole thing going on here, so That's pretty cool.
Speaker 1: I say and I hope as You know Adam Stevens points out that like yeah, actually he wasn't able.
Speaker 1: He got it as close as he could but because of the limitations You know like there weren't even enough hairstyles available.
Speaker 1: right in an NHL 21 Like you probably couldn't even get a Mika's advantage at going on with the limitations and hairstyles.
Speaker 1: They got right.
Speaker 1: so Step up your game.
Speaker 1: EA Sports right.
Speaker 1: it's in the game now, so it has to be in the game.
Speaker 0: That's what your slogan was just making fun of EA for bringing out a new golf game.
Speaker 0: They were like Yeah, come on.
Speaker 0: Yeah It is not of a great track record for like.
Speaker 0: there's the people who play it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, sports games don't overlap as much for the people who play almost all other games.
Speaker 1: If you're out there, and you want to compete with EA Sports right But you can't because they got all those licenses like yeah, and shit, right There are plenty of women's sports leagues I'm sure that you could make very happy by paying them to license.
Speaker 1: You know their team logos and players and everything and you know games.
Speaker 0: I don't have to address that or market of the people who play EA games.
Speaker 0: You might be able to make better games, too.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you could just make it like you know.
Speaker 1: there's no reason the video game couldn't be.
Speaker 1: you know even better, right?
Speaker 1: Why this if you came out with?
Speaker 1: NWHL 21?
Speaker 1: right somehow you managed to develop it all in a year, and it was better than NHL 21.
Speaker 1: There's no reason it couldn't be yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah, why couldn't it be?
Speaker 1: People would play that right.
Speaker 1: You know you might force EA to buy your company And incorporate your your thing into their lineup.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 0: so in the meta moment the geek nice book club book is the tale of Genji.
Speaker 0: We're reading it, and yeah, just follow along with us.
Speaker 0: I think I think the trajectory is Probably something like end of May or June we could probably do.
Speaker 0: the episode is what I'm feeling.
Speaker 1: Oh, you're reading that fast huh?
Speaker 0: Yeah, well I was but this just this week I've been too busy to read so I slowed down a lot Sam.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: Good good cuz I was Hit a busy wall.
Speaker 1: Yeah, luckily no new video games have been released.
Speaker 1: to like.
Speaker 1: take me.
Speaker 0: oh Yeah, unluckily that what it was made me busy this week was I actually started playing hearts of iron.
Speaker 0: God damn it.
Speaker 1: That was what's made me busy as I'm actually doing work at work.
Speaker 0: Oh That clock never rings.
Speaker 1: yeah, I know.
Speaker 0: right You always make fun of me when I'm like I'm too.
Speaker 0: I got a busy with work stuff.
Speaker 1: No, I'm hopefully gonna finish it all and then I'll be able to stop working for you know the remainder of my life.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so yeah, let's just get right into it cuz this is a big topic way back.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna link to this, but I'll warn you this was 2006 for him and Scott.
Speaker 0: We did a show called television of our youth and we talked about all the shows we watched when we were young.
Speaker 0: I am sure we talked about the Simpsons at some point in that episode.
Speaker 1: I'm sure we've talked about the Simpsons at many points throughout the life of this podcast.
Speaker 0: There have been 15 more years of the Simpsons since we did that episode Which is more seasons of the Simpsons than we have seen.
Speaker 1: That's true.
Speaker 0: That's why I want to bring that up.
Speaker 0: we Might have talked about the Simpsons 15 years ago, I think.
Speaker 0: to this date like I have seen about a quarter of all Simpsons episodes
Speaker 1: I have probably seen no Simpsons episode that came out between when we did that podcast and now I Basically if we had done a Simpsons podcast on that day It would probably have similar material to the podcast we're about to do other than the fact that we're talking about how there were 15 Years of time.
Speaker 0: I remember In AV Club said something like we're not gonna bother reviewing every Simpsons episode ever anymore.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but it's the fascinating thing about the Simpsons like the thing like that.
Speaker 0: the overarching theme of this episode I think is that it looms Terrifyingly large in not just the pop culture of people our age but like on the internet like the Simpsons is so deeply ingrained in so many places and yet Pretty much everyone on earth agrees that only the first ten ish seasons were good.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think the only term the only kinds of properties right in the world that are like big enough to like Be on Simpsons level Would be things like Pokemon I guess all Disney combined right.
Speaker 1: not any one Disney right, but like just.
Speaker 1: you know the full Disney Loadout right or like you know maybe even the full Warner Brothers loadout you but all of them together Right could be on like the Simpsons Level of bigness right like Gundam is I don't think as big as Simpsons.
Speaker 1: It's close I guess cuz Pokemon is bigger than that right.
Speaker 0: yeah, cuz remember we're not talking about number of episodes like at the word.
Speaker 0: There's like one piece episode 4,000 or what I like, but and Pokemon and Pokemon.
Speaker 1: I think is what is it got to be at least Close to ten years younger than Simpsons is?
Speaker 1: So yeah, it's it's just unbelievably huge.
Speaker 1: you could I mean I'm sure there are several Simpsons only podcasts for us to do one episode on it.
Speaker 1: It's like we can't even scratch the surface of what you know.
Speaker 1: what's going on there.
Speaker 0: It's interesting that it's one of the rare shows where it would be very easy for people like us about our age say oh Yeah, I liked X when I was young and it was good But then it got bad and everyone who likes it now does is stupid.
Speaker 0: But this is like the one case where everyone has nostalgia for like this one era of the Simpsons.
Speaker 0: But it seems like it is like a hundred percent legit.
Speaker 0: that feeling and what I've got up on the screen here And which is I'm just looking at cuz it really there's a lot of analysis like this.
Speaker 0: someone did an analysis of the IMDB rating Just like what do people rate episodes of this show?
Speaker 0: for all of the Simpsons and It maps one to one with my understanding and feeling and thoughts on the Simpsons.
Speaker 1: It's well.
Speaker 1: It's like you know.
Speaker 1: It's like yeah I see that these newer episodes that I've never watched are ranked lowly compared to the ones from our heyday, right?
Speaker 1: But it's like.
Speaker 1: is that really because they're worse?
Speaker 1: or is it because the audience of this has?
Speaker 1: I don't know I have no numbers.
Speaker 1: has the Simpsons continued to capture a The you know new audience as time has gone on?
Speaker 1: or are that because we're the prime People I want to sit right?
Speaker 0: it came out in the show my family would watch Religiously.
Speaker 1: this show came out into being when we were in like fifth sixth grade.
Speaker 1: I guess right.
Speaker 1: why the late Come here's before that?
Speaker 1: I Remember being like elementary school cafeteria.
Speaker 0: I don't think you started watching it on the Tracy Altman show like our family did pretty sure his fifth grade.
Speaker 1: when the Simpsons came out I Was in kindergarten.
Speaker 1: what like 80?
Speaker 1: No, okay, maybe a little earlier than that.
Speaker 0: I don't know I was are we?
Speaker 0: we are?
Speaker 0: but we would watch the Tracy Altman show as a family and The Simpsons like the precursors to the Simpsons were on that show as like animated skits, right?
Speaker 0: And we watched those like the night they aired as a family right
Speaker 1: and then it became its own show yeah Created by Matt Groening who also did lots of like little
Speaker 0: and I think you don't understand like if you're younger than us that TV Was still up like in American culture in particular like TV.
Speaker 1: There was no internet.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it was no internet.
Speaker 0: so when a new show came out, especially an animated show, especially a controversial animated show cuz the Simpsons was Terrible like weirdly controversial for like the first four years of its run.
Speaker 0: like.
Speaker 1: so when the show is new, right?
Speaker 1: It's like, you know the the I guess the the thing that preceded it that you would compare it to would be like the Flintstones Right like a cartoon that was on primetime.
Speaker 1: that was you know based on in a family, right?
Speaker 1: You know, it's honeymooners asked, you know Simpsons has some of that honeymooners DNA in it as well.
Speaker 0: clearly at least the early Simpsons This is a lot of the DNA of the all the early sitcoms.
Speaker 0: Yes It's almost like they took the best techniques of all the early sit long long running ridiculously popular, right?
Speaker 1: So, you know the Simpsons had a lot of that same formula only, you know refreshed, right?
Speaker 1: You know for the late 80s early 90s times Yeah, it was super controversial because it's like, you know You had all the same people.
Speaker 1: you see now getting mad about.
Speaker 1: you know, Lil Nas X and they're like Oh, you know kids watching this.
Speaker 1: it's so violent and you know heinous and dirty and you know uncouth things are happening.
Speaker 1: Kids can't be watching.
Speaker 0: when I was in fifth grade We went to an amusement park and I had a Bart Simpson shirt on and the amusement park made me turn it inside out Or they wouldn't let our family in.
Speaker 1: Wow, like don't have a cow man.
Speaker 0: Yeah that the shirt was the don't have a cow man shirt.
Speaker 0: Bart Simpson was seen as too subversive to display in public by a scary number of people when we were kids.
Speaker 1: Meanwhile Bart Simpson is.
Speaker 1: that is actually like the most corporate possible, right?
Speaker 0: Might as well be Mickey Mouse at this point but also in that era Bart Simpson like the worst thing Bart Simpson ever did in any Simpsons episode I ever saw like Eric Cartman was worse than that within seconds.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean, that's the whole thing is like a ridge.
Speaker 1: the original Simpsons The sort of you know, the the the image of it was.
Speaker 1: it's mostly about you know This is family, but the main character is Bart is as bad You know sort of troublemaking kid is not a role model for your kids, right?
Speaker 1: So you don't want your kids watching.
Speaker 1: but the show first of all Bart didn't really, you know other than like, you know Mild pranks.
Speaker 1: It's like what?
Speaker 1: Misbehaving stuff does Bart actually do?
Speaker 0: I mean later on it There's like the episode where Bart quote goes too far like there's.
Speaker 0: there's a few things like that that happen at one point Yeah, but some of those things like accidents too, right or like the dog in the vent was a legit accident Right.
Speaker 1: It's like, you know, he wasn't like.
Speaker 0: purposefully you're calling me a liar Right, and we can't quote.
Speaker 0: the fucking Simpsons is gone forever.
Speaker 0: I'm just gonna nip that in the bud right now.
Speaker 1: I caught myself but like, you know the episode like stampy the elephant.
Speaker 1: He's like he just innocently cares about this elephant.
Speaker 1: It causes trouble, but he's not like trying to have an elephant stomp the town down or anything like that.
Speaker 1: You know, yeah, but I guess but the show transfers quickly right after those first few seasons.
Speaker 0: It's like really it's a Homer focused show and because the character of Homer changes as well Right, the Simpsons from being sort of my life where I've recognized this concept of the a-plot and the b-plot of a show.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well every episode has an a-plot and a b-plot.
Speaker 1: That's the whole.
Speaker 0: yeah.
Speaker 1: But yeah, the character of Homer changes after you know Earlier episodes right earlier seasons from being more of like a bad mad dad to the sort of you know Dope Homer that you are familiar with.
Speaker 0: Homer went through these eras kind of like Lupin like there was.
Speaker 0: there was loving but just bad at things Homer who moved into like Kind of stupid Homer to evil Homer.
Speaker 0: and then there was like evil Homer who was weirdly cunning like at like a dangerous animal.
Speaker 0: and then like Borderline offensive stereotype of a mentally challenged person Homer.
Speaker 0: and they've like just Oscillated around what Homer is over the years and I don't even know what Homer is like now.
Speaker 0: I literally have not seen an episode since season 13.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I have no idea.
Speaker 1: But yeah that you know, I think.
Speaker 1: but the show quick got away from that, you know being about Bart the bad kid, right?
Speaker 1: You know to being about.
Speaker 1: you know, the family as a whole right or even some episodes are just about.
Speaker 1: you know Different characters in the town.
Speaker 1: Simpsons family is not even there.
Speaker 0: very slowly They started like Moe would have more speaking lines like one by one They would like.
Speaker 0: ah, we need to freshen the show up.
Speaker 0: bring one of the characters in hand him two knives.
Speaker 1: That's how they got so many episodes.
Speaker 1: is that by fleshing out this town and this cast of characters?
Speaker 1: They could start making episodes about different characters, right?
Speaker 1: You know, we got the famous steamed hams, right Chalmers and Skinner.
Speaker 1: it's like though talk about side characters, right Chalmers Right, but everyone knows who that is.
Speaker 1: Yep somehow, you know, but like.
Speaker 1: it's like.
Speaker 0: the reason I love the show so much other than like it was the era when there was television and it was literally the funniest thing on television at the time.
Speaker 0: Cuz like what was he gonna compete with?
Speaker 0: like SNL was never funny, so but basically The show once it came into its own and I didn't recognize This until later when I started actually care and learn about like when writers changed in the show and you can sort of see like patterns The Simpsons did something that sort of revolutionized this kind of comedic television.
Speaker 0: The show was dense with jokes to the point that it made others especially starting like season 3 or 4 especially season 4 To where it made.
Speaker 0: all the other Comedy shows I would watch as a kid just seem slow and plotting and sparse and unfunny as a result Even if you watch something like Seinfeld right, which is you know, less old than The Simpsons, right?
Speaker 1: But all right, which which started and ended in the time The Simpsons is aired.
Speaker 1: Since Seinfeld is kind of slow, right?
Speaker 1: It was fine at the time but if you watch it now It'll be like joke.
Speaker 1: They're like, they'll tell a joke and then like you'll just see Jerry like Standing there looking at someone after he says the funny line.
Speaker 0: Hello the lantern.
Speaker 1: Right, there'll be a there'll be a pause a laugh track and like nothing is happening Right and The Simpsons there is in times where nothing is happening.
Speaker 1: It's like like there's even the density of jokes.
Speaker 0: They'll be like a visual gag Simultaneous to a like a character joke and then there'll be a background joke like all in the span of six seconds.
Speaker 1: Yep, you'll have.
Speaker 1: you know, you have the a pot in a plot B plot, right?
Speaker 1: You know the every episode.
Speaker 1: this the standard formula at least is to intro the episode with this one plot and then that There's a wave in Springfield the pool track has come to town Exactly, then you transfer to the second plot.
Speaker 1: That's really the meat of the episode.
Speaker 1: Homer buys a pool Exactly, but then somehow that our original plot that you started the episode with comes and ties in Probably at the end but not necessarily originally.
Speaker 0: They tie in pretty directly like one would just directly cause the second one.
Speaker 0: But then the show started to do what you're describing where the first plot would kind of go off the second plot would spring up Sort of out of nowhere and then they tie together at the end in a hilarious
Speaker 1: Right, but as you're exploring this main plot or even this either one of the plots, right?
Speaker 1: You're seeing how.
Speaker 1: you know, it goes on over time and you're also seeing how it impacts different characters, right?
Speaker 1: So it's sort of like okay.
Speaker 1: We've got this pool in Homer's backyard.
Speaker 1: What happens with Milhouse in the pool?
Speaker 1: know what happens?
Speaker 1: Right?
Speaker 1: What happens with Bart in the pool?
Speaker 0: episode with Martin Right.
Speaker 1: what happens with Flanders in the pool, right?
Speaker 1: It's like I don't even know if Flanders is in the pool.
Speaker 1: I don't remember how long ago this was but it's like you can get lots and lots of jokes out of that, right?
Speaker 1: It's like okay there, you know, they're doing you know, I'm just making stuff up and remember episodes that do this.
Speaker 1: But it's like, you know, you'll be.
Speaker 1: you know characters might be going from A to B and they might stop in at you know, the racist quickie Mart or somewhere else right and Suddenly you're telling jokes with other character Stop it at Moe's Tavern right for a quick joke and then back out, right?
Speaker 1: You're there got the same setup and you're just hitting Throughout the town or throughout wherever at different angles and different characters, right?
Speaker 1: And even like rim said sometimes in the background, you know, it's like, okay.
Speaker 1: So the main thing going on in Moe's Tavern, right?
Speaker 1: The main joke is Homer and Moe talking about something and Barney's do something in the background To throw in a quick side joke, all right to sort of fill fill the space there.
Speaker 0: And if you're like interviews of that over and over and over again Like during that era when they hit the maximum density of jokes per second Was the era when they were just working themselves to death like the only.
Speaker 0: it's kind of like game design and the game Advance Wars And people would say oh, why is it so hard to make a game like this?
Speaker 0: Like why don't you make more?
Speaker 0: it takes so much effort to make something like that so dense with quality That I don't think that pace was even like reasonably sustainable.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and they were right it so of course, you know The joke came eventually from another long-running show South Park, right like Simpsons did it?
Speaker 1: They've been running so long and not only they've been running so long, but the shows were so dense.
Speaker 1: What could you possibly?
Speaker 1: what story could you tell right that the Simpsons has not already told right?
Speaker 1: They're running out of ideas like geek nights is And not even just the same story.
Speaker 0: you can't use like the same joke multiple times too soon.
Speaker 0: Yep, like seeds feed and seed you can't have that in the background again or a similar joke again for at least a decade.
Speaker 0: Granted that means they can use a joke three times if they follow the decade rule.
Speaker 1: But it's like.
Speaker 1: it's like, you know, the Simpsons is done pretty much everything that can be done.
Speaker 1: how does it still go on?
Speaker 0: Part of it too is that it still makes its blood comes from the stone.
Speaker 0: But like very online people like I can I have a lot more options than watching TV.
Speaker 0: So it was.
Speaker 0: this perfect confluence of TV was the only way to get a lot of like.
Speaker 0: this kind of entertainment at the time coupled with the show was Literally at a peak that had not existed in the world in that format before and then both They couldn't sustain that pace for all the reasons we talked about and The internet literally changed everything and those are the two forces that I think caused the Simpsons to become deeply mediocre.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think even if right these Simpsons had put out the exact same episodes.
Speaker 1: No episodes were changed, right?
Speaker 1: What really I think made it bigger in my life that in the lives of many people than it was and otherwise would have Was that it was syndicated so heavily.
Speaker 0: I'd said I turned on the TV random.
Speaker 1: Sure, there was in in the 90s, right?
Speaker 1: especially Pretty much mid to late 90s when I was watching the most TV right before I went to college and stopped watching TV.
Speaker 1: pretty much Right.
Speaker 1: It wasn't just Simpsons is on Sunday night.
Speaker 1: That was only when the new episodes came on after foot.
Speaker 0: reruns are on every goddamn day and multiple times every single day.
Speaker 1: We would watch right.
Speaker 1: so there would be.
Speaker 1: there'd be.
Speaker 1: we hadn't because we're in Connecticut even at the time when we didn't have cable.
Speaker 1: Okay, no cable, but we're in Connecticut.
Speaker 1: So the antenna picks up Connecticut stations and New York station.
Speaker 1: Oh, so we would have like Fox 5 which was like New York City Fox, right?
Speaker 1: And then we would have like channel 20 some Connecticut Fox Affiliate, you know channel that would.
Speaker 1: that's be where you watch like your Sailor Moon when you came home from school.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right And you could watch at like before dinner, right?
Speaker 1: like matter forget the exact times five five thirty something like that a Simpsons on one and Then the other one would immediately after have another different Simpsons episode.
Speaker 0: Yep, there was.
Speaker 0: there was a good job.
Speaker 0: It was Simpsons.
Speaker 1: Simpsons You could get a full hour of Simpsons before dinner and I think that there were at some points I don't remember.
Speaker 1: it feels like there were times where you could get three Simpsons in a day on broadcast television where I live.
Speaker 0: But also there'd be a new channels at the right time, you know, this is an old time.
Speaker 0: There'd be a new episode every week.
Speaker 0: No one had seen that episode before and literally everyone you knew would watch that episode except the Christian families that wouldn't let their kids Watch it Who would usually try to sneak over someone else's house.
Speaker 0: so like I would go to middle school the next day and literally every single person I knew had also watched that Simpsons episode.
Speaker 0: and And you can't underestimate like if you were in middle or high school with me or with a lot of people our age People were just quoting the Simpsons at each other as like background noise.
Speaker 1: Yep, if it was just like this language right the same way.
Speaker 1: We have a language of memes today, right?
Speaker 0: There was a language of the Simpsons, which is I think is why that was.
Speaker 1: there was no me.
Speaker 1: There were no internet memes.
Speaker 1: We couldn't be like, you know, yo dog, right?
Speaker 0: I put an X in your X and it's noteworthy how the Simpsons are still used as memes say even by people who didn't grow up during that.
Speaker 0: and Most Simpsons memes are from those first like 13 ish seasons for some reason.
Speaker 0: Yeah Some reason yeah.
Speaker 1: But even if you didn't watch it on Sunday night, right that episode that just came out Sunday night would get syndicated within a year or two right and Before DVD box sets you could not afford a all VHS of Simpsons unless you were rich.
Speaker 0: We can't.
Speaker 0: we taped everyone every single everyone but other people didn't.
Speaker 0: So it's not be those tapes and pass them around Sure, but you in that thanks to the syndication.
Speaker 1: I saw every freaking episode.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right You know.
Speaker 1: So and that's everyone you knew was the Simpsons watcher also saw every episode because of that syndication Yep which is so we can all those the Simpsons language together and just assume anyone we were talking to to Had seen most of the Simpsons.
Speaker 0: like that was just a thing.
Speaker 0: I could assume of anyone I talked to in my youth Except like everybody nurse were too Christian and weird about it.
Speaker 1: So now as for the the declining popularity, right?
Speaker 1: It's like I feel having again having not watched any episode.
Speaker 0: I watched a bunch of episodes of like some years ago from like seasons 15 16 17 and they were just like Okay, like they weren't nothing.
Speaker 0: they were okay, like they weren't bad.
Speaker 0: They just weren't that funny Like.
Speaker 0: I will anyway watch them as a primary activity.
Speaker 1: I can't comment on their quality But I think you know There are other reasonable explanations for why the pie player has gone down.
Speaker 1: if it's not capturing a new audience Right if it is still the same audience, there's just attrition Pete, right?
Speaker 1: Not only attrition, but it's like, you know, we're going to see those episodes as you know The the best like.
Speaker 1: that's what you're competing with.
Speaker 1: So, of course, we're gonna rate anything newer as not as good but I have experience like Emily went through this.
Speaker 0: a lot of people I know have gone through this of.
Speaker 0: they'd never seen the Simpsons and we.
Speaker 0: they watched a bunch of it in the current era and I've consistently found when I have shown people the Simpsons that They really really get into it because I usually show them the same seasons that we know like four or five six ish and then they Usually discover that they don't like the later seasons at all.
Speaker 1: Nick it's you know, that's also a reasonable explanation.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right But yeah for you know, how many other things?
Speaker 1: Right are so long running but have this reputation of getting worse, right?
Speaker 1: Usually things jump the shark and then they go away.
Speaker 1: happy days jump the shark and it didn't last too much longer after the shark.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they have like a sharp decline and either a rebound or a class.
Speaker 0: But the Simpsons just like this very very long slow decline.
Speaker 1: It's like no one wants to be the person who ends it.
Speaker 0: It's like well How do you even end a show like that?
Speaker 0: Like what's the last episode?
Speaker 1: you just you just don't.
Speaker 1: why do you have to do?
Speaker 1: A special last episode?
Speaker 1: just be like, okay, you know What was the last episode of the current season of the previous season?
Speaker 1: just like okay no more.
Speaker 0: that's what I would do.
Speaker 0: That's actually what we're there that could delisters were talking about that concept in the chat and that's what I proposed earlier.
Speaker 1: Why do you have to do a Seinfeld style ending?
Speaker 1: people might just hate it anyway.
Speaker 0: You know what I would do bad job with it.
Speaker 0: I would just make the last episode be the Simpsons characters acting out word-for-word with no changes.
Speaker 0: the last episode of mash.
Speaker 1: You could do that too.
Speaker 0: That is what I would do.
Speaker 0: That would be very funny to me.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't know if that would be funny to anyone else, I don't know.
Speaker 0: but I guess before we like the things I liked about the Simpsons the most like when I think back was like specifically Principal Skinner was the funniest character in the entire show and I will die on that hill.
Speaker 1: Okay, sure.
Speaker 0: I think the best the best humor came out of like the spaces around principal Skinner.
Speaker 1: Okay But he's not my favorite guy Because he's like.
Speaker 0: he's not funny.
Speaker 0: It's everything around him becomes becomes funny as a result of his like extreme non funniness, which itself is funny.
Speaker 0: Okay, I don't know like.
Speaker 0: what would you point to?
Speaker 0: is the parts of the Simpsons you particularly enjoy?
Speaker 1: it's weird Did like I know.
Speaker 1: actually I can't think of like a part as like which part of the Simpsons is funnier, right?
Speaker 1: It's like it's.
Speaker 1: I don't know if there is a part that's funnier.
Speaker 1: I guess there are parts that are less funny.
Speaker 1: Right, like.
Speaker 1: I didn't really care about Marge's sisters that much.
Speaker 1: They were sort of annoying, right?
Speaker 1: I wasn't you know, I was like, uh, really?
Speaker 1: Okay, you know, but I Don't know.
Speaker 1: It's just like it didn't really.
Speaker 1: I think what it is is like, you know, like I was talking about.
Speaker 1: You know the side characters in Adventure Time, right?
Speaker 1: The Simpsons is nothing but side characters And you're sort of you're getting them all the time all over the place Like any episode is giving you a huge pile of them now.
Speaker 0: You're thinking of a guy with two knives.
Speaker 0: Right, that's actually relatively later season too.
Speaker 1: And some of them are even you know More brief right like, you know seed bell guy.
Speaker 1: Right You know, it's like he appears so like.
Speaker 1: what's that guy's name?
Speaker 0: I forget What are you talking about?
Speaker 1: I was chatting with the guy with this the guy with the seed bell.
Speaker 0: Oh Hans moldman Hans moment.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like Significant.
Speaker 0: you just not have complete encyclopedic perfect memory of the first 11 seasons of The Simpsons like I do.
Speaker 1: Complete encyclopedic memory of a show.
Speaker 1: I haven't watched in 20 years.
Speaker 0: They're just burned into my brain because I watched them on loop as a kid.
Speaker 1: I mean a lot of them are burned into my brain, but you know, it's like Yeah Not gonna remember if we're gonna Hans moment's name at the job of a hat here.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I guess that the real test I've noticed is that if I go watch cuz I tried this a while ago, too I just went and picked clip like.
Speaker 0: I typed episode numbers of The Simpsons and watch clips and The old episode clips like just almost make me want to watch that episode again, even though I literally know it by heart.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm and other things that I've loved in my childhood do not do that same thing to me as an adult.
Speaker 0: The Simpsons is one of the rare things.
Speaker 0: It's gonna talk about this as something that can trap you if it's on a TV Like.
Speaker 0: you're not thinking about Star Wars.
Speaker 0: You walk by a TV like you're visiting your parents and Star Wars is on TV You.
Speaker 0: just next thing, you know credits are rolling and you just sat there.
Speaker 0: How did that happen?
Speaker 1: Yeah, a tape of Simpsons with no ads or breaks of any kind can definitely just trap a person there Watching it right at least if it's good episodes and such for however long, right weird I'll listen.
Speaker 0: or tried to tell you it was Hans moment before I Corrected you or I pointed it out and it was blocked and flagged as a possibly inappropriate comment.
Speaker 1: for some reason Hans moment is a inappropriate comment.
Speaker 0: I YouTube.
Speaker 1: Maybe there's some.
Speaker 1: maybe there's something we don't know.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 1: Maybe it's in another language.
Speaker 1: I don't know Hans moment.
Speaker 1: I'm sorry, if I if Hans moment means something that I don't know Clearly I'm clueless.
Speaker 1: Please inform me.
Speaker 0: so I don't you know, well, I did click the button to let it appear in our YouTube stream.
Speaker 1: So, oh, well, I hope that wasn't a mistake.
Speaker 0: but Yeah, the Simpsons I think at this point it's almost funnier to just see how long they can keep it going.
Speaker 0: But I don't want to watch any episodes of it.
Speaker 0: I just want to see like if it hits if it if the Simpsons out lives me That is legendary Started watching it basically like if it outlives me.
Speaker 0: it has been such a big part of my life, right?
Speaker 1: I mean assuming that I live as long as I would like right if it outlives me.
Speaker 1: Considering the people making it were adults when I was a child.
Speaker 1: They're likely.
Speaker 0: that means That everyone.
Speaker 1: it will be very likely that the people who are making it Right, we're not alive we are younger than the thing they're making right.
Speaker 1: like nobody who works on this It would have been alive when the first episode of the Simpsons air.
Speaker 0: if the venture brothers doesn't get canceled Like if it gets picked up, I feel like that'll be true of that because it takes them so long to make a season But has way way less seasons.
Speaker 0: it does sound like seven.
Speaker 0: it's taken them how long Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: but yeah, if you've know if you've somehow never watched the Simpsons like just Started like season four or five and just watch a bunch of episodes.
Speaker 0: You'll see what we mean.
Speaker 0: I think you'll find it is nice that it's not.
Speaker 1: you know There's so many things these days.
Speaker 1: are cereal?
Speaker 1: cereals are all the hotness.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but you don't watch any Simpsons anything about the Simpsons literally nothing Like.
Speaker 0: just just pick a random episode between seasons four and eight and you pretty much can't go wrong.
Speaker 0: Unless I'm looking to this chart Season six episode three is the only early season episode to have a very low rating.
Speaker 1: I think that would be like a clip.
Speaker 0: that's a clip show I think and that low rating is still higher than many of the ratings from later.
Speaker 1: So cuz they're good clips.
Speaker 1: Yeah Good clips.
Speaker 0: Oh wait.
Speaker 0: No season nine episode 11.
Speaker 0: That's the lowest one.
Speaker 0: What the fuck was that episode?
Speaker 0: I want to look that up before we stop the show.
Speaker 0: season 9 episode 11.
Speaker 1: Yeah rim found a JPEG that is like, you know average ratings by like, you know, I am DB people so people who care enough about the Simpsons to rate episodes and average their ratings together per episode and then put them in a Visualization by season.
Speaker 0: so you can see not episode 12 episode.
Speaker 0: Come on.
Speaker 0: It's telly's keep point.
Speaker 0: Oh, here we go Here we go.
Speaker 0: I want to know what this episode was.
Speaker 0: Yeah clip show Highlighting the musical bow.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it was just a clip show.
Speaker 1: Yeah But yeah, the Simpsons in by going so long they had to do every, you know, they've done everything.
Speaker 1: But that means they had to do everything right?
Speaker 1: They did musicals Sentimental parts mystery plots, right?
Speaker 1: It's like sci-fi Lots of horror.
Speaker 0: we didn't even talk about who shot mr.
Speaker 0: Burns, which was like a legit cultural event in America.
Speaker 0: Yep, like you people people talked about that like it was real Like until we found out who shot mr Burns like you don't understand.
Speaker 0: you could not avoid that conversation anywhere.
Speaker 0: Everyone had a theory.
Speaker 1: No, it was.
Speaker 1: it was pride.
Speaker 1: That was probably maybe the pink Simpsons moment, right?
Speaker 1: I don't think Simpsons ever been bigger.
Speaker 0: in the comments that itself was just parodying who shot jr of course Which is the last thing I'll leave you with.
Speaker 0: I have found that one thing that has been consistent in my life since about 2008 is that I run into a lot of people who will Notice a reference in a more current thing and say oh that's a reference to the Simpsons and have no idea That it is actually a reference to like treasure of the Sierra Madre.
Speaker 0: Yep, like the Simpsons became like because the Simpsons parodied and referenced so many things that it becomes the the nexus point Of references and people don't try to look earlier than it.
Speaker 0: They just assume it came from the Simpsons.
Speaker 1: If I tell a joke someone else told and I don't immediately say that is so-and-so's joke if this is anyone but And then you laugh at it and then you'd be.
Speaker 1: and then now that in your brain is a Scott joke Even though I stole it from someone else.
Speaker 1: That's just how you know, how are you?
Speaker 1: How are you to know unless someone points it out to you?
Speaker 1: Yeah, so How many people just quote Star Wars and nobody's gives it a shit about hidden fortress?
Speaker 0: Yeah This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at front row crew comm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 0: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 0: But unlike those other late shows it's actually recorded at night and the patreon patrons for this episode of geek nights are Alan Joyce, how do you make a link?
Speaker 0: eg dread Lily Tenebrae Chris Reimer Clinton Walton Graham Finch just like a dude guy.
Speaker 0: Now go through the last year or so a podcast and make rim sing.
Speaker 0: Ren from New Zealand review mad bull 34 cowards Ryan Perrin Sam Erickson Shervin Von Hurl Taylor Braun.
Speaker 0: you hold the key to my heart and a bunch of people who do not want me to say their names.
Speaker 0: Try if you live in New York, remember try to get a shot.
Speaker 0: Looks like appointments are opening up bit by bit.
Speaker 0: I got mine on Saturday.
Speaker 0: So hopefully we'll all join the world of the vaccinated and for now I leave you with Hello, my name is mr.
Speaker 1: Burns.
Speaker 1: I believe you have a letter for me.
Speaker 0: Okay, mr.
Speaker 0: Burns.
Speaker 0: What's your first name?
Speaker 1: I Don't know.
Speaker 1: I'm a stupid moron with an ugly face and a big butt.
Speaker 1: I like to kiss my own butt.
Speaker 1: Oh by the way, I was being sarcastic.
Speaker 1: Well, duh who'da thought Darth Vader was Luke Skywalker's father?
Speaker 1: Mr.
Speaker 1: Blow the picture for me.
Speaker 0: I don't want any damn vegetables.
Speaker 1: Maybe it's severe talking March, but you got a butt that won't quit.
Speaker 1: They got these big chewy pretzels here.
Speaker 1: They're all you guys with a beard.
Speaker 1: No five dollars.
Speaker 1: Get out of here Elder.
Speaker 0: Mattingly, I thought I told you to trim those sideburns.
Speaker 1: You didn't learn how to end it.
Speaker 0: We won Mr.
Speaker 1: Black, I'm just a big toasty cinnamon bun and he left them and went out of the city into Bethany and he lodged there.
Speaker 1: Yeah Think about it.
Speaker 1: Everyone is stupid except me.
Speaker 0: take this object.
Speaker 0: But beware it carries a terrible curse.
Speaker 0: Whoo, that's bad, but it comes with a free fro get.
Speaker 0: that's good.
Speaker 0: The fro get is also cursed.
Speaker 0: That's bad, but you get your choice of topping.
Speaker 0: That's good.
Speaker 0: The toppings contain potassium benzoate.
Speaker 0: That's bad, can I go now?
Speaker 0: Yep is your problem?
Speaker 0: someone said this thing to evil.
Speaker 1: Did you wreck the car?
Speaker 1: No, did you raise the dead?
Speaker 1: Yes, but the car is okay.
Speaker 0: All right, then, you know that dream where you're in bed and they fly in through the window My shirts chafing me mind if I take it off put it in age.
Speaker 1: Do you come with the car?
Speaker 1: Oh You're West.
Speaker 1: Oh, mr.
Speaker 1: Plow.
Speaker 1: That's my name.
Speaker 1: That name again is mr.
Speaker 1: Plow.