Speaker 1: It's Tuesday, July 13th, 2021.
Speaker 1: I'm rim.
Speaker 1: I'm Scott and this is geek nights.
Speaker 1: tonight We're talking about collecting in games and probably not the kind of collecting you're thinking about.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: Moderately.
Speaker 1: sad weekend Emily and I had to travel back out to Leroy for death in the family.
Speaker 1: Her uncle passed away sadly.
Speaker 1: I'll post a link to the obituary just to spread the little bit of his life.
Speaker 1: That is interesting to strangers But I was surprised that you were surprised.
Speaker 0: you went so soon because you know, they weren't Jewish, right?
Speaker 1: So well, we didn't go out for the funeral.
Speaker 1: we went out just to be with the family and help everyone sort of get through it because it was it was sudden and Pretty much unexpected like this was a situation like that.
Speaker 1: But I'm not gonna depress you with all the details here.
Speaker 1: You can just y'all thought link to the obituary.
Speaker 1: but on the way there as you know, we have a car.
Speaker 1: It's an old car.
Speaker 1: It's like an old Chevy Cruze and that's the best way.
Speaker 1: and kovat even in these sort of waning kovat times Hopefully waiting to get out to a now.
Speaker 0: No now they're waxing in some placing right now.
Speaker 0: So it's a New York.
Speaker 0: It is waxing.
Speaker 1: It's it's well depends.
Speaker 1: It's waxing in some neighborhoods and continuing to wane in other neighborhoods.
Speaker 1: I've read the recent data.
Speaker 0: Well, the graph is going up.
Speaker 0: That's not good.
Speaker 1: I'm still avoiding things like flying or mastering like big mass transit if I can.
Speaker 1: so we drove out there And I did recently because it's an old car go to the local pep boys because they were the only place anywhere nearby that'll take online appointments.
Speaker 1: and like I could do everything about talking to a human and I got a brake job had him replace the front rotors, you know car crap the kind of stuff I haven't had to deal with in a long time.
Speaker 0: So good not having a car.
Speaker 0: so good so good when a car doesn't have you right.
Speaker 1: Oh, I had what Josh Newman actually was tweeting about the car game recently.
Speaker 1: But we're on.
Speaker 1: cars is escalating.
Speaker 1: So I got his brake job and This is gonna be the first big trip of taken since I got the brake job and we're driving And the brakes go the brakes cut out.
Speaker 1: Ah, so as soon as we are in the middle of fuck-all-nowhere, Pennsylvania Cuz we're taking the angle way up instead of the like through.
Speaker 1: well the angle way because the angle way saves like 45 minutes of driving But a little bit.
Speaker 1: yeah, it goes through like Scranton and like middle-of-nowhere.
Speaker 0: Check you don't get all those rest stops and whatnot.
Speaker 0: if you go the angle Yeah, something like huh check engine you miss some tolls.
Speaker 0: going the angle way is less told it is.
Speaker 1: So check engine light like nothing's wrong with the car like I saw I feel like okay coming up like next time I stopped to get gas.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna check out this check engine light and deal with it later Because in RIT I drove a car with the check engine light for like three years because I couldn't afford even check.
Speaker 0: Yeah, cuz well cuz check engine light, you know, it could be in without connecting the computer thing You know to get the actual readout, right?
Speaker 0: It's like it could be fucking anything They don't see have.
Speaker 0: all errors are hooked up to one light and it's just like error And there's only two states of that light in most cars.
Speaker 1: if it turns on it means anything and if it flashes it Which almost no one has ever something bad flashing means turn the car off right now Like pull over immediately and maybe exit the vehicle.
Speaker 1: It might.
Speaker 0: I've never seen that in my life ever.
Speaker 1: I saw it once.
Speaker 1: you know what I saw it on a car where the engine had just exploded.
Speaker 1: Literally, I started the car the engine exploded like the hood dented and everything.
Speaker 1: And then the check-in engine light just started flashing and I was like, thanks.
Speaker 1: Thanks for that.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Thanks.
Speaker 0: There's no engine anymore.
Speaker 0: I'll check that engine.
Speaker 0: So, uh, none of it.
Speaker 1: I'm not too long Later, this car starts are running a little rough like shuttering.
Speaker 1: So now I'm like well so pull off immediately the next exit and We pull into the first mechanic.
Speaker 1: we could find cuz I got to get her to a mechanic because I don't want to turn it Off and we get to a mechanic and stop the car.
Speaker 1: I get out and the guys like oh we're full up I'm going done for the day.
Speaker 1: So I'm like, yeah, so I open the hood and he starts looking at the hood like looking inside.
Speaker 1: He's like, how'd you check your oil?
Speaker 1: Looks I see a little smoke.
Speaker 1: Maybe something's going on and the whole time he's talking I can see very clearly That smoke is coming off of the left front caliper on the brakes Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: long story short the brakes burn themselves out because they that brake just seized Full on while we were driving but because the cigar was going fast enough.
Speaker 1: The engine just overpowered it and Just ran the brake seized until eventually it overheated and broke completely.
Speaker 1: I go to the next mechanic who's open who normally doesn't work on you American cars.
Speaker 1: It's like this guy who only focuses.
Speaker 1: it's like a euro sports plays.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I've seen those ones.
Speaker 1: But the guy's like oh god I'll help you out.
Speaker 1: and he looks at the brake and he's like whoever did your brakes?
Speaker 1: Fucked him up like baby's first brake job.
Speaker 1: So, uh, he fixed it for me.
Speaker 0: So you get her going as we get for going up head boy.
Speaker 1: Yeah didn't even charge me that much.
Speaker 1: but he was like he gave me the rotor and he was like Drop this on the desk of whoever you're gonna go sue over that.
Speaker 0: They pay for the new brake job I got and my end is usually all service, you know has like a warranty.
Speaker 0: So you're just gonna get the warrant apply for the warranty for the service and they give you the money back that you spent on.
Speaker 1: But the emergency repair I had to get to deal with this problem.
Speaker 0: Yeah Yeah, that's probably included in the warranty on the service from the other, you know from the pet boys.
Speaker 0: You don't need to sue them unless they did not they don't want to you know.
Speaker 1: No, no, they all honor the warrant.
Speaker 0: if they if they honor the warranty and pay for all this then yeah I would say even if they do honor the warranty you just go to a small claim court.
Speaker 0: That's a small claim?
Speaker 1: Oh, that's definitely a small claim.
Speaker 0: That's just like a textbook small claim.
Speaker 0: and you walk in there You just plop the.
Speaker 0: do you plop the rotor down in the judge's desk be like, so here's where the story gets interesting.
Speaker 1: That check engine light was unrelated to this problem.
Speaker 1: So he clears the codes and he's like, oh yeah, it's like a p290 like under boost.
Speaker 1: He's like, it's not a problem.
Speaker 1: So I cleared it and he started again.
Speaker 1: It didn't come back, but that didn't make any sense.
Speaker 1: There's no turbo in that car.
Speaker 1: What the fuck does under boost mean for a car without a turbo or a super?
Speaker 0: Maybe they messed with your computer at the pet boys.
Speaker 1: Uh, maybe cuz that pet boys remember was the place where the fart car conversation was happening.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so These cut the air check engine light comes on.
Speaker 1: so now I'm in a town so like a couple days later I just go to like a local Auto Zone because they have pretty much any place.
Speaker 1: We'll read those codes and tell you what this is.
Speaker 0: your problem is You're always going to like, you know these, you know, notice how you went to a pet boy, right?
Speaker 0: Not good Then you went to just some guy out in the middle of nowhere and it was good right.
Speaker 0: then now you're going to an auto zone.
Speaker 0: lesson.
Speaker 0: Go always go to just some shady guy for the car biz.
Speaker 0: don't Brand places.
Speaker 1: you only go to an auto zone to get him to pull the codes.
Speaker 0: That's like going it.
Speaker 0: would you go to Best Buy for computer biz?
Speaker 0: No, so you shouldn't be going to Auto Zone, right?
Speaker 0: You got.
Speaker 1: if you go to go to some guy Problem is some guy is so when we got to the Eurosport place I was because he was like, oh, I don't normally work at cars.
Speaker 1: I was like, oh is there anyone else within like I don't know 50 miles that you would recommend?
Speaker 1: and he says no every mechanic In within a hundred miles of this location is bullshit.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you got to go to some guy who doesn't suck.
Speaker 0: it's not saying all the some guys are good I'm saying all the Nate the brand Wrong.
Speaker 1: I did not go to this Auto Zone to get car repairs.
Speaker 1: I went because they will pull the codes for free and tell me what they are.
Speaker 1: Give me a printout.
Speaker 1: That's it.
Speaker 1: I went there they pull the codes and it looks like the o2 sensors are just like Dying because it's.
Speaker 0: no that's the most cause like the most common thing 100% unrelated to the brakes caught fire.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: So yeah, that was my car adventures.
Speaker 0: Okay, that's I'm glad not to have a car.
Speaker 0: my I got a story that's also car related.
Speaker 0: I was not I was not in the car.
Speaker 1: I'm excited about this because this is one of those races where you all you said before the show was This would have been a situation where rim being around would have been useful.
Speaker 0: It would have been very useful.
Speaker 0: So I'm biking yesterday in a city bike to the dentist, right?
Speaker 0: Well, I just made a dentist appointment now that it's time Delayed my previous dentist - until Yesterday, so I went yesterday to Manhattan, right?
Speaker 0: and I'm city biking over right and going down Crescent and Across across in the street little intersection and there's all the.
Speaker 0: it's pretty early in the morning cuz my dentist appointments at 10 a.m.
Speaker 0: So it's 9 something, you know.
Speaker 0: The cars are backed up trying to get on the bridge on Crescent like they are usually right
Speaker 1: now
Speaker 0: And some car, you know comes in from the left side and he's you know, trying to you know, wedge himself into the You know to the to the line of traffic that is solid and barely moving And he turns a little too sharply, right?
Speaker 0: So like there's the bollards on the the bike lane, right?
Speaker 0: So he's a little like his.
Speaker 0: his left headlight is a little bit to the inside.
Speaker 0: So, you know, he's got a he's gonna have to back up a little bit right to get back into the.
Speaker 0: you know Around the other side, right, you know, and I'm like, okay, I just keep going and you know I'm on my way to the about like a block north of like, you know, the Queen's Plaza there And I look behind me and I see that that car Right rather than try to wedge into the traffic has decided you just slowly drive down the bike.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I could.
Speaker 1: I can see why cuz I'm the one who would be like pulling the license plate off the back Chasing banging on his head so not seeing anything around I just stop and turn my bike sideways.
Speaker 0: don't move bro.
Speaker 1: And it's a city bike.
Speaker 1: What's he gonna do?
Speaker 1: destroy his car?
Speaker 0: I'm just.
Speaker 0: I'm just sitting there right.
Speaker 1: and there's those of you who don't live in New York.
Speaker 1: These city bikes are bike rentals like from docks.
Speaker 1: They weigh 55 pounds.
Speaker 1: They're made of solid steel.
Speaker 0: So I just I just stop.
Speaker 0: I'm like what am I gonna?
Speaker 0: I got nowhere to be.
Speaker 0: I got other the dentist, right?
Speaker 1: You know, that's that's a remove right there.
Speaker 1: That's like the pro move.
Speaker 1: Don't don't aggressively confront just.
Speaker 0: I didn't say I didn't even say anything.
Speaker 0: I just basically, you know, just sat there.
Speaker 0: I'm just.
Speaker 0: I'm just sitting there in the bike lane does not do with nothing, right?
Speaker 0: He starts yelling and cursing and threatening or whatever and I'm like, okay hit me and go to jail.
Speaker 0: It's it's like not my problem, right?
Speaker 1: See the only thing is you gotta be standing there holding.
Speaker 0: knock my teeth out.
Speaker 0: I'm going to the dentist.
Speaker 0: Anyway, you gotta be holding your phone like obviously recording him.
Speaker 0: I didn't I didn't.
Speaker 0: you know, I don't have the phone record instinct, but you know If the incident if the incident would have lasted longer then that would have come to that point.
Speaker 1: But it was less than like a minute long incident because I got that guy who tried to punch me to back off.
Speaker 1: I didn't even record him.
Speaker 1: I just held my phone up like I was recording him and I pretended I was calling the cops on speakerphone.
Speaker 1: That was anyway, I didn't do anything.
Speaker 0: No, I would.
Speaker 0: it would have gotten to that if I it had lasted more than a few more seconds, right?
Speaker 0: You know, it's like if the guy shoots me dead, it's like well, I guess that's how I die.
Speaker 0: Okay If he runs me over, okay, I guess that's good luck getting over that city bike to get to you.
Speaker 0: it's you know.
Speaker 0: He clearly was you know a person with a lot of anger issues and no regard for the law or other human beings But his car wasn't farting Although it definitely looked like a car that you know was was cared for like whoever's driving it cared about, you know The car being shiny or whatever, you know You know, it's just generic cursing coming out of him.
Speaker 0: You know, you know get out of the way and whatever.
Speaker 0: But yeah, I just don't move and after a few seconds he backs up a little bit right and I'm just like I'm just waiting for him to go back into the traffic, you know and give up and then I'll be on my way.
Speaker 0: He just goes right on the sidewalk Because then there's consequences for someone like that Maybe.
Speaker 0: but uh, you know, I couldn't exactly do anything about that.
Speaker 0: I'm just like well He just drives down.
Speaker 0: they just got it.
Speaker 0: You know there was someone biking a city bike in the opposite like towards him and they could have blocked the sidewalk if they wanted to but They chose not to.
Speaker 0: Wasn't gonna be like?
Speaker 0: hey other random person had never met.
Speaker 0: I demand you also put your life at risk.
Speaker 1: But if I had been they fed him in me.
Speaker 1: come in the opposite direction, you know exactly you would have blocked that sidewalk.
Speaker 0: No, probably no hesitation.
Speaker 1: My phone would have somehow a bit in my hand before you even blinked.
Speaker 0: Yeah, exactly anyway, but yeah, so he went down the sidewalk and got around me and that was that before I. you know if he would have it would have lasted a little longer.
Speaker 0: there would have been some phone action, but You know just went down the sidewalk and then rather than go into the traffic, you know He basically made a left and probably was gonna go down.
Speaker 0: You know make a right towards, you know Queens Plaza and then come at it from the other direction right the way the buses come.
Speaker 0: Yep, so it's like.
Speaker 0: okay, you know, I guess I can't stop you angry guy But there's been a lot of gas-powered vehicle incursions into bike lanes lately.
Speaker 1: Queensboro like the Queens Bridge like 59th Street Bridge I see I get passed by multiple full-on motorcycles regularly like into work now.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I feel like the solution.
Speaker 0: right, you know I try to think like different solutions that aren't like, you know cops or anything, right?
Speaker 0: you know cuz it's like and You know, it's.
Speaker 0: this solution is also obviously very problematic in well extremely problematic But I kind of like it the best because all the solutions are problematic right ones that physically disable or block the car.
Speaker 0: No, no.
Speaker 0: No, I think what we should do is the rule should be that if you video it, right?
Speaker 0: So you prove that you're not just you know, do it, you know being you know a nut job, right?
Speaker 0: That if there's like a car in the bike lane or even just an illegally parked car Right and you have video proving that this car is illegally parked right and that they're breaking the law That you know tickets no courts.
Speaker 0: No, you don't need any of that shit.
Speaker 0: It's just legally open season on the car You can.
Speaker 1: I was I was waiting for the Scott moment in that idea.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's just legally open season.
Speaker 0: If you prove that, you know, this is really somebody who is misbehaving.
Speaker 0: It's like we don't need to ticket them We don't need to do any.
Speaker 0: no no bother with any of that stuff.
Speaker 0: Just you can smash and scratch the fuck out of that car with.
Speaker 0: you can't hurt me body, right?
Speaker 0: So you can't like smash the windshield that someone's in the car, right?
Speaker 0: But if there's no one in the car smash away.
Speaker 0: It's like, you know, you want to steal the catalytic converter from the car and sell it.
Speaker 0: Go the right the fuck.
Speaker 1: imagine the ads like you submit the video and GPS and all that and then an attendant Gives you the go no-go on.
Speaker 1: Can you attack this vehicle?
Speaker 0: Yeah, right exactly.
Speaker 0: And you know what it's like that would actually achieve.
Speaker 0: Well, it would achieve the desired goal I think better than any of the other options which is people with cars would be.
Speaker 0: would not fuck around right?
Speaker 0: It's like a ticket doesn't scare you from stopping speeding or illegal parking, right?
Speaker 0: You know even getting you know arrested or license points like none of those things are actually a deterrent.
Speaker 0: All I'm picturing here is if it was legal to smash the fuck out of a car, right?
Speaker 0: You wouldn't have to worry about people smashing the fuck out of cars because nobody would park illegally even once.
Speaker 0: Right because there's be people with like, you know crowbars just wandering like.
Speaker 0: please please please please.
Speaker 0: I really want to smash I really want to get my Street Fighter 2 bonus stage Right and it's like.
Speaker 0: no you would not see a double parking for even one second because everyone with a car would be Terrified that that would be the end of their car And that would achieve it's like.
Speaker 0: you don't need to worry about the vigilante justice Aspect because it would never happen.
Speaker 0: you would get the deterrent effect that you really want which is every car obeys the law Perfectly at all times.
Speaker 0: Well, this is why you had a car if you were driving, right?
Speaker 0: And that was the.
Speaker 0: that was the case that there was truly open season on cars.
Speaker 0: Would you even dare to even like go past a stop sign for like, you know a little bit, right?
Speaker 1: Well, the only thing I would do not me but like the the I don't know the royal we the person who's out there The Cartman of the crowbar
Speaker 0: you'd be the crowbar guy
Speaker 1: There's the person who would steal someone else's car that they disliked and park it somewhere illegally and leave it That way.
Speaker 1: they don't get caught with a stolen car and a bunch of bystanders destroy that car.
Speaker 0: But if you see it stealing the car would still be the crime.
Speaker 0: I mean, that's still obviously the crime Getting caught getting caught stealing a car would still be the same consequences now.
Speaker 0: So nothing would change in terms of Grand Theft Auto, right?
Speaker 0: So I mean that after the Grand Theft Auto the car was disposed of.
Speaker 1: So anyway the purge of cars aside in the news we didn't do some.
Speaker 1: Tuesday.
Speaker 1: Tuesday's are the shows we missed least often But a bunch of stuff happens.
Speaker 0: They're the easiest to do.
Speaker 1: So, uh, there's a bunch of gaming news we didn't talk about.
Speaker 1: but instead of doing a gaming news roundup, we're just gonna talk about a couple things that are particularly notable.
Speaker 1: and the main thing I want to talk about is the announcement that advance Wars 1 and advance Wars 2 are getting a Reboot like remake on the Nintendo switch.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: These are the two GBA advance Wars's right?
Speaker 0: They're gonna combine them into a single game.
Speaker 0: You're gonna get it on your switch so you can be able to play at 1080p Portable, you know and you're in your dock or 720p portably confirmed.
Speaker 0: There is some amount of online play with presumably Nintendo online subscription required of some amount.
Speaker 0: I imagine it'll just be play the multiplayer mode with randos or friend codes or who knows what right now.
Speaker 1: Finally, I can prove how fucking amazing I am at these games.
Speaker 0: But yeah, it's just gonna be no at all indications.
Speaker 0: all the information We have sovara suggests is just gonna be advanced wars like nothing really other than the online play and the increased resolution and graphics.
Speaker 0: It's just gonna be those two games same missions same maps same everything.
Speaker 0: Yeah Yeah, well, the only thing I'm annoyed about is those two games and you don't want to you know Do the online part.
Speaker 0: you don't really need to buy this.
Speaker 1: Yep, I'm gonna buy it one because I want to review it and like go deep on it and see what else they do Do.
Speaker 1: I do want to play online.
Speaker 1: and three I do want to stream the hell out of these games And I'd rather to stream whatever's on the switch instead of like my.
Speaker 0: streaming from a switch is a lot easier than streaming from a GBA or GBA emulator.
Speaker 1: exactly I think.
Speaker 0: I think the the preferred way to stream from GBA is to get a GameCube with a Game Boy player underneath.
Speaker 0: Yeah, then use that.
Speaker 1: I do have a good Emulator that I use to stream DS games.
Speaker 1: That's what I've been using for advanced wars days of ruin.
Speaker 0: But that DS I have the DS emulator.
Speaker 0: It's like cuz you don't get the touchscreen biz, right?
Speaker 0: It's like it's not.
Speaker 1: Oh, no, it's only good for advanced wars where you would never use a touchscreen.
Speaker 1: That's true, yeah, yeah, you know what.
Speaker 1: I have two ROMs advanced wars DS and advanced wars dr.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but so yeah the notable part about this is one I talked I've talked a lot in the old days like if any only notable part is that Nintendo has not Forgotten that advanced wars exists.
Speaker 1: Yes, because advanced wars I would argue there are like.
Speaker 1: it is almost alone in a genre in terms of quality.
Speaker 1: No game that is like this.
Speaker 1: in terms of turn-based military units fighting on a grid.
Speaker 1: no game in the Nintendo ecosystem and arguably much of the rest of the world's ecosystem even comes close to the level of Polish of the game mechanics of advanced wars, especially advanced wars 2 and advanced wars.
Speaker 1: days of ruin.
Speaker 1: and The reason these games are so phenomenal in my opinion is the same reason chrono trigger was so phenomenal.
Speaker 1: It cost way too much to make them.
Speaker 1: It took way too many people way too much effort and there's no way to make money.
Speaker 0: making games like that anymore Was really caused that it was that hard.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 1: We talked about this on geek nights.
Speaker 1: There was even an article about it when they revealed how many people were involved in the level design of the advanced wars games Mm-hmm, how many hours they spent.
Speaker 1: I got dig up.
Speaker 1: we talked about this like seven eight years ago.
Speaker 0: Okay, that's why I don't remember.
Speaker 1: But the thing that's also interesting is that advanced wars days of ruin the last game the one I'm actually streaming is The most fair one.
Speaker 1: It's the fairest.
Speaker 1: It's the most balanced.
Speaker 1: It's the best like ortho game competition between humans.
Speaker 1: Advanced wars 1 & 2 are way more fun But they are not balanced.
Speaker 1: and the thing I'm really curious to see is if there is any Thought to how to balance the CEOs in online play or if they don't balance them Because you could just pick the overpowered CEOs and always win or everyone will play the same few S-tier CEOs and there's a lot of cheap nonsense.
Speaker 1: like the games are more about the puzzle I mean, that's not different.
Speaker 0: That's not any different from fighting games that aren't balanced.
Speaker 0: Right, you know, it's it's like if you're playing competitive advanced wars.
Speaker 0: They're either a going to be banning right Sturm or whoever Sturm and hot year the ones I think you'd have to ban.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right.
Speaker 0: You're either putting in bands.
Speaker 1: Maybe let Mel play.
Speaker 1: This is not actually that good Right.
Speaker 0: or people are only playing the s-tier ones and the other ones aren't viable in competitive play.
Speaker 1: There's different leagues like there's the like main three CEOs only league or something.
Speaker 0: I think they're you know, just there's also the other option of Fox only final destination.
Speaker 0: No, CEO power, right?
Speaker 1: It's like just like advance, but that's kind of what days of ruin is Which is just.
Speaker 0: it's also days a little bit of CEO power, but they're much weaker.
Speaker 1: Well, yeah They're also much more balanced and fair.
Speaker 1: But the other thing is the DS one.
Speaker 0: They're way OP with the double power God and that source DS is Broke, I'll use a little Eagle and a Sammy.
Speaker 1: Eagle and Sammy combined is like a one one turn One action KO.
Speaker 0: my infantry my infantry can see like a blurry Mirage of your HQ.
Speaker 0: I win.
Speaker 1: Yep Yes, it's just unbalanceable fun nonsense.
Speaker 1: So I will see how this all goes.
Speaker 1: I'm pretty excited about this just because advanced wars was kind of forgotten Except among weirdos like me.
Speaker 1: and now that community is so excited that I found all the advanced wars streamers Everyone came out of the woodwork.
Speaker 1: I even started streaming advanced wars again.
Speaker 1: okay, in some other news Nintendo announced these Nintendo switch Pro and fanboys egged on by the less well-written Less well-curated gaming media had this idea in their head that this was gonna be a more powerful switch for some reason or a 4k.
Speaker 0: me if you look his Nintendo has a history right of going back to you know way in the olden days right super olden days the NES.
Speaker 0: They made a top loading NES.
Speaker 0: right the SNES they made there's like a better SNES model.
Speaker 0: That's like different.
Speaker 0: that looks sort of like a top loading NES.
Speaker 0: if you've never seen it It's.
Speaker 0: there's not a lot of them.
Speaker 0: I've you know, I don't see them often but they exist.
Speaker 0: There is.
Speaker 0: there was the Game Boy.
Speaker 1: then there was the Game Boy Pocket Game Boy Pocket Game Boy Color.
Speaker 0: The Game Boy Pocket was just a lot better.
Speaker 0: There's a Game Boy Color.
Speaker 0: remember the Game Boys Game Boy Advance the Game Boy Advance.
Speaker 0: There was a Game Boy Advance SP and then a Game Boy Advance micro.
Speaker 0: It's like they upgraded that shit twice.
Speaker 0: Oh, you know the DS there was DS lite.
Speaker 0: Yes Yeah, it's like Nintendo has a history of re-releasing consoles in Superior versions that are upgraded and with the 3ds.
Speaker 0: Right the 3ds could be considered one of those but also sort of a new console, right?
Speaker 0: But with the 3ds they tried something that they hadn't done before Which is they made the three the new 3ds which actually was a like a better processor, right?
Speaker 0: And There were games that would only play on 3ds.
Speaker 0: It would not play on regular DS and that did not do very well.
Speaker 0: It was a very small number of games.
Speaker 0: none of them were really significant.
Speaker 1: better when they did it more like the Game Boy Color where Some games would have a little bit of extra fun stuff or look different if you played it.
Speaker 0: Well the Game Boy Color.
Speaker 0: there were Game Boy Color exclusive games.
Speaker 0: But there were also these sort of DX cartridges and they like re-released like Link's awakening on a DX cartridge For example and Metroid 2 on the DX cartridge that added that there's.
Speaker 1: that adds that skeleton puzzle.
Speaker 0: Yeah, those exactly yeah those cartridges could play in an old-school Game Boy or pocket and they would just be normal.
Speaker 0: But if they played him on a Game Boy Color.
Speaker 0: They would be fancier than if you took the original Game Boy cartridge and put in a Game Boy Color.
Speaker 1: But generally you can't release an iteration on an existing console where now there's a bunch of games That just won't work on the old console.
Speaker 1: because now game people have to say Do I make a game using the better?
Speaker 1: Capabilities?
Speaker 1: knowing only a small number of people from this base have this they almost have to treat it like a new console.
Speaker 0: or Yeah, everything compatible Right or yeah exactly do the DX model right where you you make your game?
Speaker 0: So it works on old switches But also new switches and if someone has a new switch your game is better somehow and that adds to development cost.
Speaker 1: so what they announced was actually What I expected and I think is a perfectly like.
Speaker 1: if I need a second switch or if mine dies or something like.
Speaker 1: this Is what I would buy.
Speaker 1: the updated Nintendo switch has better battery life Be a partly because it has a bigger nicer OLED screen.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm in the comments.
Speaker 0: There's and there's some other minor upgrades.
Speaker 0: I think it might have more storage inside.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think there's a few minor upgrades like that, but games will run the same as was it's yes It's not really it's.
Speaker 0: it's obviously a better switch.
Speaker 0: if you're buying a switch today, right?
Speaker 0: You're either a need to save money for some reason in which case by the old switch or used old switch because those are still Just great.
Speaker 0: Yeah, or if you have money and you want to get the best switch obviously buy the OLED switch.
Speaker 0: Why would you buy the other one?
Speaker 0: But yeah, it's like they released the what we expected to be the upgraded switch.
Speaker 0: But all these these video game news sites they were all like, oh, there's gonna be an upgraded switch which is like.
Speaker 0: I hate it when they Report on these newses right?
Speaker 0: Like.
Speaker 0: it's like if someone comes out and like, you know July and is like Phone big leaks new iPhone this September or October.
Speaker 0: It's like there's been a new iPhone every September slash October every year Thousand and like, you know Are you a press release or are you in fact just a scheduled appointment?
Speaker 0: Exactly.
Speaker 0: It's like no Nintendo's gonna release an upgraded better switch and it's like yeah They like.
Speaker 0: I just said even the NES got one of those, right?
Speaker 0: It's now every single Nintendo console is going to get an upgraded version at some point in its life I can't like.
Speaker 0: maybe the Wii U didn't.
Speaker 0: I think that might be the only one.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but I want to point out game cube Didn't I guess?
Speaker 1: Didn't really have any like it.
Speaker 0: there wasn't like a better game.
Speaker 1: Well, the brother the game cube was just so like perfect that they just made a new console to try to get into different territory.
Speaker 0: The point is game news sites reported on that, right?
Speaker 0: They got people, you know hyped up, but they reported on something ridiculous, which they were saying Oh, you seem like a 4k switch and it's like No, that's not gonna happen.
Speaker 1: or if it could it would suck for a more powerful switch That would have higher frame rates for third-party games.
Speaker 1: Like that was something people were talking about.
Speaker 0: Yeah that it wasn't gonna happen I think.
Speaker 0: why would they?
Speaker 1: so there was a whole Of some fanboys like arguing this.
Speaker 1: but the three things I want to point out about that space like to sort of nail this point home is one.
Speaker 1: Nintendo's philosophy as they have publicly stated for many many many years decades Even is use existing proven cheap technology to make games that are good at a profit.
Speaker 1: Don't use the newest most advanced technology that is not necessary to make good games.
Speaker 0: That is like Yeah, does it make the game more fun?
Speaker 0: No, no, it does not right.
Speaker 0: Yep
Speaker 1: number two Nintendo's not gonna fracture the the user base and that's like sale base the addressable market if you want to talk about like product management Of the Nintendo switch when it is still a very healthy extremely popular console still running through
Speaker 0: the number one The number one console by a lot.
Speaker 1: and three the people who said oh, why why did they?
Speaker 1: if they upgraded the screen?
Speaker 1: Why couldn't they make it 4k?
Speaker 1: Why can't they make it support these third-party games?
Speaker 1: I can ask that question in one two, three, four five words and those five words are the ps5 weighs 10 pounds.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you would have to make like a switch.
Speaker 0: that would effectively be no different than a ps5.
Speaker 0: it would just play Nintendo games.
Speaker 1: I just imagine it take a pit to pick up pick up a pay PlayStation 5 tape to joy cons to the side.
Speaker 1: That is what a 4k 60 where.
Speaker 0: how are you that?
Speaker 0: a PlayStation 5 has external power though?
Speaker 0: You would need to.
Speaker 0: where's the battery going?
Speaker 1: strap a car battery to your waist?
Speaker 1: Like the legendary.
Speaker 1: Oh, I got a tree for it with six car batteries and a Sega.
Speaker 0: Yeah, 4k is for 1080p screens.
Speaker 0: So at merrim actually bare minimum.
Speaker 0: you could do it if you had well considering a switch That's undocked and has to go on battery power.
Speaker 0: I could do 720p, right?
Speaker 0: That's 720p is what?
Speaker 0: isn't that?
Speaker 0: you're gonna need four of those to make a 1080p?
Speaker 0: Yeah, so it takes 16 switches and a stack and tape them in a bundle.
Speaker 1: You gotta it is literally for any reasonable price point.
Speaker 1: Impossible to have the specs of something like a PlayStation 5 in the form factor of a Nintendo switch.
Speaker 1: It's not a matter of just do it better.
Speaker 1: It's a matter of you fucking can't.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I also just want to point out I think that there's you know, there's like this impression.
Speaker 0: You know the impressions of how big things are at something I talk about I guess a lot whenever it comes up right like how eSports are actually bigger than a lot of pro sports.
Speaker 0: But because the pro sports are on television and there's more money in them, right?
Speaker 0: It's like you don't realize how big you know League of Legends is Because the amount of money behind it and the amount of eyeballs behind it are not in alignment, right?
Speaker 0: There's a lot of money behind NFL football, but there's not a lot as many eyeballs, right?
Speaker 0: You know, it's like you would think soccer is you know, if you lived in the US before there was internet You would think soccer was no big deal because you can't see right, you know So much in the same way.
Speaker 0: I think in the video game console world Right, the bigness of PC gaming is sort of invisible because people can't see.
Speaker 0: people who live in console countries Like the United States can't see all the countries that don't have any fucking consoles as PC gaming only, right?
Speaker 0: and people also can't see How small actually the.
Speaker 0: the quote hardcore only because I don't have a better word for it.
Speaker 0: PlayStation Xbox console audience is relative to the switch audience Because the vast majority of these switch, you know phone game, you know Audience right are not in the gaming communities, right?
Speaker 0: So someone comes around and is like hey You know Nintendo already has like all these, you know, they've got everything but they don't have that hardcore Audience right?
Speaker 0: if Nintendo would just make you know an ultra powerful console and they got all those games that you know Sony and Microsoft have you know the calls of duty and whatever.
Speaker 0: They would just take over the whole console world and that would be it monopoly.
Speaker 1: Nope Anyone who cares about those games already has a PlayStation or an Xbox gaming PC and or they have a switch also.
Speaker 0: probably they probably do.
Speaker 0: but The thing is Nintendo could do that, right?
Speaker 0: That's a possible thing, but the perception is that like that would be a worthwhile endeavor.
Speaker 0: But if you look I think that the truth is if you look at the pie of console gaming The PlayStation Xbox piece of the pie is not a big piece of the pie.
Speaker 0: Nintendo has the entire rest of the fucking pie, which I'm is well over half.
Speaker 0: Yep, right It might even be two-thirds of the pie and you know Nintendo has a piece right.
Speaker 0: those people with PlayStation and Xboxes some of them already have switches also, right?
Speaker 0: But the the you know, those core hardcore Call of Duty people, right?
Speaker 0: It's like You know, it's.
Speaker 0: it's like none of the PlayStation and Xbox.
Speaker 0: They've got none of that Nintendo pie.
Speaker 0: They're not infiltrating it in any way whatsoever You know, well, so actually the question you should be asking is not why doesn't Nintendo just eliminate them and take over the game?
Speaker 1: Try to get into Nintendo's grill and great with them?
Speaker 0: And I just why.
Speaker 0: how come Microsoft or Sony or or any of the companies that make games to their platforms?
Speaker 0: How come they have made absolutely no attempt whatsoever to make a fun Quality game that doesn't rely on just ridiculous horsepower, you know, whatever, right?
Speaker 0: How come they can't make a game as good as Breath of the Wild?
Speaker 0: and you know Put it on compete with they're not even trying.
Speaker 1: so there's another angle here.
Speaker 1: That's especially important considering there are massive supply chain disruptions globally right now for a lot of reasons.
Speaker 1: chips are hard to get.
Speaker 1: so Why would Nintendo move into new?
Speaker 1: Difficult to acquire more expensive chips instead of solidifying supply lines?
Speaker 1: They've already protected.
Speaker 1: but Matt Piscatella is the NPD analyst and he he's a big player in the space.
Speaker 1: He tweeted an analysis of this that I want to read because it's very short and it describes like the final piece of the puzzle.
Speaker 1: Quote.
Speaker 1: back in the day Nintendo portable revisions would stabilize the demand curve and firm up ASP's.
Speaker 1: They were about maintaining sales performance and preventing the pull of price drops and stale inventory.
Speaker 1: The switch oled is right out of that successful playbook.
Speaker 0: Exactly, right.
Speaker 0: It's the.
Speaker 0: as time goes on, you know the parts that are in a switch, right?
Speaker 0: They you know, they sort of get outdated.
Speaker 0: They're not easier to get.
Speaker 0: the factories are making newer different things, right?
Speaker 0: They're not, you know, the screen clearly is that is the key component here, right?
Speaker 0: So yeah, they stop making the kind of screen that's in the switch.
Speaker 0: They're making these over.
Speaker 0: the factory is switched over to making oled screens.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: so we if we it'll be more economical for us to use those screens in the switch now instead of the old screen that no one's making anymore.
Speaker 0: and Bonus we can raise the price on it right and get a get a marketing thing out of it.
Speaker 0: Maybe someone will upgrade right, you know, but it's mostly just to you know, stabilize the the production process most of the time.
Speaker 1: if you ask especially if you're some gamer nerd like us included and you ask like why doesn't company aid do X the answer is almost always Because that wouldn't make any money or because in Nintendo's case.
Speaker 1: They're already printing money.
Speaker 1: They do not that they they're doing what they know to do to make money.
Speaker 1: your idea is something more money.
Speaker 0: It's something to do with it's all and especially when it's any technology.
Speaker 0: Right a lot of the decisions from almost, you know Almost every technology company and if hardware is involved have to do with something going on in the factory supply chain level That you know absolutely nothing about and you're not factoring into any of your thinking.
Speaker 0: you're only thinking about.
Speaker 0: you know things on your end when you know with games of like You know the game you want to play or you know, how fun it is or what's hot now?
Speaker 1: You're thinking from your perspective of I play these games.
Speaker 1: I would like to play those games on a switch.
Speaker 1: I assume everyone else does exactly what I do.
Speaker 1: Why don't companies cater to me this giant demographic?
Speaker 1: and the answer is you're not a big demographic.
Speaker 0: You're one person like advanced wars.
Speaker 1: if I why doesn't intend to make a new advanced wars?
Speaker 1: because they wouldn't make any fucking money.
Speaker 1: Making a new advanced worse.
Speaker 1: No one would.
Speaker 1: there's no way to make money.
Speaker 0: I think it also.
Speaker 0: I think it also You know.
Speaker 0: just to bring it back to the things being you know The this perception of size versus the reality of size.
Speaker 0: I blame two people for that, right?
Speaker 0: Not too individually but two groups of people.
Speaker 1: on the next Wednesday show we'll talk about this with the recent news about graphic novel sales.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the people who control who have who collect the data do not release it freely and they do not release it in ways that Are directly and obviously Comparable, right?
Speaker 0: It's like even if you look at like, you know, how many did Animal Crossing sell versus Call of Duty?
Speaker 0: They don't have the digital sales for Animal Crossing.
Speaker 0: They only have the physical sales, right?
Speaker 0: It's like you can't directly compare any of these fucking things to actually prove like Without.
Speaker 1: you can if you are in the industry and pay money to access data to make decision.
Speaker 0: Even if you pay money the data might not be.
Speaker 0: you know that?
Speaker 1: oh, yeah some.
Speaker 1: some data is just not available.
Speaker 1: Some data is bespoke.
Speaker 1: Sometimes if you want certain kinds of data, you've got to hire a firm to go generate that data from nothing.
Speaker 0: Yep, and a lot of the data that comes out is always, you know They say it in a specific way right to make themselves look in the best light if you watch any Apple keynote for examples.
Speaker 0: And then the second thing is I blame the journalists for not putting you know things in the correct size Comparison right?
Speaker 0: It's like, you know, if you're a journalist You just got to come out with the truth and be like look You know There are like twice as many people with switches out there than PlayStation 5 is or whatever the reality is like.
Speaker 0: make people's Perception match the reality of the world of how popular and big things really are.
Speaker 0: don't make the thing That you know is buying ads Or that you play right seem bigger than it actually is, right?
Speaker 0: figure out how many eyeballs are watching a thing or playing a thing and Then you know when you're creating the perception of reality in your journalism and media.
Speaker 0: Right have it.
Speaker 0: match the numbers right.
Speaker 0: if something is small time then poo-poo it be like that small time.
Speaker 0: and if something is big Time, you know, don't poo-poo it.
Speaker 0: make it You know as big as it is.
Speaker 0: Right the animal crossing coverage on your site should be like twice or three times as big as the Call of Duty coverage on your Site.
Speaker 0: that's just how it should be right don't go.
Speaker 0: You know.
Speaker 0: if you if you make a big splash on your site and then you know for one and not the other that doesn't Match the number of eyeballs.
Speaker 0: First of all, you're only hurting yourself Right.
Speaker 0: I don't know why you do this.
Speaker 0: And two you're creating the false perception in the world which damages Yeah.
Speaker 1: Like if you want to get an example of this look at how many people watch I don't know the Lowell Championships versus watch the Super Bowl or the Stanley Cup and that'll really change your perspective on like the relative popularity of things
Speaker 0: or It's really not popular compared to a lot of eSports.
Speaker 1: or look at how many Manga sell in a given month compared to how many superhero comics sell in like a decade.
Speaker 1: Yep for real.
Speaker 1: so in some last news, uh That Super Mario 64 cartridge is directly relevant to our main bit today.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so the we'll just talk about.
Speaker 0: we'll bring it up again in the main bit.
Speaker 0: But yes, somebody sold a sealed.
Speaker 0: There was a while.
Speaker 0: there were two recent sales.
Speaker 0: there was as original NES Zelda cartridge sealed in shrink-wrap that was sold for a Ridiculously large amount of money and then there was an Mario 64 cartridge in the box still shrink-wrapped You know in the plastic protecting case and everything right.
Speaker 0: that also sold for the most ever like 9.8 a plus plus water rating.
Speaker 1: like they have a whole system.
Speaker 0: Yeah, whatever their system is but just some ridiculous one point something million price and what's happening here.
Speaker 0: Is that Basically, you know people are pumping up the bids right in order to create a market for these things.
Speaker 0: You know people who probably have a lot of you know A large collection right of sealed cartridges because they were right.
Speaker 0: probably, you know You bid high on a few right just to make the perception be that they're rare and expensive.
Speaker 0: and then you can you know Slowly sell your collection off and profit greatly, right?
Speaker 0: So do not buy.
Speaker 0: Do not get into the sealed cartridge trading collecting game at all.
Speaker 0: Don't do it there.
Speaker 1: If you want to play these games you can get a cartridge that will work fine and just buy it like they're cheap They're available.
Speaker 1: You can also emulate.
Speaker 0: you get an unboxed Mario 64 cartridges like a dollar.
Speaker 1: It's like just growing on trees, but also these like these artifacts I'd say that in general gets its main bit But that kind of collecting always roughly the wrong way because it's very much in Indiana Jones.
Speaker 1: This belongs in a museum situation at best.
Speaker 0: Actually, no, but we'll talk about the main bow.
Speaker 1: We'll talk about that in a bit.
Speaker 1: I could see a one of these being in a museum somewhere for archaeological purposes.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the museum people I've seen the game preservationists on I've seen on 20.
Speaker 1: They're mostly focused on preserving all of the media and all of the game.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they're basically completely uninterested.
Speaker 0: They're big.
Speaker 0: They're like it's pointless to.
Speaker 0: you know, retail stuff is not rare.
Speaker 0: It's not gonna be lost to time.
Speaker 0: We don't give you know, here's an example.
Speaker 1: I would give before we Imagine if a museum had a recreation of like an accurate recreation with all real goods of the ticket-taking aisle of NES games from a Toys R Us in the 80s like that would be a zip it.
Speaker 0: I mean you would like that but that's not really.
Speaker 0: Preservationists aren't interested in that right?
Speaker 0: It's like it's not.
Speaker 0: it's not the kind of things not important for.
Speaker 0: you know The the kind of video game preservation is out there.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah for most of it There's other I've seen.
Speaker 1: there are people who are interested in the ancillary experiences like a round.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there are.
Speaker 0: people are interested in that but from it seems that like from a preservationist point of view the kind of like a Actual museum curators.
Speaker 0: That's not the stuff they're interested in it at all.
Speaker 0: They don't give a shit about preserving those things because they're.
Speaker 0: they're just like common and out there, right?
Speaker 0: They're not rare Special or you know, and they're not useful.
Speaker 0: you have emulators.
Speaker 0: You have other ways things are preserved.
Speaker 0: They don't need that.
Speaker 1: Well anyway things of the day.
Speaker 1: So check this out.
Speaker 1: This is a video that has a whole bunch of true like verifiable facts about Pokemon as a franchise various Pokemon games but they're all extremely weird and Useless and oddly specific.
Speaker 1: like did you know that in all Pokemon games?
Speaker 1: Except the fifth generation games when you fly use fly to go to a town You were placed directly in front of that town's Pokemon Center.
Speaker 1: But in the fifth generation games you were placed one full step in front of the Pokemon Center instead.
Speaker 0: I didn't know that but I mean, I knew it takes you to the Pokemon Center, but I didn't know.
Speaker 0: in the fifth generation You're one step ahead.
Speaker 1: That's all facts like that.
Speaker 1: This is a 10 minute long video of things that you can.
Speaker 1: these facts serve one purpose to annoy Pokemon fans if you happen to be around them.
Speaker 0: Okay So you got so also in collecting sort of news, right this is really recent.
Speaker 0: it could be a news But it's so great.
Speaker 0: It's thing of the day with territory.
Speaker 0: This woman named Linda.
Speaker 0: I don't know how to pronounce her last name.
Speaker 0: I'm sorry Guillory.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna you know But yeah, she when she was young right and being 51 I can sort of see yes someone about you know That much older than me right ten plus years older than me, right?
Speaker 0: It's like when she was growing up, right?
Speaker 0: She didn't have the NES She had you know The LCD games like the little tiny Coleco that plays pac-man.
Speaker 0: only that looks like a little arcade cabinet, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, like little electronic football with the LED lights in it, right?
Speaker 0: That's the kind of game that she was growing up with and in fact getting those games and you know Repairing them when she was a kid led her to a career in electrical engineering.
Speaker 0: So that's that's awesome.
Speaker 0: but yeah, so she went on to.
Speaker 0: you know, she just loved the fuck out of those things and Began collecting them at some point and has built up a collection that the.
Speaker 0: you know I'm not a fan of the Guinness Book of World Records, which has a lot of problems, but you know, it's a true thing.
Speaker 0: She has the largest collection of LCD gaming systems on earth with is 1599.
Speaker 0: I'm she might have 1600 by now.
Speaker 0: She finds just one.
Speaker 0: And the largest collection of playable gaming systems right at 2430, right?
Speaker 0: It's a two thousand four hundred and thirty, you know video game systems, right?
Speaker 0: And she has other things as well Like if you watch the video you can see she has every and every US NES cartridge right in a box.
Speaker 0: I don't think all of them are shrink-wrapped, but she has all of them, right?
Speaker 0: I think with boxes and manuals like she just has.
Speaker 0: you know, I guess she made good money.
Speaker 0: electrical engineering, right?
Speaker 0: And it says she's in Texas with the cost of living is low.
Speaker 0: So plenty of money to spend on collecting these things not all of which are expensive and is.
Speaker 0: and she also.
Speaker 0: she started way long ago, right but when you know, there was less hype.
Speaker 0: See she just has a massive collection and you know We'll talk about again in the main bit but in the video she just whips them out and plays them, right?
Speaker 0: She is not one of those shrink-wrapped.
Speaker 0: turn the page wash your hands Kind of collectors, right?
Speaker 0: She is like children.
Speaker 0: come into my collecting room.
Speaker 1: Let us play, you know That's like the classic arcade guys like yes, here's these very rare difficult to prepare like electromechanical games.
Speaker 1: Please come and play them.
Speaker 1: They're meant to be played.
Speaker 0: I learned in this bit.
Speaker 0: There's two a few things I learned in this video.
Speaker 0: one of that was really interesting is that you know Simon right the four button Simon.
Speaker 0: apparently in Japan the Simon was white and not black.
Speaker 0: She said she has a white Simon.
Speaker 1: Oh, I see that photo.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's pretty cool.
Speaker 0: And the other thing that I thought was really notable in this video is how she has a lot of sports related games Right, especially those LCD LED ones.
Speaker 0: A lot of them were sports related.
Speaker 1: I had a few of those.
Speaker 0: She's always point she knows and points out who the athletes are on All of the games that have.
Speaker 0: like an actual pro athlete on the box She's like.
Speaker 0: she's like look there's OJ Simpson.
Speaker 0: Look I got this boxing game.
Speaker 0: There's Muhammad Ali.
Speaker 0: Oh, look there's you know Dallas Cowboys.
Speaker 0: whoever on the on this football game.
Speaker 0: It's like.
Speaker 0: I love that, you know the appreciating that because it was before, you know All these things were made well before the days of like.
Speaker 0: who's on the Madden box, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like.
Speaker 0: You know, there's the someone's on that.
Speaker 0: It's just like a random football drawing on some box and there's a guy you can tell with a team and the number and she's like Oh, there's so-and-so on the box.
Speaker 0: It's like.
Speaker 0: So I appreciate that appreciation that she has there.
Speaker 0: So yeah, if you want to collect things collect things.
Speaker 0: the way Linda collects things.
Speaker 0: Three awesome.
Speaker 1: So in the better moment the geek nice book club book Which I'm still reading at a steady but slightly slowed pace because I've also been doing stuff outside the tale of Genji not just An early novel but the first novel anywhere on earth that a human wrote.
Speaker 0: Genji continues to sleepwalk through life and Also also in meta moment, we're not going to any fucking in-person conventions.
Speaker 0: You can forget that shit, but at least not anytime soon.
Speaker 0: But there's an online convention really soon.
Speaker 0: Like it already kind of sort of started In fact this weekend like there's several days pack.
Speaker 0: It's camp.
Speaker 0: Is it called camp packs or packs East online?
Speaker 0: Thanks, what's?
Speaker 1: it was called packs online East Officially, but when they sent us all the stuff because we met a panel that we'll talk about a second The branding was that it is camp packs.
Speaker 1: So it is camp packs like it's a summer camp theme, but also it is officially called packs online East.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: So yeah, we recorded a panel that will be broadcast when on what channel.
Speaker 1: it is Saturday, July 17th at 1 45 p.m Eastern time on the packs to twitch stream Atari game design.
Speaker 1: We play a bunch of single-player Atari games.
Speaker 1: We talk about various game design elements of those.
Speaker 1: We play a game that neither one of us had played before the actual pitfall - which was Surprisingly good and we learned some stuff about it in the course.
Speaker 0: I didn't even really know it existed.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that song that plays the checkpoints.
Speaker 1: There's a lot going on there So they can't be.
Speaker 0: camp packs online.
Speaker 0: 2021 Discord is Live, I guess if you bought a ticket for with money, but soon it will be open to the general public.
Speaker 0: So that is where you're gonna want to go for all your packs.
Speaker 1: action Yep And we'll try to be in there like the YouTube stream and the twitch to all the places this appears and the discord.
Speaker 1: We'll try to just be there to answer questions if you have any in the chat.
Speaker 1: though If it's really sunny on Saturday, I might be doing that like from a park somewhere at a laptop.
Speaker 0: Yeah, who knows what's gonna happen?
Speaker 1: But uh, yeah Yeah, so there's that and Scott introduce a new bit in the last geek night.
Speaker 1: So we're gonna keep going.
Speaker 1: only one of us can do it for a show.
Speaker 1: So I'm doing it this time second dibs.
Speaker 0: So yeah, I successfully I successfully sold the monitor to the listener.
Speaker 0: They received it today and seemed to be happy with it.
Speaker 0: So hooray, let's see if rim can can manage to sell something.
Speaker 1: Yeah So I have the ogre big battle box that gigantic fucking box That is like all of ogre.
Speaker 1: It was one of the first kickstarters.
Speaker 0: You had to explain what it is.
Speaker 1: So ogre is a game by Steve Jackson.
Speaker 1: That is actually a really cool Asymmetric two-player war game like capital W war.
Speaker 0: It's a it's a it's a really old turn-based.
Speaker 0: You know war, you know map things on a map war game.
Speaker 0: But it was out of print for a long time and they kick-started to bring it back in print.
Speaker 0: and when they kick-started it They went all.
Speaker 0: they went too far.
Speaker 1: I believe the technical term would be whole hog on this.
Speaker 0: they went ham They they went ham.
Speaker 1: So this box is like the size of an end table.
Speaker 1: It includes so many components.
Speaker 1: It is everything that ever existed for even tangentially related to ogre.
Speaker 1: You can play every scenario every everything.
Speaker 1: It's kind of amazing.
Speaker 1: But I live in a New York City apartment and this thing is way too big to play in that and you never played it Even one time.
Speaker 1: nope, because there's not.
Speaker 0: I would have played it anyway any time if you would have said hey Let's actually take a whole day and play ogre.
Speaker 0: You just never wanted to do that and never you know when I would.
Speaker 1: you know when we would have if we had a house With a gaming table where I could just leave it set up for a period of time Like one of those ones where I can like put a cover over it and use the table.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well that didn't happen.
Speaker 0: So now you're stuck with it.
Speaker 1: This is second dibs because I do know some people who once it is safe for me to visit them They may be willing to take it from me.
Speaker 1: Uh, and there's a game store who if I'm willing to drive it there, which at some point I will be in that place at the right time.
Speaker 1: I will give it to them.
Speaker 1: but if you want this giant box and I'll link to it before I Deal with it in one of these other ways you're willing to pay for shipping I will mail it to you, but I will warn you.
Speaker 0: so shipping only.
Speaker 0: you're selling it for zero dollars.
Speaker 1: I'll sell it for zero dollars.
Speaker 1: You're willing to pay for shipping And I will warn you.
Speaker 1: shipping will not be cheap.
Speaker 1: This thing is also heavy.
Speaker 0: Hmm And with that's how far it goes, you know, if you're not shipping it far It could be.
Speaker 1: I mean if you live in New York City, if so, and you'll bring me at like Queensborough Plaza I will carry it there and hand it to you.
Speaker 1: Okay, so let's get right into it in our main bit.
Speaker 1: collecting collecting and games.
Speaker 0: So there's a lot of things we have to say about collecting things in general.
Speaker 0: We're gonna avoid those.
Speaker 0: I want to talk specifically, you know on the collecting of games specifically the cartridges to games that had cartridges or you know games that were said were sold physically on CDs or whatever right and Also the video games and also the collecting of tabletop games right board games and boxes, right?
Speaker 0: Those two things only pertinent to those very specific collecting hobbies, right?
Speaker 0: So in the video game hobby, right we're seeing the usual things we're seeing and other collecting hobbies Which is people doing it for the money.
Speaker 0: Yep, right Speculation right you're buying a you know some cartridge.
Speaker 0: You know that's sealed in a box with a grade on it.
Speaker 0: because you think in some, you know found some greater fool.
Speaker 0: Okay, some number of years.
Speaker 0: It'll be worth even more and you can sell it again.
Speaker 0: So you think it's like an investment.
Speaker 0: right early some fool thinks it's an investment and you just sold it to them and you made Bank good on you, but you're evil, you know, rip or offer bad person Of course, it's.
Speaker 1: it's tricky because our one could argue that well they found value in it, but Very few people I believe who collect those kinds of things are doing so for reasons other than thinking it's an investment Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean almost all of the games that people are paying these, you know We're seeing high prices for things like, you know, like I said Zelda 1 cartridge.
Speaker 0: It's like we have Zelda 1 guys It's right.
Speaker 1: It's like, you know, if there was a Zelda 1 cartridge, it's just not like mint in box And I threw the manual away, but I've got it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know if we were seeing things like, you know ultra rare, you know prototype cartridge No one's no one has a ROM of this even.
Speaker 0: But that's the stuff Preservationists are actually looking for.
Speaker 1: the cartridges that are selling for big bucks are selling primarily based on how Popular and how much current nostalgia is there for the game itself?
Speaker 1: Not the rarity of that particular piece of plastic Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: That's what's going on here.
Speaker 1: and The rarity of like mint in box.
Speaker 1: mint in box things seem to have a fairly constant level of rarity for a lot.
Speaker 1: like you look at any given sector and you'll find like a percentage of mint in boxes from Unshipped inventory or lost in a warehouse like there's sort of a chart of those kinds of things anyway
Speaker 0: But bought it but never gave it to my kid run Christmas because he misbehaved.
Speaker 1: Yeah found it in an attic fell off a truck.
Speaker 1: But I feel that that rarity like whether or not a mint in box exists irrespective of all the other factors involved Doesn't seem to actually be tied to the prices.
Speaker 1: people are paying for these things.
Speaker 1: They're paying based on no.
Speaker 1: Mario 64 is a very important game.
Speaker 1: Therefore this piece of plastic is very important Yep, which is not true at all.
Speaker 0: That's that's not how value things work, right?
Speaker 0: I mean, I guess it does is what is someone willing to pay?
Speaker 0: but the thing is was someone really willing to pay that or Someone was just paying that to trick others into being willing to pay that right?
Speaker 0: It's like they if you know if they had to keep it, right if they had to stick it could never resell it.
Speaker 0: And they could never you know, and it they didn't have any effect on boosting the prices of other things They owned, you know, if they were buying it to have it.
Speaker 0: and you know Would that person really have paid that much for the Mario 64?
Speaker 0: No, so it's not really what someone's willing to pay for it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and also it's easy.
Speaker 1: this whole idea of a mint in box mostly came out of the rarity of like subsets of nostalgic items from like Well, like old baseball cards.
Speaker 1: There were things that people didn't think were valuable and then over time got lost and destroyed and then eventually People wanted to have those things again and because they were rare The value went up like sure.
Speaker 1: that's reasonable like trying to think of a good like an old comic book the first appearance of Cyclops or the x-men or spider-man?
Speaker 0: Well, though some of those comics are really common, right?
Speaker 0: You can just like you want.
Speaker 0: you want a Dark Phoenix saga, right?
Speaker 0: This is something people don't realize.
Speaker 0: is that x-men actually is a great example because x-men was so popular.
Speaker 0: They sold so many comics that even these really hot you think these hot series like Dark Phoenix saga.
Speaker 0: It's like you can get a Dark Phoenix saga for not too much money because it was so popular.
Speaker 0: It was so great.
Speaker 0: There's tons of them right now sold.
Speaker 0: it's sold, right?
Speaker 0: It's the shit that was either so old that people didn't care about preserving it like a you know, a spider Superman action comics whatever or Stuff that was less popular so there weren't too many out there, but then somehow gained significance later.
Speaker 1: Yeah But then there was a lot of news and a lot of pop culture ideas around.
Speaker 1: those old things that actually were rare for various Reasons became valuable because more people wanted them than they existed.
Speaker 1: But then people started the trend of whenever anything new came out They would speculate on will this be the big popular thing in the future and try to keep mint in box versions as investments?
Speaker 1: But because so many people did that They're still around.
Speaker 1: there's plenty of them.
Speaker 0: if you and if you think that well, okay, you know Even if something becomes a bust I just got to hold out even longer and hold out even longer and you hold out even longer until eventually it'll will be worth Something right?
Speaker 0: It's like no look at Beanie Babies.
Speaker 0: They won't be worth anything ever, right?
Speaker 0: It just they will not go up period the end, right?
Speaker 0: So Yeah, video games.
Speaker 0: I think you know the cartridges CDs, right?
Speaker 0: You know the mint in box part makes even less sense because if you think about comic books, especially Part of the reason you want them to be mint and such and in the best possible condition is So that if you were to read them You could actually make out the fucking words and see the correct colors, right?
Speaker 0: Not that the printing technology was that great for old ones But you know the condition of the thing somewhat matters, right?
Speaker 0: Even the baseball card like the condition of it kind of matters.
Speaker 0: if you want to enjoy the thing, you know.
Speaker 0: looking at it right, you know.
Speaker 0: and If you have a video game a beat-up old Mario 64 cartridge plays the same damn fucking game as a brand-new mitten box One.
Speaker 0: there is no fucking difference.
Speaker 0: Not one right?
Speaker 0: So having it be mint Doesn't matter.
Speaker 0: It's a. the enjoyment level is unaffected as long as it's functioning, right?
Speaker 1: It's good to go now case in point when I was a kid the thing that I did fall into this trap and collect for a while because I Thought they'd be worth something because I'd see them being sold individual cards for a lot of money.
Speaker 1: We're like those 90s x-men collectible cards.
Speaker 0: I Collected them just cuz I like the cards.
Speaker 0: I was actually looking at him recently.
Speaker 0: I still like those cards.
Speaker 0: I do like those cards a lot.
Speaker 0: I was actually thinking like man.
Speaker 0: I was like is any I'm like are because I know there are still some collectible card sets being made these days.
Speaker 0: But and I was like, hey I wonder if like is anyone made any x-men cards like right now?
Speaker 0: Is there a current?
Speaker 0: is there a current set?
Speaker 0: cuz like if there's a current set it's like maybe I would buy.
Speaker 1: So I just looked up one of the sets that I really liked and collected the 1990 impel Marvel Universe set.
Speaker 1: There were 162 cards in it.
Speaker 1: It's one of the sets I collected.
Speaker 1: You can buy a complete set of it today for under 200 bucks.
Speaker 1: And yeah, that's about right the most expensive card Like the going great in that entire set There's a few.
Speaker 0: they're a slightly hard to get but I think there's a special Stan Lee card in that set.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like no one has a long shot that I can see but they the Punisher one goes for the whopping price of $4 Spicy.
Speaker 1: I feel like I would.
Speaker 1: I was paying like 75 cents to a dollar a card in 90s dollars when I was collecting these things.
Speaker 0: so Yeah, I actually for me it was the third impel series the space one.
Speaker 0: Oh, I had some of those.
Speaker 1: I like those a lot.
Speaker 0: I collected the most of those.
Speaker 1: I almost had the full set the one I tried to get the whole set of was the Wolverine specific series.
Speaker 0: Well, those were really low quality cards paper.
Speaker 1: Yep, and then there were foils.
Speaker 0: I have I had like.
Speaker 0: I have like one pack of those.
Speaker 1: there would be occasional foil cards in those packs and I have like Two of the foils.
Speaker 1: as far as I can tell those aren't worth anything either.
Speaker 0: not worth nothing.
Speaker 0: But we're supposed to be only talking about the video game.
Speaker 0: So the point is video game collecting.
Speaker 0: you're either collecting some retail object that is common as dirt that the price has been, you know Manipulated.
Speaker 0: right.
Speaker 0: if you're collecting something of actual historical value, right?
Speaker 0: Like I said prototype cartridges Artifacts from you know development, you know ultra rare things It's like either a some of those things have been preserved right for example Like Nintendo World Championship cartridges, right?
Speaker 0: You can get the ROM of that.
Speaker 0: No problem.
Speaker 0: Or those are the things that belong in a museum, right?
Speaker 0: If you get one, I feel you're morally responsible to be making a ROM, right?
Speaker 0: You don't be Shouldn't be charging a bunch of money for those things either because we got into the comic book stuff.
Speaker 1: We're like.
Speaker 1: the thing itself has some intrinsic value because the thing was the thing But in this case the thing is the game and the game is just a bunch of code.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there's no like historical, you know, like, you know It's not much historical value in preserving like the physical, you know, Mario Duck Hunt cartridge Even if it was the you know, maybe if it was the lat literal last one
Speaker 1: There's gotta be a few around somewhere that are preserved enough for someone to investigate them.
Speaker 0: if we need to investigate them Right, but you know if you had for example, like, you know development builds of Mario Brothers, right?
Speaker 0: You know when you go to the Nintendo Store and have the pieces of paper where they were planning out Mario levels, right?
Speaker 0: Those have extreme significance right and should be in a museum and are worthy of collecting.
Speaker 0: so I can see you know It's fun and cool, you know to have a collection.
Speaker 0: right in my thing of the day Linda Like I said, she had every NES US release game, you know still in box right presumably with instruction manual at her wall.
Speaker 1: That's a compass a cool complete collection.
Speaker 1: She also has a bunch of standalone like playable console things like things.
Speaker 0: But she's playing that she's playing those right.
Speaker 0: it's like, you know, and it's like they're not.
Speaker 0: she's not treating them Like she's gonna resell them for a fortune, right?
Speaker 0: She legitimately Enjoys having them so she paid a price for them that are equal to the enjoyment that she felt she would get for them.
Speaker 0: She's not.
Speaker 0: she wasn't paying a price to them.
Speaker 0: be like a hell sell these later and get rich, right?
Speaker 0: You know, she's doing well enough to have that collection in the first place In board games because we've gone on pretty long in this show already.
Speaker 1: but yeah board games are almost this special case that bother me more because We're not talking about like liking Warhammer figures because arguably you need those if you're playing Warhammer like.
Speaker 1: that's a different thing.
Speaker 0: Yeah Right the board game collecting world seems to be better in one way and that there isn't a lot of speculation there.
Speaker 0: You know, there isn't really a bunch of people other than magic cards like in Pokemon cards Which is the specific CCG area of table or
Speaker 1: collectible is in the name
Speaker 0: right, but when you get to like a settlers or you know other than like a very few specific instances like maybe someone's got like The first settlers ever or someone's got an ancient monopoly or something like that, right?
Speaker 0: It's like, you know, you're not buying and reselling board games for the money.
Speaker 0: There are some out of print games that end up going up in price just because they're out of print.
Speaker 0: But it's not a speculators market.
Speaker 0: you're not grading them and putting it in sealed boxes that can never be opened, right?
Speaker 0: but what we are seeing are people who are buying tabletop games and Their primary interest they they're they're playing them, right?
Speaker 1: So they don't leave me but like they'll open it They'll play it once you sure.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they're playing, you know, they're open and they're playing them some right but their primary interest is Having right they you know, or they're not playing them that much like we buy a game It's like we're playing the fuck out of it.
Speaker 0: We're studying it We're trying to figure out everything there is to figure out about its systems.
Speaker 0: We don't give a shit about the.
Speaker 0: you know The the cardboard it's printed on right or the the dice that come with it or the miniatures That come with it or the quality of those miniatures or or you know, any of that stuff, right?
Speaker 0: You know, it's nice to have nice components, right?
Speaker 0: My new oath came with like metal coins Like I did buy the.
Speaker 1: I'm happy to play with the cardboard coins I don't give a shit like I did buy the limited edition when they re-release Puerto Rico like the last really good printing of it Because it came with like really nice coins and really nice components.
Speaker 1: But I didn't buy it because I thought it would be valuable or special.
Speaker 1: I bought it because it's more pleasant to play with those nice components.
Speaker 1: Granted the first time I'm out at the table some fucking nerds spilled an entire coffee on like one of the boards, but It's still playable.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's not the worst.
Speaker 0: But when you look though Right at the board gaming community if you go somewhere like board game reddit, right or board game geek It becomes apparent.
Speaker 0: There are definitely people out there who care about playing games.
Speaker 0: You know, I think all the people who are you're not collecting games if you don't care about playing them at all, right?
Speaker 0: but there are definitely people who care more or at least appear to care more about Owning than playing right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, you can see these people are.
Speaker 1: They're sleeving their cards, right there, you know Leaving cards ends up being a playability issue and expansions come out and things like that.
Speaker 1: And then you have a set of Warren cards mixed in with a set of brand new cards.
Speaker 0: Well, they would just leave those ones anyway, but the you know, there's this people who care but they're really worried about like preserving the physical object of the game and They really really enjoy.
Speaker 0: if you look at the games they prefer to buy right they are, you know Spent choosing to spend their money when they go to buy new games on games that have fancier nicer metal wood Components right and as shooing games that are just like, you know some cardboard I'd
Speaker 1: say it's even if
Speaker 0: it's an amazing game for
Speaker 1: that aspect is I see especially if you look at a lot of board game documentaries including the one going cardboard that we were featured in about alongside a bunch of other people.
Speaker 1: the Conversation in pop culture wouldn't like regular ass news media.
Speaker 1: Look at tabletop.
Speaker 1: They often ask people Oh, how many games do you own?
Speaker 1: And if you look at a lot of these conversations people all a lot of these people tend to frame their conversations about games In terms of.
Speaker 1: I own a hundred and sixty seven tabletop games.
Speaker 0: My collection is this big Yep, and also people who are like, you know, what game should I buy?
Speaker 0: You know, the discussions are always like what do I buy?
Speaker 0: or I'm gonna.
Speaker 0: I have to call my collection.
Speaker 0: What should I get rid of right?
Speaker 1: It's like, you know what?
Speaker 0: How the things that we talk about which is how to win right?
Speaker 0: How is this game designed?
Speaker 0: Right, you know rules wise.
Speaker 0: they're not having those discussions.
Speaker 1: in those communities There's a big focus on having a like.
Speaker 1: how big is your collection of tabletop games?
Speaker 1: But then the posting photos of their board game shelves, right the subset of that though That actually really bothers me because it does impact the industry is the part that bothers me, too Yep, the people who buy games.
Speaker 1: This is primarily a problem on Kickstarter.
Speaker 1: the Ghostbusters game I complain about a lot, but that was the tip of the iceberg like the floodgates opened after that games intellectual property that is popular and be kick-started.
Speaker 1: but it seems like the people who buy a lot of these games are buying them solely Either because they think they can resell the game after the Kickstarter because I don't think anyone's looking at reselling.
Speaker 1: Oh, I was poking around.
Speaker 1: I found some people talk a lot of Kickstarter games like this like even the Ghostbusters game.
Speaker 1: They don't get resold after that and people are missing a component and we'll pay a lot for that component Like I guess oh the Kickstarter exclusive Slimer that kind of crap.
Speaker 1: People think they'll make money from that.
Speaker 1: but they also.
Speaker 1: they kickstart the game Just to get the components and be able to say they have the game.
Speaker 1: and if you look at reviews of these games People seem to focus almost entirely on the quality of those miniatures.
Speaker 1: It's almost like they're actually kick-starting the miniatures and the game Literally doesn't matter because I don't even need why even put rules.
Speaker 0: You're just selling physical objects, right?
Speaker 0: Like you might as well be selling action figures, right?
Speaker 0: And so the reason this bothers me is not is you know, it's like okay those people enjoying themselves spending their money Whoever they want.
Speaker 0: Okay, whatever.
Speaker 0: but all of the companies that are at least nominally producing tabletop games right.
Speaker 0: Most of their money is coming from those people.
Speaker 0: if you were only had the people who cared about playing games buying games They board gaming would not be a large industry at all, right?
Speaker 1: So in one way parts of it would have exploded anyway, but the longer tale of games that like we like Well, I'm saying is it.
Speaker 0: thankfully those people are propping up the industry with their money.
Speaker 0: So that's like.
Speaker 0: that's a positive impact, right?
Speaker 0: But the negative impact is that in turn the industry caters to that interest, right?
Speaker 0: So the people producing games right?
Speaker 0: are you know largely?
Speaker 0: especially if you look at Kickstarter.
Speaker 0: But a large chunk of the the board game tabletop industry are making games with fans focusing on fancy components, right You know.
Speaker 0: big lots and lots of extra shit giant expensive boxes just full of goodies To appeal to that market and not Making quality games right.
Speaker 0: even look at something like, you know, modern art, right an amazing game in a tiny box And all it is is what it's a pack of cards and some chips, right?
Speaker 0: You buy an old printing of this.
Speaker 0: it looks like garbage, but the game is just as amazing.
Speaker 0: But like the newer version of the game comes with like a gavel for your auction and like a little cool.
Speaker 1: That's neat Cool.
Speaker 0: it's cool and neat.
Speaker 0: I agree.
Speaker 1: There's no mechanic around that gavel.
Speaker 0: Fuck you They're putting that there be if there wasn't that aspect to the industry of you know They're trying to sell that they're there.
Speaker 0: They didn't put that gavel in there if they didn't think it's gonna help sell the game, right?
Speaker 0: And so, you know modern art, you know, the rules aren't any different.
Speaker 0: So at least the game isn't hurt by including the gavel, but people are making new games that are basically just you know Wooden gavel in a box with some, you know, nowhere where I'd make the distinction the game.
Speaker 1: There was definitely a discourse in the 90s and early 2000s around gimmicks in games like El Grande.
Speaker 1: Did it really need that giant king feast and that giant Castile?
Speaker 1: does camel up really need that?
Speaker 1: Pyramid?
Speaker 1: the answers are those were gimmicky sure, but they were Mechanical gimmicks in the games themselves.
Speaker 1: They were mechanically relevant to the game.
Speaker 1: It's not like the.
Speaker 1: it's not like El Grande.
Speaker 1: came with a crown for whoever moved the king to where.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and it didn't and it was just a piece of wood.
Speaker 0: It wasn't like, you know some fancy Sculpted thing that you know, we're obviously they're spending their.
Speaker 0: the people producing the game are spending their time crafting the physical object rather than crafting the rules.
Speaker 1: Now we do care about the quality of the components in the sense that to some extent yeah They don't not matter say some extent.
Speaker 1: but would you play Glory to Rome if the only version available was that clip art version?
Speaker 0: I mean, I mean, you know what I play glory to Rome even the new version.
Speaker 1: It's like occasionally, you know, but yeah Recordings of you saying that you would refuse to play the old version that the new version is objectively far superior Just because it looks better.
Speaker 0: It is far superior.
Speaker 0: The old one is kind of hard to read.
Speaker 0: it Makes it a little bit.
Speaker 1: Oh, no you even even if it wasn't hard to read you went on at length about how it's so ugly She's gonna go technically that you would refuse to play it.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: Well, I mean, you know, I wouldn't choose to play it.
Speaker 1: Their aesthetics matter like a game that looks better.
Speaker 1: It does matter.
Speaker 0: you can but also do.
Speaker 0: the Game is important, but it's.
Speaker 0: it's not like, you know, you're not.
Speaker 0: it's not the first thing you're doing here.
Speaker 0: The first thing is to make a game that is fun to play and then you produce the components Appropriately right to suit the game that you have made.
Speaker 0: if you're producing components first Right just to sell them to this segment of the market, right?
Speaker 0: That's willing to pay and then your rules are just like a thing you do, you know, because it's a game I guess.
Speaker 1: yep That's like.
Speaker 1: I always hark back to that ghostbusters Kickstarter because they're all like that.
Speaker 1: now where you look at some board game Kickstarter They highlight the quality of the components and like how they're gonna build the game and everything.
Speaker 0: Stretch goal even more minis drill metal coins stretch goal cloth maps, you know It's like.
Speaker 0: I just bought oath.
Speaker 0: It has a mouse pad cloth ish, you know roll up map, but it's got.
Speaker 0: it came with metal I didn't.
Speaker 0: I paid for the minimum level.
Speaker 0: They gave me metal coins and you know fancy like rosin Books for the secrets.
Speaker 1: I actually pointed out too.
Speaker 1: and then we can bring up the aesthetics of 18xx games.
Speaker 1: No, we can because the physical games often have a very like a beautifully printed board.
Speaker 1: That's also hard to read because graphic design is definitely a passion for a lot of people who design 18xx games.
Speaker 1: But the way we play them is on 18xx games net where here's some fucking yellow and green Hexagons with bright primary colors and a bunch of numbers everywhere.
Speaker 0: Yep, it's like that's plenty of fun, right?
Speaker 0: The train game would not be.
Speaker 0: have its fun improved with like little metal trains?
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: But I guess if you I would want a suggestion to you because we've gone on long on this show is one.
Speaker 1: If you're gonna collect board games like that's cool But just make think about why you're collecting them and what you're doing with them.
Speaker 1: and please don't be that guy.
Speaker 1: That's a gender-neutral term here.
Speaker 0: But the that guy who brings up how many board games they own on asked Yeah, because that you're gonna just part of our community if you're gonna collect things, right You want to look at my thing of the day and you want to collect like Linda, right?
Speaker 0: If you're not, you know regularly going into that collection room right with the children Right and going going wild and just having a ball with playing with all the awesome fun things you've collected, right?
Speaker 0: Cuz they're fun toys Right, if you don't you got a cop a collection.
Speaker 0: if you're not regularly going in and reading tons awesome comic books and sharing them Everybody right then in my opinion you're doing it wrong, right?
Speaker 0: Either a try to make money.
Speaker 1: You're just owning things which is consumerist and capitalist and therefore I'm really opposed to games I don't particularly like and don't play often that I did buy and keep.
Speaker 1: but there's that.
Speaker 1: there's one reason for that.
Speaker 1: These are games that are not in print Do not appear to be likely to be in print again at any time in the future and if they came back into print and?
Speaker 1: Were widely available I would get rid of my copies Mmm, like I remember like.
Speaker 0: if you're not gonna play them Why do you even need them if you're not gonna play them?
Speaker 0: Why do you even need the out of print one?
Speaker 1: Because I might play.
Speaker 1: it has to be at least a game I would consider playing or a game that I want to preserve for some reason that I don't think is well preserved.
Speaker 1: It's a rare case.
Speaker 1: That's the point.
Speaker 0: There's not a lot of games that need preserving there.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I was a little worried.
Speaker 1: I didn't think a lot cheetah would ever get reprinted but lo and behold it got reprinted not that long ago.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean for example right the.
Speaker 0: I guess the oldest rarest game I got is at 70s Dune.
Speaker 0: I got you know before it was a thing I went on eBay and I picked one up and it's really got moved.
Speaker 0: pretty much all the components complete.
Speaker 0: ish, right?
Speaker 0: It's not perfect mint conditioner, but we just fucking play it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but there there is a piece.
Speaker 0: It's not like I keep Preservation.
Speaker 0: I would I hope that something came out with a new one.
Speaker 0: I'll still play my old set.
Speaker 1: But I'm saying I hope that people preserve Old physical versions of these games.
Speaker 1: because unlike a cartridge where the content of the cartridge is the same no matter what the cartridge is That's true a physical copy of a game From like the compassion in the year 2059. if someone has like oh this is what Puerto Rico looked like when it was first released.
Speaker 1: Here's a physical copy you can interact with.
Speaker 1: that's important preservation.
Speaker 1: It's harder and more important arguably for old tabletop games than it is for video games.
Speaker 0: That's true, but also old tabletop games are generally you know well-preserved wherever they are.
Speaker 1: Some of them are hard to get because you know that was.
Speaker 1: there was eras where no one thought to keep them.
Speaker 0: I Mean yeah, the super old ones right are gonna be hard to get but it's like.
Speaker 0: you know If you go to pack some plug they just got like vintage tabletop room.
Speaker 0: It's like here you go play all these old games 60 70s here.
Speaker 0: They are play them go ahead They're not they're not a big deal.
Speaker 1: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando Kay for the logos.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Speaker 0: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 1: Remember geek nights is not one But four different shows.
Speaker 0: sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays Night's is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 0: geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 1: But unlike those other late shows it's actually recorded at night and the patreon patrons for this episode of geek nights are Heidi McDickell.
Speaker 1: I'll enjoy slinky G dread Lily Tenebrae Chris Reimer Clinton Walt and Finn Just like a dude guy.
Speaker 1: kashaya 85 program thread open speed undertake a lot.
Speaker 1: option piercings orb.
Speaker 1: Rebecca done review.
Speaker 1: madbull 34 cowards Ryan Perrin Sam Erickson Shervin Von Harl Taylor Braun.
Speaker 1: you hold the key to my heart and a whole bunch of people who do not want me to say their names and now I Leave you With.