Speaker 1: It's Monday, February 1st, 2021.
Speaker 1: I'm Rim.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott.
Speaker 1: And this is Geek Nights.
Speaker 1: Tonight, we are talking about the environmental costs of computing.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: So, uh, there was a distant time, I want to take you back to when I was in, like, third grade.
Speaker 1: And I'd wake up in the morning, and, like, my parents were up and buzzing more than usual, and they'd have their radio on.
Speaker 1: And that was a very important signal, because that meant that they were listening to see if we were going to have a snow day.
Speaker 1: There was no way to look that up in the old days.
Speaker 1: You would just wake up, and a radio station would say a list of schools that were closed.
Speaker 1: I don't think kids will understand those episodes of The Simpsons in a not-too-distant future.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean, it was this one radio station that had it that was the best at doing that, and there were other stations that did it.
Speaker 0: Like, you could also, I think eventually, the TV also did it with a scroll at the bottom.
Speaker 0: At some point, they added that graphic in, like, you know, the late '90s, I guess.
Speaker 0: But yeah, there's this one radio station I would never listen to, except for that situation.
Speaker 0: And if I knew there was snow action, I would basically wake up, stay in bed, and I had the clock radio.
Speaker 0: And that's the only time I would use the radio function on it.
Speaker 1: You hear that radio on in every room of the house.
Speaker 1: My parents were listening downstairs, my brother was listening in his room.
Speaker 0: So it was on that station, and only that station.
Speaker 0: And usually, I would be, like, maybe the first one to return, right?
Speaker 0: And I would turn it on, the lowest volume, so no one could hear, and they would just say the list of all the schools, the towns in the area, in alphabetical order, and being in Trumbull.
Speaker 0: Everybody's jealous.
Speaker 0: The kids in Ansonia, they know right away.
Speaker 0: It's like, Ansonia.
Speaker 0: It's like, uh-huh, right?
Speaker 0: You don't gotta wait for shit.
Speaker 1: Those poor kids, this is a quick.
Speaker 0: Right, but you're in Trumbull.
Speaker 0: It's like you're waiting, and they're like, you know, Easton.
Speaker 1: We had two schools that had very similar names to our school, and they had way more snow days than us.
Speaker 0: Oh, they actually said the names of the schools.
Speaker 0: For us, it would be the names of the towns, because every town would just close in time.
Speaker 1: See, I lived in such a dense, well, I lived in Detroit, and then later we lived in the dense suburbs of Detroit, so they had to go by school district, and sometimes individual schools.
Speaker 1: Like, there were four school districts in our, like, neighborhood.
Speaker 0: Oh, these radio stations would just be covering, like, half of Connecticut, so they would just be naming every single town in, you know, right?
Speaker 0: And then I guess they also did some private schools.
Speaker 0: They'd be like, you know.
Speaker 1: They would go by, ours would go by, like, the county.
Speaker 0: No.
Speaker 1: But that was huge, so it was, like, it was an ordeal.
Speaker 1: Like, you had to find, like, the right radio station to get the news.
Speaker 1: There was also a hotline you could call, but it was always just busy, so there was no point.
Speaker 1: I feel like they just had one modem.
Speaker 0: Fairfield County has 23 towns in it, so.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there were multiple schools that might- And they were definitely covering more than this, at least the ones I see here, because they definitely mentioned towns that were not on this list, so.
Speaker 1: But we're in this weird situation where, like, even as an adult, like, one, as a kid, when I got older, schools definitely canceled school less readily for a lot of reasons.
Speaker 1: Like, there were just fewer snow days.
Speaker 1: But two, as an adult, I've noticed that, you know, I don't often get snow days, but even I would occasionally, like, even living in New York, get a snow day every now and then.
Speaker 1: Except now, with COVID and everyone easily able to work from home, don't really get snow days anymore.
Speaker 0: I can't honestly say whether snow days have increased or decreased, or if they've been more or less trigger-happy over time.
Speaker 0: I need to see data to know for sure.
Speaker 1: This is definitely kid brain bias, but I'm confident.
Speaker 1: second grade made way more snow days than, like, seventh grade.
Speaker 0: But, like, my feeling is that they, it's like, my feelings tell me both answers are correct.
Speaker 0: Like, oh, you know, it's like, yeah, they do, they make you go to school now more.
Speaker 0: But also my feeling says, yeah, they're too safety-minded to do, you know, more snow days.
Speaker 0: And I'm like, I don't know if they're actually more or less, and my brain just feels like both things are true at the same time.
Speaker 1: There's another factor that the science of, like, getting snow off roads got better.
Speaker 1: Like, the operation of, like, how they do it got better in a lot of places.
Speaker 0: Climate change, at least somewhat recently, there's less snow.
Speaker 1: Yep, there's also just less snow.
Speaker 1: Like, as a kid, a foot of snow would happen multiple times a year in Michigan.
Speaker 1: And even as, like, by the time I was in high school, that happened maybe once in the entire four years I was in high school.
Speaker 0: Hmm, I don't know.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but I just, I saw a ton of kids on Twitter, like, I bumped into this, like, cluster of communication.
Speaker 1: And it was a bunch of kids kind of very rightly realizing that the concept of a snow day was probably killed by COVID, because the remote infrastructure that was set up will mean that schools will never bother with that again.
Speaker 1: They'll just make them.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 0: New York is closing school tomorrow, even though I think it was technically remote learning today, but I'm telling you, I guarantee no remote learning happened today, right?
Speaker 0: There's no way.
Speaker 0: It was definitely snow day today, for sure.
Speaker 1: I just worry, I think we're gonna see a future where snow days literally don't happen at some point, like, ever.
Speaker 0: I think they'll definitely go down because of climate change and the remoteness and whatever, but I think there will still be some amount of snow day.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I think the main reason there won't be, like, my guess, again, I might be wrong, is that remote learning will be such that schools will just, they'll get up in the morning and they'll announce, like, remote learning today because of inclement weather.
Speaker 0: We'll see.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we will see.
Speaker 1: So, yeah, it's Monday.
Speaker 1: It's not time for a Tech News Roundup.
Speaker 1: We actually have some show topics.
Speaker 1: Like, what's going on?
Speaker 0: You got another month.
Speaker 1: I get to do that once a year.
Speaker 1: I gotta save it up.
Speaker 1: I gotta treasure it.
Speaker 0: Alright, so this is a tiny news and it's game and tech related, right?
Speaker 0: So we all know that Nintendo's online multiplayer is trash.
Speaker 0: For a lot of reasons.
Speaker 0: It was trash on the Wii, right?
Speaker 0: And the GameCube barely had any.
Speaker 0: So the Wii is really where it started and it was trash.
Speaker 0: And then it really, they sort of really ramped it up on the Wii U and 3DS, right?
Speaker 0: But that was also trash.
Speaker 0: And, of course, they have it on Switch.
Speaker 0: Well, apparently, the news has come out that the server side system that they use for their multiplayer was created by a company called Quizal and was called Rendezvous that Ubisoft bought in 2010.
Speaker 0: Nintendo licensed it and renamed it NEX, N-E-X.
Speaker 0: And Nintendo has been using NEX for its multiplayer system since, like, 18, it's like super old, right?
Speaker 0: They've been using it for like 18 years old by now.
Speaker 0: It's a really old system.
Speaker 0: And, in fact, in order to try to make a spicy headline, they talk about how, yeah, the Splatoon 2 NEX server has like an unused function in it that checks to see if the server is running Windows 98 or not.
Speaker 0: It's like that's how old the code is, right?
Speaker 0: But, yeah, the announcement is that, yeah, Nintendo is finally putting NEX basically in the dustbin.
Speaker 0: Monster Hunter Rise is going to be the first public use of the new system, NPLN.
Speaker 0: I assume that stands for, like, Nintendo Public Something Something.
Speaker 0: Who knows what it means?
Speaker 0: Something Network.
Speaker 1: That is the level of journalistic commentary you're going to get from Geek Nights if you're new to the show.
Speaker 1: We've speculated on what one of those letters means.
Speaker 0: Link Network?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: But, anyway, the point is Nintendo Player Link Network?
Speaker 0: That sounds good.
Speaker 0: It doesn't say what it stands for, though, right?
Speaker 1: If there was a D, I would assume it would stand for Disappointment.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so if anyone out there is going to play Monster Hunter Rise on the Switch and play the online multiplayer, right?
Speaker 0: Let us know if it's any fucking good.
Speaker 0: And, in fact...
Speaker 1: I'm not going to waste my time looking at it.
Speaker 0: In fact, it's in a preview phase right now.
Speaker 0: You can get a free demo of the game to try it out because they're using that free demo to test how NPLN performs under load.
Speaker 0: So, if that game's online multiplayer doesn't suck, that bodes well, and it probably means that all future Nintendo online games are going to be using that and not sucking.
Speaker 0: However, it could also mean every other Nintendo online thing that already exists might be shit-canned, right?
Speaker 0: Which is definitely going to happen at some point.
Speaker 0: You see, the Wii online already has been turned off.
Speaker 0: The 3DS is probably coming up next in terms of its online stuff getting the chop, right?
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: Nintendo has, like, they've chopped reliably for their entire history, this kind of thing.
Speaker 0: I do not see the, what year is it, 2021?
Speaker 0: The Nintendo Switch online stuff, by 2020, I can pretty much guarantee you that.
Speaker 0: no Switch online stuff, the store, the Tetris 100, you know, Tetris, whatever it is, 99 Tetris, Tetris 99, whatever, you know, Mario 30, whatever, none of this stuff is going to be up.
Speaker 0: It'll all be turned off by 2020.
Speaker 0: If you look at the timeline of the Wii, right, which is off now, and the Wii came out in, you know, 2006, '07, around the time that the iPhone 1 came out, right?
Speaker 0: So, that didn't last until 2020.
Speaker 0: So, yeah, and the Switch came out, you know, maybe 10 years after the Wii, so I don't think it's going to make it to 2030.
Speaker 0: Did I say 2020 before?
Speaker 0: I meant 2030.
Speaker 0: I'm old.
Speaker 0: The Switch online stuff is not going to make it to 2030.
Speaker 0: Don't bet on it.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: It's interesting because- Bet on the opposite.
Speaker 1: The technology behind it is only, like, a third of the, like, the problem with Nintendo online.
Speaker 1: because, honestly, even if the technology worked perfectly, there's so many other problems that make it just unusable.
Speaker 0: Like, the user experience is bad- You know, you can't really use it for the kinds of fast multiplayer real-time gaming that we like, the Counter-Strike style.
Speaker 0: It doesn't work for that, as far as I can tell.
Speaker 0: It's not latency-free enough for the fighting game Smash people.
Speaker 0: It's no good at that.
Speaker 1: The local wireless just doesn't work for anything, even, like, non-superfast things.
Speaker 1: Like, it just never worked, and I assume Nintendo will never get that right.
Speaker 0: But even on the Wii, and also now on the Switch, the sort of light multiplayer gaming, like, say, the Tetris 99, right, which is still presumably running on this next system, and even back on the Wii, there was a Dr.
Speaker 0: Mario game you could play multiplayer.
Speaker 0: That stuff worked, right?
Speaker 0: And the eShop, it works.
Speaker 0: So, the Animal Crossing stuff was a little flaky when it was new, but now it kind of works, right?
Speaker 0: So, some of it is down, but the stuff that needs the ultra-low latency many players, that's where it fails.
Speaker 1: So, in some other completely unrelated news, because it's Monday, not gaming day, we'll talk about the shutdown of Battleborn on the next Tuesday's show.
Speaker 0: Who cares about that?
Speaker 1: Because they're shutting it down to where even people who paid for it can't ever even play it single-player again.
Speaker 1: It's just gone.
Speaker 0: Wow.
Speaker 1: It was online only, the entire experience.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Anyway, we'll save that for another day.
Speaker 1: So, if there's one thing, you know, that we're going to talk about on Geek Nights, it's biking.
Speaker 1: But if there's another thing, it's both of us complaining about how there aren't good small phones.
Speaker 1: iPhones are better at that.
Speaker 1: Like, the smallest iPhones, pretty good.
Speaker 1: Like, that's actually an okay size.
Speaker 1: Like, the ship sailed on the size of phone I actually want, and I'm not going to die on that hill.
Speaker 0: iPhone 4 and 5 were, like...
Speaker 1: Oh my god, the iPhone 4.
Speaker 0: You can just buy an iPhone 5, it'll still work.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it will.
Speaker 0: I don't think it runs the newest iOS.
Speaker 0: You need an iPhone 6 to run the newest iOS.
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 1: But Android has been in a real rough spot on that.
Speaker 1: Like, the smallest Android phones that aren't just garbage, like basically a feature phone, are huge.
Speaker 1: And even the small, like the ones that are marketed as the small Android phone, are bigger than the smallest iPhones.
Speaker 1: They're still huge.
Speaker 0: Oh yeah, they're big.
Speaker 0: I think part of it, you know, my conspiracy theory around all this, right, is that, you know, Apple started off with the iPods, right?
Speaker 0: Yup.
Speaker 0: And then they made them smaller and smaller and smaller.
Speaker 0: It was like iPod Nano.
Speaker 1: That iPod Nano was a phenomenal piece of hardware.
Speaker 1: I want a phone that big.
Speaker 0: People were excited about something being so small and thin, and Apple kept pushing small and thin, and people loved it, right?
Speaker 0: And then, suddenly, you know, the iPhones were trying to make them small.
Speaker 0: The iPhone 1 got smaller.
Speaker 0: The 3G was smaller, the 4 was smaller, the 5 was, right?
Speaker 0: So they made them smaller.
Speaker 0: They didn't make them bigger.
Speaker 0: They had done what they did with the iPod.
Speaker 0: They made them get small.
Speaker 0: Going small, technology-wise, is difficult and expensive, right?
Speaker 0: It's easy to make a big thing.
Speaker 0: It's hard to make a small thing.
Speaker 0: You gotta cram more shit in a smaller space with more constraints.
Speaker 0: You know, you got less room to work with.
Speaker 0: You know, you might have to take out your headphone jack, right?
Speaker 0: Stuff like that.
Speaker 0: Making something big, it's like, "Oh man, this is
Speaker 0: easy.".
Speaker 0: More battery life?
Speaker 0: Not long enough?
Speaker 0: Bigger battery!
Speaker 1: A big phone with a giant screen will last longer because you can just cram lithium into that thing.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like, you know, it's no problem.
Speaker 0: So, it's like, huh, people were, at first, wanting smaller things.
Speaker 0: They wanted smaller iPod.
Speaker 0: And then, but now, people wanted bigger phones.
Speaker 0: I don't think people, right?
Speaker 0: It's, again, contributing to my belief that, for the most part, it's not people's wants that drive the market.
Speaker 0: It's the market that tells people what to want.
Speaker 0: Coupled with.
Speaker 0: People bought SUVs because they were told to buy SUVs, not because they wanted them in the first place.
Speaker 1: I agree with you, but with one caveat.
Speaker 1: I think there is an actual market force also at play.
Speaker 1: And I think that's the parallel move away from people even having a computer at all.
Speaker 1: And the number of Americans who have only a phone or a phone and a tablet, to the point that a lot of people want a phone.
Speaker 0: If you got a phone and a tablet, wouldn't you then still want the small phone and the big tablet?
Speaker 1: You'd think that, but what I have, what I see happening is a lot of people just want a big phone that's big enough to be a small tablet.
Speaker 0: And that's it, yeah.
Speaker 0: It makes sense.
Speaker 0: The point is, is that, you know, the way I see it is that people wanted the bigger phone because they were marketed to, to make them want the bigger phone instead of the smaller one.
Speaker 0: And then, you know, I think the reason that the marketing was telling people to get a big phone was because the other non-Apple phone makers couldn't produce the small phone.
Speaker 0: They just couldn't do it.
Speaker 0: It was too hard.
Speaker 0: They couldn't, right?
Speaker 0: Apple was just better than them.
Speaker 0: But also at small phone, they would have no chance.
Speaker 0: So they instead convinced people to want big phone and that way those people will, right, then they can actually compete with Apple, right?
Speaker 1: Especially because Android phones are usually sold at a lower price point to a different market segment.
Speaker 0: Indeed.
Speaker 0: And then, but the thing is, Apple's like, well, all right, you want to compete on big phone?
Speaker 0: We'll do that too.
Speaker 0: And the Apple, the iPhones is like several times faster than the Android phone.
Speaker 0: But people aren't caring about performance.
Speaker 1: Another thing that I think is still going on, and I've talked about this on Geek Notes before, is that Americans in particular have, like for a lot of reasons, like.
Speaker 1: I'm not saying it's these people's fault because the real fault is our fucking healthcare system.
Speaker 1: But a huge percentage of adult Americans do have significant and uncorrected eye problems like vision problems.
Speaker 1: Correctable uncorrected eye problems.
Speaker 1: Couple that with the fact that as smartphones became more and more ubiquitous, we had this trend of a broader segment of society is using phones, including older people.
Speaker 1: So now there's more people who want a big phone because they can't read the tiny phone.
Speaker 1: So all that combined, Sony was basically the only company making high quality, very expensive, very small Android phones like Sony is it.
Speaker 1: Like I think Sony smartphones have been consistently the best non Apple phones in the world.
Speaker 1: And they had a line, the Xperia line, which was like the pinnacle of that.
Speaker 1: And they had a subline, the Xperia compact line, which I'm a weird nerd about.
Speaker 1: I've used Xperia compacts basically for like a decade at this point, to the point that I bought two in this XZ1 compact because at the time this was the last small Android phone that was worth a damn.
Speaker 1: Sony kind of ruined it because after this one, there were more Xperia compacts.
Speaker 1: The Xperia compacts were bigger than a small iPhone.
Speaker 1: Like the compacts were getting bigger because the non compacts were just fucking tablets.
Speaker 1: So out of nowhere, Sony is resurrecting the Xperia compact line specifically aimed at weirdos like me who actually want a tiny but extremely powerful phone.
Speaker 0: How big is it actually?
Speaker 1: TBD.
Speaker 1: There's a lot like we got to see.
Speaker 1: Here's the two things we know.
Speaker 1: They seem to be comparable to the XZ1 like the last time they were making actual small ones.
Speaker 1: And two, they will continue to have headphone jacks.
Speaker 1: Sony is doubling down on waterproof phones that have a real normal actual headphone jack to use.
Speaker 1: USB-C for charging.
Speaker 1: And I am going to follow this extremely closely unless there's something wrong with it.
Speaker 1: I'm probably going to buy this phone when it actually comes out and we'll see what happens.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: My hope is like I know the ship sailed.
Speaker 1: Most people want big phones for all these reasons we talked about.
Speaker 1: All I want is for there to be a small phone.
Speaker 1: Like I want that option to exist for people who want it.
Speaker 1: That's all I want.
Speaker 0: The sales on the mini iPhone have actually not been incredible.
Speaker 0: Like they're there but they're not like blowing it out.
Speaker 1: And like we said, there's a lot of factors where people regardless of if it is the right tool for their use case or the right trend for society or all this stuff, most people now want very large phones for various reasons.
Speaker 1: So we'll see where this goes.
Speaker 1: Sony is pretty much the last game in town on Android and they're barely skimming.
Speaker 1: In some other news that was kind of just funny and sad, you can read these details but Tesla has to recall like over a hundred thousand of their vehicles because...
Speaker 0: No surprise there.
Speaker 1: But it's because the media control unit like the touch screen that's used to configure like everything on this stupid car.
Speaker 0: Oh I did see this news, yeah.
Speaker 1: Will just stop working eventually and it'll stop working.
Speaker 1: I'm going to skip some of the details because you can read the article.
Speaker 1: But the reason it stops working is kind of a... It's sort of built in that it's guaranteed to fail after a certain number of times you have started the car.
Speaker 1: Because it will consume memory that basically will become non-reusable at a slow but steady rate every time the car boots and the car will boot every time you start the car.
Speaker 1: That just reeks of a company like Tesla not actually fully understanding the use cases of how normal people use cars.
Speaker 0: I know the specific problem is that you have flash memory and people don't necessarily realize that flash memory has a somewhat guaranteed-ish number of cycles.
Speaker 0: It's like you can write the bit over and over again so many times and then it's just done.
Speaker 0: I don't know if it locks in place, all I know is that it's done.
Speaker 0: You can't use it anymore.
Speaker 1: I mean, SSDs, it's known.
Speaker 1: If you read and write to the SSD in your computer too many times, eventually it's just going to break.
Speaker 1: That's a built-in limitation of that physical hardware.
Speaker 0: As opposed to, say, a magnetic hard drive which could last forever.
Speaker 1: I have a spinning disk in the HTPC that is terrifyingly old.
Speaker 0: I just sold a 20 megabyte SCSI hard drive for the Mac Plus.
Speaker 0: I sold it on eBay to somebody.
Speaker 0: It still worked.
Speaker 0: It was from the late 80s.
Speaker 0: If you opened it up, it just looked like a three and a half inch hard drive, only it was SCSI.
Speaker 0: The point is that the person writing the software was basically saying, "Look, I want to count how many times the car has been turned
Speaker 0: on.".
Speaker 0: So they just say, "When you boot, read this number from memory, increment it by one, and write it back to
Speaker 0: memory.".
Speaker 0: But the programmer isn't thinking about the system as a whole, realizing, "Oh, that piece of memory that I'm writing to is the splash
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: That I can only write to so many times, and therefore the car will only be able to turn on so many times, and the code will... You could have written something like, "Hey, if it fails, do something
Speaker 0: else.".
Speaker 1: In a computer with your SSD, if you write some code that's going to use your SSD, the microcontroller in the SSD does a bunch of stuff to abstract that away from you and handle that kind of problem.
Speaker 0: To extend the life of the drive as much as possible, but it will eventually break.
Speaker 0: But when it does, you're not in a car, you're not sitting where you can't start your car, you can't start your computer, so you just go buy a new one.
Speaker 1: It's also the MBTF, the Mean Time Before Failure, MTBF, of that component.
Speaker 1: A computer person knows the mean time before a failure of an SSD, and you take that into account when you build systems.
Speaker 0: But if you're in a car, you can't have that, right?
Speaker 0: So when you're engineering the system, we've gotten too used to, in engineering most products that have computers in them, of doing the hardware, the low-level programming.
Speaker 0: Every layer of abstraction has a different engineer, and they create interfaces and abstraction layers to communicate with each other, but nobody is considering the whole thing together.
Speaker 0: Because A, it's so ridiculously difficult to do that with the complexity of the systems we develop these days, but also there just aren't people who understand all the different abstraction layers.
Speaker 0: Or you're someone like me, where it's like, yeah, I understand from point A to point Z, but I just don't want to get involved in some of those layers.
Speaker 0: I just want to stick to the ones I like and not deal with, say, the JavaScript-y layer out there.
Speaker 1: Well, this gets into a fundamental point that we've talked about in Geek Nights way back around engineering and engineering.
Speaker 0: If you're doing cars, you have to do the whole thing from top to bottom and consider the consequences of some decision in the dashboard all the way down to the wiring and the chips you got in there.
Speaker 1: The classic example, the one that everyone always in every textbook is Therac-25, that medical machine that shot radiation at people, and a bug in that software killed people.
Speaker 1: That's a world, that's when engineering needs to have formal practices and certifications.
Speaker 0: It's no surprise that a shit show like Tesla does not have the engineering rigor in place.
Speaker 1: No surprise at all.
Speaker 1: I saw a commentator who said something to the effect of, this was years ago, bit by bit, Tesla is learning that disrupting the car industry is not that easy when you ignore the 40 years of collected expertise of the modern car industry that figured out solutions to these fundamental problems and you want to reinvent all of that.
Speaker 1: Sometimes things are inefficient because you don't understand them sufficiently.
Speaker 1: I'm talking mostly to Silicon Valley tech bros who seem to always think they can come into some industry they don't know anything about and optimize it.
Speaker 0: Well, sometimes they do by cutting a corner.
Speaker 1: That was a load-bearing corner right there.
Speaker 0: That ends up being good enough for a lot of people and you can fuck shit up a whole lot.
Speaker 0: and then, you know, things get shitty.
Speaker 0: But also and you beat up, you know, and now suddenly capitalism, so you've destroyed the good thing that was there already.
Speaker 0: But now we've all lost because we lost the good thing, the shitty thing.
Speaker 1: But anyway, things of the day.
Speaker 1: So I don't want to use a whole bunch of skiing things because I think I was talking about skiing the other day and I used to think of the day about it, but this is pretty cool.
Speaker 1: This is footage of a ski jump competition from 1939.
Speaker 0: I knew it had to be an old one.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: The craziest thing about it.
Speaker 0: The jumps are really short and lame and uncool.
Speaker 1: One, these people all suck ass at skiing.
Speaker 0: Like holy shit are they bad.
Speaker 0: Side note, I'm trying to like say lameless because I've been told that's an ableist word which makes perfect sense.
Speaker 1: I try to avoid it.
Speaker 0: I keep saying it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's a. it's a tough one, especially because I get conflicting messages from different communities where that word is relevant to them.
Speaker 1: So I'm just trying to avoid using it generally.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: But anyway, the point is, there are plenty of examples out there of, you know, watch old sport, watch new sport.
Speaker 0: And you'll see, you know, wow, people were less good at sport then in the past.
Speaker 0: There's a gif that goes around showing you like the gold medal, like vault jump from like the 40s versus, you know, the 2000s.
Speaker 1: And it's like, oh, so nowadays ski jumpers aren't going for distance because they can go so far that it becomes dangerous to it, like to an unacceptable degree.
Speaker 0: And they're just make a ski jump place that is super long so you can go farther.
Speaker 1: You need a long enough slope.
Speaker 1: There's a lot of reasons for this.
Speaker 1: Maybe I'll make that a thing of the day, a video that explains the physics of that.
Speaker 1: But anyway, in the old days, they went for distance because they couldn't really get that far.
Speaker 1: And the funniest thing is their technique.
Speaker 1: Everyone like has their own special technique.
Speaker 1: A few of them are trying to like windmill their arms to get themselves a little more like momentum.
Speaker 1: Some of them are actually flapping.
Speaker 1: It's just kind of funny and sad.
Speaker 1: You watch a modern ski jump.
Speaker 0: Before we had scientifically determined the optimal technique, right?
Speaker 0: It's like, you know, people are just going to try whatever they can try.
Speaker 1: Look at old timey baseball.
Speaker 1: A lot more interesting things happen before people realized, wait a minute, all we have to do is just hit home runs and nothing else.
Speaker 1: Why don't we just optimize hitting home runs and nothing else?
Speaker 0: A little roboty.
Speaker 0: You're getting a little roboty.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Besides a local recording will be fine.
Speaker 1: But there seems to be some Internet bandwidth issues out in the wild.
Speaker 0: OK.
Speaker 0: So anyway, I think I talked about this somewhere recently.
Speaker 0: I forget where.
Speaker 0: It might have just been a private conversation, but I saw the 60 second documentary.
Speaker 0: It's a whole YouTube channel of 60 second documentary.
Speaker 0: I don't know if the channel is any good or not.
Speaker 0: That's you can find that on your own.
Speaker 0: This is the only video I've watched on this channel.
Speaker 0: And it is a documentary of a person whose only job in life.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Is that they are a squirrel wildlife photographer.
Speaker 0: All they do in Nikki Coleman.
Speaker 0: All this person does is photograph squirrels.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: They set up and they become like an expert at doing this.
Speaker 0: And you can learn about, you know, 60 seconds worth of information about this person.
Speaker 0: But yeah, if you have any interest in, you know, the arts.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: You know, photography specifically, I think this is a great, you know, lesson.
Speaker 0: It's like, yeah, you need to find your thing.
Speaker 0: Whatever your thing is, I can't tell you how to find it.
Speaker 0: I haven't found my thing.
Speaker 0: You found your thing.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: But if you can find your thing.
Speaker 1: Apparently, my thing is the fixed protocol.
Speaker 1: God damn it.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: It's like, why was that?
Speaker 0: Why can't I have a cool thing like taking fun pictures of squirrels?
Speaker 1: That's my cutie mark.
Speaker 1: Thirty nine equals three just appeared on my ass one day.
Speaker 0: Exactly.
Speaker 0: But yeah, you know, this guy, pretty cool stuff here.
Speaker 0: Great photos.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Also, squirrels are great to photograph in general because squirrels are just great.
Speaker 1: In the meta moment, I feel like between the snow and the fact that I'm still just stuck inside and going crazy, might start reading the tale of Genji again.
Speaker 1: Because I keep reading.
Speaker 0: every time I'm going to read, I read a comic book instead.
Speaker 1: Every time I'm going to read, I read nonfiction instead.
Speaker 1: But like I said, there was that book I was reading.
Speaker 1: I'm almost done with it.
Speaker 1: The nonfiction book I was reading.
Speaker 1: And I felt this urge to read a fiction book.
Speaker 1: And I decided that the moment I have the urge to read a fiction book in the apartment, I'm going to read the tale of Genji instead of whatever I had an urge to read.
Speaker 1: Because I do also want to read the tale of Genji.
Speaker 1: My rule is I cannot read any fiction unless it's the tale of Genji.
Speaker 1: But I'm still reading nonfiction for now, but that might change real soon.
Speaker 0: You know what happened to me is these hockey games and also video games keep taking my... Every time I got some free time, I find something else to fill it with.
Speaker 0: that isn't that.
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 1: Like I'll be at my computer.
Speaker 1: It's like, oh, I could just go sit in the other room and read.
Speaker 1: And then Hades just starts and playing Hades for a while.
Speaker 1: And then someone's like, hey, you want to play Phasmophobia in VR?
Speaker 1: And now I'm in VR.
Speaker 1: And then it's midnight and I got to go to bed.
Speaker 0: Yup.
Speaker 1: Hades just keeps falling back into my hands.
Speaker 1: That game just is... It's satisfying an itch.
Speaker 0: Yup.
Speaker 0: It's good stuff.
Speaker 0: It is.
Speaker 1: I just didn't have the patience.
Speaker 1: We already reviewed it.
Speaker 1: Listen to that episode if you want to hear us talk about Hades.
Speaker 1: Today, we're going to talk about something we've never really talked about on Geek Nights.
Speaker 1: But I want to point out that...
Speaker 0: Have we?
Speaker 1: We may have.
Speaker 1: I mean, I've definitely deleted that episode.
Speaker 1: I think when we've talked about this, we've always talked about it in the context of e-waste, like physical trash, old components, mining, that kind of stuff.
Speaker 1: What we're talking about today is the environmental consequences of computing, as in doing calculations on computers, as in all that electricity that people are burning to mine Bitcoins.
Speaker 0: Well, that's the big one, right?
Speaker 0: That's the elephant in the room.
Speaker 0: But there's so many other things.
Speaker 0: It's like there's several elephants in the room.
Speaker 0: That's just the biggest elephant that everyone's looking at.
Speaker 0: So let's talk about that one first, right?
Speaker 1: But I want to preface this by saying we're not going to get too deep into what she wrote and why this is all important, because you should read this stuff too.
Speaker 1: But you can read it in her words and the words of all the experts in the space.
Speaker 1: But you might have seen this story about how Timnit Gebru was basically ousted from Google for asking these kinds of questions and trying to put rigor behind that research and point out these types of problems and concerns.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's another conversation I want to have is about private research at the private, you know, research at the private corporations like Google.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And you know whatnot.
Speaker 0: But and there's also lots of spoilers when private for-profit companies commissioned research.
Speaker 1: They're really only interested in research that makes them more money.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: They don't want to hear bad answers.
Speaker 0: There's also all sorts of, you know, the typical or sadly typical.
Speaker 1: Sexism, racism also gets people ignored.
Speaker 0: Yeah, sexism, racism going on in that particular story.
Speaker 0: Google doesn't look good in that story, is all I can say.
Speaker 0: But anyway, the right.
Speaker 0: So you got a computer, right?
Speaker 0: To make a computer requires energy at the computer at the mine to get the raw materials.
Speaker 0: You're mostly mining.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: But also other things.
Speaker 0: Energy to transport along every step of this supply chain.
Speaker 0: Energy to protect the factories.
Speaker 0: Are they making chips and boards and all that kind of, you know, cases and plastic and screws and everything.
Speaker 0: Shipping again.
Speaker 0: I'll just shipping every step of the way.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: You don't need to explain it over and over again.
Speaker 0: The shipping and then the packaging, you know, whatever you put it all together, you start using it.
Speaker 0: And it's like, OK, you've already, you know, taken all the rare earth metals from, you know, who knows what kind of place and what conditions and what kind of laborers and everything.
Speaker 0: And now you're, you know, whatever your power system is in your house.
Speaker 0: Maybe you live in a house of the solar panel and, you know, great.
Speaker 0: But maybe you don't.
Speaker 0: And maybe you've got a coal power plant power in your house.
Speaker 0: Not so great.
Speaker 1: Fun fact.
Speaker 0: How much energy does your computer use?
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And then how much work does your computer get done in terms of not just how many, you know, instructions does it process, how much work you have it doing, but the work that it is doing.
Speaker 0: How much is that benefiting people and society?
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: I could run a fancy 3D screensaver and not be in the room to even look at it.
Speaker 0: So it's doing nothing for anybody.
Speaker 0: It's heating my house.
Speaker 0: Maybe it's cold out and it's efficient space heater.
Speaker 0: It's like, that's about it.
Speaker 0: Is that worth it?
Speaker 0: Would we have been better off with a space heater instead?
Speaker 1: But this is a conversation that almost no one in the computing world even wants to have.
Speaker 1: Like, no one wants to talk about this.
Speaker 1: And they'll often, like, you'll be, if you try to bring this kind of stuff up, you'll be accused of being reductive.
Speaker 1: It's like, it's just, everyone's really avoiding this conversation.
Speaker 0: It's also so complete.
Speaker 0: The kind of questions, if you actually start to dig into this, the kind of questions you have to ask becomes so difficult with so many factors involved that it's like nobody wants to find the answer.
Speaker 0: And in fact, finding the answer may be more costly.
Speaker 0: So, for example, let's say you wanted to calculate, you know, OK, we want to, I don't know, render.
Speaker 0: We're going to make a CG movie.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And we're going to need to render the whole movie.
Speaker 0: It's so fancy looking.
Speaker 0: It's going to take this server farm like a whole week to render it.
Speaker 0: You know, and we'll probably have to do the render several times because, you know, movies.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And it's all those sorts of things.
Speaker 0: Or however it works these days.
Speaker 0: But we've got the server is going to render.
Speaker 0: It's going to use this much energy.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: To produce the renders.
Speaker 0: And, you know, that's going to take, you know, it's powered by this kind of power.
Speaker 0: And, you know, you want to figure out, is it worth it?
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: It's going to cost us this much money is going to have this much climate impact.
Speaker 0: Should we do it?
Speaker 0: Should we not do it?
Speaker 0: OK.
Speaker 0: You want to figure that out?
Speaker 0: Guess what you have to do?
Speaker 0: You have to get some computers and calculate whether it's worth it or not.
Speaker 0: And doing that calculation, you might say, finish that calculation and say, OK, we've figured out it's worth it.
Speaker 0: But because we had to spend this extra energy on figuring out if it was worth it, now it's not worth it.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Well, I spent part of our budget on figuring out whether it was worth it.
Speaker 1: Well, like there was an old thing in like the older days where large skyscrapers would often leave lights on at night and people would see that as very wasteful.
Speaker 1: But in some situations, the reason for that was that leaving those lights on actually generated the heat necessary to keep the building at a baseline temperature using less energy than the HVAC system doing that work.
Speaker 1: But or the rendering thing, what about the cost of shipping the food to the place where the people are working for like to make all the motion capture to do that film?
Speaker 1: Like, how deep do you go?
Speaker 1: It almost turns into the coastline problem of how long is a coastline?
Speaker 1: Because any surface, if measured in enough detail, is infinitely long.
Speaker 1: So this gets really challenging.
Speaker 1: And then you get into weird, almost trolley problem conversations that aren't actually useful, especially when you try to zoom in too far.
Speaker 1: So at the bottom end of this, you can have conversations like, is it ethical to let someone who's not creating have a fancy video card that will use a lot of electricity?
Speaker 1: On the upper end, you've got a conversation like, should we ban Bitcoin because people are literally burning coal to mine Bitcoins for nothing?
Speaker 1: I think we should ban Bitcoin.
Speaker 1: I think there's a thing we can't lose sight of having those zoomed in conversations.
Speaker 1: But what I've seen and I think you've seen this, too, is that the entities that are responsible for most of the pollution, especially in this space, are the ones who push the narrative of individual and consumer responsibility and activism when they are contributing the vast majority of the problem in the first place.
Speaker 0: Yep, exactly.
Speaker 1: Not saying you shouldn't be more efficient.
Speaker 0: A car company or a fossil fuel company like a gas company might be blaming the people driving.
Speaker 0: They'll say, hey, drive more efficiently.
Speaker 0: Use an electric car.
Speaker 1: Fuck you for creating that moral hazard by making the less efficient car cheaper in the first place.
Speaker 0: It's like, why are you marketing SUVs then?
Speaker 0: You're blaming people for doing a bad thing while simultaneously trying to convince people to do the bad thing.
Speaker 0: The boat that you have that carries cars from the other side of the world to the U.S.
Speaker 0: causes more pollution than all those cars will in their lifetimes.
Speaker 0: If you look at the percentage of pollution, big shipping boats cause a huge, huge percentage of the world's pollution, like you not switching from a gas to an electric stove in your house is going to make no dent whatsoever in terms of scale wise.
Speaker 1: Now, not saying you shouldn't do it.
Speaker 0: Should we ban importing cars from other places?
Speaker 0: You have to get a domestic car.
Speaker 1: But then what if the economies of scale mean that distributing that manufacturing ends up making way more waste?
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: And we have more factory, more car factories than instead of fewer car centralized car factories.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Something like data centers.
Speaker 0: We talk about like, you know, no one wants to use Google Stadia.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: We talked about or the.
Speaker 0: But you know what?
Speaker 0: Right now, you got a situation where it's like, OK, let's say everyone has a computer in their house.
Speaker 0: Well, a lot of those computers are off and not being used.
Speaker 0: You know, PlayStation fives or whatever.
Speaker 0: Everyone.
Speaker 0: People have them, you know, but a lot of them are not being used.
Speaker 0: We spent, you know, material resources and also the PlayStation factory itself produced way more PlayStation fives than we need.
Speaker 0: We only need the number that are being used at once simultaneously.
Speaker 0: We don't need the number that people who want to play one ever.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: So every time someone buys one, it just sits there unused.
Speaker 0: That was a waste.
Speaker 0: They could have someone else could be using that one right now.
Speaker 0: Instead, if we do what Google Stadia does, which no one likes for good reasons, you could just have all of the computers in one place and have exactly the number that we're going to need to be used.
Speaker 0: And whenever anyone needs to use one, they start using one.
Speaker 0: And when they're not using it, someone else uses it.
Speaker 0: And the amount of materials saved would allow the factory to produce less of them in the first place.
Speaker 0: We could ship them to instead of distributing them widely, we can distribute them more narrowly to a single place where they're going to be run, powered by a single power source, cooled more efficiently in a group.
Speaker 0: So if you look at a single product like that, it's like you can start to see, aha, that is that would be better if you're considering, you know, the environmental concern there.
Speaker 1: Only so in.
Speaker 1: But in terms of computing specific, actually, one more point on that with the local stuff.
Speaker 1: What about a professional who is like a 3D animator, like working contract for some like studios somewhere?
Speaker 1: They need that power locally.
Speaker 1: And if they couldn't have it locally, they would be forced to use these online services.
Speaker 1: that might be less optimal compared to what they would do professionally.
Speaker 1: So but I just got a calculation.
Speaker 1: The other thing that happens, because I was thinking about this earlier, is like, yeah, I have a computer right now that can draw like 600 watts.
Speaker 1: Like I got a 700 watt power supply and I push it near its limit if I'm doing certain things on this computer, like rendering out a geek night's panel.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I got a 600 watt space heater sitting in here for like four hours or so.
Speaker 1: But that 600 watts, if we go back in time to 1988, let's say, 1989, that's six fucking light bulbs in my house.
Speaker 1: So they're like, but individual consumers did not want LEDs.
Speaker 0: Or 10 light bulbs if you got 60 watts.
Speaker 1: We did all hundred waters because we wanted light.
Speaker 1: Like everyone has to be dark like everyone else is.
Speaker 1: But so if you get to the situation where like the light bulbs are a really good example, incandescent light bulbs were ridiculously wasteful from an electricity standpoint.
Speaker 1: But they were LED ones.
Speaker 1: But they were extremely efficient from a manufacturing standpoint.
Speaker 1: They were also extremely cheap, extremely simple, extremely easy.
Speaker 1: Like there's a lot of benefits to them, but they generate a lot of heat and they waste ridiculous amounts of electricity.
Speaker 1: LEDs and CFLs without government action would be so much more expensive than them that it would be like arguably evil to ask consumers to buy those fancier lights to save energy when it would cost them a lot and individually not benefit them at all.
Speaker 1: The only reason we were able to move forward with more efficient lights over time was because of government mandates.
Speaker 1: We banned and phased out incandescent lights for a reason.
Speaker 1: That economy of scale, honestly, and this is just opinion, is what I think we need.
Speaker 1: We need regulation of the use of mass computing resources.
Speaker 1: Similarly to how we regulate factories, Google data centers should be regulated on their energy usage the same way an IBM chip fab is.
Speaker 1: Well actually they should both be regulated more too, but that's a separate problem.
Speaker 0: I mean we already have this sort of regulation with cars in some, I guess not all states have this, they have emissions tests, right?
Speaker 0: If your car doesn't pass emissions, we won't let you drive it on the road.
Speaker 0: Sometimes there's an exception for like a classic car or something.
Speaker 1: Well just like there's exceptions for incandescent bulbs in like a historical house.
Speaker 0: But yeah, it's like, yeah, okay, you want to have a factory.
Speaker 0: If your factory can't pass the emissions test, we're going to shut your factory down.
Speaker 0: It's got to be energy efficient.
Speaker 0: They've gone, in New York, New York City at least, they have the ratings on restaurants for how healthy, how sanitary they are, but the Department of Health comes around or whatever and they mark you like a restaurant, very clean, right?
Speaker 0: Oh, we saw rats in your restaurant, F, right?
Speaker 0: We're going to shut you down.
Speaker 0: They recently put up energy ratings on all the buildings, simply informative.
Speaker 0: I don't think that they are.
Speaker 0: how, what system they use to do the grading.
Speaker 1: Like the leads thing, because Europe's been doing this for a while.
Speaker 1: Like Germany's really good about this.
Speaker 0: I don't think there's any enforcement around it yet, but I know that our building got like an A, like a 90 something grade in terms of energy efficiency and other buildings got like, you know, just near us, like they look like super new buildings.
Speaker 0: They've got like D's and F's.
Speaker 0: So like they must be doing something in that building that is like, you know, I don't know, they're poorly insulated, their heating system shitty, their cooling system shitty.
Speaker 0: I don't know what they're doing.
Speaker 0: that's bad.
Speaker 0: You know, maybe their roof is not white.
Speaker 0: I don't know why their windows are bad.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: But they're doing something that is making the building, you know, have lots of, you know, emissions and waste energy usage.
Speaker 0: It's not good.
Speaker 1: So the specific thing that we want you to think about because we're going to end the show soon.
Speaker 1: I'm getting a little hungry.
Speaker 1: Got some things to do.
Speaker 1: But because we're not experts in this space at all.
Speaker 1: Like don't think that we're experts here.
Speaker 1: We're just we happen to just be two white guys doing a podcast.
Speaker 1: But that's right.
Speaker 1: What this paper raised is something that almost no one is thinking about.
Speaker 1: Specifically, the carbon footprint, which mostly comes from the electricity used to run the computers that are doing A.I.
Speaker 1: shit right now, like machine learning.
Speaker 1: It's not like, oh, yes, the computers use more.
Speaker 1: But are they using that much more than what data centers did previously?
Speaker 1: Like, no.
Speaker 1: Machine learning, like using a machine learning model to answer a question generates so much carbon dioxide that we need to be talking about that.
Speaker 1: The problems we're solving with machine learning, irrespective of all the other moral hazards there, like implicit bias and algorithms, like we're encoding racism and sexism into these solutions, even independent of all of that, we're literally burning coal to solve these problems.
Speaker 1: Services we use online that do like facial recognition arguably are burning coal to make that happen.
Speaker 1: Huge amounts of it.
Speaker 1: And part of this paper that sort of triggered our conversation is quantifying that.
Speaker 1: And that is what is making a lot of people uncomfortable, pointing out the specific carbon footprint of one transformer with two hundred thirteen million parameters in a neural architecture search generates six hundred thousand pounds of CO2.
Speaker 0: So, you know, just to end it one more.
Speaker 1: Like that Tesla thing.
Speaker 1: A programmer doesn't think about that.
Speaker 1: He just writes the algorithm.
Speaker 1: Well, they just write the algorithm.
Speaker 1: See, implicit bias just creeps in.
Speaker 0: I just want to have one more scenario since it was so relevant to our snow day story.
Speaker 0: So let's think about, you know, the cost of the remote learning.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Energy wise.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 1: Millions of kids.
Speaker 0: I was reading stories recently talking about how, yeah, actually we're using tons of energy collectively by doing video chat.
Speaker 0: If you just turn off your video during video chat when it's not necessary, you'll say if everyone did that, we would save quite a bit.
Speaker 0: But it's like, OK, well, so every school is remote learning.
Speaker 0: So all these kids have their video on all day.
Speaker 0: It's using up a lot of electricity.
Speaker 0: But those kids aren't going to school.
Speaker 0: So the transportation cost of going to school is now gone.
Speaker 1: There's also a social cost of not having video chat on deeply reduces engagement, especially with education.
Speaker 1: There seem to be some early papers about that.
Speaker 0: But the school building, you might not need the school building anymore.
Speaker 0: You might be able to just get rid of school buildings.
Speaker 0: Those are using up lots of energy, heating, cooling, lights, etc.
Speaker 0: But then you'll lose like, well, some things you can't do at school, you know, like chemistry lab or, you know, band, I guess would be difficult or sports or any.
Speaker 0: It's like you're missing those learning opportunities if you don't have the school building anymore.
Speaker 0: And you.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: So it's like there's all these tradeoffs, you know, my computer is on, but that means the heater in my office turns on less often than the heaters in the other rooms.
Speaker 0: So it's like, am I using this electricity or am I using the gas that goes into the heat?
Speaker 1: I've talked I've used this every now and then.
Speaker 1: But let's think like forward thinking.
Speaker 0: So if we use if we use the energy on the machine learning, are we going to?
Speaker 0: is that going to result in a savings elsewhere to offset it?
Speaker 0: That makes it, you know, OK.
Speaker 1: In the same way that the increased manufacturing cost of LED is is very likely a net benefit to society because of the radical decrease in electricity use.
Speaker 1: So future thinking.
Speaker 1: Remember this.
Speaker 1: There is literally no difference between an electric space heater and a computer.
Speaker 1: Fundamentally, you pump electrons through it and heat comes out.
Speaker 1: I think there is a far future.
Speaker 1: There's a lot of reasons we can't do this yet, where arguably as we move to an electricity driven society and back away from fossil fuels, we're already in an electricity driven society.
Speaker 1: But then we're in places like New York, like a lot of places still use gas for cars, gas for cooking.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there are things that aren't electricity.
Speaker 1: Like we're not we're not.
Speaker 1: we're not flying two packs in an electric powered plane yet.
Speaker 1: No, not yet.
Speaker 1: But the move to electricity, a lot of people will say that, oh, well, you're just putting the problem somewhere else.
Speaker 1: And yes, that's true.
Speaker 1: But we're putting the problem somewhere fungible.
Speaker 1: Once everything is powered by electricity, we can have very hard conversations about exactly how that electricity is generated.
Speaker 0: But also how much efficiency is lost by converting everything all the time.
Speaker 0: Like those extra conversion layers or how much electricity is lost on power lines, just you know, moving itself.
Speaker 1: And that's the that's the.
Speaker 1: there's a whole complicated space we got to deal with there.
Speaker 1: But I would like to see a future where bulk computing that's being done for the benefit of society could somehow be hardest.
Speaker 1: Like imagine if the heat in your house came from the computers in your house, that when you're not using them, they're trying to make vaccines on their own.
Speaker 0: But also the opposite is true, right?
Speaker 0: How many places on earth are people using like, you know, those dangerous shower heads that use electricity to heat the water?
Speaker 0: If they're not set up properly, they can just, you know, kill you.
Speaker 1: I've used those shower heads before.
Speaker 1: They're fucking terrifying.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: But all of those could just be doing computing and heating the water at the same time with the same amount of energy.
Speaker 1: What if everyone's house had like the furnace in your house was basically a bunch of futuristic GPUs doing cloud computing, like doing computing to make the world a better place because it wastes the same amount of electricity.
Speaker 1: The argument you could make is that a space heater that's not doing calculations is unethical.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it goes both ways, right?
Speaker 0: It's like you're doing calculations for no purpose, like making bitcoins.
Speaker 0: You're just wasting electricity and generating heat and burning, you know, the earth, setting it on fire, quite literally.
Speaker 0: Also, if you just are using electricity to just heat something only, it is just like an electric water kettle to make tea, right?
Speaker 0: Which you have, right?
Speaker 1: What if that water kettle was a little AI?
Speaker 0: That energy could have heated the water and done math and still heated up the water pretty much without losing, you know, really much difference at all.
Speaker 1: Now, of course, material science, mining of rare earth minerals to make those devices, this gets complex.
Speaker 0: Yeah, to make all those chips.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: It's like, is that worth it to make all those chips everywhere?
Speaker 0: Also, up in the... To heat up water, you need two nodes.
Speaker 1: In that 1940s era apartment building in New York City, the GPU boiler has a bug in it because one of the chips failed, like...
Speaker 0: Cyberpunk?
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 1: So I guess the only thing we could... We'll wrap this up.
Speaker 1: If you're in technology, in computing in particular, your individual action in terms of the code you write is not really going to matter unless you are...
Speaker 0: Unless the code you write is running on a large, large system.
Speaker 1: Which is increasingly accessible to people who have enough money because of cloud.
Speaker 1: Like, I could... Scott and I could pay to spin up massive cloud networks to burn... Just to burn money into bitcoins if we wanted to.
Speaker 1: We're not gonna, because we're not evil.
Speaker 1: So if you are in a position... If you're in a job where these sorts of issues come up and someone raises these ethical concerns, my advice to you is amplify their voices and support them.
Speaker 1: So we don't have another situation where someone like Timnit Gebru gets drummed out of Google for saying the truth.
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 0: Don't be... It's like if this comes up, first of all, if it's not, come up.
Speaker 0: Bring it up, right?
Speaker 0: If you think that you work somewhere that has huge computing systems that are using lots of energy and no one really cares about how much energy they make, they just... It's like, you know, you should support like, hey, making your code more efficient could actually help the earth, right?
Speaker 0: Or, hey, is the thing that we're doing with all this energy worth doing if it does this much damage to the earth?
Speaker 0: Maybe we just shouldn't do this business at all or find some other way to do it.
Speaker 0: But yeah, if someone else brings up the concerns, you should join with them.
Speaker 0: You shouldn't be all like, yeah, just poo-pooing, ignoring, whatever.
Speaker 0: Which is what seems to be mostly happening with the coin.
Speaker 0: conversation is people are just like, yeah, it's true.
Speaker 0: We know.
Speaker 0: I don't see a lot of people disputing it, right?
Speaker 0: It's like it's the truth.
Speaker 0: Like Bitcoin?
Speaker 0: Irrespective of everything else wrong with it.
Speaker 1: What you gonna do?
Speaker 1: Bitcoin?
Speaker 0: What you gonna do about it?
Speaker 0: We know.
Speaker 1: I literally think Bitcoin should like that kind of computing for those purposes should be banned for its carbon footprint alone.
Speaker 0: And I'm not against the idea of, you know, a currency that is digital and I'm not against the idea of a distributed self-signing system.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's not the.
Speaker 0: those aren't the reasons I'm anti-coin.
Speaker 1: I'm anti-coin.
Speaker 0: I'm anti-coin because it's not a currency.
Speaker 0: It's just a Fonzie scheme.
Speaker 0: And also it's burning the earth on fire.
Speaker 0: If you change those two things, I'd probably be pro-coin.
Speaker 1: Large scale proof of work where you burn computing cycles to prove that you are a part of it.
Speaker 1: Like that is a fundamental pattern that needs to be stamped out globally.
Speaker 1: We should treat that the same way.
Speaker 1: we treat things like nuclear weapons.
Speaker 1: Like, yes, that exists and you're not allowed to use it.
Speaker 1: And here's why.
Speaker 0: Yes, you can't have one of those in your house.
Speaker 0: It's a bazooka.
Speaker 0: It's not for normal people to have.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Hopefully someday we'll get to the point where no one has a military needs to do it for some reason.
Speaker 0: I guess it can because it's also the government.
Speaker 0: It can get away with it, but they shouldn't be doing it.
Speaker 1: But also the military.
Speaker 1: Here's the U.S.
Speaker 1: military has recognized for a long time, very openly, that climate change is one of the biggest threats to American security.
Speaker 0: Like they know that it is one of their job is to think about it is.
Speaker 0: And it is one of the biggest contributors to said climate change.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: You know, jet that uses a shit ton of fuel.
Speaker 1: And so arguably the U.S.
Speaker 1: military should be focusing very hard on reducing its own carbon footprint, because that reduces the likelihood of a war that the military will be necessary for.
Speaker 0: Mm hmm.
Speaker 1: So, yeah, just if nothing else, like think about this stuff like RIT made us to at least take a few classes on like like ethics and technology.
Speaker 0: I took literally every single class that was available.
Speaker 0: That was something along the lines of technology and society or whatever.
Speaker 0: I took every single one that was offered while I was there with the credits that I had to take.
Speaker 1: This has been Geek Nights with Rim and Scott.
Speaker 1: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design and Brando Kay for the logos.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our Web site at FrontRowCrew.com for show notes, discussion news and more.
Speaker 1: Remember, Geek Nights is not one, but four different shows.
Speaker 1: SciTech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 0: Geek Nights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 0: Geek Nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 0: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.
Speaker 1: Dread Lily Tenebrae, just like a dude guy, Chris Reimer, Finn, Shervin Von Harl and a bunch of people, including someone who's giving us four dollars and ninety nine cents to keep me from saying their name.
Speaker 1: Uh, we almost had some trouble putting the show up, but thankfully Google's bandwidth issues seem to have calmed down.
Speaker 1: If you heard any robot noises during the live stream, I can at least say that that is not in this recording.
Speaker 1: Stay safe out there.
Speaker 1: And now I leave you with... What can I do for you, mister?
Speaker 0: Tell me how to reach the famous Baxter Building.
Speaker 1: It's a long way from here.
Speaker 1: You'd better get some gas.
Speaker 0: Nobody tells me what to do.
Speaker 0: Besides, fuel is for lesser men.
Speaker 0: My vehicle needs no gas.
Speaker 1: You're putting me on.
Speaker 0: Every car needs gas.
Speaker 0: You witless young fool.
Speaker 0: This is not every car.
Speaker 0: And nobody may dare contradict me.
Speaker 0: For when they do, I get angry.
Speaker 0: When I get angry, things begin to happen.
Speaker 1: No!
Speaker 1: Now it's impossible!
Speaker 0: To me, nothing is impossible.
Speaker 0: I can do anything.
Speaker 1: And if you still don't believe me... I believe you!
Speaker 1: I believe you!
Speaker 1: No more!
Speaker 1: Please no more!
Speaker 1: I believe you!
Speaker 1: Then stand aside, for I grow bored with this charade.
Speaker 0: How simple it is to fill the hearts of men with fear.
Speaker 1: I have carried long enough.
Speaker 1: I must not waste my power on others when it is time for the Fantastic Four to tremble before the menace of Magneto.