Speaker 1: It's Wednesday, December 15th, 2021.
Speaker 1: I'm Rym.
Speaker 0: And I'm Scott.
Speaker 1: And this is Geek Nights Tonight.
Speaker 1: It is our holiday.
Speaker 1: animation, anime, and comics gift-giving guide 2021.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: So, uh, we were- I drove Emily upstate just to hang out with her aunt and we were doing some stuff up there the other day on Monday.
Speaker 1: And, uh, I discovered their huge movie buffs, these two.
Speaker 1: They had never seen- and they're big anime fans, too.
Speaker 1: They just had never seen Cowboy Bebop and, uh, they didn't notice it was on Netflix.
Speaker 0: Like, "Hey, what's this new thing on
Speaker 0: Netflix?".
Speaker 1: Oh, they just- they knew about it.
Speaker 1: Like, they know about anime.
Speaker 1: They knew it existed just for various reasons.
Speaker 1: They'd never actually watched it.
Speaker 1: So they got, like, the Blu-rays and while we're up there, they're like, "We're gonna watch
Speaker 1: it.".
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: It's on Netflix.
Speaker 0: Why would you watch a Blu-ray?
Speaker 1: You know, one advantage I noticed watching a couple things on Blu-ray, as opposed to on Netflix, is there is none of that chromatic banding that you get from pretty much any Netflix.
Speaker 0: I mean, yes, it is a compressed video compared to a Blu-ray, but you know what?
Speaker 0: You can also just get a pirated Blu-ray.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 1: I mean, I have a large collection of pirated Blu-rays.
Speaker 0: Which is also usually compressed, but usually, you know, someone, depending on what it is, did a good job compressing it with the right settings.
Speaker 1: All I'm gonna say is the Blu-ray Utena collection that I have, every episode is a ridiculously large file.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if you don't compress it, sure.
Speaker 0: And then, you know, whatever, but go on with the original.
Speaker 1: But we were gonna have a little bit of dinner before I headed back home and I was like, "Well, let's watch an
Speaker 1: episode.".
Speaker 1: Goddamn, is that dangerous.
Speaker 1: It was really, really fucking hard to leave instead of watching the third episode.
Speaker 1: Notice that we already went straight for episode one and episode two.
Speaker 1: Never underestimate the power of cowboy fucking bebop to be amazing.
Speaker 0: Why would- that's not news.
Speaker 1: I know, I just- I guess I forgot.
Speaker 1: Like, when we were at RIT that one time- How could you forget?
Speaker 0: Do you think we made it up when we said it in all these years?
Speaker 1: Yeah, we were like, "Hey, did you ever see cowboy bebop?
Speaker 1: What the
Speaker 1: fuck?".
Speaker 0: You didn't learn your lesson?
Speaker 1: You watched the last two, ten times?
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: And then I woke up from the fugue state as the credits were rolling on episode 26.
Speaker 1: It was now Sunday and, well, that happened.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like, you didn't learn your lesson the past four or five times.
Speaker 1: Goddamn, that show is good.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so that's how it goes.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's been a while since I've seen it.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: And it- but the thing is, right, other stuff, right, you know, that's, you know, this is why Scott is so jaded, right?
Speaker 0: There's so much new stuff, and I watch stuff, and it's like, even if it's not- everyone's like, "Oh my god, everyone's watching this fucking
Speaker 0: thing."
Speaker 0: Right?
Speaker 0: People are going crazy about, I don't know, Game of Thrones or whatever.
Speaker 0: It's like, you watch that, it doesn't- it's not as strong.
Speaker 0: If it was A+ master tier, then it would have the cowboy bebop effect of trapping you there for days on end.
Speaker 0: Right?
Speaker 0: And they're just- hardly anything does that.
Speaker 0: Almost nothing.
Speaker 1: And talking about anime, like, Ava does that to me.
Speaker 1: I don't know if Escaflowne would still do that to me.
Speaker 1: I haven't seen that show in over a decade.
Speaker 0: But I'm just saying, almost nothing does that.
Speaker 1: You know what still- you know what does that?
Speaker 0: In any artistic medium, very few things do that.
Speaker 1: Well, the weakest thing that's ever done that to me is probably Ghost in the Shell standalone complex, which I really like.
Speaker 0: I mean, the hard ones to measure, though, are movies, because a movie- if it's not a trilogy or something, like Lord of the Rings or whatever, it's like, you know, it's like Star Wars- it traps you there for the whole movie, but it's like, well, so it is just, like, any movie that's 90 minutes.
Speaker 0: It's like, only the really bad movie.
Speaker 0: are you stopping early, right?
Speaker 0: Even an okay movie traps you there for the whole movie.
Speaker 1: It's more, if I encounter it, and I get stuck by it, like, randomly, I was clicking through YouTube, and there was a really long clip of Episode 4, someone had just uploaded, and I ended up watching the whole fucking clip.
Speaker 1: It was, like, ten minutes long by accident.
Speaker 1: I was looking for the scene of the twin suns.
Speaker 0: I'm just saying, it's hard to apply that test to anything that doesn't in episodes.
Speaker 1: Actually, that gives me a segue I didn't necessarily intend.
Speaker 1: So, I'll do a Geek Bite.
Speaker 1: There's an animated show that Emily and I watched.
Speaker 1: It's only nine episodes long, season one, and it's broken up- How long are the episodes, though?
Speaker 1: Like, 40-ish minutes.
Speaker 0: And it's the long episodes.
Speaker 1: They're long episodes.
Speaker 1: So, it's basically the equivalent of, like, a 13-episode anime, but the way it's broken up is three sets of three.
Speaker 1: So, every three episodes is basically a story that ends on a really satisfying beat.
Speaker 0: So, it's like an anthology, and the three stories are, like, three different characters?
Speaker 1: Oh, no, it's just one long story, but, like, three episodes happen, and then the next three episodes take place years later, but it's the same characters continuing the story.
Speaker 1: I never thought, like, this is the show that would get me, but Arkane is the show, which is the League of Legends animated show.
Speaker 0: Oh, that one.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I saw that that existed.
Speaker 0: What I'll say about it- It's got all kinds of fancy animation.
Speaker 0: They spent a lot of money on it.
Speaker 1: It is easily the most beautiful animated TV show I have seen in five-plus years, maybe more.
Speaker 0: I mean, you get what you pay for, right?
Speaker 1: Well, 'cause it's French animation, and the studio that did it, like, they... You know, a lot of times you see the concept art for something, and it's amazing, and then the thing that they make when they animate it doesn't look exactly like that concept art.
Speaker 1: They simplify it, they change it.
Speaker 0: Still looks good, but- Oh, you mean, like, when you look at, you know, a Yoshitaka Amano picture?
Speaker 0: And then you look at Final Fantasy VI itself, and you're like, "It's just pixels,
Speaker 0: bro.".
Speaker 1: Yep, or even Vampire Hunter D. Like, that was a much simplified version of how he drew Vampire Hunter D.
Speaker 0: 'Cause how could you animate what he painted?
Speaker 1: Arkane is real fucking close to that.
Speaker 1: That is what surprised me the most.
Speaker 1: Arkane looks like.
Speaker 1: they took the concept art for Arkane and just animated it directly.
Speaker 1: It looks utterly, like, it is so beautiful to watch.
Speaker 1: But independent of that, I'm gonna say right now, it is the best animated TV show I've seen in at least five years.
Speaker 0: Oh, that came out in the last five years, or that you've seen in the last five years?
Speaker 1: That I've seen in the last five years.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: Maybe more.
Speaker 0: So even if you watch something like last year that happened to be old... Yep.
Speaker 1: This is still, it is, it trapped us.
Speaker 1: This is why it was a good segue.
Speaker 1: I didn't plan.
Speaker 1: This is one of those situations where expectations were exceeded.
Speaker 1: We were like, "Alright, let's watch that LOL show.
Speaker 1: I heard it's really well
Speaker 1: animated.".
Speaker 1: We're like, "Alright, we'll just watch it.
Speaker 1: Let's watch an
Speaker 1: episode.".
Speaker 1: And we kinda just had to watch the whole thing as fast as possible.
Speaker 1: And now we gotta wait until 20...
Speaker 0: Even though you don't know anything about League of Legends.
Speaker 0: Nope, I know zero about League of Legends.
Speaker 1: I didn't know the name of a single character in League of Legends.
Speaker 0: I also don't know the name of a single character.
Speaker 1: And it doesn't matter at all.
Speaker 1: This is just a standalone...
Speaker 0: I'm sure that if you do know about League of Legends, though, it's probably greatly enhanced, right?
Speaker 1: Oh, it is.
Speaker 1: You know what it would be like if you know League of Legends?
Speaker 1: Imagine if they may try to think of what would be a good example of this.
Speaker 1: Like, some property, like Prince of Nothing.
Speaker 1: Say they made a Prince of Nothing anime.
Speaker 1: And most people had never read the book, and they didn't know anything about it.
Speaker 1: And we come in...
Speaker 0: We turn it on, and before even the first frame, we're like, "Where's the hair and spear?
Speaker 0: Hair and spear.
Speaker 0: Time.
Speaker 0: Let's
Speaker 0: go.".
Speaker 1: Like, they show a flashback, and we're like, "Ooh, hair and
Speaker 1: spear.".
Speaker 1: Or you see a character, and you're like, "I bet that's Akamian when he's
Speaker 1: young.".
Speaker 1: You know the LoL people are doing that.
Speaker 1: But I'll say, all I'm gonna say, 'cause I'm only geekbiting this, is it is one of the best animated shows I've seen in recent history.
Speaker 1: It is A+ tier.
Speaker 1: I'm not saying S tier only because I saw it too recently, and I cannot make that judgment yet.
Speaker 1: Like, we say that a lot when we review stuff on Geek Nights.
Speaker 1: It's too new.
Speaker 1: A lot of things that feel like S tier fade to A tier with years, so I gotta wait on that.
Speaker 1: But this was so good that I recommend anyone watch it.
Speaker 1: You need to know nothing about League of Legends, nor will you be interested in League of Legends after you watch this.
Speaker 1: You don't even need to know the video game exists.
Speaker 1: It is a fantastic story.
Speaker 1: The characters are good.
Speaker 1: The pacing is fantastic.
Speaker 1: It moves fast.
Speaker 1: Every time you think, kind of like with Dragon Prince and a couple other shows, where every time you think the show is gonna fall into some trope, like, "I see where this is
Speaker 1: going.".
Speaker 1: Like, "Nope, time
Speaker 1: skip.".
Speaker 1: Or, "Nope, the plot is acting like the characters talk to each other, resolve the obvious conflict, and move on to the much more interesting
Speaker 1: conflict.".
Speaker 1: Like, immediately.
Speaker 1: It's like if you took a Blades in the Dark game and crossed it with a fantasy world, and it's just, it's hard to express how much I like this show, and I encourage everyone to watch it.
Speaker 0: Alright, so another anime news, right?
Speaker 0: So, Bell came out.
Speaker 0: We still haven't seen it yet.
Speaker 0: It's gonna be in theaters next year, I think?
Speaker 0: January?
Speaker 0: The tickets are on sale now.
Speaker 0: There's like one or two days of showings.
Speaker 0: I think one's an IMAX day, and the other's a regular free day.
Speaker 1: It's still hard to escape the fact that, even though I don't put a lot of stock in reviews, it's hard to avoid that there's no negative reviews of this movie.
Speaker 1: Like, not one.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I've also heard that somebody watched the movie on one of those online film festivals, and pirated it from there, and you could get that pirated version to watch at home.
Speaker 0: But I'm sure, shortly after the screening, you know, if you're still not comfortable, or it's still not safe to go to a movie theater, wherever you live soon, when it screens, I'm sure it'll play again at some point, right?
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 0: But even if that doesn't happen, there will be some sort of, you know, you gotta imagine home release, streaming, you know, boure, whatever, that comes next year, right?
Speaker 0: At some point.
Speaker 0: So, we'll get around to that.
Speaker 0: But, in other anime movie news, Makoto Shinkai, you know, the third anime movie guy, fourth?
Speaker 1: So, we got a poster here, it shows a door with some moss on it, and a reflection of a sky, and a sky with a bunch of clouds.
Speaker 0: That sounds like a Makoto Shinkai to me.
Speaker 0: So, you know, his uriname was, I guess, legendary, right?
Speaker 0: It was like the biggest deal ever.
Speaker 1: That holds up as an S-tier anime movie.
Speaker 0: I mean, I don't think it's without flaws, but we did an episode on it.
Speaker 0: We did.
Speaker 1: Well, I'm pretty sure we did.
Speaker 1: If we didn't, that's an easy Wednesday show.
Speaker 0: But also, you know, just the number of people that went to see it, right?
Speaker 0: The sales on that movie were just off the charts.
Speaker 0: And then, Weathering With You, eh, we did an episode on that for sure, not as good.
Speaker 1: The theme was muddled in that one, like it didn't really, like the message, it is easy to interpret its message as being a kind of bad one, and I haven't seen any disavowal of that bad interpretation.
Speaker 0: I still think his best work is Hoshi no Koi.
Speaker 1: Oh my god.
Speaker 1: If I think too hard about Hoshi no Koi, I start to get a little choked up.
Speaker 1: For that short little movie about a girl and a robot in space.
Speaker 0: We knew who Makoto Shinkai was when he was making a short animation in his basement, voice acting it himself.
Speaker 1: It's like someone joined Major League Baseball, walked up to bat, just hit a home run, walked around the bases, and every time he comes, every time he walks on the field, he either hits a home run or at least gets a triple.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so he's got a new movie, it's coming next year.
Speaker 0: There's a, I guess, a picture of it in those little press conference they had.
Speaker 0: You can watch on YouTube.
Speaker 1: Susame no Tojimari, adventure story, action film, road movie.
Speaker 1: It follows a 17-year-old girl from Kyushu, meets a young man looking for a door.
Speaker 1: They find a door in the ruins of the mountain and all hell breaks loose.
Speaker 0: Okay, not bad.
Speaker 0: At least it's not looking for a door.
Speaker 0: and you find that at the end, it's looking for a door.
Speaker 0: Oh, we found it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they find the door.
Speaker 1: The plot is they find the kids looking for a door, they find the door, there's a door on the movie poster.
Speaker 1: The door is clearly going to be one of those situations where it is both allegory and the literal reality of this movie is my expectation.
Speaker 0: And Yuasa's Inoue movie, I think, it's making moves.
Speaker 0: It's coming along, it's coming along.
Speaker 1: You know, I say this a lot.
Speaker 1: Our cup overfloweth with animation.
Speaker 1: Like, the last- Not really.
Speaker 0: There's only, those three and Miyazaki are like the four big anime movie makers.
Speaker 1: Oh, I said animation, not anime movies.
Speaker 0: Oh, sure.
Speaker 1: This has just been like an era, a platinum age of animation in the world.
Speaker 0: I guess in some ways, yeah.
Speaker 1: I'd say in a lot of ways, but even now we've got this queue of anime movies I really want to see.
Speaker 1: I feel like there's a lot of Easy Geek Nights episodes once we actually see them all.
Speaker 0: That's because they only queued up because they would be once a year, but they queued up because we've been locked inside, not going to theaters.
Speaker 0: Right, but that's it.
Speaker 1: Our personal cup of anime reviews overfloweth.
Speaker 0: All right, so last news is a sad news, but a huge news.
Speaker 0: So, there's a person named George Perez who is, if you don't know, basically, it's not an exaggeration to say that he is the superhero comic artist, right?
Speaker 1: It's like, you know, there are other big names out there like John Romita or whatever, but it's like- You look at the art that they put in the article we're talking about on the stream, and you look at that and you're like, "That is some comic book art.
Speaker 1: Look at
Speaker 1: that.".
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: George Perez, if you've never heard of him, has been doing superhero comic art since like '70s probably, right?
Speaker 0: And he's done all the big, big, big time stuff, right?
Speaker 0: Like, Christ on Infinite Earths, he was the artist, right?
Speaker 0: Infinity Gauntlet, he was the artist on, I think, most of the issues.
Speaker 0: He had to stop, I think, for some reason.
Speaker 0: Right, but like, you know, Wonder Woman, Avengers, Supermans, right?
Speaker 0: Like, all these, you know, huge, huge, huge comics.
Speaker 0: He was the artist on a ton of them.
Speaker 0: Just the quantity of his output.
Speaker 0: Like, I don't think- If you wanted to own, like, every comic that George Perez wrote or did art on, you would probably not be able to fit them in a room, right?
Speaker 0: The dude's basically been, like, you know, doing nothing since the '70s other than, you know, living life, drawing superheroes, going to cons.
Speaker 0: That sort of- That's pretty much it.
Speaker 0: It's like, I don't know how he could possibly have time to do anything else.
Speaker 0: Just the sheer amount of output.
Speaker 0: And, you know, he's basically just an all-time legend, right?
Speaker 0: But he can also really draw pretty well.
Speaker 0: But yeah, so he was at the doctor because he's old, and they were working on, I think, something in his liver.
Speaker 0: And when they were in there working on his liver, they were like, "Uh-oh, you got the pancreas cancer, the worst
Speaker 0: one.".
Speaker 1: Yup, that's what took down Satoshi Kon.
Speaker 0: No, Satoshi Kon, I think, had lung cancer.
Speaker 1: No, he had pancreatic cancer.
Speaker 1: It was a very similar situation.
Speaker 1: They found it, because usually pancreatic cancer has no symptoms until it's way too late.
Speaker 1: And by the time you detect it, you usually have a very short time left to live.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Well, I know Steve Jobs had it, but Steve Jobs detected it early, could have fixed it, but chose to do some fake medicine instead of real medicine.
Speaker 0: And if he had done real medicine, he probably would be alive now, regardless, because Steve Jobs waited till the last second to do the real medicine.
Speaker 0: He did the fake medicine at the start.
Speaker 0: But yeah, George Perez, they found it, and it's already stage three, and the doctors said he has six to twelve months.
Speaker 0: So he's like, "I'm not even gonna bother.
Speaker 0: I'm just gonna, you know, retire immediately and hang with my family and make the most of what I got
Speaker 0: left.".
Speaker 0: So he posted that to his own Facebook, and it's real sad, and yeah, if you've never paid attention to who this is, you know, now's the time, I guess.
Speaker 0: There's never a wrong time.
Speaker 1: Yep, there's so many great people out there and so many cool things out there that the idea that you can yell at someone for having not encountered a thing that you happen to have encountered, that's a stupid thing to do.
Speaker 1: If you don't know who this person is...
Speaker 0: You know how many George Perez comics I read and looked at in my life, right?
Speaker 0: And I didn't know who that was until the year 2000-something.
Speaker 1: I read a lot of comics.
Speaker 1: I didn't think a lot about who made them when I was younger.
Speaker 1: Only later did I think a lot about that.
Speaker 0: It wasn't until at least like, you know, from '82 to like 2006, so probably like 24-25 years of my life, he was drawing comics that entire time and was still drawing them up until very recently, and I didn't know who he was for those 24-25 years, right?
Speaker 0: So that's that.
Speaker 1: If you didn't see, a little minor news.
Speaker 1: It looks like because it was in theaters recently, a whole bunch of young anime fans basically just discovered Macross.
Speaker 0: Well, not Macross itself, but Macross Plus.
Speaker 0: It was a four-episode OVA series that then had a compilation movie, so you could watch the movie or the OVA.
Speaker 0: I've seen them both, but the memories of them are just combined.
Speaker 0: I have no idea what's added or removed in the movie.
Speaker 0: Other than that, they both tell exactly the same story as far as I can tell.
Speaker 1: Well, even worse, my memories are really colored by that information high music video, so those are the parts I remember the most.
Speaker 0: I mean, that's most of it, right?
Speaker 1: You can figure out the plot, like all the important parts just from that AMV.
Speaker 0: Regardless, either version is excellent, so you can't really go wrong with whichever one you choose or both, right?
Speaker 0: It's pretty much the only good Macross thing besides the original Macross.
Speaker 1: Well, you know like Dynamite.
Speaker 0: Macross Delta, Macross Dynamite, Macross 2.
Speaker 1: Dynamite, Dynamite Explosion.
Speaker 1: God.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: But anyway, so they have this Fathom Events thing in the US, which is where you can get things shown in theaters through them, right?
Speaker 0: So they got Macross Plus shown in theaters like HD Remaster, I think, yesterday, December 14th.
Speaker 0: A bunch of nerds who are willing to go to theaters went to see it.
Speaker 0: I can just watch it whenever I want, I guess.
Speaker 1: I think I have a DVD laying around somewhere.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: But the point is, if you haven't seen Macross Plus, and you didn't go to see it at the theater yesterday, you should go watch the OVA or the original movie Pronto.
Speaker 0: It is ridiculously relevant.
Speaker 0: Pretty much, it was relevant when it came out, and it's somehow always relevant.
Speaker 0: The story that is told there is like still a story of 2021 somehow.
Speaker 1: A dystopia that humanity has been steamrolling toward as hard as possible for a long time now.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: You know, the original Macross TV series was like, yeah, defeat war with, you know, consumer culture and art.
Speaker 0: And Macross Plus is, you know, capitalism and virtual idols.
Speaker 0: Virtual idols and drone warfare, right?
Speaker 1: Coupled with computer security.
Speaker 0: Artificial intelligence.
Speaker 1: And in one last news that's only adjacent to this, but I mention it partly because we're going to talk about like anime, animation, comics, gift giving guide.
Speaker 1: And one thing you shouldn't give anyone is Funko Pops because the Funko company is morally bankrupt garbage.
Speaker 0: So it's always been, it's always been.
Speaker 1: Oh yeah, but they've gone deeper and deeper.
Speaker 1: So this isn't news that they've been doing NFTs.
Speaker 1: They've been deep in NFTs for a while now.
Speaker 0: Even before NFT, you know, blockchain NFTs existed.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they have their stupid vault where they'll like release a figure.
Speaker 0: Well Funko Pops themselves are basically NFTs, right?
Speaker 0: It's a worthless piece of plastic, right?
Speaker 0: It's I guess the piece of plastic is at least...
Speaker 1: Ah, but they're extremely fungible because they're so generic.
Speaker 0: Well, but the thing is, you know, it's a piece of plastic, but at least I guess it's made of matter, which makes it slightly more valuable.
Speaker 1: Someone could, in theory, buy a Funko Pop because they like its aesthetics and they put it like on their desk.
Speaker 1: Or put it on their desk.
Speaker 1: It's no worse than like I have a little Goomba statue just sitting on my desk at work.
Speaker 0: Sure.
Speaker 0: I personally think though that Funko Pops are ugly and not cool.
Speaker 1: Really, really like bland design.
Speaker 1: Obviously like this.
Speaker 1: really cynical capitalist will just apply this to literally any intellectual property to be able to sell this to literally any human on earth.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but it's like before they had Funko Pops, there is one positive thing which I said when we were talking earlier today is that, you know, before Funko Pops existed, if you wanted like a Spider-Man's, you know, thing for your desk, let's say, right?
Speaker 0: Your options were really to buy like a really expensive fucking statue.
Speaker 0: Now those statues, some of them were designed, you know, really in poor taste in terms of especially the female character statues and their poses and outfits.
Speaker 0: But they were, you know, crafted very, very well.
Speaker 0: They were extremely fancy high detail statues sculpted by hand, right?
Speaker 0: Painted by, you know, they were just incredible, you know, as works of art and they cost hundreds of dollars.
Speaker 0: So, and I guess the only other thing they used to have back in the day besides those fancy statues was like action figure for the toy store.
Speaker 0: Right?
Speaker 0: So Funko Pop in its way sort of fills in that gap of like, all right, it's not an action figure from the toy store, right?
Speaker 0: Where you can see like the joints between Spider-Man's arms or whatever, right?
Speaker 0: But it's not a $300 statue.
Speaker 0: You can get a Spider-Man for your desk.
Speaker 0: that's a reasonable price.
Speaker 0: It's just an ugly Spider-Man with a block head.
Speaker 1: But Funko Pop also does a thing where they'll release one of these figures, but they always do these limited runs and then they say it goes into the vault.
Speaker 1: They'll never release it again.
Speaker 1: Because they're trying to get collectors to freak out and, you know, get addicted to collecting these things and artificial scarcity and all the kinds of things that come out of capitalism.
Speaker 0: Well, you know, I mean, it's not any different than like, you know, it's like, hey, you know, Magic might reprint a card or whatever, but it's like.
Speaker 0: everyone can tell which one was the first edition and which one was the reprint, right?
Speaker 0: So it's like even if they do come out, you know, make more Funkos, right?
Speaker 0: People can tell because, you know, it has to be mint in box and then you can see the box will be different on the newer print.
Speaker 0: So you can tell, ah, yes, that one was reprinted.
Speaker 0: You can see that that's the 2021 version, not the original, you know, 2010 version.
Speaker 0: Therefore, it's worth less.
Speaker 1: So what they've done now is they have transgressed on so many lines with this one thing that they did.
Speaker 1: They've got their bullshit NFTs.
Speaker 1: NFTs are a scam.
Speaker 1: I don't think anyone listening to the show thinks otherwise, though.
Speaker 1: We both did have to shut down that crypto bro who wanted to, like, work with us on game design, who reached out to us on Twitter.
Speaker 0: That could have just been somebody who, you know, searched on Google and found out.
Speaker 1: Dude emailed me.
Speaker 1: I can forward you the email.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: He emailed you specifically.
Speaker 1: Remember the tweet?
Speaker 1: He was like,
Speaker 1: "Rim!".
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so Funko Pop is made because they have NFTs.
Speaker 1: They're making an NFT of Bob Ross, the chill painting guy.
Speaker 1: I hope you know who Bob Ross is.
Speaker 1: If you don't, you're about to discover a wonderful world if you go Google for Bob Ross.
Speaker 1: What a just paragon.
Speaker 0: I was thinking about, like, watching a Bob Ross episode and trying to paint on my iPad whatever he was painting and see what happens.
Speaker 1: Oh!
Speaker 0: Because I can't paint for shit.
Speaker 0: I can't even draw.
Speaker 1: So they're making this NFT, but on one hand, that sucks because NFTs are a garbage scam and everyone who is involved in that ecosystem is just scum of the earth trying to destroy the planet.
Speaker 1: There is nothing salvageable on NFTs.
Speaker 1: Two, it's Funko Pop, so they've made a bland, tasteless, capitalist, normalized version of Bob Ross as an NFT.
Speaker 1: Three, Bob Ross's whole thing was the destruction of scarcity.
Speaker 1: Anyone can paint.
Speaker 1: Painting is just a thing we can do.
Speaker 1: He painted for the sheer joy of painting and shared that joy with all of you.
Speaker 1: But fourth, Bob Ross basically got...
Speaker 0: He was also about creating.
Speaker 0: He was encouraging you to create art and not to go and buy art.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if you create terrible art, you are doing more.
Speaker 0: He didn't sell his paintings.
Speaker 0: They're all in a vault.
Speaker 0: The company that owns his estate and whatever, they just have all the paintings.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they're selling all kinds of stuff.
Speaker 0: Licensing deals and all kinds of other nonsense to make money.
Speaker 0: But it's like, they won't sell the actual paintings.
Speaker 0: The thing that's actually an NFT, right?
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, I'll sell you a nothing.
Speaker 0: A word that says you own a word somewhere.
Speaker 0: Well, how about you sell me an actual Bob Ross painting?
Speaker 0: The actual one.
Speaker 0: You have three of each because you had to make three for each episode of the show.
Speaker 0: Hahahaha, no.
Speaker 0: Not a chance, right?
Speaker 1: But Bob Ross himself got swindled out of his own intellectual property and effectively Funko Pop has now licensed it.
Speaker 1: So, there's so much wrong with this that I absolutely have to say you should not be buying Funko Pops because that company is absolutely morally bankrupt.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean, it has been since the start.
Speaker 0: You could just tell from the way it operated from day one that it was just a shady biz trying to take advantage of, you know, gotcha psychology to sell nonsense to sell, you know, to take nerds money, right?
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: Nerds are very vulnerable to that.
Speaker 0: I was lucky.
Speaker 0: I was vulnerable to that too in my youth.
Speaker 1: Do you know how much anime plastic I would have bought if from the years 1994 through about 2004 I had any amount of money?
Speaker 0: Yeah, exactly.
Speaker 0: I would have learned my lesson, thankfully.
Speaker 1: In plastic garbage.
Speaker 1: I would have wallpapered my house in wall scrolls.
Speaker 0: Pretty much, yeah.
Speaker 0: I just learned, you know, some people haven't learned the lesson.
Speaker 0: Like, they just keep doing it.
Speaker 1: You gotta learn that lesson before you have enough money.
Speaker 1: That's the biggest thing.
Speaker 1: But anyway, things of the day!
Speaker 1: So, because it's the holiday season, there's a movie that, at least as a kid, I loved.
Speaker 1: I still appreciate this movie as a holiday movie, but there's a lot of problems with it.
Speaker 1: Home Alone, the original.
Speaker 1: So, you know, I saw it in theaters.
Speaker 1: I was a kid in that era.
Speaker 1: This is a video.
Speaker 1: One of those Wired videos.
Speaker 1: But they have a trauma surgeon.
Speaker 1: And she breaks down, very specifically, every injury in both the first and the second Home Alone movie.
Speaker 1: Very similar to those videos where, like, a professional spy talks about scenes in spy movies.
Speaker 1: She just has a very matter-of-fact and real conversation about what would have actually happened to those people with every single injury they suffer in Home Alone.
Speaker 1: Spoilers!
Speaker 1: There is no way they would have survived either movie.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: By the way, I think we've used that channel as thing of the day at least once before.
Speaker 1: We have once before.
Speaker 1: This channel would be my thing of the day pretty regularly.
Speaker 1: I really limit it.
Speaker 0: I don't subscribe to that channel on YouTube, but I do intentionally go to it and watch videos pretty often.
Speaker 0: And there are a lot of good ones on there.
Speaker 0: The funeral director guy is very good.
Speaker 1: That guy is my second favorite of all the series they've done.
Speaker 1: He's done multiple.
Speaker 1: He did a more recent update where he answered more questions.
Speaker 0: Also, the person that was a thing of the day, the TikTok dermatologist who I talked about some episodes ago, he recently appeared on that channel for the first time.
Speaker 0: Maybe a week or two ago.
Speaker 0: Not even.
Speaker 0: Just days ago.
Speaker 0: So I was like, "Oh, I know that
Speaker 0: guy.".
Speaker 0: It's the dermatologist in TikTok and now he's on the Wired channel answering skin questions from Twitter.
Speaker 0: The experts answer questions from Twitter and the videos where they watch a movie and comment on it.
Speaker 1: There's another kind of video they're doing.
Speaker 1: I don't know how many they've done, but they have this thing of "explain something," like some concept, in five levels of complexity.
Speaker 0: Oh, they've done those for a long time.
Speaker 1: I guess I didn't encounter them until just now, and there was one, a neuroscientist explaining memory to a six-year-old, and then a teenager, and then an adult, and then a scientist, and then another neuroscientist.
Speaker 1: I like that format a lot.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's the third kind.
Speaker 0: I like the first two kinds better.
Speaker 0: But anyway, third kind's not bad.
Speaker 0: But good channel.
Speaker 0: Watch anything that's on there.
Speaker 1: So what do you got?
Speaker 0: Oh, what do I have?
Speaker 0: So most of the games out there where you're building a town, building an empire, building a city or something, whatever, are usually actually games.
Speaker 0: Like SimCity, you can't just go and build all arcologies unless you cheat.
Speaker 0: You can't just build whatever town you want as art.
Speaker 0: You have to actually play SimCity, raise your taxes, not let pollution get out of control, do something about traffic.
Speaker 0: Otherwise you draw a big residential zone, no houses will appear, et cetera.
Speaker 0: So here what we have is something pretty amazing.
Speaker 0: It's called Townscaper.
Speaker 0: All it is is a web page, actually.
Speaker 0: The whole thing's built into a web page for free.
Speaker 0: They must be using WebGL or something.
Speaker 0: It's really fancy.
Speaker 0: Maybe the best WebGL thing I've seen.
Speaker 1: Good sound effects, like a good UI.
Speaker 0: It is indeed WebGL.
Speaker 0: It's pretty amazing.
Speaker 0: But all you do is select a location and either click to build or right click to unbuild.
Speaker 0: And you could build horizontally, vertically around.
Speaker 0: But you're looking at some water and you're looking at some town and you just when you click on a spot, it builds from that spot.
Speaker 0: And it just sort of makes intuitive sense.
Speaker 0: You're building street.
Speaker 0: If you build up from street, it becomes a house.
Speaker 0: You build up from house becomes a tower.
Speaker 0: You build a bunch of house adjacent to each other.
Speaker 0: It becomes like a big, larger building as opposed to a single square.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: You build something that overhangs.
Speaker 0: A big metal support comes out and goes into the water.
Speaker 0: So on and so forth.
Speaker 0: And you could just build to your heart's content, like, you know, to create an artistic scene.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Of a town, an island town in the water.
Speaker 0: that looks really nice.
Speaker 0: And it's a lot of fun to play with and really quite an impressive thing to develop in a web browser, technologically speaking.
Speaker 0: So.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: In the meta moment, the Geek Nights Book Club book, The Tale of Genji.
Speaker 1: I'm steamrolling through it now.
Speaker 0: It says I've got 20 something hours left and I'm reading, you know, I'm trying to read at least an hour plus every day, which I've been doing since I'm not working or anything.
Speaker 0: So I'm probably going to make it next year, early next year, for sure.
Speaker 0: I don't have any work excuse to stop me.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I already picked the next book.
Speaker 0: The only thing I'm really doing besides that is, you know, maintaining life, eating, sleeping, et cetera, watching hockey, you know, things you need to do to live.
Speaker 1: I'm still working this week, but I'm off next week.
Speaker 0: And then I'm working on our new website, which is coming along.
Speaker 0: And that's pretty much all I'm doing with my days inside here.
Speaker 0: Not working.
Speaker 0: Not working for money, at least.
Speaker 0: I'm just getting paid because PTO.
Speaker 1: So beyond that, I did appear for approximately three hours at the Penny Arcade Expo PAX Unplugged last weekend.
Speaker 1: And I did one panel, Rare Game Mechanics.
Speaker 1: It was basically the final, like, refined version of a panel that we piloted years ago at MAGFest in the tabletop area.
Speaker 1: And it went really well.
Speaker 1: I'm really happy with it.
Speaker 1: And as I promised, the whole thing was on YouTube with slides before the end of PAX Unplugged.
Speaker 1: It's just there.
Speaker 1: You can just watch it.
Speaker 1: If you weren't at the con, you didn't miss anything.
Speaker 1: Whole panel's just there.
Speaker 1: If you have any thoughts, feedback, comment, questions, just let me know.
Speaker 0: I got one more meta.
Speaker 0: It's December.
Speaker 0: Well, it's not Christmas yet, so it's still Advent times.
Speaker 0: And even though I am a non-believing, Jew-type person, right?
Speaker 0: There's the Advent of Code, which is where there's a programming puzzle every day from December 1st through 25th.
Speaker 0: And I've been doing those puzzles, and I've been making recordings of myself solving those puzzles every day.
Speaker 0: I just uploaded the 15th one, because today is the 15th.
Speaker 0: I noticed that the more recent videos are getting less views because they're long and probably not exciting.
Speaker 0: Just me looking at a screen.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: Just looking and thinking, looking and thinking.
Speaker 0: And also, the problems are getting harder.
Speaker 0: Yesterday and today, I had to pause the video, figure out what to do, and then come back.
Speaker 0: So, I think tomorrow I'm going to change my format.
Speaker 0: What I'm going to do is solve it just on my own without recording anything.
Speaker 0: And then, I'm just going to make a video when I'm done explaining the solution that I came up with, if I do indeed come up with a solution.
Speaker 0: I might get stumped at some point.
Speaker 0: So, check if you got bored with the other videos.
Speaker 0: Maybe watch the one from tomorrow, the 16th.
Speaker 0: See if my new format is any better.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I'm working on it.
Speaker 0: It's mostly for me to solve it, right?
Speaker 0: I don't care too much about the video part, but it's not too much effort to just do both if I'm doing one.
Speaker 1: Could be a chill time.
Speaker 1: Just hang out and watch Scott working on a problem.
Speaker 0: If you want to learn some programming, you could learn a lot from me, who's been doing it for my whole life.
Speaker 0: But also, I'm learning.
Speaker 0: Today, I learned about a heap queue thing I've never seen before in my whole life.
Speaker 1: Alright, so it's that time of year.
Speaker 1: We have a big queue of anime we want to review, but we haven't watched these movies yet.
Speaker 1: So, as we've done on the other Knights of Geek nights, we did a holiday gaming gift guide.
Speaker 1: We did a holiday tech gift guide.
Speaker 1: Now, it's our holiday weeb and comic nerd gift guide.
Speaker 0: So, it's kind of tough to buy something for a weeb comic nerd, right?
Speaker 0: Because, if someone just wants to read comics or watch anime, it's like, I guess you could gift someone a year of Crunchyroll.
Speaker 0: That would be the same as giving them money, though, kinda.
Speaker 1: A lot of people really are trying to get their friends to watch things or read things that they like, to the point that a lot of comic and anime and animation gifts are often just, "I'm giving you this because I'm trying to trick you into watching it because I want you to see it so we can talk about
Speaker 1: it.".
Speaker 1: I think that's a thing that happens.
Speaker 0: That's a guarantee.
Speaker 0: Let's say somebody hasn't read the Akira manga.
Speaker 0: A legendary thing that every human should read if it's in their language.
Speaker 0: It's like, you'd buy that for someone.
Speaker 0: It's expensive.
Speaker 0: The six-volume set.
Speaker 0: It gets available still.
Speaker 0: It's in print and it's actually the best version.
Speaker 0: yet that's available in English.
Speaker 0: You get that for someone.
Speaker 0: Is that really gonna get them to read it?
Speaker 0: Even if they were a fan of the movie, I feel like if you buy someone a comic or book, they're not gonna read it.
Speaker 0: It'd be really rare for that to actually happen.
Speaker 0: I do not recommend actually buying somebody a book, an anime, a movie in hopes that they will watch it.
Speaker 0: If they haven't watched it already.
Speaker 1: I'd say the only good gift that is a book or a compilation, things like that, is usually when you know someone is a fan of that work.
Speaker 1: Say you know someone is a mega-nerd and loves the hell out of Akira.
Speaker 1: It's just their favorite thing.
Speaker 1: And if they're also kind of a collector person or don't live in the city and actually have a house or a reading room or something, and you know they don't have the fancy collector bundle of that comic, that can be a good gift.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Well, for example, let's say you know somebody has already read all of Sandman, for example.
Speaker 0: Maybe they read all of Sandman at the library, which is a good strategy, or they read it all digitally.
Speaker 0: There's like a big, fancy, hardcover Sandman edition that's out, like box, mega box, fanciness, ultra deluxe.
Speaker 0: So if they've already read it, if someone has already read all of something like Sandman, like Akira, and they don't own it, then it's actually quite likely they're going to read it again.
Speaker 0: I've read the Akira box set that I've got several times.
Speaker 0: I'll probably read it again now just because I'm talking about it.
Speaker 0: It's the Cowboy Bebop effect Rim was talking about.
Speaker 0: If I start, that's it.
Speaker 0: And then I won't finish Telegenji, so I won't.
Speaker 1: You've given them the gift of triggering them to enjoy that thing they love again when they weren't necessarily planning to.
Speaker 1: And for a lot of people, that doesn't apply as much to like me and Scott, but to like a lot of more normal people.
Speaker 1: They do like to have those artifacts in their lives, especially if they don't live in a tiny apartment in the city.
Speaker 0: Exactly.
Speaker 0: So if you're going to buy somebody an actual comic, an actual book, an actual anime box set, right?
Speaker 0: I think you actually want to lean towards something that you a) know they're a huge fan of already, not trying to make them a fan of something new, and b) they don't have.
Speaker 0: You don't want to buy someone something they got.
Speaker 0: That's obvious.
Speaker 0: Okay, so the next obvious play, right, is you're buying anime gifts, is you can go get some merch.
Speaker 0: Get the plastic.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: It's like superheroes, animes, all these things, they make all their money from merch, merch is out there to get, you can go get it.
Speaker 0: But 99% of the merch is garbage, so you should be able to know, you know this person you're buying a gift for well enough.
Speaker 1: Are they the kind of person who still puts wall scrolls up on their wall?
Speaker 1: Do they have a room filled with anime weeb plastic?
Speaker 1: Do they have busts around?
Speaker 1: You can figure out the level of quality, nature, style.
Speaker 0: Do they have a cork board full of pins?
Speaker 1: If there's someone like that, if someone's got a giant cork board filled with anime pins, then a pin or a collection of pins from an anime you know they like is just a hole in one.
Speaker 1: Assuming they don't already have those exact pins.
Speaker 0: Exactly, so if you know the person likes awful merch, it's real easy, just buy them the awful merch for the thing they like that they don't have already.
Speaker 0: It's super easy, just shoo in.
Speaker 1: It could be nice merch, like a really fancy or limited run art book.
Speaker 1: It's the same as the plastic, it's just a different level of cost and like, I don't want to say class, I don't want to make a class judgement here, but a different level of how someone engages with their collector mentality fandom.
Speaker 0: Well of course you could, like I was going to say, if it's someone who's not into the cheapo garbage merch, you could go and find the rare merch, the special merch, the thing they didn't even know existed.
Speaker 0: The thing that's merch, but is also a useful thing.
Speaker 0: Just the other day I was looking, you know, the instapot.
Speaker 0: An instapot is something that almost everyone is going to want to have in their kitchen.
Speaker 0: It's a very useful, high quality cooking device.
Speaker 1: I love the shit out of ours.
Speaker 0: They have Star Wars instapots right now.
Speaker 0: They got an R2D2 one, they got a Darth Vader one.
Speaker 0: I'm not even selling for them, right?
Speaker 0: They didn't pay me for this.
Speaker 0: But if you got a Star Wars fan on your hands, right?
Speaker 0: Well how about a Star Wars instapot if they don't have an instapot, right?
Speaker 0: It's like you can get a gift in another useful category of object, right?
Speaker 0: That has nothing to do with nerdiness, but you get the nerdy version of it and suddenly you're in business, right?
Speaker 0: They got Hello Kitty, they got Hello Kitty fucking everything, right?
Speaker 0: They got Pusheen, Pusheen everything.
Speaker 0: Not as much as Hello Kitty though.
Speaker 1: Now what I'm really a fan of, in my opinion and among my set, the gift along those lines that's the best is the one that's either very high quality or is subtle.
Speaker 1: Like a tie that just has the anime girl just on it in the center, that's eh.
Speaker 1: I'm sure there are people who like that kind of thing, that's not my bag.
Speaker 1: But like the tie that's very subtly the nerve logo, but like tasteful, subtle.
Speaker 1: A person who doesn't know wouldn't recognize it, but a person who knows recognizes it.
Speaker 0: I like that kind of style.
Speaker 0: A tie clip that has a Rainbow Dash cutie mark on it.
Speaker 1: Oh, some Rainbow Dash cuff links would be like an A+ gift.
Speaker 0: Right, exactly.
Speaker 0: So we like that stuff, but there are also other merches out there that are like the exclusive, rare, really clever, perhaps limited, perhaps not merches, usually imported oftentimes.
Speaker 0: For example, there was a big hype on the internet recently.
Speaker 0: There was that Gengar backpack.
Speaker 1: Oh yeah.
Speaker 0: So something like that.
Speaker 0: It's like really high quality, really fancy, really clever.
Speaker 0: There's something special about it.
Speaker 0: It's not just a normal, old, everyday plastic toy.
Speaker 1: I mean the best gift in that space is the merch that the person would like, but either don't know exists or wouldn't be able to get on their own.
Speaker 0: Yep, exactly.
Speaker 0: And the thing is, if somebody is into the cheap merch, like they're just a kid, they love all the merch, even if it's the plastic nothing, getting them the fancy one is still going to work.
Speaker 0: It's just I figure.
Speaker 0: why get the fancy one if that person will be satisfied with the not fancy one?
Speaker 0: Why blow the money?
Speaker 0: Spend the money commensurate with what it takes to make the person happy.
Speaker 0: The gift receiver happy.
Speaker 1: Especially, going back to something you said earlier, for a superhero underwear pervert type comic fan in particular, if they've read all the X-Men, but they have floppies laying around, even if they are a collector, if they don't own those big compilation books specifically, those I've seen, like we said earlier, be a trigger of, "Well, I read all of the original Road of X-Men
Speaker 1: again."
Speaker 0: Because they're
Speaker 1: not going to be getting out their original that they've got in their plastic case somewhere, but if you get them that modern print, they're probably going to read it because they don't actually want to go get out 40 floppies to read that same story.
Speaker 0: Now, in terms of collectible stuff, if someone likes to collect things, super easy.
Speaker 0: Just get them.
Speaker 0: whatever the thing they collect is, they'll always want more of it forever.
Speaker 0: They haven't learned the lesson yet.
Speaker 1: Just like grandma who collects those spoons.
Speaker 0: Exactly.
Speaker 0: What if they have learned the lesson?
Speaker 0: What if you want to buy something for me, literally?
Speaker 0: Well, think about this.
Speaker 0: Even someone like me who learned the lesson, they collected something in their past.
Speaker 0: for sure, if they're a nerd.
Speaker 0: 99% chance they collected something in the past.
Speaker 0: So, if I was going to buy something for Rim, right?
Speaker 0: Rim who collects nothing and wants to get rid of all the things in his house.
Speaker 0: You know what I could buy, Rim?
Speaker 0: I could go out on eBay and get Rim a mask action figure from the 80s.
Speaker 1: Yep, just one.
Speaker 1: Because I'm not collecting them, but if I had just one, I would never buy that on my own.
Speaker 1: But if one appeared as a gift, he'd be sitting on my desk at work.
Speaker 0: That's right, right?
Speaker 0: If I got Rim like a mask Funko Poppy, he'd throw that shit right in the trash.
Speaker 1: Yup, I could hit someone in the street.
Speaker 0: So, it's like you could come to me and you could buy, I used to collect superhero cards in the 90s.
Speaker 0: If you went on eBay, there are still plenty of unopened boxes and packs of those cards.
Speaker 1: Oh yeah, get like one booster pack.
Speaker 0: Yeah, just get like, it would cost you like five bucks to get like one pack of like Marvel superhero card series 3.
Speaker 1: Fuck, I just imagined how fun it would be for about five minutes to take like one of those old unopened packs and just open it and read all the cards.
Speaker 0: I got over that.
Speaker 0: I don't want a thousand of those cards, but I would- I thought about it and I was going to spend the money and then I just went on YouTube and watched someone else open them.
Speaker 1: Ooh, that's a pro move.
Speaker 0: And then I saved my money and I saved the space in my apartment.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so you could do something like that.
Speaker 0: Alright, so obvious next thing you got to do when you're done with the official merch is you got to go for the fan merch.
Speaker 0: Go to your artist alley, go look at who was in the artist alley at the convention and go to their website, go to their Etsy shop, go to their Instagram and figure out where their shop is.
Speaker 0: Right, maybe they have a Kickstarter even.
Speaker 1: Just like we said in our other episodes on this topic of buying gifts during the holidays, commissioning art of the thing they like from an artist who has a cool style is like the A+ gift.
Speaker 1: Like that is S tier gifting in the modern era 2021.
Speaker 0: Yep, just fine.
Speaker 0: Or a lot of the artists out there, especially the bigger ones, they know it's holiday season.
Speaker 0: That's their only job as artist, right?
Speaker 0: I think it's a little too late now because it's already December 15th.
Speaker 0: But a lot of them, it's like they make specific news designs for the holiday season expecting you to buy them as gifts and they put them up and then they sell out, right?
Speaker 0: A lot of calendars, especially calendars are really hot in November, December from artists.
Speaker 0: So like, you know, some artists, I know they put up calendars and then they sell out right away.
Speaker 0: But if you can get one of those calendars and the art in the calendar is the art your gift receiver will appreciate, go for it.
Speaker 1: So especially with comics and anime, a gift that can often go well, this is especially good for someone who's a really big fan but hasn't gotten to the point of knowing anything about their hobby.
Speaker 1: Like the kid who's watched a million anime but has never heard of even a single director, like that kind of person.
Speaker 1: One of those books that is a combination art book but also history, like a Fred Schott book sometimes, or like a book about the comics industry, things like that tend to be the kind of gift that someone like that might not necessarily ever think to buy.
Speaker 1: And it's not the kind of thing they'd ever think to start reading on Wikipedia, but a well-made book about their hobby could one, help them level up their interest in that hobby, two, edify them a little bit, and three, it's a gift that they would probably enjoy and appreciate but wouldn't have expected or sought out on their own.
Speaker 0: Well I mean I think if you're gonna go down that road, right, it's like if you buy someone a big coffee table art book, it's like are they gonna read it?
Speaker 1: And they gotta know the person.
Speaker 1: Gift giving always comes down to knowing the person.
Speaker 1: I, in my life until I moved to the city, loved the shit out of giant history coffee books with giant photos, like here's a coffee table book of tanks made in 1939.
Speaker 1: I just lived for that shit.
Speaker 1: But now I don't want anything like that in my life.
Speaker 1: I'm trying to get rid of every physical book I own except for a handful of very important or sentimental ones.
Speaker 0: But actually in comics specifically, we did an episode of magazines recently talking about how a lot of them these days are just full of ads and whatnot, and there are still plenty of magazines just like that, but there are also magazines that are very informational deep dives, big long interviews, that sort of thing.
Speaker 0: And so if you just subscribe to that magazine and have it sent to that person's house, right, it's actually quite likely that that magazine will end up near the shitter and get read, and then they'll learn something that way.
Speaker 0: So make sure, you know, for example, I think there's like Back Issue magazine is one that I know.
Speaker 0: It's like a very underwear-pervert-y, deep-diving, you know, I don't even think it comes out every month.
Speaker 0: I think it comes out maybe quarterly, maybe, I'm guessing?
Speaker 0: But, you know, it's a huge thing.
Speaker 0: So, something like that.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: I guess, oh, final thing, obviously, right, is make something, right?
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: If you can, you just make something.
Speaker 1: It's COVID times.
Speaker 0: Better than commissioning, just making.
Speaker 1: It's COVID times, so the gift that I can't recommend but is an A+ gift is if there's an event, like, a creator you know they like is going to be doing a road show or signing autographs or like...
Speaker 0: Tickets to go to the movie that's playing.
Speaker 1: Tickets to go to the movie that has the director doing like the Q&A afterward, like those kinds of things.
Speaker 1: A lot of people don't realize those things exist, don't pay attention enough to notice that they're happening.
Speaker 1: A lot of comic, anime, animation fans, those are the kinds of gifts that they would never in their lives think to do, and you can be the hero, but it's hard to recommend that during COVID.
Speaker 0: I guess the last one that I can think of for now, yeah, I guess I haven't thought of anything else, is we talked about not getting somebody like a comic or a thing if they tried to get them to watch it, right?
Speaker 0: But what you can do is a lot of people out there, even if they have all these subscriptions to streaming services and comiXologies and who knows what else they've got digitally or whatever, not everything is on there, right?
Speaker 0: Which is why smart nerds like us pirate everything.
Speaker 0: You might have on the receiving end of your gift, someone who doesn't pirate, doesn't know how to pirate or whatever.
Speaker 1: I see where you're going.
Speaker 0: Yeah, load them up, get them a big old, just go, you don't have to cost you any money, right?
Speaker 0: Go and build up some huge pirated collection of stuff and hook it up for them in such a way that they can go dig into it, right?
Speaker 0: Be like, but yeah, here you go.
Speaker 1: It's every anime from the 90s and 2000s all on a hard drive or every anime from the 90s and 2000s on a flash drive in a Raspberry Pi that is an HDPC.
Speaker 1: Just plug it into your TV.
Speaker 1: It'll just work.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I set it up with the thing and you know, it's like, oh, here.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's a Kindle preloaded with all the sports manga ever, right?
Speaker 0: And it's like, just go wild, right?
Speaker 0: With the, with the piratey gift.
Speaker 0: And then that might actually, you know, be something that the person will, you know, use, right?
Speaker 0: As opposed to here, I got you, you know, five volumes of One Punch Man because I really want you to read it.
Speaker 0: And then it sits there and then, you know, that's it.
Speaker 0: They never read it.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: Unlike gaming, because in the gaming show on this, we talked about how like being willing to play a game with someone is actually a really good gift.
Speaker 1: I've seen people posit this idea before.
Speaker 1: I don't think being willing to watch something with a friend as a gift that you weren't already willing to watch, except as a gift that does not play the same way with a media you watch as opposed to a game.
Speaker 1: Like don't give your friend the gift of I'll watch that stupid show that I think is stupid with you.
Speaker 1: That's not going to go well.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's, you know, it's like, that is my gift.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Well, not only that, but it's like, what kind of friend if, if you, A, end up enjoying the show and you should have just watched it on your own, you were wrong.
Speaker 1: You should watch Arkane.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 1: You should watch Arkane, Scott.
Speaker 0: Sure.
Speaker 0: But B, if you watch the show and don't like it and you suffer and that's a gift, you're basically saying that like, if that person is your friend and they consider it a gift that you suffered, it's like they're enjoying that you're suffering.
Speaker 0: Are they, is that really your friend?
Speaker 0: Why are you?
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: It's like, why are you willing to suffer for someone who enjoys that you suffer?
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Usually when you, usually when you suffer for them, it's like for their sake, like, you know, I worked really hard to get money to pay your medical bills so you don't die.
Speaker 0: Not I suffered so you could watch me suffering and you enjoyed it unless you're into that sort of thing.
Speaker 0: But assuming that's not the case, right?
Speaker 0: If that person wants you to suffer and considers it a gift, that person's probably not a friend and probably doesn't deserve a gift and don't suffer for them.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: Now, if you have a friend where you know this would work well, the good equivalent of that would be, again, COVID asterisk, depending on when you listen to this, because COVID, like, maybe this is not a good idea right now in the current situation on Earth.
Speaker 1: But arranging the weekend marathon of the show is, assuming that it's a show, you know, your friend would watch, especially if it's like a party where like some other people come to.
Speaker 1: But if you arrange the time, arrange the place, arrange the food, like make it an event that works and they just show up and get to watch the show.
Speaker 1: That could be a very good gift if it's the kind of person where they would appreciate that kind of gesture.
Speaker 0: If it's also, if it's safe, remember, you can rent movie theaters, right?
Speaker 0: For private screenings of things.
Speaker 1: It's not even that expensive.
Speaker 0: It's not even that expensive and you can get your food on there, right?
Speaker 0: So, I don't know if that's a great holiday gift, but it's a good, you know, birthday party gift.
Speaker 1: I think it would be a great holiday gift in a non-COVID time.
Speaker 1: Like, yo, I rented this theater and we're going to watch the Ava movies ourselves.
Speaker 0: You know what?
Speaker 0: That's a good, that's a good multi-gift, right?
Speaker 0: It's like, you don't want to buy a gift for each person.
Speaker 0: You're like, I'm gifting the entire friend group a party at the rented movie theater.
Speaker 0: It's like, yes, right?
Speaker 0: That could work.
Speaker 0: If it wasn't COVID, you might actually save money versus the cost of 10 gifts if you got a lot of friends.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Similar along those lines, but again, these are gifts that are hard to recommend in 2021.
Speaker 1: If it's an anime weeb who's really into anime music and karaoke and like they've gone full weeb, then taking them out and arranging a karaoke party at the really nice place for four hours.
Speaker 1: A plus gift, not in the year 2021, but outside of that, A plus gift.
Speaker 0: Concerts also, you know, could be related, right?
Speaker 0: You might be able to go to like, not just, you know, oh, the band that did the opening song to your favorite anime is touring the US or the idol group is in the US, but also, ah, the, the symphony is covering the soundtrack of the, you know.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Or for, Joe Hisaishi is doing shows in Radio City.
Speaker 0: They're all sold out and the tickets are like a thousand dollars, so we're not going.
Speaker 0: But if you could get them.
Speaker 0: That's a gift for me.
Speaker 0: I'll take it.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Like your gaming friend, like, oh, some symphony is covering some Final Fantasy music.
Speaker 1: Easy gift.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: Exactly.
Speaker 1: So and beyond that, like we've because we've done this topic on multiple other Geek Nights nights, a lot of our other advice would just be repeating ourselves and really just boils down to.
Speaker 0: I think we did repeat ourselves anyway.
Speaker 0: We did.
Speaker 1: But we did have the right anime flavor because like some things don't work the same way in this world.
Speaker 1: In the world of anime or passive media as opposed to active media.
Speaker 1: But don't buy Funko Pops like don't like.
Speaker 1: that's just a specifically bad gift considering everything we just talked about.
Speaker 1: But generally it comes down to knowing your friend.
Speaker 1: Like a good friend knows what kind of gift to get another friend.
Speaker 1: Scott knows not to get me the same thing that I know not to get him.
Speaker 1: Anything that takes up a ton of space.
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 1: Hey, Scott, I got you a ray themed refrigerator.
Speaker 1: It's arriving tomorrow.
Speaker 0: Well, I'm in a rented apartment, so I'm not allowed to change the refrigerator.
Speaker 1: I got you the Eye of Vogler.
Speaker 0: Unless there's a penguin in it and it's a mini fridge, I don't want it.
Speaker 1: I got you the Eye of Vogler filled with giant robo DVDs.
Speaker 0: Oh, that's great.
Speaker 0: I'll resell that.
Speaker 0: I did.
Speaker 1: I did eventually throw away that Eye of Vogler.
Speaker 1: I do not have that anymore.
Speaker 0: You couldn't resell it for a bunch of money?
Speaker 1: No, and it was not rare.
Speaker 1: I do have the DVDs still, but I got rid of every DVD case I own.
Speaker 1: And every DVD I own is in this giant binder.
Speaker 0: Oh, I did that a long time ago.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: I did that a long time ago, too.
Speaker 1: I haven't acquired new DVDs since then.
Speaker 0: Nope.
Speaker 0: Well, I think I might have a couple.
Speaker 1: I did acquire the remastered super fancy utenna box.
Speaker 1: That's the last DVD I think I acquired.
Speaker 1: That was a long goddamn time ago.
Speaker 0: I bought a USB optical drive just in case.
Speaker 0: I don't think I've used it.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: Same.
Speaker 1: I have a USB optical drive.
Speaker 0: And that was years, many years ago that I bought it.
Speaker 1: The last time we used it was pre-COVID because it was faster to watch, what, Three Witches or some movie we were watching.
Speaker 1: Because we happened to have the DVD physically available.
Speaker 1: It was faster than pirating it.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 1: But yeah, that's about it.
Speaker 1: We can stop right there.
Speaker 1: This has been Geek Nights with Rym and Scott.
Speaker 1: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design, and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at FrontRowCrew.com for show notes, discussion news, and more.
Speaker 1: Remember, Geek Nights is not one, but four different shows.
Speaker 1: Sci-Tech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays, and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 0: Geek Nights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 0: Geek Nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 0: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.
Speaker 1: And the Patreon patrons for this December 15th episode of the Geek Nights Podcast are... Heidi McNicholal, Joyce Link, Eiji, Dreid, Lily, Tenebrae, and a bunch of people who don't really want me to say their names.
Speaker 1: Chris Rhymer, Clinton Walton, Dex, Finn, JustLikeADudeGuy, Kishiai85, Rebecca Dunn, Revu, Medbull, 34 Cowards, Sam Erickson, Shervin Von Harl, Taylor Braun, TheIronFront.
Speaker 1: You hold the key to my heart and a bunch of people who do not want me to say their names.
Speaker 1: We're skipping shows off and on during the holiday season as we do every year.
Speaker 1: That'll continue this season, but you'll get a few more shows over the course of the next few weeks.
Speaker 1: And we'll see how things go.
Speaker 1: Stay safe out there, wear your masks.
Speaker 1: I wouldn't necessarily say going to conventions is a great idea in the near term considering how Omicron is going.
Speaker 1: But for now, I just leave you with...