Speaker 0: It's Tuesday, March 9th, 2021.
Speaker 0: I'm Rym.
Speaker 1: I'm Scott.
Speaker 0: And this is Geek Nights.
Speaker 0: Tonight, we are talking about Moon Hunters.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: So if you're watching the livestream, you might notice that my background is a lot different, because I actually got, finally, a proper professional backdrop.
Speaker 0: And the difference between the cheap ones that I've used before and then bailed on versus the expensive ones is that the expensive ones are way smaller and are really easy to deploy and undeploy and take up only a tiny amount of space, so I'm very happy with this purchase.
Speaker 1: Are you saying the more expensive one is superior?
Speaker 0: The more expensive one is superior to a degree.
Speaker 0: that is shocking in this case.
Speaker 1: As with many things in capitalist society, you get what you pay for.
Speaker 0: The only difference, though, is that for anyone who doesn't live in, like, a New York apartment, the expensive one is really not better because you got space to just have, like, a backdrop.
Speaker 0: But in New York, like, I don't have room for that shit.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if you have room, you can just take, like, a sheet and spray paint it with green paint or some shit.
Speaker 0: If you got a room, just have an actual background.
Speaker 1: Or, like, paint your wall green.
Speaker 0: Exactly.
Speaker 0: But I didn't go with green.
Speaker 0: I decided, because chroma-keying, like, I don't really do that much.
Speaker 1: You got magenta, gray.
Speaker 0: I went black.
Speaker 1: Black?
Speaker 1: Okay, black works.
Speaker 1: Black actually works really well.
Speaker 1: As long as you don't wear black.
Speaker 0: But even then, like, the blacks in the foreground stand out really nicely because it's the super matte black.
Speaker 0: It actually works pretty well.
Speaker 0: I'm excited about this.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you can, like, if you, even if the background is black, if you light yourself heavily, anything you're wearing, unless you're wearing, like, a Vantablack shirt or something, you know, you'll be, I guess, you could make it work.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it also means I can get away with having way less light in my face, so I turn my spotlight way the fuck down, and it's real nice.
Speaker 1: Anyway.
Speaker 1: All right, so there's, uh, we got a lot of materials going on, because it's been a while since we did a show at all, right?
Speaker 1: And some big happenings in the gaming world.
Speaker 1: And for once, I guess it's not good, but there was a drama that was closer to us than most dramas in the past.
Speaker 1: And in addition to it being closer to us, I feel like I know everything there is that we need to say about it and can actually comment on it, unlike, say, the MAGFest drama where we were like, "We don't know what to make of this," right?
Speaker 1: "We know exactly what to make of this
Speaker 1: drama.".
Speaker 1: So, we've already broken it down, I think, on our forum and our Discord and everywhere else, so if you weren't in those places, you might not have heard, but we'll just break it down again on our show.
Speaker 1: so there's no, you know, questions roaming around, right?
Speaker 1: So, to give you the background, there is a person named Adam Koebel.
Speaker 1: Koebel?
Speaker 1: I think it's Koebel.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: Is a well-known tabletop RPG community person, or former community person.
Speaker 0: Former is a good way to put it.
Speaker 1: Sure.
Speaker 1: Adam Koebel was one of the people who created the Dungeon World RPG, which is a game that I've played a few times and enjoyed the few times I played it, though it is not without problems.
Speaker 1: I don't think we've done an episode on it, right?
Speaker 0: We played it at PAX.
Speaker 0: We're gonna play it, like, one more time and then do a show on it and then COVID.
Speaker 1: I don't think we need to do a show on it anymore.
Speaker 1: Anyway, it's a tabletop RPG that is powered by the apocalypse.
Speaker 1: It has the same base system as Apocalypse Worlds, as many games have these days, but the setting is classic, you know, dungeon-y, right?
Speaker 1: You know, D&D setting.
Speaker 1: Adam Koebel was also a GM for one of those... I don't know which one, I could look it up, but it's one of those online, you know, come watch people play RPGs on Twitch things, right?
Speaker 1: So he was a GM for one of those.
Speaker 1: And during one of those sessions for that RPG, where he was the GM, he, without the consent of the players, right, there was a sexual assault scene in the game that was quite harrowing for the players.
Speaker 0: When I link to the news, the news itself links to, like, the stream at the point where this happens.
Speaker 1: Obviously, content warning for watching that stream.
Speaker 0: I'll even quote what the article says, "This clip is not for the faint of heart.
Speaker 0: Even if a description of a sexual assault doesn't bother you, the sheer mortifying train wreck in progress likely
Speaker 0: will.".
Speaker 0: Because if you weren't familiar with the incident that is sort of why Koebel is not really welcome in these spaces, this incident is probably way worse than you expected.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: So this is the main incident, which is why he was, quote, "cancelled," right?
Speaker 1: And basically became, you know, he didn't face any actual real, like, consequences legally or anything like that, right?
Speaker 1: He didn't, like, lose a job or anything, you know, but he was basically shunned, rightly so, by the community.
Speaker 1: He was like a pariah, right?
Speaker 0: And you can read about all the details, like, he didn't really issue an apology, he stayed silent for a while.
Speaker 1: His apologies did not seem sufficient, right, et cetera.
Speaker 1: The usual, you've heard stories like this before, right?
Speaker 1: So, that's Adam, right?
Speaker 1: I don't know Adam, I don't, if I, it's possible I may have, like, met, like, I, you know, We've met Adam a few times.
Speaker 1: If it's possible, but, like, before Googling him, I would not have recognized his face, right?
Speaker 1: Or, like, if I've ever, you know, seen him, I didn't know, right?
Speaker 1: So, that's the kind of level of relationship we have with that person, is?
Speaker 1: I don't know them.
Speaker 1: So then, right, someone we know quite well, right, is Luke Crane, who has been someone who, I guess, was friend of the show status since the oldest of days.
Speaker 0: Yup, one of our earliest big interviews, like, we got really, Burning Wheel literally got us into indie RPGs.
Speaker 1: Yup, some of, you know, his works, we have lauded his works for over a decade, right?
Speaker 1: And, you know, at the time we met Luke, he was just some guy making tabletop RPGs.
Speaker 1: And then, over time, you know, we worked together a few times on a few small things here and there.
Speaker 1: And then, he became the head of games at Kickstarter and is now, I believe, the VP of community at Kickstarter.
Speaker 1: So, he really leveled up in the world since, you know, we met him.
Speaker 1: And our relationship with him, I don't know how it looks to a listener of the show, like, how close it looks like we are to certain people, right?
Speaker 1: 'Cause it's, like, someone I'm very close to, like, say, my mother, right, doesn't get a lot of airtime on Geek Nights.
Speaker 0: Maybe she should.
Speaker 0: We should bring your mom and my mom on the show.
Speaker 1: Uh-oh.
Speaker 1: Luke Crane gets way more airtime, right, on Geek Nights.
Speaker 1: So, to a listener, I worry, like, does it look like I'm closer to him than I am, right, based on that perception?
Speaker 1: But I would characterize our relationship as, like, mostly business acquaintances, right?
Speaker 1: I communicate with him, at least in the past, I communicated with him when we were doing something together, right?
Speaker 1: Or I would say hi at a convention.
Speaker 1: I think the most recent thing we did together was we played a LARP with him at a PAX a year or two ago, maybe?
Speaker 0: Yup.
Speaker 0: I've done a few minor things that you weren't involved in, but they were all... They're really public things.
Speaker 0: They were just, like, consulting things.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we play-tested the Mouse Guard RPG and made a little video with, you know, a few years back.
Speaker 1: Yup, back when we still did- Not the Mouse Guard RPG, the Mouse Guard board game.
Speaker 1: Swords and strongholds, right.
Speaker 1: You know, but that's it.
Speaker 1: Like, I haven't spoken to Luke probably in well over a year, right?
Speaker 1: It's not like, you know, I don't want people to think we're, like, a close friend, right?
Speaker 1: But it's still a person that I know and know well.
Speaker 1: All right, so what did Luke Crane do?
Speaker 1: So, as I mentioned on a previous Geek Nights, Kickstarter, where Luke is a vice president, right, had the zine quest, the third year of zine quest, which is basically a time period where they encourage people to publish and kickstart tabletop RPG zines.
Speaker 1: And there are many tons and tons of wonderful zines to choose from.
Speaker 1: So, of course, as you would expect, Luke Crane put a zine out, right?
Speaker 1: He put up a Kickstarter, and the Kickstarter was for the perfect RPG, and it was, like, a tongue-in-cheek kind of deal, right?
Speaker 1: Like, hey, hey, hey, we're going to make the perfect RPG zine, right?
Speaker 1: It'll be sort of a, you know, a joke, right?
Speaker 1: There'll be some sort of message about how, like, the perfect RPG can't exist or something.
Speaker 1: It was obviously something along those lines.
Speaker 1: And there was a long list of, you know, the usual suspects in the community who he got involved, because Luke is a well-connected and prominent figure in the tabletop RPG community.
Speaker 1: He was close to all the other people.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and a lot of them are people we are similar relationship with.
Speaker 0: We kind of know them.
Speaker 0: We talk shop semi-regularly.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know, a lot of those people are people who have similar, you know, they're the tabletop RPG community.
Speaker 1: peeps, right?
Speaker 1: The same as you have, like, you know, the anti-Twitter peeps, right?
Speaker 1: They're sort of this community of people that we're not close friends with, but we're podcast-y, you know, nerdy friends with at conventions.
Speaker 1: We say hi, right?
Speaker 1: We tweet at them occasionally, right?
Speaker 1: So, all those usual suspects were on the list of people.
Speaker 1: So when the Kickstarter came up, like, and he posted the thing, I just sort of, I didn't even read it, to be honest.
Speaker 0: I was just like, "Oh, those are all people I like,".
Speaker 0: and I just hit go.
Speaker 1: I was like, "Oh, Luke put...".
Speaker 1: I said, "Oh, Luke put up the zine that I knew was going to be put
Speaker 1: up.".
Speaker 1: And as with many other zines that went up from people I knew or, you know, didn't know, I just looked at it.
Speaker 1: I said, "Oh, Luke's zine is up now.
Speaker 1: Click back," right?
Speaker 1: And then I closed the window and went on with my day.
Speaker 1: And then, later in the day, there was a "I smelled through my internet nose".
Speaker 1: a drama, right?
Speaker 1: And if you hadn't put the pieces together so far, this zine that Luke was putting together, which is an anthology of sorts with all those people involved, Adam Koval was on that list.
Speaker 1: And if I had seen that, I mean, this is a drama, the drama with Adam Koval, it's like, I don't know a lot of people or a lot of dramas, right?
Speaker 1: Like I said, Adam was a person I didn't know.
Speaker 1: I knew about that drama, right?
Speaker 1: I knew about that one.
Speaker 1: Like, had the news
Speaker 0: not been what we're talking about and I'd seen that, then what we'd be talking about on Geek Nights right now would be like us looking into Adam being involved in this when we found out and, like, asking Luke about it, asking people about it, like, "What's going on?
Speaker 0: Why is he
Speaker 0: here?".
Speaker 1: So, yeah, if I would have seen that name on there, I would have been like, "Whoa, what is going on
Speaker 1: here?".
Speaker 1: But I didn't see that name on there.
Speaker 1: Other people did, and so they reacted as I did, as I would have, and said, "Whoa, what is going on
Speaker 1: here?".
Speaker 0: Now, remember, this isn't necessarily, like, the important reaction is not people like us who would have backed it saying, "Oh, whoa, what's going
Speaker 0: on?".
Speaker 0: The people who were on the list didn't know he was involved in the project and they all backed out because they did not want to be involved.
Speaker 0: In a project that he's involved in for all the reasons you can imagine.
Speaker 1: So, now, normally, when you submit something to an anthology, right, poetry, you know, any kind of anthology thing, comic anthology, right, you don't.
Speaker 1: it's not really that common practice to know who else the contributors are, right?
Speaker 1: It's just like, you know, it's like, "Hey, I'm publishing an anthology, send in your works and then I'll let you know if I'm going to include them or not and compensate you
Speaker 1: accordingly.".
Speaker 1: You could ask who else is going to be in there or what else are you putting my artwork next to, but it's not, you typically don't necessarily do that.
Speaker 1: It's not like that standard a thing.
Speaker 1: But maybe it has to be now that this is a, you know, maybe we recognize that.
Speaker 1: maybe we should change that, right?
Speaker 1: So, what happened was, is the other people who had, you know, Luke called a bunch of people, I assume, and was like, "Hey, you want to submit to my ASEAN thing?
Speaker 1: You want to participate in this perfect RPG
Speaker 1: thing?".
Speaker 1: People knowing Luke and his reputation and their relationship with him said yes.
Speaker 1: But then once they saw, after the Kickstarter went live, that Adam was on the list, they called Luke and said, "Nope, I'm out.
Speaker 1: I'm not, you know, like, what's he doing there?
Speaker 1: I'm not, you know, I'm not doing
Speaker 1: this.".
Speaker 1: And then, right, there was a notice to everyone who backed the Kickstarter, I don't know, do we want to read it?
Speaker 1: You can read it online yourself.
Speaker 1: It's basically Luke's message to everyone, which is like, people, he said that, I'm going to paraphrase, you can hear the exact words.
Speaker 1: He said people backed out, and he claims that some people were harassed to back out, and therefore- Which has been pretty well refuted by all the people who did back out.
Speaker 1: Yeah, at least I haven't seen anyone claim that they were harassed to back out, right?
Speaker 1: I've only seen, personally, Luke's claim that other people were harassed to back out.
Speaker 0: I saw people who had, I saw at least two different people who had backed out publicly stating that they backed out because of Adam's involvement.
Speaker 1: I have seen several people say that they backed out on their own volition, right?
Speaker 1: Regardless, being, Luke said that being unable to deliver the product as promised, he would just cancel the whole thing, the end, right?
Speaker 0: That's where this gets extra problematic, because that, it's very clear that he could have removed Adam from the project, but the fact that he chose to end the project instead?
Speaker 1: Okay, well, okay, so hold on.
Speaker 1: So, some people were, I guess, since so many people focused on this point, even though I think it's not that big a deal, and it's kind of minor and conspiracy theory, I can't not bring it up.
Speaker 0: I know what you're going to bring up, I got a screenshot of it here.
Speaker 1: Many people pointed out that in the list of contributors on the Kickstarter happened to be oddly listed in reversed alphabetical order by first name, which puts Adam at the bottom, as if Luke was attempting to hide, or whoever made the Kickstarter, right?
Speaker 1: I don't know if Luke might have worked with someone to do it, right?
Speaker 1: If he did it all himself.
Speaker 1: Was intentionally trying to hide Adam's name at the bottom somewhere so he wouldn't notice something like that.
Speaker 1: That's not possible, but it doesn't really matter if his name was in the fine print or in the big print.
Speaker 1: What if his name was, Adam's name was huge?
Speaker 1: It doesn't change the problem that, you know, Luke, who knows, definitely knows who Adam is way more than we do.
Speaker 0: But the fact that he decided to include Adam in this project, knowing full well, everyone in this entire tabletop industry knows.
Speaker 0: If
Speaker 1: I know Luke knows he doesn't have an excuse, right, it means that he was, you know, just regardless of anything that happened after, the fact that Adam was on the project, regardless of how he was listed, means that Luke Crane thinks it was okay for him to be there and was supporting him and, you know, including him, a person who no one else finds it acceptable to include.
Speaker 0: It would be very hard to believe that Luke was not aware that many of the other names on this list would not want to be involved in a project with Adam.
Speaker 1: Yes, it is.
Speaker 0: That is implausible.
Speaker 1: It is very implausible.
Speaker 1: I cannot believe that, right?
Speaker 1: It's basically, you cannot believe that Luke didn't know about the incident or that Adam was persona non grata or that other, right?
Speaker 1: He had to have known when he did this, which is a huge disappointment, right?
Speaker 1: It's like, I'm not disappointed that I'm not going to get this project.
Speaker 1: I'm disappointed in Luke as a person.
Speaker 1: Like, really, dude?
Speaker 1: Really?
Speaker 0: Like, I actually debated how much investigative journalism to do.
Speaker 0: Like, we ended up not reaching out to Luke for comment.
Speaker 0: Like, I'm just not, basically, I'm not going to talk to Luke Crane anymore and I'm waiting to see if he issues any sort of real public statement about this or not.
Speaker 1: So, that's the thing that I want to point out, right?
Speaker 1: So, how much do I know Luke Crane as a person having worked with him as, like, you know, a little bit over a large number of years, right?
Speaker 1: Not that much, right?
Speaker 1: You know, I know a lot of his thoughts about games.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I know a lot of us thought we've spent a lot of time talking about games together.
Speaker 1: Right, but it's like, what do I know?
Speaker 1: I don't know him, like, as a person.
Speaker 1: Like, I don't know his family or his friends or, you know, you know, or anything.
Speaker 1: I'm not, you know, close to him on, like, a human level.
Speaker 1: But one thing I do know, at least, that I've, about his personality, that I have gathered over the years and I saw, the last time I saw this, really, the last time it really stood out to me was when Kickstarter was unionizing.
Speaker 1: And Eli saw other Kickstarter employees and non-Kickstarter employees all saying something, right, positive or negative, about that unionization effort, which I believe proved successful, if I'm not mistaken.
Speaker 1: And he didn't say a damn thing about it.
Speaker 1: Not one thing.
Speaker 1: He said nothing.
Speaker 0: On one hand, when someone has a job, like, depending on their level, like, they might not be allowed, like, there's a lot of things that could go on there.
Speaker 1: As a vice president, I don't know about the rules.
Speaker 1: He might not even be in the union.
Speaker 1: He might be on the other side of that negotiating table and therefore not able to say anything.
Speaker 1: He might have been pro or anti-union.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: But that's not the point.
Speaker 1: The point is, is that was the latest example in a pattern of behavior that I have seen from Luke Crane as a whole and noticed, like, the one thing I noticed about him as an acquaintance is that he is silent on many, many things.
Speaker 1: You know how bad people will go into, you know, to people and say, you know, stop talking about politics, only talk about games, right?
Speaker 1: You know, and the kind of shitty people will say that, right?
Speaker 1: Luke is not one of those.
Speaker 1: I've never known him to be one of the shitty people who says that.
Speaker 1: He doesn't go to other people and say, stop talking about politics, only talk about games.
Speaker 1: At least I've never heard him say that.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: I've never encountered that.
Speaker 0: And many of the people who are in his orbit will very often talk about politics.
Speaker 1: Indeed.
Speaker 1: What he is, is he is a person who shuts up about politics and doesn't talk about anything but games.
Speaker 1: He follows those.
Speaker 1: He doesn't give those instructions to anyone else.
Speaker 1: that I have seen.
Speaker 1: But what I have seen is him following those instructions.
Speaker 1: He just doesn't say like he's not the kind of person who will tweet Black Lives Matter.
Speaker 1: It's like you don't have to be super active on social media if you don't want to.
Speaker 1: It's not like some requirement of the world.
Speaker 1: or, you know, if you're not that kind of outspoken person, not everyone's an outspoken kind of person.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: But Luke Crane specifically is a prominent figure in a community, is a powerful figure at an important organization, Kickstarter, and is basically silent, as far as I can tell, on lots and lots of things.
Speaker 1: He only talks about his business and he just shuts up about everything else, which leaves a lot of sort of, you know, if you're not super close to him, I guess you had to be way closer to him than we are to know what he actually thinks about a lot of things.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: It's like, I don't know what he thinks about a lot of, you know, most things because he just doesn't say anything.
Speaker 0: Like the tabletop RPG community is very liberal, very progressive as a whole.
Speaker 0: Obviously not everyone is, but like the community is really focused and a lot of designers are focused on things like consent and games and access and diversity.
Speaker 0: And he existed in that space with all those people.
Speaker 0: And I think everyone sort of just assumed that he was like on board with everything.
Speaker 0: And he may be, we don't know.
Speaker 0: He's never really said much about it.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: It's like, you know, he got the benefit of the doubt of, of me sort of assuming his stances on things because he was an accepted and well-regarded member of a community of people who were outspoken on those things.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: So it's like, if you see, you know, a whole bunch of, you know, super, you know, a whole bunch of communists, right.
Speaker 1: Just straight up commies.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: And they're hanging out and they're hanging out in a bar.
Speaker 1: And there's someone else who doesn't look like a communist.
Speaker 1: They're not wearing, they're not handing out newspapers.
Speaker 0: What do you think a communist wears?
Speaker 1: A Che Guevara beret or some shit.
Speaker 1: You know, they, they don't, they're not carrying around a copy of Marx or anything.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: They just look like a normal person.
Speaker 1: There is nothing to indicate to you that they are or are not communist, but they hang out in the communist bar.
Speaker 1: Their friends are communists.
Speaker 1: They're welcome there.
Speaker 1: They're high-fiving the communists, but they never are given the communist speech or, you know, doing communist things.
Speaker 1: You don't know how they vote because that's secret.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: But you got to assume that that person's a communist too.
Speaker 1: Why are they hanging out in the comedy bar?
Speaker 1: So that is Luke Crane, right?
Speaker 1: His, he was in that community, well accepted by these people.
Speaker 1: So I had just, even though he was been silent, I had taken that to mostly, you know, understand that he is just not that kind of person who is outspoken on things like that.
Speaker 1: And you don't have to be, there's no requirement they had to be.
Speaker 1: But we, this latest, you know, I was a little eh with the, with the union thing, but obviously now extremely eh.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Well, this is, no one gets the benefit of the doubt if they behave this way.
Speaker 0: Like multiple steps along this specific project, they all require giving the benefit of the doubt.
Speaker 0: And you don't give the same person the benefit of the doubt a bunch of times in a row if doubts are piling up.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So, I mean, uh, it doesn't look like Luke Crane's going to say anything else.
Speaker 1: He's going to continue his pattern.
Speaker 1: You know, I'd be surprised if he said anything else.
Speaker 1: He's going to add him in this pattern of silent complicity, right?
Speaker 0: Including Adam in the project, uh, appearing to hide this fact from the other people.
Speaker 0: Like those are two things.
Speaker 0: And then third, not only not really apologizing for it, but basically trying to blame others for the failure of the project instead of Apollo.
Speaker 0: Like, even if he had apologized for including Adam and like continued the project without Adam, I'm not saying that would absolve him of any responsibility.
Speaker 1: No, that would have still shown a huge misjudgment on his part, even if he corrected it.
Speaker 0: It would have, but misjudgment followed by earnest apology and amends is better than fighting back plus silence.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: And that's the other thing is if Luke had just come out.
Speaker 1: So I don't know what he believes again, cause he's silent on everything mostly.
Speaker 1: Um, but he would have come out and like defended his choice to, to include Adam.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: And said, you know, and it's funny because burning wheel, it's like, he'll sign burning.
Speaker 1: Fight for what you believe.
Speaker 1: And yet he will not fight for what he believes.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: I don't even know what he believes.
Speaker 1: What are Lou Crane's beliefs?
Speaker 1: He's got a blank character sheet.
Speaker 1: Um, at least as far as I can tell.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: And I guess the GM knows what it says.
Speaker 1: Uh, but if he does believe something that we disagree with, if, you know, if he believes that it would have been okay to include Adam.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Cause it is not okay to include Adam.
Speaker 1: It's not.
Speaker 1: Um, but at least if you had the guts to just come out and present, you know, your argument, at least then I would still be extremely disappointed.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: And I still would, it would still be like, eh, right.
Speaker 1: Um, but at least then you could have some respect.
Speaker 1: that like, oh, okay.
Speaker 1: Uh, you know, I see that you're wrong and you, that's, I can see what you are now.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Um, but the, to not say anything on top of the same disappointment, uh, provide is an image of cowardice.
Speaker 1: So you've now not only lost like the approval, you've also lost some respect.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Um, whereas at least, you know, uh, if he had defended it, I wouldn't, I guess I still wouldn't respect him, but cause he'd be wrong, but I could respect the, you know, the lack of cowardice.
Speaker 1: Not a polly.
Speaker 0: Say what, say what you're gonna, you know, a not apology plus silence is like the worst possible option of all the options.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Um, and it's, you know, and because he, it's mostly because he is in such a position of prominence and power within the community, or at least maybe not anymore.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Um, but I guess he still has his job.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: We haven't heard any news about that.
Speaker 1: So, um, he's still that position.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Comes with a great amount of responsibility.
Speaker 1: Uh,
Speaker 0: and we're not the only ones who are like taking a guess by this, like go, go look at the list of people who contributed or were going to contribute and go re like, I'm not going to put, I'm not going to read all their comments, but many of them posted about this on Twitter.
Speaker 0: They were mostly as shocked as we were that Adam was involved in this project and shocked at Luke's response.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I mean, nobody, this was, you know, I guess cause Luke was silent to all of them as, as well.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: They didn't know.
Speaker 1: But this brought, this actually raised an interesting, if you had asked me, if you had asked me the day before, right, I would have been like, no, there's no way he would ever do something like that.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: I couldn't have met you.
Speaker 1: It's like, no, there's, there would have been no chance.
Speaker 0: I was very surprised to actually read this news and see what happened.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: It was, it was quite shocking.
Speaker 1: Like, it's like, Whoa, okay.
Speaker 1: I guess you aren't what I thought you were.
Speaker 0: But I bring up an anecdote because this was published in our forum and a few other places, but this is an incident that I was present for back in like 2010, which at the time didn't think about, but like I remember it clearly, uh, the whale shark, a friend of ours who did a bunch of panels on heavy metal and things.
Speaker 0: This was a long time ago, but he gave a panel at a Kineticon where Luke happened to be, cause we'd invited Luke to do some panels on his own and there was a whole thing going on.
Speaker 0: And, uh, Luke attended this.
Speaker 1: Eleven years ago.
Speaker 0: Yeah, this was a long time ago, but Luke attended this panel about metal.
Speaker 0: And the whale shark, when doing this panel, did a section at the end about white supremacists and Nazis in the metal community and how we need to aggressively remove them from our community.
Speaker 0: How like that is a problem.
Speaker 1: That is still a problem and it is still a fact.
Speaker 1: I'm there.
Speaker 1: I'm worried every time I go and listen, like metal on Spotify, like I always Google these bands, like, are they not right?
Speaker 1: It's like in other genres of music, right?
Speaker 1: It's like future funk.
Speaker 0: I don't usually have to like Google to see if the future funk band, you know, if you didn't be surprised, like I was a big fan of Pogo until I found out what a piece of shit he is.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's like, I think Pogo might be like one of the few.
Speaker 1: The only thing I have to Google for now at DJs is like, are they coin people?
Speaker 1: Yeah, but but metal people, it's like, yeah, metal bands have good odds of being white supremacists relative to other genres.
Speaker 1: You have to search them out and see if it's, you know, luckily, Spotify does let you block bands or I think you can actually report them and get them removed.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: But here's the thing,
Speaker 0: we do know that Luke is into metal and Luke attended this panel and at the end of the panel, Luke approached the whale shark, who is also knows him like we're all in the orbit together, and basically said, and this is nearly verbatim, like I remember this.
Speaker 0: I was there.
Speaker 0: Don't end on a down note like that.
Speaker 0: Sure, we have our bad boys, but they're not that common.
Speaker 0: And that go back to that moment really puts a sour taste in my mouth.
Speaker 0: If there is an incident of him telling someone to not aggressively purge Nazis from the metal community and like don't bring up that down note in a panel about it.
Speaker 0: Like the plausible deniability.
Speaker 0: I'm not saying Luke's a Nazi.
Speaker 0: I'm saying his silence is a pattern that in retrospect is much more recognizable based on this current incident.
Speaker 1: I think he definitely has like a personality of, you know, silent complicity, right?
Speaker 1: He would rather he doesn't want to like, you know, have conflict or he just says nothing.
Speaker 1: He clearly believes something, but he doesn't want to like get into a flame war about it.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Which is somewhat understandable, you know, given the Internet, but like he just avoids saying, you know, any of his beliefs on anything other than, you know, games.
Speaker 0: Well, the extra weird thing about this is that Luke and Adam before the incident were both pretty well respected for like.
Speaker 0: their games involved a lot of like consent.
Speaker 1: I can't deny.
Speaker 1: I enjoy all their you know, the games that they have made right there.
Speaker 0: But in terms of like they're not without flaw, but mechanically including consent, mechanically, like enforcing things like allowing people to role play in a safe space.
Speaker 0: Like that was something that previous to the incident with Adam, I associated with Adam and previous to this, I associated with Luke.
Speaker 0: And it's interesting that even though these ideas are expressed in their works, they did not appear to be expressed in their real lives.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So even us, even people like us who may, you know, be out here saying all these things.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: You got to keep an eye on us to make sure.
Speaker 1: Of course, we're not.
Speaker 1: we won't have the silent problem.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Haven't I been on Twitter last week telling people that NFTs are bullshit and Bitcoin is literally evil.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: You you always know where we stand.
Speaker 0: But you know, we might be wrong, but we're not going to.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 1: It is entirely possible that we will go down a dark, a dark road.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: And surprise, surprise you with hidden in hidden bad takes on things at some point in the future.
Speaker 1: It's not impossible.
Speaker 1: You know, I'm working hard to make sure that doesn't happen.
Speaker 0: You also might run into some old bad takes.
Speaker 0: I mean, Geek Nights has been around since 2000.
Speaker 1: If you go to old Geek Nights, I'm sure you can find plenty to ruin us on.
Speaker 1: You know, but I would probably agree with you if you odds are twenty twenty one.
Speaker 1: Scott, if you pulled up a 2007 Scott podcast, right, found me saying something shitty and say, wow, you said something shitty.
Speaker 1: I'd be like, yeah, I sure did.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we remember this one episode in particular.
Speaker 0: I was thinking about where we were talking about how unions in our fields of work didn't make sense.
Speaker 0: And we don't we don't.
Speaker 0: we doubled down on that back then.
Speaker 1: I mean, I can see, you know, I'd probably agree with some of the individual points I made, but not the overall.
Speaker 1: I'd probably be like, yeah, let's make a union and not have a shitty one.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Anyway, you can read like a link to this Reddit post that kind of explains this whole situation in extreme detail.
Speaker 0: And honestly, like I said, we didn't reach out to Luke.
Speaker 0: We're really still say something publicly.
Speaker 1: I have not.
Speaker 1: I have not gotten involved in any of the, you know, things happening.
Speaker 1: I am just.
Speaker 1: I heard what everyone had to say.
Speaker 1: I listened.
Speaker 1: And then I said just now what I know and what I think about it.
Speaker 1: And that's it.
Speaker 1: That's there's nothing else.
Speaker 1: I think it's I think it's going to be the end right there.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: I don't I don't think we're going to.
Speaker 1: I would be surprised if there was a further development on this front.
Speaker 0: I can say that I am.
Speaker 0: One thing that I am not going to do is we had been talking until covid kind of messed everything up about trying to do a burning con of some kind.
Speaker 0: Like bring that back.
Speaker 1: That's not.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that is not talking about that.
Speaker 1: We've been talking about that on and off for quite a long time.
Speaker 1: You know, somehow it's like because burning con was a con that died and we are trying to start a small con.
Speaker 1: And it was sort of like we've always been like, hey, let's you know, we can get all these things going together.
Speaker 1: It's never good.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: If we do that, it's going to be entirely on our own at this point.
Speaker 0: So in so to turn this to a positive note, I think what we want to talk about briefly is a bunch of kickstarters, some of which are zines that are super good that you should check out that are not a problem.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: So you missed out on the perfect RPG or everyone did.
Speaker 1: So I've kickstarted quite a few zine and non-zine RPGs.
Speaker 1: Some of these may have ended.
Speaker 1: But regardless, I'm going to talk about all these really quickly.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: So the first one is this one over.
Speaker 1: This one's not over yet.
Speaker 1: It's called Our Traveling Home by Ash Kreider.
Speaker 1: This is basically Howl's Moving Castle, the RPG.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: So this is castle that moves around our traveling home.
Speaker 0: I see a bird lady, a red panda.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you are.
Speaker 1: You definitely have, you know, a non-typical family.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Living in this home, traveling around.
Speaker 0: A game about queer romance, found family and finding healing through belonging inspired by the works of Studio Ghibli.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: So if that doesn't sell you on the RPG, I don't know what kind of nerd you are.
Speaker 1: OK, the next one.
Speaker 1: Is this still available?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: It will only be funded reaches its goal by twenty three days to go.
Speaker 1: OK.
Speaker 1: Coyote and Crow, the role playing game.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: So we're always talking about, you know, RPGs and how racist and colonial they are.
Speaker 1: And it's like, well, show me the RPG that's not.
Speaker 1: Well, here it is.
Speaker 1: It's Coyote and Crow.
Speaker 1: It's a game about Native Americans made by Native Americans.
Speaker 0: An alternate future of the Americas where colonization never occurred.
Speaker 0: Instead, advanced civilizations arose over hundreds of years after a massive climate disaster, et cetera.
Speaker 0: This looks pretty cool.
Speaker 1: The thing that sold me on this game, which sells me on a lot of games and books, by the way, was the map, which is an upside down North America.
Speaker 1: With outlines of different, you know, territories on it.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: And I was like, oh, that that alone, like they could just put that picture up and said there is a game associated with this with this JPEG.
Speaker 1: Would you like to pay money for it?
Speaker 1: And I would have said, yes.
Speaker 1: So Coyote and Crow.
Speaker 1: Excellent.
Speaker 1: We got this one.
Speaker 0: I hope you want to say.
Speaker 1: Oh, Wizards grimoire.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 0: That's the one I was bringing up.
Speaker 0: This is an updated Wizards grimoire.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So we did a show on Wizards grimoire by Vincent Baker.
Speaker 1: I don't think you can kickstart this anymore.
Speaker 1: I think it ended, but you can probably still get it eventually.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: But yeah, Wizards grimoire is being updated.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's being updated in zine form.
Speaker 1: You can get your hands on it, I guess, when this launches, because the backing period is over.
Speaker 1: Now here's the interesting thing.
Speaker 1: There's two of these.
Speaker 1: I want to point out after Wizards grimoire, I got really turned on to the solo RPG biz.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Because it's like, hey, you know, you get your solo RPG on.
Speaker 1: You don't need to worry about arranging anything with other people so much.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: So here's two really good looking solo RPGs that I'm going to try.
Speaker 1: One of them is the last will and testament of Gideon Blythe, a keepsake game about a family legend, lineage and the burden of destiny for zine quest three.
Speaker 1: By G on shim.
Speaker 1: It is a solo RPG, but you're like producing this, you know, like you get yourself a blank moleskine and some artifacts, and it's almost like you're scrapbooking and making the story at the same time.
Speaker 1: Um, given, you know, the ephemera that come with the game.
Speaker 1: Uh, and if you pay enough money, you can, you know, it'll include a lot of ephemera.
Speaker 1: You know, fabrics, scraps, artifacts, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: It looks like there's going to be, I guess, an app version two.
Speaker 1: Oh, that'll be really interesting.
Speaker 0: Mobile only zine players follow screen friendly directions to create the family album.
Speaker 0: So there's, there's a bunch of ways to interact with this.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: So it's like you're, you're someone who has found this album, but you're also creating the album as you play.
Speaker 1: Um, and it's a solo RPG.
Speaker 1: You can just do this by yourself.
Speaker 1: It's, I guess this looks very experimental and cool.
Speaker 0: Like one of them, like a mechanic is there's an example of play they show in the Kickstarter to just to figure out the terminal fate of a character's beloved.
Speaker 0: There's a bunch of descendant cards and you black out all but one word on them.
Speaker 0: And that determines the fate of some characters.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: So the last one, very similar vein to the previous one is called amending, right?
Speaker 1: A space mending, um, by, uh, shinging core.
Speaker 1: I hope I pronounced their name correctly.
Speaker 0: Perhaps that is a play on words.
Speaker 1: Uh, that's the person's name.
Speaker 0: No, I'm saying I'll bending.
Speaker 1: Oh yes.
Speaker 1: The title is, is this is also a solo RPG where you get a cloth map.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: And you literally, so onto the map, the path you are taking with a needle and thread, you travel around the map and when things happen.
Speaker 1: So in the example here, right, there's a spot where, uh, the person, uh, I guess must have uncovered like some gems or something and they sewed a bunch of like little blue sparkly dots into that area of the map.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Um, so obviously it's not a difficult sewing project, right?
Speaker 1: You just sort of, you know, needle in, needle out kind of situation, right?
Speaker 1: Um, you know, you can do this whether you are amazing at sewing or have never sewed in your life.
Speaker 1: But it's like you're, again, you're creating an artifact and also telling a story and playing a solo RPG at the same time.
Speaker 1: Just the idea of that is worth my money.
Speaker 1: And then they got a photo, if that doesn't sell you on it, they got a photo of somebody wearing their map as like a scarf and it's like, if that's okay.
Speaker 1: That's like guaranteed RPG sales.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Um, and you can play this entirely by yourself, right?
Speaker 1: So if you have no friends who want to play RPGs with you or they're not reliable as RPG people are, you can kickstart this and on your own, tell a story and create a beautiful, keepsake, uh, for yourself.
Speaker 1: So all these, you know, and more A+ RPGs to kickstart that aren't the perfect RPG, which isn't happening.
Speaker 0: And one last little quick news before we get into the main bit and talk about Moon Hunters.
Speaker 0: Uh, so Roll20 is a pretty good website that doesn't just support Dungeons and Dragons.
Speaker 0: Like it supports other RPGs too.
Speaker 0: Like Blades in the Dark is directly supported in there.
Speaker 0: So, uh, I'm using Roll20 now.
Speaker 0: I never really used it before.
Speaker 0: In fact, right after this Geek Nights recording, I'm gonna go play Blades in the Dark.
Speaker 0: Uh, you might be thinking, well, with COVID happening and everyone's stuck at home, are a lot of people playing role playing games online?
Speaker 0: So previous to COVID, oh, I guess, uh, yes, Roll20 had about 5 million accounts on it, on the platform.
Speaker 1: That's all I always question that when people say how many accounts they have, cause how many are bots?
Speaker 1: How many are using their accounts?
Speaker 1: I think like I might have an account.
Speaker 1: When have I used it?
Speaker 1: I don't remember.
Speaker 1: It must've been years ago if I even have one.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: So I always want to know the active users, like in the past week.
Speaker 1: That's what I want to know.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Anyway, but assuming you use that metric during COVID, they have added 3 million new users to Roll20.
Speaker 1: Even if those, even if those aren't all active users in the past week, that you cannot deny that a lot more people are using Roll20 than before.
Speaker 0: And I can say that during the early days of COVID, like Roll20 would have some performance issues because so many people were using it at the same time.
Speaker 1: Or their servers were so weak.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: But I think there is a, there is enough evidence that there was indeed an explosion of online role-playing because Roll20 is just one way people do this.
Speaker 0: A lot of people just play RPGs by just being in a Discord.
Speaker 0: Just doing a Zoom call.
Speaker 0: So, uh, it'll be interesting to see what I really want, what I'm really curious about because I don't know what's going to happen.
Speaker 0: What will the role-playing landscape look like in a post-COVID world?
Speaker 0: Because I think a lot of people started role-playing who previously didn't because they were stuck at home, had more free time or were bored and started doing it online.
Speaker 0: Will this translate to more people playing in person?
Speaker 0: Will this translate to more online groups existing even post-COVID because it's easier to find people you want to play with instead of whoever happens to be at your local game store?
Speaker 0: Like, this is going to be a very interesting space to watch over the next 18 months.
Speaker 1: Yeah, uh, you know, we'll see how it goes.
Speaker 1: But, you know, even if people aren't playing, you know, the best RPGs, better than no RPGs.
Speaker 1: So, more RPG playing is good.
Speaker 0: But anyway, things of the day.
Speaker 0: So, check this out.
Speaker 0: This is literally the best thing I've seen on the internet today.
Speaker 0: It was posted today.
Speaker 0: It's my thing of the day.
Speaker 0: It is a minute and thirty second long video that appears to be done in one shot and it is just the camera on a drone flying into a bowling alley.
Speaker 0: And it is beautiful and amazing.
Speaker 0: and you will be surprised at two different points in this video.
Speaker 0: Watch it all the way to the end.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I was, uh, this is quite an excellent, you know, short film here that I hadn't seen.
Speaker 1: Actually, for once, I hadn't seen it until Rims sent it to me.
Speaker 1: I had some questions about it.
Speaker 1: Like, how the heck did they do that?
Speaker 1: But that's it.
Speaker 0: There are two exact moments in this video where you will think, "Whoa, I didn't expect
Speaker 0: that.".
Speaker 1: Yeah, and also, you know, the way the people were involved.
Speaker 1: Really excellent work.
Speaker 1: Big fan.
Speaker 1: Alright, so, I think I saw this from someone in our forum shared this with the class.
Speaker 1: And I believe that's where I found it originally.
Speaker 1: So, what this is, is there is a drummer that I had not heard of previously, but is an excellent drummer named Larnell Lewis.
Speaker 1: And Larnell is not someone who is a drummer in the metal genre, right?
Speaker 1: Metal has come up again on our podcast.
Speaker 1: However, Larnell, here in this video on YouTube, listens to the very famous song "Enter Sandman" by Metallica.
Speaker 0: If you don't know that song, like, you've definitely heard it, even if you don't realize it.
Speaker 1: If you're listening to this podcast, you know that song.
Speaker 1: It's like, there's only one listener, and they've definitely heard that song.
Speaker 1: Anyway, but Larnell claims to have never heard that song before.
Speaker 1: Larnell listens to the song, and basically in, I think it's two tries, but regardless of how many, one or two tries doesn't matter.
Speaker 1: It's impressive nonetheless, right?
Speaker 1: Just heard the song, doesn't have like, you know, music, or sheet music or anything, right?
Speaker 1: And then plays the drums as if, you know, he's on stage, and the rest of Metallica except for the drummer is there, and he's got to fill in.
Speaker 0: The YouTube comments on this video are great.
Speaker 0: "Why did it take YouTube six days to recommend this to
Speaker 0: me?".
Speaker 0: Up next, Tool.
Speaker 0: See what he makes of that.
Speaker 0: Meanwhile, Lars has been playing this for 30 years and still can't get it right.
Speaker 1: So yeah, this is amazing to see someone who not only has, there's plenty of people in the world who are talented at various musical instruments, but it is an even smaller subset of those people who can just, like, you know, you might find someone who's like amazing at, you know, I don't know, violin.
Speaker 1: And then if you were to just play for them once, like a recording of a brand new violin piece, would, you know, to hear it, memorize it, be able to play the whole thing back to you in one or two tries doesn't even matter, right?
Speaker 1: That is incredible.
Speaker 1: And so, yeah, like
Speaker 0: in music theory classes, like back when I was serious about music, I got to the point where I could listen to one note being played at a time on a piano for like a minute and transcribe it as I went and then play it back.
Speaker 0: One note at a time very slowly over the course of like 30 to 40 seconds was the best I could muster.
Speaker 1: This is well worth all nearly 20 minutes of your time to watch this video.
Speaker 0: It's good.
Speaker 0: In the better moment, the only thing we can talk about in the better moment is that Scott sent me an image and that image was of the tale of Genji.
Speaker 1: That's right.
Speaker 1: Last night, I basically sometime around nine something, I was like, you know, I really don't have anything else to do right now.
Speaker 1: And but it's kind of too early to go in bed and I kind of ran out of video games, kind of, you know, what should I do?
Speaker 1: And I said, oh, I guess I'm in like a reading mood.
Speaker 1: Wow.
Speaker 1: It's like, oh, well, if I'm in a reading mood, I guess I had to read that book, don't I?
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: And so I did.
Speaker 1: I have to read that book.
Speaker 1: I did not finish the chapter I was in, but I got a significant portion of the way through it before my eyes would not stay open.
Speaker 1: And I will probably do the same thing tonight after I'm done with all my biz here.
Speaker 1: So it'll be a while.
Speaker 1: The tale of Genji, the first novel ever written by a human being that we know of is not a short book by any stretch.
Speaker 1: But I will complete reading it within my lifetime sometime in the coming weeks, months, who knows?
Speaker 0: So the Geek Nights Book Club is afoot again.
Speaker 0: So if you start reading now, you'll be able to follow along because, you know, we'll do like we normally did during book clubs is we'll chat a little bit during the meta moment about things that have happened in the book.
Speaker 1: All I'm going to say is I feel like I could write like a one paragraph summary of each chapter of the Tale of Genji.
Speaker 1: And then that would just.
Speaker 1: you could just replace the whole book with that and it would be fine.
Speaker 1: But anyway, we'll see.
Speaker 1: So, yeah, Tale of Genji is still the book club book.
Speaker 1: I'm looking forward to finishing it so we can do a different book club book.
Speaker 1: I don't care what the hell Rin picks it next time.
Speaker 0: But again, the problem is not the book because it's not, oh, I don't want to read the Tale of Genji.
Speaker 0: I'm not reading fucking any fiction right now.
Speaker 0: I'm reading all nonfiction.
Speaker 1: I'm saying I'm just saying there's nothing.
Speaker 1: the book is not the problem.
Speaker 1: It's simply the amount of time we've been on it.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: It's like to just be on a different book.
Speaker 1: The context in which we are reading it.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: If I had just been reading it on my own and not for this book club and it had been just a selection for a year, you know, two years.
Speaker 1: I don't know when we selected it.
Speaker 0: I will say I do know what my book selection will be.
Speaker 0: I've already decided.
Speaker 1: Good.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: I mean, for future selections, I got so many.
Speaker 1: But I'm probably going to pick ones that are shorter and faster.
Speaker 0: I was about to say, just be careful because if you cross me, the Count of Monte Cristo is coming out of the woodwork.
Speaker 0: Count of Monte Cristo.
Speaker 1: I'll take the Count of Monte Cristo.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: As long as we don't see it's regardless of the book, Count of Monte Cristo, as long as we don't take two years to read it.
Speaker 1: It'll be.
Speaker 0: I mean, I powered through the Count of Monte Cristo in like a month and a half.
Speaker 0: OK.
Speaker 0: I was actually really into it.
Speaker 0: I was reading it at this breakneck pace.
Speaker 1: No, I mean, I was.
Speaker 1: you know, I was.
Speaker 1: I was reading Tale of Genji last night as fast as I read books.
Speaker 1: So, you know.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: Let's get right into it, because we went on for a while here, but I don't think we have to talk forever about this.
Speaker 0: Moon Hunters is a game that we want to talk about, one, because we played it recently, even though it's from 2016.
Speaker 0: But two, it is out on the switch for like 15 bucks.
Speaker 0: Like it's out.
Speaker 0: But right now, like literally right now and until March 15th.
Speaker 0: So you've got like a week.
Speaker 0: It is on sale on Steam.
Speaker 0: So instead of fourteen ninety nine on Steam, this game is two dollars and twenty four cents.
Speaker 0: This game.
Speaker 0: just if don't even listen to the review, it's two dollars and twenty four cents.
Speaker 1: Just I found this.
Speaker 1: So I found this game, which is developed by Kit Fox Games in my Steam library.
Speaker 1: And I didn't know where it came from, but it was a lot lately.
Speaker 1: It was a co-op multiplayer game that I could play with friends.
Speaker 1: And I was with friends online looking for a co-op game to play together.
Speaker 1: And, you know, most of the steam, the PC games that are online, real time play together with Steam, play together or with Internet functionality tend to be action RPGs or sort of, you know, Smash TV, twin stick.
Speaker 1: Same kind of deal.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: You know, games like Enter the Gungeon.
Speaker 1: Or I've been playing with our friend Scott Johnson.
Speaker 1: I've been playing.
Speaker 1: Children of Morta is another one in the same sort of category.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: So this one, Moon Hunters, I finally figured out where I got it from.
Speaker 1: It was from on itch.io.
Speaker 1: There was a Black Lives Matter support bundle and the game was included.
Speaker 0: Oh, that explains it.
Speaker 1: And that is why I have a copy of that game.
Speaker 1: So, but yeah, it's on super sale on Steam right now.
Speaker 1: It's called Moon Hunters.
Speaker 1: And in this game, you are literal Moon Hunters.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: The moon's gone.
Speaker 0: Go find it.
Speaker 0: You've got five days.
Speaker 1: The sun goes down and the moon does not come up.
Speaker 1: And it is a clear sky.
Speaker 1: And the moon should be there because you are people of the moon religion.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: And you know where the moon is and it doesn't show up.
Speaker 1: And you're like, oh, shit.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: And then your village is like, all right, princess Luna situation going on.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: And your village is like, go fucking find the moon before we all die.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Like you're the strongest people in our, in our village.
Speaker 1: And you can choose from four different or I guess several different like groups.
Speaker 1: We're like the wolf clan, different clans.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: And it's like, yeah, where's the moon?
Speaker 1: Go and find it.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: You have this many days to find the moon before like the, you know, the world is ruined.
Speaker 0: It's just five days.
Speaker 0: You know what it reminds me of like superficially, like right from the start.
Speaker 0: What was it?
Speaker 0: Five second hero.
Speaker 1: Half minute hero.
Speaker 0: That's what, yeah.
Speaker 0: I haven't played the game in so long.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Got a little bit of that going on.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: But in that, this game, there's a lot of interesting, unique stuff this game is doing.
Speaker 0: But the gist of it is you start with these characters, you play through the game.
Speaker 0: You don't find the moon and the world ends probably.
Speaker 1: But then we didn't find the moon, but we probably could have you played it more.
Speaker 0: But when you play it again, some of the things that you would learn from the previous time, changed the world a little bit.
Speaker 0: And now you can explore the world a little more.
Speaker 0: There's more options.
Speaker 0: There's more history.
Speaker 0: So it's sort of like a procedurally generated roguelike in a sense?
Speaker 1: It's very much in line with what you have, the trend of the times, where it's a roguelike game, where each game, each time you play, you know, it's a completely different, or not completely, but very different experience where things have been randomized and procedurally shuffled in various ways.
Speaker 1: But also, every time you play, you carry a bit of statefulness over to your next play.
Speaker 1: Right?
Speaker 1: Rogue Legacy did this, where you'd level up your guy.
Speaker 0: Hades is like the hottest game that does this.
Speaker 1: Hades, exactly.
Speaker 1: Every play of Hades, some things are shuffled, right?
Speaker 1: You fight a different boss at the end of level one.
Speaker 1: You play with a different weapon.
Speaker 1: But, of course, in your second play of Hades, you've upgraded things, right?
Speaker 1: Same pattern here in Moon Hunters.
Speaker 1: The thing I think separates Moon Hunters apart is really just the storytelling aspect here in this game.
Speaker 0: Which is interesting.
Speaker 0: When you read about this game, it is described on their page as, quote, "Moon Hunters, the personality test
Speaker 0: RPG.".
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's somewhat an apt description, right?
Speaker 1: Is that while a lot of the gameplay is that sort of twin-stick action RPG, right?
Speaker 1: Move and then shoot bad guys until their health bar goes down kind of gameplay, you know, that you see so often.
Speaker 0: That's the least interesting part of this game.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's actually like that part of the game is just kind of eh, right?
Speaker 1: It's like typical.
Speaker 1: It's not bad, but it's not great.
Speaker 1: It's just run of the mill for that genre, right?
Speaker 1: The rest of the game is super unique and interesting.
Speaker 1: So, first of all, when you walk around towns and talk to people, right?
Speaker 1: There'll be some dialogue choices of like, you know, what do we tell this person, right?
Speaker 1: And every player, because you're playing co-op with up to four people, right?
Speaker 1: You will choose one of the choices.
Speaker 1: You all choose.
Speaker 1: You vote.
Speaker 1: You might choose this.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you vote.
Speaker 1: You might choose the same thing.
Speaker 1: You might choose different things.
Speaker 1: And if there's a tie, whoever in your party has the highest leadership score is the leader and gets the tie-breaking vote.
Speaker 0: These are real fun.
Speaker 0: Like, right away, like we started playing this game.
Speaker 0: As soon as we realized we were voting on what to say to someone, someone locked in their vote and it got really funny and we were hooked.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you can't unlock your vote.
Speaker 1: So it's like everyone locks in.
Speaker 1: If you lock in first, that was your choice to lock in first or you don't have to.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that was real fun.
Speaker 1: And then there's real consequences.
Speaker 1: And this is where the personality test part comes in.
Speaker 1: For example, we chose, I think, what did we choose when we played most recently?
Speaker 1: Avenge on one of the choices, right?
Speaker 1: And then we both got points in vengeful as like our vengeful stat, like, increased.
Speaker 1: And you say like, okay, well, that's neat.
Speaker 1: What does vengeful stat actually mean?
Speaker 1: Well, for example, another stat was foolish, right?
Speaker 1: So we didn't have any points in foolish.
Speaker 1: We were not fools.
Speaker 1: We encountered someone along our adventure and the game told us, yeah, this guy would have fought you if he thought you were more foolish.
Speaker 1: But since we weren't, he thought that we were, you know, intelligent people and therefore he didn't mess with us.
Speaker 0: In one of the towns, there's these old people just talking to each other.
Speaker 0: And if you go over and try to listen to them, it tells you like, unfortunately, you don't have the patience to listen to this crap.
Speaker 1: And it's like patience is highlighted.
Speaker 1: So it's like if we want to hear what the old people are saying, we have to go somewhere else and do something patient to get patient stat up.
Speaker 1: And then we can go to the old people and hear what they're saying.
Speaker 0: So all these decisions you make as a group and individually, we'll get to that in a second along the way, define your characters, which define how they interact with the world.
Speaker 0: And then at the very end of the game, regardless of if you find the moon and save the world, I don't actually know if you can find the moon.
Speaker 0: We haven't beaten beaten it.
Speaker 0: But you almost get this history like it almost, you know, those 80s movies where it's like the credits show, like what happened to everybody.
Speaker 0: Like Joey Jojo blew up in the war and Doc became a lawyer and then got shot, like something like that.
Speaker 0: You kind of get that for your character.
Speaker 0: Like it tells you the story of your character, like based on the decisions you made, how did you end up?
Speaker 1: Now, along your way, where you're doing this sort of, you know, average run of the mill action RPG gameplay where you have different classes and a few different abilities, teleport, range, melee, you know, that sort of stuff.
Speaker 1: You will have to choose where you're going to go next in a very Slay the Spire kind of style.
Speaker 1: You start off in your home village and the moon disappears.
Speaker 1: But then it's like, okay, where do you go next?
Speaker 1: Do you go to over to there, to that cave?
Speaker 0: You head over to the sun cult, which is probably the culprit.
Speaker 1: You're in the moon group, you're moon people, moon hunters.
Speaker 1: What happened to the moon?
Speaker 1: You're pretty sure those evil sun cult guys did something.
Speaker 1: So do you go over to the sun cult and like take it to the man and say, hey, what'd you do with the moon, jerks?
Speaker 0: We did that the first time, we went over and fucked the sun cult up.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we sure did.
Speaker 1: I think we unlocked the sun cult guy as like a playable character even.
Speaker 1: Something like that.
Speaker 1: There's stuff that goes on.
Speaker 0: That guy though, he, anyway.
Speaker 1: There's something interesting going on there.
Speaker 1: But yeah, there's all sorts of interesting characters you meet.
Speaker 1: Like none of the, a lot of games will sort of like Slay the Spire for example.
Speaker 1: You have a question mark and then you'll have a fight and they're clearly separate.
Speaker 1: Here it's like.
Speaker 1: every area you go in, even if it's just mostly a town, might have a couple guys to fight, right?
Speaker 1: And even an area where you are fighting lots and lots of guys with several bosses, like a big battle area.
Speaker 1: There'll be several people to talk to, to have dialogue with, to get quests from, to learn things from.
Speaker 1: And you gotta pay attention.
Speaker 1: With a hermit in it, all kinds of stuff.
Speaker 0: If you don't pay attention to what people are saying and try to solve the puzzle, you gotta go to the places that make sense for what you're actually trying to accomplish.
Speaker 0: And you can just go off on wild goose chases, like go somewhere that doesn't really matter.
Speaker 0: Or you can pay attention or go somewhere interesting.
Speaker 0: You can go do something completely different from trying to find the moon and see how that turns out.
Speaker 0: But all those places also let you unlock more of the game.
Speaker 0: Like once you find a type of food, now that type of food is always available.
Speaker 0: It's like in the game we just played, we met this bird lady and she seems important, but she doesn't want to talk to us unless we make her a fish sandwich.
Speaker 0: So if we ever get fish, we're going to try to go back to that place in a future playthrough and see if we can get this bird lady to talk to us.
Speaker 1: Exactly.
Speaker 1: And then of course on the map, it's like, "Oh, well there's a place that has fishing.
Speaker 1: Maybe we should go to that place and try to fish and then get the recipe for the fish sandwich for cooking.
Speaker 1: And then the recipe will be available on future playthroughs and so on and so
Speaker 1: forth.".
Speaker 1: So I think like I've said a bunch of times, the combat action part of the game is kind of eh.
Speaker 1: But what I think the game gives you, that's sort of new and unique, is you get the stat building visual novel action that you would normally see in a Tokimeki memorial almost.
Speaker 1: But better design.
Speaker 0: Simply because it tells you what you needed to interact with the thing.
Speaker 1: Exactly.
Speaker 1: But also, not only do you get that, you get to play through it quickly.
Speaker 1: Playing Tokimeki memorial takes a long time, right?
Speaker 1: Even playing some of the other stat building visual novels takes a while, right?
Speaker 1: They're not quick games.
Speaker 1: Here you can play through a playthrough in a sitting with your friends.
Speaker 1: I think it would actually be best at a party with four people, right?
Speaker 1: You could play through and it's like, "Okay, we did
Speaker 1: that."
Speaker 1: And then you can learn so much and get another playthrough.
Speaker 1: And you can really, you know, if one playthrough of a game takes so long, it's like that replay using what you learned from the first time might not ever happen.
Speaker 1: Here you can iterate quickly and really explore all the space available in a shorter amount of time, or you're more likely to re-explore.
Speaker 1: And then on top of that, right, so you've got the shorter stat building visual novel with greater replay, and then you've got the multiplayer aspect, right, where you're playing it together.
Speaker 1: When you play Tokimeki Memorial together or some other stat building visual novel, it's everyone yelling at each other and you're outside the game in the meta picking your choices, right?
Speaker 0: But here, if Scott's like, "We should share our water with this guy," and all the rest of us are like, "No, fuck him," and we vote to deny him water, that's what we're doing.
Speaker 1: You're literally all together doing it at the same time.
Speaker 1: And then sometimes you're doing that voting, but sometimes you're not.
Speaker 1: You still have the individual play, right?
Speaker 1: So at the end of each day in the game, like I said, the game is five days long, you camp.
Speaker 1: And when you camp, each player individually chooses what they're going to do when they camp at night.
Speaker 0: I love that part.
Speaker 1: This is a really fun part of the game, right?
Speaker 1: So you're presented with a screen that reminds me a lot of Golden Axe with the campfire, and you pick a spot, and some of the spots tell you straight up, like, "This is going to increase these stats for you," right?
Speaker 1: So maybe you want to increase leadership, so you pick a certain thing that increases leadership so you can become the leader.
Speaker 1: Or maybe you're a melee character, you pick the thing that will increase your strength.
Speaker 1: And then cooking, you can pick a recipe, and then stuff happens and you pick a recipe, right?
Speaker 0: And often when you pick something, independent of that stat boost, you'll get your own, like, "I'm keeping watch while Scott's sleeping.
Speaker 0: I have to deal with the situation by myself and answer a question that no one else gets to vote, just
Speaker 0: me.".
Speaker 1: You will get some sort of story encounter, some often, and I guess not always, but very often, while you're doing your camping activity and get to do an individual choice for your character.
Speaker 1: that is a lot of fun.
Speaker 0: And I will say these choices, like, another game that evokes in my mind is Arabian Nights.
Speaker 0: Or a thousand and one, like, that are the game, because the choices are vague and simple.
Speaker 0: Like, do I share or deny the thing?
Speaker 0: Do I flirt or distract?
Speaker 0: Like, you get very different and vague options, and the story kind of just follows them.
Speaker 1: And they are not the sort of blatant black and white sort of mortal choices you get in, like, a Fallout kind of game, where it's like, "Do I kill the guy, steal from the guy, or try to persuade the
Speaker 1: guy?".
Speaker 1: Or, you know, just be nice to the guy.
Speaker 0: Well, we found the skull, like, the Skull Shrine, and the options it gave us were "Pray" or
Speaker 0: "Study.".
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like, I prayed because I want to pray to the awesome skull.
Speaker 0: Yeah, all hail Zomelguster.
Speaker 1: But neither one of those is necessarily good, bad, wrong, right?
Speaker 1: They're all interesting choices that, you know, you're going to choose probably according to your personality, in this personality test RPG, right?
Speaker 1: What you choose in the choice of, you know, "Pray" or "Study" to the skull says stuff about who you are, the real person, right?
Speaker 1: So, I would recommend this game not necessarily for everybody.
Speaker 1: I would say if you have, it's okay with just two people.
Speaker 1: If you got at least one other person, if you're going to play it alone, I think you're going to lose a lot of the effect of it.
Speaker 1: Not all of it.
Speaker 1: You can play it alone if you want.
Speaker 0: But I think three or four, this game shines the most.
Speaker 1: Three or four, it shines a lot.
Speaker 1: Two is still good.
Speaker 1: I think it's worth playing with two if that's all you can muster.
Speaker 1: If you can get people to play this and play repeat plays of it, it is well worth the ridiculously low price it is on Steam right now.
Speaker 0: Two dollars!
Speaker 1: Damn, that is low.
Speaker 0: Now, right now we had trouble getting the online play that's built in to work, but the game works 100% fine with Steam Remote Play.
Speaker 1: Yes, so technology-wise, yeah, their game does have online play built in.
Speaker 1: I don't know if the online play on the Switch works because I obviously did not buy it on Switch.
Speaker 1: It might or might not work.
Speaker 0: It claims to have online support on the Switch.
Speaker 1: Yes, on PC, we could not get the online functionality to work, but using Steam Remote Play together, it worked perfectly fine.
Speaker 1: On the main menu, you have some trouble because only one person can control the main menu and it might not be the person whose computer is playing the game.
Speaker 0: It ended up being me, but we sorted that out.
Speaker 1: But once you're in the game, then it will recognize everyone's controller and you all join and it'll work.
Speaker 1: I did have trouble with it one time, but I didn't have trouble with it just recently, so it worked.
Speaker 1: But if you're playing locally and you just have four friends in your house at post-covid, and you have four controllers, then you're going to have a real good time.
Speaker 1: You won't have any technological issues with this game whatsoever.
Speaker 1: It'll work perfectly.
Speaker 1: So yeah, Moon Hunters, terrific use of two dollars for sure.
Speaker 0: It surprised me.
Speaker 0: It was way more than I expected and I want to keep playing it.
Speaker 1: Having played a lot, I guess not a lot, but quite a handful of these co-op action RPG things in Covid times, because that's the most common co-op game you're going to see on Steam.
Speaker 1: This one is definitely one of the better ones that will get more play, despite the fact that parts of it are meh.
Speaker 1: The parts of it that are unique are so unique and interesting that it is worth my time.
Speaker 0: You're not going to find another game like this yet.
Speaker 1: Two dollars.
Speaker 0: Two dollars.
Speaker 0: And not two dollars and less than a quarter, to be fair.
Speaker 0: Plus shacks, so another nickel or so.
Speaker 1: You can go on itch.io and I don't know what the price is on itch.io, but it's probably, I imagine, pay what you want, because that's what itch.io does for a lot of things.
Speaker 1: A plus.
Speaker 0: This has been Geek Nights with Rim and Scott.
Speaker 0: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design, and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at FrontRowCrew.com for show notes, discussion news, and more.
Speaker 0: Remember, Geek Nights is not one, but four different shows.
Speaker 0: SciTech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays, and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: Geek Nights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: Geek Nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 1: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.
Speaker 0: And the Patreon Patrons for this episode of Geek Nights are Alan Joyce, Eggman, Meikle, Link, Eiji, Graham, Finch, Yule, Dequina, My Heart, and I'll go through the last year or so podcasts that make representing Clinton, Walton, Ryan from New Zealand, Ryan, Perrin, Revue, Madbull34, Coward, Strand, Lily, Tenebrae, JustLikeADudeGuy, Chris, Rymer, Shervin, Von Hurl, and a bunch of people who do not want me to say their names.
Speaker 0: Huh?
Speaker 0: Good.
Speaker 1: We're going to touch it a little bit, but we're going to pass it then.
Speaker 0: Right here.
Speaker 0: This guy is a long-term person.