Speaker 0: It's Wednesday July 21st 2021.
Speaker 0: I'm rim.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott and this is geek nights.
Speaker 0: tonight We are talking about old Hanna-barbera cartoons.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: So, uh just because I tend to be pretty lucky and other than injuries like I almost never get seriously sick I don't really have any reason to go to a doctor.
Speaker 1: So I'm disease.
Speaker 0: Yep, that was God that was horrifying horrifying food poisoning.
Speaker 0: So the last two times I've been to a doctor for something serious were injuries and that's over the past like five years.
Speaker 0: Lyme disease was like I was still working at IBM.
Speaker 0: I hadn't even graduated from our IT.
Speaker 0: yet I actually had to go back and finish my senior year.
Speaker 1: severe severe allergy.
Speaker 1: Like you couldn't even breathe at night.
Speaker 0: that Actually, that's never happened to me.
Speaker 1: I thought you had like a Like a some allergy thing.
Speaker 1: Oh, no, was that like a reflux?
Speaker 1: was That was?
Speaker 0: I had bad heartburn at at RIT.
Speaker 0: Like so bad that I went to the doctor and the end result of all that they were like How many hours of sleep do you get on an average night?
Speaker 0: and don't lie to us?
Speaker 0: and I answered honestly And the doctor was like, I'm not prescribing you anything.
Speaker 0: sleep at least six hours a night for a week And I will bet you money.
Speaker 0: it goes away and guess what it disappeared completely if I got at least six hours of sleep.
Speaker 0: Sure That was during that era, you know, there's that.
Speaker 0: there's an era at RIT where Scott I recognize this, you know We were freshmen hanging out.
Speaker 0: There was a whole new experience.
Speaker 0: We'd stay up to like 11 hanging out then we'd stay up to like midnight Hanging out and then over that year in the next year We started to push that boundary further and further and further.
Speaker 0: then we hit a point that was too late Like we were saying.
Speaker 1: Is that one time we
Speaker 0: were staying out to like two three in the morning and it was like, okay We got a fucking sleep cuz we do actually have classes sometimes
Speaker 1: That bonitis
Speaker 0: yep, so, uh, I and actually the last I got a physical three years ago and I got a physical two years before that because generally every time I get a physical my doctors tell me I don't need to come Back anytime soon unless I have a complaint until I turn 40. and since I turned 40 next year.
Speaker 0: I figured alright I'm gonna get a physical.
Speaker 0: it's been three years.
Speaker 0: Just make sure there's nothing wrong that I don't know about.
Speaker 0: You know, like the blood work might say oh you got a thing like there's boat there's laden bonitis just ready to come out.
Speaker 0: So, um, I got.
Speaker 1: I Returned Bonitis to the boning electric bonaloo.
Speaker 0: So I got up physical for the first time in three years today.
Speaker 0: And of course, I saw a different doctor because my PCP who I see so rarely is on like long-term leave.
Speaker 0: so I just went to some random other doctor.
Speaker 0: they had all my charts like it didn't matter and And They read through my chart and they looked at me.
Speaker 0: and what the lady said was that I was and I'm not exaggerating I'm saying exactly what she said.
Speaker 0: You're the healthiest and most fit person I've ever seen.
Speaker 0: like.
Speaker 0: you don't need to come back in anytime soon But I don't know what to tell.
Speaker 0: you come back in a few years.
Speaker 0: Do you want to schedule your?
Speaker 0: you know, you're gonna be 40. you want to schedule a colonoscopy at some point?
Speaker 0: Just because and otherwise she was like, yeah, I got nothing for you.
Speaker 1: Keep doing what they say to me.
Speaker 1: They say to me the dentist they're like, well your teeth are clean.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'm not quite.
Speaker 0: I'm not as that lucky at the dentist.
Speaker 0: the dentist They're more like, yep Your teeth were fucked up the way you described from eight years of braces as a kid.
Speaker 0: There's nothing we can do about that.
Speaker 0: So, uh, yeah pending blood work I seemed I seemed to still be doing okay trucking along.
Speaker 0: the only funny thing was she asked about my diet and And real with my weight and everything and she basically said that I should eat a lot more carbs than I do Like specifically like eat more carbs for the love of God not to gain weight But because my blood sugar is like always really low Because I just don't eat enough food.
Speaker 0: compared to my activity level I'm not at the level where like and my fat like the body fat and all that combined.
Speaker 0: She basically said like My blood sugar probably gets way too low way too often because I'm straddling this line Just from how little I eat compared to how much exercise I get.
Speaker 1: Thanks so much.
Speaker 0: No, actually she said exercise more just eat more - Okay, that was the most exciting.
Speaker 0: There's still COVID like I'd like.
Speaker 0: while we're like seeing friends bit by bit and starting to do stuff It's not like I can go on a big trip or anything.
Speaker 0: So that physical was the most exciting thing that's happened to me recently Doctor's office the only.
Speaker 1: I'm surprised they're even doing physicals.
Speaker 1: It's like, you know, there's a pandemic.
Speaker 1: Why would you waste time doing you know?
Speaker 0: yeah, they actually.
Speaker 0: so they had sort of said yeah hold off on anything not essential like last year and I'd be basically stuck.
Speaker 0: though the email I got was like, yeah, you know last year was rough But this year you should start scheduling your preventative treatment type stuff again Unless you have a good reason not to Maybe next year.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I did been three years.
Speaker 0: I figured like it was.
Speaker 0: probably I should get one just in case.
Speaker 0: But meanwhile yesterday You know, we got up.
Speaker 0: I was doing my thing just working and There's a funny smell like in the apartment and it was a kind of ozone II kind of Bernie and I was like Yeah, it doesn't seem right.
Speaker 0: and then I went over to the balcony and I just felt stronger.
Speaker 0: So I opened the door and it smelled like everything was on fire.
Speaker 0: And then of course I checked.
Speaker 0: the wildfire smoke had made it to New York way more than it ever has Like it started way across the country.
Speaker 0: Yeah, okay in Canada The AQI in New York City yesterday was 170 which is like the chart usually shows like 0 to 50 is like green.
Speaker 0: 50 to 100 is like yellow like yeah, it's not great.
Speaker 0: up to 150 is like a orange.
Speaker 0: you should probably like don't go run them don't go.
Speaker 0: run 10 miles outside and 150 up is usually red like do not go outside.
Speaker 0: This is dangerous.
Speaker 1: The thing that bothers me the most is when there is an AQI Situation right?
Speaker 1: They're always like don't go outside.
Speaker 0: Don't exercise.
Speaker 1: Don't exercise.
Speaker 1: Don't go outside.
Speaker 1: Don't you know.
Speaker 0: and that's true because it's actually dangerous like it could hurt your lungs like depending on the kind of course it could.
Speaker 1: Right, that's I'm not saying that's not true Yeah, but what I'm saying is that it's a very victim-blamey thing.
Speaker 0: what they would that is a very u.s Thing I have been in.
Speaker 1: France Is high.
Speaker 1: when the AQI is high they should say don't drive no driving allowed period.
Speaker 0: I have been in places Outside of the u.s.
Speaker 0: Where that happens.
Speaker 0: I was in Singapore Makes sense.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like Singapore Paris both places have like Paris.
Speaker 0: They were like, yep Congestion charges are bigger because of this or don't drive.
Speaker 1: a friend on Twitter Suggested that when the AQI is high that you just jack up all the tolls on everything to be like a hundred dollars plus.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 0: I've seen places where they do things like yep.
Speaker 0: fireworks are now banned until further notice.
Speaker 1: Anyway That's at all times.
Speaker 1: Yeah doesn't stop anybody.
Speaker 0: Well, the congestion charges at least for Manhattan are slowly working through.
Speaker 1: Sure, but the point is we are capable of putting, you know, stop trade, you know We do.
Speaker 1: they did them during the hurricane.
Speaker 0: They said no transportation don't you can't go anywhere as humans are capable of a lot of things.
Speaker 0: The problem is we're bad at executing on those things because half of us want to change the same things.
Speaker 1: Just do the same transportation ban you do when a hurricane is coming when there's an AQI problem growing.
Speaker 0: agreed But the problem is half of America even a lot of people in place like New York City like it's still 20 or 30 percent of the people here a Want objectively bad things on purpose?
Speaker 1: So too bad.
Speaker 1: and also I know that this particular AQI incident was due to fires far away bad.
Speaker 1: right now It's like but if you turn off the cars Then that would.
Speaker 1: so it would probably bring it down from 150 to like.
Speaker 1: Oh, that was something that you know really stood out during the pandemic.
Speaker 0: like last year that summer New York City's air was so good.
Speaker 0: It was like Startling like it like it will stick with me because this summer it's completely it's.
Speaker 0: not only is it back to normal But the air is way worse because traffic in New York City is not just at an all-time high for like New York City Which it is.
Speaker 0: It is also at an all-time high for all of America.
Speaker 0: right now We literally have the worst traffic in America and the worst traffic New York City has ever had.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm, but last time and the air is shit now like the air is just shit here like it always is.
Speaker 0: Last summer the air was so good that like I smelled things in Manhattan that I'd never smelled before some of them not great But I also smelled good things like I smelled a lot more flowers.
Speaker 0: and If I look at my Strava like just my biking times my running times everything Even at the start of COVID not toward the end of last summer where I'd been running like a maniac and like just getting better At it my times were just better like at the start of last summer and I think it's partly just because the air was way better Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: I can't prove that but I have data that shows I was like 15% faster at the start of last running season compared to any other running season in my life.
Speaker 0: No, and the only difference was the air was way better.
Speaker 0: So yeah, anyway, we got some news.
Speaker 0: I guess what I want to start with is we have not seen it yet, but Bell Hosts Mamoru Hosanna's upcoming movie his latest work current upcoming.
Speaker 1: It's out.
Speaker 0: Well, it's out.
Speaker 0: I mean, we haven't seen it yet It's out.
Speaker 0: Is it out everywhere?
Speaker 0: Cuz it depends.
Speaker 1: It's the number one movie in the J at the Japanese box office.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't know people with you know, the Olympics can't have spectators, but people can go to the movie theater to see this.
Speaker 0: Yeah, uh, but I think what's notable is we talked about how it's coming like how we're excited about it How it appears like it's gonna be good.
Speaker 0: It's track record.
Speaker 0: Let's just bet in a thousand.
Speaker 0: So, you know Babe Ruth is coming up to the bat and odds are he's gonna hit another home run.
Speaker 0: But something moderately phenomenal happened.
Speaker 0: I say moderately because the caveat of this is this is a kind of performative thing that happens at Cannes like it's happened before but on can.
Speaker 0: but So when the film was shown there It got a 14 minute standing ovation from the audience.
Speaker 0: the record in the history of this festival was pans labyrinth.
Speaker 0: With 22 minutes labyrinth is overrated.
Speaker 1: I mean, I would say it is.
Speaker 1: I like it all I like.
Speaker 1: I think it is correctly rated.
Speaker 1: I Think people I mean my impression is that people absolutely lose their shit over patents.
Speaker 1: labyrinth like oh, it's some fucking incredible.
Speaker 1: And I'm like, it's really good, but it's not fucking credible.
Speaker 0: I would say it's incredible.
Speaker 0: It's on the lower end.
Speaker 1: I don't think so.
Speaker 0: It's a better movie than citizen Kane.
Speaker 0: I Would argue from a structural standpoint it is a better-made movie.
Speaker 0: Granted the difference is citizen Kane did some techniques that weren't widely done or had never been done.
Speaker 1: Well, yeah, I mean citizen.
Speaker 1: it's like a Mona Lisa situation like is them?
Speaker 1: how great?
Speaker 1: do you want a moment Lisa on your wall?
Speaker 1: Do you want a citizen can't on your wall?
Speaker 1: No, but they basically invented.
Speaker 1: it's like but The other.
Speaker 0: but so it's notable that an anime got such a response.
Speaker 0: But it's also notable that the few reviews I've seen or like candid statements from Everyone who wrote a review wrote like oh my god, they lost their shit.
Speaker 0: I have not seen.
Speaker 0: the worst review I saw said that this is the best movie of the year and something like The level.
Speaker 0: I'm not.
Speaker 0: I'm not saying it's hyperbole.
Speaker 0: it very well could be but people are acting like this is the greatest movie They have ever seen in their life.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so what I found out actually is I knew That the fact that it was called Belle that it had some relation to you know beauty.
Speaker 0: Oh, I assume Beauty and the Beast from that 10-second teaser pre teaser trailer.
Speaker 0: We saw of course.
Speaker 1: That's that's obvious It's not a secret at all.
Speaker 1: But what I found out was that the actual Japanese title of this movie is Belle.
Speaker 1: Colin Probably pronouncing this wrong Ryuto Sobokaso.
Speaker 1: Sobokaso know he may which the dragon princess Colin the dragon and the freckled princess, so it's instead of a beast instead of Beauty and the Beast It's the Beast but replace the Beast of the dragon.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah drag Alrighty, you're speaking to hand and replace Beauty with freckled princess and see you then you reverse them So the monster comes before the end.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so it's like Beast and the Beauty But you replace Beast with dragon and Beauty with freckled princess.
Speaker 0: So you're already speaking my language and - it's set as we know in a world where there is an online Virtuality like metaverse very similar.
Speaker 0: Yeah It's only you could almost argue that it's like it's set in the same universe as summer wars Just in like the future where the technology got better.
Speaker 1: Maybe I don't know but there was an interview with hosted it.
Speaker 1: that's going around very brief and you know He took some shots at Miyazaki in the interview.
Speaker 0: I was gonna talk about that next is a little bit very very entertaining.
Speaker 1: But the other thing he said in the interview is like look, you know We keep making all the media we keep making is like Oh internet bad internet scary, right?
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: He's like network like he's like the Internet's just a reality now.
Speaker 1: So he's like he's you know, and you can see try.
Speaker 1: he's trying quite obviously To create media with somewhat positive, you know out, you know internet Like the moral of summer wars was not that internet system.
Speaker 0: We have to take it down before it.
Speaker 0: Skynet stuffs The more.
Speaker 0: the moral of that was a bunch of other stuff and there were both positive and negative aspects of that.
Speaker 1: So Digimon summer wars and now Belle he just he's done three internet movies, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah So that's pretty cool.
Speaker 1: And you know also you thought was I've been thinking independently recently which I guess I'm in alignment with him in some way, right?
Speaker 1: And you know, we see you look back in time at you know Popular media, especially sci-fi stuff, right and there was Sort of an optimistic side of things in 50s and 60s, you know, you had like, you know world of tomorrow type stuff going on.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and nowadays almost all Sci-fi stuff is some sort of dystopian, you know, um play gods.
Speaker 1: Yeah So it's it's sort of nice.
Speaker 1: It's like, you know, there are some other people not doing.
Speaker 0: there's a chance We could not fuck this up.
Speaker 0: and there are good things that have come out of all of this.
Speaker 1: There is some mean things aren't looking good.
Speaker 1: It sure looks like in the real world we am play God.
Speaker 0: Well, cuz our equivalent of all these online universes for most people in America is basically Facebook, which is right.
Speaker 1: In the real world, we clearly am play gods.
Speaker 1: in most sci-fi stuff You know is telling a story of warning us stop playing gods, but it's nice to see some sort of Positive outlook like hey the internet can be a good thing for humanity.
Speaker 1: Here is let me show you a world in which that is true, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah like that.
Speaker 1: So, uh, even I'm not we need to even if it's false.
Speaker 0: Oh, but I guess also like.
Speaker 0: I am NOT going to Come in to finally seeing this movie Expecting it to be the greatest film I've ever seen.
Speaker 0: but I have never seen This level of just got like this type of discussion at this level right from so many voices from a movie in my life.
Speaker 1: It's ya know all we've seen plenty of anime movies coming right from.
Speaker 1: you know Any kind of movie like there been high fives making all these movies, right, you know There wasn't hype for any other previous hosted a movie in this fashion, right?
Speaker 0: But I'm saying I have not seen this level of hype for really Mirai almost any movie.
Speaker 0: You know a lot of them were well received But they were not hyped this extensively like just the the uniformity of voices who very rarely would say something so hyperbolic saying that it's the greatest film they've seen is.
Speaker 0: I 'm just trying not to Read into that too much and come into this movie with expectations, but this movie could be really good.
Speaker 1: It could also be.
Speaker 1: those are the same people who you know overate Pan's Labyrinth and it won't be incredible It'll just be really good.
Speaker 0: I mean, I still think Pan's Labyrinth is incredible.
Speaker 1: I don't think so.
Speaker 1: Okay, so It's just really good.
Speaker 0: Anyway, and that thing you alluded to.
Speaker 0: so I'm gonna go through a little thread of a Twitter conversation here because there's an article on the Japan Times where you get a like.
Speaker 0: it's a bunch of stuff on my more hosted.
Speaker 0: You can just read it.
Speaker 0: It's a pretty good article, but we got some choice.
Speaker 0: Notes That he had some comments on how Miyazaki Handled female heroines and you can.
Speaker 1: well, I learned some things from this art.
Speaker 0: Oh, I learned some things too.
Speaker 1: I did not know that he worked on any amount of Utena under a different name.
Speaker 0: Yep So mom our hopes that I worked on a bunch of episodes of utenna doing doing storyboards and key animation.
Speaker 0: In fact, it appears that he storyboarded the last episode.
Speaker 1: I Also did not know but he did it under this name Katsu.
Speaker 0: Yo Hashimoto.
Speaker 0: Sure, and that is the only thing.
Speaker 0: he did that under that name except He also was a unit director for stem or a Champloo under that name and I can't find any information on why you use that Name for those three projects and nothing else like no one's written anything about this that I can find.
Speaker 1: Usually it's because you're supposed to be working on one thing and you got a side project, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, but he did a lot a lot of reasons that artists use names.
Speaker 1: You know songwriters use different names all the way.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I'm saying he has a huge portfolio and the only works he ever used a pseudonym on where?
Speaker 1: It's not.
Speaker 1: pseudonyms are not are not anything to like, you know care about Never a big deal or have any interesting reasons behind.
Speaker 0: but he used it for three different films that are not.
Speaker 1: it's probably you know It's most likely just like boring old royalties reasons or something like that, right?
Speaker 1: It's never.
Speaker 0: those things.
Speaker 0: Those things can be very interesting.
Speaker 0: I'm not saying it's suspicious.
Speaker 0: I'm think it's interesting.
Speaker 1: They're almost never interesting.
Speaker 1: I often find those songwriters who use different pseudonyms.
Speaker 1: It's because they're.
Speaker 1: they're a songwriter.
Speaker 1: they could write any kind of music and they use different song names for different genres for branding purposes and or Separating.
Speaker 1: there's music amongst different publishers.
Speaker 1: They'll sign a deal under one name and send a different deal under another name.
Speaker 1: things like that.
Speaker 0: Storyboarded six episodes of utenna that are all pivotal pivotal ones and he storyboarded a chunk of the utenna movie, right?
Speaker 1: okay, anyway the point the other city major thing that I learned that I did not know is he actually was the director of how's moving castle but Halfway through he was like fuck this and he got out of there and that's why he's not the director of house moving.
Speaker 0: That's a movie.
Speaker 1: I think that's that is a huge information that I guess other people may have already known that I did not know.
Speaker 0: I feel like that movie would have been a lot better if he had actually been the director to the end.
Speaker 1: quite I quite agree, but that gives a lot more knowing.
Speaker 1: that gives much more weight to his Miyazaki zing.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and you can read about the Miyazaki zing.
Speaker 0: Oh, no We because we're getting back into our lives a little bit and we've been skipping to some geek nights.
Speaker 0: We tend to go way long in the news because Scott and I don't even have time to talk that often except during making the show.
Speaker 0: So all our episodes have been super long lately, but you can read that quote yourself.
Speaker 0: and there's also a thread of the utenna people who Figured all this out and they're talking a lot about huh?
Speaker 0: the episodes he worked on were pivotal around jury the character specifically and he seems to have Storyboarded away from the original script.
Speaker 0: There's a And I want to read.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna dig more into that but I don't know enough But I see a bunch of people trying to do that research and like digging hard to get evidence of that.
Speaker 0: Yeah so this Conversation is like ongoing Among people who are trying to figure it out and I'm just gonna keep an eye on them and see if there's anything interesting there Or at least some specifics to corroborate it.
Speaker 1: Mmm, so I think I think it won't be until you know, this is coming out this year.
Speaker 1: I don't know if we're gonna see another Big anime movie from anyone until next.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and in terms of animation about the scheduling We still have a backlog.
Speaker 0: you was is or we have a big backlog of animated movies?
Speaker 0: We still got a watch and review on gig nights not even anime like you didn't see legend of hay yet.
Speaker 0: No, and that's not really it Mike legend of hay is they like a tier Animated movie?
Speaker 0: it is fantastic and I think you'll really like it.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so you had a thing you want to talk about the Popeye.
Speaker 1: Oh Yeah, so this isn't really so much a news really.
Speaker 1: It's just a thing that I've discovered recently because someone else I follow has been retweeting it.
Speaker 1: So there is an official Popeye Twitter account that I assume is run by some marketing social media manager Who must work for whoever owns Popeye right now?
Speaker 1: I don't know who that is.
Speaker 1: I could probably google it really easily but so can you.
Speaker 1: and I was just really.
Speaker 0: I just noticed what the actual name of the account is the at name.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so this account is run very very well But it is also extremely like, you know pro LGBTQ and leans hard into the fact that you know Popeye is basically like.
Speaker 1: I don't know what he what he qualifies as gender wise but it's not a system amphibious Yeah Right.
Speaker 1: So I just think that it's really kind of awesome.
Speaker 1: You know, you see a lot of other brand, you know, it is just.
Speaker 1: you know I don't know what if they're actually doing anything right, you know in terms of like, you know Money or anything like that, but it's like just to see a brand, you know Not just put up some rainbow flag in June, right but to be always seemingly always frequently Right actively like leaning into it hard right and not just being like, you know making some corporate.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well, it's a. it's a take that for all the problems of rainbow capitalism a not a benefit of it But a a thing to note about it.
Speaker 0: Is that rainbow capitalism type things happen more When the people making decisions with money decide that that is the majority of people they're going to make money off of themselves And it often can represent a sea change in the general sentiment of a population.
Speaker 1: Hmm.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's just I'm really even though I'd you know, how much do I care about Popeye?
Speaker 0: I care quite a bit because the one thing a lot of people like look at this account I'll say this most people have this idea of what Popeye is but never actually read Any of the old Popeye comics or saw the old pop air cartoons?
Speaker 0: They are fucked up weird shit They are.
Speaker 1: they are so weird You have no one of those things are like I saw.
Speaker 1: I probably saw mostly pop old pop.
Speaker 0: Oh, I saw like the old radically Spare.
Speaker 1: yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I have seen them.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but I thought a lot I was because they weren't on.
Speaker 0: they weren't on TV with any regular Film reels of Popeye cartoons that we would bust out and watch.
Speaker 1: Okay, we didn't have those The Popeye actual comics.
Speaker 1: I you know, I saw them once in a while But it's like I could have bought a whole book of them.
Speaker 1: But you know you still can but I just never did because I didn't.
Speaker 1: yeah It wasn't a high priority like oh, let me buy all the Popeye collection, but I busted a Tracy collection instead.
Speaker 0: Yeah, all I'll say is if you never read old Popeye you're in for a ride.
Speaker 0: It's there is no way it's even close to what you think it's like.
Speaker 0: and you know If you've never seen the live-action Popeye movie with Robin Willie, I have not.
Speaker 1: I didn't even know there was such a thing.
Speaker 0: right, I can't.
Speaker 0: but the live-action Popeye movie is orthogonally adjacent To the live-action Dick Tracy movie in that it is a fucking set piece.
Speaker 0: They made that Popeye true to the car to the old comic Popeye probably to a degree that was unhealthy and unwise and Robin Williams basically just ate the mic and swallowed it.
Speaker 0: He ate the camera.
Speaker 0: He ate the scenery.
Speaker 0: He threw himself into that role to a degree.
Speaker 0: That was almost too much even for Robin Williams.
Speaker 0: Okay, then that movie I would say is a triumph.
Speaker 0: But I also am not going to necessarily say that it is good.
Speaker 1: I don't think it's as good as Pan's Labyrinth.
Speaker 0: Ah No, it is not as good as Pan's Labyrinth But it is.
Speaker 0: it is something and I'm just gonna leave it at that.
Speaker 0: I kind of want to watch it again.
Speaker 0: It's been decades.
Speaker 1: Yeah, follow follow the official Popeye account on Twitter.
Speaker 1: It's it's it's worth it.
Speaker 1: Even if you don't give a lot of craps about Popeye.
Speaker 0: but anyway things Of the day.
Speaker 0: so uh Scott you familiar with the epic of Gilgamesh?
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's you know, I've played Gilgamesh.
Speaker 0: the game is So, uh, if you if any of you out there have never read or like don't know a lot about the epic of Gilgamesh it's one of the oldest like things humans have made.
Speaker 0: that is a narrative and This is like Early early civilization that still exists that we still have.
Speaker 1: Yes that we know that we can still read Survive.
Speaker 0: this is like this is a Babylonian poem.
Speaker 0: Like we're talking thousands of years before Homer so Thousands of years before the Odyssey thousands of years now.
Speaker 0: It might be older.
Speaker 0: It might be older in the time the Odyssey of written was written and perfoil written performed.
Speaker 0: then the Odyssey is to us today like.
Speaker 0: that is the sense of scale you need to internalize.
Speaker 0: and One thing about it is that it is about the concept of how did animals become human?
Speaker 0: And the answer spoilers is through urban living like it really like the narrative of this story if you have never read it is basically that humans didn't become human until they lived in cities and Like lived in an urban environment and people who did not live in urban environments were not yet fully human.
Speaker 0: And that is up.
Speaker 0: That is a take for so partially true.
Speaker 0: Yeah in a lot of ways I mean, I live in New York City and it's pretty dire out there outside of these borders But I digress.
Speaker 0: so but one thing that happens in the epic of Gilgamesh got it right is that Shamat sends Goes out to find Anki do who is a human who is not yet human.
Speaker 0: It is a in human form But he acts and lives like an animal and he is very powerful and very wise as an animal.
Speaker 0: and the whole story is about He becomes human and becomes friends with Gilgamesh, but Anki do.
Speaker 0: There's a pivotal pivotal scene that gets talked about a lot especially when like high school kids read Gilgamesh where he has sex with her for a week and That is a scene like that.
Speaker 0: So we always knew that that scene was written in one way and it was written slightly Differently in an updated version of the epic like hundreds or maybe even a thousand years later Recent like very recent evidence that is pretty rock-solid like clay tablets that are all confirmed Have shown us that that is not two different versions of that sex scene.
Speaker 0: There are two Different week-long sex orgies that happen in the tail of Gilgamesh one.
Speaker 1: Well, you know there was.
Speaker 1: there was a lot of anime to watch in those thousands of years ago, right?
Speaker 1: So that was pretty much the only entertainment you had.
Speaker 0: Yeah Kind of like how kids read Shakespeare and think it's dry.
Speaker 0: But if you see Shakespeare perform.
Speaker 0: Well, you're like, oh It's a bunch of sex jokes and fart jokes, oh I get it.
Speaker 0: I was supposed to cheer and yell and interrupt them during this scene.
Speaker 0: So yeah Gilgamesh.
Speaker 0: two separate week-long sex orgies Confirmed and this article does a really good job of framing how they figured this out and why it matters and why.
Speaker 0: living in New York Is great.
Speaker 0: So what do you got way to go?
Speaker 1: Go to Gomesh.
Speaker 1: So way back in the in the elementary school times right all the computers in school were mostly Apple twos.
Speaker 1: Maybe a Mac was towards the late elementary school time.
Speaker 1: Yeah And all the printers we had were mostly like, you know Apple the the dot matrix ones, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, they were the ones that could print on unlimited length pages with the little tear-offs usually.
Speaker 0: Yeah, exactly Technology came a long way while we were young.
Speaker 1: So if you wanted to print something well, you could open up a word processing program type text and print it out.
Speaker 1: Right, but maybe you wanted to print something that wasn't just text.
Speaker 1: Well, it's the JPEG and the gift did not exist yet.
Speaker 1: So You wanted to print something else?
Speaker 1: It's not like, you know, you could like draw something on your screen like with InDesign.
Speaker 1: So there was a program that was extremely popular in our school and I assume every other school and anyone else who had an Apple to computer called the print shop, right and Basically, you would open up this program and you could choose, you know Like you want to put.
Speaker 1: you want to print a big banner a greeting card, right?
Speaker 1: It's like there were choices of things you wanted to print out and then you would you know Fill in sort of these templates like it's like.
Speaker 1: okay choose one of the pictures the cake the bear, you know You know you got choices, right and You could change the banner the the borders if you wanted to and you could change the colors Depending on what inks your printer had, you know, and you could type some text and you know Yeah, a lot of there was a lot of you know, creative flexibility you have with this little program and then you would push print and One thing you could do that even computers today really can't do very well because it was dot matrix.
Speaker 1: It could just print something fucking long.
Speaker 1: You know print very often these really long banners that would say like happy birthday so-and-so.
Speaker 0: You know every elementary school has like the incident that gets talked about during like a particular time period.
Speaker 1: you printed something long.
Speaker 0: I didn't do it, but the incident was basically who printed the big dick?
Speaker 0: It came out of the printer one day and nobody would take no one would take the fall And we know whatever figured out who did it and that was like the incident.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I want to say this was second or third grade Yeah, but yeah, so this program, you know, there's like nothing else that prints things like this program does right?
Speaker 1: It's a very Particular aesthetic and these particular designs.
Speaker 1: you really can't replicate them.
Speaker 1: But somebody took the old Apple program and they emulated it obviously not difficult at all And they stuck it in a web browser again not difficult at all.
Speaker 1: archive org has a huge archive.
Speaker 1: I'm sure that probably includes this program Emulated.
Speaker 1: but on this website the print shop club They have modified slash hooked into this emulated ROM of this application.
Speaker 0: Oh shit I thought you're thinking today was just this web page working.
Speaker 0: Not that bad.
Speaker 1: I didn't even notice that bit in such a way because just emulating an old Apple to program is no big deal.
Speaker 1: Right every single right.
Speaker 1: they have emulated it and modified it in such a way.
Speaker 1: Then it comes time to print with this Apple to program in your web browser.
Speaker 1: That's zero dollars.
Speaker 1: At least nowadays.
Speaker 1: It's zero dollars.
Speaker 1: It will create for you a PDF.
Speaker 1: So then you can.
Speaker 1: I guess you still can't print something long because you have a dot matrix printer, but any of the one pagers Long if you send it to the right kind of print shop and a PDF.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah you send your send your long multi page PDF to the right place and they'll print you something long, but Now you can print a print shop greeting card for whoever on there.
Speaker 1: You know birthday anniversary, whatever.
Speaker 0: So our friend red's birthday will happen during our beach trip.
Speaker 0: I uh, I think we should all make out a little.
Speaker 0: I think we should make some greeting cards.
Speaker 0: Okay, I got some ideas.
Speaker 0: I'm feeling this.
Speaker 1: You can't get a Pokemon into this thing.
Speaker 0: No, I'll have to draw one badly In the meta moment.
Speaker 0: the geek nice book club book the tale of Genji.
Speaker 0: as Genji continues to sleepwalk through life I feel like by the end of summer we'll be ready to talk about this on the show.
Speaker 1: While it is the first novel ever written by any human ever It is not even close to being as old as the tale of Gilgamesh.
Speaker 0: Nope, but tale of Gilgamesh is a saga.
Speaker 1: It is indeed.
Speaker 1: It is not a novel and that is why The tale of Genji is still the first novel ever written by human beings that we are aware of.
Speaker 0: Genji It's just like I say this every time but though as I keep reading He just sleepwalks through life Like he's like.
Speaker 0: he's almost like a Captain Tyler figure except he never seems to have a moment where he does something that matters.
Speaker 0: We'll see how.
Speaker 0: it'll see how it keeps going but uh, I got some thoughts on it so far But it's enjoyable.
Speaker 0: my advice to you though If you're gonna start reading it with us now that we're reading it a pretty steady pace Don't fuss over fiddly little details to figure out exactly what happened If you're like a little vague on how who said what or like who someone was.
Speaker 0: Just unless you're trying to become a scholar of Genji just keep trucking read it like you'd read a dime store romance novel.
Speaker 0: Yep, like that's the way to go.
Speaker 0: In some other news.
Speaker 0: We just did a panel a new one at the penny arcade Expo online East called Atari game design.
Speaker 0: It live stream.
Speaker 0: a lot of people watched.
Speaker 0: it was very well received.
Speaker 0: The entirety of it is now on YouTube.
Speaker 0: You can just watch it.
Speaker 0: It's live.
Speaker 0: Then yep, it's up there.
Speaker 0: check it out.
Speaker 0: It's pretty good.
Speaker 1: I have in a somewhat also news I have Mostly finished at least 1.0 finished right even though I then immediately filed a bunch of issues against myself The tool That will form the foundation of the new geek nice website.
Speaker 1: So I'm gonna be making like a little video.
Speaker 1: It's already on github and whatnot.
Speaker 1: But I'm gonna make a little demo video Said if you want to make a website You'll be able to see how to use this tool to get Basically a whole bunch of shit done in like a matter of minutes and then start making your website.
Speaker 1: So Now that this exists it took me a long time to make it I can use it and be able to develop Geek nights website and make changes to it very very quickly and rapidly.
Speaker 1: So that's all gonna be rolling Really when it's not nice out anymore, yeah, which is fine.
Speaker 0: cuz like I there's a bunch of projects.
Speaker 0: I have a project around taking every main bit of every geek nuts episode ever and pulling it out into a standalone thing.
Speaker 0: Cuz people might want our review of like an anime.
Speaker 0: For that we did in like 2007 and don't need 30 minutes of us talking about Bikes or the pub crawl outside or whatever the hell was going on at Beacon at the time Yep.
Speaker 1: So yeah, it's if you're if you want to make a program a website And there isn't an existing web application that does what you want to do.
Speaker 1: Like you don't make a blog just use WordPress.
Speaker 1: if you want to make e-commerce.
Speaker 1: There's a lot of choices.
Speaker 1: Yep Like I hiccup suddenly, but if you want to make something like this I want to make a website that does not exist, you know There isn't a software that does the website you want to do.
Speaker 1: You may want to consider using the thing that I just made YouTube and whatnot.
Speaker 0: geek nights will finally at some point one Incorporate our new branding into like our website which still has our old brand.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's what's gonna happen.
Speaker 1: Oh, I should probably mention the thing.
Speaker 1: I'm the tool I made is called Django.
Speaker 1: go boot because it helps you boot up Django better than the regular template thing that they give you.
Speaker 1: use the default Django start project.
Speaker 1: that doesn't get you anywhere.
Speaker 1: Yeah this the thing I made.
Speaker 1: gets you the template and the repository and the CI CD stack and Launches your production server as soon as you make a release.
Speaker 1: all it does almost everything for you know to do anything.
Speaker 0: It's good stuff.
Speaker 1: You do it to do a tiny bit.
Speaker 0: It also means we can start to add one.
Speaker 0: Eventually, it means some things we wanted to add to our website.
Speaker 0: We'll be able to appear on our website.
Speaker 0: Yep, we have pointedly avoiding like avoided putting new types of things on the website because that would have meant fucking with the old website.
Speaker 0: All right, so, uh, let's dive right into it.
Speaker 0: Hannah Barbara cartoons Uh, uh, we're not covering like the history of Hannah Barbara cuz they You can go
Speaker 1: online you can go on YouTube you can go on anywhere and there are people who are like scholars of this shit and they know all the fucking details of how everything went down and we don't know any of that and even If we researched it, we couldn't why bother repeating what someone else who knows more already said.
Speaker 1: so We're just gonna focus on hey our Experience with these things.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like cuz we watched a lot.
Speaker 0: both of us watch a lot of Hannah Barbara cartoons, even if we didn't realize they were Hannah Barbara for much of our lives.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so for for those who are unaware, right?
Speaker 1: Maybe not from the US or not have younger, right?
Speaker 1: In the United States, right cartoons have been around a long time.
Speaker 1: Anime, you know that you had your Disney's.
Speaker 1: you had your Warner Brothers is right flesh your brother putting out, right?
Speaker 1: They were putting out these really high quality animations, you know in theaters playing before movies, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, you watch a Bugs Bunny from like, you know the 40s or whatever looks incredible, right?
Speaker 1: and then once Television came around, you know six mostly.
Speaker 1: we're talking 60s 60s 70s 80s and then fading out 90s, right?
Speaker 1: in those times You Need TV animation.
Speaker 1: so they did replay the movie.
Speaker 1: quality animations on television, right?
Speaker 1: I saw a lot of Warner Brothers on TV, but you needed something to go on TV.
Speaker 1: That was cheaper, right?
Speaker 1: less to produce Yeah.
Speaker 1: And so in the United States the Hannah Barbara production studio, I had a large hand in producing Lots and lots and lots of television animation from the city, you know especially 60 70s 80s and then fading out in the 90s
Speaker 0: people who made like 1957 the people who made Tom and Jerry and a bunch of people who used to work at him.
Speaker 1: Tom and Jerry was like MGM Right.
Speaker 0: Yes So basically a bunch of people who were working in and around MGM got together to make This and there and then the two people who drove it all and like founded the studio Were named Hannah and Barbara William Hannah and Joseph Barbara.
Speaker 1: So the you know, the shows often feature much lower quality Animation right?
Speaker 1: You'd be like wow, this is newer than that.
Speaker 1: then like Snow White Snow White looks a hundred times better than this.
Speaker 1: It's like yeah well snow yeah kind of.
Speaker 0: when I was long and a Barbara cartoons actually messed with my like in like my perceived chronology of animation because I assumed as a kid like when I was really young at a pre-internet era that Like Yogi Bear was ancient compared to all these Disney things.
Speaker 0: I was watching Yeah, it was.
Speaker 1: but you know, the thing is you had to make how many episodes of Yogi Bear?
Speaker 1: You only had to make 90 minutes.
Speaker 1: snow white snow.
Speaker 1: I had more money and was on a movie theater.
Speaker 1: right the Yogi Bear didn't make as much.
Speaker 1: I was a kid.
Speaker 0: There was no internet.
Speaker 0: I didn't know.
Speaker 1: All right, so Hannah Barbara the other thing that really you know Stood out about them was just they were.
Speaker 1: they were definitely a quantity shop, right?
Speaker 1: Just throwing shit against the wall, right seeing what stuck when things stuck They made lots and lots of episodes of that thing Right and worked harder at it and did a better job on it and when things didn't stick they would end quickly.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there's a lot of shows they made that had a very small number of episodes.
Speaker 0: I would never got replayed anywhere ever even just looking at the stuff from like the 60s and 70s.
Speaker 1: I only recognize like 10% of these shows Because a lot of things like we're throwing shit at the wall They didn't stick and they weren't popular.
Speaker 1: and then just like alright enough of that.
Speaker 0: Let's move, you know Like I got I got to talk about this this Roman holidays thing because I found it on this list.
Speaker 0: They they only made 13 episodes.
Speaker 0: So the Flintstones, you know thing they made Super popular like that was a that was like that is still a touchstone of American pop culture the Flintstones.
Speaker 0: So they were trying to remember it was trying to recreate the success of the Flintstones by having another show With a modern ish family living in a heavy heavily fictionalized ancient time.
Speaker 0: So they made a show called the Roman holidays.
Speaker 0: Basically the Flintstones but set during ancient Rome from the Jetsons is just Flintstones in the future.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: There's even a movie.
Speaker 0: So, uh, they made this show with characters like mr.
Speaker 0: Evictus and Mr.
Speaker 0: Tycoonius and it looks like it was just awful that failed instantly.
Speaker 0: But also they have fucking Dom DeLuise to voice a bunch of the characters.
Speaker 1: Well, how big of a deal was Dom DeLuise at that time?
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah at that time.
Speaker 0: So, let's see.
Speaker 0: This was miss early seven.
Speaker 1: my he might have been a big deal already.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 0: this was early 70s.
Speaker 0: So he had not yet done all those Mel Brooks movies.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so Not a big deal yet.
Speaker 0: I didn't realize he didn't become a big deal until the basically right after that.
Speaker 0: That was like the last not big deal thing.
Speaker 1: He did Well, so we We did a whole episode on Scooby-doo alone.
Speaker 1: So let us not speak of Scooby-doo.
Speaker 1: Let us speak of everything else.
Speaker 0: So I. the one thing I got to say first is those shows that I wrote like as a kid.
Speaker 0: I Recognized a lot of things that I thought were Hannah Barbara and I was right and I always had this perception as a kid That they were bad.
Speaker 0: But I still watched them, but I didn't like watching them.
Speaker 0: Like it was.
Speaker 1: this weird situation Depends on which one.
Speaker 0: like Yogi Bear I never liked but I watched it a lot on TV for some reason I just never liked ever here.
Speaker 1: I just didn't.
Speaker 1: I just didn't really like.
Speaker 0: I didn't like it at all.
Speaker 0: I don't know why I watched it like.
Speaker 0: it just seemed so Plotting and insipid and like.
Speaker 0: the jokes weren't funny and it was like the same fucking joke every time.
Speaker 1: but somehow It was the same joke every time.
Speaker 0: that's it was just on TV and I would just sit there watching it.
Speaker 0: But some of the shows I would actively watch and enjoy like I particularly as a kid.
Speaker 0: I like the Flintstones I like the Jetsons, uh, I didn't actually like Johnny Quest, but all of my friends liked it.
Speaker 0: I just didn't think I did not like.
Speaker 1: Johnny Quest was a weird one in that if you saw The aesthetic of Johnny Quest what Johnny Quest is supposed to be right?
Speaker 1: I looked at it and I'm like That's the thing.
Speaker 1: I should like that aesthetically.
Speaker 1: That's amazing, right?
Speaker 1: It's like but actually watching Johnny Quest.
Speaker 1: I never enjoyed it.
Speaker 1: So I never.
Speaker 1: I never watched it.
Speaker 1: that much interesting because like one of my favorite looks like a thing I should like.
Speaker 1: but no actually I don't.
Speaker 0: one of my favorite animated shows in history including anime is actually the venture brothers.
Speaker 0: I think it's.
Speaker 0: it's a like.
Speaker 0: it is a phenomenal and unique show which is primarily a Johnny Quest pair.
Speaker 0: It started as a Johnny Quest parody like straight up But then it you know it it did.
Speaker 0: I know this is a word that people misuse a lot But I mean this directly specifically and I'm choosing this word carefully.
Speaker 0: It evolved into a deconstruction of shows like Johnny Quest and then it went way beyond that into being like a post Johnny Quest thing and they just kept it going.
Speaker 0: somehow They kept it going.
Speaker 1: all they had to do and then they just died will change course.
Speaker 0: now I did enjoy some of the like.
Speaker 0: they made a lot of shows that I would see like once and then never see again and every able to fight again like a lot of cartoon adaptations of Real things like they made some Three Stooges like one-offs.
Speaker 0: They made some Laurel and Hardy one-offs sure.
Speaker 1: Well, cuz most of these things right aired before we were even alive.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and we all and on broadcast television if there's a Saturday morning cartoon, you know, for example I don't know.
Speaker 1: Let's see again.
Speaker 1: This is let's see, it's fine.
Speaker 1: Oh, here's a good example, right?
Speaker 1: So there was a show called fantastic max.
Speaker 1: apparently it had 26 episodes.
Speaker 1: I saw that when I was a kid because it was actually on like daily on syndicated on a particular channel at a particular time.
Speaker 0: I've never heard of or seen fantastic max nor do I recognize it from looking at images?
Speaker 1: It's actually a really sort of imaginative show.
Speaker 1: I want to say it's almost like Muppets babies and she's really never heard of this.
Speaker 0: This does not exist in my universe.
Speaker 1: It's like this kid is like he's a baby in a crib Right named max and he's got like a friend robot and shit, but he's like.
Speaker 1: then he's going off on like space adventures.
Speaker 1: But actually it was just his imagination or something.
Speaker 0: along those more images I see from the show the less I recognize that I've definitely never encountered bad to this show in my life until just now.
Speaker 1: But yeah I watched like many episodes of that show because it happened to be on right.
Speaker 1: a show I liked a lot better than that Was captain caveman who I thought was funny hitting things with his club and that was basically almost never on right.
Speaker 1: It's like.
Speaker 1: I'd be lucky if I think it was hated captain caveman and I'll admit I also.
Speaker 0: I also hated Hence on scrappy.
Speaker 0: do I also hated wacky races to be honest?
Speaker 1: Wacky races.
Speaker 0: There's there's my problem with wacky races.
Speaker 0: when I encountered it The concept was like perfect.
Speaker 0: I just pump it into my veins.
Speaker 0: get all these cartoon characters of all these things.
Speaker 0: do it right like that.
Speaker 0: I was so into that concept, but every single episode I watched was the antithesis of humor.
Speaker 1: Like he's just monthly going.
Speaker 0: yeah like that.
Speaker 0: I like that but he has to go In a context that is novel and funny at some point.
Speaker 1: No such thing.
Speaker 0: No Like wacky race, you know, it's funny.
Speaker 0: The wacky races are heavily parodied in venture brothers as well.
Speaker 1: Okay, sure But yeah, it's like.
Speaker 1: you know you is pretty much just like what.
Speaker 1: when were you born?
Speaker 1: When were you home watching TV, right and you know, obviously the big shows the ones that had tons of episodes.
Speaker 1: It's like I don't know.
Speaker 1: I may have seen every Jetsons.
Speaker 1: It's possible.
Speaker 1: But you know, this may have seen every Flintstones.
Speaker 1: I don't remember them all.
Speaker 0: there's actually only a hundred and sixty six episodes of the Flintstones.
Speaker 0: That's less than a Sailor Moon.
Speaker 1: So this is something that shocked me because even as a kid I knew that the Flintstones was like an was one of the only cart like first.
Speaker 1: only Cartoon that was like on primetime television was super popular It was a super big deal and that it was super until The Simpsons.
Speaker 1: It was the longest running, right?
Speaker 1: So I had been under the impression when I was a kid that the Flintstones was Still running and had been raw.
Speaker 1: I was too with a lot of these shows and that And that I had seen that I was seeing new episodes.
Speaker 1: when it was on prime It was on primetime even when in like in the 80s at certain only that but a lot.
Speaker 1: and I was under the impression that I was seeing a New Flintstones episode and it was only today that I realized from Wikipedia that actually no he ran from nineteen sixty nine sixty six And that was at the end.
Speaker 1: But the other why the hell was it on primetime in the 80s.
Speaker 1: I don't understand.
Speaker 1: Well, what was that big a deal?
Speaker 0: do it to that?
Speaker 0: a lot of these shows.
Speaker 0: they wouldn't even air early episodes of them because sometimes they were in black and white or They like didn't fit the style of the time.
Speaker 1: There's a lot of release.
Speaker 1: Yeah only a subset of the episodes were actually getting syndicated and repeated and you could you know You could sort of actually see even as a child You could sort of see like there were shifts in the show right Flintstones For example, when the alien gazoo guy shows up, right?
Speaker 1: You can definitely see there's like pre gazoo Flintstones and post gazoo Flintstones and you can even as a kid I understood like ah, they're trying to you know, get the show like revitalized like I would
Speaker 0: know and for any and this happened for a lot of Hanna-Barbera cartoons an Episode would come on and between the opener and how the animation looked especially like how thick the lines were and how straight the line Was I would know ooh, this is gonna be a good one or this is gonna be a bad one.
Speaker 0: I knew like kind of like with Tom and Jerry like you could tell oh, those are the bad Tom and Jerry's But there were definitely different sets of them, right?
Speaker 1: There were Johnny quests then there was like new Johnny quest and then there was like there were like three different Johnny quest Serieses.
Speaker 1: right and like only one of them was the one that was like shown much later.
Speaker 1: We probably never even seen the first two But I also the episode was different the third one and we talked about this a lot with Scooby-doo.
Speaker 0: Some of these shows I'd see even possibly the first episode onward.
Speaker 0: But because of the way pop culture talked about them and just because like there would be elements of the show I didn't understand.
Speaker 0: as a kid for various reasons I always assumed that these shows had been running since like for decades like they just been running like I came in and Oh, the Flintstones was the only one that I thought like had been running.
Speaker 0: I thought that about Scooby-doo and a bunch of other things too School Scooby-doo.
Speaker 1: I understood that like the original Scooby-doo was no longer running but like pup named Scooby-doo was like the.
Speaker 0: oh No, but I just I knew that the pup named Scooby-doo was was weird like recent garbage and I only like the older ones.
Speaker 1: I Got you.
Speaker 1: I kind of like the putt anyway, and it's well, we all agree that anything was crappy.
Speaker 0: Do was bad news.
Speaker 1: So another thing is that.
Speaker 0: but I think he raised about why did we have all these weird perceptions?
Speaker 0: And why was it like?
Speaker 0: I think what happened was no information available But also the anime filter kind of like how a lot of people like oh in the 90s like all the anime was great.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's more that head of our Barbera one.
Speaker 0: they only made more episodes of shows.
Speaker 0: that did well when they first ran and then in syndication the Stuff that was aired was basically the cream of the crop the most popular exactly proven successful things.
Speaker 1: So we saw the distilled best that had a Barbara had to offer In order to see a bad one on TV in the broadcast days, right?
Speaker 1: You would have had to watch it on Saturday morning, right when it was a brand new show.
Speaker 1: You could only see bad stuff if it was brand new and if it didn't do well, it was gone very quickly.
Speaker 1: It was beyond your Saturday morning cartoons for like a few weeks and then you know, maybe what 12 13 weeks, right?
Speaker 1: So it's a few months, right?
Speaker 1: So you had to be watching for that those few months and then the show was gone and it will never be reshown anywhere And it wasn't popular.
Speaker 1: so they didn't make VHS tapes, right and it had to be while you were alive You know, yeah, and the other thing sometimes You would see a hand of our bear characters, right?
Speaker 1: You know the ones that come to mind.
Speaker 1: for me the most in this category are like the huckleberry hound the megillah gorilla And the snagglepuss huckleberry hound.
Speaker 0: that was the first one.
Speaker 0: the huckleberry hound show Yogi Bear and was a spin-off.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but those three characters in particular were characters I was completely familiar with.
Speaker 1: if you showed me those characters as a kid.
Speaker 1: I could tell you what their name was Yep, right and I could tell you that they were head of our rare characters But I had never seen I don't think I still have never seen an episode of huckleberry hound or snaggle.
Speaker 0: in fact The only thing I ever saw huckleberry hound in that wasn't just like a marketing cameo Ever.
Speaker 1: a wacky races was either wacky Yogi Yogi Bear and friends.
Speaker 0: Uh So I hated those tired friends to the point that Yogi's Ark.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it was Yogi's Ark, right?
Speaker 0: I forgot about Yogi's Ark.
Speaker 0: I watched that show.
Speaker 1: I hate lying in the bucket.
Speaker 0: They hated that show, but I watched it for some reason.
Speaker 0: But The good the bad and huckleberry hound is a movie I've never reason.
Speaker 1: we saw this parody of the real movie the good bad.
Speaker 0: It is arguably a parody of the good the bad and the ugly is an animated like film Produced in 1988.
Speaker 0: It is the second worst movie.
Speaker 0: I have ever seen to completion in my life Literally and specifically this movie.
Speaker 1: I didn't know it existed till today's is.
Speaker 0: So as a kid, I first I guess we'd watch it a bunch and I thought I guess I assumed you know Cuz the way adults would react to it and I knew the good the bad and the ugly I just like.
Speaker 0: for some reason I guess I like this movie but watching it slightly older Not only did I realize that it is one of the worst most plotting unfunny things humans have ever made But to now I realize that our parents hated this movie and hated the fact that we liked it and kept wanting to watch it.
Speaker 0: It is so bad.
Speaker 1: So Hannah Barbara though did make good stuff, right?
Speaker 1: So towards the end of the Hannah Barbara days, right?
Speaker 1: They were powering the sort of original Cartoon Network in the late 90s.
Speaker 0: Girls came out of that.
Speaker 1: girls is like technically Hannah Barbara.
Speaker 1: still there were all these cartoon cartoons Right before Cartoon Network studios or sort of in in in league with Cartoon Network studios.
Speaker 1: It was like a partnership and then Cartoon Network studios split off and was its own thing.
Speaker 1: I don't need Hannah Barbara anymore.
Speaker 1: But you know Dexter's lab is a Hannah Barbara, right?
Speaker 1: That's a. that's an incredible a plus all-time show.
Speaker 1: You know those other cartoon cartoons like the Johnny Bravo cow and chicken.
Speaker 1: It's I am weasel.
Speaker 1: It's like well, they weren't that bad?
Speaker 0: Yeah, right.
Speaker 1: Powerpuff Girls also legendary, right?
Speaker 0: So they made an animated adaptation of dumb and dumber.
Speaker 0: I Guess.
Speaker 1: so in 1995 13 episodes, right?
Speaker 1: There was also some other stuff They did.
Speaker 1: that was also sort of good in a way, right?
Speaker 1: So like Hercule it's right.
Speaker 1: It's like okay that has you know It's not the greatest but it's you know, this it's kind of a cool sci-fi thing right with the with the gleep in the gloop.
Speaker 0: Well, there was there was a bill and ten cartoon that I did watch and enjoy.
Speaker 1: Yeah, this thund are the barbarian which I love a lot.
Speaker 1: but you know, obviously it's not that great But it's you know, there's a certain there's a thing about it right that I like You know of the old like top cat is actually if you watch a top cat It's like okay the episodes are very same II but it's actually kind of funny.
Speaker 0: Pick an episode of top cat if you haven't seen one recently.
Speaker 0: It's better than any Yogi Bear episode ever.
Speaker 1: maybe You know space
Speaker 0: goes holds up Okay, but it holds up in the same way that like the honeymooners or any old because
Speaker 1: it's a parody of the honeymooners exactly
Speaker 0: But it holds up about the same level like it's interesting that it is both parody but also entertaining enough on its
Speaker 1: own.
Speaker 1: Well, it's not a it's not a pair Slash it's the same fucking thing.
Speaker 1: It's just hey, let's do the same thing.
Speaker 0: Yeah, honeymooners.
Speaker 0: They didn't ever have an alien show up though.
Speaker 1: I Guess Mork and Mindy would be when the alien showed up.
Speaker 0: Mork and Mindy.
Speaker 0: I'm Carrie.
Speaker 0: I feel like young people don't even know that show existed.
Speaker 1: I Think there.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there was a Mork and Mindy Cartoon that they did which is always.
Speaker 0: I was actually isn't?
Speaker 0: I was talking.
Speaker 0: I was out talking to people online at a different discord a few weeks ago and Someone complained that Like yeah American TV only now realized that like fantasy stuff is really popular like fantasy That's not true at all.
Speaker 0: And it was like yeah, I dream of genie bewitched Mork and Mindy like the old gold shows had really which was also at B, which was also like tremendous.
Speaker 1: I was reading recently somebody.
Speaker 1: I don't know how true this is.
Speaker 1: It sounded true.
Speaker 1: They said they were basically saying yeah bewitched was huge in Japan.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and There they tried to say that it was responsible for a lot of you know The creation of the magical girl stuff which sounds plausible.
Speaker 1: the timings, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah So that's fascinating if true But you know in the quantity it's like yeah the lots and lots of garbage stuff.
Speaker 1: That was Popular for some reason but you know, like the Smurfs was a head of our Barrow show.
Speaker 1: Okay, that was like 256 episodes.
Speaker 1: I only ever saw a few and wasn't that into it?
Speaker 0: I was into Smurfs apparently until and Care Bears - not that that's Hanna-Barbera.
Speaker 1: And then they tried to sort of revive Smurfs with Snorks right which weren't as successful.
Speaker 0: I watched the Snorks.
Speaker 0: I would argue the Snorks was a better show than the Smurfs, but it was not good.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well Snorks ran for quite a while.
Speaker 1: It was like 60 something freaking episode.
Speaker 1: Snorks was one of the ones I could have watched cuz it was on Saturday morning.
Speaker 0: I was always watching it when we were.
Speaker 1: it was like Snorks is on.
Speaker 1: change a channel.
Speaker 0: We would be a grandma's house like Snorks was just beyond and grandma had a giant TV so we'd watch it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I did.
Speaker 1: I would change a channel or do something else when Snorks was on.
Speaker 0: Yeah Moby Dick and Mighty Mitor Is an American Saturday morning cartoon Hanna-Barbera CBS.
Speaker 1: There was a cart.
Speaker 1: They did a cartoon adaptation of I dream of genie just called genie.
Speaker 1: That was 16 episodes.
Speaker 1: I've never even knew that existed till this second.
Speaker 1: You could you could like.
Speaker 1: the sheer quantity is just like off the charts of how much stuff they.
Speaker 0: yeah Just throw it all at the wall And if anything's good put a little more budget into it and milk it forever.
Speaker 1: And I think a lot of it, you know, some of the stuff had some positive like Space Ghost right had a lot of positive aspects mostly because Space Ghost was revived and Reused as a character and other things.
Speaker 1: that was better, but if you watch old Space Ghost, it's not that great.
Speaker 0: It's pretty dire, but it's not.
Speaker 1: it's actually above average for its time Sure, but the their aspects of it in notably the character designs right that were really incredible Even though the stories were not great.
Speaker 1: Well,
Speaker 0: look at what like Space Ghost and contemporary especially like Hanna-Barbera like superhero designs Compared to what superheroes tended to be drawn like in cartoons before that Mmm, there are some imagine
Speaker 1: Interesting
Speaker 0: character designs that you can see a line of thinking that leads to be tasks in the distant future.
Speaker 1: Yeah, what they lacked in writing stories or you know Not always lacked in writing stories, but often lacked in writing stories almost always lacked in animation and production value.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right the character design right and that the concepts were almost, you know.
Speaker 1: So that is you know that why a lot of them I think endure.
Speaker 0: Yeah It's on that strength alone The fact that they generally came from because like there there were the shows that were here is a toy.
Speaker 0: Make a show around this toy.
Speaker 0: the show exists solely to sell the toy But all the most Hanna-Barbera stuff was.
Speaker 0: this is a show.
Speaker 0: we are selling the show and then we're advertising things and milking the intellectual Property.
Speaker 1: yes, then we will make merch from the show the character that we made.
Speaker 1: Like let's make a character and then try to sell the characters merch after.
Speaker 1: well The the other of course, that's half of it.
Speaker 1: The other half was here is an existing intellectual property.
Speaker 0: We need a cheap way to milk that with a.
Speaker 1: we want our animated cartoon version of whatever that is to go on television Or in some cases like go BOTS it was like transformers is a big thing.
Speaker 1: Let's make Right, let's we can we can't we don't have that intellectual property, but we can make go BOTS.
Speaker 1: They can't help us.
Speaker 0: The Gary Coleman show Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: I did not know that existed.
Speaker 1: That's an example of there's an existing popular thing Gary Coleman.
Speaker 1: Let's make an animated version of it.
Speaker 1: Yeah It was very very common.
Speaker 1: So yeah, so this you know Hanna-Barbera right because of wheat the when we were born right we were.
Speaker 1: if you were born any later It really only that if we were born just a little bit later only that like late 90s good Cartoon Network stuff rid of really hit us.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if we were born earlier, it probably would.
Speaker 1: this stuff probably would hit us way more.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I think later Hanna-Barbera would hit us way more.
Speaker 0: The 80s was this specific era like late 70s.
Speaker 0: through the early not like the end of the 80s there was a certain set of Hanna-Barbera stuff that was recycled and almost re-released as new to a generation and Kind of worked like like you said weed.
Speaker 0: That was just.
Speaker 0: that was TV to us.
Speaker 1: Yeah, a lot of people our age and I think that most people who are younger they got like nothing cuz he was done.
Speaker 1: It's like they had.
Speaker 1: they lived in like this golden age of you know, like you.
Speaker 0: just adventure time was But it was also.
Speaker 0: there was a yoga bear like Yogi Bear was out in the 60s And so our parents watched it Us and then suddenly Yogi Bear is on TV again and their kids are watching it.
Speaker 0: That was like that one cycle that was rarely replicated before or after like the timing just happened.
Speaker 1: Yeah before then I mean, you know, there wasn't TV always right.
Speaker 1: TV was relatively new before Hanna-Barbera Right, but you know previous generations.
Speaker 1: Well, they're you know, their kids weren't necessarily into the same stuff.
Speaker 1: You know jazz music rock music, right, you know.
Speaker 1: And then this was like they had the chance to like produce the same thing for the two several generations in a row Or at least reproduce right Scooby Doo pup named Scooby Doo, right?
Speaker 1: But We did not we we only sort of did that right, you know, we had transformers.
Speaker 1: then we had like transformers beasts Whatever, you know Ninja Turtles.
Speaker 1: We have that right Ninja Turtles.
Speaker 1: and there's like a newer Ninja Turtles My little pony my little pony.
Speaker 1: friendship is magic.
Speaker 1: Right that pattern sort of continued of the old generations thing being sold to the newer generation But this was taking the original thing unmodified and just putting it back on TV.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's.
Speaker 1: the difference is that we just had the old 60s Flintstones.
Speaker 1: They didn't make a new Flintstones for us.
Speaker 1: We were just why there was.
Speaker 1: I guess there was that one.
Speaker 1: we're like Pebbles and bam when we're grown up or whatever.
Speaker 0: that oh my god, I forgot that existed.
Speaker 1: It wasn't good But mostly it was.
Speaker 1: they just showed us the old Flintstones directly.
Speaker 1: No one was gonna take old my little pony.
Speaker 1: Just put it on TV in 2015.
Speaker 0: And there's something and I it's.
Speaker 0: I don't think it's that these shows like Hanna-Barbera like had the secret and aged better.
Speaker 0: I think it's just that they made so many things that I had the machine.
Speaker 0: Just a machine but that small subset aged well because they happen to be very good Relative to everything else but like old my little pony not good You know, you couldn't just put some good aspects to it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but you couldn't just put that on TV.
Speaker 0: It would not.
Speaker 0: you sound just would not play it And most Hanna-Barbera stuff you could not just put on TV.
Speaker 0: that this this very narrow lens of Hanna-Barbera Was successful in this regard and nothing else they made was.
Speaker 0: Those other things were successful in their original runs, but they never came back for a reason In terms of you know, I think it really took.
Speaker 1: there's probably something I'm missing but it really feels like you know Disney Afternoon was the the seal breaker right sort of like.
Speaker 1: alright, that's enough of that.
Speaker 0: Yep Couple with me discovering anime when I was in fourth grade.
Speaker 0: really just put it put the brakes on me watching any of this stuff.
Speaker 1: But I'm just saying it, you know up until the Disney Afternoon It was like, okay, we're just churning out whatever for the kids.
Speaker 1: Rerun, you know the Looney Tunes like once.
Speaker 0: once any Disney Afternoon thing appeared like once I saw and I saw like 10 seconds of tailspin and Dale rescue Rangers be the first one.
Speaker 0: Oh my god DuckTales the first.
Speaker 1: it was DuckTales and chip and rescue Rangers refers to when those shows came out.
Speaker 0: I don't think I watched a second of 80 Hanna-Barbera like old stuff again after that point adults Pretty much.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it was like, you know, here.
Speaker 1: Let me show you the real stuff.
Speaker 0: Kids today with your like Adventure Time is the old show at this point Like you couldn't even have like, you know to put on.
Speaker 1: you know, like tailspin.
Speaker 1: It's like.
Speaker 1: what show could you put on before or after it?
Speaker 1: that wouldn't make the contrast to a parent, right?
Speaker 0: And then snagglepuss comes on stage, hey, yeah, it's like.
Speaker 1: what is this?
Speaker 0: You Haven't seen Westworld which you showed at some point.
Speaker 0: I think you'd really like it because it's a cyber saw the old Brenner Westworld a long time ago.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the dude.
Speaker 0: I don't remember much you would enjoy the new Westworld specifically.
Speaker 0: I think I know you won't watch it So it doesn't matter
Speaker 1: plus in it now, but
Speaker 0: there's a scene where a character who is an AI is Sees a picture from like the real world Like the outside like a tourist leaves a picture behind and they're programmed to not be able to recognize modern things.
Speaker 0: And there's the scene.
Speaker 0: she's looking at this picture and she's just like like someone shows that you were like.
Speaker 0: What do you think of this?
Speaker 0: because he's trying to like do a thing and she looks at it.
Speaker 0: She's like, but I don't see anything like.
Speaker 0: I don't see anything at all.
Speaker 0: I don't understand what I'm looking at.
Speaker 0: I feel like that is how a kid today after they saw like the modern DuckTales would react to Any amount of snagglepuss animation?
Speaker 1: yeah, and this isn't like a situation where like It Was just it where it was like bad for its, you know, it's just old and that's why it looks that way, right?
Speaker 1: It's at.
Speaker 1: it's like no tailspin like holds up.
Speaker 1: You can watch that now.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I despite tails held up.
Speaker 0: Okay It's just the new DuckTales made.
Speaker 0: it honestly did a way better job, right?
Speaker 1: Is that the quality?
Speaker 1: the quality level of it was just like, you know below?
Speaker 1: par Unacceptable levels off.
Speaker 0: it had a barbera.
Speaker 0: They knew what they were doing low production value on purpose.
Speaker 1: You know even something like, you know, Rocky and Bullwinkle wasn't Hannah Barbara, but it had a low production value.
Speaker 1: But it also made up, you know, I had writing was way better Right, Rocky and Bullwinkle had writing and and and also the character design.
Speaker 1: so it had two things, right?
Speaker 1: So we could Rocky Bullwinkle holds up on that even though there's no animation really to speak.
Speaker 0: I feel like you could take any long-running old Hannah Barbara show run it into a AI Natural text generator platform and it would just spit out scripts.
Speaker 0: That would be good enough.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean Rocky Bullwinkle is a freakin cereal, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, it was like it was.
Speaker 1: basically when you think about it Rocky Bullwinkle is really just a radio show that just happened to have a happen to have like loosely animated Animatics on top of it, but it was a really.
Speaker 1: but it was a really.
Speaker 1: if you just listen to Rocky and Bullwinkle That's probably like a top tier radio cereal like as good as the shadow.
Speaker 0: Oh, I saw a great Twitter thread recently where someone was listening to a bunch of old radio dramas and they were like no Don't like.
Speaker 0: venerate these old shows.
Speaker 0: Most of them are Hot garbage unlistenable shit.
Speaker 0: Just let them be lost to time.
Speaker 1: That is true.
Speaker 1: Very true.
Speaker 0: But a few survived because they weren't like they were the good ones.
Speaker 0: Exactly the shadow and the rock in the shed We had.
Speaker 0: we had so much of the shadow on LPS that we would listen to at night.
Speaker 1: You can just download it all now.
Speaker 0: I think who knows what evil lurks in the hearts of men.
Speaker 0: The show knows.
Speaker 1: and Natasha Who's in squirt?
Speaker 0: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at front row crew.com for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 0: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 0: But unlike those other late shows it's actually recorded at night and the patreon patrons for this episode of geek nights are Heidi McNichol Allen Joyce link eg dread lily teddy bear Chris Reimer Clinton Walton Finn Just like a dude guy.
Speaker 0: kashaya.
Speaker 0: 85 program thread open speed undertake law adoption peers absorb Rebecca John review mad bull 34 cowards Ryan Perrin Sam Erickson Shervin von Harl Taylor Braun.
Speaker 0: You hold the key to my heart and a bunch of people who do not want me to say their names.
Speaker 0: I am confident that none of you have ever encountered this before Jerry.