Speaker 0: - It's Thursday, February 25th, 2021, I'm Rem.
Speaker 1: - And I'm Scott.
Speaker 0: - And this is Geek Nights.
Speaker 0: Tonight, we are talking about leftovers.
Speaker 0: If you have any idea for a Thursday show for the love of Satan, tell us.
Speaker 1: - Let's do this.
Speaker 1: - Not only are we low on show ideas for especially Mondays and Thursdays, as usual, we're low on opening bits 'cause we don't go anywhere or do anything.
Speaker 0: - Anything that could happen to me is something that primarily happens on the internet, usually because I've read an article or in social media that Scott has also read.
Speaker 1: - And that would be news or thing of day, it wouldn't be opening bit.
Speaker 0: - Exactly, opening would be like, so I was riding my bike, but that's not gonna happen.
Speaker 1: - It has to be something that, I don't know.
Speaker 1: So I guess the only thing I got for an opening bit is that it's becoming, when we first got locked in the house, right?
Speaker 1: You know, I guess I worked in the house all summer, right?
Speaker 1: But for some reason, I didn't have a problem with this particular thing, right?
Speaker 1: But now, as the winter is ending, the Earth moves, right?
Speaker 0: - Oh, are you having sunlight coming in on your monitor?
Speaker 1: - Yeah, so the sunlight's come in and hitting me in the face at like, you know, earlier in the day.
Speaker 1: And it's hard to work, but I can't-- - Close your blinds.
Speaker 1: - They are closed.
Speaker 0: - Then they're not blinds.
Speaker 1: - Well, they're not, you know, they're not, you know, the ones that we haven't-- - You need curtains and blinds.
Speaker 0: There's multiple layers you need in there.
Speaker 1: - But we never had those in this room, in the office room.
Speaker 1: We have them in the bedroom, right?
Speaker 0: We don't have them in this room, and I can't like-- - We got some ones that are, they diffuse the light enough to where no amount of it can generate glare if they're down, but it doesn't block all the light.
Speaker 1: - Your window faces like a building.
Speaker 1: There's no light coming in.
Speaker 0: - No, there is actually, there is a narrow channel, and just as every spring, like around this time of year, that channel where there's an unblocked view all the way past Queensborough Plaza Station, a beam of light would come in, and previously it would hit my monitor directly.
Speaker 0: But the way things were shifted around, it kind of goes between our two monitors now, but it is gone if I just close that little blind.
Speaker 1: The point is, is I can't get someone to come install a blind or a curtain.
Speaker 1: If I could do that, then I could go to the office.
Speaker 0: It's like, there's no-- - Install it yourself.
Speaker 0: It's real easy.
Speaker 1: - It's not that easy.
Speaker 0: - It's real easy, but I've installed many of them.
Speaker 0: I almost said, "I'll come and help you,".
Speaker 0: but no, that's the whole point, and I can't.
Speaker 0: That's the problem.
Speaker 1: - In my previous apartment, I installed it on my own, and it was not the greatest.
Speaker 1: It was a little, you know, a little dodgy.
Speaker 0: I don't know, maybe I'm better at that, or maybe you have a weird window?
Speaker 1: - I think the problem is, is that a lot of these, you know, in these apartments, right, the space on top of the windows is just like a concrete thing.
Speaker 0: - Ah, I only mount things to the sides on either side of the window, and in this apartment-- - Oh yeah, I used to have a, I had a tension rod.
Speaker 1: I guess I could do the tension rod again, which, no-- - No, not a tension rod.
Speaker 0: I put mounting brackets on both edges of the window on the sides, and then I mounted the thing on those brackets.
Speaker 1: - There's already a rolly thing with brackets in that spot.
Speaker 1: This is like-- - So put something in front of the rolly thing.
Speaker 0: - Or take the rolly thing down.
Speaker 0: I just tore those rolly things down.
Speaker 0: I tore the shitty things out, and I buried them in the back of a closet, and if we ever move out of this apartment, I'm gonna put 'em back and take my nice curtains with me.
Speaker 1: - Well, that's, you know, that's the story, is that it's hard to work late in the day with the sun.
Speaker 0: - It is, it's funny, though, because I have a similar problem of, I've been, I was planning, like literally, right after PAX East, I was going to hire one of those services to have someone come and mount a TV on the wall so I could, like, make more floor space--.
Speaker 1: - I know a guy, you gotta get my guy.
Speaker 0: - And I was also gonna have them mount that monitor we have in the kitchen on the wall there, so it doesn't have to, like, sit.
Speaker 1: - My guy, my guy Abe, he'll hook you up.
Speaker 0: - That's exactly what I was gonna do.
Speaker 0: Like, I had this plan, these three screens I wanna mount, because I could do that by myself, but fuck if I want to do that by myself.
Speaker 0: And also, unlike a curtain, the consequences of me doing it poorly are far more severe.
Speaker 0: - Yeah, you know, and my guy Abe-- - I don't wanna wake up one night to, what was that sound, to discover that my TV is broken?
Speaker 1: - I mean, in my previous apartment, he hung the bike on the wall, and it never fell on me while I was sleeping, right?
Speaker 1: And he's hung two TVs on the wall that have not fallen down on any people.
Speaker 0: - Yeah, basically, I wanna mount--.
Speaker 1: - And he hung these two long shelves on the wall in this office here, and they're not moving.
Speaker 0: - I was gonna mount ski racks way up by the ceiling.
Speaker 0: I was like, I got like 10 things, well, I got like seven things I wanna mount.
Speaker 0: And literally, I have this to-do box in my Google key that lists, like, mount the things, and it lists these seven things.
Speaker 0: And the date when I was gonna do this is the weekend after PAX East.
Speaker 0: So here I am with the old TV still sitting there on the thing.
Speaker 0: And also breaking, that TV's starting to die.
Speaker 0: It's getting dimmer and dimmer and dimmer, and whatever LED drives the optical audio out just doesn't light up anymore.
Speaker 1: - Okay.
Speaker 0: - Yep.
Speaker 0: So I guess we can get right into news and such.
Speaker 0: It's Thursday, it's the lounge, we can talk about anything.
Speaker 1: - Sure, your lounge.
Speaker 0: - I have got--.
Speaker 1: - Let's talk about lounge, let's do a Thursday show on lounges.
Speaker 1: Can you talk about the whole episode about lounges?
Speaker 0: - I can talk a lot about lounges.
Speaker 0: In fact, I have very, I have a lot of opinions on what I like about lounges compared to bars.
Speaker 1: like, a lounge in your house, or a lounge as a place to go?
Speaker 0: - I'm talking about, like, a lounge that you would go to and have drinks in.
Speaker 1: - There's a lot of things that count as lounges.
Speaker 0: - I like loungewear, like leisure clothes.
Speaker 0: I like lounges.
Speaker 0: - A lounge chair.
Speaker 0: - Chase lounges in particular.
Speaker 1: - Lounging.
Speaker 0: - I like lounging.
Speaker 0: What I like the most, I think, an adjacent topic.
Speaker 0: there is sunken conversation pits.
Speaker 1: - What's the etymology of the word lounge, anyway?
Speaker 1: - Lounge, probably.
Speaker 1: - Could be French, French?
Speaker 0: - It's probably Latinic, if I had to guess.
Speaker 0: Oh, look it up right now.
Speaker 0: Lounge, etymology.
Speaker 1: - I'm already good with it.
Speaker 1: Early 16th century.
Speaker 0: - It's gotta be Latinic.
Speaker 0: - Something.
Speaker 0: - To move indolently.
Speaker 0: (laughs) - (laughs) - I'll tell you, if there's a--.
Speaker 1: - Latin, long, longus, long.
Speaker 0: - Lungus, a slow, lazy person.
Speaker 1: - Old French, elongie, lengthen.
Speaker 1: So there is some French Latin there.
Speaker 0: - Yep, lungus, a slow, lazy person, which came from an earlier term, longus, an idle, stupid dreamer.
Speaker 1: - Okay.
Speaker 0: - So, you know, if I'm gonna do something, there's two ways I like to do it, energetically or indolently.
Speaker 0: (laughs) I guess grudgingly is the third way.
Speaker 0: Sometimes I do things grudgingly.
Speaker 1: - Anyway, all right, so here's the news.
Speaker 1: There's a lot going on with this news, even though it's a K-pop news, it actually, none of the discussion around this news has to do with actual K-pop, really.
Speaker 0: - All right, I-- - And a lot-- - I skip this and don't understand it, so.
Speaker 1: - And a lot of what it is is, you know, some of the things are, I can't confirm, 'cause obviously, A, I don't speak Korean, B, I've never been to Korea, and C, I gotta take some hearsay from people who claim to on the internet, right?
Speaker 1: But here's the deal.
Speaker 1: Going back in K-pop time, right, well, first of all, just some foundational work, right?
Speaker 1: If you are a celebrity in the United States, you can commit relatively heinous crimes and maintain a career, right?
Speaker 1: You can be a rapist, you can be a cult leader.
Speaker 0: - You can literally commit murder and lose a civil case.
Speaker 1: - You can murder people, right.
Speaker 1: And it's like, you can, you know, you could like, you know, the first one that always comes to mind for me are people like Mike Tyson, right, you know?
Speaker 1: And you can rehabilitate your career and get extra chances that you may or may not deserve.
Speaker 0: - There's a reason why in American lexicon of celebrity, there's the concept of like the apology to her, like that's a thing.
Speaker 1: - And my opinion on that is basically like, yes, people should have second chances, but not until everyone gets a first chance, right?
Speaker 0: - Reconciliation comes after consequences.
Speaker 1: - You give somebody else a second chance, you just denied someone a first chance, right?
Speaker 1: 'Cause there's a limited number of chances.
Speaker 1: So give everyone a first chance, then we can talk about second chances.
Speaker 1: Anyway, in South Korea, the culture is much, much less lenient in these regards.
Speaker 1: If you commit or like not even necessarily convicted of a crime in like jail, but like if you just like got in trouble doing something, you know, slightly bad, your career is basically over.
Speaker 1: You have to, at minimum, like, you know, extremely apologize and like go into hiding and disappear from the public spotlight for an extended period of time until you believe it is safe to return, right?
Speaker 1: And sometimes this is warranted, right?
Speaker 1: 'Cause people do still commit heinous crimes and then their careers are over, right?
Speaker 1: And that's kind of good.
Speaker 1: But on the other hand, people do things that basically shouldn't even be crimes.
Speaker 1: So recently a member of the boy group B2B, right?
Speaker 1: Got caught with weed.
Speaker 1: and in South Korea, you think weed is criminalized here, right?
Speaker 0: It's way more criminalized there, right?
Speaker 1: Actually got caught doing weed, basically career over permanently, right?
Speaker 1: It's like, you know, meanwhile, if he had just lived in the US, he could weed it up, no problem.
Speaker 0: In fact, if anyone's state he's in, he could do it live on TV and no one could say anything.
Speaker 1: Right, so that's, you know, there's a whole, we could go down that road, but regardless, this opens two doors, right?
Speaker 1: You know, door A, if a celebrity does something, right?
Speaker 1: Then, you know, somebody could, you know, report it and ruin their career and they may or may not deserve that.
Speaker 1: But also people can falsely, right?
Speaker 1: Accuse celebrities of wrongdoing.
Speaker 1: If, you know, perhaps they're just trolls and they hate that celebrity for whatever reason, you know, some teenager and there's like a band they don't like, they can, you know, accuse them.
Speaker 1: And, you know, if they, it might be hard to disprove and you could seriously disrupt somebody's career just by making some accusations.
Speaker 1: Also, they don't have freedom of speech there.
Speaker 1: Like you wanna talk about censorship, like their TV is literally censored, right?
Speaker 1: The government says, no, you can't show that on TV.
Speaker 1: And also, you can't just comment whatever you want on the internet there, right?
Speaker 1: If you comment and you say like false rumors, you spread false rumors on the internet there, you can like get sued and, you know, whoever you spread false rumors about can take you to court and you could be in actual real trouble for doing that, which is good and also bad.
Speaker 1: But that's not even the topic we're going to yet.
Speaker 0: - Yeah, it looks like it's actually a little bit better than like the defamation rules in the UK from skimming this because it does separate defamation upon false claims from true claims, which is complicated and weird and I don't know enough about Korean law and I'm trying to like learn more about this now.
Speaker 1: - There was actually a YouTube video about that particular subject with some lawyers answering questions that I could maybe find the link to again, maybe.
Speaker 1: But this is the topic, right?
Speaker 1: So recently, you know, over time, there have been accusations of various idols, right?
Speaker 1: 'Cause idols are usually people who are, you know, maybe high school age, maybe just college age, right?
Speaker 1: So they're still pretty close to their school days.
Speaker 1: And there were at least a few idols who when they were in school, were bullies and shitty people, right?
Speaker 1: Who would harass classmates and abuse classmates to various degrees.
Speaker 1: And they just happened to end up being celebrities after school, right?
Speaker 1: And in Korea, you know, bullying is not just like, you know, light teasing, right?
Speaker 1: If someone says bullying, we're talking about like, you know, usually hitting someone, right?
Speaker 1: You know, like really, you know, like demeaning and treating someone like a piece of shit on a regular basis.
Speaker 0: - I mean, like that is how a lot of bullying is here too, but there is a-- - Exactly.
Speaker 0: - But there's definitely, there is a, in Korea in particular, there has been a, there's a lot of news you can read about this.
Speaker 0: Like don't think I'm trying to claim to be an expert on Korea.
Speaker 0: Bullying, especially in the equivalent of high school, is a specific societal problem that's trying to be addressed there.
Speaker 1: - Yeah, it's a big problem.
Speaker 1: And there, you know, it's like, I've seen some people who have said that the, who, I haven't seen any data for this and I don't believe it, that, you know, they used to have corporal punishment in schools, right?
Speaker 1: You used to just beat the kids in Korea a lot more recently than you were able to beat the kids in the US.
Speaker 1: I guess maybe, or maybe not, right?
Speaker 1: - Yep.
Speaker 0: - It wasn't that long ago that you-- - Fun fact, I was beaten in school 'cause I went to a Catholic school.
Speaker 1: - Right, sure.
Speaker 1: But there are people who are saying like, yeah, since that went away, kids were, now can bully and the teachers can't do anything about it.
Speaker 1: And I'm like, yeah, I'm pretty sure the kids are probably, I'm pretty sure the kids are bullying before then also.
Speaker 0: - Yep, and also like in America at least, the teachers could do something, they just don't.
Speaker 0: And we've talked about that on Geek Nights before.
Speaker 1: - Right, so that's yet another topic, right?
Speaker 1: But what's happening now is there were a few cases where people, you know, had the victims, right, they had the courage to call out the idols who bullied them accurately and they ruined people's careers, right?
Speaker 1: Perhaps deservingly so.
Speaker 1: But now what has happened is there are floodgates.
Speaker 1: Like there is, they had to make a mega thread because so many idols have been accused of bullying with varying degrees of, you know, truth or supporting evidence and whatnot, right?
Speaker 1: Basically it's like, well, whose career is over now, right?
Speaker 1: Is it real, is it not?
Speaker 1: Is this a troll, right?
Speaker 1: Normally under normal circumstances, you just believe the victims, right?
Speaker 1: That's the default, right?
Speaker 1: Believe the victims.
Speaker 1: But when you, this is like a special area where it's like, yeah, I wanna believe all the victims, of course.
Speaker 1: But there is such a large culture of anti-fandom, right?
Speaker 1: Where, you know, and there are so many people who have also been shown to be crying wolf, right?
Speaker 1: Like there is.
Speaker 1: some people were like, they accused someone of bullying and a whole bunch of people come out and they're like, actually I was in school with that person, you're full of shit, right?
Speaker 1: And so now you can't know, it's harder to believe the victim no matter how much you want to, right?
Speaker 1: It's like, even if you keep telling yourself to believe the victim and like, you know, all the wolf crying infects your brain.
Speaker 0: - Yeah, the intersection of celebrity and modern connected fan culture makes this a like perfect storm of difficult situation.
Speaker 1: - So now it's like, there's just this flood of constant accusations against various peoples.
Speaker 1: And it's like, well, is this person bad or not?
Speaker 1: I saw one the other day and based on internet, you know, text I read on the internet, which is nothing, right?
Speaker 1: It seemed like it was false.
Speaker 1: And there was another one I read today.
Speaker 1: that seems way bad, like it's true, right?
Speaker 1: You know, based on the text I read on the internet, which is, right, who knows, right?
Speaker 1: I never met these people.
Speaker 1: I don't speak their language, right?
Speaker 1: So now the other interesting thing, and I don't know how true this is, but regardless of whether this is true, part of it is true and it's very interesting.
Speaker 1: So in Korea, they have Naver, which is basically Korean Google, right?
Speaker 1: You know, Webtoon, that thing we talk about frequently, Naver runs that, Naver runs a lot of stuff.
Speaker 1: But if you're doing a web search in Korea, you're using Naver, you're not using google.com, right?
Speaker 1: And on the Naver homepage, they have, it's not like the Google homepage where it's just a search box.
Speaker 1: They list like, here are the top 10 things people are searching for right now, real time search rankings.
Speaker 1: And that's kind of a big deal.
Speaker 1: Like people, you'll see celebrities be like, woo, I released my song and I was number five in the real time search rankings, right?
Speaker 1: It's like people are paying attention to that thing more than we pay attention to like Twitter trending topic.
Speaker 0: - Yup, I mean Twitter trending topic is ignored unless, the only time I've ever clicked on one is when I can't fathom what is trending around that word.
Speaker 1: - So a true thing is that they're actually going to be removing, I don't know the exact details 'cause I can't read the homepage, but one of those trending sections is like gonna get removed from the Naver homepage.
Speaker 1: Like they announced this.
Speaker 1: So someone suggested that it could be possible, right?
Speaker 1: That the flood of accusations are coming because once that thing is gone, you won't be able to get the attention on your accusation anymore.
Speaker 1: And people are rushing to make the accusations while that thing is still there.
Speaker 1: So I don't know if that part is true, but the part about the trending thing being a big deal there and it being removed soon is true.
Speaker 1: But that's just really fascinating, right?
Speaker 1: Like imagine if Twitter was like, we're gonna remove Twitter trends next week, what would people do this week in terms of manipulating Twitter trending topics while it was still a thing?
Speaker 1: - I think the differences-- - How would people's behavior change next week after it was gone?
Speaker 0: - I think the difference is generally.
Speaker 0: American fan cultures have never been like organized around trying to make things trend.
Speaker 0: It's mostly been like bots driving that sort of thing, usually for political purposes or like or K-pop stuff often gets forced that way often from the fans, but I bet nothing would change and nothing would be different because Twitter trends are not the cultural touchstone here that a lot of people seem to think they are.
Speaker 1: - What if the Google homepage showed you the top 10 things people are searching for right now in real time?
Speaker 0: - Yup, I wonder what that would look like.
Speaker 1: - Yeah, I know, there is that other page they have, the Google whatever, Google trends or whatever.
Speaker 1: that shows you stuff, but no one goes there, right?
Speaker 1: Would that change people's behavior?
Speaker 0: - This is why this is such a, like there's so many topics here in this news because like that microtopic of like fan culture and like organized fan activism for the intellectual property that they happen to enjoy and how weirdly organized and rabid they're getting about it as time goes on.
Speaker 0: Like there's a whole week of Geek Nights episodes about just that.
Speaker 1: - Right, I can just say, all I can say is that A, it's one of those cases, much like GameStop where someone has found a way to push the buttons on their keyboard, right?
Speaker 1: Do nothing, don't have to leave your chair, you can just push buttons on your keyboard and cause real consequences for real people in the real world.
Speaker 0: - I mean, we had that news the other week where someone added a bunch of poison to the water supply by just touching buttons on a keyboard.
Speaker 1: - Sure, but that was a more difficult button pushing.
Speaker 0: - Well, apparently it wasn't, but anyway.
Speaker 1: - Well, for someone who has to have some amount of technological prowess, right?
Speaker 1: This is literally like you can tweet and cause problems in the world, right?
Speaker 1: You can sign up for an E-Trade account and push a button and cause GameStop stock to, you know, cause Wall Street to panic, right?
Speaker 0: - Well, it gets down to a fundamental thing.
Speaker 1: - That power of being able to put just, without that much technological knowledge, just being able to touch your phone in a pattern, right?
Speaker 1: Just rub the face of your phone and the world changes is so alluring that whenever it's possible, whenever someone finds a way to do that, people will do that.
Speaker 0: - Well, we talked about this, in 2016, we did a panel at a PAX called The Grind.
Speaker 0: We're talking about grinding in games, but we talked a lot about the problems that arise in any system, doesn't have to be a game, when the incremental cost of taking an action that has some sort of meaningful effect approaches zero.
Speaker 0: Couple that with the way social media lets people organize those basically costless transactions, the costless actions they can take.
Speaker 0: It's very, instead of an old day where you would have to hit that button a million times, you can hit a button once and 999,000 other people will each then hit that button once and have the same effect.
Speaker 1: - Yep, well, it is a cyberpunk tale, the likes of which geek nights cannot ignore.
Speaker 1: And that is the news.
Speaker 0: - I'm sure we'll be talking about topics and fallout from this for some time to come.
Speaker 0: So if there was ever a news that was a like, where if we brought up the topic or like this came up in conversation, a random listener or Scott or anyone who knows me would say, wow, that's a really rim thing to be talking about right now.
Speaker 0: This news will be up there.
Speaker 0: This would be up there with things like, we're talking about how nuclear weapons are made or how to set clocks.
Speaker 1: (laughing) - How to make annoying noises.
Speaker 1: - Wah.
Speaker 1: - If the clock on the trumpet was set improperly.
Speaker 0: - So this, if you're not familiar, Scott, with the mystery and I'm making quote fingers here of Dyatlov Pass, like have you ever heard of that thing?
Speaker 1: - No.
Speaker 0: - Really?
Speaker 1: - Maybe I don't.
Speaker 1: Maybe I do know it and I just don't know the name of it.
Speaker 0: - You might.
Speaker 0: So this is the kind of thing that people tell ghost stories and have conspiracy theories about it, but the thing itself really happened.
Speaker 0: Basically in 1959, and I know a lot about this because it's fucking rim, like it's me, what do you want?
Speaker 0: You'll see why this is up my alley in a minute.
Speaker 0: - Uh-huh.
Speaker 0: - A bunch of kids like went out on a hike into the wilderness in 1959 in some mountains in Russia and they never came home.
Speaker 0: So people were like, oh, like.
Speaker 0: they sent a search party to go find out like what happened to these kids.
Speaker 0: And they eventually found in the Dyatlov Pass, which is an area they were gonna be hiking through, they found their naked, mutilated, radioactive bodies.
Speaker 1: - Okay, I have not heard this story.
Speaker 0: - It was like the biggest news in 1959.
Speaker 0: Like this was a mystery.
Speaker 1: - Well, I wasn't around then, so.
Speaker 0: - But yeah, so in the Soviet Union, like this was a big deal.
Speaker 1: Like it was a mystery.
Speaker 1: - I'd say so.
Speaker 0: - What the fuck happened to these people?
Speaker 1: - That's probably, that's an even bigger news than the kids trapped underwater that happened a little, you know, when was that, 100 years ago?
Speaker 1: - Yeah.
Speaker 1: - It was Thailand, right?
Speaker 0: - Yeah, I recall.
Speaker 0: - That feels like it was from a different time and it feels like it happened right after Dyatlov Pass.
Speaker 0: - So anyway, this was a real mystery that was solved for, like it is solved and has been solved for a long time from a. this is probably what happened standpoint, but there were so many weird attributes of the story that no scientists could say, yes, 100%, this is what explains like weird part of the--.
Speaker 1: - You can't 100% explain anything.
Speaker 0: - Exactly, solipsism, fuck it.
Speaker 0: Drop the mic.
Speaker 0: But conspiracy people and UFO people in the '60s were obsessed with this, so.
Speaker 1: - Of course, why wouldn't you be?
Speaker 0: - And to this day, people are obsessed with this.
Speaker 0: There is an article that came out recently like this year where the part of this that was actually unexplained is pretty definitively explained thanks to Disney's Frozen, the movie.
Speaker 0: Literally, no joke.
Speaker 0: Yeah, this article is fascinating.
Speaker 0: I can break it down pretty quick 'cause I'm a weird nerd.
Speaker 0: So here are the things that were strange about the incident when they found their bodies and I can explain them all with common sense.
Speaker 0: One, the bodies were all naked.
Speaker 0: That makes sense.
Speaker 1: - They were probably fucking in the woods.
Speaker 0: there's a thing called paradoxical undressing.
Speaker 0: Humans will just take off their clothes.
Speaker 1: - Okay.
Speaker 1: - That's interesting.
Speaker 0: You didn't know that?
Speaker 1: - I knew a lot about hypothermia, but I didn't know that about hypothermia.
Speaker 1: - Okay, so if you are ever-- - Thank you voyage of the Mimi.
Speaker 1: - All
Speaker 0: right, my advice to you, Scott, in case this ever comes up, 'cause I think this might've been important that you didn't know this, if you are ever really cold and then with nothing changes, you start to feel too warm and you feel like you should take your clothes off, fucking don't.
Speaker 0: Your body is lying to you because it's broken.
Speaker 0: People who are experiencing hypothermia will literally undress themselves.
Speaker 0: Like it's like, that is a thing.
Speaker 0: So obviously hypothermia, that's why they were naked.
Speaker 0: Two, their eyes were missing.
Speaker 0: Coyotes or something.
Speaker 0: just ate them, like duh.
Speaker 0: That's like animals will go after the eyes first.
Speaker 0: But I can see why that would have been creepy.
Speaker 0: They found these bodies and their eyes were missing and they were naked.
Speaker 1: - Weren't there other animals chewing on other parts?
Speaker 1: - They were like a little bit.
Speaker 1: - When you see bite marks near the eyes or something?
Speaker 0: - There were some bite marks and things too, but like the eyes were missing from literally every body and people were like weirded out by that.
Speaker 0: Also remember, some of these things, only conspiracy nut jobs were weirded out by.
Speaker 0: The Soviet like researchers who like were studying this explained these things pretty straight away.
Speaker 0: Mystery three, all the people had suffered severe blunt traumas, like they had been beaten with baseball bats.
Speaker 0: That was unexplained at the time.
Speaker 1: - Someone beat them.
Speaker 0: - One of the theories was they were murdered 'cause they got close to some Soviet like military thing or UFOs or whatever.
Speaker 0: But that's the part they solved.
Speaker 0: That was the one unsolved part.
Speaker 1: That was actually unsolved.
Speaker 1: - Has "Frozen" solved that part?
Speaker 0: - Science has solved that part with the movie
Speaker 0: "Frozen.".
Speaker 1: - "Frozen" solved that part.
Speaker 0: - Yes.
Speaker 0: So part four, the bodies were found scattered across a wide area.
Speaker 0: Like a few of them were found way down in the woods.
Speaker 1: A few of them were found- - They were trying to walk for help and they died in different places.
Speaker 0: - Yep, the ones who weren't beaten to death were running to get help, or at least get somewhere like in the trees to then try to make a fire and warm up before they died.
Speaker 0: Some of them were dragging bodies- - Makes common sense.
Speaker 0: - Or trying to rescue the other people who were hurt, et cetera.
Speaker 1: - I'd be surprised if they all died in the same spot.
Speaker 1: Like if you're sitting there with your, I don't know, eight friends and they're all dead, are you just gonna keep sitting there?
Speaker 0: It's like- - Yeah, if you find a campfire with eight skeletons sitting around it, that is suspicious as fuck.
Speaker 1: - Yeah, that's way more suspicious than some bodies around.
Speaker 0: - All right, the bodies were radioactive, which was a sensible, like.
Speaker 0: that seems to be true that the bodies, there was radiation- - It's Soviet Russia, there's uranium just in the woods.
Speaker 0: - Nope.
Speaker 1: So there's a lot of- - They ate too many bananas, all bananas.
Speaker 0: - There's a lot of nut job conspiracy theories about that.
Speaker 0: The answer is pretty simple.
Speaker 0: This is another thing that anyone who camps would already know.
Speaker 0: Camping lights are radioactive.
Speaker 0: Like there's thorium in them.
Speaker 0: That's how they work.
Speaker 1: - Oh, well in 1950 something, yeah.
Speaker 0: - Even today, you can get camping lights, unless you're- - Not if it's a lithium LED thing.
Speaker 0: - No, but if it's powered by kerosene.
Speaker 1: - Sure, but no, you're not using those.
Speaker 1: 1958, in 1958 you are.
Speaker 0: - Yeah, but even in modern times, there are often use cases for a kerosene lantern because they also provide heat.
Speaker 1: - Hmm, maybe.
Speaker 0: - And they're way brighter than LEDs.
Speaker 1: Like for how much- - Depends on the LEDs.
Speaker 0: - For how much fuel and weight you have to carry with you.
Speaker 0: Anyway, the way camp lanterns work is they don't actually, it's not the fire that is providing the light.
Speaker 0: The fire is actually really small.
Speaker 0: There's a metal mantle around it that gets heated up by the fire and then it radiates light.
Speaker 0: They use thorium and other nonsense that happens to glow with more visible light and less infrared light.
Speaker 0: Like that's that.
Speaker 0: That explains the radiation, but the radiation is also the thing that the UFO nut jobs are all obsessed with.
Speaker 0: So this article explains why the bodies looked like someone had taken a baseball bat to them.
Speaker 1: Originally, common sense people assumed- - That's what happens to your flesh when you get frozen?
Speaker 0: - Nope, so common sense people had assumed there must've been an avalanche, they were sleeping in their tents and avalanche happened.
Speaker 0: They were like pushed down the mountain and hurt severely.
Speaker 0: And then they tried to like make a fire, get help, help their friends and slowly- - How long did it take them to find the bodies?
Speaker 0: - Weeks, months.
Speaker 1: - Then you'd still, you'd see evidence of an avalanche, I think.
Speaker 0: - So that's where it gets complicated.
Speaker 1: Possibly not because avalanches are not that well understood, especially- - You'd see that up on the mountain there wasn't enough snow and there was too much snow down by the bottom.
Speaker 0: - Avalanches aren't around, there was snow there and now it's down here.
Speaker 0: They're more around a surface in layering of snow shifts.
Speaker 0: And if you're not an expert and depending on the terrain, like that is not as straightforward as you would think.
Speaker 0: But also all the data we had as of like last year showed that avalanches don't cause that severity of blunt trauma.
Speaker 1: Like they don't beat you up- - You just get buried in snow and suffocate and freeze.
Speaker 0: So how come these people looked like they were beaten to death and then some of them froze to death?
Speaker 0: Like one, an avalanche couldn't really cause that.
Speaker 0: And two, the terrain they were on shouldn't be able to have an avalanche.
Speaker 0: At least not to the scale that would have been necessary to cause this disaster.
Speaker 0: Effectively, the snow that was used, the effects in the movie "Frozen" led to developments to do avalanche simulations that were much more precise and accurate than we had done previously.
Speaker 0: And researchers were able to simulate the kinds of conditions in this particular region and determined that in the right conditions, it's rare but not impossible, an avalanche and that type of terrain, which would seem impossible even to experts, could happen suddenly and would cause that kind of blunt trauma specifically.
Speaker 0: - They were killed by a freak, like one in a million avalanche because where they happened to camp was a place that by all knowledge of experts at that time and until recently, should not be able to have an avalanche.
Speaker 0: They miscalculated.
Speaker 0: They just got really unlucky and set up camp in the wrong spot and were murdered by a ridiculous avalanche.
Speaker 1: And this article- - That's a good reason to stay inside in the winter and not go skiing or do anything else stupid in the mountain.
Speaker 1: - So, sorry- - The lesson here is don't ski.
Speaker 0: - Sorry, weird nerds.
Speaker 0: It wasn't a natural uranium reactor that formed in this ravine due to the shape of the mountain nor was it UFOs.
Speaker 1: - Don't ski, don't hike, stay inside.
Speaker 0: - But anyway, things of the day.
Speaker 0: So a few of you, more than one person and fewer than 10 people have been commenting on my beard over the course of this.
Speaker 0: 'cause I generally don't wear a beard and during quarantine, I've been wearing a beard.
Speaker 0: So the annoyance of a beard is that it's actually, assuming you are lucky enough if you want a beard to have the kind of hair that will grow into a nice beard.
Speaker 0: 'cause some people just can't grow a beard even if they want one.
Speaker 0: - That's true.
Speaker 0: - Assuming like you're past that point.
Speaker 0: The other problem with a beard is if you just, most people, if you just let a beard grow naturally, you're gonna look like a deranged mountain man eventually.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: You might look like someone who knows a lot about posix and eunuchs, like.
Speaker 0: - But if you try to trim a beard, it is very easy to fuck it up and then you have to get rid of the whole thing.
Speaker 0: Beards are actually like, they're much like much, the reason why people who style hair have to get certifications and get some training is one, for racism that we'll talk about in another episode someday, but two, because it is a skill, like dealing with hair is, and like styling it is really difficult.
Speaker 0: There's a reason why everyone's hair looks like shit right now.
Speaker 0: 'cause we can't go get haircuts from people who know what they're doing and it's really hard to do that right at home unless either someone you know is an expert or two, you have a really simple hairstyle that you can achieve without having to have much knowledge or skill.
Speaker 0: So I had to learn how to take care of my beard better without just going to a barber to do it.
Speaker 0: for me and of all the videos and things I found, this one's the best.
Speaker 0: This is like, this is a 10 minute video that will explain in like very specific detail exactly how to shape a beard if you want to have a beard, kind of like the one that I'm sporting right now.
Speaker 0: And I learned a bunch of tricks and it made it way easier to manage my beard during quarantine.
Speaker 1: - My major beard problem was not a problem with the beard itself, it was face skin problems.
Speaker 0: - Oh, this talks about that too, about like beard oil, all the different ways to keep face skin.
Speaker 1: - I tried that shit, it didn't work.
Speaker 1: It partially worked.
Speaker 1: It's much easier to take care of my face skin, it was much easier to shave the beard and rub shit on my face skin than to do.
Speaker 0: - I'll get stuff in like my chest hair area but I'm very lucky in that I don't have any like face skin problems at all.
Speaker 1: - I don't either, if I keep shaving my face and applying things to my face.
Speaker 0: - But the one takeaway, if you don't watch this video and you are the kind of person who has a beard but the beard just feels like it looks messy and shitty, it's shaping a beard requires kind of constant upkeep.
Speaker 0: but people who have beards that you might think, oh, they look really good, it's because they're literally doing this like every couple of days.
Speaker 0: You can't just have a beard unless you're really lucky, you actually got to do stuff to it.
Speaker 1: - I think the other thing is that, regardless of your shaping, is like you have to start the beard, you do just sort of have to like, let it go until it reaches point X and then you do the shape of the beard.
Speaker 0: - This video actually talks about that, let it go until it hits that point.
Speaker 0: 'cause if you try to shape it before then, it's gonna look terrible.
Speaker 1: - Exactly, you just gotta let it go until you have the beard.
Speaker 1: then you can start doing it and then you have to keep doing it.
Speaker 0: - But the main reason I make this my thing of the day is that everything they tell you in this video, you can do at home if you have any sort of clipper and any way to shave yourself, like you don't need specialized equipment or like anything super fancy.
Speaker 1: - You need something sharp.
Speaker 0: - Yeah, and it's aimed at you doing it to yourself in front of a mirror, it doesn't require another person to help you.
Speaker 1: - That is something that's different about a beard versus hair, right?
Speaker 1: It's all in the front.
Speaker 1: Hair, you gotta do the back.
Speaker 0: - It even solved the problem and it was an obvious solution for me that I always have of.
Speaker 0: I try to make the two lines like the same size on both sides of my face and then I make one of them too short, I try to make the other one match, I made it too short and then the whole beard's gone.
Speaker 0: I have avoided that for months thanks to this video.
Speaker 1: - Oh, good, all right.
Speaker 1: So I got a thing of the day here.
Speaker 1: All around the world people are playing sports that they shouldn't, but I guess there's nothing I could do to stop them really, so I'll whatever.
Speaker 1: One of the sports, a sport I don't pay attention to often but I have some amount of respect for is rugby.
Speaker 1: And there is a team of rugby players that I didn't know existed called the Kaiviti Silk Tails from Fiji.
Speaker 1: They're the Fiji professional rugby team and under normal circumstances they would play and I guess it's the NSWRL, I guess that stands for New South Wales Rugby League I imagine.
Speaker 0: - I'm pretty confident you are correct.
Speaker 1: - And the coach of the Kaiviti Silk Tails is a person named Wes Nyguama, I think I'm pronouncing the name correctly because I heard an announcer at a rugby game say it on YouTube.
Speaker 1: And he is a famous former rugby player.
Speaker 0: - That's always dangerous though because I literally had a teacher in high school when we were learning about Goethe who pronounced it-- - Goeth.
Speaker 0: - Goeth and I had another teacher at RIT, a professor who also pronounced it Goeth.
Speaker 1: - Yep, but I know for a fact though that like for example, if you're a hockey announcer you gotta pronounce a lot of names, French Canadian names, European names and I know for a fact that the hockey announcers go and they talk to the players or have someone else do it and they get the correct pronunciations and practice them at least if they're any good at the job.
Speaker 1: So I trust a sports announcer pronunciation more than a teacher pronunciation.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so this team wanted to play in the season.
Speaker 1: that was happening in Australia, right?
Speaker 1: But you know, they're in Fiji.
Speaker 1: So what the fuck they gonna do with this pandemic going on?
Speaker 1: They got a situation.
Speaker 1: The pandemic I guess is less bad down there but it's not non-existent.
Speaker 1: They still got a quarantine and such.
Speaker 1: So the plan was this.
Speaker 1: They would go to Sydney.
Speaker 1: I assume they had like a flight or a boat or something just to themselves as guy, right?
Speaker 1: They went to Sydney and they went to this hotel and they stayed in that hotel, right?
Speaker 1: Pretty much with no one else for 14 days and they survived a quarantine for 14 days to prove that they didn't bring any COVID from Fiji.
Speaker 1: and then they can go about engaging in their rugby play according to whatever protocols that league has set up, right?
Speaker 1: That seems all perfectly normal, right?
Speaker 1: And for 2021.
Speaker 1: So what the hell about this is a thing of the day.
Speaker 1: Here's what it is.
Speaker 1: Before, after they finished their quarantine, right?
Speaker 1: The team, the hotel architecture just happens to be really conducive to this.
Speaker 0: - Oh wow, yeah, you're right.
Speaker 0: Look at that.
Speaker 1: - The team came out and to thank the hotel staff for taking care of them in their 14 days of isolated quarantine in the Sydney hotel where presumably no one else was staying other than them and the staff and presumably the staff weren't leaving.
Speaker 1: 'Cause I guess they must've been quarantined in there with them, right?
Speaker 1: Otherwise it makes no sense.
Speaker 1: The staff could have just brought in some COVID, right?
Speaker 1: They sang the staff.
Speaker 1: I'm sure they paid them also, but I hope they did.
Speaker 1: But they sang the staff this congratulatory song or thank you song, I guess.
Speaker 1: And it's like, yeah, let me see your professional sports team sing, right?
Speaker 0: - God, I just imagine like trying to hear the Rangers sing something together.
Speaker 0: - Kratty could play the piano at least.
Speaker 1: - They can barely sing like a holiday song to play on the jumbotron.
Speaker 1: How are they gonna sing a thank you song to the hotel staff?
Speaker 1: But yeah, really good singing here.
Speaker 1: They could form a little choir on the side.
Speaker 1: A little chorus, yeah.
Speaker 0: - Cool biz.
Speaker 0: In the meta moment, can't fucking go anywhere.
Speaker 0: So let's get right into it.
Speaker 0: Leftovers, one, it's a food show.
Speaker 0: Somehow we haven't talked about this.
Speaker 0: We got another food show.
Speaker 1: - Yeah, leftovers could refer to a lot of other things that are leftover, but we're talking about food leftovers.
Speaker 0: - Yeah, food leftovers.
Speaker 1: - The common use of the word is when you had some food and then you didn't eat all of it, there's some leftover food and you eat it later or you don't eat it later.
Speaker 0: - Yeah, that latter one's important.
Speaker 0: But there are two distinct classes of leftovers.
Speaker 0: Leftovers you get from a restaurant, like a doggy bag and food you made.
Speaker 1: - Yup, and you made too much.
Speaker 0: - But what's interesting about this topic, I think the reason why it actually kind of makes sense to talk about it now is that if I look at my life, my entire childhood, leftovers were really important because as a family, my parents were busy and cooking food was a pain in the ass and we didn't always have time.
Speaker 0: Leftovers were a great way to plan meals in such a way that they didn't have to cook as much for a family.
Speaker 0: And then-- - Yeah, my mom would cook.
Speaker 1: She would cook one night and then two days later, we would eat the food from two days previous.
Speaker 1: You know, so she doesn't have to cook again.
Speaker 1: It's like, yeah, why should, you know, if you cook, even if a smaller portion or a larger portion doesn't significantly increase or decrease the cooking effort, depending on what you're cooking, obviously, but you know, it's like, you know, if I'm making cookies, for example, right, putting more flour into the mixer doesn't take longer.
Speaker 1: I can make more cookies in the same amount of time as long as I don't have to do a second mix, right?
Speaker 0: So then, leftovers became extremely important to me personally when I was at RIT because I was poor as shit and couldn't even afford food.
Speaker 0: So making a meal that was big enough to eat like three more times was really important to my survival.
Speaker 0: Like I would plan my meals, or like I'd cook that giant beef bolognese like spaghetti thing and you and I would eat it for like three or four days sometimes, get a little dodgy toward that fourth day.
Speaker 1: - Regardless, yeah, that's how it goes.
Speaker 0: - And that continued into like our lives in Beacon when we had to commute 'cause we didn't have time, like our whole life was structured around, let's cook few meals that can then be re-eaten on later days so we don't have to cook every single day.
Speaker 0: 'Cause we had to take a train home for an hour and then record gig nights.
Speaker 0: 'cause back then we did gig nights four nights a week.
Speaker 1: - Yeah, you get that crock pot going, right?
Speaker 1: And that's gonna feed you for like a few days, right?
Speaker 1: And the thing is, there's a question of like, when is it, it's sort of an arbitrary distinction of like, when is it leftovers and when is it just meal prep, right?
Speaker 1: 'Cause that's what a lot of people, I know a lot of people is like, I've even heard of like families doing this where like they'll do meal prep, like they'll spend, it was a guy I worked with years ago, at least 10 years ago and his family, whole family would like, parents, siblings, on Sunday, they would do meal prep and cook a shit ton of food and like fill their fridge with cooked meals.
Speaker 1: And I don't even know if they would eat one of those meals on Sunday.
Speaker 1: It would just be, and then the rest of the week, they wouldn't cook anything.
Speaker 1: They would just be eating those, you know, for lunch, dinner, whatever.
Speaker 0: - My line, I have two lines there, I think.
Speaker 0: Like when it, by default, everything is food prep.
Speaker 0: It is leftovers if you ate some of it and then you put the rest of it away, like after you ate that.
Speaker 0: You get a big casserole out, you're eating a bunch of it, you look at what's left and you package up, put it back in the fridge, leftovers.
Speaker 1: - Right, well, the ultimate leftover is when you have a family feast of some kind, a Thanksgiving, a Seder coming up, right?
Speaker 1: Some kind of holiday feast, right?
Speaker 1: And you make stuff during those feasts, like a whole damn turkey or a whole big blob of potato.
Speaker 0: - Cal and a stuffing.
Speaker 1: - Yeah, you make like a pile of food, right?
Speaker 1: And then people just sort of serve themselves from that buffet family style and there's gotta be leftover, it's unavoidable, unless you invite way too many families.
Speaker 1: and then, right?
Speaker 1: And that's the ultimate leftover.
Speaker 1: 'cause that is the tastiest food.
Speaker 0: - Well, 'cause also it's usually the special food that you don't make that often in your normal life.
Speaker 1: - Oh yeah.
Speaker 0: - Like I like stuffing, I don't make stuffing like that often.
Speaker 1: - It's also conducive to reheating.
Speaker 0: - Exactly.
Speaker 0: - But where something also becomes leftover is, even if you did the meal prep, if all you really like ate some of it, but maybe you like cut it in half first and put one half in the fridge and ate one half right away.
Speaker 0: If the only thing you have to do to it is just reheat it, might also just be considered leftovers.
Speaker 0: But if it's like, you've gotta actually do a primary cooking or a primary kitchen thing to it, other than just reheating it, then it might've been more meal prep.
Speaker 1: - Right, 'cause like you might make meatballs and then you might sauce up half the meatballs and then just put some bare meatballs in the fridge.
Speaker 1: And those are still, I think, an ingredient, right?
Speaker 1: And there's still an ingredient because when you finally go to eat them, hopefully they don't go bad, you might, for example, put them on a bread and make a meatball sub, which wouldn't be a leftover, 'cause the first time you use the original meatballs or some other dish.
Speaker 0: - And then, well, basically in terms of my life though, to get back to what I started with, why I think this is an interesting topic.
Speaker 0: right now, as we moved to the city and I didn't have to commute and there's more local grocery stores and I can walk to places and food delivery and everything, I got to the point to where we didn't, leftovers, I liked them, but they weren't that important because we tended to start buying a lot of food to cook fresh and cooking a meal that is enough for both of us.
Speaker 0: We didn't generate as many leftovers and there wasn't as much time pressure in my life where I needed to make sure there were leftovers.
Speaker 1: - Well, I think that comes to-.
Speaker 0: - And now leftovers are an important part of my life again, 'cause I got to eat breakfast, lunch and dinner in this apartment seven days a week.
Speaker 1: - Yeah, there's a few things going on there, right?
Speaker 1: It's like, depending on the number of people you have, if you only got one person, oh, I got hiccups.
Speaker 1: If you only got one person, portion sizes in the US are gonna be too much for a meal, right?
Speaker 0: So it's really hard to go on- remember that RIT where I'd cook, I'd heat up a can of green beans and eat a ham steak.
Speaker 1: - But it's like, even if you go on the internet and you search meals for one, it is really hard to cook a meal for one person, one serving, right?
Speaker 0: - Breakfast is doable, not lunch and dinner as much.
Speaker 1: - Yeah, it's like, you could make one sandwich, but it's like you bought ingredients for that sandwich and those ingredients don't, you can't really buy a number of slices of cheese for one sandwich.
Speaker 0: - If you're making sandwiches for one and you buy some ham, you're having ham sandwiches for a week.
Speaker 1: - You go to the deli, you're like, "I want an eighth of a
Speaker 1: pound.".
Speaker 1: It's like, you get a quarter or a half.
Speaker 0: - When we were at RIT one time in Wegmans, I did actually get an eighth of a pound of sliced ham and an eighth of a pound of cheese because I could not afford to buy more food.
Speaker 0: Those were rough times.
Speaker 1: - Anyway, but yeah, once you get two people, it's like, there's a lot of meals you can cook.
Speaker 1: that are two servings, right?
Speaker 1: If I get a Blue Apron, we're doing the meal boxes, see our previous episode, right?
Speaker 1: All those meals are mostly two serving meals.
Speaker 1: If there's two people who are home and eating, cooking and then eating, there's no leftover, right?
Speaker 1: It's a two serving meal.
Speaker 0: - But it's also very easy to, for two people, double that recipe to four and then have a meal plus that meal again on another day.
Speaker 0: But with one person, doubling a meal to two is not nearly as straightforward and easy.
Speaker 1: - Yeah, when I was one person, I would cook a Blue Apron and I'd eat half and I'd put half in the fridge, right?
Speaker 1: If you got two people there, that doesn't happen, right?
Speaker 1: You just eat them both, leftover doesn't exist.
Speaker 0: - But above that scale, I find the only leftovers that tend to be useful, like when a bunch of people are around, are the one pot or big mush type meals, like a big stew, a big casserole, a big pizza, that kind of thing.
Speaker 1: - Oh yeah, pizza slice leftover.
Speaker 0: - Yeah, that's what I had for lunch today because we ordered pizza last night.
Speaker 1: - Ooh, exciting.
Speaker 0: - The other kind of leftover, the restaurant one, I don't want to give that short service, we talked about this on "Geek Nights" years ago, but we first went to Australia for our, like that first PAX Australia.
Speaker 1: - Australia coming up two times today.
Speaker 0: - Right?
Speaker 0: We went to this Mexican restaurant.
Speaker 0: Now, we both know better now, never go to a Mexican restaurant in Australia, holy shit.
Speaker 1: - We went there because that was the only place that was open at that time of night, pretty much.
Speaker 0: - We went to this Mexican restaurant late at night on like Phillip Island, and we ordered what we thought was a reasonable amount of food, and it was like, it was an inordinate amount of food.
Speaker 0: - Yup, way too much food.
Speaker 0: - They brought us like a comical amount of food.
Speaker 0: And then we were like, whatever, like we just had, the whole time we were like, well, we'll just wrap this up, take it back to the hotel and like heat up in the microwave and like, cool.
Speaker 0: And then at the end of the day, like at the end of the meal, we asked for the check and we're ready to leave, and we asked if we could have a doggy bag, and the waitress is like, no, it's illegal.
Speaker 1: - And I didn't think she said it was illegal, she just said no.
Speaker 0: - Yeah, well, she said no, and she's like, she said we're not allowed to, 'cause that restaurant had a policy.
Speaker 1: - Yeah, I don't remember anything about being illegal, but she definitely said no, and definitely did not let us take the food.
Speaker 0: - Yup, and we were like, okay, you're just gonna throw all this away, and she's like, yup, and I was like, okay.
Speaker 0: But I encountered this, 'cause I've been to Australia many more times, I've encountered this, I've had restaurants tell me it was illegal straight up, like all sorts of nonsense.
Speaker 0: The deal is, a lot of countries other than the US have way better food safety rules, though a lot of countries have worse rules.
Speaker 0: Australia actually is a lot more on target about the dangers of takeaway food from restaurants, because a terrifying number of Americans get food poisoning from leftovers, like it's a big problem.
Speaker 1: - Really?
Speaker 1: - Yeah.
Speaker 1: - I did not know, this is news to me, how do you get food poisoning from a leftover?
Speaker 0: - By not chilling it fast enough.
Speaker 0: Most people, it sits out on the table for a long time, but they're not home.
Speaker 0: The difference between being at home and being at a restaurant is that most people, when they eat at a restaurant, have to travel a decent distance to get back home, probably dessert and other things, so the food that they are going to take home with them in the doggy bag has been sitting in the danger zone for a significant amount of time, and when they get it home, they're not weird like me, they don't crash cool it before they put it in the fridge, they might let it sit out for a little while, or they put it in the fridge and it takes a long time for it to get to a safe temperature.
Speaker 0: It's real easy to fuck yourself up with leftovers from restaurants.
Speaker 1: - Okay.
Speaker 0: - So in Australia, it's like culturally expected that you wouldn't take food home from restaurants, and many restaurants will tell you they won't let you, 'cause they don't trust you to not get food poisoning and then try to come after them for it somehow.
Speaker 0: In America, if you try to go after a restaurant, because the leftovers you took home made you sick, you are not gonna win that case.
Speaker 1: - No, but you'd have to get sick from the food while you're in the restaurant, and you'd have to prove it was the food's fault and nothing else.
Speaker 0: - And even then, you probably are not gonna be able to get any recompense from that restaurant.
Speaker 1: - Yeah, if you wanna get recompense, you have to get burned by coffee.
Speaker 1: that's 1,000 degrees.
Speaker 0: - Yup, which again, that case was justified.
Speaker 0: That specific case.
Speaker 1: - Exactly, I'm saying, it would have to be something so egregious and obvious, like coffee that's way too hot.
Speaker 0: - Yup, because even in the year of our lower 2021, I hear people misrepresent what happened with that McDonald's case.
Speaker 1: - It's easy to do.
Speaker 0: - Yup, but honestly, living in the city, just for personal anecdote, living in New York City, leftovers from restaurants are one of my favorite things, 'cause I can get home real quick and I know food safety.
Speaker 0: I am confident that I can safely transport those leftovers home and reheat them later.
Speaker 1: - I mean, I just put them in the fridge immediately as soon as I get home, and I never really thought about the food safety aspect of it, but I guess it hasn't been a problem because most of the time, even pre-pandemic, the leftovers from restaurants would have been delivered to my house anyway, so I'd
Speaker 0: eat them,
Speaker 1: and then they wouldn't even have time to be in the danger zone traveling home.
Speaker 1: They're already home.
Speaker 0: - Yup, 'cause that's another thing that's changed in my life.
Speaker 1: - Just go right in the fridge.
Speaker 0: - I don't know about you, but definitely, as I've lived in New York City, which is no more time pressure in my life, but also, at least not from commuting, but also, as I ate at better restaurants and had a little more money, fancier and better places tend to have smaller portions when you eat out, so leftovers are less of a thing,
Speaker 1: and
Speaker 0: the kinds of places I get leftovers from are the kinds of leftovers that are very easy to safely reheat.
Speaker 0: We're talking about things like dumplings or a pile of Indian food.
Speaker 1: - Yup, well, it's like, they're also, because of the cost of delivery and eating out, I kind of actually want the extra food, so if I order Indian food, I will order samosa, and they give you two samosas.
Speaker 1: I'll order some sort of meal that will be dumped onto rice for eating.
Speaker 0: - Which is already usually at least two people's worth of food.
Speaker 1: - Right, and then maybe some naan and maybe a mango lassi.
Speaker 1: It's the first time I eat, when I eat the food immediately, I eat one of the samosa, right?
Speaker 1: I'll eat some of the stuff on rice, whatever the food I got was, right?
Speaker 1: Some sort of curry or who knows what, and then I'll tear the naan in half and eat half of it 'cause it's enormous, right?
Speaker 1: And then I'll drink the whole mango lassi.
Speaker 1: And then the second time, it's like, well, I don't
Speaker 0: have mango
Speaker 1: lassi anymore, but I have a half a
Speaker 0: naan,
Speaker 1: and if I ate all the rice, I could just make more rice in my rice cooker or heat up the old rice, and then I still have the food in a plastic container that I can dump on the rice, and I got another samosa that I can heat up in the toaster oven or the microwave.
Speaker 1: And it's like, it's perfect.
Speaker 1: It's like, yeah, it costs a lot of money, but I actually divide it by two, very reasonable.
Speaker 0: - Yeah, like same with the pizza.
Speaker 0: Like I'll order a whole pizza, though lately in COVID times, 'cause we don't, like can't eat out that often, there's a very limited type of food I can get delivered easily.
Speaker 0: So whenever there's a food like pizza that scratches an itch that I can't easily scratch by going out like I would in pre-COVID times, sometimes we just get into goblin mode and eat the whole pizza, even if we were planning on having leftovers.
Speaker 1: - Yeah, the number of slices I've been eating has been varying.
Speaker 1: Like sometimes I'll be eating two, and sometimes I'll be eating four, and the pie we usually get has eight.
Speaker 1: - Yep, four.
Speaker 1: - It's a big difference whether I go two or four.
Speaker 0: - I find that as I'm getting older, I'm hitting that point of four slices of pizza, if it's too late, is a recipe for heartburn and indigestion.
Speaker 0: 'Cause I am hearing 40.
Speaker 1: - Sometimes it happens though.
Speaker 0: - Have a little red wine with it, and then yeah, where it's thumbs time.
Speaker 1: But leftovers- - Yeah, I think leftover wise, there are some foods that are like good as leftovers.
Speaker 0: - Oh, we could do like a tearing of leftovers.
Speaker 1: - Yeah, like there's some foods that like they don't reheat well.
Speaker 1: It's like, yeah, okay, you got some leftover, whatever it is, but it's like, what are you gonna do with it, right?
Speaker 1: It's like, eh.
Speaker 0: - Well, that's like the bottom right.
Speaker 1: - Sometimes you have some leftover, yeah, you have some food that's leftover, but it's like, how are you gonna reheat that?
Speaker 1: It's kinda, you know, what are you gonna...
Speaker 0: - Well, that's the transformative nature.
Speaker 0: Like there are foods that you cannot really reheat to be the same thing again, like fried chicken.
Speaker 0: You cannot reheat fried chicken to the same level of like expected quality, but you can use fried chicken to do something in a dish that is not just fried chicken.
Speaker 0: Like I'll scrape the chicken off with a fork and like mix it up into something and cook it like in an omelet or make a sandwich out of it, but I won't try to reheat the fried chicken to then bite into a drumstick.
Speaker 1: - Oh, I mean, I will do that, but I just won't expect it to taste and be as crispy as it was originally, but I will use the toaster oven and it will be much crispier than it would have been using microwave.
Speaker 0: - No, but like the S tier, the foods that are the easiest to reheat where the quality is similar to, or if in some cases identical to the original.
Speaker 0: Pizza, as long as you do it right, pizza reheats so well, just do not...
Speaker 1: - You gotta make a real, real hot oven.
Speaker 0: - Make your oven like however hot, unless you know the temperature, my advice is simple.
Speaker 0: However hot you think you need your oven to be for pizza to reheat it, just make it hotter than that and put it in for a shorter time than you think is necessary.
Speaker 1: - Just watch it and when you see the cheese move, - As soon as the cheese is bubbling a little bit, take it out, it's good to go.
Speaker 0: Like 400 degrees, that's pretty good, but you could go hotter.
Speaker 1: - Yeah, 500, nothing wrong with that.
Speaker 0: - High temperature, short time, that is the way to do pizza.
Speaker 0: The only alternative like way to reheat a pizza, but it's a pain in the ass, is to put it on like a cast iron griddle.
Speaker 0: That actually works pretty well too.
Speaker 1: - That works too, 'cause it's basically a pizza.
Speaker 0: - Microwave turns a leftover pizza into just disgusting poison.
Speaker 1: - Yep, pretty much.
Speaker 0: - Like the cheese turns like kind of translucent, it gets like slimy and chewy.
Speaker 0: And so many people make the mistake of doing the load.
Speaker 0: A lot of people generally with leftovers will try to do low temperature long time, 'cause it feels like--.
Speaker 1: - No, that's the danger zone that we talked about.
Speaker 0: - Yep, not only is it the danger zone, but the bacteria, but too, that feels safe, 'cause like in a sous vide, oh, I can't overcook it.
Speaker 0: You can definitely overcook things at a low temperature for a long time.
Speaker 0: But it's like a pizza in the oven.
Speaker 1: - You can also dry the fuck out.
Speaker 0: - At like 300 for an hour, and see what comes out of your oven.
Speaker 0: You're not gonna wanna eat that thing.
Speaker 1: - It'll be way too dry, way too dry.
Speaker 0: - But like Indian food in particular, but also a lot of like Chinese dishes, like kind of take out delivery Chinese in America at least, the best way to reheat it in my opinion is to put it in a sauce pan with some oil, and again, high temperature, short amount of time.
Speaker 1: - It depends, you know.
Speaker 0: - Unless it's a saucy thing, like a soupy saucy thing, then just reheat it like you would a sauce.
Speaker 1: I never wanna put that stuff in the microwave usually.
Speaker 1: - That is the, you know, you hate a microwave for any use, but actually that is the use of a microwave, is that particular thing.
Speaker 0: - It depends on what's in the dish, 'cause if the dish has a significant amount of inconsistent thicknesses or ingredients, like an Indian dish that is a sauce with large chunks of chicken in it, the chicken will get dried out even as the sauce gets overcooked in a microwave.
Speaker 0: But if it's just like a sog with nothing else in it, the microwave could actually do it pretty well.
Speaker 0: 'cause you don't have these like inconsistent areas.
Speaker 1: - You just gotta do like 30 second mix, 30 second mix if you're really worried about that.
Speaker 0: - But that will not solve the problem of if the chunks of chicken meat are too large, they will dry out.
Speaker 1: - Bust it up.
Speaker 0: - They also will not get hot enough in the center in a microwave.
Speaker 1: - Bust it up in advance.
Speaker 0: - Or, but if you don't wanna bust it up, you could just put the whole thing in a sauce pan and let it steam for a while, it'll taste way better.
Speaker 1: - Microwaves a lot less work and you don't have to clean a sauce pan.
Speaker 0: - Sauce pan goes in the dishwasher.
Speaker 1: - I usually don't put the pans in the dishwasher.
Speaker 0: - Why, they just work?
Speaker 1: - 'Cause there's not enough room in there for all dishes.
Speaker 0: - I got, what, how?
Speaker 1: - Gotta run it two times with them.
Speaker 0: - You don't have to run it two times, what the hell?
Speaker 1: What are you doing?
Speaker 1: - You don't have to run it one, 'cause not all the things would fit in one shot.
Speaker 1: I'd have to run it once and then--.
Speaker 0: - It's one sauce pan.
Speaker 1: Just one, just one in the sauce pan.
Speaker 1: - Yeah, but that means the dishwasher would fill much more frequently if I was putting large things in it.
Speaker 0: - One sauce pan takes the space of like four cups.
Speaker 1: - It's got that big, long handle on it.
Speaker 1: It takes a long handle.
Speaker 0: - I can just put stuff over the handle.
Speaker 0: The handle doesn't actually impede the water at all.
Speaker 1: - No, it doesn't impede the water, but it impedes, I can't like put a plate where the handle is.
Speaker 0: - Yeah, but I can put other cups over where that handle is.
Speaker 1: - I guess my dishwasher, just the sticks on the racks in the dishwasher are not great for putting large things.
Speaker 1: - I might be lucky.
Speaker 0: Our dishwasher, like the sticks are really, when we first moved into this apartment, it was a weird layout.
Speaker 1: - I mean, you can adjust some of the sticks in our dishwasher, which is handy, but you can't adjust them in a small area.
Speaker 1: It's like you adjust it and you've adjusted half the rack.
Speaker 0: - I guess it's a total aside, but I remember when we moved into this apartment, I remember thinking the layout in our dishwasher is weird.
Speaker 0: Like it wasn't like any other dishwasher I'd ever seen or used, like it's just kind of weird, but it seems like it's just better.
Speaker 0: Like it's way easier to cram it full of stuff and everything cleans just fine.
Speaker 1: - I mean, I can cram it full of stuff.
Speaker 1: I usually just don't put big old pans in there, you know?
Speaker 1: I just put every plate we own instead.
Speaker 0: - But some things require specific technique to reheat well.
Speaker 0: Like if you have just like a biryani and you try to put that in a microwave, it's gonna get dried out and weird.
Speaker 1: - Hmm, you can add a little water.
Speaker 0: - Yeah, if you add a little water and put it in a microwave, it will reheat in a very inconsistent way and you'll literally run into like peas that are still cool while there are pieces of rice that are effectively burned.
Speaker 1: - And so you got to do 30 seconds in the stir and do 30 seconds to stir it.
Speaker 1: - Yeah, what I've found, what I do now-- - Or do like three minutes in the microwave, then the whole thing is so hot, nothing's uneven.
Speaker 0: - Nah, I just look online to find professional chefs and their advice for how to reheat different kinds of things and I make a very simple evaluation.
Speaker 0: Is the method they describe too much of a pain in the ass?
Speaker 0: And does the result significantly, is it significantly different from the shitty way I might've done it otherwise?
Speaker 0: And that's how I decide how to reheat different things.
Speaker 1: - The one thing is that in a fancy restaurant, right, they have those little like, it's sort of like the little broiler that like hangs from the top, right?
Speaker 1: And it's just like, you can just slot something in.
Speaker 1: Like I forget what that's called.
Speaker 1: It's like a little, it's basically like a little broiler, but it's just got a little slit opening, basically, like a little hatch that opens in the front.
Speaker 1: It's above, it's not below, like with your oven, right?
Speaker 1: And that is a super good way to reheat stuff or keep stuff hot, especially like, you know, like a piece of meat or something.
Speaker 1: It's like, those things are way good, but you don't have one of those.
Speaker 0: - Yep, convection ovens are really good for reheating stuff too.
Speaker 0: Way better than an oven for many purposes, except pizza.
Speaker 1: - But they could also dry things out, so you can, yeah.
Speaker 0: - But you can get away with shorter time in a convection oven for reasons, depending on the dish.
Speaker 0: Like a samosa in a convection oven will reheat pretty well, actually.
Speaker 1: - Yeah, that's a good use for it, 'cause it's a fried thing to begin with, right?
Speaker 1: it's like a lot of people call the convection oven an air fryer, which I think is, you know, I think that should be illegal to do that.
Speaker 0: - I remember being so mad about that.
Speaker 0: I just always assumed that air fryers would like mist something with hot oil in some way, just use less oil.
Speaker 0: Then when I learned that it's nothing.
Speaker 1: - Yeah, it's nothing.
Speaker 1: But if you have an already fried thing, like a samosa, right, or French fries, and you put them into an air fryer, convection oven.
Speaker 0: - They got you.
Speaker 1: - Right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, they got me.
Speaker 1: If you put it into a convection oven, it's like, well, it's already been fried.
Speaker 1: That's gonna actually be a decent way to reheat it and maintain its crispy nature.
Speaker 0: - Yeah.
Speaker 0: So in terms of the food safety thing, one thing that I never did when I was younger, but I do now, because I learned a lot more about food safety, is that most leftovers, you actually got to reheat that shit all the way to about 160, or you might take in a significant bacterial load.
Speaker 0: - That is something I never, I used to just heat things until they were warm enough.
Speaker 0: And sometimes I'd even eat things cold.
Speaker 0: But now I do, when I read leftovers, I make sure I use a meat thermometer and I actually make sure I got it to a safe temperature long enough to kill whatever might be in it.
Speaker 1: Something else is if you, depending on what you're cooking, you might be able to increase the food quality and safety, perhaps as well, by preparing, knowing it's gonna be a leftover.
Speaker 1: So let's say you wanna make a chicken parm.
Speaker 1: So most of the work of the chicken parm is frying the chicken.
Speaker 0: - Fry a few eggs for chicken.
Speaker 1: - So you pound out and fry, say like four chicken boobs, and you can only gonna eat one chicken boob.
Speaker 1: And you got three extra chicken boobs.
Speaker 1: So you're only gonna eat one right now.
Speaker 1: So put some sauce and melt some cheese on that one right now that you're gonna eat.
Speaker 1: Don't sauce and cheese the other three.
Speaker 0: - Yep, same point.
Speaker 1: - Put those in.
Speaker 0: - You wanna make a salad?
Speaker 0: - Put those shit away.
Speaker 0: - And have salad leftovers.
Speaker 0: Don't put the croutons in the whole salad 'cause they're gonna turn into just mush if you put that salad in the fridge.
Speaker 1: - Exactly, so you make the salad, but you don't put the crouton in there.
Speaker 1: That way, you only put the crouton in at the table and you're gonna have a better leftover salad experience.
Speaker 1: - Exactly.
Speaker 1: - You might not even wanna put dressing in the salad in advance, only put it at the table.
Speaker 0: - The other thing that I do now, I learned this when I worked in restaurants, but I started applying it to my own life a few, like several years ago.
Speaker 0: And it's actually helped a lot because if you adequately crash cool something, like a proper leftover, you cooked it, and now you wanna just put the whole thing away.
Speaker 0: Consumer fridges can actually cool things down that quickly.
Speaker 0: And in fact, if you put something that's too warm in your fridge, it might make other things that are next to it in your fridge unsafe in a way you don't realize.
Speaker 1: - Depends, usually just one little- I mean, it's possible, but it's like, yeah, you put one little container of food in there that is a little bit warm.
Speaker 1: - Well, here's the example.
Speaker 0: If you have a whole pot of hot soup and you put it in the fridge and it's next to your milk, your milk's probably fucked.
Speaker 1: - Yes, that would be a bad situation.
Speaker 1: But I think most of the time you're putting in like a little reusable container with some stuff in it, that's fine.
Speaker 0: - Yeah, it's a little bit, 'cause if it's a larger amount of leftovers.
Speaker 1: - If you put in a giant, still hot cauldron of chicken soup into the fridge, yeah, you're gonna significantly cause some trouble.
Speaker 0: - But here's the sort of the rocket fuel equation.
Speaker 0: If you let a larger thing, like say you ate half a casserole, you want for the other half in the fridge, if you let it sit out until it's cool enough to safely put in the fridge, it's been in the danger zone too long.
Speaker 0: There's too much bacteria growing in there.
Speaker 0: But if you put it right in the fridge, it's gonna fuck up your fridge for like four hours.
Speaker 0: The way to do it is there's two techniques that I learned from professional chefs.
Speaker 0: One, you take whatever the dish, whatever it's in, like say it's a big pot of soup, dump it out into another pot that is at room temperature.
Speaker 1: - Nope, there's a lot of heat in the pot.
Speaker 1: - And you can just get rid of all that heat instantly.
Speaker 0: - And then you just put that second pot right in the fridge.
Speaker 0: Or number two, take that second pot and stick it in a bowl of ice water and let it sit there outside of your fridge for like 10 minutes first to crash cool it, to get it through the danger zone as fast as possible before you put it in the fridge.
Speaker 1: - Yeah, I basically never put anything in the fridge in its like original container.
Speaker 1: I always, I have these like reusable glass lock things.
Speaker 1: - Yep, yep.
Speaker 1: - It's basically just a glass food container with a plastic lid that snaps on.
Speaker 1: They also have a little hole that you can open and close and that's really useful 'cause that way you can just open the hole and put it in the microwave or close the hole and put it in the fridge and whatnot.
Speaker 1: Or you can take it with you to eat if you actually go to a work or something.
Speaker 1: You know, that kind of thing.
Speaker 0: - Yep, and I guess in terms of like left, the thing that I think everyone does is there'll be a leftover that you like, it's might be safe to eat, but you're not 100% sure.
Speaker 0: So you choose to just not eat it and eat something else instead, but you don't throw it away yet.
Speaker 0: And then a couple of days later, well, now it's definitely bad and then you feel a lot better about throwing it out.
Speaker 0: I feel like that's a pattern.
Speaker 1: - Yeah, we had a recent meal.
Speaker 1: It wasn't from, it was the sun basket box, right?
Speaker 1: And the meal came with these two sweet potatoes and they were fucking huge sweet potatoes.
Speaker 1: And the way it had me cook the sweet potatoes was a good way, but I think their proportions were way off.
Speaker 1: I had to like, you know, it was like, you know, we're mixing honey in there to sweeten them up and stuff.
Speaker 1: And I added more honey 'cause they were so big, but it still kind of wasn't enough.
Speaker 1: And we kind of got full and there was still a lot of potato left.
Speaker 1: So I put the sweet potato, you know, back in the fridge, right, in a different container, but it's like, there was no opportunity to just eat some sweet potato.
Speaker 0: - Yup, like that's gotta be like a side dish to another whole meal.
Speaker 1: - Right, it's like, we would have had to, you know, we were unexpected to have them and there was no plan to make something to go with them, right, and we were eating other things that were planned to eat.
Speaker 1: And so the sweet potato had to go, it outlived its welcome.
Speaker 1: sadly, right?
Speaker 0: - My rule now is basically 48 hours, or if I look in the fridge and I wanna eat a leftover, but I balk at all, like, I feel it's like, oh, I wonder if it's actually still safe.
Speaker 0: If my instinct is I don't wanna eat it right now and I choose to eat something else, I assume I should just throw it away 'cause it's gonna be like the banana that never gets turned into banana brew at that point.
Speaker 0: - This has been Geek Nights with Rim and Scott.
Speaker 0: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design, and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 1: - Be sure to visit our website at frontrowcrew.com for show notes, discussion news, and more.
Speaker 0: - Remember, Geek Nights is not one, but four different shows, SciTech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays, and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: - Geek Nights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: Geek Nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 1: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.
Speaker 0: - And the Patreon patrons for this particular episode of Geek Nights are Alan Joyce, Heidi McNichol, Link Iggi, Graham Finch, You Hold the Key to My Heart.
Speaker 0: Now go through the last year or so of podcasts and make Rim sing.
Speaker 0: Clinton Walton, Ren from New Zealand, Ryan Perrin, Revue, Mad Bull, 34 Cowards, Dread Lily, Tenebrae, Just Like a Dude Guy, Chris Reimer, Finn, Shervin Von Horl, and a bunch of people who do not want me to say their name.
Speaker 0: If any of you are interested in playing a play-by-mail game of Civilization VI, check out the Geek Nights Discord.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna post something to the forum.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna make a little Google thing, like a survey to fill out if anyone wants to join.
Speaker 0: We started a game a long, long time ago.
Speaker 0: that was all good fun in Civ V. I wanna do it again in Civ VI.
Speaker 0: So keep an eye out from that.
Speaker 0: I'll probably post that out there tomorrow.
Speaker 0: But for now, I will leave you with...
Speaker 1: - Oh my God.
Speaker 0: - What?
Speaker 1: - Did you just kill him?
Speaker 1: - Yeah, I guess I did.
Speaker 1: - I mean, that guy's single-handedly killed hundreds of our men.
Speaker 0: - I mean, he was just standing there.
Speaker 1: - I mean, did you punch him hard?
Speaker 0: - I guess.
Speaker 0: Just a standard punch.
Speaker 1: - I mean, do we still stand guard?
Speaker 1: That guy was the guy.
Speaker 1: - Yeah, that was the guy.
Speaker 1: - That was the guy this was all about.
Speaker 1: I mean, it's not like there's another guy.
Speaker 1: - I guess we should tell the boss.
Speaker 0: - Yeah, okay, sure.
Speaker 1: - Cool.
Speaker 1: - Hey, boss?
Speaker 0: - What do you want?
Speaker 0: You should be guarding.
Speaker 0: He could show up any minute.
Speaker 0: - That's kind of the thing.
Speaker 0: He already was here.
Speaker 1: - Well, bring him in.
Speaker 1: I want to see him.
Speaker 0: - Well, we already took care of him.
Speaker 0: - You what?
Speaker 1: - Well, he was just standing there and I punched him and he died.
Speaker 1: - This is same guy who chased us across seven continent.
Speaker 0: - Yep.
Speaker 1: - Same guy who took down 30 of our helicopter.
Speaker 1: The guy we shot with RPG and he fall out the plane into ocean attacked by shark on boat and boat explode.
Speaker 0: - That's the one.
Speaker 1: - You punched him and he died.
Speaker 0: - Yeah.
Speaker 1: - Okay, I guess that's good.