Speaker 1: It's Thursday, July 1st, 2021.
Speaker 1: I'm Rym.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott.
Speaker 1: And this is Geek Nights.
Speaker 1: Tonight, we are talking about hidden to bricks.
Speaker 1: Bailing.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: So, uh, this is the kind of day where I might say warm today, but it's actually significantly less warm today compared to yesterday.
Speaker 0: Well, it's just 'cause it's raining.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it looks like it's gonna rain pretty much constantly until, like, Monday.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's how things work.
Speaker 0: You know, you have hot, hot, hot, storm, storm, storm.
Speaker 0: Hot, hot, hot, storm.
Speaker 0: The hotness makes water go into the sky to make clouds.
Speaker 0: That's how the weather works.
Speaker 1: The storm that went through last night was pretty fun, though, 'cause it just felt so much like those, like, really intense storms that I was used to as a kid.
Speaker 1: that would happen on a semi-weekly basis living in a not-New York.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it wasn't that intense.
Speaker 1: It was more intense than the average New York City storm.
Speaker 1: Usually, the storms here, at least until the last few years, were kind of just nothings.
Speaker 0: There's still, it's like, you know, I don't know about the, like, if you measure wind speed and, you know, rainfall, they might be considered intense.
Speaker 0: But, like, if the thunder isn't so loud that you're like, "Oh, shit," right?
Speaker 0: Or, uh...
Speaker 1: I mean, it's hard.
Speaker 1: I grew up in Michigan.
Speaker 1: It's very hard for any storm to be so intense that I go, "Oh,
Speaker 1: shit.".
Speaker 0: I'm just saying, like, you know...
Speaker 1: I've literally watched a tornado go down the street in front of my own house.
Speaker 0: If the thunder is just, like, rumble, rumble, rumble, it's, like, whatever, right?
Speaker 0: I want it to be like... Right?
Speaker 0: Like, everyone in the house jumps, like, "Oh,
Speaker 0: shit.".
Speaker 0: That's, you know, right?
Speaker 1: I remember one time lightning struck the neighbor's house, and it was so loud in our house that we thought we got struck.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and it, you know, it should be frequent, right?
Speaker 0: It can't be a lot of these storms.
Speaker 0: It's like, "Okay, maybe it'll be a couple booms that are loud," and then it's gone, right?
Speaker 0: It's like, "No, no, no.
Speaker 0: Hang around for a good half hour.
Speaker 0: Like, just keep booming for a half hour, at
Speaker 0: least.".
Speaker 1: Actually, what these storms remind me of the most are the storms I was used to if I was further south or when I'm overseas in parts of Asia during monsoon season.
Speaker 1: 'Cause they come in rapidly.
Speaker 1: Heavy rain, and then they pass pretty quickly, too.
Speaker 1: And that's a pattern that was...
Speaker 0: Yeah, so it's like a tropical island.
Speaker 0: Like, you'll be out on the beach, and be like, "Uh-oh, you see a storm coming,".
Speaker 0: so you go inside.
Speaker 1: I remember the first time we went to Alabama.
Speaker 0: Florida, the same thing happens.
Speaker 1: First time in my life as kids, we went to Alabama.
Speaker 0: And then it goes away, and you go back outside.
Speaker 1: Yup, on the way to Florida, and in both Alabama and Florida, I encountered something I just never experienced in my life, was it's sunny around noon-thirty, noon-forty-five.
Speaker 1: Suddenly, there's driving rain you can't see for, like, five minutes, and then it's just sunny again.
Speaker 1: Like, nothing happened.
Speaker 1: But I was actually at the office, 'cause I go in a couple days a week, and all the phones went off.
Speaker 1: It looks like it didn't get everyone's phones.
Speaker 1: Like, people in Queens didn't seem like they got this alert.
Speaker 1: Like, it seemed like it was targeted to people in Manhattan, but all the cell phones there went off.
Speaker 1: And New York State and New York City both have, like, these emergency notification systems, and there's the national systems and all that.
Speaker 1: But there's different categories, like classes, of how important an alert is.
Speaker 1: I'd never seen an extreme one before, and it was interesting that this was the time they used the extreme warning, as opposed to, like, the normal warning.
Speaker 1: 'Cause the extreme warning basically said, "Yo, turn your AC down, or we're gonna have a power outage, like,
Speaker 1: imminently.".
Speaker 0: Yeah, there's not enough information about that, right, for me to say anything for certain.
Speaker 0: But things I do know, as I saw some reporting this morning, that A, it did have an effect.
Speaker 0: Electricity usage went down a little bit after they made it, so I think they might have been A, seeing if it worked.
Speaker 0: B, they might have detected, there might have been legitimate, they might have detected that power was going on.
Speaker 1: There were a bunch of pretty big but localized outages all around the city around that time.
Speaker 1: There was a big one in Williamsburg, they actually set up some cooling buses.
Speaker 1: Like, there's buses idling with air conditioning, and they were passing out dry ice.
Speaker 0: I also wonder if, you know, the last summer, right, everyone was, you know, inside, using their own personal air conditioners, and not at the office.
Speaker 0: So, I was thinking, well, the office air conditioners are way more efficient, and if everyone goes to work, the home ones are off, which are less efficient.
Speaker 0: That might have had an impact, but everyone was home last summer, but last summer wasn't as hot, so I don't know about that one.
Speaker 0: But also, I do know that the old, shitty, but still somewhat safe, I guess, nuclear power plant was shut down very recently.
Speaker 1: Which, there's a lot going on with that.
Speaker 1: Shutting down Indian Point reduced the available power capacity for this entire region significantly.
Speaker 0: And they replaced it with fossil fuel and non-renewable resources.
Speaker 1: I hate to say this, we almost would have been better off, well, no, we would have been better off if the plan hadn't been shut down Indian Point and do nothing, but the plan had been build a new nuclear power plant, and then shut down Indian Point.
Speaker 0: I don't know why the fuck they didn't just do that.
Speaker 1: Because America won't build nuclear power plants, because we're terrible.
Speaker 0: Just do it.
Speaker 0: Just building, you know, it's like you already have an Indian power plant there.
Speaker 1: Actually, you want to know why we can't?
Speaker 1: There's two reasons why we can't build nuclear power plants in America.
Speaker 1: One, I hate to always say this, but it always comes back to this, it's the Republican Party's obstruction.
Speaker 1: We can't change any regulations.
Speaker 1: This is New York.
Speaker 0: New York could have built it itself.
Speaker 1: Nope, that's federal.
Speaker 1: New York can't do that.
Speaker 0: New York can't build a power plant?
Speaker 1: Not a nuclear power plant.
Speaker 1: Do you know how nuclear power plants are regulated?
Speaker 0: We're not allowed to build a nuclear power plant with our own New York money?
Speaker 1: There's a lot of, there's 20ish years of planning.
Speaker 0: Even if we've already got one, we can't replace one?
Speaker 1: No, there are 20ish years of planning at the federal level to even get to the point of having a permit to build a new nuclear power plant.
Speaker 0: Even though it's entirely within the borders of our state?
Speaker 1: Yeah, no, it's federally regulated.
Speaker 1: New York could just be building one.
Speaker 0: Even though we're already importing radioactive fuel from somewhere?
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's all federally regulated.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but we're already getting fuel for the one we had.
Speaker 1: Well, actually, also, do you realize how little fuel they actually take?
Speaker 0: Yeah, not much.
Speaker 0: You don't have to get it that often.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but it's done federally.
Speaker 1: But two, more importantly, because of Republican obstruction, we can't update our processes, so we can't build modern plants or new things.
Speaker 0: Why don't the nuclear power, how come the nuclear power companies aren't bribing as well as the fossil fuel power companies?
Speaker 1: Because nuclear power doesn't make you any fucking money.
Speaker 1: This needs to be fully run by the government.
Speaker 0: You sell it for just as much as fossil fuel, and you don't have to buy it.
Speaker 0: You don't need to buy a lot of fuel.
Speaker 1: Nuclear power is better for the environment and better for pretty much all the practical things, but the cost of making it secure in dollars and making it safe and regulating it in dollars, that costs so much that you basically can't make money running nuclear power plants.
Speaker 1: The right way to do it would be to have the federal government run them.
Speaker 0: What other countries do they want to have a bunch of nuclear power plants?
Speaker 1: Well, really, there's a lot of solutions to this, Scott, but they're literally impossible because our government cannot change any laws right now.
Speaker 0: Anyway.
Speaker 1: Anyway, but the fact that because we couldn't make new power plants, we just replaced all of that capacity with fossil fuel, we actually drastically increased the amount of pollution that New York City generates by shutting down Indian Point without a nuclear alternative.
Speaker 0: But also, states are just ignoring federal law when it comes to weed, right?
Speaker 0: Weed is still illegal federally.
Speaker 1: That is not going to fly.
Speaker 1: You can't ignore the law when you build a nuclear power plant.
Speaker 0: Why not?
Speaker 0: Just do it.
Speaker 0: I feel like I dare you.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: We got a mayor.
Speaker 0: If I was governor of New York, you know I'd do it.
Speaker 1: I feel like if you were the governor of New York, you would end up in jail for one thing or another.
Speaker 0: Well, the cops would probably arrest me because of how much I fucked them over.
Speaker 0: They'd find some excuse, right?
Speaker 0: They would just be like, "You've done enough of this anti-cop guy.
Speaker 0: Let's find some reason to arrest
Speaker 0: him.".
Speaker 0: There
Speaker 1: is another problem in America around this nuclear power thing that for a lot of reasons, a lot of leftists and a lot of even people who care about ecological issues tend to misunderstand nuclear power and be deeply opposed to it, which is part of why no politician will ever stake their tent posts next to the story of "I'm going to do more nuclear power," because that just kills your campaign because of honestly misguided resistance to nuclear power.
Speaker 0: Too bad.
Speaker 1: Too bad what?
Speaker 1: There's no way to get someone elected who's for nuclear power because too many people on the left hate it and Republicans will oppose anything.
Speaker 0: Just lie and then do it.
Speaker 1: Ah, yes, but even then, you can't unless you change the laws and regulations and guess what that requires?
Speaker 1: 60 senators.
Speaker 0: Just do it anyway.
Speaker 1: What do you mean?
Speaker 1: do it anyway?
Speaker 1: There's no.
Speaker 1: just do it.
Speaker 1: That is literally impossible.
Speaker 0: Just do it.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: What resources are you going to use?
Speaker 1: New York State probably couldn't even afford to build a nuclear power plant.
Speaker 0: Well, that's a different problem.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Who are you going to hire?
Speaker 0: Tax the rich people of New York.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I guess we can't do that for a lot of other reasons, too, because of Upstate.
Speaker 0: Just do it anyway.
Speaker 1: What do you mean?
Speaker 1: do it anyway?
Speaker 1: With what?
Speaker 1: With a vote that we can't do?
Speaker 0: No, just go to the rich people's house and take the fucking money.
Speaker 1: Who specifically goes and does that?
Speaker 0: Uh, I don't know.
Speaker 1: Should Schumer and de Blasio just like show up at someone's house with Cuomo and just like take their wallet?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I guess if I was governor of New York, I could just show up at a rich guy's house.
Speaker 0: They'd let me in.
Speaker 0: If I would.
Speaker 0: And I'd be like, guess what?
Speaker 0: This is stick up.
Speaker 1: You know, and you could Bill Murray that you're like you robbed them of all their cash and you leave.
Speaker 1: and then who the fuck is going to believe them that this even happened?
Speaker 1: You're saying.
Speaker 0: I'd live stream it.
Speaker 1: Sir, are you saying that Senator Rubin.
Speaker 0: You know how many votes that would get me if you live streamed me, the governor.
Speaker 0: Just imagine the hearing.
Speaker 0: Governor Scott showing up at evil rich at like, I don't know who's the most evil rich person in New York.
Speaker 0: Fuck it.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: Dolan, right?
Speaker 0: The guy who owns the garden, right?
Speaker 0: Everyone hates him.
Speaker 0: I show up at his house and I'd be like, yeah, we're taking this house and we're taking the Knicks and we're taking the rain.
Speaker 1: No, no, no.
Speaker 1: You slow roll it though and you do it by you just show up, you rob them and then no one believes them.
Speaker 0: I know I live stream it.
Speaker 0: You know how many votes I would get if I did that?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: There are a lot of, there are a lot of weird, angry white boys who would die to defend people like Elon Musk.
Speaker 0: Well, Timothy Dolan is not Elon Musk.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I feel like he's got to have a bunch of fanboys that they're weirdly obsessed with the content of billionaires.
Speaker 0: But also if he did live in New York, that would also make an amazing live stream.
Speaker 0: just robbing him live.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'm here with the tax collector.
Speaker 0: Plus all the rich people, right?
Speaker 0: You know, it's like rob them.
Speaker 0: It's like 100% of them have cheated on taxes.
Speaker 0: I just have to find how they cheated on the tax, the state tax.
Speaker 0: Oh yeah.
Speaker 1: It's almost like the IRS should be going after rich people instead of poor people.
Speaker 0: But again, I could be, I could just show up and be like tax collector, right?
Speaker 0: We're taking this Monet and we're taking this Golden Vase and we're taking this platinum toilet.
Speaker 1: Oh, like Robin Hood style?
Speaker 1: You're the evil sheriff.
Speaker 1: Well, I guess the good sheriff in this case.
Speaker 1: Just show up and demand a bag of silver to make you go away.
Speaker 0: Take all the fart cars, sell them to other states and then set borders so they can't get in.
Speaker 1: So there's a good segue.
Speaker 1: Speaking of fart cars, uh, Scott's got some news here.
Speaker 0: I do have some news.
Speaker 0: So, uh, you know, this is only, you know, a little study, right?
Speaker 0: Where they just sort of did, it was more of an experiment than I will say.
Speaker 1: I have seen other studies for over a decade that say the same thing, but yeah.
Speaker 0: So, you know, we complain about the fart cars, people taking their cars and removing catalytic converters and putting, taking off mufflers just cause they want to make noise.
Speaker 0: That's their hobby, right?
Speaker 0: Just making lots of loud noise for whatever reason.
Speaker 0: But an old adage for motorcycle people has always been loud pipes save lives.
Speaker 0: Now we all know the truth, right?
Speaker 0: Even South Park got this one right.
Speaker 0: Sorry, right?
Speaker 0: That, uh, at least in some ways that episode has other issues.
Speaker 1: Parts of that episode were not right, but anyway.
Speaker 0: Yes, but the part that people who have loud motorcycles that are unnecessarily loud are just annoying.
Speaker 0: Uh, and they're not cool, right?
Speaker 1: They're also extremely polluting.
Speaker 1: Like, yes, you might think, oh, well, it's more polluting without the catalytic converter.
Speaker 1: You have no, like they, especially if they're those bootleg motorcycles that actually have a two stroke engine, those things pollute more than like the hundreds and hundreds of miles of SUV driving for like a week's worth of driving.
Speaker 0: Regardless, right?
Speaker 0: Motorcycle people, you know, it is true that riding a motorcycle out on the road, uh, in the United States can often be quite dangerous and risky, riskier, you know, to, at least to yourself, right?
Speaker 0: Not necessarily to others.
Speaker 0: Um, and lots of people, you know, die even if they're wearing helmets and armor.
Speaker 0: You know, I think, you know, a lot of people I know who are motorcycle people have, you know, significant number of them have fallen and gotten, you know, injuries that stay with them forever if they, if they survived.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: So it is dangerous.
Speaker 0: It shouldn't be a motorcycle.
Speaker 0: inherently, you know, a two wheeled motorized vehicle, right?
Speaker 0: Um, is way better than a car.
Speaker 0: We'd be much better off if there was way more motorcycle and motorbike usage.
Speaker 0: I don't want to, you know, denigrate the motorcycle, especially not an electric one, right?
Speaker 0: While an electric car won't save us electric, you know, bikes, motor, whether they're big enough to be called electric motorcycles or just e-bikes, right?
Speaker 0: I don't know, whatever, you know, classification you want to, you know, make there.
Speaker 0: Those are great.
Speaker 0: Those are going to help our, if we use those more, that's going to be great for us.
Speaker 0: But, uh, motorcycle people in the motorcycle culture have long a also enjoyed making lots of loud noises with combustion engines.
Speaker 0: But unlike cars, they have this excuse that they've always used in the U S which is loud pipe, save lives.
Speaker 0: The idea that, you know, you're going to put, you know, it's like if you honk a horn, that's not, you're not going to go honking a horn all the time.
Speaker 0: Right?
Speaker 0: So, but if your motorcycle makes loud noise with its pipe, you know, from, from, right, then everyone can, the logic, simple logic is that cars will hear you even if they can't see you.
Speaker 0: because yeah, especially with all these fricking SUVs and trucks and shit, it's like you're way small, low to the ground.
Speaker 0: They're way up off the ground.
Speaker 0: Right?
Speaker 0: It's like, you know, a lot of big tractor trailers and shit out on the highway.
Speaker 0: It's like, yeah, you can't, a lot of times they don't see you, they change lanes and then you die.
Speaker 0: Right?
Speaker 0: Um, so being noticed would be a concern as a legitimate concern.
Speaker 0: if you, if cars and other giant deadly vehicles did notice you, they don't want to, the drivers by and large don't want to hit you.
Speaker 0: Um, so that would increase your safety.
Speaker 0: So it's like get a motorcycle.
Speaker 0: that's, you know, making a lot of loud noise with the pipe and supposedly common sense cars will notice you were there or at least they'll hear you that you're somewhere and they'll look around for you before they make a movement.
Speaker 1: Now, nevermind the fact that I can, my anecdote is when I have driven and I hear a loud motorcycle, it's impossible to know where that motorcycle is because it's just when I hear it at all, it's just this diffuse noise that's coming from everywhere.
Speaker 0: Well, but you start looking around for it.
Speaker 0: You're not going to like shift lanes if you don't know, right?
Speaker 0: You know, if you haven't seen or, you know, you still hear that noise coming from like somewhere and you're not going to just like shift lanes without looking and noticing.
Speaker 1: Every time I've ever heard it, cause I hear it a lot now when I drive up like to go hiking or camping on a weekend, uh, when I hear it, it appears instantly already passing me.
Speaker 0: And that's what this study showed.
Speaker 0: is that loud pipes, the old adage that seems like common sense, uh, actually is not true because the vast majority of cars and vehicles these days, right?
Speaker 0: Are closed, right?
Speaker 0: Especially on the highway.
Speaker 0: You're not driving with the windows open.
Speaker 0: You got air conditioning, even crappy cars have air conditioning.
Speaker 0: Usually I guess if you got a convertible, right?
Speaker 0: Maybe it'll it won't.
Speaker 0: But then you have so much wind noise depending on the, well, I'm saying it's so I'm talking about, you know, how many people are driving convertibles, right?
Speaker 0: The majority of cars on the road, vehicles on the road are have all the windows closed, right?
Speaker 0: And modern cars are very, very good at blocking out outside noise.
Speaker 0: You can hear the radio and the music and your GPS talking to you and other people in the car.
Speaker 0: They're designed that way, right?
Speaker 0: To be as quiet as possible so that when you're driving, you don't hear shit outside unless it's like horn honking at you.
Speaker 0: Like fancy cars even do stuff like if road noise increases, they automatically increase the very fancy sound system that will use active noise canceling to cancel out the engine noise of the car.
Speaker 0: that is itself, right?
Speaker 0: Its own engines that you don't hear your own engine when you're in your own car.
Speaker 0: And that's really nice.
Speaker 0: But the point is, is that the loud pipe won't save you because the majority of cars won't hear your pipe even a little bit until you are very close to them at which the point you've reached, you're already too late to be, you know, it's too late to be noticed, right?
Speaker 0: You've already gotten too close to the car that you want to be hearing you.
Speaker 0: So loud pipes don't, in fact, don't save lives.
Speaker 0: They just harm lives by making people angry with loud noise, hurting your own hearing, polluting, being annoying, etc.
Speaker 0: There is basically no positive element to them other than the enjoyment that someone feels because they like them and they have one.
Speaker 0: There is absolutely no other positive element to them that I can find.
Speaker 0: And therefore I say that if I was governor of New York, governor, king of New York, you know, and legislator and everything, the rule would be if you have a loud motorcycle, we take it from you and we make it quiet.
Speaker 0: And if you make it loud again, we take it from you and you don't give it back.
Speaker 0: And if you ride another one, then we kick you out of the state.
Speaker 0: You can't come back in.
Speaker 0: And if you try to come back in, then we keep you in a jail.
Speaker 0: I really want to abolish prison.
Speaker 0: But if you're really going to go that far, okay, fine.
Speaker 1: In my life, the people I've encountered or seen who say this adage, I am very confident that the majority of them don't actually believe it.
Speaker 1: And it's just a thin excuse.
Speaker 1: they knowingly say it's like a talking point they just use to get people to stop criticizing their extremely loud should be illegal motorcycles.
Speaker 0: Well, I think just, you know, in general, a lot of talking points, you know, and I can sort of see this because, you know, I guess in many ways everyone is victim to this.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And that there's some common sense thinking.
Speaker 0: It just makes basic sense.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 1: It's like it doesn't think about it at all because the sound you're moving forward quickly.
Speaker 0: So the you're thinking, you know, the problem is, no, you saying thinking about it at all.
Speaker 0: You've already begun thinking too hard about it.
Speaker 0: The basic right is loud noise.
Speaker 0: People notice it.
Speaker 0: The basic thought.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Not going into any more thought.
Speaker 1: But I don't think they've ever thought it protects me.
Speaker 1: I think they've always thought it pisses people off and or gets them to look at me.
Speaker 1: And that's my primary goal.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: But sure.
Speaker 0: But the point is there.
Speaker 0: at the basic level, it makes common sense the same way that at only without looking into it.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: With only the basic level of thought, you think, well, crime is up, therefore we should get more cops.
Speaker 0: It's the same basic thinking where you're not looking at data, investigating, checking nuance, checking details, just basic common sense thinking.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And you get things wrong when you only think that way.
Speaker 0: But it's hard to convince someone that, you know, common sense is wrong because it is common sense when you only look at the surface.
Speaker 0: It's just so obvious.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: How could that possibly be wrong, even if it's extremely wrong?
Speaker 1: So in some other news, New York City, we talked about this a little bit a while ago, like all these different ideas for new subway cars.
Speaker 1: These were visible in a bunch of places in the city for a while, but apparently they did an official unveiling of the new R211 subway cars that it looks like they're going to replace the A train and the C train cars first.
Speaker 0: Well, those are the oldest busted trains.
Speaker 1: Those are the ones that still have like wood paneling on the inside.
Speaker 1: Like they're they're really ugly.
Speaker 1: They're really bad.
Speaker 0: They're also the most delayed trains, I think.
Speaker 1: And these new subway cars, aren't these the ones?
Speaker 0: aren't these the new ones that have the?
Speaker 0: they're like, you know, open, open.
Speaker 1: So they're not going to make all the cars open.
Speaker 1: So basically they're getting 500 of these things and 20 of them will have the open gangways, meaning it's one long car like start to end as opposed to separate individual cars that you're not allowed to walk between.
Speaker 1: Now, studies show pretty much everywhere else on earth that the open gangways are just better.
Speaker 0: They increase the capacity in which way in which they increase the capacity because you can ride in the in the gangway.
Speaker 1: Not just that, but also because people diffuse and spread throughout the entire train instead of being stuck in the car they entered on.
Speaker 0: So those will still spread throughout the entire train now.
Speaker 0: Just not so much.
Speaker 0: Only the people brave enough to go between the cars.
Speaker 1: Very few people do that.
Speaker 1: And most subway cars, they lock it these days.
Speaker 0: I've never seen it locked.
Speaker 1: It's locked all the time.
Speaker 0: I've never seen it locked in between.
Speaker 1: In fact, I have before Covid, I have oftentimes, especially on the seven or the four.
Speaker 0: Are you sure you just don't know how to open it?
Speaker 1: No, no.
Speaker 1: I've seen people get in and then they can't get back in and they're like banging on the door until someone opens it for them.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 0: If you're in the middle part, that can happen.
Speaker 1: You can't get into the next car because it's locked.
Speaker 1: Sometimes you can force it open from the inside, but you can't force it open from the outside.
Speaker 1: The point is also to take to their people to go out there.
Speaker 0: Well, forget that.
Speaker 0: People die going in the middle.
Speaker 0: That's the.
Speaker 0: that's the reason I don't do it because, yeah, people fucking die.
Speaker 0: Not even exaggerating.
Speaker 0: People have tried to go between the current train cars and it's not safe to go between them while the train is in motion.
Speaker 0: And you can die if you mess up out there.
Speaker 1: But it creates a ton more space.
Speaker 1: And it also is like there are real studies.
Speaker 1: People diffuse and spread out more evenly throughout trains.
Speaker 1: when this is true compared to any other circumstance, like any other layout is the best.
Speaker 0: Doesn't it also help the cooling of the train, like the heating and cooling?
Speaker 1: It pretty much helps everything.
Speaker 1: The only argument anyone has ever made against these things is an argument only made by New Yorkers.
Speaker 1: And it's that the entire train will have a problem.
Speaker 1: if there's a problem on the train, as in a smelly person, a violent person.
Speaker 1: Now it's a whole train problem instead of just.
Speaker 0: Well, it's in one in some ways.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: In some ways, no.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Smell might come from one car to another, but it will go to the next car over and the next car.
Speaker 0: You can get away.
Speaker 0: And since it's open, you can get away.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: If you get on a smelly car and the door closes behind you, you can escape.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I mean, but they're not making a lot of them yet, but they have the option to get a ton more of both the open gangway and the regular one.
Speaker 1: So it seems like they're going to use the small number of the open gangway ones they got as an experiment and they'll decide what to do based on that.
Speaker 0: I see this as just another one of those, you know, go sign situations.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: People look at it.
Speaker 0: They apply their common sense thinking.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And they don't like change.
Speaker 0: But then if you just make the change happen and ignore people who don't know better and then they'll get used to it and that'll be that.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: It's like the end.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: Just do it.
Speaker 1: The other cool thing is these trains have a lot less seating.
Speaker 1: So more people are forced to stand, which you can cram a ton more people in.
Speaker 0: But they you know, the only you know, I think, you know, right now we have seating and then we have priority seating for people with disabilities.
Speaker 0: I feel like all seating should be priority seating people disabilities.
Speaker 0: Well, the way they're doing it needs to be needs to be there.
Speaker 1: There's a big section of disability seating in these new cars where the seats are flipped up by default.
Speaker 1: So it's standing room.
Speaker 1: But that's the place where also wheelchairs would go and the seats can flip down.
Speaker 1: And they're only for people who need them.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: I'm saying like we should eliminate all that.
Speaker 0: We should have the amount of seating that is needed for, you know, the number of disabled people that are likely to be on train, according to what we figured out.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: So that, you know, no disabled person has to stand.
Speaker 0: But we shouldn't.
Speaker 0: No abled person should be, you know, sitting.
Speaker 0: Why?
Speaker 0: Why were you sitting?
Speaker 0: if you're if you're able?
Speaker 1: I mean, if there is a seat and I'm going like, I don't know, all the way out to Flushing or Rockaway, I'll sit down.
Speaker 1: I mean, you know, it doesn't really matter if you're if you know what I really like to sit down if I'm taking the stupid E out to the train or to the airport, E to the air train.
Speaker 1: I'll sit down on that if I can.
Speaker 1: I usually can't because E train is always completely full in both directions all the time.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: But if you're considering the design of the train, we want to increase capacity.
Speaker 1: Well, we only need to increase capacity during the rush hours.
Speaker 1: So, you know, one thing that absolutely if I if I had my way and there was an ethical way to do it, I would say that most seats in the entire system should be removed during rush hour.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Oh, you want temporarily remove it?
Speaker 0: So one idea seems like unnecessary work.
Speaker 0: Just remove them, period.
Speaker 1: Well, one idea that they were floating a while back, I don't think they're going to do that here, is the idea that the four center cars on the most important subway lines would have no seats during the rush hours.
Speaker 0: Wouldn't every?
Speaker 1: every single station's entrance is so different that you can't design the cars around that.
Speaker 1: I read there's an article about that specific idea.
Speaker 0: Sure, but the center is going to be on average closer.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And therefore, you know, the person who needs the seat would travel less far.
Speaker 1: No, that's that's apparently there is.
Speaker 1: that's not true at all based on the just radically different configurations of all the subway stations.
Speaker 0: They do every other car.
Speaker 1: Well, the idea was you just make an area of dense pack, no seating in the center and everywhere else has seats.
Speaker 0: Hmm.
Speaker 0: If someone who needs a seat, they shouldn't have to go far.
Speaker 1: But Scott, I'm saying there's no way to do that.
Speaker 1: You realize how many stations, especially every other car, every other car wouldn't help in that way.
Speaker 0: You're never more than one car away from a seat.
Speaker 0: That way you don't.
Speaker 0: you're not going to have a situation where, you know, the station is at the front and the seats are in the middle and the person has to go.
Speaker 1: Well, they couldn't do that because the no seat ones are also the gangway sections.
Speaker 1: There will be trains where some sections are gangway and some sections are blocked off.
Speaker 0: They can mix and match.
Speaker 0: OK, for what reason?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 1: Partly for all the reasons I described.
Speaker 1: Part of this is to experiment on what actually works.
Speaker 1: It's very difficult to model the behavior of subway riders because the system is so dense and all the stations are so different and unique.
Speaker 1: You pretty much just have to experimentally see how people behave and then make changes based on that.
Speaker 1: In some other news, I'm sure you saw the thing that bugs me the most about this story is that the reporting is still saying things like 16 dead, 150 unaccounted for.
Speaker 1: This is one hundred and sixty three dead people.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: Yes, it is.
Speaker 1: So an entire ass apartment building, well, condo building just collapsed and killed a ton of people in Florida.
Speaker 1: And all the evidence points at this was just criminal negligence, as it always is.
Speaker 1: And mostly the real culprit here seems to be Florida not regulating anything because it's a Republican state.
Speaker 1: Like all the problems of America always seem to boil.
Speaker 1: Like these are the kinds of problems that happen when you have such a broken country as this.
Speaker 1: Our infrastructure is just going to get worse and worse and worse.
Speaker 1: This is going to happen again soon, probably, like in the next five or ten years.
Speaker 0: And while this is a huge, horrible disaster that I do not want to diminish in any way.
Speaker 1: Half as many people were killed by guns in Chicago last weekend.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Everything that you said is just correct.
Speaker 0: But how many people died in this building collapse?
Speaker 1: One hundred and sixty three is the likely count.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yesterday, two hundred and eighty three people died of covid in the United States alone.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: So, you know, while it is it is one hundred percent true that our infrastructure is falling apart and will kill many more people.
Speaker 0: It always bothers me the proportion of emphasis that is put on two different things.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: By the media.
Speaker 0: It's like, you know, one person is shot.
Speaker 0: Huge news.
Speaker 0: Like it's the end of the world in a town where, like, you know, at the same day, several people in the town could have died from, like, heart attacks.
Speaker 0: And they're not like, what's causing the heart disease in the town?
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: It's not a story at all.
Speaker 0: They don't even discuss it.
Speaker 0: Well, those stories happen.
Speaker 1: It's just people aren't that interested because they're used to that baseline amount of death.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Like look at mass shootings.
Speaker 1: Mass shootings barely get reported on in America anymore because they're so common.
Speaker 1: Literally, if less than 20 people die, it won't even make the news.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: It's like we need the news to emphasize correctly.
Speaker 0: And, you know, if the news is going to make its money by stoking fear.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Make the fear you stoke proportional to the reality.
Speaker 0: There's plenty of things to be right.
Speaker 1: I would argue that if you did that, you don't need to.
Speaker 1: you would just make less money because more sensationalist outfits would just steal your entire audience.
Speaker 0: You can you can just listen.
Speaker 0: There's plenty of things to be afraid of.
Speaker 0: You can just sensationalize proportional to reality.
Speaker 1: So I would argue that may not actually work because a lot of people, their ideology drives which media they consume and which causes they care about, not the media telling them what to care about, but they seek out the media that confirms what they already want to believe.
Speaker 0: You know, but how do they get that way to begin with?
Speaker 1: Well, that's a whole geek that's a whole geek night's a week.
Speaker 0: I'm saying is I like to?
Speaker 0: I like to change the maze.
Speaker 0: You can't change the rat.
Speaker 0: Change the me.
Speaker 1: But here's here's what's going on here.
Speaker 1: But part of the reason why things like this are should be newsworthy is that this a few hundred like this many people dying of heart disease is a much more complex, nuanced and widespread problem.
Speaker 1: But this case was one hundred percent preventable by very minimal regulation like this, like it would not have taken much to prevent this from happening.
Speaker 1: and things like this keep happening because no one's willing to deal with the fundamental problem, which in this case basically is it is unethical to let towns, cities or even states have their own regulations for important things like infrastructure.
Speaker 1: Why does Florida get to have different rules for buildings than New York?
Speaker 1: They really shouldn't be allowed to because in almost all cases, conservative states just don't have rules and then people die.
Speaker 0: I mean, it doesn't matter.
Speaker 0: You know, I mean, it doesn't matter who makes the rules as long as you're forced to have good rules.
Speaker 1: But it just so happens that good rules only come from progressive Democratic legislation and bad rules only come from Republican states.
Speaker 0: Well, you know, maybe, you know, if states rights becomes the thing, right, maybe we'll end up in a situation where the, you know, the, you know, the standard of living in Democratic places becomes extremely high.
Speaker 1: We're already there.
Speaker 0: And right.
Speaker 0: But I'm saying it becomes even more dramatic.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 1: But there's some specific things that I want to flag for this story.
Speaker 1: The thing you should really look at is how did this happen?
Speaker 1: is specifically because now we don't know the details of exactly like why it collapsed.
Speaker 1: There's going to be years investigations.
Speaker 1: But this is one of the biggest residential disasters in American history.
Speaker 0: But this kind of thing happens all the time in other countries.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Well, actually, it's not that common.
Speaker 0: I've seen a lot.
Speaker 0: My point is building collabs news in the United States is relatively rare.
Speaker 0: When's the last time you've seen one?
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 1: But I feel like a few nuggets came out.
Speaker 1: is that one?
Speaker 1: there is a clear evidence.
Speaker 0: you India building collapses.
Speaker 1: There is clear evidence that this buildings had severe problems.
Speaker 1: And obviously, like Florida didn't require this building to be inspected for 40 years.
Speaker 1: But the big problem was that it was a condo.
Speaker 1: So there was a condo association that managed the building.
Speaker 1: Like people own these apartments.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: These repairs were known to that needed to be made.
Speaker 1: But the board of the condo could not get them made because they ended up being very expensive because the building was a piece of shit and the residents were fighting about not wanting to pay for the repairs.
Speaker 0: People care about more about money than other things.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Is the fundamental?
Speaker 0: is the fundamental problem underlying everything.
Speaker 1: So as a result, you have a condo board that has to decide how to pay for the repairs of a building.
Speaker 1: that is not a government.
Speaker 1: This is like a private institution and the like.
Speaker 1: the people voting in this are just the random ass.
Speaker 1: people who live in this building.
Speaker 0: And many of them, they vote, they voted to some of them voted to die and they got their way.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: A lot of people in this building may have voted to die.
Speaker 0: They even voting to die.
Speaker 0: You'd still don't deserve to die.
Speaker 0: So it's still they don't deserve this.
Speaker 1: I'm not I don't want to blame them.
Speaker 1: I'm saying the failing of society was that they had the choice in the first place.
Speaker 1: That is not the kind of thing that should be up for vote.
Speaker 0: Are you pro democracy or anti democracy?
Speaker 1: I am anti.
Speaker 0: Make up your mind.
Speaker 1: So in this case, look at the problem is what you.
Speaker 1: this is the same reason why HOA's homeowners associations are such a problem.
Speaker 1: This is a body that is not a government, does not have the controls and protections that a government run democracy would have.
Speaker 1: This is a private institution with its own rules that has to make life or death decisions.
Speaker 1: You cannot put life or death decisions in the hands of unqualified people without government guidance, regulation and guardrails.
Speaker 0: I think the problem is simply that you can't put life or death decisions in the hands of someone with an ulterior motive in this case, usually money.
Speaker 0: And it's the same thing with even in the government.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but it's worse than making life or death decisions.
Speaker 0: who have this ulterior motive of the money.
Speaker 1: The people live in this building, much like a homeowners association.
Speaker 1: They vote and it's like you can vote and engage in your government.
Speaker 1: But this was not a government.
Speaker 1: So the condo board.
Speaker 0: But the point is without the without the incentive of they're sitting there and they're doing like, you know, the old Lisa needs braces thing is like, you know, they're sitting there.
Speaker 0: Well, fix my building or get a bunch of money.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: It's like the only reason they didn't vote to repair the building is because it would mean spending money.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: It was even worse than that.
Speaker 1: The board, the condo board, the the governing body that makes all these decisions like an HOA is volunteer.
Speaker 1: You've got to like actively be involved in this thing.
Speaker 1: And most of the people on that board actually resigned in twenty nineteen and everything fell into disarray because of all the drama of this non-government entity requiring people to be active in it to do basic things like maintain a place that a bunch of people live together.
Speaker 0: Sure, sure, sure.
Speaker 0: But if it wasn't for the money, even the disarrayed thing would have voted to repair because there wouldn't have been any reason not to.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: It was greed that would make them.
Speaker 0: the only reason that you wouldn't repair your building.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Is because you didn't care about money more than life.
Speaker 1: But would they have in the sense that the voting is that the people who make these decisions are just the people with enough free time to volunteer to deal with the condo association of the building they happen to live in.
Speaker 0: If there wasn't, you know, why did they vote no?
Speaker 0: There was a. it wasn't.
Speaker 0: you know, did they just do nothing?
Speaker 0: They voted no.
Speaker 0: We're not going to repair.
Speaker 0: Why would you make that choice of no?
Speaker 1: So the board, it's not clear because the building doesn't just vote.
Speaker 1: The board members vote.
Speaker 1: So right.
Speaker 1: So imagine if in your building, whoever is busybody and like just bored enough to like go to these board meetings and deal with it without any compensation.
Speaker 0: But even if you take a busybody, even if there's one busybody old lady and you go to the old lady and you say, "Old lady, you got two choices.
Speaker 0: Repair the building.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, the building needs repairs.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: Or but it's going to cost a bunch of money.
Speaker 0: So or we can keep a bunch of money, right?
Speaker 0: If that or money isn't there, even the busybody old lady is going to say, "Yeah, fix the
Speaker 0: building."
Speaker 0: Right?
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: So it looked like the repair costs because the building had been so poorly maintained by the board for so long were just skyrocketing.
Speaker 1: And it was going to cost like four times more than they'd even thought when they'd last got it assessed.
Speaker 1: And basically the building was managed poorly by this volunteer board of busybodies for 40 years.
Speaker 1: And people kept quitting the board because even before the repair costs because of drama.
Speaker 1: No one wanted to deal with the drama.
Speaker 1: And because it's not a government, no one was paid to deal with the drama.
Speaker 0: I think the one thing that really stands out to me, actually, I don't know if this is a positive or not, is that it appears based on what we've learned that the level of just repair was so extreme, right?
Speaker 0: The fact that it took this long for it to collapse actually speaks to the original quality of the building, right?
Speaker 0: In that you had to really, really go hard on the not repair.
Speaker 1: Modern construction.
Speaker 1: And by modern, I say like after the early 70s that those nothing can short of a weird disaster or extreme negligence that exposes the rebar inside of concrete.
Speaker 1: It's almost impossible to have a building constructed with these methods collapse.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: So the point that I'm trying to make though is if anyone's afraid of their building falling down, right?
Speaker 0: Unless you are specifically aware of like, you know, some obvious damage along these lines.
Speaker 1: If I lived in Florida in a building that was built more than 20 years ago, I'd probably be afraid and want inspections immediately.
Speaker 0: I'm just saying.
Speaker 0: But if you know, if you don't go in the basement and see like a bunch of leaks and cracks and all sorts of really obvious damage, you know, and things of that nature, it's probably OK.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Oh, here's a sad money line.
Speaker 1: In April, the residents were up.
Speaker 1: Dozens of residents of the building signed a letter questioning the need for repairs and demanding a lower assessment of the price of the repairs because it would have doubled the maintenance dues they currently pay to do any of these repairs.
Speaker 0: People just care more about money than human life.
Speaker 0: That is the fundamental problem of even their own lives.
Speaker 0: Every single, every single thing, every single problem we have everywhere is because of that thing right there.
Speaker 1: But anyway, things of the day.
Speaker 1: So check this out.
Speaker 1: Emily and I hike a lot.
Speaker 1: That was one of the things we could do during the lockdowns.
Speaker 1: And we're keeping it up.
Speaker 1: And now we're going to start camping and doing a lot more like long trip, long distance backpacking and everything.
Speaker 1: If you've ever wanted to get into this kind of stuff, like I have a background of like Cub Scouts and like I camped a lot as a kid, so I had a good understanding of the basics.
Speaker 1: But of course, technology changed.
Speaker 1: Things got better.
Speaker 1: Some conventional wisdom that might have seemed common sense 20 years ago when I was doing this.
Speaker 1: Not true under modern scrutiny.
Speaker 1: So things change.
Speaker 1: So I'm doing my research, too.
Speaker 1: But if you want to get into backpacking and camping, REI, their YouTube channel is actually an A plus resource.
Speaker 1: These videos are super accurate.
Speaker 0: They're trying to sell you shit.
Speaker 0: They don't want you to.
Speaker 0: they want you to die.
Speaker 0: They want you to survive on your camping trip.
Speaker 0: Come back and buy more shit.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: But also, REI is a company I respect because REI is a co-op.
Speaker 1: That's true.
Speaker 1: Like I'm a member.
Speaker 1: REI is actually like one of the few ethical large companies out there.
Speaker 1: I say ethical with a little bit of quote because it's very hard.
Speaker 0: It's not that large.
Speaker 1: They're a pretty large company.
Speaker 1: I don't know what their market cap is.
Speaker 0: It's not small, but it's not like, you know, large.
Speaker 1: I'd say they're fairly large.
Speaker 0: At least it's way better than at least it's better than EMS that it replaced.
Speaker 1: Well, anyway, so in their channel, they have a sub, like a thread, like one of the people who hosts videos, Miranda in the Wild.
Speaker 1: That is the series to watch.
Speaker 1: This woman just talks about with a high degree of skill and knowledge and demonstrations all the different things you need to know about backcountry, camping and hiking and everything.
Speaker 1: And it's just fantastic.
Speaker 1: Like it's also utter entertainment.
Speaker 1: Like it's a great channel.
Speaker 1: I highly recommend it.
Speaker 1: The one I'm going to link to is every modern way to filter water when you're out in the wild to then safely drink it because that stuff has progressed a lot since the last time I drank water from a stream in the wild.
Speaker 1: And let me tell you, I'm never using iodine or bleach again.
Speaker 1: I'm never doing the boiling method again unless it's an emergency situation.
Speaker 1: Modern stuff is so much better.
Speaker 1: These pumps are fantastic.
Speaker 0: Cool.
Speaker 1: So what do you got?
Speaker 0: So, you know, usually when you're playing, usually a D&D or something, right?
Speaker 0: Or if you're into fantasy worlds and things of that nature, you know, medieval type stuff.
Speaker 0: You know, what's something that comes up often?
Speaker 0: Like the different jobs, right?
Speaker 0: You know, you think about blacksmiths the most, of course, but also tavern keepers, right?
Speaker 0: You know, and heralds, heralds are a big one.
Speaker 0: You know, and you know, you think about these old timey jobs from the olden days, right?
Speaker 0: Because you're going to be encountering those people on your way.
Speaker 0: You know, the ones I like to think of a lot are the coffin maker, right?
Speaker 0: The cooper, right?
Speaker 0: But one that I didn't think about really pretty much at all is the farrier, right?
Speaker 0: A farrier and rim nose from clipping bunny toes.
Speaker 0: A farrier is someone whose entire job is just clipping horse toes and horseshoes and related to only horse feet.
Speaker 0: That's their whole job.
Speaker 0: Horse feet only.
Speaker 1: Horse feet are real important to horses and the people who interact with them.
Speaker 0: Imagine being a horse and having a foot problem and there's no, and it's like you're just on wild horse.
Speaker 0: That's not a good time, right?
Speaker 0: You're really, you know, you have this really a symbiotic relationship with a human whose entire job is to handle horse feet.
Speaker 0: That's a good time.
Speaker 0: So I had never gave a thought about farriers in my whole life, but thanks to the YouTube algorithm, as soon as you watch one video of farriering, right?
Speaker 0: You're going down that well and you're seeing all kinds of stuff.
Speaker 0: So just because one person happened to link to one farrier video.
Speaker 0: Now you're seeing all kinds of, you know, horse hooving in all kinds of nonsense.
Speaker 1: I'm just thinking there was a time, this is not true anymore, but there was a time when YouTube updated their recommendation algorithm where you type in a word and it recommends words to look for where.
Speaker 1: if anyone, at least in like America, typed the word horses and hit space into YouTube, what would be recommended?
Speaker 1: The rest of that phrase for anyone was, and I'm quoting here, mating up close for a long time.
Speaker 1: That was the recommendation that was showing up for a while.
Speaker 1: It is not true anymore.
Speaker 1: Anyway.
Speaker 0: Well, that's good.
Speaker 0: So yeah, I didn't know.
Speaker 0: I didn't know jack shit about horse shoes.
Speaker 0: Other than that, you know, you generally want to protect the horse's foot.
Speaker 0: That's why they put a horseshoe on there.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And they nail it through.
Speaker 1: the, you know, especially depends on what kind of like work the horse is doing and where the horse, what the fuck do I know about horseshoes?
Speaker 0: Nothing.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Well, what do I know now?
Speaker 0: Slightly more than nothing.
Speaker 0: And I'm going to link to you the best horseshoeing video that I saw.
Speaker 0: And it's a horse that's got, you know, some foot problems.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And there's sort of obvious foot problems.
Speaker 0: Even if you're not a farrier, you can just see something ain't right with the horse's foot.
Speaker 0: It needs some help.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: So, you know, they give it a little toenail clipping, which is a rim.
Speaker 0: You should, you know, after you're watching this, you're going to be like, man, bunny toenail clippings, easy peasy.
Speaker 0: You know, that's not someone's entire career.
Speaker 1: My trip with the difficulty of bunny toe clipping the nails is that they're fragile little guys.
Speaker 1: So you can't you got you can't just manhandle them like you can.
Speaker 0: They go they go for the horse's foot.
Speaker 0: They're going with like big old files.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Like when I call the dog sales, you just like pull out a dremel and hold the dog.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: The tools they got, it's like they look like they're ready to go into like a, you know, a machine shop.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like things.
Speaker 0: But yeah, they do something really cool in this video, which is quite ingenious and was probably not possible until relatively recently.
Speaker 0: You know, they trim the horses, you know, they get the foot as nice as they can.
Speaker 0: They apply some nice, you know, medicine, I guess, horse Neosporin or whatever the equivalent is.
Speaker 0: And then, you know, you can't really put a bandaid on a horse foot.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: So what they do is they use a mold and some, you know, resin.
Speaker 0: And they squirt, they inject it into the mold and they basically create like a like an artificial like horse hoof around, you know, the real hoof.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And then they put a shoe on that.
Speaker 0: It's neat.
Speaker 0: And it's like.
Speaker 0: it's like, damn, I want to.
Speaker 0: I want to do that to my foot without the nails, not the nail part, but the other parts.
Speaker 0: It's like, I guess, without the filing off my foot part also.
Speaker 1: I did lose a toenail.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there is.
Speaker 0: If you like this video, just by watching this video, get ready for YouTube to send you down the whole of horse pedicures.
Speaker 1: The recommendations.
Speaker 1: It's already there.
Speaker 0: It's already there.
Speaker 0: It's going to be.
Speaker 0: There's a whole like, you know, you know, YouTube horse pedicure world of farriers and their works to explore, even though I'll probably, you know, maybe I'm going to ride a horse in the rest of my life.
Speaker 1: Oh, we went riding actually not too long before Covid.
Speaker 1: We went out to a wedding upstate and we went trail riding.
Speaker 1: I hadn't ridden a horse in like more than a decade.
Speaker 0: And it's unlikely I will ride a horse more than a handful of times in the rest of my life.
Speaker 1: I would like to get into.
Speaker 0: I'll probably watch more farrier videos in my life in the rest of my life than I will ride actual and I will likely never shoe a horse in my life.
Speaker 1: So so I will just point out I looked up to be sure REI, which was founded in the 30s, is a. they make three billion dollars a year.
Speaker 1: They're huge.
Speaker 0: So that's that's not huge.
Speaker 1: I mean, it's huge up to the.
Speaker 1: it's not a megacorp.
Speaker 1: It's not an Amazon.
Speaker 1: Anyway, anyway, in the meta moment, we're going to be live at PAX Online East 2021 on July 17th, which is coming up with Atari game design at one forty five p.m.
Speaker 1: on the PAX two twitch stream.
Speaker 1: We will not be live at PAX West because it is way too soon to have a convention.
Speaker 1: And with all these masking and social distancing and capacity limitations, it's going to be the first PAX we've not attended since we started attending them in 2008.
Speaker 0: I'm OK with that.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I hate to break that streak.
Speaker 1: I felt good to have that streak going for so long, but just an arbitrary streak, just some arbitrary thing, whatever.
Speaker 1: But I would like to be able to go to PAX, but it just seems like it's too soon.
Speaker 0: If they're when they're you know, it's like if you think.
Speaker 0: if they I said this before, I'm going to say keep saying it.
Speaker 0: If they think the PAX itself is not safe enough to hold in a normal fashion, you know, if you're going to hold it, of course, you need those safety precautions if you insist on holding it.
Speaker 0: But if you don't think it's safe enough to hold without those precautions, I will simply take the even safer route of not going.
Speaker 1: If you need the precautions, it's too soon.
Speaker 1: And that's how we're going to treat all conventions.
Speaker 1: So hope cautiously optimistic for PAX Unplugged.
Speaker 1: But if they require masks and rules, we're out, which will be sad, but we'll see.
Speaker 1: We're still reading the Tale of Genji.
Speaker 1: I've been reading it.
Speaker 0: I read it recently.
Speaker 1: Partly because the weather's not been great lately, so I have more time indoors.
Speaker 0: It's going to rain a lot this week.
Speaker 0: It's going to rain for like a week.
Speaker 1: Might be clear on Sunday.
Speaker 1: Somewhat clear on Sunday.
Speaker 1: Maybe.
Speaker 1: We'll see.
Speaker 0: Monday's the day.
Speaker 1: Monday will be the biking day.
Speaker 1: Maybe the beach day.
Speaker 1: We'll see.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so we're reading the Tale of Genji.
Speaker 1: Genji continues to just kind of just close his eyes and squint at things and not worry too much and just split through life.
Speaker 1: Causing problems.
Speaker 1: Reminds me a lot.
Speaker 1: Solving problems sometimes.
Speaker 1: Mostly just causing problems and not noticing he's caused them.
Speaker 0: What's the one?
Speaker 0: The Rothfuss one?
Speaker 1: Oh, the Kingkiller Chronicle.
Speaker 0: It reminds me a little bit of that.
Speaker 1: I can see that.
Speaker 0: I gotta say, there's a little bit of commonality.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Only without the fantasy magic part, obviously.
Speaker 1: I do feel a little bit.
Speaker 1: the, you know, the path of least resistance is the path of least resistance.
Speaker 1: So it's hard to fault Genji for following that path most of the time.
Speaker 1: But well, we'll talk about it when we talk about the book, but we're reading it and you should read it too.
Speaker 1: It's the first goddamn novel ever.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: There were novels before that.
Speaker 1: So, uh, Balan.
Speaker 0: Mm hmm.
Speaker 1: I mean, I'm going to put I'm going to put the closing music there and then we'll come back to the show.
Speaker 1: This has been Ignite with Rym and Scott.
Speaker 1: It's moderately funny.
Speaker 1: I think the listener will find that a little bit funny.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 0: So Rym just told me the joke he inserted into this.
Speaker 0: I don't think it's that funny.
Speaker 1: If you think that joke was funny at all, tweet.
Speaker 1: I'll tell him that that joke was funny.
Speaker 0: Sure.
Speaker 0: So basically earlier in life.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: I was we weren't wise in our ways.
Speaker 0: And there were often be situations where, like, you know, you start doing something and due to social pressure or custom or psychology or whatever have you, you sort of feel like, you know, you don't even consider escaping.
Speaker 0: It's like you're in and you're in.
Speaker 0: It's like, I guess I'm doing this now.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: You're not even like thinking about it.
Speaker 0: You're just sort of not.
Speaker 0: you're just doing the thing you set out to do.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: For example, when we went to New York City to go see Shigeru Miyamoto, we waited in line at the Nintendo store half the day.
Speaker 0: We didn't see him.
Speaker 0: And then we went home.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Well, there was a Geek Nights episode about that, I think.
Speaker 1: God, that was a long time ago.
Speaker 0: We could have.
Speaker 0: And it would have been wiser for us to realize the truth, which is that so many people were cutting in line in front of us.
Speaker 0: We were waiting so long.
Speaker 0: They weren't letting us in.
Speaker 0: There was so little information.
Speaker 0: You know, there was going to be a strict limit on the whole thing.
Speaker 0: It was easy to see that we were never going to get in those doors.
Speaker 0: We were not close enough to the front.
Speaker 0: And we would have been able to save time in our lives by simply getting out of that line and going home hours earlier and not wasting a day.
Speaker 0: We could have gone and done something else.
Speaker 1: My moment growing up like I like I had a thing and I think this is a sentiment a lot of people seem to have of if I start reading a book, I'm going to finish it.
Speaker 1: And I remember as a kid for the first time, I started reading a book and I got like the deep way into it.
Speaker 1: And then I made the conscious decision to not read the rest of it because that book sucked.
Speaker 1: And that was like a moderate revelation for me that, oh, I can't I could just stop.
Speaker 1: I don't have to follow through on something that sucks.
Speaker 0: Right now, it's a little tricky because I sort of also have the opposite problem, right, which is something I really do honestly want to finish.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: You're working on a thing you want to work on.
Speaker 0: You know, maybe some podcast or maybe, you know, maybe you're making something right.
Speaker 0: You want to do this and you just can't finish it.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: So it's like and it's you can't even get yourself to work on it.
Speaker 0: It's like the opposite problem.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: You can't get in.
Speaker 0: You want to get over the finish line, but you can't finish.
Speaker 0: So because you have that problem when you're in a situation where you're headed towards the finish line and it's like you don't want to bail.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: You sort of can get the mix.
Speaker 0: You really have to evaluate is that, you know, look at what you're in for.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Are you stuck?
Speaker 0: Are you staying just because you think you have to stay?
Speaker 0: Are you enjoying yourself?
Speaker 0: Is this really what you want?
Speaker 0: And, you know, be able to strongly commit or quit as soon as possible.
Speaker 0: That's that's the longer you go.
Speaker 1: You got to make that decision.
Speaker 0: And it's really not.
Speaker 1: it's not easy because otherwise you fall in the sunk cost fallacy.
Speaker 1: Like, well, I've been standing here for four hours.
Speaker 1: I might as well stick around because there's a chance that Miyamoto is going to sign myself a two cartridge.
Speaker 1: But the reality was the chance was so low.
Speaker 1: If you and the longer you wait before you bail, the more cost you have paid in time or money or energy or something.
Speaker 1: And the outcome was the same.
Speaker 1: So if there's even a chance you're going to bail on something, you've got to make that decision.
Speaker 1: ASAP.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: The sooner you bail, if bailing was the right choice, the sooner you bail, the better off you are.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: If you wait 10 more minutes and then bail, well, you just lost those 10 minutes.
Speaker 0: You could have just decided the same thing earlier.
Speaker 1: Now, I remember RIT because this problem happened a lot.
Speaker 1: Like, I'm not going to try to get into all the different anecdotes, but where we would decide to do something as a group, it kind of sucked.
Speaker 1: Or like one person really wanted to do something.
Speaker 1: The rest of us weren't super into it.
Speaker 1: We go along with it anyway.
Speaker 1: It's actually not great.
Speaker 1: We all stick around.
Speaker 1: And there was an episode, I guess, South Park came up again.
Speaker 1: The trifecta will come when it comes up a third time around that time.
Speaker 1: And when we used to be watching South Park, an episode dropped the return of the Fellowship of the Ring of the Two Towers or whatever.
Speaker 1: And in that episode, a character has a moment where he learns the truth about his situation.
Speaker 1: He walks out and he makes his hand gesture and he's just like, I'm out.
Speaker 1: And they're like, what?
Speaker 1: And he's just like, I'm out.
Speaker 1: And then he leaves and that's it.
Speaker 1: And at RIT, Scott and I very consciously made the decision to make that a thing in our group.
Speaker 1: We started to, whenever we had two things, we'd either bail by saying, I'm out.
Speaker 1: Like, we're done.
Speaker 1: This is over.
Speaker 1: Or it's all you.
Speaker 1: Where if we chose not to bail, whoever was the person who was advocating for not bailing, it's all you means you are now responsible for any misery that follows.
Speaker 1: But if you are correct and our instinct to bail was wrong, you get all the glory.
Speaker 1: You were the one who got us this experience.
Speaker 1: I don't think anyone ever was the.
Speaker 1: it's all you.
Speaker 1: And it was good for them in the long run.
Speaker 0: You're usually the all you.
Speaker 0: It's usually all you.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: And a lot of the things that we tried to do did not work out so great.
Speaker 1: But we became like especially like I have a very well-known among my friends.
Speaker 1: My bail tolerance is like a hair trigger.
Speaker 1: Like, you know, I'm walking to a Starbucks and there's more than one person in line.
Speaker 1: I just walk right back out.
Speaker 0: Your bail tolerance has gone to the extreme in the other direction.
Speaker 0: A little too far.
Speaker 0: You got to bring it back.
Speaker 0: You know, it's like they'll be sick.
Speaker 0: It's like, yeah, if I'm going to a restaurant and it's way full and there's people just packed out front, it's like, OK, we're not waiting to eat here.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: But there'll be a place with like, you know, it's full.
Speaker 0: There's like one group waiting in front of us and we'll be like bail.
Speaker 0: And I'm like, there's one group.
Speaker 0: We're going to be sitting in like 15, 20 hours.
Speaker 1: But I've been in situations where that delicious food is here.
Speaker 0: It's going to be what I've been in situations in front of us.
Speaker 1: Like, fuck you, Sukkotai, where there was an open table and they told us 15 minutes multiple times over the course of an hour and did not give us a table.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: But at that point, it's like, yeah, if I see the open table and then I wait 10 minutes and if they don't give it to me when I ask, then I bail.
Speaker 0: But you're you're at the point where you're bailing.
Speaker 0: Like you walk in, you'll take you'll like take a snapshot of the scene and then leave.
Speaker 1: It's like, give it 30 seconds.
Speaker 1: I think part of what part of what happened there is.
Speaker 1: I do this particularly with restaurants.
Speaker 1: And I think it's an artifact of living in New York, especially in a neighborhood full of great restaurants for so long, that if there is even the slightest bit of resistance walking into a restaurant that I like, there are 10 other restaurants I like just as much within a 15 second walk of that door.
Speaker 0: I think another problem is that with restaurants specifically, right, if you are currently looking for a restaurant, you are hungry.
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 1: And hungry is just a few minutes away from hangry.
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 0: So you're less tolerant of waiting in that situation.
Speaker 1: If I'm hungry, I will go from let's eat at this restaurant to.
Speaker 1: I'm just going to buy four Gatorades from this deli.
Speaker 1: And that is my dinner.
Speaker 1: I will bail two Gatorades and stickers like faster than I will wait an hour to sit down at a restaurant.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: So don't bail that as much as rim is bailing.
Speaker 0: But there are plenty of situations, you know, most notably, I think, is, you know, the tabletop game is the one we bring up all the time.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: You if you're playing a tabletop game with people, you sort of have this obligation that like you're not supposed to quit.
Speaker 0: It's like even if you've already lost, if the game is over, if you're not having a good time, if one of the other people sucks as a jerk, if people are playing slowly, if you have to go, you know, to somewhere legitimately, there's this sort of social obligation that like you feel like you can't leave.
Speaker 0: You have to stay.
Speaker 0: It's like, no, you absolutely can leave.
Speaker 0: Even if the other people are upset, you can leave.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: You should leave.
Speaker 0: If you have any reason whatsoever to leave, leave.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Well, the way the way I actually look at that with games in particular, like a board game is there's like there's different like there's the mood where, say, five people are playing a game.
Speaker 1: One person is not having a great time, but they committed to playing.
Speaker 1: the game is a moderately different situation from something I see very commonly where nobody is having a good time.
Speaker 1: Literally no one in the game is having a good time.
Speaker 0: In either situation, either the one, you know, in the first situation, the one person should bail.
Speaker 0: In the second situation, everyone should collectively be like, yeah, you know, I don't want to play anymore.
Speaker 0: And everyone will say, yeah, you know what?
Speaker 0: We all don't want to play anymore.
Speaker 0: Just put it away.
Speaker 0: But the one I see the most common is... Bailing is the solution either way.
Speaker 1: The one I see the most in most common in board games is one person is having a good time.
Speaker 1: The rest of the table is not.
Speaker 1: And usually the person who's having a good time, the bail wasn't during the game was actually too late to bail.
Speaker 1: The problem is actually that all the people in that game agreed to play the game in the first place, but didn't actually want to.
Speaker 1: They foresaw this situation, but they went along with it anyway, and then they reaped exactly what they sowed.
Speaker 1: Usually the person who's having a good time is the person who is aggressively trying to recruit people to play that game.
Speaker 1: Like, not the third South Park.
Speaker 1: Another relevant South Park episode.
Speaker 1: The zip lining.
Speaker 1: Where one person aggressively convinced other people to do the thing that sucked that no one liked.
Speaker 1: Be wary of anyone who is aggressively selling you on playing a board game with them at a convention.
Speaker 1: There is a reason why they are trying so hard.
Speaker 0: I always find it interesting, there's so many overeager people who really want to do something.
Speaker 0: But those overeager people can't all find each other to form a group of overeager people.
Speaker 1: Oh, I've seen.
Speaker 1: I swear.
Speaker 0: That would be the perfect scenario for those people, but they somehow can't make it happen.
Speaker 1: So one thing that happens is sometimes those people overlap a little bit with that guy.
Speaker 1: And the only thing that that guy hates more than being excluded is being included by another that guy.
Speaker 1: But in terms of the games, not to get into that topic, I feel like usually what happens is those people are all really jazzed about different games.
Speaker 0: That can happen.
Speaker 0: So if your friends want to go walking up a mountain and every single friend is going up the mountain, and you don't like going up the mountain, you can just stay home like I did.
Speaker 0: You don't have to go.
Speaker 0: No one's making you go.
Speaker 0: And look, those people are still my friend, I think.
Speaker 1: I guess when it comes down to it.
Speaker 0: They still see me.
Speaker 0: They still talk to me.
Speaker 1: In terms of practical advice, you have to think about whatever.
Speaker 1: there's a thing you could do, you need to actively think.
Speaker 1: Don't just go along or don't just passively think.
Speaker 1: Like, actively interrogate yourself.
Speaker 1: This is literal introspection.
Speaker 1: Do I want to do this?
Speaker 1: What do I expect this to be like?
Speaker 1: What is the likelihood that my expectations will match reality?
Speaker 1: And what are the expectations of the people around me?
Speaker 1: Actually, seriously try to articulate the answers to those questions.
Speaker 1: Because I see so many times, and part of the reason why I bail so readily on things is in the past.
Speaker 1: There were many situations.
Speaker 1: There was a road trip that was the second worst road trip I've ever been on in my life.
Speaker 1: Huge disaster this whole trip.
Speaker 1: Not that the worst one was the one you and I went on together.
Speaker 1: With the ticket and the bad food and all that situation.
Speaker 1: But the second worst one, I foresaw that it was going to be a terrible road trip.
Speaker 1: I looked at this trip and I thought, wow, this is going to go wrong, this is going to go wrong, this is going to go wrong.
Speaker 1: There's no way this could be successful.
Speaker 1: But I decided against my own better nature to go along with it and be optimistic.
Speaker 1: Maybe it'll be better, maybe it'll be okay.
Speaker 1: And it was very much as the trip progressed, like by the second day, it was an open the envelope Lisa situation.
Speaker 1: As everything that I'd predicted had become true, the foretold had happened, the prophecy was fulfilled.
Speaker 0: So other things, right, is I want to, you know, a little more serious, right?
Speaker 0: Is you're talking about things like games and whatnot?
Speaker 0: is like you can bail, right?
Speaker 0: It is an option, at least, you know, at least if you're listening to this podcast, it's likely an option for you to bail on things that are like really serious.
Speaker 0: And you wouldn't normally think you could bail on.
Speaker 0: It's like your family has met for Thanksgiving every single year, your whole life, it's an automatic.
Speaker 0: You don't have to go to that.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: No, there might be consequences.
Speaker 1: There might be fine.
Speaker 0: You might want to.
Speaker 0: Sure, there might be consequences for not going like.
Speaker 0: maybe someone's mad at you and your family.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: But if you don't have a good time doing it, you don't have to fucking go.
Speaker 0: You could you you can do something else.
Speaker 0: You don't have to do that.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: You need to.
Speaker 0: And I think you just even consider some people don't even consider that it's like that's an option, but it's always an option to not go.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: You know, it's like school.
Speaker 0: You don't have to go to that.
Speaker 0: There is consequences, but you don't have to work.
Speaker 1: I will say there are.
Speaker 0: you can just quit your job.
Speaker 0: There are consequences.
Speaker 0: Some people are in a way better position and can do that more readily than other people.
Speaker 0: But if the shittier your job is, the lower paying and worse treated that you are at the job, you know, depending on where you live and your other situations in life, it might be easier.
Speaker 0: You know, don't quit if you need the money.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Don't quit before you find a new one.
Speaker 0: But you can.
Speaker 0: probably the worse the job is, it's might the easier it is to get over that bar and find something at least a little better.
Speaker 0: It might still be shitty.
Speaker 0: But, you know, so it's like you can quit.
Speaker 0: You know, don't just stay in your job because you got some routine or something.
Speaker 1: Well, part of what the part of the with in terms of real things is it comes down to to have you made affirmative commitments or not, because it's a very different situation.
Speaker 1: If Scott was like, hey, let's go, I don't know, something you'd want to do that I wouldn't give a shit about.
Speaker 1: Let's go to this net runner and Gundam making convention not to do panels.
Speaker 1: We're just going to show up.
Speaker 1: We're going to do a meet and greet.
Speaker 1: And then we're just going to be at this con after that.
Speaker 1: Like, I'm not going to be super into that.
Speaker 1: But if we commit, like geek nights is going to be at this con.
Speaker 1: I can't bail on that.
Speaker 1: Like I can bail on that.
Speaker 1: But you generally should.
Speaker 1: if you make a commitment, you should stick to that commitment or don't make the commitment in the first place or be honest about it.
Speaker 1: Like if Scott invited that con and I was like and maybe I don't bail yet.
Speaker 1: Maybe I don't say no.
Speaker 1: Maybe I say I'm not sure I need to decide.
Speaker 1: when do I need to make the decision by those.
Speaker 1: Those are the conversations to have.
Speaker 1: We have.
Speaker 1: I've gone to cons that I would have bailed on, but I'd signed a contract to go to that one car that we signed a contract to go to.
Speaker 0: that we could have.
Speaker 1: We could have bailed out if we'd known in advance.
Speaker 0: There are definitely things where you cross a line of no return.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And there is sometimes there's a return with it with a valid reason.
Speaker 1: Well, like, hey, I'm going to come to your wedding.
Speaker 1: Hey, I can't come to your wedding.
Speaker 1: I broke both my legs this morning.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: That's a good one.
Speaker 1: Or I accidentally scheduled my own wedding that same day and didn't tell anyone.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Or it's like, hey, let's start a family and make babies together.
Speaker 0: Actually, I'm going to just run away.
Speaker 1: It's like, you know, that's what I was going to bring up earlier.
Speaker 1: If you can just bail on anything like that, just bail on, I don't know, kids.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: It's like, you know, there are ways, you know, to go about, you know, you've crossed the line of no return.
Speaker 0: There are ways to, you know, divorce and do whatever, you know, in a way that is, you know, healthy.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And does not cause lots of damage and whatnot to other human beings.
Speaker 1: Well, like if we had to bail on a convention we'd committed to for a valid reason or even an invalid reason.
Speaker 0: We promised you'd come to a convention, but a pandemic happened.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: Like, here's a formal email.
Speaker 0: A tornado hit my house.
Speaker 1: Like, here's here is why we're not coming.
Speaker 1: Here's the situation.
Speaker 1: Let's discuss alternative.
Speaker 1: Like there's there's a whole.
Speaker 1: or like another example, esports, like don't quit a game, right?
Speaker 1: If I just play Overwatch, I go to a random casual mode and then I just I'm bored and I just quit.
Speaker 1: Like, sure, that doesn't impact other people that much.
Speaker 1: And I didn't commit that much.
Speaker 1: I was playing in the random mode anyway.
Speaker 1: But if I affirmatively choose to join the competitive queue to play a competitive game, there is an implicit contract that I agree to finish the game I get put in.
Speaker 1: So it's a materially different situation to bail on that competitive game because I knew going in what I was committing to.
Speaker 1: But I feel like generally people should bail more often than they do.
Speaker 1: I feel like a lot of people choose not to bail on things either out of misplaced senses of commitment or more often misplaced optimism about how that thing will go down.
Speaker 0: Or misplaced or misinterpreted obligation or false obligation.
Speaker 0: For example, let's say you're at work, right?
Speaker 0: I'm not going to talk about quitting work anymore.
Speaker 0: Let's say you're at work and someone puts a meeting on your calendar.
Speaker 0: You know, it's and it's a boss.
Speaker 0: A boss puts a meeting on your calendar.
Speaker 0: You can say, no, you don't you don't have to go.
Speaker 0: It's like too many meetings.
Speaker 0: You know, you don't even need an excuse.
Speaker 0: You can just say like, no, I'm not going to that meeting.
Speaker 0: I can't go.
Speaker 0: No one's going to make you.
Speaker 0: No one's probably not going to fire you right for something like that.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: It's like you don't got to go.
Speaker 0: You know, someone says, hey, you know, you say you're working at the office and it comes around.
Speaker 0: It's like five o'clock and someone comes up and is like, hey, we got this thing we got to do.
Speaker 0: You can be like, you know, not to quit.
Speaker 0: You might get fired depending on how shitty your job is.
Speaker 0: But, you know, if they say, hey, can you do this one more thing?
Speaker 0: You can be like, no, I'm good.
Speaker 0: It's five o'clock.
Speaker 0: I got to go home.
Speaker 0: I got to go.
Speaker 0: My kid's going to be home.
Speaker 0: I got to you know, I got stuff to do.
Speaker 0: I got to cook food.
Speaker 0: See, you know, you got to deal with that.
Speaker 0: That's not my problem.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: But the optimism thing is pressured into doing something you don't got to do.
Speaker 0: Don't make it you know, don't make yourself feel like you must do something that you must not do.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Of course, you know, accurately evaluate the real consequences.
Speaker 0: You know, some people, I think, imagine consequences that aren't real or imagine consequences to be worse than what they might really be.
Speaker 0: It's like, yeah, OK.
Speaker 0: You know, at your job, there might be a shitty.
Speaker 0: There are definitely shitty jobs out there where someone will just fire you for just going home at the hour you're supposed to go home instead of doing the extra work.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: But is that really what's going to happen?
Speaker 0: Is someone maybe going to come to you tomorrow and give you a stir in talking to like, hey, why didn't you do that thing?
Speaker 0: You're not a team player.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: It's like, well, could you just, you know, quietly hear them say that and say sorry and you still have your job.
Speaker 0: So someone gives you a bad evaluation at work.
Speaker 0: That could happen.
Speaker 0: It's like, do you still have your job?
Speaker 0: Do you care?
Speaker 0: It's just a piece of paper.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: With a with a thing on it.
Speaker 0: It's like, do you care about that?
Speaker 0: Maybe you do care about that.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: But I don't.
Speaker 0: So it's like you had to consider what are the real consequences.
Speaker 0: Are you willing to suffer them?
Speaker 0: Are they really that bad?
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Sometimes it's hard to realistically predict consequences.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: But, you know, maybe you can just ask.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: If someone says, hey, you want to do this, stay late and do this work and be like, well, what what if it doesn't get done?
Speaker 0: What will happen?
Speaker 0: Just ask, you know, honestly be like, hey, what what will happen if we just let that go till tomorrow?
Speaker 0: Is that consequence really that bad?
Speaker 0: You know, because if I stay and do it, here's what's going to happen to my life.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 1: And it also gets complicated by what your goals are.
Speaker 1: So Geek Nights, we bailed on a few shows recently just because we can finally see some of our friends together.
Speaker 1: And like that's a that's a laser that I need to.
Speaker 1: it's been charging for over a year.
Speaker 1: Like that is a higher priority in my life than doing some individual Geek Nights episode.
Speaker 1: But at the same time, when we started Geek Nights, we agreed that we would try not to bail and do the Penny Arcade model of just crank the show out no matter what, even if it sucks.
Speaker 1: And that's how we'll force ourselves to get better.
Speaker 0: So we'd try to cross.
Speaker 0: Let me cross the line of where it's not a problem anymore.
Speaker 1: But we do try not to bail on the show unless we have a good reason.
Speaker 1: But if we have a good reason, like Scott and I will discuss, like, hey, should we bail on the show?
Speaker 1: And we we like we try to make that decision immediately.
Speaker 1: Like if we're going to bail on a show, we make the decision as early as possible.
Speaker 1: That's we're not going to show that day.
Speaker 1: We don't even worry about it.
Speaker 1: We walk away.
Speaker 1: We're fine.
Speaker 0: But there's no consequences for not doing a Geek Nights episode.
Speaker 1: But putting that pressure on ourselves to not bail early on was a very powerful tool to make us get good in a hurry.
Speaker 1: And there are pros and cons to that.
Speaker 1: But the fact that we chose it and we could have bailed, we chose not to.
Speaker 0: You could just bail on the whole show.
Speaker 0: We could just never do any Internet stuff again.
Speaker 0: We could just be like, bye, delete all social media.
Speaker 0: We could do it right now.
Speaker 0: Delete website.
Speaker 0: I could just turn everything off in like two seconds.
Speaker 0: It would be really quick.
Speaker 1: But no, instead, we're weird nerds.
Speaker 1: And so unlike every other website, even if you link to Geek Nights in like 2006, those links probably still work.
Speaker 0: They will definitely work.
Speaker 0: I guarantee it.
Speaker 1: And I think we've gone on.
Speaker 1: For a show talking about bailing, we've gone on longer than a normal episode of Geek Nights.
Speaker 1: So I think this is a good point to wrap up.
Speaker 0: We haven't done a show in a while, so we made up for the previous two or three shows we didn't do.
Speaker 1: And we'll be on a semi-regular schedule as time goes on.
Speaker 1: But for now, this has been Geek Nights with Rim and Scott.
Speaker 1: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design, and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at FrontRowCrew.com for show notes, discussion news, and more.
Speaker 1: Remember, Geek Nights is not one, but four different shows.
Speaker 1: Sci-Tech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays, and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 0: Geek Nights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 0: Geek Nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 0: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.
Speaker 1: And the Patreon patrons for this episode of Geek Nights are Heidi McNicholallen, Joyce Link, E.G, Dread, Lily Tenebrae, Chris Reimer, Clinton Walton, JustLikeADudeGuy, KshayaYa85, Programmed, Throwed, Openspeed, UndertakeLaw, Adoption Pierce, Absorb, Rebecca Dunn, Revue, Madbull34, Howards, Ryan Perrin, Sam Erickson, Shervin Von Harl, Taylor Braun, You Old, The Key To My Heart, and a bunch of people who do not want me to say their names.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we bailed on the show on Tuesday, so I figured we'd do a show on bailin', but you won't see us bailin' that much.
Speaker 1: And you're gonna see a lot of Geek Nights streams, you're gonna see a pretty relatively faster turnaround time on Roomly Reviews and the whole Disney show.
Speaker 1: You're gonna see a few of those that we're gonna queue up in the immediate future.
Speaker 1: But for now, I leave you with...
Speaker 0: I'm gonna eat chips for lunch.
Speaker 1: Spicy chips.
Speaker 0: Spicy chips.
Speaker 0: Mmm, spicy chips.
Speaker 1: Ooh, they make me gassy.
Speaker 1: But I love spicy chips.
Speaker 1: Are you eating chips for lunch again?
Speaker 0: No.