Speaker 1: It's Wednesday, July 7th, 2021.
Speaker 1: I'm rim.
Speaker 1: I'm Scott and this is geek nights.
Speaker 1: tonight We are reviewing the phenomenal odd taxi.
Speaker 0: Let's do this All right, so a few months ago, I guess my dishwasher is making a noise still washing.
Speaker 0: It was washing the dishes perfectly, but it was making a noise, right?
Speaker 0: So I put in a repair request of the building like you do with the app.
Speaker 0: That's our fans.
Speaker 1: Oh, you have an app.
Speaker 1: I just have to go.
Speaker 1: I have to get literally go down and talk to the doorman And then they'll usually hand me this special piece of paper like a carbon copy for but I got to fill out the form.
Speaker 0: Anyway, we got an app.
Speaker 0: So we also have an app that tells us when packages come in all kinds of stuff.
Speaker 0: They have an app Marion.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we do So.
Speaker 0: then what happened is the day they actually got a dishwasher repairman like they like, okay The person's coming and I'm like, okay and no and it definitely didn't make the noise.
Speaker 0: now The day before the person came the noise went away, so I said listen the noise went away You don't bother me, right?
Speaker 0: So they said okay, they cancelled it.
Speaker 1: It brought the noise back.
Speaker 1: That's how this works.
Speaker 0: Yeah, of course, it's obvious right.
Speaker 0: a couple weeks later noise comes back.
Speaker 0: So I finally put in a repair request and so today they said they said oh, we're gonna come look at it tomorrow.
Speaker 0: So I said they're like, what time should we come?
Speaker 0: I'm like anytime, you know, whenever.
Speaker 0: of course today the super comes at 9 a.m.
Speaker 0: Sharp, I'm like, all right I said anytime come on in but Like at work.
Speaker 1: if someone says if I ask hey when can I schedule this meeting?
Speaker 0: and they say anytime That means anytime I'm like, all right, at least you're here.
Speaker 0: I'm not gonna turn you away.
Speaker 0: coming in check out the dishwasher You know, it made the noise.
Speaker 0: it reproduced its noise.
Speaker 0: nice They basically I think all they really did was like just open it all up and clean it out and close it again.
Speaker 0: I haven't it.
Speaker 0: they got it to go.
Speaker 0: then they we didn't test the full cycle of it because that you know.
Speaker 0: I got to get some dirty dishes and whatnot, but it didn't make the noise on the first cycle anymore.
Speaker 0: It made a different noise.
Speaker 0: So I guess that's an improvement.
Speaker 0: Yeah We'll find out when I actually.
Speaker 1: I guess the problem is you're not as much enough nor am I of a dishwasher expert to know If the new noise is better worse the same like.
Speaker 1: think about all the noise.
Speaker 1: I'll know for sure.
Speaker 0: I'll know.
Speaker 0: I think the noise it was making was a little weird because it was when they when they when we tested it It was completely empty of everything.
Speaker 0: No racks.
Speaker 0: No dishes.
Speaker 0: So the water was like loud against the edges of the dishwasher, right but anyway, the Interesting part right was not.
Speaker 0: you know, this minor dishwasher maintenance is that I learned a few things.
Speaker 0: number one I didn't know that if the dishwasher is like, you know There's no way to like skip cycles and just make it do whatever you want.
Speaker 0: But if it's in the middle of washing apparently you can just push the start button a whole bunch.
Speaker 0: It'll drain all the water out.
Speaker 1: I told you that when you complained about the noise on geek nights multiple times I explained that procedure.
Speaker 1: That's the quick way to test if there's a problem with the dishwasher.
Speaker 0: Well, anyway, the second thing is that in my kitchen, right?
Speaker 0: You know, yeah cabinets, right and there's a space between the cabinet and the floor, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, and usually there's some sort of like, you know, I don't know what you call it right like a piece of welding.
Speaker 0: Yeah, yeah, just a flat thing underneath, you know, so that you like, you know, isn't just a gaping space underneath the cabinets.
Speaker 0: So ours, I guess there's like a piece of metal.
Speaker 0: It's like all shiny.
Speaker 1: Yeah, our dishwasher has a piece of metal there.
Speaker 0: Well, I mean our whole.
Speaker 0: it's not our dishwasher.
Speaker 0: It's the entire kitchen.
Speaker 1: I just have like one down there except for the dishwasher is the dishwasher has its own Piece of metal that goes in that the refrigerator has its own piece of plastic.
Speaker 0: But the entire kitchen other than the oven which goes all the way to the floor is ours is on the floor There's.
Speaker 1: no there's nothing down there.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but the under the cabinets there is just a piece of metal that just goes all the way around with a space where the Oven is interesting.
Speaker 0: they just reached in as soon when they came and they just grabbed it and yanked it off.
Speaker 0: and I'm like I didn't know.
Speaker 0: I thought it was like part of the cabin.
Speaker 0: It was just a big sheet of plastic with that shiny on one side and had three and there were three claws on it And the claw.
Speaker 0: the cabinets had feet like little like adjustable feet and the claws were just clipped onto the feet and as a whole world underneath the cabinets of filth and I was like Fucking.
Speaker 0: tell me that I could have been cleaning under there this whole time.
Speaker 0: Look how disgusting it is.
Speaker 1: Clean under there store stuff under there.
Speaker 1: It's in New York any space counts.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Well, yeah So a I got this new space in my apartment.
Speaker 1: I just increased my square footage But I know what I would put under there the sleep mats for camping cuz you got to leave them unrolled or they get shitty.
Speaker 0: well be Now I can clean under there.
Speaker 0: But see now I have to clean under there.
Speaker 1: You know you could do when that when the when the plastics back in place just never speak of it again.
Speaker 0: Well, no now I know how to take it off.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but I'm saying you don't have this terrible gnosis.
Speaker 1: Walk away just if anyone's like what's under there.
Speaker 1: you're like a nothing nobody knows You know.
Speaker 0: just to wrap up the anecdote.
Speaker 0: so there we have these in the bathrooms.
Speaker 0: we have these floor heaters, right?
Speaker 0: We've never.
Speaker 0: we've never used them in theory.
Speaker 0: They could be nice, right?
Speaker 0: It's like you.
Speaker 0: imagine the cold bathroom floor.
Speaker 1: turning on see the problem is our building is so warm from its natural Business that the bathroom floor is always warm.
Speaker 0: I've never needed them, right?
Speaker 0: We've never turned them.
Speaker 1: Those are the guys that you want in like a house that has on a motor hotel or something.
Speaker 0: So they're there.
Speaker 0: but we never use them ever not even once.
Speaker 0: but the one that's in one of the bathrooms Right doesn't actually work.
Speaker 0: It's supposed to like show a clock.
Speaker 0: It shows an error message.
Speaker 0: Uh-huh So I'm like, oh while you're here come look at this error message and he's like, do you actually use this?
Speaker 0: And I'm like no.
Speaker 0: and he's like, yeah, you really shouldn't use it.
Speaker 0: There's no reason to you have a floor mat in there.
Speaker 0: It's like the floor is never cold.
Speaker 0: What the fuck do you need this for?
Speaker 0: Yeah, it just wasted.
Speaker 0: He's just like it'll just waste a lot of electricity and cost you money.
Speaker 0: and yeah, that's a piece of shit.
Speaker 0: Just ignore it.
Speaker 0: and he's like, don't worry.
Speaker 0: He won't charge you if you move out and I'm like, I'm not moving out.
Speaker 1: That's good to know.
Speaker 0: He also was very amazed.
Speaker 0: The watermelon knife was out and he was like, what's that knife for?
Speaker 0: I'm like watermelon.
Speaker 0: He thought that was really great.
Speaker 0: He was amused at my watermelon.
Speaker 1: Yeah Yeah, one time we had someone coming into a maintenance at an air conditioner and they were real excited about all the audio equipment.
Speaker 1: Here I was explaining like oh, yeah, that's the microphone I use for the podcast and that's a different kind of microphone And these two microphones work different ways.
Speaker 1: and I ended that guy doesn't work at our building anymore But I later on I ended up giving him the old geek night's mixer as a gift.
Speaker 0: Cuz I'll buy a watermelon knife for the super.
Speaker 1: Yeah So, uh in that there's a bunch of news we'll talk about some of these briefly some of them longer than others, but One little one.
Speaker 1: Scott told me about this and I know more about it than him because I skimmed an article.
Speaker 0: Whoa, all I heard was a rumor and I was like, oh I heard this I heard this rumor whisper.
Speaker 0: That sounds true Let me just mention it.
Speaker 0: and barely rim found more information.
Speaker 1: Yeah So that the article is titled after years on a weird island the x-men are finally superheroes again and I click on this.
Speaker 1: and what I see?
Speaker 1: because usually if I see an x-men comic and this has been for like most of My adult life.
Speaker 1: I don't know what the fuck is going on on that cover.
Speaker 1: I don't recognize half those characters But I look at this and it looks like the x-men that I know I see a Wolverine.
Speaker 1: It's a lady Wolverine, but it's a Wolverine.
Speaker 1: It's a superhero comic.
Speaker 1: So it's very obvious It's a lady Wolverine, but I digress.
Speaker 1: there's.
Speaker 1: I see a rogue.
Speaker 1: the rogue looks like the rogue.
Speaker 1: I know I see an old-school Jean Grey.
Speaker 1: I see a Cyclops with a normal Cyclops shit going on It just it looks like the x-men.
Speaker 1: I have not seen a man that looked like the x-men in a long time and it's x-men number one.
Speaker 0: Yep, I asked me how many x-men number ones are there?
Speaker 0: right so many.
Speaker 0: that would be a good tribute number one.
Speaker 1: I would be a good tribute.
Speaker 1: question.
Speaker 0: X-men number one.
Speaker 0: ultimate x-men number one get everyone to raise their hands.
Speaker 1: How many x-men number ones are there in the history of the x-men?
Speaker 0: Yeah But yeah, apparently, you know x-men comics I know that.
Speaker 0: you know, some people have said that they're.
Speaker 0: they have been doing interesting stuff lately Even though I haven't read one in for fucking ever right or at least I've read ones recently.
Speaker 0: But they were old ones whoever I haven't read a new one.
Speaker 1: Oh, wow, apparently this the weird island stuff is going on for like two years.
Speaker 1: I guess they were all living.
Speaker 1: Yeah, all the mutants are on the island of Krakow.
Speaker 0: It was all this weird stuff going on.
Speaker 0: I think there were even vampires at one point.
Speaker 0: I don't know when that was.
Speaker 0: someone's probably gonna tell me is five years ago.
Speaker 1: There's been like three different times where there were vampires, but I feel like one of those was a what-if.
Speaker 0: But and there was.
Speaker 0: there was a sword thing.
Speaker 0: I think right sort of thing.
Speaker 0: It was an x-men sword thing.
Speaker 0: I don't know what the details are.
Speaker 0: But apparently just today's Wednesday, which means new comic book day And so x-men number one, I believe came out today and it's the most Normal what you expect x-men to be x-men Based on what I've heard.
Speaker 0: I haven't read it in a long time.
Speaker 0: So if you're someone who likes x-men Maybe now's the time for x-men I'm.
Speaker 0: what I think I'm gonna do is I'm gonna wait six to twelve months and buy the trade of X-men number one through six.
Speaker 1: All right, so they have a note here in the article.
Speaker 1: there is there any required reading.
Speaker 1: all of the X titles are heavily connected, but X-men number one is an accessible introduction that doesn't get bogged down in this big thing.
Speaker 0: Okay, so it's it's one, you know, these times come around now and then right.
Speaker 0: so now is one of those times.
Speaker 0: Last month's your shot.
Speaker 1: x-men number 21 featured the debut of the new x-men team at the Hellfire Gala apparently and The team responsible for this new x-men number one was responsible for planet x-men number one.
Speaker 0: You know, I like a space x-men.
Speaker 0: that's how the best x-men is in space.
Speaker 1: it is planet x-men space.
Speaker 1: Oh planet size x-men number one.
Speaker 1: Sorry.
Speaker 0: I don't fucking know.
Speaker 0: I just assumed the word planets in the title.
Speaker 0: It must be like in space planet size x-men.
Speaker 1: Are they just Giants?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: Anyway someone if you care about the x-men you can look at this news.
Speaker 1: That is all I got to say other than that.
Speaker 1: It looks like the x-men I know and rogue is like.
Speaker 1: rogue is just the Fox x-men rogue.
Speaker 0: Yeah Another tiny news, right?
Speaker 0: So it's not video game day on geek nights, but as GDQ is ongoing right now.
Speaker 0: I've seen some awesome runs.
Speaker 0: the Mexican runner did the battle toads turbo tunnel.
Speaker 1: Oh, I gotta watch that later.
Speaker 0: someone today did a Geo guesser speed run Where they had to guess.
Speaker 0: they had to do five perfects, you know Couldn't be off by more than like five meters.
Speaker 0: If you don't know a Geo guesser is go watch it and you'll see.
Speaker 0: And of course once they're doing it on as GDQ live, right?
Speaker 0: They get the worst possible ones.
Speaker 0: They give them a hard time.
Speaker 0: They're like, no, not a buja Nigeria.
Speaker 0: Yeah GQ is gonna go from is still going and it will.
Speaker 0: it'll end on Saturday.
Speaker 0: It's gonna end.
Speaker 1: Well, yeah, the finale is on Sunday at like 2 a.m.
Speaker 1: At 11.
Speaker 1: Yes on Saturday.
Speaker 0: Yeah Effectively, but also their YouTube channel is the.
Speaker 0: their automatic pipeline of going from stream to YouTube is functioning I think better.
Speaker 0: it's.
Speaker 0: it's been functioning well in the past But it is functioning now better than it ever has.
Speaker 0: like soon after a run ends the.
Speaker 0: you know The clipped out video of that run is on YouTube, correct on their channel.
Speaker 1: Like it's good to know cuz I pretty much very rarely do I watch these actually live.
Speaker 1: I usually watch the VOD on YouTube as soon as it's there.
Speaker 0: And also, of course you can donate to MSF and also, you know, they always have their donation prizes.
Speaker 0: if you donate at least $250 in total over the course of the entire SGD Q you gain effectively one raffle ticket at most Which is eligible for you to win many prizes that change over time, but one of the prizes is a kick-ass gaming PC.
Speaker 0: But that kick-ass gaming PC has an RT Whatever a geforce 3070.
Speaker 1: No, they're giving away a geforce 3070 that has a bunch of shit attached to it.
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 0: The computer might be better than the computer.
Speaker 0: I have.
Speaker 1: I doubt it's better than anything I've got but I guess I upgraded more recently than you.
Speaker 0: It's like it's like a brand new like top-of-the-line AMD Ryzen, whatever AMD.
Speaker 0: That's the best one.
Speaker 0: It's probably faster than my computer.
Speaker 0: The point is $250 for a raffle ticket.
Speaker 0: It's like what you're donating.
Speaker 0: So you're not even losing if you lose and if you win, oh How did I miss this f-zero one?
Speaker 1: I got to watch that later snake.
Speaker 1: There's a lot of all tracks GameCube the GameCube one.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's.
Speaker 0: but they've done that one before.
Speaker 0: but they did Do snaking before.
Speaker 1: maybe just didn't watch it.
Speaker 1: Maybe I'm stupid.
Speaker 1: I don't remember doing snaking on every track.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there's a lot of good ones.
Speaker 0: So check them out.
Speaker 1: I could snake on like One track in that game.
Speaker 1: I never got good at that game.
Speaker 1: That game was so hard Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: So some other little news.
Speaker 1: There's two things going on with MAPPA the studio right now the anime studio One of which is good news, but there's a big asterisk on that good news because of the second news.
Speaker 1: So yep Chainsaw Man, which we reviewed didn't finish reading it, obviously, but Chainsaw Man.
Speaker 0: I've read the latest volumes though.
Speaker 1: Ooh, I'm a volume behind.
Speaker 0: It's uh, I think I'm in volume.
Speaker 0: I think I read five volumes.
Speaker 1: I think I continue to enjoy Chainsaw Man quite a bit.
Speaker 1: And a Chainsaw Man anime is coming and what I'm gonna link to is the news where MAPPA debuted the footage recently like last week Chainsaw Man's first trailer is as gory as you'd hope And that's what I wanted.
Speaker 1: Chainsaw Man if it's an anime has got to make Castlevania look like Child's Play.
Speaker 1: It doesn't have to be Apocalypse Zero.
Speaker 1: That's a whole different brand of things no one should watch but Chainsaw Man's gotta have an appropriate amount of gore and blood to do justice to those two-page spreads in the manga.
Speaker 0: The only thing that I worry about with Chainsaw Man is that like I really need you know They're collecting pieces of the gun devil, right?
Speaker 0: So if it ends up being an Inu Yasha Situation I'm not gonna like it but I call eventually I give up on it if it just takes too long.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but if they can manage to make it something that you know ends after a reasonable number of volumes Right or at least wraps up the gun devil plot and goes on to a second plot or something like that Because it's like, you know, if I don't get a gun devil payoff by like volume 20, it's like Long to hold out whatever
Speaker 1: happens.
Speaker 1: There has to be a moment where I turn the page and the deal with the gun devil is the kind of thing like in sanctuary Where I go Oh dip when I turn the page Yeah, it's like.
Speaker 0: I think I gave up on one piece after like 17 volumes.
Speaker 1: Maybe right you made it further than me.
Speaker 1: It was the fish man.
Speaker 1: I ended you.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I finished.
Speaker 0: it was like I. the fish man fight was going on for too long So I stopped buying it.
Speaker 0: But then I had already pre-ordered the next volume and that was the volume where the fish man fight ended.
Speaker 0: that Reminded me that I liked one piece, but I was like, nope.
Speaker 0: It's in two volumes.
Speaker 0: It's gonna be another fish, man I'm done.
Speaker 1: The problem is I actually was trying to read read like a few weeks ago randomly I was reading like a spoiler sort of like synopsis of one piece just to see like oh, where did the show go?
Speaker 1: But and that was okay.
Speaker 1: The problem for me was much like the wheel of time.
Speaker 1: the synopsis itself was so long that I couldn't be bothered to finish reading.
Speaker 0: I Don't need to.
Speaker 0: I need to know what happened in between.
Speaker 0: just tell me what the one piece is already.
Speaker 0: That's all I want to know.
Speaker 0: I literally want to see a sentence.
Speaker 0: That is the one piece is what friendship love Draw, I don't know whatever.
Speaker 0: That is literally gold.
Speaker 1: It's the first piece of a puzzle.
Speaker 1: and then they have to go after the second piece.
Speaker 0: Like I don't care what it is.
Speaker 0: Just tell me what it is.
Speaker 1: I was a joke in English God, we used to anime cons every time we talked about one pose.
Speaker 1: I would always show the best pirate boat ever.
Speaker 1: I'd always show those anime openers the Italian one-piece opener, but I always made the same joke gum gum fruit.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't care something always stage in a different way, but always be blah blah blah I don't care about Luffy.
Speaker 1: to part two the quest for the second piece and always get like an okay laugh from the audience.
Speaker 0: So what I kind of what I kind of wish is that you know almost every store, you know fictional story out there Where there's some kind of treasure, right?
Speaker 0: It's like there's always some sort of catch.
Speaker 0: right genie, you know He always screws you on them wishes.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know how they do those genies though.
Speaker 0: I wish that the one piece is just like Immortality invincibility.
Speaker 0: it's good.
Speaker 0: It's perfect and great.
Speaker 0: You're king of the world and everything's awesome.
Speaker 1: It's like one of the swords you find at the end of Final Fantasy 4.
Speaker 1: You're just like.
Speaker 1: well, that's the Ultima weapon.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's just fucked that one piece.
Speaker 0: I hope it's just fucking awesome Unbelievable.
Speaker 0: no catches no tricks is just the greatest.
Speaker 0: the end You know what?
Speaker 0: It's like.
Speaker 0: and then Luffy was was the the Pirates?
Speaker 0: there were no bad pirates.
Speaker 1: ever again The very end everybody out and he looks at it and no one watches.
Speaker 1: He'll can tell what the hell it is and he it just zooms in and it just says the heron spear Yeah, something like that, right?
Speaker 1: So I put an asterisk on that news because I'm legitimately excited about a chainsaw man anime and the fact that map is doing it.
Speaker 1: It's a big deal but We know that the anime industry in Japan doesn't pay shit to the animators.
Speaker 1: Nope, like and you got to work long ass hours and poor conditions and get paid almost nothing and like you think that like it's Bad, but it's so much worse than even the American animation industry.
Speaker 0: in terms of just work life is already bad.
Speaker 1: Yep, and Turns out mapa is paying way below even the paltry market rates in Japan today.
Speaker 0: So it's already.
Speaker 0: Anime is already unethical.
Speaker 0: This is like double unethical anime.
Speaker 0: It's like.
Speaker 0: it's like the difference between the factory where they make the iPhones and the other factory that has you know, Uyghur labor.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's even worse.
Speaker 1: I got I got a lady that yeah, there's another story I didn't want to talk about just cuz I haven't I didn't read enough yet.
Speaker 1: But I saw a story last night around how Chinese studios are Poaching Japanese animators by offering and basically triple salary if they'll come to China and animate.
Speaker 0: and there's a whole thing going on with that Which could if you want to animate and you don't mind going to China, you know, and honestly What I'd when I say the numbers like I wouldn't go to China for any money.
Speaker 0: But you know some people would well considering how desperate you might be.
Speaker 1: So here's the numbers from the article I'm gonna link to.
Speaker 1: so the the going rate which is Garbage tier in Japan right now is about 40 US dollars per cut like a cut of animation 40 bucks, which is basically like being paid like a 7-eleven like hourly employee.
Speaker 1: Yeah Mappa is paying as low as $34 a cut right now and In the article the person they interviewed said the rate that this should be which would already be pretty low should be $134 a cut.
Speaker 0: that that even still seems low.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean like a hundred and thirty four dollars will get you like, you know an illustration from a furry fan artist.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like the last time I commissioned that doesn't even move.
Speaker 1: the last time I commissioned some Animatics like a minute worth of animatics was like four ish hundred bucks.
Speaker 0: So Yeah Seems way low.
Speaker 1: so excited about chainsaw man anime.
Speaker 1: But I live in a society and I have to recognize that the chainsaw man anime is unethical Even by the standards of the Japanese animation industry to date.
Speaker 1: It's it's it's double unethical Yeah, and it's hard to say what to do about this because this is like it's not like animation or animates.
Speaker 0: You destroy cat McCrush capitalism.
Speaker 1: Yep, like, you know often we talk about like how we're communists.
Speaker 1: We're not kidding Like.
Speaker 1: that's not a joke.
Speaker 1: That's not even an exaggeration in my case.
Speaker 0: Well, I mean, it's a you know, the thing is you have communism and people think of like, you know The Soviet Union and it's like listen the Soviet Union's, you know problem was a they didn't have the computers and technology of now Which would have helped, you know Managing an economy
Speaker 1: irrational weird behavior of the?
Speaker 1: u.s Did not help them have a healthy alternative government and also autocracy, right?
Speaker 0: I want communism with democracy.
Speaker 0: It's like yeah, that's the combo right.
Speaker 0: and it's like we've had this You know cold war going on and both sides.
Speaker 1: both sides lost.
Speaker 0: what I would argue Yeah, both sides had one part right and one part wrong.
Speaker 0: It's like we got to combine the good part over here Right and arguably.
Speaker 1: arguably America was not even close to a democracy until maybe.
Speaker 0: of course Yeah, but the point of course not.
Speaker 0: but at least there it wasn't, you know autocracy.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it was something.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'll put it this way is more day.
Speaker 1: I am a communist voting.
Speaker 0: that happened.
Speaker 1: I am NOT a Soviet.
Speaker 1: We're not tankies.
Speaker 1: Like that's a whole other like weird mess of bad ideas.
Speaker 0: No, not at all.
Speaker 0: So in some other news All right, the Godzilla thing Yeah, so there's a Netflix anime that's been out for like a little while now But I just happened to watch it cuz I had it was raining, right?
Speaker 0: So I watched an anime.
Speaker 0: so going outside there was rains going on.
Speaker 0: So it was Godzilla singular point.
Speaker 0: It's one of those Netflix original animes, right and you might think man you guys are talking about a lot of Netflix original anime.
Speaker 0: See, well, that's yeah, cuz I'm subscribed to Netflix right now.
Speaker 0: I only subscribe to one thing at a time.
Speaker 0: Eventually, I'm gonna run out of Netflix Unsubscribe and switch to something else and you're gonna be hearing nothing but HBO max shows.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I feel like HBO max.
Speaker 1: There's a winner.
Speaker 1: We're all gonna park our subscriptions cuz they picked up like fucking everything.
Speaker 0: Yeah, this is not like some.
Speaker 0: I don't want anyone to think that there's some favoritism here between streaming services.
Speaker 0: It's just.
Speaker 0: I'm only subscribed to one at a time.
Speaker 0: Although I am always subscribed to crunchyroll at all time.
Speaker 0: Oh, I'm always crunchyroll And that's because crunchyroll has an annual payment thing.
Speaker 0: if they did the monthly thing I would do the same switching.
Speaker 1: now Our household is crunchyroll and Disney Plus and then whatever service has the things we're watching which right now is no thanks.
Speaker 0: So I watched all of Godzilla singular point.
Speaker 0: I wouldn't have watched it all.
Speaker 0: I would have only watched some of it if it wasn't raining.
Speaker 1: Yeah This sounds like this review is about to be like my review of all those anime I watched when I was living alone in Poughkeepsie Maybe.
Speaker 0: so, I mean, it's not a bad show, right?
Speaker 0: It's it's some of the animation is really kind of awesome You know.
Speaker 0: if you like Monsters, you know, there's some really cool monster animation and monster scenes going on.
Speaker 0: I do like monsters and there's you know, the aspect of that sort of like, you know Fantastical sci-fi aspect of like trying to figure, you know, everyone's trying to figure out like why do the monsters work?
Speaker 0: What's the deal?
Speaker 0: How do we stop them?
Speaker 0: right, you know everywhere the monsters go there's like these red dust everywhere.
Speaker 0: What's the deal with that?
Speaker 0: right and the humans are trying to figure it out, right?
Speaker 0: And it's also got lots and lots of callbacks to you know, the series of Godzilla movies, right?
Speaker 0: So it's like if you are familiar with got the you know All the Godzilla creatures and monsters and you know things like Jet Jaguar, right the robot.
Speaker 0: It's like you'll.
Speaker 0: there's a lot of you know, basically direct references that will sort of tingle your nostalgia, whatever, right.
Speaker 0: The negatives of this show I think is it a While there's the characters are like some of the characters have good designs and good personalities and are interesting.
Speaker 0: There is no character like development.
Speaker 0: It's just like this character is who they are Right.
Speaker 0: watch them do what they do.
Speaker 0: And it's like they don't have like an like an arc of like growth or change or anything.
Speaker 0: It's like this character is an old man who likes robots.
Speaker 0: He's an old man who likes robots at the start of the show.
Speaker 0: He's an old man who likes robots at the end Place for that.
Speaker 0: it's like this girl.
Speaker 0: It's like yeah, she's the the science research girl, right?
Speaker 0: It's you know, who's who's figuring everything out and she's that at the start of the show and she's that at the end of the Show.
Speaker 0: she doesn't have any.
Speaker 0: there's no human conflict.
Speaker 0: The conflict is the humans versus the science to solve the you know, Godzilla monster problems, right?
Speaker 0: That's that's the central conflict of the show.
Speaker 0: and the second problem in the show.
Speaker 0: Is that the science problems?
Speaker 0: And some people have said I have watched this I watch these sub diversion.
Speaker 0: people were saying that the dub is great.
Speaker 0: that's what people said so I'm inclined to believe them because they're people I trust.
Speaker 0: and And While watching the show with subtitles, which is what I did.
Speaker 0: There's a lot of just like nonsensical science blah blah blah blah blah Right prop for now and prop for now and prop for now and sentences that don't make sense.
Speaker 0: Mistranslations of like, you know.
Speaker 0: Like poems like, you know, it's like, you know they're like.
Speaker 0: they got the tiger tiger poem in there right with the fearful symmetry as like a reference several times symmetrical tiger on fire Right and like, you know, that's a thing that was originally in English, but the subtitles got it wrong, right?
Speaker 0: It's like.
Speaker 0: it's like what?
Speaker 0: But so people said the dub is actually more sensical.
Speaker 0: so that may be true.
Speaker 0: So maybe try the dub.
Speaker 0: if I guess if you're watching with subtitles and you get to a part We're like the subtitles like make no sense.
Speaker 0: Like what the fuck did they just say?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: that means nothing.
Speaker 0: Maybe rewind a little bit and turn on the dub and see what they say.
Speaker 0: Maybe it makes more sense.
Speaker 0: But yeah it's like if the central point of the show is like this humans versus science thing going on and Then you don't translate it in a way.
Speaker 0: not it's not.
Speaker 0: I'm not saying like inaccurate, right?
Speaker 0: I'm not sure.
Speaker 0: but it's like in a way that means nothing.
Speaker 0: It's just like words.
Speaker 0: you you're not following anything.
Speaker 0: that's happening.
Speaker 0: Yeah Doesn't really work.
Speaker 1: like Star Trek which was often guilty of that would basically use all those words in a context to convey something To solve a problem and then move past it.
Speaker 1: the show wasn't about those nonsense words.
Speaker 0: Yep And then yeah, there's.
Speaker 0: no I was also disappointed.
Speaker 0: There was no payoff of monsters fighting each other.
Speaker 0: But at the end of the show, you know, there's.
Speaker 0: you know There's always that post-credits deal right and it's like they make.
Speaker 0: if they make more of this which I think they might they may Said they were going to already that might have monster on monster battling.
Speaker 0: So that might be worth.
Speaker 1: I'll say you're into the monster on monster.
Speaker 1: Yeah Anyway, yeah If it rains enough, I feel like I could watch this.
Speaker 0: Yeah I think if you're uh, I think this is only for people who are like if you're a real like Godzilla type fan right then this is for you.
Speaker 0: if you're just like you like a Godzilla now and then you know it's only if The hurricane is over your house.
Speaker 1: So similarly I'll geek bite something just really briefly cuz I know I'd like.
Speaker 1: I'm really big into like to get birdie and the owl house and All these other shows that Scott hasn't watched yet.
Speaker 1: But the owl house is such a phenomenal show like as a kid's show.
Speaker 1: It's great, but it's also like there's a lot going on.
Speaker 1: I've talked about it before.
Speaker 1: Season 2 is coming out bit by bit and I've seen enough of season 2 to be able to say season 2 of the owl house just as good continuing on the same plot the back story of the world everything continues to be intriguing and I think it's gonna continue to be a. the dark undertones are legitimate.
Speaker 1: This show is weird and dark and has a lot of sci-fi elements.
Speaker 1: There's fun stuff going on.
Speaker 1: So if you haven't watched the owl house watch it season 1 ends in a pretty good spot and You don't have like season.
Speaker 1: You could stop and wait for season 2 to finish before you started it.
Speaker 1: in case there's more cliffhangers season 1 will end at a point that you would be comfortable with waiting on and season 2 so far is Great.
Speaker 0: So I want to introduce a new segment to geek nights which you haven't done in.
Speaker 0: I don't know a hundred years.
Speaker 0: This is breaking news yeah, so I'm Temporarily which means permanently.
Speaker 0: I've decided to call the segment second dibs, right?
Speaker 0: The idea is that I've got some stuff and it's not.
Speaker 0: it's stuff That's still good and I don't want to throw it out in the garbage, right?
Speaker 0: But I've already given first dibs to people I actually know like actual friends family close people right and they didn't want it.
Speaker 0: So the second dibs are is for the listener, right?
Speaker 0: We're gonna see if the listener wants something that I have that I don't want anymore.
Speaker 0: and if the listener doesn't want it Then you know, sometimes it might be something free sometimes it might be just pay shipping sometimes it's gonna cost money Right, but if none of the listeners want it then third dibs is gonna go to eBay Facebook marketplace some shit like that, right?
Speaker 0: So what I have for you is the first item up for dibs And if you want the item just contact us via any of the contact mechanisms that we have.
Speaker 0: There are many pick one our discord Our forum an email Twitter DM whatever.
Speaker 0: so I recently replaced My second monitor, right?
Speaker 0: So now I've got two daddy to 4k monitors now, so One of the monitors that I had the two monitors one of them broke and it temporarily swapped it with an identical one.
Speaker 0: That was rims.
Speaker 1: I gave rims back when I got my first 4k monitor which is good timing because my Backup monitor that I was using in the kitchen finally died and now I put this one in the kitchen spot.
Speaker 0: So my second non 4k monitor just got replaced, but it still works.
Speaker 0: It is a Dell u24 10 ultra sharp monitor.
Speaker 0: It is 1600 by 1200 resolution 16 by 10 aspect ratio.
Speaker 0: Really good, you know color accuracy.
Speaker 0: considering it's an LCD monitor.
Speaker 0: It has a absolutely ridiculous number of inputs HDMI displayport DVI VGA and component.
Speaker 0: you can plug a frickin we into this with like a component cable if you want to Right.
Speaker 0: It's really useful to have all those inputs.
Speaker 0: I'm kind of sad.
Speaker 0: my new monitor doesn't have those You.
Speaker 0: it's totally works.
Speaker 0: it doesn't have a stand because the original stand I got rid of but It's basically my mom.
Speaker 1: It's basic.
Speaker 0: I put my.
Speaker 0: I put my monitors on arms.
Speaker 0: So my new monitor.
Speaker 0: I came with a stand that I'm not using.
Speaker 0: so it's on a stand.
Speaker 0: It's just not the stand it was supposed to go with.
Speaker 0: it's on a stand from a much newer brand new Dell monitor.
Speaker 0: So arguably it's a monitor.
Speaker 0: It's an old Dell monitor on a stand that's designed for a newer 4k Dell monitor.
Speaker 0: So it looks a little weird from the back, but it totally works.
Speaker 0: So it's honest and it's just not dust and it's supposed to have.
Speaker 0: Not bad I can give you with this.
Speaker 0: Oh, it has a USB hub built in And I can give you with this monitor.
Speaker 0: I can give you a power cable.
Speaker 0: I can give you the USB cable so that you can plug it into your computer and then it will act as USB hub.
Speaker 0: Right and I can give you a display port cable that is guaranteed to have all the pins so that it's not going to fry Your computer meaning it's missing the pin that will fry your computer.
Speaker 0: Yes, I can give you a guaranteed correctly working safe Functioning DisplayPort cable.
Speaker 0: I can even give an HDMI cable if you tell me you need one.
Speaker 0: I can give you a VGI and a DVI cable if you ask for one, too.
Speaker 1: I mean if you want old cables for video stuff We could hook you up right.
Speaker 0: if there's a I mean by default I'm gonna give you the cables I said.
Speaker 0: But if you if you need one of those other cables I can I can give it to you.
Speaker 1: Oh doesn't also have a built-in card reader.
Speaker 0: It does.
Speaker 0: yeah built part of the USB hub is an SD card reader.
Speaker 0: It's USB 2 mind you.
Speaker 0: but yeah It is a. there is a built-in SD card reader on the side next to the USB hub ports And also it because it has all those inputs.
Speaker 0: It does picture-in-picture, so if you plug in like several devices Oh shit, I forgot all those old ultra sharps had that.
Speaker 1: I don't think the new ones had that I think the new one might Ever play less inputs.
Speaker 0: I've never knew it has made less input, so it's not really there's no point to it, right.
Speaker 0: But yeah, you could plug in for example a Wii on the component inputs, and I don't know Your laptop on the DisplayPort input, and then you could have like the Wii game in a little box in the corner.
Speaker 0: You could even move it around or like you know whatever and then have your computer like you can do.
Speaker 0: all kinds of picture-in-picture layouts With mixing the inputs together, it's pretty.
Speaker 0: it's pretty cool even though it's an old monitor.
Speaker 0: so I bought this monitor for like five hundred dollars way a long time ago that and I just replaced it with a 500 ish dollar monitor.
Speaker 0: but it's so old and also the monitors have one problem and That it is sort of yellowed.
Speaker 0: if you look at the monitor from like a distance at the wrong angle You can see this sort of like.
Speaker 0: it looks like there's a yellow blob around the edges of the screen and like only the center Of the screen looks like it's the right color.
Speaker 0: But if you're sitting close to the monitor just using it like you can't notice at all.
Speaker 0: it looks perfectly normal.
Speaker 0: So there's some sort of yellowing.
Speaker 0: I think what's happened is that UV light like does these reflectors, but inside the monitor behind the backlights There's like white reflectors that reflect the backlight back at the screen.
Speaker 0: Right because there's no point in having the backlight shoot light out the back of the monitor.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right.
Speaker 0: It just makes the screen brighter to put reflectors behind the backlights.
Speaker 0: I think those reflectors Supposedly have yellowed from UV light over the years make sense.
Speaker 0: monitors from like who knows when 2014 Maybe it's really old.
Speaker 0: So that might be the problem, but it doesn't affect the functioning of the monitor.
Speaker 0: So if you want this monitor, and it's not gonna be free, but it's gonna be pretty cheap right like hundred bucks you think Oh For like it makes God an offer.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like it was a top-of-the-line monitor right like amazing.
Speaker 0: It's just way old and has some yellowing going on and I want to recoup some of the cost of this new Monitor.
Speaker 0: that will hopefully last just as long.
Speaker 0: so if you need a monitor computer monitor, that's kind of awesome.
Speaker 0: actually Let me know.
Speaker 0: yep, and the other rule we have otherwise I'm gonna by the by the next time we do a show or whatever.
Speaker 0: It's just gonna be on eBay if no one wants it.
Speaker 1: yep And the other rule we have with this bit is if one of us does it the other one can't do it.
Speaker 1: So I can't try to voice this recalled fire extinguisher on you.
Speaker 0: No, you'll do that.
Speaker 0: We're gonna.
Speaker 0: You know we're not gonna do too many at once because otherwise we'll run out of bits, right?
Speaker 0: We'll get well all the shit in our house will be gone.
Speaker 1: Or geek nights gets weird, and there's like the arrow where we were just doing basic nights home shopping club basically geek nights GVC.
Speaker 1: I Feel like next day for the next one.
Speaker 1: you got to try to talk in that kind of tone.
Speaker 1: like.
Speaker 1: this monitor features an array of functions.
Speaker 0: It just most of them will be much shorter than this one, but just the monitor has had so many features I think like the.
Speaker 0: the next thing I'm gonna try to get rid of has you know way fewer features, so So in the mood.
Speaker 1: actually it's time for things Of the day so check this.
Speaker 1: this was uploaded on June 27th.
Speaker 1: This was a recent video.
Speaker 1: I just found it kind of randomly.
Speaker 1: I wasn't even subscribed to this account.
Speaker 1: It's a an animation kind of in the Yamashibai style Style and it's basic.
Speaker 1: It's called yokai Bob the Builder, and it is.
Speaker 0: it is a like legitimately scary four-minute long show Where in the title tells you everything you need to know.
Speaker 1: yeah?
Speaker 0: You know yokai are you know?
Speaker 0: Bob the Builder is oh my god.
Speaker 1: And the moment when Bob the Builder shows up He just he looks like one of those like yamashibai looking yokai And he bangs his hammer on the ground and the couple in the house just like oh my god.
Speaker 1: Oh, what are you?
Speaker 1: and he's just like we can fix it.
Speaker 1: Don't you think?
Speaker 0: guys blues.
Speaker 0: Yokai Maya the B.
Speaker 1: Oh, I would watch it.
Speaker 1: yokai Maya the B. Would be perfect.
Speaker 1: yokai David the gnome David the gnomes already terrifying.
Speaker 0: yokai Dora the Explorer.
Speaker 1: But yeah, when you see this you'll see what I mean.
Speaker 1: like they got the style right.
Speaker 1: It's clearly.
Speaker 1: it's like.
Speaker 1: it's not anime like it's.
Speaker 1: it feels like someone Made something that wanted to feel like anime, but wasn't quite deep enough in anime to get it perfect.
Speaker 1: But the yokai part is like spot-on yokai.
Speaker 0: Elmo My co-worker took their kid to sesame place.
Speaker 0: Oh, we're talking about that.
Speaker 0: yeah So what do you got thing of the day?
Speaker 0: Yeah, so the hockey's going on right now.
Speaker 0: the Stanley Cup could come out as soon as tonight Maybe before you even heard this episode.
Speaker 0: it may have come out already because the lightning up three games to one.
Speaker 1: I hope it doesn't cuz I'm not a particular fan of the Habs But I'd rather anyone of a Tampa win.
Speaker 0: so as long as I was lost I don't care.
Speaker 1: you know my dad was like hey like before like the allergies were eliminated.
Speaker 1: Hey, well on New York teams gonna make it to the end right.
Speaker 1: so that's something.
Speaker 0: yeah No, that's.
Speaker 0: that's if a New York team is gonna win.
Speaker 0: That's either the best thing or the worst.
Speaker 0: It's not like okay It's.
Speaker 1: I've realized that only New Yorkers are that weird about it because there's so many teams.
Speaker 1: There's such a dense area.
Speaker 0: You think people you think Cubs fans are happy at the White Sox win.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I guess that's the other bar.
Speaker 1: That's one.
Speaker 0: Dodgers fans are happy if like the Angels win.
Speaker 0: it might be even though.
Speaker 0: It's Anaheim and not LA or whatever.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: yeah, I Don't I don't I feel like no right People who got two teams only like one of the two teams.
Speaker 1: I mean honestly I couldn't care less if the Mets or the Yankees win the World Series.
Speaker 0: Anyway.
Speaker 0: So yeah, so the one game that the Habs have won so far was game four and there was his dude.
Speaker 0: I don't know his name.
Speaker 0: I think he's like works like SB nation or does he does like?
Speaker 0: he's like a. he's like a sports media person for the Habs.
Speaker 0: He's not.
Speaker 0: he's not just some fan.
Speaker 0: Okay, so that's why he was being interviewed on TV Outside the arena right during the overtime of game four By the sports television people and so they're asking questions like you know how do you think the game's gonna turn out?
Speaker 0: You know it's so he.
Speaker 0: you know he predicts the finish of the game.
Speaker 0: He's like.
Speaker 0: yeah He's like.
Speaker 0: I think we're gonna score.
Speaker 0: You know if we if we win this one right I think he's like we're gonna score a goal here in the overtime.
Speaker 0: It'll be the be the Habs and he thinks Anderson's gonna score the goal During the inner during the interview.
Speaker 0: While he's still there Anderson scores the goal to win the game in overtime, right?
Speaker 0: So this is like this is pretty awesome video here And honestly like it doesn't it doesn't spoil the video.
Speaker 0: It's for me to tell you what happens in the video.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but I won't link to it.
Speaker 1: but if you know what the blab is they're showing the game.
Speaker 1: if you don't have any other way to see hockey and Basically if you never watched ice hockey the games that are happening now are kind of the peak of the sport.
Speaker 1: Things get different during the Stanley Cup playoffs compared to all they just get.
Speaker 0: did it Yeah in the playoffs and so this is the finals.
Speaker 0: so they're even more different.
Speaker 0: But yeah hockey players You know they play a long season of hockey which you you normally for.
Speaker 0: like football you such a brutal sport you play less games.
Speaker 0: Right hockey plays a lot a lot of games for something that you know probably should be less games like sometimes.
Speaker 0: I took a survey today.
Speaker 0: That was like how many games should the season be?
Speaker 0: and I chose like half as many right?
Speaker 1: It should be way back in same number of day games.
Speaker 1: We have tickets to maybe.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I was like man.
Speaker 0: I was like you should cut it way back.
Speaker 0: I don't think that was a popular choice, but that's what I chose now, but regardless hockey players Don't play.
Speaker 0: you know they play seriously, and they play hard in the regular season.
Speaker 0: sometimes They do play their hardest in regular season games that mean a lot, but playoff hockey is completely different.
Speaker 0: It's like if you go to the Madison Square Garden to see a playoff hockey game You'd think it was a different building.
Speaker 1: yeah when you went to see a regular season like a few times I have been in person at a Stanley Cup playoff game like especially past the first round.
Speaker 1: It's weird to be in a building that you've been to so many times with the same size crowd and somehow it is three times Louder at all times, and it's just the.
Speaker 0: everything is different right now.
Speaker 0: It's the same building right.
Speaker 0: say It's like.
Speaker 0: it's like what the heck.
Speaker 0: It's like you're playing the same hockey by the same rules almost the same rules.
Speaker 0: Overtime is different.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the old the big difference for those you're on hockey people is in normal hockey and most sports.
Speaker 1: There's a point where the game will like okay.
Speaker 1: It's overtime.
Speaker 1: We're gonna do some bullshitty thing just to end the game or we'll do something quick Or it'll just be a tie.
Speaker 1: some sports just allow ties in playoff NHL hockey.
Speaker 1: nope just keep fucking playing normal hockey until someone wins.
Speaker 1: We'll go all day.
Speaker 1: We'll go forever.
Speaker 1: the rules literally are go forever.
Speaker 0: So I think if you're going to be a new hockey fan Or you're going to try to get someone to be a new hockey fan Playout postseason hockey is I think ideal.
Speaker 0: to show people first Yeah, you know it's sort of bad because when they watch a regular season hockey the next year They'd be like
Speaker 1: hey You know what it's like when the anime club
Speaker 0: riding the roller coaster first
Speaker 1: the anime club showed episode 5 of cowboy bebop But you know the spike just to be like hey check out how fucking awesome anime is.
Speaker 1: everyone's like woo.
Speaker 1: And then not all anime is like that.
Speaker 1: People see Cagliostro and like who gonna watch way more Lupin, and then they watch like All.
Speaker 1: right, let's bet a moment.
Speaker 1: We're reading the tale of Genji.
Speaker 1: I'm continuing to read it.
Speaker 1: Genji continues to be the exact same kind of person.
Speaker 1: I feel like there is not growth or change.
Speaker 0: It's the first novel ever and Let's get into our taxi cuz our taxi is yeah, so phenomenal I'd take yeah.
Speaker 0: So there's people on the internet.
Speaker 0: We're all ranting and raving about this anime called odd taxi all of every episode of which is on crunchyroll And the final episode actually just came out like a week 29th was the last episode of 13 so a couple weeks ago.
Speaker 0: So what happened to me is I finally got around to watching it when there were every episode except the final one was out.
Speaker 0: I watched it on like there was a.
Speaker 1: there was a strong pressure.
Speaker 1: No one was telling me Oh, you gotta watch odd taxi, but the people I know who are deep into anime and the anime industry people and Anna Twitter.
Speaker 1: Everyone was talking about this show, but also avoiding talking about it in any amount of detail.
Speaker 0: Yep, so I watched all the episodes except for the final one because it wasn't out yet.
Speaker 0: And then I watched the final one the day it came out and that was it.
Speaker 0: and now we can do a show on it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I've seen about a little over half of it, and we're gonna finish it pretty quick because it's so good.
Speaker 1: But what that means is I can speculate a little bit without spoiling Just based on what I've seen but the
Speaker 0: show
Speaker 1: if I had to just describe it on a really high level it's a psychological thriller where there's a core mystery but a bunch of other stuff is happening like in the orbit of this mystery and There's a lot of very dark and sinister Undertones constantly in a show that on the surface is a bunch of cute animals interacting with this taxi driver.
Speaker 0: Yes, so you know in snatch right you have all these different care whole cast of characters all doing different stuff But they're all sort of tied together right by the diamonds right and sort of linking their different stories.
Speaker 0: And there's the scene where they all literally crash into each other At the climax.
Speaker 0: so odd taxi is similar, but not so right.
Speaker 0: it's similar.
Speaker 0: And there's a cast of characters who all have their own stories that you all care about.
Speaker 0: individually right.
Speaker 0: all these separate arcs Right but at no point do all the characters crash into each other.
Speaker 0: It's that all the characters are linked to Right.
Speaker 0: okamura is his name right a taxi driver Otakawa the taxi driver, it's like you know what it's more like in that regard.
Speaker 1: Durara has all these different characters with their crazy deals But they're all tied together by like the mid not like the mythological events that are happening in that neighborhood in ikebukuro.
Speaker 1: Yep sure exactly reminds you of that show a lot in terms of that aspect of it.
Speaker 1: But instead of being and it's a crazy anime bullshit It's more like there's a paranoid agent weird thing going on that the show is like skirting the edges of something dark and sinister and foreboding.
Speaker 0: Yep, so you have this taxi driver.
Speaker 0: He's just a taxi driver And you know he's mostly always just drives like super safe And he's sort of quiet and weird with people.
Speaker 0: right you can tell he says like some discomfort like being with people Talking to people normally.
Speaker 0: He'll be like Sarcastic or whatever right?
Speaker 0: and there's all these other characters who have their own plot lines that you know sometimes touch each other.
Speaker 0: Sometimes don't.
Speaker 0: some characters don't know each other at all.
Speaker 0: You know some characters are very close to each other.
Speaker 0: right there part like.
Speaker 1: there's a gorilla who is like a psycho a psycho like a Psychiatrist who also is like the Otakawa.
Speaker 1: the taxi driver goes to his clinic.
Speaker 1: There's a nurse that he knows.
Speaker 1: there There's this other monkey guy who Not a spoiler easily gets scammed by a very obvious scam that happens in the real world.
Speaker 1: There's two brothers who are cops and one of them seems like he's corrupt and the other one seems like he's stupid.
Speaker 0: Right so right, so there's like Otakawa The Monzai duo I love the most.
Speaker 0: Yeah, Monzai duo is great right so it's pretty right.
Speaker 0: so you know Otakawa is connected to the gorilla.
Speaker 0: He's his patient right and the nurse there right, but what does the nurse have to do with the cops?
Speaker 0: like not much?
Speaker 0: But Otakawa is connected to the cops right he like.
Speaker 0: he knows them like he'd.
Speaker 0: you know he sees them.
Speaker 0: They pull him over sometimes.
Speaker 1: That was something that stood out to me even in the very beginning.
Speaker 1: is that it starts out like he's just a taxi driver.
Speaker 1: but as the show goes on it seems like these characters have interacted with him before and know a lot about him.
Speaker 1: and There's all these moments where he?
Speaker 1: Reveals that he knows a lot more than you would expect him to about some random thing.
Speaker 0: He knows a lot he's.
Speaker 0: all these people are in his taxi spilling the beans and all kinds of stuff thinking He's just a taxi driver.
Speaker 1: There's like this whole plot where all these different people keep coming up to him and like they want his Video from the dashcam like right, so that's that's the central mystery at the start of the show right?
Speaker 0: is that?
Speaker 0: Supposedly there was some Yakuza boss right a Yakuza boss's daughter who is missing.
Speaker 0: And or you know that no one knows right miss It's like it's the talk of the town.
Speaker 1: like that's the news recently that this girl is right.
Speaker 1: It's it.
Speaker 0: and the cops were looking for them But then stopped looking and then it did strongly implied but never shown that the the the Yakuza boss daughter took a ride in this taxi and Basically without.
Speaker 0: they don't say anything right, but there's he's.
Speaker 0: they imply that a that She was in the taxi.
Speaker 0: you never see that she was in the taxi.
Speaker 0: They never show that.
Speaker 0: yeah, right This is dashcam footage.
Speaker 0: so people yeah He has video of everything that's happened in the taxi and people are fight trying to get him You know to give them the footage right and he you know stuff happens there That but you don't see.
Speaker 0: you never shown the footage right.
Speaker 0: you have no idea What would happened.
Speaker 0: and also see he's talking to someone in his apartment?
Speaker 0: Who's in the closet?
Speaker 0: literally the physical closet not metaphorical closet, and they don't talk back to him So you don't know what the fuck is in his closet.
Speaker 0: Is it?
Speaker 0: is it the girl?
Speaker 0: is it what?
Speaker 0: so yeah?
Speaker 1: It's nothing is like he like having see.
Speaker 1: like if you watch a little bit of the show There is no one in the closet is a viable theory.
Speaker 0: Yeah, is he just talking to himself?
Speaker 0: It's like you have no ideas, but there's this strong implication that he may have right Kidnapped or not maybe not kidnapped, but maybe she intentionally like you know befriended him And it's like he's hiding her because that's what she wants.
Speaker 0: That's heavily implied But no one knows and that's that's sort of like the this beginning spark mystery that sort of spirals and connects All the other people and their mysteries and their deals.
Speaker 1: yeah And throughout the rest of the show at least for the first full half of the show The implications around most of these characters get more and more sinister But they never quite full-on reveal a lot of things.
Speaker 1: so the show ends up feeling like a really tight Psychological thriller where the tensions just slowly building episode by episode.
Speaker 0: It's you know those things the story stereotypical thing.
Speaker 0: we're like the crazy Detective or person has like a wall with a bunch of photos and streams on nails connecting them and all that stuff, right?
Speaker 0: So imagine one of those.
Speaker 0: only as you go it actually makes sense.
Speaker 0: It's like whoever made this show whoever wrote this story did that and it actually connects.
Speaker 0: And it's like it was just like a genius piece of writing to make all those things actually work and connect to each other.
Speaker 0: It's like oh, no, it's actually.
Speaker 0: it's not just some you know rantings of a you know a madman or whatever.
Speaker 0: It's it's actually yeah, you know yeah, we made this thing happen.
Speaker 0: look watch it unfold.
Speaker 0: I think what I like most selectively give you and don't give you the audience information at various points in time.
Speaker 1: what I like the most is that the dialogue between the characters is Very like it is.
Speaker 1: it's hard to describe exactly what I mean by this.
Speaker 1: it is very precise and it reveals exactly what the show wants you to know and characters will say things that Imply a lot of other things that will cause you to speculate about the motivations of other characters.
Speaker 1: I'm being vague on purpose because it shows a mystery.
Speaker 0: Also, they also people talk to each other.
Speaker 0: the way I think at least according to the subtitles the way people talk to each other Right it's like but like little subtle like the tax driver seems kind of unaware like a taxi driver sometimes But when he's talking to some people.
Speaker 1: He'll just say something that makes it very clear.
Speaker 1: He knows way more about what's going on than he's letting on.
Speaker 1: But then in other situations.
Speaker 1: He is like very clearly surprised by what someone else said to him.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so the the different sort of groupings of the plot right is.
Speaker 0: there's the gorilla nurse guy.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there's the social media guy hippo.
Speaker 1: There's though at the mandrill dobu the the criminal I'm making quote fingers Who's on the loose that the whole town is like after for various?
Speaker 0: Yeah, he's like.
Speaker 1: he's like a little town is Tokyo, but that live streamer guys like I'm gonna get you you criminal.
Speaker 0: Yes, he's an actual gangster.
Speaker 0: that guy yeah like actually doing crimes But he has other motivations.
Speaker 0: Then you've got though that's the idol group right.
Speaker 0: and then there's the monzai group.
Speaker 0: is that all of them?
Speaker 0: That's most of it right?
Speaker 1: yeah I mean the idol group has like the three members we know about plus the manager guy who's clearly up to something and that other Guy in the background is clearly in on it.
Speaker 0: So there's these.
Speaker 0: there's these sort of connections between the groups right.
Speaker 0: it's like there's a connection between One of them people in the monzai group and one of the idols in the idol group.
Speaker 0: there's a connection between the criminal guy and The not the gorilla, but the the nurse who's a alpaca llama But she's not back up, but everyone else all has a red line back to Oda Kawa.
Speaker 0: Yeah, every single person's going back to Oda Kawa right?
Speaker 0: they've either been in his taxi Or he's involved with them directly in some way.
Speaker 0: right he listens to the monzai group and the monzai guy was in his taxi once right You know there's a. there's a giraffe kid.
Speaker 0: Who's a fan of the monzai group right?
Speaker 0: He's barely in the show, but I know she was in the show more.
Speaker 0: But yeah the show basically just unfolds this mystery.
Speaker 0: right.
Speaker 0: and then in the final three episodes Right the second to last and third to last episodes are The odd taxi.
Speaker 0: like there's actually a thing the odd taxi that happens right.
Speaker 0: I'm not gonna say any more about that.
Speaker 0: It's the one during Yeah during the course of the odd taxi much is revealed and then in the final episode.
Speaker 0: Right the final episode on the one hand is like a great ending and on the other hand could be viewed as Disappointing in the depending on your perspective because what they do in the final episode is it.
Speaker 0: it's almost like an epilogue.
Speaker 0: It's.
Speaker 0: it's plays like an epilogue right, but it's actually like.
Speaker 0: You know usually an epilogue is like years after the ending.
Speaker 0: This is like no the ending, but it plays like an epilogue.
Speaker 0: They literally go.
Speaker 0: it's like someone went down a checklist of every loose end right and was like all right.
Speaker 0: we'll do this one and And it's like litter every single one in the last episode every loose end every question you had.
Speaker 0: They just go one by one.
Speaker 0: they're like and this is what happened to this and this is what the deal was with that And this is what that was about and this explains that and so and so and so all in that one final episode.
Speaker 0: So that is in some ways really satisfying because who the fuck does that?
Speaker 0: there's usually some hanging shit.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right But they left nothing Unknown other than the future of course, but yeah, you know that's always unknown.
Speaker 1: well That was a spoiler.
Speaker 1: the world doesn't end as a result of the odd taxi.
Speaker 0: Oh I guess not.
Speaker 0: Story about a taxi driver is not an apocalyptic tale the funniest thing We want.
Speaker 1: we watched a couple episodes, and we both had this image of if this were a live-action show like it could work But he's a really great live-action.
Speaker 1: Oh, I imagine Bruce Willis specifically playing Ota Kawa.
Speaker 0: Is that just because he drove a taxi in Fifth Element?
Speaker 1: no But it's it's because of like his attitude and like his dialogue and like I just imagine a sort of slaw Slightly slovenly looking like middle-aged Bruce Willis sitting there having those conversations Because Ota Kawa has these moments where he seems really like schlubby, but then he'll just get this hardness about him out of nowhere
Speaker 0: Mmm.
Speaker 1: I'd like that's the kind of thing that Bruce Willis does pretty well And I feel like he would be like that.
Speaker 1: that's the kind of actor I would set to play Ota Kawa in the live-action adaptation.
Speaker 0: The only thing I could the only other thing I can say about the show is if you're one of the people Unlike me right.
Speaker 0: if you're unlike me, and you want you value surprise highly, right?
Speaker 0: Because you know I'm not spoiling the show just out of courtesy right because obviously I won't do that But you can spoil it for me, but I already seen it all.
Speaker 0: Is that you know?
Speaker 0: I think a lot of people avoid spoilers because they want to be surprised.
Speaker 0: the show may surprise you Depending on who you are right.
Speaker 0: I don't know about that, but Basically while it was nice to see all those resolutions.
Speaker 1: I was not surprised by anything We've made Emily, and I why as we're watching it have made some specific predictions, and we're very or I.
Speaker 0: I don't even know what specific predictions you have made But I will just just knowing the fact that you have made a prediction and that you are an intelligent person who can you know?
Speaker 0: Read subtext, and you know see Chekhov's guns hanging on the wall and things about.
Speaker 1: this show is so full.
Speaker 0: the Chekhov's Chekhov's Arsenal.
Speaker 0: yeah Just knowing that you are someone who can recognize that I'll bet 80% chance your predictions are probably just dead on right?
Speaker 0: It's.
Speaker 0: it's that kind of show where it's like yep.
Speaker 0: It's it is what you thought it was But it doesn't.
Speaker 0: it doesn't take away from it right?
Speaker 0: it doesn't need surprise because what you thought it was Was was great.
Speaker 1: what I like about it is doesn't need to be surprised just the character.
Speaker 1: the tension in almost every Conversation any character has is palpable and that is what drives this show forward More so than the mystery itself.
Speaker 1: and the one thing I get the other thing I can say is in terms of we always talk About the great anime or the one where you end an episode and you are compelled Without even thinking your body just moves on to the next episode.
Speaker 1: It was real hard to stop watching this show last night to go to bed.
Speaker 1: Mmm like even the great pretender as much as I liked it.
Speaker 1: I could be like okay.
Speaker 1: That was enough anime for tonight.
Speaker 1: But this show was one of those rare shows where if I was in college if we were in college And I'd watch one episode of this.
Speaker 1: well.
Speaker 1: It's also so short It's only what twelve thirteen thirteen episodes, but if I'd seen one episode of this in college I would have finished it that night.
Speaker 0: No matter what it's not long.
Speaker 0: You can finish it in six.
Speaker 1: You know six hours I mean we used to like we used to watch In one go basically right.
Speaker 0: yeah, it's the last thing I want to say about the show.
Speaker 0: the thing I like about the show the most right is Not even this very well-crafted You know mystery plot with all these characters and all this right, which is all awesome.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's just simply just the atmosphere of the show.
Speaker 0: yeah It's like if you're.
Speaker 0: I don't know if you've had this experience.
Speaker 0: You know we have but I don't know if other people listening.
Speaker 0: the listener has right of like.
Speaker 0: You're in a hotel in some city, and you wake up early and you go out And it's still dark.
Speaker 0: right and it's quiet and the streets empty.
Speaker 0: mostly There's some people around.
Speaker 0: right the con the desk person at the hotel is there right the one guy with the taxi Who's gonna drive it to the airport.
Speaker 0: is they get to the airport?
Speaker 1: It's empty But there's the one person there the airport desk to take your man And a lot of the characters are the kinds of people who are up and about during that Liminal hour.
Speaker 0: you go you go to the bodega That's open at 1 a.m.. To get something.
Speaker 1: only the bodega guys there on the street And it's the same bodega guy at 1 a.m.. Every day.
Speaker 1: So if you go in at night at that early hour every day Then like it's you to see each other every day that of each other's that real-life Atmosphere of being in a city place that would normally be crowded and busy, but it's dark quiet and empty.
Speaker 0: But you're not completely alone.
Speaker 0: There's someone else there But they're not a person you're close to.
Speaker 0: there's some sort of stranger that you're with right at an at a weird hour Possibly a stranger you recognize But don't know and that part is and it's and it's a stranger that you're going to interact with right in some way even if It's just capitalism right?
Speaker 1: well Just like the kinds of conversations on how it has with his passengers like you might as well Just taking that out of someone else's - calf right.
Speaker 0: so that atmosphere that feeling The show doesn't always have that atmosphere at all times right.
Speaker 0: there's parts of the show where it's crowded daytime Right oh the things going on.
Speaker 0: but a lot of the show especially earlier in the show is just that atmosphere almost all the time because it's about a guy who Drives his taxi, and oh did we mention he doesn't really sleep right.
Speaker 0: so yeah He's out and he's driving it.
Speaker 1: no You know what else?
Speaker 1: it reminds you.
Speaker 1: because of his insomnia and because of the not enough again I haven't seen the whole show.
Speaker 1: it is implied that he is mentally unstable And it's also implied by the way seeing a gorilla.
Speaker 0: He's seeing a gorilla You know doc.
Speaker 1: yeah, right, but it's implied that the other people around him also pick up on that in the show.
Speaker 1: and There's a I don't you ever saw.
Speaker 1: there's a movie the machinists Very similar.
Speaker 0: There's a movie called that.
Speaker 1: it's you probably like it.
Speaker 1: It's a psychological thriller.
Speaker 1: It's not.
Speaker 1: it's not like this.
Speaker 1: There's only one.
Speaker 1: There's a mystery and a thread, but it doesn't.
Speaker 1: it's a very similar atmosphere at times.
Speaker 0: The point is there's something about that atmosphere that I I know for some reason I like it even in real life shared a little spaces like pre-dawn late like that.
Speaker 1: that.
Speaker 0: yeah, right.
Speaker 0: So if I experience that in a usually you're experiencing that in a movie or television show right you're not really Experiencing that so much in a book.
Speaker 0: that often right I think you know while you could put it in a book the book doesn't Make you feel the same way because it doesn't have the you know The show portrays and like makes you feel that very very directly and very realistically.
Speaker 0: I felt the exact same feels right that I felt like.
Speaker 0: you know.
Speaker 0: I felt like I was waiting outside in the dark alone trying to get a taxi or Walking on a Manhattan Street to get to the subway alone at night.
Speaker 0: Yeah, all the stores are closed except for one.
Speaker 0: You know this.
Speaker 0: I felt exactly like that when I was watching the show and I like that personally.
Speaker 1: so And yeah, I don't really want to say anything else cuz I'm gonna watch the rest of it like Just wait till it's night and just go walk around.
Speaker 0: Hey, that's kind of why I like.
Speaker 0: the problem is it's really crap.
Speaker 1: Like to get the full night biking experience, I know we want night biking that other time.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I do it in the winner and in yeah But like to get their real night biking experience you got to start later and go further like do it in Manhattan instead of Queens.
Speaker 1: But anyway, yeah anyway Yeah I've seen in a while.
Speaker 0: Yeah best.
Speaker 0: I don't know and I don't know if there is based on anything.
Speaker 0: or is it originally?
Speaker 1: it's based on a manga.
Speaker 0: Okay, I didn't know those among Let's see.
Speaker 1: It was in superior Del Pana.
Speaker 0: Say no, like I don't need to read the manga.
Speaker 0: after watching the show two volumes.
Speaker 1: It says them Oh, wait, is the manga still says the mug is still going?
Speaker 0: Whoa, is there more me?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 1: Let's see the series aired.
Speaker 1: I'm looking to see what the deal is with the manga cuz I always the show the show and oh, no The manga is an adaptation of the anime.
Speaker 0: Okay, we don't need that.
Speaker 1: Yep that I see no reason to read a my adaptation of this considering how good this is.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's it's you're good.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so.
Speaker 0: But if you have I always say this you're gonna.
Speaker 0: if you're gonna live your life and you're gonna you think you're gonna survive.
Speaker 0: You know, you got six hours of time in your life.
Speaker 0: that you're you know, you're not gonna like pass away soon.
Speaker 0: Right, you can spend the six hours to watch odd taxi and you could do much worse.
Speaker 1: I would actually say this is one of those shows where if you if you like anime at all Just watch the show don't like why you just go watch even if you don't like any.
Speaker 1: I was gonna get to the second part.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna tell my mom to watch this cuz she would Can watch the odd taxi.
Speaker 1: Yeah, both our moms would like this show a lot.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think everyone I can't think of many people who wouldn't like the.
Speaker 1: I need adult humans that wouldn't like the odds Like the straw man who is like, oh animation is for children and I hate it If you actually get him to watch even a few minutes of the first episode.
Speaker 1: It's hard to imagine a person who is not intrigued by what is going on.
Speaker 0: The only person I could see being turned off by this is one of those.
Speaker 0: You know people who can't see past the surface level and it's like like oh this animal people Can't deal with that people.
Speaker 0: Yeah, someone who's like that.
Speaker 0: It was so, you know closed-minded in that way or I can't see past that.
Speaker 0: That's the only person I can imagine Or like a child right wouldn't?
Speaker 0: I think younger people probably wouldn't enjoy this.
Speaker 0: They might think it's a little boring and it's a lot of social commentary stuff going on Especially with the social media guy and the game playing guy.
Speaker 1: Oh my god the game playing guy.
Speaker 1: that the episode where you get that guy's backstory was so well written.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah What he's when he's?
Speaker 1: what do you were like?
Speaker 1: his mental dialogue like he is narrating his own life and the way he like.
Speaker 1: He actually accepts responsibility for the shitty things.
Speaker 1: He's about to do was it was just an interesting notes?
Speaker 0: Yeah, that guy's a that's a really great character.
Speaker 0: That is a really great under.
Speaker 1: I think that's like an under appreciated part of the show that guy now that is spent especially when there's a moment when there is CCTV footage of that guy doing a thing and someone else sees that and thinks it's a different person.
Speaker 0: Yep But yeah, watch the odd taxi and I'm gonna go get food.
Speaker 0: same.
Speaker 1: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Speaker 0: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 1: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 0: But unlike those other late shows It's actually recorded at night
Speaker 1: and the patreon patrons for this episode of geek nights are Heidi McNichol Alan Joyce link eg dread lily Tana by Chris Reimer Clinton Walton Finn just like a dude guy kashaya Yeah 85 program threat open speed undertake a lot out from Chris absorb Rebecca Dunn.
Speaker 1: review mad bull 34 cowards Ryan Perrin Sam Erickson Shervin von Harl Taylor Braun.
Speaker 1: you hold the key to my heart and a bunch of people who do not want me to Say their names.
Speaker 1: just watch add to odd taxi and now I leave you with.
Speaker 0: We're gonna be talking about the.
Speaker 0: We'll be talking about the.
Speaker 0: Do you think that's funny?
Speaker 0: I'm leaving.
Speaker 0: Do you find it amusing that we'll be talking about the?
Speaker 1: Yes, we're also gonna be talking about But sauce.