Speaker 0: It's Tuesday, December 7th, 2021.
Speaker 0: I'm Rym.
Speaker 1: -I'm Scott.
Speaker 0: -And this is Geek Nights.
Speaker 0: Tonight, we are reviewing Metroid Dread on the Nintendo Switch.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: Uh, not working.
Speaker 1: Just every day, waking up, do whatever I want.
Speaker 0: -Uh, working.
Speaker 0: -If only... -Uh, working.
Speaker 1: I was at work today.
Speaker 1: -If only there was some way that I could do this and live this life of wake up and do whatever I want.
Speaker 1: But, also, A, not have it be cold, B, not have a pandemic outside so I can do things, uh, and C, have enough money so that someone else could do all these chores for me.
Speaker 0: -'Cause that's... -Oh, so you want to be landed gentry with, like, butlers.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well, it doesn't... I think everyone deserves that, you know.
Speaker 1: And even the people who end up doing the chores, it's like, okay, you know, they shouldn't have to do that more than, like, you know, once a week or something.
Speaker 0: Well, the way I've always thought about it, like, the ideal democratic communism I want, the idea is that you give everyone bare minimum, like, they'd live, everyone's got everything they need to live, be relatively happy.
Speaker 1: And also, if we had, say, for example, like, you know, even more socialisms, right, like, we had a shared kitchen, you know, it's like, oh, well, then I could just clean that kitchen once a week and then I got six other days to do...
Speaker 0: -To do things...
Speaker 1: -Instead of having seven kitchens for seven people who have to clean the seven kitchens once a day, every day, you could have one kitchen, everyone cleans it once a week.
Speaker 0: Ah, but what if some of the people in your building with that shared kitchen are just, to use a word, a phrase that I've liked lately to describe certain kinds of people, shit-asses.
Speaker 1: Then you don't... You get kicked out.
Speaker 0: By who?
Speaker 0: What if the majority of the people are using that kitchen?
Speaker 1: That's part... That's... Doing the work of living there is part of the rent, effectively.
Speaker 1: -So you would get, you know...
Speaker 0: -You've reinvented the co-op.
Speaker 1: -Yes, exactly.
Speaker 0: -Like the Soviet-style co-op.
Speaker 1: -Yeah, not the co-op city co-op.
Speaker 1: -No.
Speaker 1: -The way I look at it... -Yeah, I'm doing all... I'm getting all kinds of stuff done over here.
Speaker 1: You know, having all sorts of good times.
Speaker 1: Some of it's metamoment material, what's not metamoment material.
Speaker 0: Sitting around, looking around?
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know, stuff.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I got my booster, and the reason we missed Wednesday gig nights last week is that the booster... I was basically out of commission for 48 hours after that thing.
Speaker 1: Well, I didn't have any really problems with the first two, you know, six to eight months ago, other than pain in the arm, so we'll see what happens.
Speaker 0: -That was my first shot.
Speaker 1: -I thought I was getting my booster the day after Thanksgiving, but I was just an idiot, and I didn't read the calendar correctly.
Speaker 0: You were the only one.
Speaker 0: Emily was trying to get an appointment quickly and got one at CVS.
Speaker 0: Their website is so shitty, 3
Speaker 0: a.m.,
Speaker 0: 'cause I guess that was an option.
Speaker 1: Oh, no.
Speaker 1: What happened was I opened my doctor app.
Speaker 1: I opened my doctor app, and it said "Friday," and it was a few days before Thanksgiving, so I just said, "It said 'Friday,'" and I didn't look beyond the word "Friday,".
Speaker 1: so I just said, "Yes, appointment for Friday at 1230,".
Speaker 1: and I went in Friday at 1230, and they were like, "No, you made your appointment for Friday, December 19th,".
Speaker 1: so I guess I'm going there 12 days from now, 'cause, eh, you know, I'm staying inside for all these days.
Speaker 1: -It doesn't really matter.
Speaker 1: -I'm telling
Speaker 0: you, the most anxiety-inducing thing that ever happens in my life, I mean, I have a pretty good life, is I'm always vaguely afraid that I'm gonna have an appointment to do a thing, like meet someone, get on a plane in particular, and I'll just show up on the wrong day.
Speaker 0: Like, I'll just have fucked up my calendar, show up on the wrong day, like, "Your flight was yesterday, you're not going to PAX," or, "Flight to PAX?
Speaker 0: That flight is next week, what's wrong with
Speaker 0: you?".
Speaker 1: I may have discussed this when it happened many, many years ago.
Speaker 1: Not that many years ago, but, you know, I was living in New York City at least, maybe early 2010s.
Speaker 1: There was some College Humor thing in the city when College Humor was still a thing, and I had bought tickets to it, and then I was in the shower one day, and I thought about it, and I was like, "Oh, yeah, that thing.
Speaker 1: When was that
Speaker 1: thing?".
Speaker 1: And I get out of the shower, and I go and I search in my email for the tickets to it, and I'm like, "Yeah, what day was that
Speaker 1: It turned out it was that day, and it was too late to go.
Speaker 1: It had already begun, and I was like, I bought tickets to a thing and just didn't go.
Speaker 1: I wasn't doing anything that day, I just didn't go because I forgot about it, and then I started using Google Calendar, and it never happened again.
Speaker 1: All right, so that actually happened.
Speaker 1: It wasn't like some dream of like, got tickets, didn't use them.
Speaker 1: I actually had tickets and didn't use them.
Speaker 0: I finally, after like two years of this pandemic, stopped having the recurring dream of, my brain just knows that there's paxes on the certain cadence, plus magfest, that we go to and perform at, so I have like a whole, like my brain is just like, you know that feeling when you're laying in bed, and you feel comfortable, and your alarm hasn't gone off yet, but you almost feel like you've been laying in bed too long, and you have the fear of,
Speaker 1: "Did my
Speaker 0: alarm not go off?
Speaker 0: Did I not set it?
Speaker 0: Did I just sleep through it?
Speaker 0: It feels too
Speaker 0: late.".
Speaker 1: Why would I set my alarm?
Speaker 0: Because you're an old man, I don't know what's up with you.
Speaker 0: If I don't set an alarm, I'll just sleep forever.
Speaker 1: I mean, I basically am just sleeping until my body decides to get up.
Speaker 1: That seems good.
Speaker 0: I mean, my body would like to get up around 10, which is not really an option.
Speaker 1: I don't have anywhere to go.
Speaker 0: True.
Speaker 1: I don't have any appointment.
Speaker 0: But my brain just has this cadence of, "Paxes happen on this like fairly reliable schedule," and then suddenly I'm just not going to them, and my brain's like, "Yo dog, didn't you write the panels?
Speaker 0: When are your panels?
Speaker 0: What panels are you doing?
Speaker 0: When's the next pax?
Speaker 0: Shouldn't you be there
Speaker 0: already?".
Speaker 1: Yeah, anyway.
Speaker 0: Anyway, there's a bunch of gaming news.
Speaker 0: I guess we can start with a little thing.
Speaker 0: A bunch of games are having problems right now, because a bunch of things are having problems right now, because Amazon is like super fucking down.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we've talked about this before.
Speaker 1: We'll talk about it again, I'm sure, is that too many internet services are hosted on Amazon Web Services cloud platform and the services that they provide, and most people who set up things on Amazon Web Services, they do offer ways to, for example, create a database that's like multi-region, so that if one region explodes or gets cut off, your database is still up in other regions, and you're very resilient if you do that sort of setup.
Speaker 1: But that kind of setup isn't just like a push button thing.
Speaker 1: It requires, even though they do a lot of the hard work for you, it still requires engineering effort and money.
Speaker 1: They charge more money for that, right?
Speaker 1: So the vast majority of people who set up things on Oz set things up just very simply, the way you would with any other hosting, the way that like the Geek Nights website is set up, even though that's not on Oz.
Speaker 1: It's partially, I guess, but mostly not.
Speaker 1: You know, just an easy-to-instance, whatever.
Speaker 1: And most people, because the way the world works, have things set up in the US East 1 region zone, right?
Speaker 1: Because US East is where people are, where we live also, where people, it's where the most people are.
Speaker 1: And it's closer to Europe than US West.
Speaker 1: So even though even California companies, all the Silicon Valley people will still- I've never set something up in US West, ever.
Speaker 1: I have multi-region stuff in US West, just for, that's what I use.
Speaker 1: Any region that's not US East, it's like US East is always the primary region where you do everything.
Speaker 1: And then the other regions are just like the backup fail over us.
Speaker 1: So yeah, US East is having problems today, big problems.
Speaker 1: And that means that, you know, a lot of things, a lot of internet services of all kinds are down or broken because we've built all on this one thing.
Speaker 1: And if that one thing breaks, a lot of other things break.
Speaker 0: Now it's interesting, because on one hand, from an individual perspective, especially because it's Tuesday, like a small gaming company, it's way cheaper and cost effective to just spin up cloud services, to do stuff like having physical data centers is very much a huge expense and a huge pain in the ass.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I mean, it pays off for you in terms of some things like your hardware costs, right?
Speaker 1: So it's like you buy computers and then you don't have to buy computers again, whereas you have to pay OZ monthly.
Speaker 1: So eventually those computers pay for themselves and you don't need new ones, you know, and hard drives won't break that much.
Speaker 1: And then you say you end up saving money over this like long term.
Speaker 0: You can even go further.
Speaker 0: A lot of people to manage them.
Speaker 0: A lot of people don't even make servers.
Speaker 0: They're not putting like a virtual server on EC2 and Amazon.
Speaker 0: A lot of people, newer things especially, are just leveraging cloud services to directly provide services via those capabilities of the cloud without actually having like a so-called server running an operating system up there.
Speaker 1: Well, it is still a server running an operating system, but they call it serverless because the cloud provider gives you an abstract interface via which to launch your application, usually some kind of container.
Speaker 1: You'll make a Docker container.
Speaker 1: And normally if you wanted to host that yourself, you would have to make a Kubernetes cluster and all this stuff right on servers.
Speaker 1: Instead, Amazon made a cluster and they have this Fargate thing and they have this, you know, ECS thing.
Speaker 1: And it's like you just give your container to that and they built up all this software that hides the servers from you, even though they are very much there.
Speaker 0: Now what's interesting is this affects a lot of things like.
Speaker 0: VRChat has a bunch of random parts of VRChat that are down right now because of this.
Speaker 0: But one thing, something I've always internalized in the kinds of jobs I've had when we're doing a risk assessment is that for many companies that are not mission critical, where lives depend on them, Amazon and things like it don't go down that often, but also
Speaker 1: it's pretty rare
Speaker 0: if they do go down.
Speaker 0: The answer you can give is basically, well, yes, we're down and so is everybody else.
Speaker 0: Nobody has an advantage over us right now.
Speaker 0: So who gives a shit?
Speaker 1: That's one thing.
Speaker 1: It's a situation in which from an individual perspective, right, using this platform is the most cost effective, best way of doing things.
Speaker 1: But from a societal perspective, everyone putting all their services, all their eggs into one basket is like, it's like, I got one egg.
Speaker 1: What basket do I put it in?
Speaker 1: The biggest, strongest basket.
Speaker 1: So now you have everyone puts their one egg into this basket and now, yeah, it's a big, strong basket, but all the eggs are in that one basket.
Speaker 0: Well, like with Google, you and I both, you have a lot of our data in Google services.
Speaker 0: If Google got hacked, like for real, like somehow compromised fully, worst case scenario, on one hand, yes, all a lot of very personal information is now compromised for me.
Speaker 0: On the other hand, society has deep problems because of that hack, like so big that my problems are almost lost in the shuffle.
Speaker 0: So yeah, the ramifications of this on an infrastructure level are more of a Monday episode.
Speaker 0: But yeah, if you're trying to play some game and something's not working today, good chances due to this Amazon outage.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I wonder if we'll see, you know, the companies that do really care about never being down, perhaps not just go multi-region but also maybe like have a failover to Azure failover.
Speaker 0: Oh, that already exists.
Speaker 0: All big companies do that.
Speaker 0: I know, I know.
Speaker 0: Of course, you know, but there's services that will auto deploy your shit to all the different cloud services and like work between them.
Speaker 0: Like there are people who say, will those, will those get some more customers?
Speaker 0: The problem is I feel like a lot of those things have their own single points of failure such that it doesn't solve the fundamental problem of everyone's moving to these services run by giant mega-corps that don't have our best interests at heart.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: I just still, I would like to see a return or, you know, a resurgence in not the bullshit crypto distribution model, but the real distribution distributed model of the internet, which is just that everyone runs servers all over the place.
Speaker 1: We've got a web, you know, the way email works, the way the web works.
Speaker 0: Well, the way email worked.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Exactly.
Speaker 0: But, you nerds who don't listen to Monday geek nights, web browsers and the worldwide web was just one of many things we could use the internet for.
Speaker 0: And the big idea of a web site or web stuff was that every web browser is also a web server.
Speaker 0: Everyone makes content and everyone interlinks with everyone else's content.
Speaker 0: And there is no central server for really anything.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so other news going down, a really common thing these days is you find someone that you're a fan of and you join their Patreon and Patreon has a Discord integration.
Speaker 1: That's pretty, very well polished.
Speaker 0: Oh, right.
Speaker 0: I keep forgetting I should enable that for our Patreon.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So you join a Patreon and then if the person who runs the Patreon associates that Patreon with a Discord server, then, and you have Discord, your Discord account linked to your Patreon account, then when you Patreon someone, you automatically get joined to their Discord server.
Speaker 1: And on top of that, the person who runs that Patreon can now give you access to like special Patreon only channels or features or roles or benefits and whatnot.
Speaker 1: And it's just a really common model.
Speaker 1: And it makes sense, right?
Speaker 1: It's like you're producing some sort of entertainment, you know, maybe you're a Twitch streamer, probably, you know, you get money from subs, you get money from, you know, whatnot, you know, donations, advertisements, if you run those, and then, you know, people want to join your community.
Speaker 1: So, you know, they want to join your Discord, not just your Twitch channel and make friends with the other people who are fans of you and you can charge them money to do that.
Speaker 1: Well, Discord is now realizing like, hey, why are we letting Patreon take all the money on this model?
Speaker 1: And they are now testing something that I imagine will eventually become a widespread feature, which is, yeah, you could just make a Discord server and directly, without integrating any other services, gate all or some of the features and channels in the Discord server behind money.
Speaker 1: So somebody using only Discord and nothing else, no Twitch, no Patreon, no nothing, could set up a server and say, "Hey, you want to pay $5 a
Speaker 1: month?".
Speaker 0: It's a great way to even do things like people who make a clan or a rating group, like small time things for like playing games online, having their little membership dues to pay for like whatever stuff they do as a group.
Speaker 0: There's a lot of ways to use this kind of thing.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So it has a lot of things going on, but the fact is, you know, Discord, you know, sort of bumping out Patreon, right?
Speaker 1: But also I could see it as even bumping out, you know, how could they bump out Twitch?
Speaker 1: Well, it's like you can just stream on Discord.
Speaker 1: If you get enough people into your Discord server and people can find your Discord server somehow, either via maybe a Twitter or something, you might not even need the Twitch.
Speaker 1: You can just completely stream only on Discord to your own people.
Speaker 0: You can avoid copyright stuff to a big degree.
Speaker 0: And you can also have a more intimate, closed experience with, you know, we always talk about that very few people can be a megastar in any domain.
Speaker 0: That's just rare, often toxic.
Speaker 0: But a lot of small content creators have a small but dedicated group of fans who like exactly what they're doing.
Speaker 0: And this is a great way to concentrate them together and they will pay that person to keep making the thing that they specifically care about.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think a lot of people do this already.
Speaker 1: But the problem is the money that they're getting doesn't come in through Discord.
Speaker 1: It has to come in through some other channel.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: But yeah, I think this is pretty much you can see.
Speaker 1: this is clearly now the established model is create some content, not for people like us who aren't trying to make money, but the people who are trying to make money.
Speaker 1: This the model is create art, put the art out there on some channel for free of some kinds that people can find you and become a fan of you.
Speaker 1: And then charge money for either, you know, some exclusive arts, even though that's not perfect, because those can leak very easily.
Speaker 1: And then charge money to either join the community or join the VIP part of the community or both.
Speaker 1: You know, because you can absolutely.
Speaker 1: there's no way somebody can like steal that.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 0: It's also interesting because this get.
Speaker 0: I think there's a few things going on here.
Speaker 0: One is the economy is kind of messed up.
Speaker 0: And this is a way for small creators to make a revenue stream and avoid a lot of the middlemen that provide nothing and just collect rent along the way.
Speaker 0: It's also a way to sustain the people who have the one thousand true followers.
Speaker 0: But the cynical side of me says that what we're going to see is every goddamn service on earth is going to try to come up with some half-assed way.
Speaker 0: Discord, I think, is doing a good job with this, but I can imagine a lot of other online services trying to come up with an equivalent thing and try to get people to self monetize via their platforms with whatever it is their platform provides.
Speaker 0: I think we're gonna see a lot of these spin up and a lot of them go away over the next few years.
Speaker 0: But I bet Discord will stick around.
Speaker 0: I think Discord, Patreon, maybe OnlyFans, I don't know.
Speaker 0: There's some trouble with them still.
Speaker 0: We'll see who survives this current round, I guess.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: I can see using this a lot of people have like a family and friends Discord or like a private Discord where.
Speaker 1: And why would you collect money then?
Speaker 0: Well, say in your group of friends, you do an annual beach house retreat or an annual party somewhere.
Speaker 0: And this is the way everyone pays the dues to a central place to cover the cost of that party every year.
Speaker 1: I don't think this works that way.
Speaker 1: I think this is.
Speaker 1: Oh, you mean every.
Speaker 1: it's like everyone pay five bucks a month to join the Discord.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Or the people who are in the channel just be like, hey, if you want to I'll tell you the address of the party.
Speaker 1: if you Venmo me 10 bucks.
Speaker 0: I know some friends, not our friend group even, but some friends of ours have talked about Chase in particular.
Speaker 0: Groups of friends that set up like more complex, larger structures like these are friend groups that are a little more organized and they're almost like mini conventions.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you can do that sort of thing.
Speaker 1: I don't think that charging everyone a monthly fee that Discord takes a cut of is going to be the model for you need your friends to collect money together.
Speaker 1: I feel like it only could definitely is only going to work for collecting money from the public and your fans.
Speaker 0: I think that could work if you had sufficient scale of friends and sufficient scale of activities.
Speaker 1: that if you have that many friends, those aren't friends.
Speaker 1: Those are now fans.
Speaker 1: There's that many people.
Speaker 0: You could argue that line gets blurry at a certain weird size between really big and very small.
Speaker 1: You're going to charge people a monthly fee.
Speaker 1: I don't know if they're not just fans or audience of some kind.
Speaker 1: I don't think that really, I can see what you, what I think, what it also could work well for is, um, you know, Patreon and these sorts of things aren't often used by big companies.
Speaker 1: Uh, if you're a big company, say a video game developer publisher, right?
Speaker 1: You set up a Discord for your fans because you don't have a forum anymore because you know who, who would do that, right?
Speaker 1: Um, you know, you have your actual paid community managers in there and whatnot, but then you have your gated channels that cost money.
Speaker 1: And in those channels, you're giving out, you know, beta keys and you're, you know, you're actually getting feedback from, you know, this does sidestep, but it causes another externality.
Speaker 0: The same problem that Twitter has that Twitch has is that any rando can make an account and start fucking around.
Speaker 0: As soon as you have to pay for the thing you want, like pay to be able to chat in the Discord or the Twitch, 99% of trolls and harassers disappear because very few people are motivated enough in their hate of some creator to pay a monthly fee to harass them.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: If you retreat to your own Discord, it's like, yeah, you're going to still need moderation in there, obviously, but a lot less than just some public Twitch.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I think this would be pretty cool if there was some way to, you know, on Twitch, right?
Speaker 1: Sort of erase the Twitch chat, just like block it all and then have, you know, a Discord chat be funneled in.
Speaker 1: It's like, you can't chat there unless you go to the Discord, which could be gated, but everyone can never let you do that because that would undercut a lot of how they make.
Speaker 1: of course it would, of course it would.
Speaker 1: But if you did that in your own Twitch video, you see chats from the Discord.
Speaker 1: So everyone in Discord has to know that they're chatting publicly, but that no public people can chat.
Speaker 1: They can only read.
Speaker 0: We're waiting for a few new features.
Speaker 0: I've done a little bit of testing, but we do plan to, don't worry, we're not gonna start charging money, but I do plan to start streaming the Geek Nights live, even if we keep doing it on YouTube, also streaming it inside of the Discord.
Speaker 0: There's just some reasons.
Speaker 1: I wish they would add video to the stages.
Speaker 1: Then we'd be using that so much.
Speaker 1: There's a Discord like feature suggestion website, an official one.
Speaker 1: And there is a post there that's like, "Hey, add video and screen sharing to
Speaker 1: stages.".
Speaker 1: And it's got a lot of upvotes, but if everyone listening goes and upvotes it, that might encourage them to work harder on that.
Speaker 1: You know, they gotta be working on such an obvious feature, but that feature will be like an explosion of easy content.
Speaker 0: Can you imagine if we could just do our panels like in a Discord with slides up on the screen, video of us, people queuing up questions.
Speaker 0: There's so much cool shit we can do.
Speaker 1: Taking Q&As that we don't like to do, bringing in guests.
Speaker 1: A guest on the show would just have to join the Discord and like join the stage and we'd say, "Let them join
Speaker 1: stage.".
Speaker 1: That's it.
Speaker 1: We'd be good to go.
Speaker 0: We're here with a listener from Omaha who has some comments on our... So yeah, we're keeping an eye on this.
Speaker 0: We've got a lot of other stuff in the hopper obviously, but once Discord stage is added a little bit more, we'll be using it heavily and we'll see where this community building goes.
Speaker 0: I think this is a material threat to Twitch today because Twitch is.
Speaker 0: the cracks in the Twitch universe and ecosystem are definitely becoming more and more apparent, especially for non-white creators.
Speaker 1: I think people need still some public thing.
Speaker 1: You can have your closed community, that's where your real action is, but you need some public things so people can find you.
Speaker 1: Discovery isn't a problem for consumers because there's so much stuff.
Speaker 1: We don't need help discovering things.
Speaker 0: If I never looked at the internet again, just from the games I know came out in the last few years, I could entertain myself for like five or six years.
Speaker 1: Yeah, exactly.
Speaker 1: So discovery is no longer a problem.
Speaker 1: That's the problem we're trying to solve.
Speaker 1: It's long been since over solved.
Speaker 1: It's too easy to discover new awesome things that you don't have time for.
Speaker 1: The problem is on the other side, someone who creates something wants to be discovered.
Speaker 1: They need to shout louder than everyone else in that sea of things that are easy to discover.
Speaker 0: So I think there's a lot of ways to address that, but that would turn this into a show about this, but we'll be talking about this topic again, mind you.
Speaker 0: In some other news, we rotate through which AAA video game studio is the worst one at any given time.
Speaker 0: It's usually Ubisoft.
Speaker 0: Ubisoft is the news I'm about to talk about.
Speaker 1: Ubisoft is always the most micro transaction-y, scammy, one with awful games.
Speaker 0: Like Blizzard, usually that's the worst one.
Speaker 1: Blizzard is really bad right now, partly because they laid off a way off the deep end Blizzard Activision, and then EA is never good with their FIFA gambling, but even so, Ubisoft is regularly the worst one.
Speaker 0: Like Riot, don't forget, they have very similar problems to Blizzard.
Speaker 0: In fact, they had very similar problems recently to Blizzard, but now Blizzard is in the news because Blizzard's problems came back again.
Speaker 0: All of those are bad.
Speaker 1: They're all bad, but it's like I would rank probably Ubisoft last place, EA second to last.
Speaker 0: Ubisoft is bad enough to where I actively, like I would actively avoid Ubisoft games even if the game itself was good.
Speaker 1: Thankfully, I've been avoiding Ubisoft games for, uh, I don't even remember one I've bought.
Speaker 0: Yep, thankfully I very rarely am even interested in any Ubisoft games because the kinds of games, they're all garbage, but Ubisoft is really fighting for the crowd of shittiest AAA studio.
Speaker 0: They are actively and aggressively pursuing NFTs now, so what they're gonna do- I mean, that's not a surprise.
Speaker 0: No, not a-.
Speaker 0: what surprises me is that they didn't already have this live, uh, that this is somehow new, but I was surprised that Ubisoft was not like the first adopter of this blockchain chain NFT bullshit.
Speaker 0: Ubisoft is trying to use blockchain, uh, and they're launching this on December 9th in two days to have gear in Ghost Recon, like cosmetic hats basically, but when you get the hat in game, you get a fucking NFT, that means you own that hat, and that NFT will let you use that hat in, in the future, other Ubisoft games.
Speaker 1: Uh, I want to- now before we go any further, I want to point out- Hold on a second, so this is actually, um, you know, approaching, right, forgetting the environmental and other bullshit, right?
Speaker 1: This is actually approaching something where, you know, "Hey, now suddenly owning-" in quotes, right, having that token on the blockchain associated with your wallet cryptographically, right, would actually confer something resembling ownership, like
Speaker 0: no
Speaker 1: one else in any Ubisoft game is going to ever be able to wear that specific hat because there's only one of them, they didn't make more.
Speaker 0: Yep, some other game company, not Ubisoft, could be like, "Hey, if you have a particular NFT from the Ubisoft whatever ecosystem, then you get this same equivalent item or something similar-".
Speaker 1: Oh, you could, you could do that, but also the question is now, alright, so let's say I give Ubisoft money, they mint a blockchain coin, they, in their server, right, they look at that coin, and they recognize that that goes with my account somehow, maybe by looking at the wallet, and then associate my wallet with my Ubisoft account, and then their server just, you know, allows me to choose that hat to wear in various games.
Speaker 1: There is a beg to question.
Speaker 1: The question is, if I go, right, because Ubisoft doesn't control the blockchain itself, right, so if I go and, say, sell that coin, so I go to a coin exchange, and I sell that coin to someone- Yes, they are
Speaker 0: directly saying they expect people to speculate on trade, sell for real money, these things, outside in the real world.
Speaker 1: Right, so if I sell that coin, is it, you know, they could, but are they actually going to correctly and properly set up their servers to recognize that the hat has been sold?
Speaker 1: Who owns the hat now?
Speaker 1: Which Ubisoft account?
Speaker 1: is the person who now owns the hat?
Speaker 0: So, the short answer is yes, that is, they're building their own servers to do this.
Speaker 1: But are they doing it right?
Speaker 1: I just don't have a lot of confidence that they will make it work technologically.
Speaker 0: Oh, I think they'll make it work technologically.
Speaker 0: I think it's going to be buggy and broken as all fuck.
Speaker 0: I think there's a way deeper and more fundamental begged question.
Speaker 0: What part of this entire fucking thing requires blockchain?
Speaker 1: None of it.
Speaker 0: This could be done with their own database that they already have.
Speaker 0: The limiting factor on multiple games respecting the same token is implementing that in the games.
Speaker 0: Not who has the ownership, but actually implementing the assets.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they don't need to implement the, you know, use blockchain to do this.
Speaker 1: They could do it with the database, as is true for all blockchain things.
Speaker 0: Oh, but what if you want to sell them for real money?
Speaker 0: You can't do that with Counter-Strike hat.
Speaker 0: Well, guess what?
Speaker 0: In Team Fortress 2 and Counter-Strike, people sell those things for real money all the time.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they just use Valve's database.
Speaker 1: Valve has a database.
Speaker 0: Yeah, or remember the Diablo real money auction house?
Speaker 1: Yeah, but what it does is it saves Ubisoft from having to implement these trading house, right?
Speaker 0: No, because they're gonna implement something far more complex to facilitate the recognition of these trades.
Speaker 0: They're also running this as their own service.
Speaker 0: They have a name for it.
Speaker 0: I think the more fundamental problem is no part of this ecosystem is in any way enhanced by using blockchain, NFTs, cryptocurrency bullshit than by just doing it a normal way.
Speaker 1: That's not new.
Speaker 1: There's nothing that a cryptocurrency can do that can't be done with a database better, other than crime, right?
Speaker 1: Someone said that recently.
Speaker 1: It pretty much sums it up, right?
Speaker 1: So there's nothing new about that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they could do it better with the database, but they could save themselves the effort of having to create a trading house.
Speaker 1: Steam had these people at Valve created a trading house where you could buy and sell things, right?
Speaker 1: They don't have to make that.
Speaker 1: All they have to do is put mint a coin when they give you a hat and then look at the blockchain to see who owns the hat.
Speaker 0: They're gonna provide a trading house and use the technology as well.
Speaker 1: Well, then they didn't save themselves anything.
Speaker 0: Well, because they're not.
Speaker 0: The only reason a company like Ubisoft would ever do anything like this is solely that they want the buzz of the crypto bro bullshit to drive money their way.
Speaker 0: They're trying to get people to say, "Oh, Ubisoft supports NFTs and I'm a dipshit, so I'm gonna go use Ubisoft stuff
Speaker 0: now.".
Speaker 0: That's my goal.
Speaker 1: It's just that somebody might- It's a popular buzzword.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but also if you're doing crime, it's like, "Well, if I could launder my money with some random picture of a monkey," right?
Speaker 1: Or I could launder my money using an Ubisoft hat and there's a chance that some kid might actually want that hat and there might be some value to it instead of just a picture of a monkey.
Speaker 1: So that's probably a better place to launder my money and it's backed up by some legitimate evil company.
Speaker 0: But if you're not trying to launder and commit a crime and you just want to actually own the stupid monkey, none of this technology is needed for that and it just destroys the earth for no reason.
Speaker 1: Yes, that's not new so there's no point in discussing the parts we've already discussed in the past.
Speaker 0: So here's a thread, a link to all the evil crap that Ubisoft is doing.
Speaker 1: and remember Ubisoft has always been the worst.
Speaker 0: As bad as Activision Blizzard is right now they're real bad.
Speaker 0: Ubisoft is the king of being a shitty AAA game company.
Speaker 0: But anyway, things of the day.
Speaker 0: So this is a long video.
Speaker 0: This is an hour and eight minutes long.
Speaker 0: It's from Wired.
Speaker 0: Thankfully it is annotated in that YouTube way so every single chapter of this video has its own tiny section in the timeline and this is an explanation of every single style of beer on earth in a good order of discussion from beginning to end.
Speaker 1: Couldn't you just, this sounds to me like, I mean that's good information even for someone who doesn't like or you know even drink any alcohol.
Speaker 1: but it feels like you could have just made that a webpage instead of a video.
Speaker 0: Oh there's a million web pages like that.
Speaker 0: What I enjoy about the video is that it's not about, no one should come to this video.
Speaker 0: if you're trying to figure out the difference between a porter and a stout like just go google that.
Speaker 0: But if you just want to internalize the scope of beer and spend about an hour doing it, it's entertaining.
Speaker 0: It has a lot of context.
Speaker 0: It's really well done.
Speaker 0: It explains interesting and relevant details.
Speaker 0: I guess it's much more curated than any website I've seen like this.
Speaker 0: It's one of the rare examples of a video that I think is sufficiently information dense to be useful and interesting.
Speaker 0: It's also legitimately entertaining if you don't give a shit about beer.
Speaker 1: I learned a lot from this video.
Speaker 1: I feel like what you could do I think if this was a webpage.
Speaker 1: right, if I was someone who cared about beer.
Speaker 0: There are web pages like that.
Speaker 0: I could link to like 10 of them.
Speaker 0: There's like two different competing big beer wikis.
Speaker 1: What I would do is I would just make a fucking checklist and I would drink one of everything over a period of time.
Speaker 0: This provides a lot of history and interesting context too that I did not know about some of these varieties of beers.
Speaker 0: Some beers I thought were very similar have very different histories.
Speaker 0: It reminded me that the czech pilsners are delicious for a reason.
Speaker 0: Is sugar the reason?
Speaker 0: No, better quality.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 0: Better quality and specific varieties of hops is the main reason.
Speaker 1: Anyway, all right.
Speaker 1: So there's an old game, an Atari game called Pole Position.
Speaker 1: Pole Position I think is actually a fantastic game because even with a crappy old computer from the 80s that doesn't have a lot of bits, a racing game was actually one of the earliest types of games.
Speaker 1: You could make a really smooth, high quality racing game without much because the only controls you have are sort of analog left and right.
Speaker 0: It's not really 3D like the way they actually render these graphics.
Speaker 1: Right, exactly.
Speaker 1: There's not much to it.
Speaker 1: It's just sort of like, "Stay in line.
Speaker 1: Don't go on the
Speaker 1: grass.".
Speaker 1: It's not that complex.
Speaker 0: I don't remember if it was a launch title, but there was an Atari 2600, Pole Position, whatever.
Speaker 0: When the Atari 7800 came out, which was similarly powerful pre-MMC chip to the Nintendo Entertainment System, it had some flaws that made it not succeed in the end of course.
Speaker 1: You and your 7800 talking to, you know, everyone.
Speaker 1: But they released a 7800 only version of Pole Position that was shockingly advanced for its time.
Speaker 1: I mean, you know, there were plenty of games.
Speaker 1: There was Outrun, Rad Racer, all kinds of these games.
Speaker 1: Pole Position was the first one and the other ones didn't make too much improvement on it.
Speaker 1: I guess Outrun had better music and art and whatnot.
Speaker 1: But anyway, for a very long period of time, there was a high score at Pole Position, right?
Speaker 1: We're talking arcade Pole Position with the actual sit-down cabinet with the steering wheel and everything.
Speaker 1: And no one had really broken it, but this person in September, I had this thing of the day sitting around a while.
Speaker 1: I just didn't use it until now.
Speaker 1: In September, Daniel Yamnitz on their own YouTube channel recorded a video of presumably the cabinet that they own playing the legit old original Pole Position on the, you know, tournament competition settings.
Speaker 1: At the end of the video, they're like, "Oh, I got the high score.
Speaker 1: I better go take a look at the jumpers to prove I didn't cheat,".
Speaker 1: right?
Speaker 1: It doesn't look like they cheated at all.
Speaker 1: And yeah, they beat the world record for Pole Position.
Speaker 1: It's quite amazing.
Speaker 1: I've always wondered what was the fastest way to race in Pole Position, because it's a pretty short game, right?
Speaker 1: You do a qualifier, you do a race, and that's sort of it.
Speaker 1: You don't keep racing or anything.
Speaker 1: So apparently the fastest way to do it is obviously you got to start in low gear and then go to high gear as soon as you can and stay in high gear and drive like a lunatic and only go down to low gear and hit the brakes.
Speaker 1: I can't even tell if he's hitting the brakes, but for very short periods of time when you're taking like the really hard turns or otherwise in danger and stay out of the grass as much as possible, obviously only go into it very briefly for these ridiculous turns.
Speaker 1: Obviously don't crash into any other cars and do that the whole time and you'll get a score of 67,260.
Speaker 1: So congrats, Daniel.
Speaker 1: That was awesome.
Speaker 1: I like Pole Position.
Speaker 1: It's a good game.
Speaker 0: It is a good game.
Speaker 0: God, now I just have flashbacks to hanging out in the not RIT's cafeteria, but U of R's cafeteria because there was that DDR machine and there was a Ridge Racer around the corner from it.
Speaker 1: The Ridge Racer is 3D.
Speaker 1: Cruisin' World, Cruisin' USA, I think were the last significant racing games to have like the sort of 2D model.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you want to go old.
Speaker 0: Look at Night Driver on the Atari 2600.
Speaker 0: The road is just dots on two sides.
Speaker 1: Virtua Racing was the first major one to be 3D.
Speaker 0: Oh my God, that Virtua Racer arcade machine with the four views you could pick between.
Speaker 1: Virtua Racer is basically, I consider that to be Pole Position too, right?
Speaker 1: It's like, do I need any other racing games besides Pole Position and Virtua Racing?
Speaker 1: I feel like I don't, anyway.
Speaker 0: So, in the meta moment, the Geek Design Book Club book is still the tale of Genji.
Speaker 1: Since I'm not working, I read so many chapters like yesterday and the day before.
Speaker 0: It's easy to steamroll through if you just sit down and read and like I've said before, if you don't sweat too much, like who exactly is having a particular conversation unless it's really important?
Speaker 0: You can read a summary or like figure that out after you finish the chapter.
Speaker 1: I think what happens a lot is like, for example, in the chapter I just read, what actually happened in the chapter?
Speaker 1: You know, some people talked about a thing, right?
Speaker 1: So that conversation was sort of what happened, but half the chapter was like describing the scenery of where they were in great detail.
Speaker 1: Like, ah, yes, there were these torches and these flowers and they were standing in this garden and the garden looked like this and there was an event happening in the garden that was like this and then eventually they came, you know, they were sitting between this curtain and now they have the conversation.
Speaker 0: It's like, it's interesting how the like the mini climaxes and like the big moments in Genji are these extremely short like couple sentences and then the entire, it's like you could totally miss them because there's no, you know, narrative flow.
Speaker 0: More than once I've been reading anyway and then I back up like, oh shit, did she just die?
Speaker 0: And I back up like, oh shit.
Speaker 0: But like I'll get several paragraphs past a death before I realize someone actually died right there.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: So yeah, people die.
Speaker 1: In other meta news, since I'm not working, I got a lot of stuff going on.
Speaker 1: It's December, which means advent of code, even though I don't celebrate Christmas.
Speaker 1: I'm doing 25 two-part computing programming puzzles between December 1st and December 25th.
Speaker 1: So I'm uploading that to YouTube, my YouTube channel every day until I give up on it.
Speaker 1: Who knows?
Speaker 1: Last year I did all of them, except two stars.
Speaker 1: So not too bad.
Speaker 1: Also a new website is coming along.
Speaker 1: Those are basically my two priorities, right?
Speaker 1: I'm doing a lot of things, but my two highest priorities are the new website, which is making a ton of progress now and the reading the book.
Speaker 0: Don't forget to invoice me for when we got to pay our contractor.
Speaker 1: But yeah, things are moving along and I'm also going to be making other things once those two other main priorities, right?
Speaker 1: I still got some time after that.
Speaker 1: So yep, stuff's happening.
Speaker 0: And on Friday this week, I will be at PAX Unplugged for a few hours.
Speaker 0: I'm going to roll in at 1pm, do a panel in the Crab God Theater, Rare Game Mechanics.
Speaker 0: I've rewritten half this panel.
Speaker 0: I watched the panel we did before again.
Speaker 0: I did some more research, but if you are not already going to PAX Unplugged, you do not need to worry about missing this because like I've said repeatedly, I am going to upload this to YouTube before the end of PAX Unplugged.
Speaker 0: unless something happens like, I don't know, someone steals my camcorder out of the back of the room and runs away with it and somehow escapes.
Speaker 0: Unless something terrible happens, video of this will be online before PAX Unplugged even ends on YouTube.
Speaker 0: And otherwise, we'll see how many shows we do toward the end of the holiday period when holiday stuff happens, but we're both generally around.
Speaker 0: So generally, Geek Dies episodes are going to just keep coming out.
Speaker 0: Alright, let's get right into it.
Speaker 0: So, full disclosure, I like Metroid games, but I have not played many recent Metroid games, and this Metroid Dread was literally my foray back into Metroid.
Speaker 1: I have played just about every Metroid game ever, some of them several times.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: Also, you're pretty good and fast, especially some of the older Metroids.
Speaker 1: No, that is not true.
Speaker 1: If you are good and fast, I am garbage next to people who are good and fast.
Speaker 0: You're good and fast relative to the average rando.
Speaker 1: That's true, if it's a game that I've played before, then I know where stuff is.
Speaker 0: So, I hadn't played a bunch of Metroids in a while.
Speaker 0: Did you actually beat it?
Speaker 0: Did you do the last little bit today?
Speaker 0: I haven't beaten it yet because I only started playing it a week ago.
Speaker 1: Yeah, when this game came out, Metroid Dread came out, I immediately played it a whole bunch, and I got all the way to the final boss, and then I didn't feel like beating it because I was like, "Well, then it's going to be over.
Speaker 1: There won't be any more
Speaker 1: Metroid.".
Speaker 0: I know that feeling.
Speaker 0: I fucked around not killing Ganon for a long time in Breath of the Wild.
Speaker 1: So, then Rym was like, "Well, let's do a show on it
Speaker 1: today.".
Speaker 1: So, I'm like, "Well, so earlier today, since, again, I'm not working the entire month, I went ahead and I just loaded it up and I beat the final boss, and that was the
Speaker 1: end.".
Speaker 0: Yep, I got to Bird Uncle and I just beat that big, like, tentacle boss.
Speaker 0: However far that is through the game, but it's moving along and I've played it enough to have a lot of thoughts on the game mechanics.
Speaker 0: Hot top level, though, Metroid Dread.
Speaker 0: Remember, it is a 2D Metroid, which is a big deal.
Speaker 0: 2D games, especially Metroidvanias and Metroids, are somewhat like, they're my jam and they're Scott's jam.
Speaker 0: Just keep making them and making them good.
Speaker 0: I'll just keep playing them.
Speaker 0: But, two, I really liked it so far.
Speaker 0: I plan to beat it soon and I highly recommend it.
Speaker 0: if you like 2D Metroid games.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean, that's pretty much all there is to it.
Speaker 1: I think I talked about it a bit when it came out on the show, but just, you know, yeah, let's, you know, just reiterate, right?
Speaker 1: It's like, some people say that, like, this is the best Metroid there is, which, you know, I could understand why you might say that, right?
Speaker 1: It's clearly the most polished, right?
Speaker 1: It has all the benefits of being made in the current year and not in 1990-whatever.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: Similar to how many people say Breath of the Wild is the best Zelda game ever made and that is a plausible argument, but there are also very plausible counter arguments to that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's sort of like when you're comparing, like, you know, baseball players now to Babe Ruth and it's like, okay, it's like, you know, Babe Ruth, if he had to play baseball now, would be, like, you know, he was a schlub, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Or like hockey.
Speaker 1: He would not be good if he had to play baseball now against current baseball player, right?
Speaker 1: But then again, if he was born in 1980 or 90-something, right, with the same DNA and the same, you know, whatever, he would have had the advantages of all the modern advancements in nutrition and fitness and maybe he would be even better, right?
Speaker 0: Or here's an example.
Speaker 0: There's a famous hockey player, uh, Sawchuck.
Speaker 0: If you're not a hockey person, go Google a picture of this person.
Speaker 0: You'll understand exactly what his deal is.
Speaker 0: Was he great because he was great or was part of his greatness because he was one of the few people willing to take pucks to the face in an arrow and there was not a lot of protection?
Speaker 1: Also, you know, Wayne Gretzky's got all those, you know, so many goals and assists, but he played in a time where it was easier to score.
Speaker 1: If you had to play now, he wouldn't be able to score as much, right?
Speaker 1: So, you know, people are like, well, you know, is Ovechkin better than Gretzky?
Speaker 1: No, but he is a better scorer.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: He's, you know, Wayne Gretzky would probably, if he had to play hockey today, if he started his career, when Ovechkin started his career, he probably wouldn't have, you know, as many goals as Ovechkin has.
Speaker 0: Of course, Wayne Gretzky would score from all over the place.
Speaker 0: He didn't have an office where everyone could be like, he's there.
Speaker 0: He's right fucking there.
Speaker 0: Do something or he's going to score.
Speaker 1: He also mostly got assists at, you know, most of his, his unbeatable records are mostly points-based and not goal-based team player.
Speaker 0: But yeah, that's why it's hard to say if this is the best game.
Speaker 1: So it's like, if you just compare the games to get all the Metroid games against each other and don't take any other, don't, you know, sort of do any sort of grading, uh, right.
Speaker 1: Um, then, yeah, it's probably the best Metroid game, but if you say, well, look at what the games were when Super Metroid came out, it's like Super Metroid was punching way above its time, right?
Speaker 0: Super Metroid was like a decade ahead of its time.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: You know, Metroid Dread, is it ahead of its time?
Speaker 1: Not really.
Speaker 1: It's just sort of, it's at its time.
Speaker 0: It's exactly what I wanted to play right now.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: It's, it's just, it's the Metroid experience, right?
Speaker 1: Polished extremely heavily, right?
Speaker 1: Uh, and that's it, right?
Speaker 0: Like very similar to, uh, not to harp on this, uh, Castlevania games, like the other half of the Metroidvania type of world.
Speaker 0: We had Symphony of the Night, which was phenomenal.
Speaker 0: There's a bunch of other 2D Metroid, or Metroids, Castlevanias that came after that.
Speaker 0: They're really good.
Speaker 0: Some of them might even be equal to, or in some ways, some narrow ways, I'm being very specific here, better than Symphony of the Night.
Speaker 0: However, if you look at what existed in that genre or that space before Symphony of the Night, Symphony of the Night was like an alien from space coming down and handing onto us a new artifact.
Speaker 1: Except for Super Metroid.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but, but it was, it was a super, there's a reason why the power of Super Metroid and Castlevania became a genre that to this day we call Metroidvania.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So, I mean, you know, if you like a Metroid game, Metroid Dread is going to give you, you know, terms of controls in terms of graphics, in terms of, you know, design, music, you know, everything is pretty much, you know, as good as it's going to be.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: You know, there is, you will find no flaw on this heavily polished stone.
Speaker 1: At least no like, you know, flaw that you can say is sort of like a universal objective flaw.
Speaker 1: Like, ah, this, you know, there's something wrong with it.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: However, for at least me personally, you know, this is what I mentioned last time I talked about it.
Speaker 1: There are a few things that for me make it only second best to Super Metroid probably.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: So the first is that, you know, there's a plot and it's not a bad plot.
Speaker 1: Um, it's a better plot than some of the like Metroid Fusion, for example.
Speaker 0: I like in the beginning how the plot is given to you in drips and drabs and typical video gamey way, like, oh, here's the computer.
Speaker 0: It tells you some stuff, but then there's a point where bird uncle shows up and just spends like four minutes just telling you what's happening.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: It's like, but the like rim said, given to you in basically cut scenes, talking, voice acting, these sorts of things, Super Metroid, part of the magic of Super Metroid.
Speaker 1: And I am going to compare this game to Super Metroid a lot, which is fair, right?
Speaker 1: Uh, Super Metroid, the only plot that they give you in like, and part of it was the technological limitations of the Super Nintendo.
Speaker 1: You couldn't really have a video cut scene with voice acting so easily, um, and not use up all the memory on the cartridge, but the only really plot it gives you in text form is just, you know, uh, that one voice acting at the beginning, right?
Speaker 1: Where it's like the last Metroid is in captivity.
Speaker 1: The galaxy is at peace.
Speaker 1: And then some text, a little bit of text and every, all the rest of the story is told to you in game.
Speaker 1: It's like, they don't cut away.
Speaker 1: It's like, you know, spoilers are Super Metroid, right?
Speaker 1: When the baby Metroid that was at the end of Metroid two comes back and it's enormous, right?
Speaker 1: It's like, you just see it there.
Speaker 1: You can, you're still Sam is you're still looking at the game.
Speaker 1: You're still walking around.
Speaker 1: You can try to shoot it and everything, right?
Speaker 1: It's like, it's right there.
Speaker 1: You know, it's in the plot of Super Metroid is integrated into the gameplay the same way that half-life.
Speaker 1: one and two do it.
Speaker 1: Half-life does it a little bit less good, you know, cause they do, they trap you in a room and make guys talk to you sometimes.
Speaker 1: Um, but even so, in my opinion, that is the right way to have a plot in a video game.
Speaker 1: A cut scene just makes it less of a game and more of a movie.
Speaker 1: Um, Metroid Dread doesn't have, isn't like some ridiculous, you know, Metal Gear cut scene thing where this cut scene is all over the place.
Speaker 0: Um, you know, it's mostly not cut scenes, but like when you beat a boss, you're playing the game, fighting the boss the whole time.
Speaker 0: But when you finally beat the boss, most of the time it cuts to like a really mini cut scene that shows how bad ass Samus is doing the things that you can't do with the controller.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Um, but yeah, a lot of the plot is told to you with cut scenes as opposed to environmental storytelling.
Speaker 1: And that to me is a negative, right?
Speaker 1: I like the environmental storytelling better where you're just playing the game the whole time.
Speaker 1: The second thing is...
Speaker 0: Even the original Metroid, like why are there these weird bird statues everywhere?
Speaker 1: Right, exactly.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Whereas here it's like the bird statues are these beings called Chozo.
Speaker 1: Here's one of them.
Speaker 1: It's talking to you now.
Speaker 0: Of course the original Metroid, you couldn't even know what they were at all.
Speaker 0: It wasn't even really that good.
Speaker 1: You could, because it was in the instruction manual.
Speaker 0: Ah, yes.
Speaker 0: A bunch of text exposition that was given to you in a physical cut scene.
Speaker 1: But the instruction, all the instruction manual told you is like, it's Chozo.
Speaker 1: And you're like, what the fuck is Chozo?
Speaker 1: It didn't tell you anything else.
Speaker 1: Regardless, the second thing is that other Metroid games, even Super Metroid to a large extent, um, there's bad guys that are just, you know, the non-boss bad guys, uh, are, you know, all over the place, but they're largely not a threat to you ever.
Speaker 0: Unless you're not cautious.
Speaker 0: Like if you're just like not that good or not paying attention or getting lazy, it's easy to bump into them.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: But for the most part, like the bad guys in Metroid games are just sort of decorations on the level, right?
Speaker 1: They give you something to do, a reason to shoot your gun when it's not a boss, right?
Speaker 1: Just like, Oh, there's a bad guys in this room.
Speaker 1: I guess I have to push the shoot button a few times to get to the other side of the room.
Speaker 1: I can't just run across.
Speaker 0: It gives you a natural sense of progression.
Speaker 0: And then as you just get better at the game, you can move through areas you've been through where there's enemies, you know how to handle faster or competently with less thought.
Speaker 0: Like you just sort of memorize a pattern or no, you can run past a certain guy or you have a better upgraded weapon at that point.
Speaker 0: And they go down easier, but it does give you a sense of progression that you wouldn't get if you were just exploring and fighting bosses.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: But for the most part, the bad guys aren't part of the challenge of a Metroid game, the normal bad guys.
Speaker 1: They're just, you know, decoration, environment stuff, right?
Speaker 1: Whereas in Metroid Dread, the regular old bad guys.
Speaker 1: for, you know, as you progress through the game, if you backtrack to an area where there's weaker bad guys than your current equipment, yeah, they're just going to be decoration.
Speaker 1: But as you're progressing through the game, the regular old bad guys are like in your way, you have to get past them and you have to actually do a little bit of like action game button timing stuff to get to defeat them, right?
Speaker 1: They're not necessarily difficult, though there is a hard mode.
Speaker 1: you can unlock after you beat the game, which probably does make them more difficult.
Speaker 0: But they also, when they hit you, especially in an area you haven't fully explored yet that you're currently supposed to be in, they'll mess you up.
Speaker 0: They do a shit ton of damage, way more than I expected.
Speaker 1: Even on not hard mode, right?
Speaker 1: If you mess up, then you pay the price.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: And also, right, the bosses are very much, you know, the classic action game.
Speaker 1: Simon says, you see this animation, that means you have to do this.
Speaker 1: That means slide, that means jump, that means dash to evade that enemy's attack, that means shoot him now, right?
Speaker 1: And that's how you defeat enemies because that's how action games work, right?
Speaker 1: And then you also have some timing things, right?
Speaker 1: It's like when you see a flash, push X to counter attack.
Speaker 1: You also have a little bit of quick time event things at certain parts in little cut scenes here and there, not too much, very small amount.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we'll describe the enemy thing because I think there's some interesting game mechanics stuff to talk about there.
Speaker 0: There's good and bad parts of that aspect of this game.
Speaker 1: Right, but the point I'm making is that this Metroid is much more of an action game than other Metroids.
Speaker 1: where the action parts are, you can just sort of gloss over them and just, it's more, the exploring is what matters.
Speaker 0: Because one specific thing I noticed in this Metroid compared to other Metroids I have played is that in this one, you know, the typical fashion, you get items that lets you interact with or get past obstacles you couldn't get past before, kind of like in a Zelda 3.
Speaker 0: Now you can go back and go to an area you couldn't go to before, like.
Speaker 0: that's a big part of the game loop.
Speaker 0: But in older Metroids, you could explore a lot more broadly and when you got a new item, the game didn't do a ton of work to point you in the right direction of where you could use it.
Speaker 0: It kind of assumed you'd explore and figure stuff out, backtrack on your own, etc.
Speaker 0: This game often, when you solve a puzzle in a certain area, it'll, you get to a certain point in these areas, it'll block paths in that area to really push you into backtracking toward where the interesting stuff is that you can interact with the things you recently acquired.
Speaker 0: So, it'll like, you find a teleporter pad early in the game, the first one, and as soon as you use it, a bunch of shit falls down and blocks the path back, so you're forced to go forward in the area you just got to.
Speaker 0: That happens a lot.
Speaker 0: You can often get around those blocks if you really want to backtrack and get the one thing the game's guiding you away from, but it's often tedious, so I tend to just go where the game wants me to go.
Speaker 0: But it did remove a small aspect of exploration that I did enjoy more in other Metroid games.
Speaker 1: At a certain point, the game does sort of unlock and you can go anywhere freely, but yeah, at least they did a better job of that than Metroid Fusion does.
Speaker 1: Metroid Fusion literally, you're locked in this zone, now go to the next zone.
Speaker 1: Whereas this did the same concept, but made it feel more natural and integrated, but it still was, I still prefer Super Metroid.
Speaker 1: It's like, you can just go anywhere that you can go.
Speaker 1: It's up to you to remember where, or figure out where the, you know, remember there was a green door you couldn't open.
Speaker 1: You just got super missile.
Speaker 1: Where was that green door again?
Speaker 1: Oh, right.
Speaker 1: It was over in that place.
Speaker 1: Let me go to that place and use my green.
Speaker 0: It is hard to express how fucking jazzed I was to be able to open green doors, right?
Speaker 0: That's that's so those green doors, the whole game.
Speaker 0: And I'm just like, damn it.
Speaker 0: How do I get in there?
Speaker 1: But anyway, so it's more of an action game.
Speaker 1: And the, the action game that it is, is an extremely polished, high quality action game.
Speaker 1: Like there aren't much better.
Speaker 1: I just personally, I'm not playing Metroid for the action.
Speaker 1: So I'm a, it's like, yeah, they put in like one of the best possible action games.
Speaker 1: That's amazing.
Speaker 1: But I would rather have that personally, I'd rather have there be no action game.
Speaker 1: It's like, I want the enemies that don't really challenge me.
Speaker 1: I want to just, I want, I'm there for the explorer.
Speaker 0: You want just like an Odyssey?
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean, I'm not there for, you know, shooting the regular old bad guys or for a really complicated boss.
Speaker 1: I'm just, I just want to fill the boss full of missiles.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: It's like, you know, there's a bad guy.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: I'll shoot the bad guy.
Speaker 1: But it's like, I don't want to have to have like the dual with this regular old bad guy.
Speaker 0: And you know, it's like, but I also don't, I don't want to go back to original Metroid one on the NES of you better have 90 missiles and you don't miss with any of them.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: That's also the wrong Ridley in that game sucks.
Speaker 1: There's a reason I'm comparing to super Metroid, not regular one is you don't need to read this.
Speaker 0: Not like most Metro games are playing.
Speaker 0: You don't really need to go back and beat the original Metroid.
Speaker 1: You, what you, what you should do is you should play the original Metroid a little bit so you can understand what it was like.
Speaker 0: That'll tell you everything you needed to know about that game.
Speaker 1: Then play Metroid zero mission.
Speaker 0: I guess also internalize only better.
Speaker 0: The coolest thing Metroid one did was the game was called Metroid.
Speaker 0: The instruction book was like, watch out for fucking Metro.
Speaker 0: They will fuck you up.
Speaker 0: You come into the game.
Speaker 0: There are no Metro until the very, very, very end of the game.
Speaker 1: Well, I think that Nintendo had a pattern of that, right?
Speaker 1: Zelda was legend of Zelda.
Speaker 1: It was, it was not named after the name character.
Speaker 1: It's like.
Speaker 1: Metroid is not named.
Speaker 1: The main character is Sam is not right.
Speaker 1: It's like, you know, Mario.
Speaker 1: It's like, okay, the name of the game is the name of the main character.
Speaker 1: You know, Sonic, the name of the game is the main character.
Speaker 1: Zelda and Metroid.
Speaker 1: No, it's not.
Speaker 1: The name of the game is not the name of the character.
Speaker 1: It's the name of something else, right?
Speaker 0: But then you finally encounter Metroids and they're just all up in your grill.
Speaker 0: There's a million of them constantly coming at you and it's crazy.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: So the thing they get the mechanic, cause every Metroid game, well, most measure games have like either a new mechanic or the thing that's interesting about this Metroid.
Speaker 0: This one is it has the stealth component around a particular kind of.
Speaker 0: there's sort of a boss.
Speaker 0: I'd say that they count as bosses.
Speaker 1: Maybe.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: There's there's bosses and then there's Emmys or EMMIs, which sort of function like bosses, but they're a little bit different.
Speaker 0: They add a stealth element that I have not encountered in Metroid games I've played before.
Speaker 0: Metroid Fusion has the, I never played Metroid Fusion.
Speaker 0: full disclosure.
Speaker 1: A little bit.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Well then how do you understand what's going on in Metroid Dread?
Speaker 0: Uh, cause the plot is really simplistic and it's really straightforward.
Speaker 1: Well, you know, anyway, so yeah, the Emmy thing is basically there are certain zones in each, in each of the areas of the planet.
Speaker 1: Cause it's a Metroid game, named areas of the planet, but each major named area has a zone.
Speaker 1: That's like the Emmy zone.
Speaker 1: So when you go there, there's like these doors and you can just tell it cause it signals to you visually that once you go in that door, you'll be in the Emmy zone.
Speaker 1: And the Emmy zone is all weird and scary.
Speaker 1: And there's an Emmy in there and you basically can't kill it.
Speaker 1: It's invincible.
Speaker 1: If it grabs you, you can escape with some really well-timed button presses.
Speaker 1: Maybe if you're really good.
Speaker 0: The game is even like, look, listen, kids, don't think this is a mechanic.
Speaker 0: We expect you to use, do not rely on this.
Speaker 0: Do not like try to get good at it.
Speaker 0: It is not the way to play.
Speaker 1: I'm sure there are people who can do it every time.
Speaker 1: No problem.
Speaker 1: I had about like a 30% success rate.
Speaker 1: I'm getting fascinating.
Speaker 0: Uh, it as echoes of something that five nights at Freddy's did very well too.
Speaker 0: Uh, if the game was, cause the way this works is when you get into an Emmy zone, they will like, listen for you, hunt you down.
Speaker 0: And if they touch you barring this quick time event, it's instant death.
Speaker 0: You just die.
Speaker 0: There's nothing you can do.
Speaker 0: You cannot fight them.
Speaker 0: You cannot even like shooting them.
Speaker 0: Doesn't really do anything.
Speaker 1: You just, they're just invincible.
Speaker 0: So if they, if them touching you was just instant death, that's still really scary.
Speaker 0: But the fact that there's this tiny chance you might be able to escape by hitting X at the right time during that animation gives you this false sense of hope and makes you like engage more with this instant death mechanic and it increases.
Speaker 1: Otherwise, if you didn't have a chance, you would just like, you know, you know, as soon as you knew you were caught, you'd be like, fuck it.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: You wouldn't even, but it's like you hold on and you actually experience the horror of being caught.
Speaker 1: You submit yourself to that.
Speaker 0: Similar to how five nights at Freddy's to escape gives you all these, it does all these things to convince you as a player, instead of just closing your eyes.
Speaker 0: Cause you know, the jump stairs coming, leaning in and paying attention to, so you end up getting more gotten by the jump scare than you as an intelligence adult would have been.
Speaker 0: This mechanic in Metroid Dread literally increases the dread you as a player feel around these Emmys.
Speaker 0: And I think that is the most interesting mechanical innovation used in this game, like full stop.
Speaker 1: Now, the problem is, is that, you know, when I started playing the game, the first couple Emmy zones, right.
Speaker 1: It totally worked, right.
Speaker 1: It was very scary to go in the Emmy zones.
Speaker 1: The Emmy was catching me all the time.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: But then by the third or fourth Emmy zone, I realized like, wait a minute, this game is structured in such a way.
Speaker 1: Like, I don't need to go.
Speaker 1: Cause I was trying to explore the Emmy zone while avoiding the Emmy to figure out what the hell to do in there.
Speaker 1: But then I realized, wait a minute, every time you encounter a new Emmy door, the game is designed for you to just run through to the next Emmy door and escape the zone.
Speaker 1: And if you just keep going forward in that fashion, as quickly as you can, you'll eventually arrive at the method to get rid of the Emmy permanently, then unlock that zone, removing the Emmy so that you can explore it freely.
Speaker 1: There's no reason to hang around in there.
Speaker 1: So once I realized that after the, like the third Emmy zone, I never got caught by an Emmy again, ever.
Speaker 1: I fucked up some platforming, like that happens sometimes, but yeah, but it's like, I just, I saw an Emmy zone and I didn't even give a shit about what was in that zone.
Speaker 1: I just ran from, I looked at the map.
Speaker 1: I said, okay, well, this is the entrance.
Speaker 1: Where's the next exit.
Speaker 1: It's probably around there.
Speaker 1: And I just went in, I ran through as quickly as I could.
Speaker 1: I didn't do stealth metal gear style.
Speaker 1: I didn't try to do any shenanigans.
Speaker 1: I just ran through.
Speaker 1: no exploring, no nothing, you know, got out the other side and that the Emmy was now not scary at all.
Speaker 0: Once I realized, you know what the deal was, I think they should not have given you, they should not have let you destroy the Emmys.
Speaker 0: They should have done that differently.
Speaker 0: I'd rather know.
Speaker 1: I think letting you destroy them is fine.
Speaker 1: I think what they should have done is given you some incentive or reason to explore and hang out in the Emmy zone while the Emmy was still there.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Don't just construct it in such a way that like, yeah, just run through and explore it later.
Speaker 1: It's like, it's a Metroid game.
Speaker 1: I should basically always want to explore.
Speaker 1: And you know, this thing should basically be like, yeah.
Speaker 0: Imagine if it was more like the Emmy was exploring under pressure.
Speaker 1: Imagine
Speaker 0: a bigger Emmy zone that was like really vertical, let's say, and there's a bunch of shit to explore and you couldn't destroy that Emmy, but it was further away from you and you had like more room to maneuver and you couldn't, you just literally had to, with that sense of dread play Metroid in a place where there's only one monster and it's really, really dangerous.
Speaker 1: But yeah, and also despite being stealth, right?
Speaker 1: You know, the old, the old palace guard stealth game, right?
Speaker 1: You're hiding in the hedge maze, Zelda 64 style.
Speaker 1: There's a lot of other games that do that.
Speaker 1: it's like, they could have done that.
Speaker 1: You could have brought in more than one Emmy and been like, okay, you're in a ball in some vents and it's like, go through the vents with the correct timing, looking at where the Emmys are so that their flashlights don't touch you while you're in ball shape.
Speaker 0: They made all the Emmys the same, which was also kind of boring.
Speaker 0: Like I wish the Emmys, they're not all exactly the same.
Speaker 1: They do get more dangerous, but dealing with them is effectively the same because you just don't run away from them.
Speaker 1: It's a problem.
Speaker 0: I call it the portal problem back when we played portal two all the way to the end.
Speaker 0: When I realized that portal one and portal two, the puzzles are really good.
Speaker 0: I really love those games.
Speaker 0: In fact, I'm actually finally playing the multiplayer with our friend right now.
Speaker 0: We're going to finish that like tomorrow.
Speaker 1: It's really early 20 years too late, but it's fun.
Speaker 0: But I realized like portal two got really easy when in the course of my playthrough pretty early on, I realized that there's so few avenues of solving puzzles just with the limited tools you have in the game that you can kind of just fall forward into solutions without thinking about the problem at all.
Speaker 0: Like, oh, there's two angled places.
Speaker 0: Definitely going to make something momentum.
Speaker 0: shoot out of those angles.
Speaker 0: One of the two of them will get me to the next area or we'll get the cube to the next area and approaching from the every puzzle in portal two with like one or two eventually rare exceptions.
Speaker 0: You can just fall forward into victory without even understanding what the puzzle was.
Speaker 0: And I've noticed the Emmys were the same way.
Speaker 0: Just fucking run and you'll beat the Emmy eventually without having to think about it at all.
Speaker 1: And I just think that puzzles though, there is one mini puzzle and that is, you know, you, you have in each Emmy area, you eventually beat.
Speaker 1: this brain thing is reminiscent of the original mother brain and you get your weapon temporarily powered up in such a way that it can defeat the Emmy.
Speaker 0: I like how you have to do the really like scary thing of shoot at it while it's approaching you until you melt the cover.
Speaker 1: But it's that sequence is actually sort of a puzzle because you need to shoot the gun at the Emmy.
Speaker 1: You need to charge it up, shoot it at the Emmy for a long enough period of time for it to break through the Emmy, right?
Speaker 1: It's not just like shoot it and you beat it.
Speaker 1: So it's a mini puzzle of you have to get Samus into a position where the Emmy is far enough away and coming at you slowly face first so that you can now get the weapon ready and fire it and have enough time to kill the Emmy with it before the Emmy reaches Samus.
Speaker 1: And it's like a mini puzzle to examine, you know, the limited arena in which the Emmy is and where you can go.
Speaker 0: Is there a really long one time it got me, there's a really long place.
Speaker 0: I think it was the third Emmy.
Speaker 0: And I was like, okay, I'll do the obvious thing.
Speaker 0: I'll stand at the end of this long, long area.
Speaker 0: And then I have a long time to shoot it.
Speaker 0: And it didn't follow down where I expected right away.
Speaker 0: And for just a second, I think, oh, did it go in and it fell on top of me.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: It's, there's a little mini puzzle of how do you get, you got to get the Emmy into the right spot and Samus into the right spot.
Speaker 1: And then, you know, there's an action game element of not only to do that, you have to skillfully get the weapon out and start shooting it with good aim and keep that good aim right on Emmy's head until it's destroyed without fucking up.
Speaker 1: So it's, that's a fun little game, like a sub game within a game there.
Speaker 0: But aesthetically, the other thing, the Emmys are not that interesting of a puzzle for all the reasons we discussed, but the other cool thing about them is at least in terms of their design, they are so creepy that like burbling chirping noise that they make when they're hunting you is fantastically creepy.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Everything aesthetic about this game is 100% on point, like nothing wrong with it whatsoever.
Speaker 0: The environments are all radically different and interesting.
Speaker 1: It's very Metroidy.
Speaker 1: All the Metroid tropes are intact.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I'm really enjoying it.
Speaker 1: If you have a Switch, you should play this game, obviously.
Speaker 0: It's a must buy game.
Speaker 0: If you've never played a Metroid game, you could just start with this one.
Speaker 0: You don't need to know anything else.
Speaker 1: You could just start with any of them, but I recommend playing, you know, actually the remade ones are going to be much better to play.
Speaker 1: So I would play Metroid Zero Mission.
Speaker 1: Samus Returns, which is for the 3DS is a remake of Metroid 2.
Speaker 1: Super Metroid is Metroid 3, and it's never been remade because it doesn't need to be remade.
Speaker 1: You can just play it on your Switch.
Speaker 1: also though, in that Super Nintendo app, if you have Switch online.
Speaker 1: And then you've got Metroid Fusion, which is kind of meh.
Speaker 1: Maybe you can like read about it or play it if you really want to.
Speaker 0: Don't play Metroid Hunters.
Speaker 1: That's the Metroid games that aren't in the Metroid main series.
Speaker 0: That one is actually listed in the official Metroid story chronology for some reason.
Speaker 1: I mean, they're all in the story chronology somewhere, but it's like Metroid 1, 2, 3, 4.
Speaker 1: This Metroid Dread is actually Metroid 5, right?
Speaker 1: Metroid Prime is like a side prequel deal, right?
Speaker 1: And Metroid Hunters is another offshoot side deal.
Speaker 1: The only main Metroid games that are 2D, normal Metroid games are Metroids 1, 2, 3, 4, 5.
Speaker 1: That's it.
Speaker 1: And this is Metroid 5.
Speaker 1: So Metroid Fusion is Metroid 4.
Speaker 1: So, you know, it's not as good as the other ones, but it won't take you that long to beat it.
Speaker 1: You know, it won't be a complete waste of time, but you don't have to.
Speaker 1: It's not as good.
Speaker 1: You can read about it just to get the plot, synopsis, whatever.
Speaker 1: And then play this one for reals.
Speaker 0: This has been Geek Nights with Rim and Scott.
Speaker 0: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design, and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at frontrowcrew.com for show notes, discussion news, and more.
Speaker 0: Remember, Geek Nights is not one, but four different shows.
Speaker 0: SciTech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays, and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: Geek Nights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: Geek Nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 1: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.
Speaker 0: And the Patreon patrons for this episode of Geek Nights are... Oh, they're not sorted.
Speaker 0: Let's see.
Speaker 0: One.
Speaker 0: Patreon.
Speaker 0: There we go.
Speaker 0: Heidi McNichol, Alan Joyce, Link Egee, Dread, Lily Tenebrae, and a bunch of people who don't want me to say their names.
Speaker 0: Chris Reimer, Clinton Walton, Dex Finn, JustLikeADudeGuy, Kishii85, Rebecca Dunn, ReviewMadBull34, Cowards, Ryan Perrin, Sam Erickson, Shervin Von Horrell, Taylor Braun, The Iron Front, You Hold the Key to My Heart, a bunch of people who do not want me to say their names.
Speaker 0: And I don't know how many shows we'll do in the coming few weeks, because as I said, you know, it's the holiday season, we got stuff going on, but we'll do several.
Speaker 0: Don't know if I'll be able to hang out with anyone at Unplugged.
Speaker 0: I'm really literally just going to be in and out.
Speaker 0: But for now, I leave you with something that will likely be a thing of the day next week.
Speaker 1: I don't want a lot of Christmas.
Speaker 1: There is just one thing that I need.
Speaker 1: What about the presents underneath the Christmas tree?
Speaker 1: I just want to boldly go more than you could ever know.
Speaker 1: Make my wish come true.
Speaker 0: All I want for Christmas is Captain Long.
Speaker 1: It's almost Christmas, and there is just one thing I need.
Speaker 0: I don't care about the presents underneath the Christmas tree.
Speaker 1: I don't want to hang my stocking there above the fireplace.
Speaker 1: Number one won't make me happy with the toy on the Christmas day.
Speaker 0: I just want to make it so more than you could ever know.
Speaker 1: Make my wish come true.
Speaker 1: All I want for Christmas is.