Speaker 1: It's Thursday March 25th 2021.
Speaker 1: I'm rim I'm Scott and this is geek nights tonight We were talking about solitaire puzzles and puzzle books and such like.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: so uh try to make plans for this weekend and tomorrow and the nice weather.
Speaker 1: and Scott I ran to a little bit of an impasse cuz I went to one website and it said it's gonna be like 79 degrees tomorrow and Case I would cancel work.
Speaker 1: and Scott went to a website that gave a like 15 to 20 degree lower estimate.
Speaker 0: We try that much lower.
Speaker 0: It was more like 10 degree lower.
Speaker 1: 10 degrees is still a significant difference.
Speaker 0: It is very significant degrees.
Speaker 1: Fahrenheit is like a seasonal difference like that's why I act and dress very differently If it's 60 versus 70 or 70.
Speaker 0: for yeah I mean the point is is that the weather of the coming next coming few days in this geographic area is Probably going to be at its coldest like at the night time like high 40s and High 50s on the forecast.
Speaker 0: I'm looking at right now and at the best part of the day It might be like low 70s at best right probably high 60s.
Speaker 0: So for a lot of people that's plenty good weather for going outside.
Speaker 0: for me.
Speaker 0: That's still a little cold.
Speaker 1: How did you get so old so fast?
Speaker 0: It's a little bit cold.
Speaker 1: I can't just go with no jacket shorts and If it's low 60s mid 60s if it's above 45 I can run in shorts and like a thin long sleeve shirt for hours.
Speaker 1: If it's above 60 I can just bike like shorts t-shirt, let's go.
Speaker 0: No, it's too cold.
Speaker 1: how Well anyway, uh Now, I don't know like.
Speaker 1: it'll be really interesting to see because we went to three different weather websites and got three significantly different weather forecasts for like tomorrow and Saturday.
Speaker 0: One of them you said had the wind warning tonight and another the National Weather Service at the wind warning tomorrow night.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so check to make sure you weren't reading.
Speaker 1: the weather says gale warning tonight Thursday we're checking.
Speaker 0: you were looking at weather calm weather calm.
Speaker 1: avoid the subject area as per instructions.
Speaker 1: gale warning Friday.
Speaker 1: Oh, no, it starts at Friday 8 a.m Okay Gale one so more.
Speaker 1: it starts Friday morning until Saturday morning, so it's all weekend.
Speaker 0: This know where.
Speaker 0: I don't know what weather calm you're looking at.
Speaker 1: Streaming it.
Speaker 1: I said it to Queens.
Speaker 0: Okay, yeah, 48 78 interesting.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: No No, yeah All right.
Speaker 1: We'll see how this go.
Speaker 0: whether that gov does not agree with weather.com.
Speaker 1: No, which is which is fascinating, but no the gale warning is apparently from tomorrow morning until Saturday morning.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 0: Well biking and gale is not great.
Speaker 1: Southwest wins 20 to 30 knots with gusts up to 40 for what the fuck?
Speaker 0: Now what I learned from a man that I met in a chance encounter while biking many years ago in the city.
Speaker 0: Is that as if it's not raining?
Speaker 0: That would be an excellent time to get your box.
Speaker 0: kite.
Speaker 1: Kite flying is something I have not done since I was.
Speaker 1: what was the like?
Speaker 1: we tried to fly a kite at RIT once.
Speaker 0: That's one of those things that could be a great Thursday geek night's episode if we knew anything the fuck about it.
Speaker 1: I know a little bit.
Speaker 1: I used to fly kites a lot.
Speaker 1: You don't know enough to talk about 30 minutes like a fucking expert Even if I can if I share every anecdote I have because some things happen with kites the anecdote I have.
Speaker 0: I've tried to fly kites like cheapo kites occasionally.
Speaker 0: Obviously those aren't gonna make my own kites.
Speaker 1: I had a collection of kites.
Speaker 1: I'd fly them all the time.
Speaker 1: I tried to get into that kite battling but it's actually not fun at all.
Speaker 0: And then I met at that dude one time and that was my kite.
Speaker 1: Was it the dude who's always on the east side bike path?
Speaker 0: No, because there's a dude.
Speaker 0: There's this dude who works at the the Queen Science Museum.
Speaker 0: I don't know if he's still there.
Speaker 1: I've seen this dude for like a decade.
Speaker 1: whenever I do my half marathons I always run like up the east side path and I come down like over Randall's.
Speaker 1: I like I have all this route.
Speaker 1: I do every time and There's one spot where if it's windy at all the same dude has been there for like a decade.
Speaker 1: fly in a gigantic box kite So far in the distance that it's like weird.
Speaker 0: That's how you know the pros.
Speaker 0: The kite is so far away.
Speaker 0: You think yeah helicopter a plane is.
Speaker 1: I've never seen him launch it.
Speaker 1: cuz he appears to start flying these kites like.
Speaker 0: I did actually meet one guy in that area one time on on one of the The bridges the pedestrian bridges that goes over the FDR.
Speaker 0: He was on the staircase.
Speaker 0: I don't know if it's the same guy, but I did meet a guy in that area one time.
Speaker 0: Yeah He didn't hand me his kite, but he let.
Speaker 0: he was.
Speaker 0: he's like feel the string.
Speaker 0: The string was tight like it felt like someone was yanking on the other end.
Speaker 1: feel the string was something that like.
Speaker 1: That was how I learned to fly kites.
Speaker 1: my dad when he was teaching me as a kid.
Speaker 1: I remember he would like not hand me the kite because a little kid just I think was afraid I just lose it or something.
Speaker 1: But he was like touch the string see how it stops.
Speaker 1: you know It's pulling and that's how he kind of taught me like he made me put my hand on his string.
Speaker 0: Getting into that situation.
Speaker 0: you know once you once it's there, it's like okay You're just holding this thing right.
Speaker 0: you can let out string or bring in string But you know getting it well.
Speaker 1: There's a novice with some basic lessons.
Speaker 1: if you have enough room to get a running start against the wind You can get a kite going pretty easily if you don't have like the east side path the reason I'm so fascinated with this dude.
Speaker 1: He's got to be a pro.
Speaker 1: Starting a kite especially a box kite from a standstill without like a running start.
Speaker 1: I could never fucking did it in my life Like I could never pull it up.
Speaker 0: bet if we search for this on YouTube we can just find we'll find videos of people like Doing it right.
Speaker 1: there's technique.
Speaker 1: the internet will tell us everything kind of like how way back I had that thing in the day that was like remember the pine bog the The pine box Derby like that that's bit, and how it's been ruined by the internet.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but how on the internet you can just look up the exact perfect car.
Speaker 1: everyone.
Speaker 0: Just instead just like net decking and magic people just net carring.
Speaker 1: yep As a kid I tried to make my thing is good.
Speaker 0: Even as a kid there was someone who they didn't net car cuz there was no net at the time.
Speaker 1: But like they had a parents who like knew they had.
Speaker 0: they knew someone who knew like the best design and because they had that Information from somebody right I remember the Cub Scouts.
Speaker 1: Well, I won the like our dens tournament like with the six of us in the den, and then I was like oh fuck I get to go compete now for real with like the actual like the whole pack, and I show
Speaker 0: up
Speaker 1: and There I saw that almost every other car was identical.
Speaker 1: They were all identical to each other with different colors exactly was way different and mine was like half the speed of theirs.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I want to say I cried.
Speaker 1: This was a long time ago.
Speaker 0: I didn't cry I was I was salty cool.
Speaker 1: I was real salty.
Speaker 0: I Thought my car was the coolest looking But actually you know it was.
Speaker 0: I just painted it red and put all kinds of.
Speaker 0: I got had these Rub on decal.
Speaker 1: those robot decals felt so good to put on.
Speaker 0: I rubbed on pretty much every decal.
Speaker 1: yep I got a decals like I wrote that fire on the side fire on the top.
Speaker 1: I put all the extra ones I didn't have anywhere to put on the bottom.
Speaker 1: Just cuz I wanted to you.
Speaker 1: I thought it was cool But I put a little metal man like with a helmet like in the top of it.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so uh yeah uh in the news.
Speaker 1: I was thinking to myself like what are we gonna Talk about?
Speaker 1: like what's what kind of news could I talk about?
Speaker 1: That I remembered.
Speaker 1: there is the biggest fucking news going on right now, and it is not everybody.
Speaker 0: everybody knows this news.
Speaker 0: It's not news.
Speaker 0: It's not news if you if you pay attention to the world at all you know this news.
Speaker 1: But the reason I want to talk about a little bit is one.
Speaker 1: It's it's on one hand Aspects of it are very funny.
Speaker 1: on the other hand Nothing like this has happened in a long time.
Speaker 1: This is like.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, this is a fucking Catastrophe.
Speaker 1: this is causing like global economic damage.
Speaker 1: This is hard.
Speaker 0: doing the typical we're doing.
Speaker 0: the typical geek nights.
Speaker 0: We were like we keep referring to a thing and then we say what it is.
Speaker 1: You know.
Speaker 1: It's funny.
Speaker 0: We uh way back You know it's the boat stuck in the canal.
Speaker 1: What else can we talking about?
Speaker 1: But Way back when we bought those our fancy chairs.
Speaker 1: if you listen to that geek nights episode where we talk about the chairs We spend almost nine minutes Leading up to actually saying that we bought chairs.
Speaker 1: at no point Do we say the word chair we keep talking about.
Speaker 1: we thought about doing this for a long time?
Speaker 0: Yes, it's the such a geek night's thing.
Speaker 1: But anyway you I'm not like you can read how this happened, it's amazing.
Speaker 1: this hasn't happened before like yeah, and Frankly if you're like me This is the kind of like Wikipedia rabbit hole that could occupy you for weeks.
Speaker 1: the the Suez Canal is a fascinating Topic.
Speaker 1: like seriously.
Speaker 1: I'm not kidding.
Speaker 1: go read the Wikipedia article about the Suez Canal.
Speaker 1: There is so much going on about that thing.
Speaker 1: you think a Panama Canal is important?
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm the Suez Canal.
Speaker 1: But the the other cool thing about this that you can learn is the sheer number of people whose sole Profession is continue is making the Suez Canal function.
Speaker 1: That is like an army of humans working every single day 24/7 to make that thing work.
Speaker 1: like Ships catches go into it They like form convoys.
Speaker 1: only like a hundred and sixty ships go through it a day like there's there is like how it works How they organize these ships.
Speaker 1: like there's a class of ship called a Suez max because it is literally the maximum size that can fit in the Suez Canal.
Speaker 1: It's super cool, but the article I'm gonna link to It actually talks about like what's the impact of this boat being stuck in this canal with that tiny little digger slowly working?
Speaker 1: enormous?
Speaker 1: enormous impacts 400 million dollars in economic damage alone an hour Every hour.
Speaker 1: 400 million u.s.
Speaker 1: Dollars of economic activity is being lost.
Speaker 1: and that's gonna see includes.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so this count this includes things like something isn't getting to his destination on time.
Speaker 0: therefore something else, right?
Speaker 0: It's includes things like something on a boat is spoilable and it's spoiled.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it includes things.
Speaker 0: Oh, it includes things like there is a suppose has to go a boat has to go around now Or we has to go around.
Speaker 0: some boats are waiting more Waiting.
Speaker 0: is I waiting or going around?
Speaker 0: doesn't matter that boat.
Speaker 0: Your is money is being lost.
Speaker 1: You can if you don't know where the Suez Canal is it connects the Red Sea in the Mediterranean Sea.
Speaker 1: go look at Google Maps And figure out how to get a boat between the Red Sea and the Mediterranean Sea if the Suez Canal is not there.
Speaker 1: But like that some of this damage is.
Speaker 1: there are goods that are part of a supply chain for other goods.
Speaker 1: So those other goods are not being blocked by this.
Speaker 1: But no one can make more of those.
Speaker 0: and then once the boat if the boat doesn't get to his destination to empty It doesn't get to fill with something else.
Speaker 0: It's the stuff waiting to go on a boat.
Speaker 0: Then the boat isn't showing up.
Speaker 0: You know an emptying.
Speaker 1: we're approaching the point where the impacts of this boat being stuck are going to last for years already literal years Mm-hmm and Like I learned some things.
Speaker 1: I think only like a hundred and seventy boats actually traverse a day because that's how much in each direction maybe total.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know they did.
Speaker 0: obviously, you know for such an important thing.
Speaker 0: It's it brings up questions like you know, well, it was working fine all this time, right?
Speaker 1: So it's how come this never happened?
Speaker 0: Well, no, and what do we know about boats?
Speaker 0: Nothing canals nothing, but it's like you could have like invested into the canal Maybe widened it deepened it.
Speaker 0: they have.
Speaker 1: there have been significant investments.
Speaker 1: The Suez Canal is better than 25. as late recently as 2015 There was significant work to make this canal even better.
Speaker 1: The Panama Canal is also good proved and made large not good enough.
Speaker 0: Apparently.
Speaker 1: Well, cuz there's no such thing is good enough.
Speaker 1: It's induced demand.
Speaker 1: No such thing is good now, I guess That's true unless every boat that wants to go anywhere in the world can get there Without having to wait at all.
Speaker 1: There's there's a bottleneck But like one of the things that we're not even counting yet all these ships that are stuck Mean that new ships can't even be loaded because it's a cargo containers have not made it back to places like China.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I said that already.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but like specifically the empty cargo containers are all bottled up now Just like being piled up like all over the u.s.
Speaker 1: This This is the it's interesting how a lot of news is get talked about a lot in pop culture around the world.
Speaker 1: But a news like this people are making fun of it and like it's the interesting situation.
Speaker 1: but very few people seem to really like be internalizing how Drastically this one ship having a accident in this one tiny place has impacted the world.
Speaker 0: Mmm, or at least you know the world of people who have money to buy goods.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah I mean there are people are not.
Speaker 0: you're not living in a capitalist kind of.
Speaker 0: you know a place with.
Speaker 0: you know That's involved in trade.
Speaker 0: if you know, then it probably won't affect you at all.
Speaker 0: Yep, there are still like weird ravification still that you know, but yeah majority of people on earth are affected but it will it.
Speaker 1: what it echoes is the one of the theories around the Bronze Age collapse Which is you know during the Bronze Age bronze was very important as you might.
Speaker 1: you don't say I don't say called it the Bronze Age like you don't say what was important about the Iron Age.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: What about the Stone Age?
Speaker 1: Why do we call it?
Speaker 0: Anyway, so the Stone Age?
Speaker 0: I don't think would have been.
Speaker 0: you know, I mean, it's like yes We only had the technology of stone in the Stone Age, but I don't think it would have been like.
Speaker 0: well It wouldn't because stone yes might yeah, it's like my.
Speaker 0: yeah, it's like my stone boat clogged up the canal on this.
Speaker 1: There was an era in the Bronze Age where there was a like large global trading network like Significant like massive trading network and a lot of complex societies all around the world and I'm talking like pre-grease.
Speaker 1: the problem was bronze requires a few different pieces of like a few different materials that in Vanishingly few circumstances actually exist in the same place.
Speaker 1: So an entire global trade network existed to make sure that everyone could make bronze because bronze was necessary.
Speaker 1: When that when something disrupted that trade it basically destroyed civilization as most humans alive on earth at the time knew it Mmm, because the society was built on the foundation of that trade supporting the things that made that civilization function on a fundamental level.
Speaker 1: global shipping is very like that in the world today.
Speaker 1: if Another disaster happened like if the Panama Canal got blocked at the same time Like that could cause society to collapse maybe like we don't know humans.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there's a lot of.
Speaker 1: So just think about those things.
Speaker 0: people people losing their jobs, right?
Speaker 0: It's like well got to close the factory We don't have any materials to work with.
Speaker 1: Yep, or things like well can't make certain medical supplies anymore at all Because part A is made in China and part B is made in like Europe and part C is made in America.
Speaker 1: Well, there's no way to get those three parts together anymore.
Speaker 1: And none of those countries has a factory to make the other two parts.
Speaker 1: And oh just build a new factory.
Speaker 1: Yeah that that you know, what with what?
Speaker 0: with what materials?
Speaker 0: materials that come on a boat?
Speaker 1: There's a reason.
Speaker 1: there was a dark age between the Bronze Age and the next age.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it took a while to build stuff.
Speaker 1: But if you it's funny cuz the day this happened I was super busy at work like really busy.
Speaker 0: So really busy reading about the Bronze Age.
Speaker 1: I Was actually like I was in meetings like all day.
Speaker 1: So the day ends and I'm like fuck and I go to Twitter and I see this ship and I'm like, oh fuck Oh shit.
Speaker 1: Oh fuck.
Speaker 1: and I go into like discourse.
Speaker 1: I'm about to talk about it And I'm the only person who is like everyone else was like already following this like minute by minute And I just missed it for like.
Speaker 0: it is definitely a news that for some reason I saw people Finding out about it like so delayed.
Speaker 1: I'm still seeing.
Speaker 1: I saw somebody someone I work with found out about it today when I mentioned it.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: So I think the reason is is that it's such a big news you that people can't help but share it.
Speaker 0: Right, a lot of people won't share all the news that they read.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's such of news like this is very as a big shareable news.
Speaker 0: So almost everyone has Retweeted it or you know posted it again in a you know saw it in one place and posted it in another.
Speaker 1: There's been like three evolutions.
Speaker 1: So the meaning of it, right?
Speaker 0: So you can sort of see because there's a higher percentage of people at least I think there's a higher percentage of people sharing this News when they discover it.
Speaker 0: I was able to see this delay of who's reading the internet every second of every day like me knowing it immediately and Who is finding out an hour later a day later, right and so on.
Speaker 0: you could see like people Discovering as time goes on and you can know now sort of infer their internet reading habits or their level of busyness From when they retweeted Or posted this.
Speaker 0: this that's an analysis.
Speaker 1: That would be interesting to study like Wow, like the right like how people react to news.
Speaker 1: I know there are people who are studying this kind of thing But I'd love to see those like a an impact map of like how the news spreads and how it reverberates And like that that sort of visualization and analysis.
Speaker 0: All right, let's go some other news.
Speaker 0: All right, so we had a thing of the day was the last week two weeks ago.
Speaker 0: Remember what is the anime cicadas, right?
Speaker 0: Everyone knows you watch an anime and it's Japan in the summer and they'll be Shots still shots of power lines with cicada noises to let you know that it's summer and it's about to be summer and the northern Hemisphere which means cicadas are coming, right?
Speaker 0: So, you know Japan will if you sure if you go to certain places in Japan You will hear those cicada noises if you're there at the right time in the right weather situation.
Speaker 0: But in the US we also have cicadas and I'm sure they're all around the world.
Speaker 0: In fact, I just learned a few minutes ago listening to a cicada podcast That was that was a few minutes long But right before I did this show cicadas have been around a hell of a long time.
Speaker 0: ancient peoples were writing about cicadas And so there are many different kinds of cicadas.
Speaker 0: They're obviously some that just come every year all the time, which is why you sort of hear them all the time.
Speaker 0: But then there's those ones that only come every so often, right?
Speaker 0: They go they're underground and then they all come out at once and then they go underground They breed the eggs or whatever or underground again and they come out again and like this cycle and the the.
Speaker 0: so we're the ones That are coming this year are the 17 year cicadas.
Speaker 0: So hopefully you will depending on your age if you're not like a hundred already.
Speaker 0: odds are you'll get to see them again.
Speaker 0: in 2038 we'll see them again, but it's the brood ex cicada.
Speaker 0: They're coming, right?
Speaker 0: And Obviously you have when you hear about this animal if you're a curious person You have a lot of freaking questions.
Speaker 0: How the heck do they know to come out every 17 years?
Speaker 0: What is the point of that?
Speaker 0: Why not just come out and breed every frickin year?
Speaker 1: Why are we talking of this?
Speaker 1: What do you mean bill?
Speaker 1: I didn't hate them.
Speaker 0: Why did they make these noises?
Speaker 0: Why are there so many of them, right?
Speaker 0: There's so many questions about this animal.
Speaker 0: What's up with the fungus that eats it from in the inside and makes its ass fall off?
Speaker 0: Yes, that's a real thing.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So I had all those same questions some of those questions We actually don't.
Speaker 0: no one knows the answer to.
Speaker 0: we don't know why how they can tell That it's all.
Speaker 0: we don't know how they know that it's been 17 years and all signal to each other to come out together.
Speaker 0: We don't know that.
Speaker 0: we're trying to figure that out.
Speaker 0: But of course the most fascinating question is the one we don't fucking know.
Speaker 0: But every other question regarding cicadas can be answered by the podcast we're gonna link to and Maybe an article or two, who knows.
Speaker 0: but it's cicada time and it's cicada time is good news for people like me who rent And don't have to deal with any sort of like scraping cicadas off the lawn.
Speaker 1: And I deal with the fish flies like they're fish flies have a similar seasonal like every night every.
Speaker 1: I don't know the cycles or anything.
Speaker 1: But every now and then a year would happen where there would be like Imagine it's just snowing dead bugs like a foot of dead bugs like that would happen in Connecticut.
Speaker 0: We had.
Speaker 0: basically there would be one day every year or few.
Speaker 0: I don't remember was every year or every few year, but our back porch Would just become 100% patio area 100% covered in flying.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah the flying is like forgot about that.
Speaker 0: It would be flying ant day and we try to you know, like get rid of as many flying ants as we could.
Speaker 0: But there was no stopping the fun.
Speaker 0: But so it'd be like oh, it's flying ant day.
Speaker 0: everyone get inside don't go on the back porch It's okay, get covered in flying ants.
Speaker 0: They didn't bite or anything, but it's like.
Speaker 0: who wants to be covered in flying ants?
Speaker 1: You know, there's someone out there who's like it's fucking my day.
Speaker 1: Here it comes For me.
Speaker 0: for me cicada time is awesome because I like cicada noises and I don't have to deal with the hassle.
Speaker 0: But some people who perhaps have lawns, especially it may be like a Virginia area, right?
Speaker 0: You're gonna.
Speaker 0: you know, depending on where it is the Brood X comes When they come for however many days it is.
Speaker 0: you're gonna be waiting through them.
Speaker 0: X might be coming and you're gonna be hearing and they're gonna be given a lot of noise.
Speaker 1: They're loud.
Speaker 0: If you there's too many of them and you know, they're big.
Speaker 0: they're like two inches big right and that's just one.
Speaker 0: And there's gonna be I think the in the podcast.
Speaker 0: they said in some places there could be millions of them per acre.
Speaker 1: That's a lot.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if you don't know what an acre is.
Speaker 1: Well, welcome to America.
Speaker 1: You can go look that up.
Speaker 1: It is weird when I think about like units of measure that I use I have a very clear idea of Exactly how big an acre is and it's a unit of measurement.
Speaker 1: I use that a regular basis.
Speaker 0: one acre is four thousand ish square meters.
Speaker 1: It's about the amount of like one relatively sustainable Farmstead for subsistence farming.
Speaker 0: It's like I think of it.
Speaker 0: I think of it is like a plot a plot of land.
Speaker 0: It's applies.
Speaker 0: what do you think about a standard plot of land like a front yard a house in a backyard?
Speaker 0: It's like, you know, it's an acre.
Speaker 1: Well, you know because you know I grew up in the suburbs.
Speaker 1: Suburbs are usually class like suburbs that aren't super dense.
Speaker 1: people talk about like half acre and acre meaning how much land does each house have?
Speaker 1: Fancier like rich people suburbs that cause sprawl and problems.
Speaker 1: houses are on full acres.
Speaker 1: Usually they're on like a half acre and then dense suburbs.
Speaker 1: Like you just get the bare minimum the houses all crammed together.
Speaker 1: Anyway, anyway, and some other news New York has joined much of the rest of the enlightened world and is officially going to legalize Recreational cannabis.
Speaker 0: hasn't happened yet, but it's real soon.
Speaker 1: It's real soon.
Speaker 1: No one's gonna be able to buy it in New York probably for over a year because now They have to write all the actual laws because it's all on the boat.
Speaker 0: We're getting stuck.
Speaker 0: All the weed all the the weed from the other side Choice weed is just feeling what whole shipping container.
Speaker 1: I just imagine one dude sitting on that boat and being like it's gonna go bad.
Speaker 0: There's a shipping container on the boat.
Speaker 0: It says like weed to New York It's jam-packed like the most.
Speaker 1: it finally gets to New York.
Speaker 1: There's gonna be one dude passed out in the empty container.
Speaker 0: He's like he was the guy who's working on the boat.
Speaker 0: He's like, you know, he's like.
Speaker 0: I had so much time I was actually able to look through all the containers figure out what was in him And I had.
Speaker 0: I had nothing to do.
Speaker 0: it couldn't go anywhere.
Speaker 0: I had to stay on the boat.
Speaker 0: What else is I gonna do?
Speaker 1: So it'll be a while But it's really good news because it was a while ever in Massachusetts legalized.
Speaker 1: It actually took a while for there to actually be places to buy it.
Speaker 1: but the important part is that the The framework and the laws that are actually going to make this happen for real are Very focused on restorative justice to the people who were harmed by the drug wars.
Speaker 1: up to this point It's not enough like it's a lot.
Speaker 1: I want to make it clear.
Speaker 1: This is not enough But the fact that it's a lot is something.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean, you know voting matters in New York just some years ago in recent memory, right?
Speaker 0: There was a situation where like there was a group of you know Democrats in quotes right who were basically Republicans.
Speaker 0: they voted with the Republicans even though when you went to go vote on the ballot, they would be labeled as Democrat and We used to complain about them weirdly often on geek night.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 0: Yeah a government our governor or was Shockingly still our governor, right?
Speaker 0: Nobody here likes him, but yeah, yeah Republicans don't like him because he's not a Republican and Democrats Don't like him because he's a Republican.
Speaker 0: But he Yeah, he helped those people get into position so that he would have more power, right?
Speaker 0: Otherwise the state legislature if it was all Democrats would just you know Be passing very progressive things that he didn't the governor doesn't like.
Speaker 0: he's not that progressive or at least, you know Sometimes they'll pretend to be anyway, but yeah, we voted we got rid of those people enough of them So that they don't matter anymore.
Speaker 1: and guess what when actual Democrats controlled our state Senate suddenly New York's passing a lot of really good legislation.
Speaker 0: We did everything except cancel rent.
Speaker 0: We did some stuff to help prevent people from getting evicted, but we weren't able to cancel rent.
Speaker 0: We did everything else.
Speaker 1: Yep, but look at this.
Speaker 1: We did.
Speaker 1: we got some real change that helped people as opposed to change that actively harmed people.
Speaker 1: mm-hmm and You only do an article.
Speaker 1: it talks about the specific social equity things that they're doing to make to Apply some restorative justice.
Speaker 1: It's all pretty good stuff.
Speaker 1: The taxes are reasonable.
Speaker 0: They're
Speaker 1: projecting like I don't even know where the number is But the number they had for like how much tax revenue they think they'll get in the first year after this goes live Like we could rebuild the whole fucking New York subway, of course I don't know what's gonna actually happen with that money and we'll see there's gonna be a
Speaker 0: lot.
Speaker 0: Well, a lot of the money is gonna go into the pocket of like, you know The guy with the bodega at the end of the street whose entire window is full of bongs Got?
Speaker 0: he's got CBD and he's got vapes and whatever.
Speaker 0: right once that guy could just sell just fucking weed.
Speaker 0: He is gonna be banking it right?
Speaker 0: It's time.
Speaker 0: Like if you had money in New York right now Why not buy one of those bong bodegas?
Speaker 0: Yeah, like your future is that is a good investment.
Speaker 1: right now It looks like it covers some states have kind of messed this up.
Speaker 1: It also covers some things like you will be allowed to grow your own if you want to just for some limits.
Speaker 1: some states Yeah, and it allows for establishments to allow people to consume cannabis in Semi public.
Speaker 1: like you could have a bar that allows cannabis or a restaurant that allows cannabis, which a lot of states don't allow.
Speaker 0: So they're actually making as long as it's not inside.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Well, also a lot of cannabis isn't smoked.
Speaker 1: It's edible.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean if yeah, I guess if you're not smoking that go on.
Speaker 0: I do inside I don't but in many
Speaker 1: places it is illegal to consume it anywhere but your own home and I I do appreciate the fact that if you're gonna make something legal Then you should also remove like obviously don't let people smoke in public and around other people But don't make something legal and then say oh, but you have to hide it from everybody.
Speaker 1: mmm Like I just know.
Speaker 0: you know.
Speaker 0: My only concern is I just don't want it to.
Speaker 0: you know I want everyone who wants to smoke weed to be able to do so without going to jail or anything like that Also without doing it right next to me.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I just don't want it to smell like weed everywhere.
Speaker 1: Yep Not in my apartment in New York, like when I go for my half marathons, it smells like weed like everywhere already.
Speaker 0: As long as it doesn't, you know, I mean you expect it sometimes to go to a concert.
Speaker 0: It's gonna smell like weed.
Speaker 1: You'll get a whiff when you're walking by but I don't want it to be a whiff coming in my window From the downstairs balcony every.
Speaker 0: if I'm in a situation where I'm in like a restaurant and I just want to you know Eat food outside and it smells like weed outside and I'm sitting still.
Speaker 0: I'm just gonna look.
Speaker 0: I got to leave the restaurant.
Speaker 0: I can't be sitting here.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and that is the same as cigarettes Like.
Speaker 1: that's how I think of that.
Speaker 1: Like if someone lights a cigarette within like a couple hundred yards of me I can smell it instantly know exactly where it is.
Speaker 0: And this isn't even to mention anything about the harms of inhaling whatever, right?
Speaker 0: It's just like, you know, if there was someone just set off a harmless stink bomb in the restaurant.
Speaker 0: It's like I don't want to stay there.
Speaker 0: You know as far as I know skunk spray doesn't hurt you other than making it smell real bad, right?
Speaker 0: Maybe it does.
Speaker 0: I don't know but but it just smelled.
Speaker 0: if it smells like skunk.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna be mad.
Speaker 0: I don't care how much it hurts me or not But the fact that it could hurt me I just only makes it worse from what I read.
Speaker 1: The legislation is also informed by particularly how legalization went in Colorado and Washington Because a lot of states have done it different ways and they kind of fucked up parts of it.
Speaker 1: But yep studies have shown like studies by the states meaning they have a vested interest in finding out if they need to change their laws.
Speaker 1: in Washington and in Colorado there have been no Significant negative consequences like that is a very.
Speaker 0: you don't say that.
Speaker 1: Oh Nothing, particularly bad happened Like you use didn't know Like.
Speaker 1: like basically the only said on that not drawback.
Speaker 1: The only side effects were way fewer.
Speaker 1: non-white people were going to jail and there's a whole bunch of tax dollars huh.
Speaker 0: So, yeah, so I you know while it's it's you know that on the tax dollars while that's nice You know, it's still a regressive tax.
Speaker 0: Well, yeah text the rich text.
Speaker 0: You should text the rich and not the weed.
Speaker 1: Yes I am I'm not.
Speaker 0: texting the weed is basically just like a lubricant to get it through a legislature.
Speaker 0: at this point It's not actually something I approve of.
Speaker 1: if anything text alcohol a lot more and don't tell you because if someone's
Speaker 0: gonna use text Alcohol and cars
Speaker 1: alcohol kills so many people and We just it's not gonna kill a lot of people like the harms I'm actually I
Speaker 0: am actually hoping that just naturally without any intent the Legalization of weed just naturally results in less alcohol.
Speaker 1: So it might be to hold.
Speaker 0: some might be too hopeful.
Speaker 1: So I'm hopeful but I've shown that that appears to be true, but I don't I don't care about the studies.
Speaker 1: You know why.
Speaker 1: I think that's true.
Speaker 1: all the alcohol companies started investing heavily in cannabis Mmm, they know that this is going to their alcohol industry is going to shrink.
Speaker 0: They're gonna make weed alcohol.
Speaker 1: Yeah Yeah, yeah, there are.
Speaker 1: there are.
Speaker 1: in fact if you get a tincture tinctures literally are just cannabis dissolved in alcohol But it's not a lot of alcohol because otherwise you're gonna have a problem.
Speaker 0: So it's like vanilla extract of weed basically.
Speaker 1: Yeah So you could put it in your cookies or whatever exactly or put like one drop onto your tongue Like that's how they get used.
Speaker 1: those came out of mostly medical stuff.
Speaker 1: But anyway, you can read this article.
Speaker 1: it has all the juicy details and While you can't buy it in New York probably until around this time next year If the race is on now,
Speaker 0: New York and Massachusetts bring it in, you know Yeah,
Speaker 1: Massachusetts is making bad because it's very funny If you look at where the dispensaries are in Massachusetts where it's
Speaker 0: Right next to the fireworks.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they're all so literally like if you go from New York into Massachusetts.
Speaker 1: There's one like right there and almost every major freeway And all of all the cars parked in the parking lots are New York plates because we actually pass them on our way up to now
Speaker 0: entering now entering Tennessee Fireworks liquor store
Speaker 1: and you
Speaker 0: might go
Speaker 1: well since it's federally illegal and it's illegal in New York.
Speaker 1: Why don't the cops care that it's all New York plates?
Speaker 1: and the answer is they're Massachusetts cops.
Speaker 1: it ain't illegal in Massachusetts.
Speaker 1: They give zero fucks about New York and they're more than happy to get those tax dollars from New Yorkers.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm, like Oh New York money coming into Massachusetts.
Speaker 0: Sounds good.
Speaker 1: But anyway things Of the day.
Speaker 1: This is just too cute.
Speaker 1: This is just a Long Series of photos.
Speaker 1: it's before and after photos of people's pets dogs cats even a rabbit.
Speaker 0: But before after what?
Speaker 1: so it's before and after young old young calling them a good boy.
Speaker 1: You take a picture of your dog.
Speaker 1: Then you say like good boy, and then immediately take another picture.
Speaker 0: All right, I guess some some animals would react and some wouldn't.
Speaker 1: it's interesting because the dogs Almost universally like emote in a very human way and likes visibly smile and react.
Speaker 1: The birds also react very strongly.
Speaker 1: the cats like with the first cat.
Speaker 1: the cat literally just turns around and sits down.
Speaker 0: Why would you do two photos though?
Speaker 0: I feel like just do have a video.
Speaker 0: just you know It's a listicle but It's I mean with the photos.
Speaker 0: with the photos you could just take two photos and say that one was the after one.
Speaker 1: I mean you could.
Speaker 1: this could be entirely faked.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the video I think is much better and we give it.
Speaker 0: you'd see the transition right from the normal face to the the happy Face and that would be much more.
Speaker 1: the best one is the rabbit because there's good boy to the rabbit and the next picture It's the rabbit just is slightly closer.
Speaker 0: You know, it's a boy rabbit.
Speaker 1: I mean it might not be.
Speaker 0: Yeah All right.
Speaker 0: So my thing of the day out in the country of Slovenia where I've never been but maybe one day I'll go there.
Speaker 1: I would really like to go.
Speaker 0: not in.
Speaker 0: there's not a pandemic.
Speaker 0: They have a computer history museum and in their computer history museum They have many cool things such as a whole bunch of terminals, right?
Speaker 0: Terminals the likes of which you may not have, you know, some of which I've seen a VT 100 a VT 220 What the hell's a paka 3100, right?
Speaker 0: It's like or you know, I think I've seen Adma three A's or ADM three A's, right?
Speaker 1: But yeah a whole lot of cool terminals And that just looks like a modern modern a CRT from the late 90s.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but Here's this article about a very interesting installation.
Speaker 0: They have there and in this installation They've got you know, like a deck VT 320, right?
Speaker 0: they got some terminals and they got you know, some big old old-school computers and they got a Enormous dot matrix printer from way back in the day, right and this person has set up a system whereby there is a An old original Game Boy with the Game Boy camera in it and you take a photo with the old Game Boy camera and this original Game Boy and Then you go over to this terminal and you can print out on the dot matrix printer the photo you took With the Game Boy and
Speaker 1: basically like ASCII it is beautiful.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so this is a Terrific thing going on the Slovenian computer Museum interactive exhibits like that because it's one thing to look at it all computer and go wow That's an old computer, but to actually interact with weird old technology.
Speaker 1: I think is important.
Speaker 0: I would really love to maybe like.
Speaker 0: that could be a really cool thing to do is like, you know There's computer museums all around the world in various places.
Speaker 0: What if we toured the computer museums of the world?
Speaker 0: We just went to every computer museum that you could.
Speaker 1: you could do like a long-running series on that.
Speaker 0: Basically you'd run you'd be able to do them all.
Speaker 0: there can't be that many right, but it would still be cool.
Speaker 1: Hey if any of you are rich and you want to fund that if you if you can pay us to live We'll fucking do it.
Speaker 0: Oh Just just an aside.
Speaker 0: This is my thing of the day.
Speaker 0: There's a guy called.
Speaker 0: He's a sort of this semi famous camera dude named Japan camera hunter.
Speaker 0: His stick is like you want to buy a camera, but you don't want to cut you want to get it.
Speaker 1: I'm pretty sure you made him a thing of the day in a distant past.
Speaker 0: Oh, maybe but like you can you can have him go and buy a camera in Japan for you and then he'll mail it to you.
Speaker 0: But he went to the somewhat new ish Nikon museum that is opened in Japan and he made a YouTube video where he goes to every single part of it.
Speaker 0: They had like the world's largest like glass ingot there and such You know all kinds of cameras that went to space all that kind of shit.
Speaker 0: It was like I've seen the whole museum on YouTube, but I want to go there now anyway.
Speaker 0: So that's cool.
Speaker 1: in the minute moment, we're actually reading the tale of Genji so read along with us.
Speaker 1: It's the first novel like ever.
Speaker 1: that's the first one.
Speaker 1: if you're gonna read any novels at some point in your life You got to read the first one.
Speaker 0: You're gonna have a lot of time to read while you're waiting for the boat to show up.
Speaker 0: His long book will you know get you through?
Speaker 0: and then once you've read the first book you can read the second novel.
Speaker 0: Whatever that is someone.
Speaker 0: let me know what the second novel ever is Because that's what we have to read.
Speaker 0: next.
Speaker 0: we're gonna start at the beginning read every novel ever written by.
Speaker 1: I still remember to this day the first novel I ever started reading and Stopped reading and chose to never read another page again in my life And it was piers anthony's chimeras copper.
Speaker 0: Okay, the first novel I read and stopped reading and didn't finish was I Don't even know I was so mad at that book like I got.
Speaker 1: it was a trilogy and I read dragons gold It's I. I read serpent silver is alright, and then chimeras copper.
Speaker 1: I sort of realized that this whole thing was just bad And I don't know.
Speaker 0: I don't think I don't even know if there was.
Speaker 0: I can't remember one.
Speaker 1: Anyway, I guess I also didn't actually finish reading great expectations.
Speaker 0: Yeah, all right, so let's do some meta.
Speaker 0: Oh, we're already in the meta moment.
Speaker 1: Any other meta moment to say there is potentially there's light at the end of the tunnel and a post-covid world.
Speaker 1: So maybe in 2022, we'll start talking about conventions again.
Speaker 0: It's possible.
Speaker 0: All right, whatever you should come and find us on the internet if you know.
Speaker 0: if you whatever internet place you like to be.
Speaker 0: You know if you like a YouTube if you like a Twitter.
Speaker 0: if you like You know a discord.
Speaker 0: if you like just a web forum, right?
Speaker 0: You just want to email somebody?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: We are on all the places of the internet.
Speaker 0: come and find us.
Speaker 0: It's not hard.
Speaker 0: Just type geek nights into Google.
Speaker 1: Whatever text entry input in front of you right now one of them or yours.
Speaker 0: You're a smart person.
Speaker 0: We have a website.
Speaker 0: front row crew.
Speaker 0: calm like even you.
Speaker 1: type it into Twitter.
Speaker 1: Someone might just respond to you with like geek nights.
Speaker 0: Eh Yeah, you can.
Speaker 0: you can find us if you.
Speaker 0: if you found this podcast somehow you can find all our other things.
Speaker 0: I know I believe in you.
Speaker 1: In particular I call your attention to.
Speaker 1: Steam has a capability if you're not aware where you can curate a collection of games with like your own review like here is a Curated collection of recommended games Scott is looking at like fleshing that out without the games We like.
Speaker 0: and yeah, we have this.
Speaker 0: we have a steam an official geek night steam group.
Speaker 0: It's existed for a very long time But I actually went and messed with it the week or two ago and maybe we'll pay more attention to it.
Speaker 1: Yep Similarly I am looking at cuz my board game geek account is where I post all of our game reviews to board game geek and I poked in there a couple weeks ago and a lot of people are engaging with that content like hmm more like Dozens of people are like commenting on a lot of those videos.
Speaker 1: I was surprised.
Speaker 0: We also we even have a subreddit that has been extremely rarely used, but it exists.
Speaker 1: So the newest post and there's probably several you're interested in or would like interact with or use Either of those.
Speaker 1: let us know because if you're interested and we tend like you want to help us or if you're interested You just tell us yeah I'd use the hell out of a curated like board game review on board game geek.
Speaker 1: That'll encourage me or Scott or both of us to continue to poke at these things.
Speaker 1: mmm No, I guess we just do the main bit.
Speaker 0: what should I eat for dinner?
Speaker 1: Uh, we had a late lunch of yumplings.
Speaker 1: So yumplings you say yeah, so we might have a light dinner cuz that was a lot of we I.
Speaker 0: how many yumplings did you get?
Speaker 1: I ate 12 dumplings.
Speaker 0: you ate 12.
Speaker 0: We hope we get eight and we we get not eight.
Speaker 1: We got 24 and I ate 12 of them.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we get 12 and eat six each.
Speaker 0: You don't get 12 and eat 12 each.
Speaker 1: All right, let's see.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's hard to beat that yumpling in this area.
Speaker 0: All right, you need like a soup dumpling to like challenge it right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, but soup dumplings don't survive delivery.
Speaker 1: That's the problem.
Speaker 0: That's I'm saying.
Speaker 0: but that's why the yumpling is so terrific.
Speaker 1: If someone can make technology to deliver a soup dumpling completely intact and perfect They could be a robot that delivers and it has soup finishes like it makes the road.
Speaker 1: It makes the dumpling outside your door before it rings the doorbell.
Speaker 0: It's making them on the way to you and they're ready as soon as it or at times it so with their final one is Ready as it when it arrives at the door and it just gives you the steamer basket that just finished.
Speaker 1: Oh for all that have a food truck that literally just like makes the food and drives around dropping it off in real time.
Speaker 1: Okay, anyway, let's do the main bit.
Speaker 1: so Solitaire puzzles and games and stuffy.
Speaker 1: I even said games.
Speaker 0: I think this.
Speaker 0: this could be arguably a Tuesday show but Technically speaking these things are not.
Speaker 0: at least they're not ortho games.
Speaker 1: They're not ortho games.
Speaker 1: unless you add a meta layer above them of some kind.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you can do the crossword puzzle the fastest kind of thing.
Speaker 1: And while they are interactive amusements That is it that I like that definite.
Speaker 1: They're also a series of interesting decisions depending on what type of thing you're engaged with.
Speaker 1: not necessarily But they fit some definitions of game but not other definitions of game.
Speaker 1: Not just because we're hurting for Thursday episodes are we doing this now but also because which we are make no mistake We are hurting for Thursday.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah But I guess this also shows that like the topics like when people talk about things generally there's actually a lot of nuance and gray areas and spectrums and fuzziness and People who try to categorize things very black and white like that is a game.
Speaker 1: That is not a game.
Speaker 1: Those are the rules of conversation tend to be insufferable people and tend to miss out on a lot.
Speaker 0: So well, it's you know, I always say it's like, you know, there's semantics.
Speaker 0: you can have a semantic discussion.
Speaker 0: What does this word mean, right?
Speaker 0: And then you can sort of you know, since we have brains we can figure out even if someone uses words that technically mean X You know that that person means why right?
Speaker 0: There's just not better words.
Speaker 0: and but there's you know, just because something is Semantically, you know Logical that doesn't necessarily mean that the reality underlying the semantics follows the same rules, right?
Speaker 0: It's like oh you've category.
Speaker 0: You've correctly decided that that is the word game applies to that thing and not that thing.
Speaker 0: But nothing about the world is any different.
Speaker 0: That's just something about the English language is different, right?
Speaker 0: It doesn't have any actual meaning for like what you're gonna do with your life, right or what decisions you should or should not make But also anyway in the way we break up geek nights.
Speaker 1: We're talking about these in terms of like a lot of like.
Speaker 1: we're not gonna talk about the game Mechanics of these things as much as this is a social and human topic.
Speaker 1: There's a lot more going on here and what we actually want to talk about, right?
Speaker 0: So, you know my whole life especially in the days before things like smartphones Game boys, right, you know those sorts of things.
Speaker 0: you wanted something Portable that was entertainment.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and it was really hard to beat the old, you know, there were really two things.
Speaker 0: I remember we'd go on family trips and our parents would buy us.
Speaker 0: They still make them.
Speaker 0: There's these yes and no invisible ink books.
Speaker 0: Yeah it's a book that comes with a Pen and the pen is filled with this invisible ink, right?
Speaker 1: I found a picture of yes and no specifically.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and you basically there's all these different activities in the book and you engage with the activities by.
Speaker 0: You know rubbing this, you know special pen on the paper and it reveals like this this line that's been hidden or that You know these.
Speaker 0: there's markings that have been hidden on the page and this various, you know games and other games again, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, some of them are just like trivia questions and you're trying to rub the correct answer and you know Because it's a permanent thing.
Speaker 0: It's like you can sort of see how well you did on the trivia, right?
Speaker 0: You could just completely rub every single page But that would sort of be defeating the purpose.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and and then So those were.
Speaker 0: I really like those and then there were also You know, you'd go to the grocery store and there would be like.
Speaker 0: I think I don't know if it still exists It was like games magazine even it was basically just like a or various like books you can get for real cheap.
Speaker 0: It was like penny press kind of thing I'll wear for a few dollars.
Speaker 0: You can get this big old fat book and it might just be like a thousand crossword puzzles a thousand word searches.
Speaker 0: But the best ones are the variety ones because they had stuff like p cross Sudoku Cryptograms the logic puzzles.
Speaker 0: I really like those ones.
Speaker 0: Just you know, some of them like some of them I couldn't really figure out how to do.
Speaker 0: Instructions weren't great.
Speaker 0: So I wouldn't.
Speaker 0: I would just skip though.
Speaker 1: They're very much adjacent to those little like Plastic games.
Speaker 1: that would be like a little piece of plastic like a little like a size of a cell phone But thicker filled with ball bearings and some sort of way to flick the ball bearings around and there'd be like puzzles and things To do with the ball bearings.
Speaker 1: It's an adjacent space.
Speaker 0: Yeah nowadays all of these things have been just been turned into cell phone apps, right?
Speaker 0: It's like you don't need to buy a crossword puzzle paper book.
Speaker 0: You can just get the New York Times crossword puzzle app on your phone.
Speaker 0: You're good to go.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: and even kids like there's kid tablets and like kid versions of phones that are durable and have the same thing and These still exist.
Speaker 1: They're out there.
Speaker 1: I think they still serve a purpose especially because you know kids like they like to engage with tactile things sometimes.
Speaker 1: But these are a big part of my childhood because well, I could just read.
Speaker 1: you might say but room is God If you're bored, what's more entertaining and portable than a book?
Speaker 1: And yes, that's true.
Speaker 1: I won a lot of people like I'm one of those people cannot read Like long texts in a moving vehicle without getting no readily sick and getting a headache.
Speaker 1: Same same like if I read more than a paragraph of text in a moving vehicle.
Speaker 1: I'm basically fucked for like four hours.
Speaker 1: Like I just have.
Speaker 0: only if it only if it's a car I'm good on the bus or the train or the plane.
Speaker 1: Just not a car car a bus.
Speaker 1: I actually have trouble with two But granted New York bus.
Speaker 1: I haven't really ridden other buses in a long time Mmm, but anyway, yeah.
Speaker 1: But also these things like it's.
Speaker 1: it's not like a book is of one kind of entertainment, but sometimes you're bored.
Speaker 1: But you want a more interactive kind of entertainment and that's where these things always shine like I want to do something.
Speaker 1: I want a more active activity instead of a passive activity.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like, you know a book sort of fills that need of you know length, right?
Speaker 0: It's like I want to dive deep into some fictional world for a period of time, right?
Speaker 0: You know, so it's good before bed on the beach or you're there for hours or who knows right how long you're there Right, you know a comic book or maybe smaller, right?
Speaker 0: You can do the same thing only in a shorter burst.
Speaker 0: You know the puzzle book.
Speaker 0: it's like you can just open it up.
Speaker 0: do a puzzle do part of a puzzle You know, there's no.
Speaker 0: you can stop it start it.
Speaker 0: It doesn't even matter right.
Speaker 0: you can change.
Speaker 0: you don't like it.
Speaker 0: Go to a different one, right?
Speaker 0: You know who cares?
Speaker 0: no one's like grading you on your puzzle book.
Speaker 1: when I was a little kid like the mazes were the ones I was the most into.
Speaker 0: I love a good maze, but the problem is a maze is like, you know Sort of like really quick and then it's over and there's only a few mazes or
Speaker 1: it's literally just random and you'll sit there forever Trial and error like there's no technique Only go turn left.
Speaker 0: I always thought I was I thought always thought it was clever starting at the end of the maze But it's like.
Speaker 0: well, that's just the same thing.
Speaker 0: I started get the start.
Speaker 1: the difference is I there were a lot of mazes the way they were designed where They were designed to be difficult going one way because you'd make a lot of dead ends.
Speaker 1: But if you come in but there's only one true path if you come in from the exit a lot of times You basically what if I just took?
Speaker 0: what if I took the same exact maze and I took the word?
Speaker 0: entrance and I put it where the word exit was and I put the word exit and then put it where the entrance was?
Speaker 1: depending On how the maze was designed that mayor may not have an impact.
Speaker 1: May just like how you can design a very you're not.
Speaker 0: the point is you're not clever for starting at the exit.
Speaker 1: Well, or you're as clever as you were expected to be Sure.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the ones the things that I actually enjoyed the most in this genre once I was older than like five or six years old.
Speaker 1: we're specifically Books like the Encyclopaedia Brown style, but there's a lot of series of this.
Speaker 1: we're like you get a really short story and then there'd be a question at the end like that was sort of a logic puzzle and That at the back of the book usually printed like upside down or backwards.
Speaker 1: You needed a mirror would be the answer.
Speaker 0: My favorite was similar to that.
Speaker 0: It was the actual logic puzzles and but the way those would work is.
Speaker 0: they would be like a few sentences, right?
Speaker 0: And it would be like, you know, Joe's hat isn't green.
Speaker 0: Sue has You know A brother?
Speaker 1: I actually really enjoyed that kind of puzzle that I think.
Speaker 1: that's why I like that one PI detective game.
Speaker 0: we played a fax with Anthony that one time and it's like they give you the the minimum number of facts Possible.
Speaker 0: and then there's this grid and it's like they like it'd be like it right and it's like, okay Well, there's this five people there's five items and this you know, and there's you know, it's like, you know You know Sue's brother has a you know doesn't have an umbrella, right?
Speaker 0: It's like you got to put all these facts together and there's this grid where you can put X's and say okay a process Right Sue doesn't have a green hat.
Speaker 0: So you go from Sue.
Speaker 0: you go to the right and you find the green hat column and you put an X and then you Go to the green hat column and you put an X in the other side, right?
Speaker 0: It's two-dimensional logic.
Speaker 0: and then you basically X off right.
Speaker 0: the things, you know aren't true.
Speaker 0: and you put if something is true you put a Circle and you X off all the things that conflict with that.
Speaker 0: when you find a circle you just X off everything else.
Speaker 0: Right because you know that that's the right answer.
Speaker 0: and it's very similar to p-cross in a way But it's more like p-cross with a plot whereas actual p-cross, which I also enjoy is is is produces like an image, right?
Speaker 0: Whereas this produces an answer to two questions about a motherfucker.
Speaker 1: Oh my gosh.
Speaker 1: So one of those books this is this is like the peak of irony.
Speaker 1: I don't remember what this book was called.
Speaker 1: I don't remember any other mystery from this book Like it was framed as you would be presented with a court case and then you'd have to be the jury like guilty or not Guilty.
Speaker 1: and then in the back of the book was here's the actual situations.
Speaker 1: You'd find out if you sent someone innocent to jail or you let a murderer get free or whatever.
Speaker 1: I don't remember anything from this book except of the mysteries that were in it.
Speaker 1: I Accidentally opened the book one day and saw the answer to one of them And I and I was like five years of sex five or six years old and I remember thinking to myself I'm just gonna I'm just gonna not read that mystery and just try to forget and someday when I'm adult I can come back and do this one without it being spoiled.
Speaker 1: The newspaper was at fault.
Speaker 1: The fucking newspaper was at fault.
Speaker 1: I remember that but I don't remember what the case was.
Speaker 1: I specifically just now remembered something that I spent 31 years trying to forget.
Speaker 1: Well fucking brain god damn it the newspaper was at fault.
Speaker 1: I will never forget.
Speaker 0: you can just get a book of a hundred other mysteries that you can do instead.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but as a kid, I was so adamant that I need to forget this in the future.
Speaker 1: Mmm, I have not thought about that in decades.
Speaker 0: There was also the.
Speaker 0: the cryptograms were kind of fun, right?
Speaker 0: It would be like it would be like, alright Here's a sentence but all the letters of the alphabet are actually swapped with other letters of the alphabet.
Speaker 0: So it could be it's not rot 13 because that would be too easy.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but it's like okay baby code breaker, right?
Speaker 0: It's like a is actually s and T is actually Q and P is actually e. right.
Speaker 0: and you look all they do is give you A sentence and it's written.
Speaker 0: all the letters are jumbled up and you sort of have to figure out.
Speaker 0: Okay?
Speaker 0: Here's the letter Z all by itself as a single word.
Speaker 0: That means Z has to either be a or I Or I guess that's it.
Speaker 0: Right?
Speaker 0: Is there any other one letter words?
Speaker 0: We'll say a or I. you know, okay.
Speaker 0: Well, there's a two letter.
Speaker 0: So now you look for other Z's and you're like, okay well here is a Word and it ends in two Z's.
Speaker 0: so ending in two eyes is pretty rare.
Speaker 0: Is it Pompeii, right?
Speaker 0: It's like, you know, it's probably You know to eat.
Speaker 0: I don't know right stuff like that.
Speaker 0: and you have to figure out.
Speaker 0: you figure out some letters and you can figure other letters.
Speaker 0: But god the letter, you know L has appeared the most.
Speaker 0: that must be easy.
Speaker 1: It's the most things are appearing letter like sudoku and pi cross and what you just described because they're all sort of like an iterative logical process you can engage with in your brain.
Speaker 1: that is oddly Satisfying to resolve even though you're not doing anything particularly difficult or complex You're basically just implementing a simple algorithm in your brain.
Speaker 0: Yep, exactly.
Speaker 0: It's like that's the thing is when we play like a board game, right?
Speaker 0: Especially a new one or any new, you know video game or something.
Speaker 0: what's going on in your brain?
Speaker 0: Is you have no heuristic whatsoever?
Speaker 0: You are developing a heuristic.
Speaker 0: you're creating an algorithm doing real problem solving right is here is the thing.
Speaker 0: We need to get an answer, but we don't know how to get the answer.
Speaker 0: We need to first figure out how to get the answer and then engage that mechanism That will produce the answer and then we can engage that mechanism as many times as we need to.
Speaker 0: we can play settlers 10 times And I've already developed the mechanism and I'll play settlers 10 times.
Speaker 0: a sudoku a pi cross anything like that.
Speaker 0: is The mechanism is already known or it should be known.
Speaker 0: Yeah, my.
Speaker 0: if it's not known.
Speaker 1: first do sudoku.
Speaker 0: you might solve sudoku for the first time like oh You might not know that mechanism and you might it develop it But eventually you you're gonna have it and then you're just sort of doing the same work that a computer does.
Speaker 0: you're just executing right on this process
Speaker 1: And for some
Speaker 0: people like sometimes it's kind of nice
Speaker 1: it's a soothing feeling it's because you know what it almost gives you a flow State but with no stakes like a lot of things like when I'm playing like I'm skiing or playing an advanced video game That I'm good at.
Speaker 1: you get that flow state.
Speaker 1: We're like you're a cheer succeeding and achieving and it might be definitely you're doing work either physical or mental but you're also succeeding at it as you go and you just like get into this groove and This is a easy way to get into like a limited version of that state very quickly as an amusement.
Speaker 1: I think there's something you know We talked about.
Speaker 0: you know, I'm obviously a knowledge worker as like according to capitalism, right?
Speaker 0: And you know, but and there's obviously a lot of disadvantages to doing some you know What class capitalism would say is not knowledge labor, right something that is like, I don't know filing papers in a filing cabinet or I Don't know stacking shelves in the grocery store, right just sort of like a menial repetitive task.
Speaker 0: But when you see people who love grinding and RPGs and stuff like that It's like, you know, even my brain sometimes is in the mood, you know, not often In the mood for a menial repetitive task, right?
Speaker 0: So a menial repetitive task that actually has you know, some complexity to it, right?
Speaker 0: There's a little bit of crunch on it You know, that's like I guess human brains or at least many human brains like that sort of thing.
Speaker 0: Yeah But what's interesting is and you got you wonder if you could figure out what sort of Brain someone has based on which puzzles in the puzzle book They like to do and which ones they skip.
Speaker 1: the the thing is the puzzle that I like the most is one that you can't Get except with electronics the water pitcher puzzle Doing.
Speaker 1: well, I could I could do water pitcher puzzles all day and not get tired of it for a while.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean, uh, you know, what's his name, right?
Speaker 0: Professor Layton.
Speaker 0: Professor Layton is basically this in video game form.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but it's also interesting because Some things that seem like a much more complex game when you're good at them become this like if I play nourishing my hex on my Phone.
Speaker 1: it's this.
Speaker 1: it's the same feeling.
Speaker 0: I'm not mad.
Speaker 1: No point.
Speaker 1: Do I make a difficult decision?
Speaker 1: I just go through the motions of implementing this algorithm that I have internalized in tune to a unconscious degree, uh Honestly slay the spire is like that.
Speaker 1: I'm not getting better at slay the spire in any meaningful way.
Speaker 1: I'll play.
Speaker 0: so you kind of need to a little bit at least.
Speaker 1: yeah a little bit But it it's incremental like I'll lay it down in bed and just throw on a level 10 ascension slay the spire.
Speaker 1: I just go through the motions and play it and it's just.
Speaker 1: it's really soothing.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean sometimes you do develop new, you know tricks, right?
Speaker 0: Sometimes those tricks are actually, you know new right like you've.
Speaker 0: you've enhanced your your algorithm In a way, but sometimes it's you haven't actually like changed your process.
Speaker 0: You've just sort of like rearranged your process in a brain.
Speaker 0: in your brain It's like the have any with p-cross somewhat recently where it's like I wasn't able to solve, you know There was no p-cross before that I couldn't solve and there isn't one that I can't solve now.
Speaker 0: It's not like I upgraded my p-cross.
Speaker 0: But there are certain situations where I was evaluating them by counting in a certain way and then I realized Oh just count in this different way and it's like now I'm counting in a different way I can.
Speaker 0: you know, I'm crossing off the p-cross.
Speaker 0: This is like a different order.
Speaker 0: I'm still getting to the same end point in relatively, you know, it doesn't seem that much faster or anything.
Speaker 0: But it's like my brain decided to think about the p-cross process in a new way for some reason.
Speaker 0: You know, it just it just happens.
Speaker 0: I guess I don't know if it's good or bad or just nothing.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I feel like jigsaw puzzles are adjacent to all of this.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, definitely Some adjacency going on there.
Speaker 0: One thing I think we got to give a special mention is the crossword puzzle, right?
Speaker 1: so as a kid, I'll admit until I was like in in college, I Gave crossword puzzles the short shrift like I didn't respect them as much like I as a kid.
Speaker 1: I sort of thought they were a knowledge game primarily and I didn't really are kind of.
Speaker 1: they are kind of vocabulary and now but they're Also a game of a little bit of tactics and strategy and being clever like you answer the questions You can answer.
Speaker 1: that gives you more ammo to go after the ones you're struggling with.
Speaker 1: Like there's better game design there than I appreciated when I was younger.
Speaker 1: You know, I think also if it's a well-designed crossword puzzle Well, the other thing is ruined.
Speaker 1: a lot of schools, especially elementary schools will make crossword puzzles for the kids and they're just garbage.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if you you know the New York Times crossword puzzle if you're not familiar right.
Speaker 0: basically on Monday It's pretty easy and then on Sunday it levels up throughout the week and on Sunday is a big hard one And then it goes back to easy again On Monday, so like that's their pattern and the Sunday ones always have some sort of clever trick to them.
Speaker 0: They'll always do these things like oh my god Look, there's the letter L and is on a diagonal or all the very long answers the ones that are like You know many letters long will have like a common theme to them or spell something out, right?
Speaker 0: so that gives you like additional clues not just the across clues and the down clues but There's extra information to go on.
Speaker 0: if you're extra clever and can spot what they're doing Right that can either a help you solve the crossword puzzle faster, right?
Speaker 0: Make you feel like you've discovered something when you see what they did or just reward you more for solving it the correct way And then seeing the clever thing they did with the with the crossword puzzle that you know Isn't just a straightforward crossword puzzle.
Speaker 1: But the other thing is as a kid a lot of the knowledge you needed to beat the crossword puzzles least that I'd like Remember trying to do in like the true knowledge.
Speaker 1: I didn't know I was that I was kid.
Speaker 1: That's why I was a kid cuz I was stupid like I didn't know things Yeah, and like I'd see my dad my mom or my dad cuz they both did like they like they'd said look at the ones They finish.
Speaker 1: I'd be like I didn't understand most of the answers when I was a little.
Speaker 0: yeah My grandmother was big on the crossword puzzle right near my uncle George.
Speaker 0: He plays the crossword puzzle.
Speaker 0: The crossword puzzle can also be a social thing.
Speaker 0: you know there's always that stereotype of like asking someone like hey What's a word?
Speaker 0: Right and you can not only get the clues from the clue, but also just looking at the letters.
Speaker 0: It's like okay.
Speaker 0: You know I don't know what the hell the clue is.
Speaker 0: it's someone some celebrities name from a TV show I didn't watch.
Speaker 0: I can google it, but that would just be cheating, but I can see that It's like you know our blank M. Well.
Speaker 0: I guess it must be rimmed.
Speaker 0: That's it.
Speaker 0: That's the only name.
Speaker 0: I know that starts with our three letters that starts with R And ends with M.
Speaker 1: You know it's your vocabulary skills as an APA and M as in man.
Speaker 0: see Yep, it comes in with your addition.
Speaker 0: You know the actual trivia knowledge together the combo.
Speaker 1: but the other thing I really appreciate about crossword puzzles is a well-designed one will have a lot of clues intersecting with a very little black space between them.
Speaker 1: the craft of constructing something like that just fascinates me.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there has been some scandals.
Speaker 0: We talk about the plagiarism going on, but yeah there, but for the mode.
Speaker 0: But you know someone made those crossword puzzles originally and that was hard work.
Speaker 0: And you know it's a. it's definitely a good person has to have to make one you have to have.
Speaker 0: you know such an amount of Vocabulary and trivia knowledge that you can stump these really smart people out there Yeah, or do something so clever to where when they solve it.
Speaker 1: They go.
Speaker 1: Huh well you look at that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's and you got to put that out.
Speaker 0: You know with regularity It's not.
Speaker 0: it's not easy work to make the crossword puzzle.
Speaker 1: so speaking of things that don't require any mental effort And you go through the motions till they're done.
Speaker 0: I think we can end the show there All right good on for over an hour.
Speaker 0: Hockey games gonna start, and I need food.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's perfect timing.
Speaker 1: Okay bye This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 0: be sure to visit our website at front row crew.com For show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 1: remember geek nights is not one But four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows It's actually recorded at night and the patreon patrons for this episode of geek nights are Alan Joyce.
Speaker 1: How do you make a link?
Speaker 1: eg dread lily tennant break Chris rhymer Clinton Walton Graham Finch?
Speaker 1: Just like a dude guy now go through the last year or so a podcast and make room sing grin from New Zealand Review mad bull 34 cowards Ryan Perrin Shervin vulnerable Taylor Braun you old the key to my heart and a bunch of people who do Not want me to say their names Dateline.
Speaker 1: now that boat is still stuck and I think it's gonna still be stuck there for a while.
Speaker 1: so in honor of something unrelated to that.
Speaker 1: I leave you with Break bread with the enemy.