Speaker 0: It's Thursday, May 20th, 2021.
Speaker 0: I'm rim.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott and this is geek nights tonight.
Speaker 0: We were talking about things that grind or grease or possibly have no particular impact on our gears.
Speaker 1: Let's do this All right.
Speaker 0: I actually got nobody but that I can start with.
Speaker 1: I got no even.
Speaker 0: Let's start with mine.
Speaker 0: You can do yours.
Speaker 0: How's that?
Speaker 1: I'm just gonna say warm today.
Speaker 0: Huh, you can start with.
Speaker 1: that works, I think that works better.
Speaker 0: if I say it first, all right You start with that then I'll do my thing.
Speaker 1: Woman today.
Speaker 1: woman It is.
Speaker 1: no it's not woman.
Speaker 0: The problem is we used to do that earnestly and say it was warm today when it was warm and do the other bit when It was cold, but then we inverted it and did the opposite for years.
Speaker 0: So now I'm never sure which one Remember ever doing the opposite.
Speaker 1: I'm saying it's actually finally warm.
Speaker 0: We started pretty it's pretty great around 2008 or 2009. for years We would be like warm today when it was way too cold.
Speaker 0: And then that was our shtick.
Speaker 1: I don't remember that shtick.
Speaker 1: I just remember being honest with the weather.
Speaker 0: Yeah I had to turn on the air conditioning because I can't have the windows open Because they're working on the facade of the building and there's so much dust out there.
Speaker 1: It's a problem And it's not working.
Speaker 1: I haven't had to turn the AC on yet, but I did turn on the fan.
Speaker 0: briefly I have the windows open all the time except during and I've had wind.
Speaker 1: I've had windows open But there's no.
Speaker 1: the construction is far enough away That's not it.
Speaker 0: So I realized now how bad the facade on this building is and why they're redoing it.
Speaker 1: the city like that old a building.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they built it shittily.
Speaker 0: They're replacing you like a scary percentage of the bricks in the facade.
Speaker 0: Okay, they took like 50 bricks out of the facade just around our balcony alone And there's a giant pile of bricks and they're masonry them back in one by one.
Speaker 1: So I guess the bricks aren't the problem but such someone did shitty masonry.
Speaker 0: Yep The bricks in the facade were put in so shittily that they were all a like serious risk of injury or death to anyone walking Under our building.
Speaker 1: So I guess whoever did that original masonry.
Speaker 1: Are they gonna get sued or insurance or what?
Speaker 1: I have no love for the landlord.
Speaker 1: if they have to pay could they own a building?
Speaker 1: they can certainly afford it.
Speaker 1: But if it was, you know If I paid to have something done and it was done so shittily that it needed to be redone way ahead of schedule.
Speaker 1: I Would want yeah Well, you know what?
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's the classic situation of someone can be bad but also be wronged and still deserves justice for when they were wronged.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know within bounds there's certain people who don't deserve justice even but that's a whole separate conversation.
Speaker 1: I could just be like look, you know under normal circumstances.
Speaker 1: This would require some you know, some Justice action, but you've done injustices.
Speaker 1: So we're just gonna say it cancels out this afraid This will be your consequence.
Speaker 0: that other thing useful skeleton stole a bunch of stuff from your company But your company was exploiting workers so bad that you can't get anything back from them.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like huh, you know, this guy screwed you over.
Speaker 1: build in your building shittily, but you're an evil landlord.
Speaker 1: So I don't care eat it fucked.
Speaker 0: So, uh last weekend we uh, We went up hiking or two weekends ago.
Speaker 0: Oh god, it was two weekends ago.
Speaker 0: last weekend We went biking because it was finally warm enough.
Speaker 0: I saw you bike to you I'm you went up into the Tarrytown Bridge We went up to Briarcliff Manor and then just turned around and came back on the South County.
Speaker 0: hmm, though, uh When we went hiking the other day we went up to somewhere different.
Speaker 0: we wanted to do some mountain climbing.
Speaker 0: So we went up to the corner of like Connecticut massive who sits and New York.
Speaker 0: There's like a little corner there.
Speaker 0: We're like a like it's you just driver like even just driving past you go over all those borders a bunch of times Mm-hmm kind of near where the Harlan Valley Railroad usually is and I know where that is.
Speaker 0: We hiked this mountain and on the way home We were like, why don't we stop at the cafe Maya and get takeout and like eat that?
Speaker 0: Yeah, so we'd stop at the original cafe Maya the one on 90 not the one on in Fishkill Mm-hmm, and there's nobody eating outside.
Speaker 0: It's like empty.
Speaker 0: So we actually sit down outside and they turn out of heat lamp and we're just by ourselves.
Speaker 0: and we got that.
Speaker 0: I got Emily got a Verano.
Speaker 0: I got the enchilada squeezes.
Speaker 0: There's a really good time.
Speaker 0: the waiter Was talking to us and being like extra friendly like in a mask on we had a master.
Speaker 0: We're talking to him, but he's like being extra friendly and like we're just chatting and then he's like.
Speaker 0: I feel like I know you and we start talking.
Speaker 0: Remember when the cafe Maya opened in Beacon and then eventually failed?
Speaker 0: Yeah, so we were some of the only people that eat ate there apparently like it didn't go well at all.
Speaker 0: So yeah, uh, he remembered us because he was the only waiter they ever had.
Speaker 0: He was no waiter at the cafe Maya on Main Street in Beacon.
Speaker 0: He recognized us Me and Emily, I mean, that's cool.
Speaker 1: But also somebody was There there.
Speaker 1: that's their job for 10 years.
Speaker 0: Okay, I get the impression that that place actually pays them pretty well.
Speaker 1: I hope so.
Speaker 0: Yeah, what kind of like the bear?
Speaker 1: I hope after 10 years though, that guy's like just a manager and was doing waiting because there was you know slow time.
Speaker 0: Also, yeah I mean Let's put our communist hat on.
Speaker 0: the real answer is there should be dignity in all labor and there should be Totally expected and fine for most people to have a fairly quotes easy job their whole life.
Speaker 0: No one should have to try to get promoted into a quote real job because there's no such thing as a red job.
Speaker 1: I agree 100% but at the
Speaker 0: current late capitalism that implies that that dude probably is not Not on a great trajectory
Speaker 1: Right, but also even if you do have, you know dignity and good compensation in all labor I still feel like you know, if you've been you know Waiting tables for 10 plus years and you're just sort of still doing that.
Speaker 1: It's like I've been promised I during for 15 years Right, but it's like you you're you know, you must freakin, you know, really love that spot.
Speaker 0: I don't love product managing.
Speaker 0: Exactly The problem is capitalism.
Speaker 0: Anyway, anyway, I was that was just a surprising moment.
Speaker 0: So he taught it.
Speaker 0: he was.
Speaker 0: we actually talked to him a bit about that cafe Maya and how they thought it'd do so.
Speaker 0: Well, and the problem was all the people in bacon Most of the people who lived in Beacon wouldn't eat at the restaurants on Main Street.
Speaker 0: They'd all drive to the places in Fishkill Mmm, like the people who actually walked to Main Street and like ate in those places Relatively small group of people and on weekdays fucking nobody eats on Main Street.
Speaker 0: Well, so, uh, yeah, they tried really hard.
Speaker 0: We did we did.
Speaker 0: we were like the only ones.
Speaker 1: I Think they also might have tried too soon.
Speaker 1: I've heard that Beacon Main Street has, you know only continued to.
Speaker 0: It has.
Speaker 0: there are a few places open that were definitely like over fancy and catered to Out of towners like people who drive up from New York City and are only there on the weekends and we're overpriced food.
Speaker 0: But the restaurant scene in Beacon is pretty fucking awesome.
Speaker 0: We used to go up there a lot before COVID and we plan to go up there a lot.
Speaker 1: They still have that.
Speaker 1: what happened to his location is still open.
Speaker 0: Yeah but The problem is we went up to Beacon a bunch of times on weekends because we were hiking up there like in the previous years And it was awesome.
Speaker 0: Like it felt like like Main Street was crowded.
Speaker 0: There were people everywhere like walking around just tons of people.
Speaker 0: like it felt really bustling.
Speaker 0: Emily went back up like during that period when we were like We had to move up to Beacon.
Speaker 0: it wouldn't be so bad.
Speaker 0: She went up on like a Wednesday to take care of something like took the Metro North without me completely dead.
Speaker 0: There are only people there on the weekends.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's yeah.
Speaker 1: So they're working.
Speaker 0: So, uh Yeah, anyway in some news New York just announced and other states have done this It's I got a lot.
Speaker 0: I got a. I have a nuanced take on this and you might be surprised that I'm totally okay with this.
Speaker 0: New York State is now going to have a Vax and scratch program where if you are not vaccinated against kovat currently and During the time range they're doing this you go and get the vaccine.
Speaker 0: They will give you a for free a $20 lottery ticket for the upcoming five million dollar mega multiplier lottery.
Speaker 0: Okay Uh, I want.
Speaker 1: some other state did this recently I don't I just give people if it's a $20 scratch-off when I just give people 20 bucks.
Speaker 0: Yeah Because people are bad at statistics and I feel like the kind of
Speaker 1: rather have the 20 bucks
Speaker 0: I would argue The kind of person who needs to be given an incentive to go get a vaccine when it is free and easy to get one And wouldn't get a vaccine without that incentive Probably more swayed by the lottery ticket than 20 bucks.
Speaker 0: Maybe yeah, but other states did this to like.
Speaker 0: this was a thing and on one hand I am totally okay with this because the reality is humans are let's just charitably say complex and Anything that gets people to get the shot is okay in my book at this point like just get people to get the shot.
Speaker 0: but so like I'm totally okay if this stuff works and the evidence shows that other states that have done similar programs had Massive upticks in people getting the vaccine.
Speaker 0: So I am 100% good with this.
Speaker 0: I'm not mad about it I'm just disappointed in it because I hate that this works on people.
Speaker 0: I hate it because it doesn't work on me Like I know it doesn't.
Speaker 0: but also I'm weird and prickly about things like advertising and extra skeptical Like I like any email I get.
Speaker 0: that's even like slightly off I assume is malicious and delete like that's the kind of life I live.
Speaker 0: if I see an ad I assume the thing is bad until proven.
Speaker 0: Otherwise, I know you're like that, too It's just really sad to me how effective these lottery incentives for vaccinations are.
Speaker 0: But if they work do it do whatever works, that's how public health policy policy Right.
Speaker 1: I mean there's a it's.
Speaker 1: you know, we know that there are certain psychological tricks that work You know on most people even on people who are aware of them.
Speaker 1: occasionally Oh, right.
Speaker 1: I can get tricked and add might sneak in and trick me like Yeah, you know it happens and The problem is not it's like the tricking someone in and of itself.
Speaker 1: You could argue that it does harm someone in that you have taken away their agency or some aspect of it and manipulated them And that in and of itself is a violation a moral violation of the person's free will.
Speaker 0: if such a thing exists It is perhaps for a use of weapons.
Speaker 1: Yes, perhaps.
Speaker 1: But If you are manipulating someone into doing something that is perhaps Empirically beneficial to themselves others society the world the universe Right, and there wasn't some other way to do it.
Speaker 1: That was say less harmful, right?
Speaker 1: It's like okay.
Speaker 1: Is it?
Speaker 1: you know, this person refuses to willingly get the vaccine?
Speaker 1: I will attempt the moral path of convincing them.
Speaker 1: just normally They refuse still.
Speaker 1: Okay, what is more harmful a let them go about their business?
Speaker 1: Unvaccinated be trick them with a lottery ticket kind of situation Be hold them down and inject them with physical force.
Speaker 1: I'm good with the two that you just raised right But you get the idea it's like, you know, you don't really want to go exactly my take on this kind of thing to like.
Speaker 0: These psychological tricks are gonna be used for evil no matter what we do have to minimize the uses for evil But the reality is it will be used for evil.
Speaker 0: Look at bad memes Misinformation campaigns like people who watch Fox News and literally believe objectively false things right, but if these things exist anyway And will be used for evil then don't we do we not have a moral obligation to use them for good wherever possible?
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean, you know, there's the old saying do the ends justify the means right?
Speaker 1: and obviously the answer depends on the means Right, of course, you know The answer is you know The saying is the ends don't justify the means.
Speaker 1: and I think people take that as like just this absolute thing Which is like, you know, and they think of like some extreme circumstance, right?
Speaker 1: It's like, you know, oh, you know you just You know, we want to.
Speaker 1: we could get rid of say I don't know tax filing.
Speaker 0: We can literally just get rid of that whole industry and have the government auto file taxes for people.
Speaker 1: that would put that way No doubt, that would be a good ends.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we can achieve that by murdering every single person at the TurboTax corporation.
Speaker 0: Well, we could also have.
Speaker 1: it would not justify those.
Speaker 1: those means would not justify that end.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but a but even imagine this.
Speaker 0: the means would be the IRS just provides it for free as a service.
Speaker 0: the Includes a whole ton of people don't have jobs anymore.
Speaker 1: Well, but that's it.
Speaker 1: That's an ends.
Speaker 1: That's not a means that has nothing to do with ends justifying the means.
Speaker 1: Those are ends.
Speaker 1: Those are additional ends.
Speaker 1: Those aren't means.
Speaker 0: Arguably, well one could argue that shutting down the industry is also the means to the end of people don't have to do taxes anymore.
Speaker 1: Semantic I think.
Speaker 1: people get the idea that you know, it's like yeah there are cases where ends don't justify means.
Speaker 1: but it's like yeah, if you're if your means is trick someone and the end is You know end a pandemic.
Speaker 1: You could just have them, you know that end could justify that means.
Speaker 1: it definitely could You know.
Speaker 0: So in some other news, I know we talked about this before.
Speaker 0: we thought that the peppermint butler Adventure time was gonna come next as most people did.
Speaker 0: we learned that in fact, it's the one about Finn and Jake.
Speaker 0: Neither of us have seen it yet.
Speaker 0: Uh But people are talking about it already.
Speaker 1: All I've really seen you know is is you know, not that I care about spoilers But people other people do care about spoilers, so they haven't posted any.
Speaker 1: so I haven't seen any And not that I'm looking for them either.
Speaker 1: I'm just gonna watch it probably pretty soon Yep, but yeah, what I've seen is a lot of people have saying like wow that hits hard Wow.
Speaker 1: It is serious Wow I shouldn't have watched that to start my day what?
Speaker 0: clubs headline Bob said it best.
Speaker 0: Finn and Jake are back and they've brought adventure times darker impulses with them.
Speaker 1: Yes, that gives me the impression that maybe they should have done this one last unless the P butts one got something going on.
Speaker 0: Yeah Maybe they don't want to end on this note, or maybe they'll keep making these forever.
Speaker 1: Maybe that's just how things worked out.
Speaker 1: But yeah, apparently this really hits huh?
Speaker 0: So that your time as a whole hit pretty hard in a lot of different.
Speaker 0: no Apparently this is this is even more even more and I want that because adventure time pushed.
Speaker 0: I do want that and all sorts of different directions.
Speaker 0: So fuck me up with the.
Speaker 0: fuck me up with the feels adventure time.
Speaker 0: I'm ready.
Speaker 1: You're gonna get fucked up.
Speaker 1: That's what's gonna happen.
Speaker 0: I Think I'm excited enough about this to where even though we're only about halfway through the last season of castle vassal I think we're gonna watch this first.
Speaker 0: Mmm, I didn't see one spoiler.
Speaker 0: I ended up a random YouTube video for Castlevania got recommended to me and the title was so and so's death in Castlevania and it had a thumbnail that was like well, that's how that character goes down.
Speaker 0: Thank you Internet.
Speaker 1: I guess I kind of wonder who it could be.
Speaker 0: Well knowing the Castlevania lore excludes several characters Indeed unless they break from the Castlevania lore I mean I could I'm willing to put a small amount of money down.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well we'll talk about that separately.
Speaker 0: when we actually talk about that show ending I think it.
Speaker 0: I think it'll deserve a final thoughts.
Speaker 0: episode Mmm, like a review of the entire thing.
Speaker 1: It's not really gonna end they're gonna make another thing.
Speaker 0: Ah, the another thing though.
Speaker 0: They've said it's gonna be different characters and possibly in a different part of the timeline.
Speaker 1: I think it'll be a different Belmont right?
Speaker 1: This one is what.
Speaker 1: which Belmont are we dealing with in the current one Trevor?
Speaker 0: Yeah, the next.
Speaker 0: so they could go Richter they or they could go Simon do a precursor story Which I think there's plenty of Belmont's that they can do right?
Speaker 0: I'd like to see a Simon one.
Speaker 0: I Mean, yeah, duh But anyway things of the day, what do you got?
Speaker 1: So this?
Speaker 1: articles from like late April here and What it is.
Speaker 1: It's sort of like this I guess a piece in this magazine about this guy and his job or at least his job was To be the money collecting counting person for the MTA Right in New York.
Speaker 1: So all the basically all the subway bus money.
Speaker 1: You know all the cash right it has.
Speaker 1: you know, you put quarters in the in the bus.
Speaker 1: You can still do that if even though they they take you can swipe your phone in the bus now But you can still put quarters in And you know if on the subway it's like yeah, you got the MetroCard, but then they got the MetroCard machines.
Speaker 1: You're shitting cash into those things and then MetroCard come out or you go up to the window the window You give them cash.
Speaker 1: they give you MetroCards.
Speaker 1: right all that cash goes to one place eventually Where it is counted and organized and such and such.
Speaker 1: and this person was the boss of that place And you know its security and its operations for a very long time and It's pretty close to where we live.
Speaker 1: It's it's you know, we don't know the exact location because it's semi-secret But you know, it's mixed in amongst the bakeries and other warehouses and stuff over there garages and it's really fascinating how that kind of place operates and it seems you know, like It would be very lucrative if you could heist it but also next to impossible to heist it.
Speaker 0: well It would be easier to heist Materially than Fort Knox just because cash is way lighter than gold.
Speaker 1: Sure, Fort Knox.
Speaker 1: I heard doesn't have that much gold is really the Federal Reserve you want to get yeah Which is also nearby in a basement.
Speaker 1: Good luck.
Speaker 0: Yeah I always just think back to why didn't fucking anyone in high school Actually tell me about the kinds of jobs that existed in the real world?
Speaker 1: Well, cuz these are these jobs that are like this that are like these one in a million jobs, right?
Speaker 1: It's like this.
Speaker 1: it's it's a unique position.
Speaker 1: It's not like oh you could be a cash room runner.
Speaker 1: It's like that's not a common job.
Speaker 0: There's only so many come from someone working in an industry and slowly Specializing while also rising in the ranks within that industry.
Speaker 1: There's only so many organizations that have a need for such a person and that person usually gets in that position Because they've done like.
Speaker 1: another thing.
Speaker 1: like I remember I was listening to a podcast About the guy who was a lawyer and you know, there was like the 9/11 You know fund to sort of give money to all the people who suffered in 9/11 right to distribute money, right?
Speaker 1: So this lawyer was just like managing this this, you know benefit fund, right?
Speaker 1: How did that lawyer get that job?
Speaker 1: Apparently a long time ago.
Speaker 1: There was some other similar fund.
Speaker 1: the guy was just you know, like a early in his career kind of lawyer and He just happened to get you know a job You know managing one of those sorts of funds and is just now by circumstance these like premier expert on running those sorts of things.
Speaker 1: Right, it's it's not so like if you go to law school there probably isn't even like, you know I can't imagine there.
Speaker 1: Maybe there's a class on something like that Because it's such a specialized thing.
Speaker 1: How many of those frickin things are there right?
Speaker 1: You know, not too many It's.
Speaker 1: you know, there aren't room for that many specialists, but just being in the right place at the right time You know and have is just how you can end up in something and then if there's just the right number of Things in that category.
Speaker 1: Well now that's your that's your life.
Speaker 0: now You know, it's kind of funny cuz that's sort of how I like on a low-key way how I ended up doing the kind of work that I do is I learned this one protocol and Slowly.
Speaker 0: that just kept worming its way into my life and giving me like different opportunity.
Speaker 1: You didn't I didn't seek out.
Speaker 1: you didn't seek it out.
Speaker 1: You weren't?
Speaker 1: you didn't know about it in advance.
Speaker 1: You're just in a spot.
Speaker 1: you had to learn that you were in a spot doing a thing.
Speaker 1: You had to learn a thing and then because you learn the thing then not too many other people knew.
Speaker 1: Well now that's your thing.
Speaker 0: Yep I'm trying to get away from that being my thing But it's hard because I have a. I have a scarily deep reputation for strangers I meet in my industry like oh, you're the fixed guy.
Speaker 1: I know you I've heard of you.
Speaker 0: Okay No one remembers me as the clock setting guy.
Speaker 0: At least I got a guy wormed my way out of that one.
Speaker 1: You should go back to clock setting.
Speaker 1: It's more fun.
Speaker 0: It's different now.
Speaker 0: I actually don't know the state-of-the-art Me either.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's not NTP though.
Speaker 0: I'll tell you that you could.
Speaker 1: you could figure it out.
Speaker 1: I'm sure.
Speaker 0: well I have people who do that for me.
Speaker 0: I could I could go ask my people.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so my thing of the day could possibly.
Speaker 0: Well, probably not because I doubt there's a lot of glass in this place But it could plausibly if there was a glass security wall of some kind be a way to Perhaps liberate some of that coin.
Speaker 1: So, uh, never.
Speaker 0: I never heard of this term before but I learned it Well, I was literally looking up the details of this thing of the day.
Speaker 0: There's a whole Wikipedia article on the concept of ninja rocks.
Speaker 1: That sounds like a kids show.
Speaker 0: Yep, it's also.
Speaker 0: I guess these existed before but they started being called ninja rocks in the 90s Probably because America was obsessed with ninjas for some reason during that era.
Speaker 0: Like that was the thing late 80s through like late 90s like America.
Speaker 0: There's a lot of ninja stuff in pop culture.
Speaker 1: So we need sure we should bring the ninjas back a ninja rock.
Speaker 0: There's a small Incredibly light thing Usually made of like alumina and it looks like a really tiny pebble.
Speaker 0: like they're so small and light You'll be shocked that this would work.
Speaker 0: But if you throw them at a piece of glass Especially safety glass tempered glass.
Speaker 0: It'll just fucking shatter Mm-hmm, like a pebble wouldn't do it even with the glasses even if the glass is laminated.
Speaker 0: Yeah laminated Tempered glass it'll shatter but it'll stay within the laminate usually.
Speaker 1: Well, that's what lemon it's for.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you don't get cut up with glass if it breaks.
Speaker 0: So, uh what the so I want?
Speaker 0: I wondered after I learned these are called ninja rocks.
Speaker 0: Hey could I buy these on Amazon?
Speaker 1: and it turns out you could just buy them on Amazon because I've heard rumors that you could just Like take a spark plug and sort of smash it and take the pieces of the ceramic part.
Speaker 0: That is exactly it.
Speaker 0: Nothing, if you can't buy anything called a ninja rock on Amazon But you can buy spark plugs for a few bucks each.
Speaker 0: And yeah, basically just smash a spark plug with a hammer and all the white pieces that fall out.
Speaker 0: Those are ninja rocks.
Speaker 1: Like how how hard do you have to throw it?
Speaker 0: Uh, not that hard like with your arm strength.
Speaker 0: You could basically carry them in your pocket Like it.
Speaker 1: or does I have to throw it?
Speaker 0: throw like imagine throwing a tiny pebble like it's a baseball.
Speaker 0: Okay, so you have to react to throw it like wing it like you're trying to skip a rock about that level of violence.
Speaker 1: Right, but like if I just go like eh it's not gonna do it.
Speaker 1: probably some power.
Speaker 1: you need some power.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but you know what is what is so if this this?
Speaker 1: I've only heard of this.
Speaker 1: I've never witnessed it.
Speaker 1: It weren't really true.
Speaker 1: I've done it.
Speaker 1: if it's really true explained to me the physics behind this.
Speaker 0: Oh, so the ceramic or alumina like that type of material is extremely brittle and extremely hard.
Speaker 0: It also if you break it because it's so brittle it forms a lot like multiple extremely sharp points That are small.
Speaker 1: That's that's true.
Speaker 0: so if you wing it at a piece of tempered glass those sharp points have a high percentage likelihood of Hitting one of those tiny fault lines that causes the tensile strength to loot to explode and have the whole thing shatter.
Speaker 1: It's I say because it is so pointy.
Speaker 1: Yes All of the power goes into that one Very small area.
Speaker 0: you need pointy and hard are the key but you might but you might.
Speaker 1: if you miss You may have to throw if you might not work every time.
Speaker 0: the thing is when I've done it It worked every time and I've seen videos where it just works.
Speaker 1: every time Like I have to watch on you you have a easier thing of the day.
Speaker 1: YouTube video explaining it is Frating because my good and I don't have to search for one.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I haven't used the slow-mo guys in a long time because the I've talked about I've used them multiple times.
Speaker 0: Oh Yeah, they uploaded a new video Yesterday because there is a new phantom camera and it can record at up to 800,000 frames per second.
Speaker 1: It's a big number.
Speaker 0: That is the biggest number that Still black.
Speaker 1: Is it black and white?
Speaker 1: I'm guessing.
Speaker 0: Nope full color This can.
Speaker 1: usually the ultra high-speed ones are black and white only.
Speaker 0: so this one can record like high resolution video at Higher frame rates than almost any one of the cameras they've ever used before and it cost eight hundred thousand dollars a dollar per frame.
Speaker 0: So if you turn it if you reduce the vertical resolution But keep the horizontal resolution you get this thing all the way up to a little over 800,000 frames a second.
Speaker 0: and it's funny because the first half of the video is he's like this fucking camera Like.
Speaker 0: look at this the.
Speaker 0: the exposure time is now being measured in Nanoseconds.
Speaker 0: ten twelve nanoseconds of exposure per frame.
Speaker 1: That's pretty great.
Speaker 0: so, uh, he records throwing a piece of a spark plug add some tempered glass and it's so High frame rate that you actually can see the breaking of the glass moving slowly Which they've never been able to achieve with any camera they've ever had before.
Speaker 0: Awesome, it's Really amazing to watch.
Speaker 0: and of course, they uploaded it in glorious 4k.
Speaker 0: So this video is only is less than 10 minutes long and a hundred percent worth watching In the better moment.
Speaker 0: still mostly stuck inside, but it's warm out.
Speaker 1: Yep, we were gonna do a show Tuesday, and we didn't because rim bailed.
Speaker 0: Yeah, bye bales at the pet.
Speaker 1: It was at the pet vet.
Speaker 0: I had to take the pet to the vet.
Speaker 0: moogies fine He's.
Speaker 0: he's got to go back to the vet on Monday for a tooth thing.
Speaker 0: He needs a dental Cleaning and we got to grind down some little spurs on his teeth, but he's doing fine Tooth spurs.
Speaker 1: I want can I get some tooth spurs?
Speaker 0: You don't want to spurs.
Speaker 0: They hurt a little bit when you chew.
Speaker 0: No, I'm gonna grind it down to get rid of them.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I wanted to grind up things by chewing Molars.
Speaker 0: for that your molars are good enough.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they're okay My molars are pretty good at that.
Speaker 0: But uh, yeah, we'll do that show.
Speaker 0: Don't worry We'll review Pokemon snap.
Speaker 0: It's uh, it's just Pokemon snap to like almost exactly.
Speaker 1: also in the meta moment The book club book is still you know, the tale of Genji.
Speaker 1: It's gonna be that for a while, you know But hopefully not too much longer.
Speaker 1: We'll see.
Speaker 0: Yep I'll.
Speaker 0: uh, the problem is even if I start going back to my office in the coming months Occasionally, I'm gonna be biking cuz I'm not riding the subway yet.
Speaker 0: So nothing's changing.
Speaker 1: Well, you know what was changed.
Speaker 1: I think is that I'm not Watching hockey games.
Speaker 1: so that is basically if I'm not doing geek nights, you know I'm gavel.
Speaker 1: I have more free time than I did before and not losing like a few hours here and there.
Speaker 1: and also the.
Speaker 1: you know This hockey season there were so many games closer together.
Speaker 1: So I was losing way more time.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but But also it's warm enough for me to just go sit in the park and read which is something I've been right.
Speaker 1: The balcony I have here compared to the one at my previous apartment is way more usable and comfy.
Speaker 1: So if it's warm, it's like I got it's like I finish eating dinner.
Speaker 1: It's like what I got to do.
Speaker 1: Oh go outside and read on my balcony.
Speaker 1: Why not?
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: And while I could also play the switch out there I'm uh, I'm switched out right now.
Speaker 0: I've played enough games on the switch.
Speaker 0: I played Pokemon snap.
Speaker 0: enough to review it.
Speaker 0: I don't have to play switch every single night and people are.
Speaker 1: you know, I could play games with people But people don't seem to want to play games Much these days.
Speaker 1: they want to go where it's warm play overwatch with me.
Speaker 0: No, I'll buy it for you.
Speaker 1: No I don't even have battle net installed anymore.
Speaker 0: I'm trying to cut down I don't build up and I guess otherwise stay tuned for there's gonna be a new another packs online and There's a high likelihood.
Speaker 0: We'll be doing between one and three panels for it.
Speaker 0: So stay tuned on that and It's all I got.
Speaker 1: Follow us on just yeah follow us in the internet.
Speaker 1: We are everywhere.
Speaker 1: and I just want to remind people You know that our forum specifically, you know, we got a discord going on.
Speaker 1: We got a forum, you know, we got Twitter.
Speaker 1: You know, we got YouTube, right?
Speaker 1: We got.
Speaker 1: I think our community has become like a little dispersed.
Speaker 1: right people are going to the place that they want to be Which is good, right go to the place that you want to be.
Speaker 1: But our forum specifically right I think is like not getting.
Speaker 1: You know, it's it's still active even after all these years, but it's like its activeness is not increasing.
Speaker 0: Well, it's interesting because the mostly what I see is forums serve an important purpose But it's a purpose that a lot of people on the internet don't care about anymore as if you want to have an asynchronous Conversation where you type a lot.
Speaker 1: well, that's true, but I think also there are quite a few people who use our forum as Like a platform to like host what would otherwise be like a standalone blog, right?
Speaker 1: So it's like we got.
Speaker 0: I like that a lot.
Speaker 0: I actually like.
Speaker 0: I don't post in our forum a ton because I'm busy But I read our forum because good stuff gets posted there, right?
Speaker 1: So like imagine, you know, it's like, you know We got a listener who's big in a pro wrestling that we haven't been into since we were kids.
Speaker 1: Right and when big pro wrestling stuff comes they make what's basically in this one thread like a huge as blog post.
Speaker 1: I read it even though I don't know or care about pro wrestling that much.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I read it.
Speaker 1: Anyway, you know something big will happen in like, you know, I don't know.
Speaker 1: imagine the gathering and it's like.
Speaker 1: we don't care about that But there's a listener who does and they come and make a huge blog post about it right or you know We don't care about.
Speaker 1: I don't care about Formula One racing as much as I used to but occasionally some Something will happen and someone will post a big thing.
Speaker 1: You know, it's like those people could just have their own blogs of their own Twitter threads and post those things on their own somewhere But they all post them in the same place.
Speaker 1: as we got a friend who's designing a board game.
Speaker 1: They make like huge Design diary posts all the time, right?
Speaker 0: It's like and I see that's a ton of people read that stuff.
Speaker 0: Even if very few people are posting that stuff, right?
Speaker 1: So it's like if you started your own WordPress blog, you know, how many people would read it, right?
Speaker 1: You know if you're if you're not already a popular famous internet person probably it, you know, it'd be hard, right?
Speaker 1: So, you know, I would recommend if you if you're this something you're doing, you know that you could make like a big-ass posts about right?
Speaker 1: It's like I'm posting big-ass kpop posts in there that no one responds to but I think people are.
Speaker 0: I read.
Speaker 0: I read everyone.
Speaker 0: They're fascinating.
Speaker 1: I don't care if people are reading them or not But I just you could read.
Speaker 0: you could probably get a history of like the last X years of kpop I really like there's been a thread that I've been enjoying that is just called songs about trains that you started.
Speaker 0: and Yeah, it just keeps going And I keep finding more songs about trains.
Speaker 0: My favorite post though was someone who just out of nowhere realized that song that was made famous in the Blues Brothers is about a train.
Speaker 1: Sure, so, you know, I just if you're so if you're somehow listening to this I think you belong at least as a lurker in our forum.
Speaker 0: It is totally cool to lurk in that forum Like you don't have to community community front row crew.
Speaker 1: calm if you try to make an account there.
Speaker 1: Make sure that when you fill out the registration form you fill out all the stuff and make make it clear to me Who will be seeing or registration application that you are a real human being?
Speaker 1: You know who listens and whatnot, so I don't reject you.
Speaker 1: And if I do reject you just email me and that will make it very clear or you know It'll make it clear that you were real person and I rejected you back.
Speaker 1: But I've never had I assume like I'm basically not hesitant at all to reject if I have the slightest doubt because I feel like If I accidentally reject someone they'll be like, hey, why'd I get rejected?
Speaker 1: I'm like, ah, it's a real first.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'll fix that right for you right now.
Speaker 1: That's never happened.
Speaker 0: So and our discord is cool I like our discord too.
Speaker 0: I actually I try to make a point of hanging out in there more even if I don't post a lot cuz I'm just busy.
Speaker 0: But you know the difference between them is the discord is just people kind of bantering and playing random games And it's a fun active place.
Speaker 0: But like Scott said the forum is really like.
Speaker 0: just there's a lot of content there and that content is actually pretty good.
Speaker 1: The discord people do have little do use the voice chat a lot and hang out and they also will stream games They're playing.
Speaker 1: I seen people streaming some some stuff in there.
Speaker 0: We will eventually when they add slide and video support to the discord stage We will definitely also be doing geek nights.
Speaker 0: live in there.
Speaker 0: Yep, so actually last thing I'll say we're.
Speaker 0: I don't know when we're gonna do this But we are we're planning at some point.
Speaker 0: talk today.
Speaker 0: This is something I 100% want to do is use the discord stage To do a call-in show which we never did before because while we had the technology to do it The pipeline to do call-in podcasts is a gigantic pain in the ass and the discord stage Actually makes it really reasonable and easy to do.
Speaker 1: Yep, theoretically.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and I want to try it.
Speaker 1: So stay tuned after him after 15 years We'll finally do the call-in style radio show.
Speaker 1: We won't do it all the time something something that Something that normal old radio stations have been doing since telephones.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know how they did it.
Speaker 0: They had the if it was a show with like two hosts.
Speaker 0: They had the third person who dealt with all that shit and had a bunch of technology.
Speaker 1: It was their actual jobs.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we're not hiring anyone to work on the geek nights except like graphic designers and maybe some coders.
Speaker 0: but stay tuned on that, too.
Speaker 1: mm-hmm all right, so The title?
Speaker 1: yeah, well it was.
Speaker 1: it was my idea that I was against that I knew rim would be for.
Speaker 1: yeah Basically, you know how we have tech news roundup, right?
Speaker 1: But it's all tech news and I was like, hey, it's Thursday Let's just do a roundup of things that are a not news Not things of the day because we could use those as news the things that they don't waste them, right?
Speaker 1: And are not things that could be a geek night's show topic, right?
Speaker 1: But yet you have something to say right?
Speaker 1: that seems to happen quite a bit like I got something to say about something.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right, but yet It's not like a show topic.
Speaker 1: It could be like a mini rant, but it isn't necessarily a negative grind My gears style rant.
Speaker 1: it could just be like I noticed a thing and I have something to say about it and whatever and I Was like it.
Speaker 1: well if we could you know Just combine all those into one show.
Speaker 1: that got real Out of your system.
Speaker 0: Eldian swatch the deal with.
Speaker 1: we already did it.
Speaker 1: We already did a podcast about nothing.
Speaker 1: We can't do that again But it's a.
Speaker 0: it's funny cuz on the patreon for a while and I kind of stopped doing it during Covid in particular and a little bit before.
Speaker 0: there's rants rims rants.
Speaker 0: I am planning to bring that back.
Speaker 0: I just I got to get enough of a Backlog right after the cut right after the call-in show, uh, probably right after the call-in show actually.
Speaker 0: But I did that for a while.
Speaker 0: But what I struggled with was that because that was a scheduled thing I had to have something to talk about every week and I had to force it and I felt like I had to talk about it long enough to make it like a podcast If that was worth listening to like go at least 15 or 20 minutes.
Speaker 0: Otherwise, like who cares?
Speaker 0: So It's a lot of things.
Speaker 0: I have maybe Three minutes of things to say but then Scott might have something to say and it's a lot harder to do that kind of thing.
Speaker 0: When it's just me talking to the void I feel like I have to lecture and fill the time as opposed to a normal conversation.
Speaker 0: Two friends might have about a thing where stop Scott might have some insight.
Speaker 0: I didn't think of or an anecdote to relate and like how every now and then mere Scott has had to do a panel by herself at a con and It's way hard to do the kind of panel we do for an hour without someone else to bounce off of.
Speaker 0: hmm Is by myself once at a Connecticut and that was grueling All right.
Speaker 1: So here's an is an example of something that came to mind where I got something to say, right?
Speaker 1: So, you know being a person who has you know podcasted Streamed YouTube videoed owns lots of cameras and other recording equipment, right?
Speaker 1: I sort my brain.
Speaker 1: It's like any literally almost anything I do.
Speaker 1: that's not just like everyday stuff or even sometimes everyday stuff.
Speaker 1: I sort of get into my head the idea like oh, man I should record that or put it up or make a. you know, I've been production out of it.
Speaker 0: I have forced myself years ago to not live that way because for the first like five years We did geek nights that consumed my every thought.
Speaker 0: anything I did anywhere was like, oh I gotta figure out how to turn this into content and put it on geek dice expand the Empire, huh?
Speaker 1: Really it's like in me up All right, it's like oh let's go biking.
Speaker 1: it's like man.
Speaker 1: I should bring camera and I should make I should make like a little video montage of this bike ride and upload it when I'm done Right, and what I found is that you know, maybe if I did that every single time, right?
Speaker 1: It would be enough content.
Speaker 1: It actually, you know, I would get better at it from practicing and doing it more And it would grow an audience and it would.
Speaker 1: there would be.
Speaker 1: there probably could be a return on investment.
Speaker 1: But the problem is is that the effort required in doing it sort of a takes away from the thing you're actually doing.
Speaker 1: yup, right and B puts up a barrier to where you might not actually do the thing, right?
Speaker 1: So like, you know, oh I'm gonna go on this bike ride.
Speaker 1: Well now if I'm gonna carry all this camera shit, maybe I'm.
Speaker 1: you know, it's like fuck it.
Speaker 1: Let's just stay home Right or all right.
Speaker 1: Well, let's not bike as far because I'm carrying all this shit or You know, I'm not gonna bike along I'm not gonna bike long and get in the zone Right and concentrate and biking because I keep stopping and doing camera shit all the time.
Speaker 0: the GoPro Problem is what I've seen.
Speaker 0: some people call that they get a GoPro and then now like every time they ski they think well I bought that GoPro.
Speaker 0: I can't waste it.
Speaker 0: So they like try to use the GoPro to capture video of skiing But that's really hard and it adds a lot of overhead to skiing.
Speaker 0: I'm a lot happier when I don't either don't bring that GoPro at all or I bring it and I tell myself in advance I am only going to bother fucking with this piece device if something interesting is happening and I want to record this for me.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's what I do is I have Yeah on my bike.
Speaker 1: I have a GoPro mount on the front and when I go on the bike ride I put the GoPro in there and I make sure the batteries are charged and the memory cards empty up.
Speaker 1: But other than that I don't like, you know Turn it on record the whole ride Swap the memory cards and swap the batteries constantly because that's a pain in the butt and you know, you don't remember it You don't notice it.
Speaker 1: It's a big distraction and you just get a bunch of useless footage.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right It's like if I need to take photos and I'm on a bike ride I just use my iPhone which is actually a better still camera than the GoPro is.
Speaker 1: At least the GoPro that I have.
Speaker 0: I have the newest.
Speaker 0: It's actually I've GoPro.
Speaker 1: I have GoPro 5.
Speaker 0: the newest GoPro is scary good.
Speaker 1: It's really good.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the five is still 4k 30 or whatever.
Speaker 1: I'll just still plenty good enough.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah I mean for the things will actually use them for to make content like review con like recording ourselves playing a board game.
Speaker 0: Those two GoPros are going to be indispensable.
Speaker 1: Yeah I think the the features that the only feature I've seen that my GoPro does not have that new war ones do have is the Ability to stream to your phone which would then stream to the internet.
Speaker 0: Yeah I think I have more slow-mo options and the low-light performance is better.
Speaker 1: You probably like higher frame rate or whatever Stuff like that.
Speaker 1: But anyway, the point is is it's just like.
Speaker 1: yeah, it's just a thing that you know.
Speaker 1: I could talk about that, you know I could produce more content, but I don't because it makes you know, it's sort of like.
Speaker 1: You know sort of like interferes with the thing you're actually doing.
Speaker 1: running of Strava Strava Addiction is something people run into to where like I don't have that Right, I push start and when I end the bike ride if I stop.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but the people who like have to make sure it's right and worry about the stats and like get it every time like lately Unless I'm running like four or five miles.
Speaker 0: Like if I'm doing a short workout, I don't track it I don't like going to Google Fit and like even type anything in.
Speaker 0: I don't even try to even bring my phone and it's so It was so liberating to just walk outside start running not think about anything.
Speaker 0: Just enjoy it.
Speaker 0: yep, I the only I basically if it's The listener is just like ah GoPro FOMO.
Speaker 1: Yeah, because Oh FOMO for sure.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like I have my bike computer Which I only use them like a long bike ride when I need the GPS functionality.
Speaker 1: and with that I just I'm putting I'm gonna be using the bike computer because I want to don't not get lost and that will Automatically send over to Strava, right?
Speaker 1: So I have to do any special Strava stuff right.
Speaker 1: the indoor biking again with the with the Zwift bike MMO Automatically will go to Strava.
Speaker 1: I don't do anything special right?
Speaker 1: my Apple watch If I go if I if it senses that I'm exercising It'll be like hey, are you walking?
Speaker 1: and I'll just be like, yes, right?
Speaker 1: I don't go into it and intentionally You know poke it.
Speaker 1: It's just I let everything sort of track passively.
Speaker 1: if something isn't passively tracked.
Speaker 1: It's not tracked I don't care, right just go about my business.
Speaker 1: But
Speaker 0: I don't want to get too far in the direction of never making interesting content because one of the things that did make us Sort of get good at this quickly was we were a little hungry to make content and we did experiment a lot in the early Days, it was a lot of effort and we kind of stopped like the last like seven or eight packs as we went to.
Speaker 0: We literally brought the bare minimum equipment to do the bare minimum content creation and we just enjoyed our packs.
Speaker 1: and I don't I've had This idea like oh, I got all this stuff I'll edit the video on my laptop while we're there.
Speaker 1: and it's I never did it.
Speaker 0: That one never really and it was barely did.
Speaker 0: it was fine early But we recorded one of those and I was pretty drunk and it worked out.
Speaker 0: But like in San Antonio that one year we went around and spent like an hour Interviewing those statues and like doing a bunch of fun.
Speaker 1: You're very lonely at that that that packs out of the first.
Speaker 0: Yeah we also.
Speaker 0: We did that thing like three or four times where we'd go through the expo hall and like get a bunch of footage and like Put a big video together and it was fun.
Speaker 0: But it took so much effort and so few people gave a shit after the first one.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: Well, I don't care how many people give a shit.
Speaker 1: It's a question of whether I enjoy me.
Speaker 0: That's it.
Speaker 0: I'm focusing right now on other than baseline geek diets where it's like we still force ourselves to do it.
Speaker 0: But I'm not gonna try to make content unless it is fun to make that content beyond the baseline content I already make right.
Speaker 1: if I'm if I'm gonna be making content, it's like I. you know, it can't be.
Speaker 1: you know It's like I've always thought oh, it's you know, it's it's so great.
Speaker 1: video photo Recording just sort of goes with everything that you're doing right.
Speaker 1: if I'm doing some other hobby It's like well, I can just combo or I can get two for one deal.
Speaker 1: But now it's like.
Speaker 1: I still do Photo video stuff as a hobby, but I'm only doing it if it is the primary thing Like I'm going to go out and do photos now, right?
Speaker 1: It's photo time.
Speaker 1: I'm not like.
Speaker 1: well, I'm doing um, I don't know Biking right better, you know carry 20 cameras with That happening.
Speaker 0: Well, I remember the moment the one magfest.
Speaker 0: we were like fuck it Let's not even record our panels.
Speaker 0: and I packed so little to bring to that con.
Speaker 0: It was weird.
Speaker 1: Yeah All right.
Speaker 1: So that was that's an example of a thing.
Speaker 1: I got something to talk about.
Speaker 1: It's not a show.
Speaker 1: It's not you.
Speaker 0: So I grew this beard because you know been my whole life I would I was mustached until not too long after our IT and then I got rid of the mustache and then I would alternate between clean-shaven stubbly because I'm lazy and Scraggly beard because I'm extra lazy.
Speaker 0: that eventually goes back to clean-shaven.
Speaker 0: Maybe like four or five times I've grown a beard on purpose, but usually only for a relatively short span of time that I get rid of it.
Speaker 0: but I grew a beard during quarantine and I kind of just kept it and I actually maintained it.
Speaker 0: and Now I'm in a situation where?
Speaker 0: Almost everyone I know who has interacted with me on video chat is Constantly telling me that I look better with a beard and I should keep the beard.
Speaker 0: and there's like this Huge pressure of you look great with a beard never get rid of it.
Speaker 0: That is amazing.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and I would never thought I'd be the kind of person who would wear a beard because I tended to always like to be pretty clean-shaven, uh And I'm 50/50 on if I'm gonna keep the beard after COVID or not It's up to you.
Speaker 1: You can always grow it back.
Speaker 1: I can take.
Speaker 1: it takes me when you're 90 year old man The beard still gonna grow.
Speaker 0: I mean it takes About eight days to grow a full beard for me Like it's a full beard after eight days like wait eight days shave the neck.
Speaker 0: I think the one difference is when I started having a beard longer than two a couple weeks I actually had to go learn how to take care of a beard because it's not actually that intuitive.
Speaker 0: Like a lot of people want to grow a beard and the beard ends up not looking the way they want.
Speaker 0: Sometimes you just lose the genetic lottery like it's patchy like you can't do anything about that.
Speaker 0: Sometimes you got a hair issue where it doesn't work out.
Speaker 0: But if you can grow a good beard Like you got to learn techniques of like what to do about it or it'll kind of look bad by default.
Speaker 0: I think a lot of people get discouraged because it just looks bad.
Speaker 0: They don't know why they don't want to pay someone to fix It and you actually have to learn to do some things and maybe even buy a little bit of equipment.
Speaker 0: like you can't get away with just scissors most likely.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean, I know, you know, I do think I actually look better with you know Some amount of facial pretty good with a beard like a like a one of those clean-cut like a lot like a very stark line.
Speaker 0: Beards looks pretty good on you, right?
Speaker 1: The problem is is that basically I was just having so many face problems like, you know Itching and scratching and ingrown herring and all that kind of stuff and I'm just sort of like I went the opposite direction during the quarantine.
Speaker 1: It's like well, I don't you know have all this time not commuting.
Speaker 1: I can actually shave More frequently, right And you know put lotions on my face whatever.
Speaker 1: I tried the beard oils and they didn't really work.
Speaker 1: So that's really that was my attempt right?
Speaker 1: It's like alright Let me try these beard oils and my beard oil and a beard balm.
Speaker 0: I use the beard oil just kind of all the time and I use the balm if I'm going out or doing a video and I The beard to like stay nice and like well-groomed.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like it.
Speaker 1: It helped a little bit, but it didn't it.
Speaker 1: after a certain point the beard, you know when the beard got bigger It's like no your face itches no matter what now.
Speaker 1: and I was like, oh fuck this right.
Speaker 1: and it's like This way I don't have any Irritation in my face.
Speaker 1: if I just don't have it then who cares if it looks worse, whatever.
Speaker 1: I'd rather not have face irritation up.
Speaker 0: So the listener was actually asked a question.
Speaker 0: What special techniques did you have to learn?
Speaker 0: I had to learn how how to make the line like where does the line go between beard and neck?
Speaker 0: It's real easy to get that wrong.
Speaker 1: And I just watched it was a YouTube videos this thing of the day that you that taught you where to go.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I watched a lot of YouTube videos and that one was the one that was like the good thing at the day thing.
Speaker 0: But honestly, I just watched like five or six different YouTube videos and they all mostly said the same things about how to manage beards.
Speaker 0: and I just did what they said.
Speaker 0: and Other than I shaved this a little bit under my lips I can play my trumpet Mmm, actually, that's the segue I've.
Speaker 0: I've been playing my trumpet a lot during quarantine and I really want to keep that up.
Speaker 0: Like that's one of those things of.
Speaker 0: I'm never gonna make trumpet content or like music content really for the internet ever again because like I'm not gonna dedicate myself to making music enough to be good enough to bother sharing.
Speaker 0: But I do appreciate the hobby where you're not a pro You're not the most skilled or the most talented but you do it because it's fun on its own and I'm good.
Speaker 1: I just like I said, I just do photography.
Speaker 1: It's like yeah, basically mostly gave up on like try and like make some portfolio side or that kind of nonsense, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, like I dump a lot of my photos just in my Google photo timeline mostly so in the future I can scroll back through it and just see oh, what was I taking pictures of in like October?
Speaker 0: 2008 like.
Speaker 0: oh, I guess I took a lot of I don't know Google Glass photos.
Speaker 0: that must have been when I had the Google Glass you know.
Speaker 0: but Yeah playing the trumpet.
Speaker 0: It's been interesting because It took me a long time like almost a year to get all those muscles back to like be able to play it Well, and it was frustrating because I was very good like to the point where I literally almost went to school for music instead all this tech stuff.
Speaker 0: and It was frustrating to have been Legitimately good at something and be terrible at it when you pick it up again because you have lost muscles You've lost like physical skills that you need to relearn.
Speaker 1: Well father time.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know imagine what it feels like to be.
Speaker 1: I don't know yarmul yaga.
Speaker 1: You know who's playing hockey out in Czechoslovakia or whatever?
Speaker 0: I mean even with like as much as I'm doubling down on running.
Speaker 1: Czechoslovakia doesn't exist.
Speaker 0: I'm almost 40.
Speaker 0: I'm never going to run a 17-minute 5k again in my life.
Speaker 0: like 20 19 to 20 minutes is the best I'm gonna do and I do not feel great after those 19 minutes in my current body.
Speaker 0: So, you know that we've talked to the geek guys before.
Speaker 0: I'm kind of focusing on Sports.
Speaker 0: at least that I see old people doing a lot.
Speaker 0: I don't see old mountain bikers.
Speaker 0: I don't see like too many old people rollerblading seriously.
Speaker 0: I see a lot of old runners a lot of old bikers and a lot of old skiers.
Speaker 0: So those are the three sports.
Speaker 0: I am doubling down on a guy.
Speaker 1: should we should quadruple down a shuffleboard there I could play some shuffleboard.
Speaker 0: I like shuffleboard a lot.
Speaker 1: I love shuffleboard, but the only place to play shuffleboard is that place in Brooklyn.
Speaker 1: That's all fancy for like, you know pride.
Speaker 1: There's no like, you know, just like.
Speaker 1: there's no like shuffleboard just in the park.
Speaker 0: I like bocce more to be honest.
Speaker 0: There's buys.
Speaker 1: There's a though the bocce you can do in the park over by me.
Speaker 0: So, but actually what I want shuffleboard more what I want to start doing.
Speaker 0: so Ted if you don't live in New York City, like I used to play tennis I used to love tennis.
Speaker 0: the problem with New York City is by law You can't actually use the New York City Municipal Tennis Courts without a tennis license.
Speaker 1: Yep, there's all sorts of bureaucracy around who gets to play tennis and when on the courts because it's a large amount of space that's Occupied by only two or four people.
Speaker 1: Yeah There's only so many courts and there's a lot more people that want to use them than there are courts and time on which to Play them especially on weekends.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm sure if you want to play, you know an early afternoon This you might be competing with old people.
Speaker 1: There's so many people.
Speaker 0: but there's also special tennis courts.
Speaker 0: Like if you bike up the west side, you'll pass a few tennis courts that are special because they're clay.
Speaker 0: Aren't that many of those?
Speaker 1: there's different courts in different places, you know the sum up in the Bronx and this is private ones There's.
Speaker 1: there's you know, this semi public ones.
Speaker 1: they're all over different Different rules in each one.
Speaker 0: like as much as I want to get back into it.
Speaker 0: It's too much of a pain in the ass living in New York City.
Speaker 0: I actually gave up tennis when we left Beacon because in Beacon there's tennis courts.
Speaker 0: I could just go play it like the high school.
Speaker 0: so, uh Yeah, but wall ball courts do are not licensed.
Speaker 0: You can just use a wall ball court if someone else isn't using it.
Speaker 1: So racquetball.
Speaker 0: Yeah Well, you can't.
Speaker 0: racquetball.
Speaker 0: courts are all indoors and mostly private like you gotta pay.
Speaker 1: Oh, no They play racquetball out in like McCarran Park and in the in the same areas.
Speaker 0: That is not technically racquetball because you need to have all the walls.
Speaker 0: All sides need to be walls at the place where the lines are so you can bounce them off the walls or it's not actually Racquetball.
Speaker 1: Well, they're playing one one wall racquetball.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's not racquetball.
Speaker 0: That's that's one of a few different sports But it's racquetball adjacent.
Speaker 0: They're all in the same class of sport.
Speaker 1: They have rackets and they got the blue rubber ball and they're hitting it again.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but that is not racquetball.
Speaker 0: racquetball rules are very specific around like how it works.
Speaker 0: Have you all right?
Speaker 0: Have you ever played racquetball?
Speaker 1: No, it's old man game.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but it's also a young man game.
Speaker 1: You did just say you're gonna play old man game.
Speaker 0: I do but I don't want to play racquetball because I have to pay to join like a gym that has racquetball.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you don't want to play pickleball.
Speaker 1: Oh, that's an old man game.
Speaker 0: Pickleball sucks ass.
Speaker 0: It's not fun.
Speaker 1: I never even heard of it until relatively recently.
Speaker 0: I know I think You were like pickleball what the fuck is pickleball?
Speaker 0: and I was like, how have you never heard of picketball pickleball?
Speaker 0: We did a whole thing.
Speaker 1: Now I've heard of it for the first time like maybe two years ago.
Speaker 0: But what I'm thinking about doing is me and Emily could just do this.
Speaker 0: There's a bunch of wall ball courts behind us and while I cannot play racquetball or tennis We could just volley that blue ball back and forth against that wall and that would mean like I just said But that's not racquetball that's not even a. that's not a sport.
Speaker 0: we're just playing volley we're just volleying We're not playing.
Speaker 1: tell that to the people.
Speaker 1: tell that to the people in McCarran Park.
Speaker 1: They're playing it way serious.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I just want to hit a ball back and forth.
Speaker 0: It's the equivalent of just play catch.
Speaker 0: But I dug out as part of cleaning up.
Speaker 0: now that we're cleaning stuff up and donating things.
Speaker 0: after COVID I dug out my old baseball mitt.
Speaker 0: I had a guy had a catcher's mitt and just a regular bit.
Speaker 0: the catcher's mitt I threw away because it was rotten because this thing is from like the 20s and My other catching mitt like my regular old like outfielders mitt had also rotted to nothing.
Speaker 0: So it was not salvageable.
Speaker 0: just threw it away Mmm, but rackets don't really go bad.
Speaker 0: So all my old rackets are fine.
Speaker 0: So that is what I'm gonna do in that park.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean they don't go bad, but sometimes depending on the string Will reduce or that's true Solid piece of wood racket, but Yeah, technologies will change and then the racket could be like there's.
Speaker 1: you know Remember like back in the day tennis rackets looked almost like, you know badminton rackets do now, right?
Speaker 1: It's like that.
Speaker 1: It's like those one, you know, it's like yeah, you might have one that's still good But that no it's.
Speaker 0: it's I threw away.
Speaker 0: I had some racquetball rackets that were like from the late 60s.
Speaker 0: I got rid of those.
Speaker 0: those things were terrible Mm-hmm, but I feel like that's how I can get my racket sport craving done and scratch that itch without having to deal with the Whole New York City licensing system or some private club that has racquetball courts Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: So something just something else right?
Speaker 1: So one thing that's been bothering me lately I don't know how many people know about this right is we got this problem, especially where I live the fart car problem.
Speaker 0: I Got a lot to say about that.
Speaker 1: There's a lot going on here.
Speaker 0: It's a really it's a specifically bad problem here because we live next to the Queensborough Bridge.
Speaker 0: They are going back and forth over that bridge all night every fucking night and they have been for like six months, right?
Speaker 1: So there's basically there are certain people who they enjoy and I actually respect, you know as a hobby, right?
Speaker 1: You know driving, you know tricking out your car, right?
Speaker 1: No different than customizing your computer to make it cool and go faster, right totally off.
Speaker 0: well to the to the extent of I am super not cool with the people who Disable the pollution controls on their car to do that.
Speaker 1: Yes that well, I mean, yeah, you know.
Speaker 1: But I mean, I'm also super not cool with people who trick out their computer and then mine bitcoins Yeah in doing damage with their hobby is not cool No matter how cool your hot.
Speaker 0: the fart cars are almost all Technically illegal because they've almost all removed their muffler and replaced it with nothing.
Speaker 1: indeed There's also people who are riding all sorts of dirt bikes and ATVs and other sorts of vehicles that are not street-legal Right, but it's like, you know riding that vehicle on its itself as a hobby is totally cool Right, just you're doing it on these public streets in a way that is, you know Dangerous and hazardous to others.
Speaker 0: it is like like seriously Like you should see some of the shit that I witness with these kids on a pretty regular basis.
Speaker 0: You know cuz I run a lot I bike a lot but lately Full-on ATVs are just screaming down like separated bike paths all the time, right?
Speaker 1: It's also very noisy and disturbing the whole neighborhood.
Speaker 1: They're also so it's like
Speaker 0: really polluting because most of those things are two-stroke engines Which arguably should be banned in the u.s Two-stroke engines like if you drive a two-stroke engine vehicle for a couple hours You probably give out like exude more material pollution than an actual SUV being driven regularly.
Speaker 1: Well, I don't know about that.
Speaker 0: I found multiple stats on that.
Speaker 0: I'll dig one up maybe But the point is Controls right.
Speaker 1: so you have this problem and that people are doing a thing that I think should be able to be done.
Speaker 1: There's validity in the thing right enjoying that hobby.
Speaker 1: So you don't want to just ban it outright right especially, you know, someone who really cares.
Speaker 1: They tricked out their car their car.
Speaker 1: Actually if I saw their car, maybe I think it was cool, right?
Speaker 1: It's like I don't just be like, you know, you can't do this anywhere ever right?
Speaker 0: Well, they're doing something that is anti-social.
Speaker 1: Yes, they're doing it But they're doing enjoying this valid hobby in a way that is damaging and disturbing to other people and causing You know external harms.
Speaker 0: People do that stuff all the time, but if they came through your neighborhood, you know It's out like not a dense city.
Speaker 0: Maybe a few hundred people hear you and then you're gone in New York.
Speaker 0: if you drive one of those things around in like Queens Several hundred thousand people were woken up by that possibly and it's not and it's not just one's going by right now And it's not just a few people.
Speaker 1: It's lots and lots of better trend.
Speaker 0: It's during coding police.
Speaker 0: There's a lot like don't we're not super not saying we support the police like don't even think we're going down.
Speaker 0: We're gonna get to that aspect of it next but the police be in New York City Partly in reaction to the black lives matter protests and partly in reaction to kovat Stopped enforcing a lot of traffic.
Speaker 0: They never.
Speaker 1: they never enforce.
Speaker 0: they enforce this one a little bit and now barely because Now like they don't enforce it at all and the number of people doing it has been rising steadily for over six months I don't think enforcement would decrease it.
Speaker 1: Anyway, even if they did enforce it, right?
Speaker 0: They did.
Speaker 0: I remember I saw them writing a ticket to a dude who had a motorcycle on the Queensborough bike path once Pre kovat.
Speaker 1: Okay one time.
Speaker 0: Yeah nowadays.
Speaker 0: I'll be running over that and a full tickets don't discourage Speeding now, right?
Speaker 0: But a speeding before this past summer.
Speaker 0: I don't think I would encounter a full-size motorcycle on the bike path Except maybe once every several years and it was like a crazy event.
Speaker 0: now I am passed by a gas-powered motorcycle on the Queensborough bridge bike path every single weekend during my run.
Speaker 1: Yeah full-size motorcycle Alright, so what could be done?
Speaker 1: what can be done about this, right?
Speaker 1: So I just got through the you know, explaining how enforcement will.
Speaker 1: even if you enforce right?
Speaker 1: You're not going to decrease the behavior significantly most likely and you're going to cause a lot of you know It's just harm that's not gonna.
Speaker 1: it's eye for an eye.
Speaker 1: Most of the people doing this activity are not white people.
Speaker 1: They are young people of color most of the people who are doing this right almost exclusively, right?
Speaker 1: So, you know, but it's like yes, they're misbehaving also.
Speaker 1: But if you the only body we have that can do enforcement is police.
Speaker 0: that's not gonna.
Speaker 1: actually Not only if you got the police to and try to enforce these laws Would it not solve the problem.
Speaker 1: It also would just cause more harm to the people in those communities who don't need any more harm done to them, right?
Speaker 1: So we need to come up with some other solution.
Speaker 0: I don't know what to do about it.
Speaker 0: So one thing that's been happening in the last few months like it This is a new thing But I'm seeing it a lot is they'll take the ATVs and the motor dirt bikes To a park like the Queens Ridge Park or the Randall's Island.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it happened one time.
Speaker 0: every time I run down and they'll just tear around and tear up the grass and drive around on the grass for hours and pretty much only leave if Someone comes and harasses them like eventually a cop car comes in the horizon and they leave and go to a different parking.
Speaker 0: keep doing it Mmm, so all the baseball fields are torn up with dirt bike tracks.
Speaker 1: now Alright, so my idea to fix this which is obviously something that will never happen ever Is This right?
Speaker 1: So obviously you don't want to chase people and the police actually have a policy of not chasing people because it actually creates a more Dangerous situation especially in the city.
Speaker 1: I think that you know, you go and see like videos of car chases and like, you know highways and like Florida or whatever.
Speaker 1: I think they shouldn't do that either.
Speaker 1: Yeah Chasing people just makes more danger.
Speaker 1: Don't do that is that you should a. just chill and They're not hard to find.
Speaker 1: you can see these people.
Speaker 1: they want to be seen.
Speaker 1: Check out my cool car.
Speaker 1: just video them from somewhere right?
Speaker 1: It's like you see a fart car.
Speaker 1: You can see it.
Speaker 1: There's license plate, you know, it's like there it is.
Speaker 1: It's just chillin at the stoplight and then it's gonna go.
Speaker 1: it's gonna you know Do a little burnout and go to the next stoplight.
Speaker 1: just identify it right.
Speaker 1: sit in a few places around town.
Speaker 1: Just chill and just gather lots and lots of you know.
Speaker 1: Identifying be like up.
Speaker 1: that car clearly has no muffler right down the license Right?
Speaker 0: Oh that too with that data do not have Police as they exist today with guns in any way be involved in what gets done with that data.
Speaker 1: no, then take that information and Just go to write.
Speaker 1: those people live somewhere.
Speaker 1: They're keeping that car.
Speaker 1: They're not driving it all the time, right?
Speaker 1: They're keeping that car somewhere, right?
Speaker 1: the car is Street illegal, right?
Speaker 1: It's street illegal.
Speaker 1: So we shouldn't allow that car on the street period up, right?
Speaker 1: It's not legal to be on the street.
Speaker 1: Just go to where the car is and just take the car.
Speaker 1: Just take it.
Speaker 1: be like.
Speaker 1: it's not street legal.
Speaker 1: We're not gonna allow it on the street.
Speaker 1: bring a truck put this, you know You can't drive it somewhere right.
Speaker 1: put it up on the truck and take it away.
Speaker 1: It doesn't matter if the person's there or not.
Speaker 1: Just fucking tow that shit and don't tow it to the impound lot where the person can get their car back.
Speaker 1: No, they lose the car.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: It's like you can't have this.
Speaker 1: It is an illegal item.
Speaker 1: It is now come.
Speaker 0: so the problem is it is technically not illegal to own only to drive on a public street.
Speaker 1: Well, you could change the point that but I could own a dirt bike.
Speaker 0: I could put the dirt bike in my car drive it somewhere.
Speaker 0: It's legal and then drive it Right.
Speaker 1: So what I think what you could do is, you know to sort of be like, okay, we've taken the car, right?
Speaker 1: What are we gonna do with this right?
Speaker 1: We don't want to sell it because then someone's gonna drive it modify it It's not street illegal and then sell.
Speaker 1: they'll just modify it back.
Speaker 1: that's pointless Right.
Speaker 1: what we should do is we should build a cool We should write build a cool racetrack place for all the cool people to enjoy legitimately and perhaps more safely the hobby of Driving cooled cars and motorbikes around make like a big like a fucking pair.
Speaker 0: No, that is how most cities solve the problem of skateboarders ruining all the masonry.
Speaker 0: just make skate parks, right?
Speaker 1: It's like Germany has like like a Nurburgring like it's like where they have f1 races But you can just go there and drive, you know, it's like we have some places like that.
Speaker 0: I don't have a free public one.
Speaker 1: There's no free public Racetrack right that you could just go right and we even if we did have one it certainly wouldn't be big enough to handle all These.
Speaker 1: it's so popular, right?
Speaker 1: But we should make a huge out in Long Island somewhere right where we hate build.
Speaker 1: it did replace a golf course, right?
Speaker 1: Make it that big as bad golf.
Speaker 0: makeup makeup is really accessible.
Speaker 0: free buses and transportation make it easy for New York, right?
Speaker 1: You're so when you take someone's car.
Speaker 1: when you take someone's car, right?
Speaker 1: You should a give them right an unlimited Metro card, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, and all sorts of other transportation for that might buy their Metro card, right?
Speaker 1: That might be their transportation that you just confiscated.
Speaker 1: so you need to sort of compensate them Right, maybe even give them like, you know the cheapest car.
Speaker 1: That's not a new illegal car a car that like you couldn't.
Speaker 1: we wouldn't want to modify because it's so uncool.
Speaker 0: Here's your 2012 Chevy Cruze eco.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right something like that.
Speaker 1: People would figure out a way to modify.
Speaker 1: But bring all the cool cars to the car paradise, right and then Be like, hey your car is in a garage at the car paradise.
Speaker 1: you can come there and Drive it all around the racetrack all you want, right?
Speaker 1: Like just come on down and your car is waiting for you.
Speaker 1: But there's a wall around the place and you can't get any cars out of there.
Speaker 1: They're just stuck in there Right the end they don't leave.
Speaker 1: Um, you know, so built a race car it stays at the racetrack.
Speaker 1: You can never take it out of the racetrack.
Speaker 0: Here's there's the the one hard mode.
Speaker 0: Most of these things are not only not street-legal.
Speaker 0: They don't have license plates.
Speaker 0: They're just a dirt bike.
Speaker 1: That's the dirt bikes are the unidentified.
Speaker 1: dirt bikes are the problem You're gonna have to.
Speaker 1: you know, the identification you get to see the person who's on it and identified them.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but that starts getting into facial recognition problems.
Speaker 1: The other problem is there's so many problems there, but the cars at least The you could.
Speaker 1: the cars are a significant portion.
Speaker 1: So just reducing those would help a great deal.
Speaker 0: It would.
Speaker 0: America has a problem.
Speaker 0: where I'm do not.
Speaker 0: we still cannot go back to the old way or even the current way.
Speaker 0: But when police officers were not armed and would have would pull people over or interact with people to confiscate a car.
Speaker 0: Violence against the people who tried to do that was common.
Speaker 1: Yep, indeed very common.
Speaker 0: but this gets into something I think about a lot that's adjacent to this.
Speaker 0: the New York City Street like speed limit if you're not On a special road like the FDR is 25 like everywhere unless there's an exception.
Speaker 0: Cops Should not be able to pull anyone over for speeding in New York City because cops pulling people over is a big part of how They fuck with people who should not be fucked with.
Speaker 0: But we should have enforcement of that speed limit.
Speaker 0: My idea has always been there should be speed cameras and everywhere Yeah, and any car that's a 24/7 Yeah.
Speaker 0: And any car no matter what anywhere in New York City.
Speaker 0: if it's on one of those streets and it hits like 27 miles an hour you get mailed a ticket.
Speaker 0: An absolute 100% enforcement of that speed limit no exceptions.
Speaker 1: and if you pass three cameras three tickets.
Speaker 1: Yep, right If you're going if you go 60 and you somehow get through three take three different cameras identify you as speeding.
Speaker 1: Well, you were speeding three times.
Speaker 0: babies like, you know a common sense.
Speaker 0: like the speed limit is 25 set it to 30.
Speaker 0: It only does the ticket if you get above 30, right?
Speaker 1: We also need times to be scaled based on what you can afford etc, etc.
Speaker 0: Yeah, rich people should hurt a rich person to get that ticket, right?
Speaker 1: The main point here is that like look it's like we have this problem of fart cars, right?
Speaker 1: You know you know ruining everybody
Speaker 0: like Nova like the majority of New Yorkers want to deal with this problem because it is a
Speaker 1: only people only the People who aren't any the only people who like the fart cars are on the far car So every single other person does not like them.
Speaker 1: maybe some kid thinks that
Speaker 0: I cared a lot less about this kind of thing when we lived outside of the city, but it's so Dense here and like I can it's hard to express to you out there If you don't live in New York how much of a problem this has become just in the last few months
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: So the point is is that like look it's like every solution we try to come up with right?
Speaker 1: It's like well we can't because right these other things and it's like you look and you see the root Right is the car culture and the gun culture of the United States, right?
Speaker 1: This is actually just an offshoot of that.
Speaker 1: if we solve our general car problem, right in that You know, we don't if we destroy car culture itself and you know Like the same way that like Amsterdam or the Netherlands did our roads won't be conducive to fart.
Speaker 0: so This actually gets into something if we destroy.
Speaker 1: if we ban guns and don't have a stupid Second Amendment Then you could enforce things against people without having to shoot them or bring or worry about them shooting you.
Speaker 0: this gets to a farmer.
Speaker 1: Do something like confiscate someone's car, right?
Speaker 0: This is something that bothers me a lot.
Speaker 0: the ways we can end on this because we made a plenty long show.
Speaker 0: But that all gets to the a fundamental problem in America.
Speaker 0: Is that at all levels of our government?
Speaker 0: We have minoritarian rule.
Speaker 0: guns are a good example.
Speaker 0: the vast majority of Americans want strict gun controls.
Speaker 0: a Near majority of Americans want to get rid of the Second Amendment.
Speaker 0: Yet somehow we can't make any gun rules Not even the ones that like 80% of Americans support.
Speaker 1: the majority of New Yorkers probably want to get rid of fart cars Can't but the problem is the way our government is set up.
Speaker 0: the minority of people Mostly rural people have the majority of the power.
Speaker 0: by the way, the system is designed.
Speaker 0: That is a fundamental problem that we can't get past.
Speaker 0: What's if the majority opinion on a lot of things were possible to be expressed in our government?
Speaker 0: I'm not saying things would be perfect because our majority also has a lot of stupid ideas But it would mean that we could have earnest debates and try things right now because of this minoritarian rule we can't try Anything for almost any problem?
Speaker 0: Right, but the we can't change.
Speaker 1: there is like a lot of people, you know privileged people act like or believe they're like.
Speaker 1: Oh, I don't care about politics.
Speaker 1: It doesn't affect you whatever.
Speaker 1: and then we get mad about something like fart cars And it's like guess what?
Speaker 0: Right?
Speaker 0: It's all the same.
Speaker 1: pros and the filibuster are not unrelated.
Speaker 0: Yep But here's what bothers me.
Speaker 0: this is like that the zoomed in like wonk thing that bothers me.
Speaker 0: I don't know if there is a legal way to fix that because fundamentally the US Senate holds all the power and because of the filibuster rules you need 60 senators to agree to pass literally anything and you need 50 senators Minimum to agree to change the filibuster rule to even force someone who wants to make it 60 to have to stand there and piss their pants.
Speaker 0: We cannot get 50 senators who would agree to change the rules of the filibuster So that you have to actually piss your pants if you want to do it.
Speaker 1: No, you could do it with What?
Speaker 1: Evil, yeah The only ways to change that Would you do it by waiting for a lot?
Speaker 1: We just waiting.
Speaker 0: we just wait long enough and hope that enough people die now because demographic trends are actually putting more power in states That have such a margin toward Republicans in the Senate that Democrats cannot feasibly or plausibly win a statewide election in those states.
Speaker 0: Gerrymandering doesn't even fix that because the gerrymandering is at the level of the state boundaries themselves and the structure of the Senate is defined In the Constitution.
Speaker 0: amending the Constitution requires a majority of the states.
Speaker 0: The majority of states are red and not and there is no possible way to make them blue in the foreseeable future.
Speaker 1: Well, something don't happen eventually, you know, she gets bad enough.
Speaker 0: people get mad enough or they won't Because people the majority of people are mad, but the people are mad are concentrating themselves in blue states where it's better.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well if but event, you know Eventually, you just have 70 Republican senators who will just make things worse for everyone and no one can stop them.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but then the people who live in the blue states will get mad, you know get mad.
Speaker 0: What do they do?
Speaker 0: What are we gonna do to see think they could do?
Speaker 1: who knows what they'll do?
Speaker 1: I'm just saying that hopefully that's far enough in the future.
Speaker 1: It won't be.
Speaker 0: all I'm saying is that the system as it's designed There is literally no legal path to fixing that fundamental problem right now.
Speaker 0: Mmm, I don't know what to do about that.
Speaker 0: I don't have an answer.
Speaker 0: I don't have an idea other than changing it.
Speaker 0: But the only way to change it is to use it.
Speaker 1: Try really hard and you know win some elections that you believe are unwinnable.
Speaker 0: We would have to win 11 new Senate seats in red states statewide elections And not lose any of the ones we already have.
Speaker 0: George is gonna be hard to keep because we didn't pass the Voting Rights Act.
Speaker 0: We didn't pass the Voting Rights Act because the Senate.
Speaker 1: Yeah, do something try something try water.
Speaker 0: That's that's why I don't know.
Speaker 0: that can't fight I don't.
Speaker 1: that's what I don't understand.
Speaker 1: right is like, you know, you're these senators are actual human beings, right?
Speaker 0: It's I so saw.
Speaker 1: some of them are in favor and understand how important them are evil.
Speaker 0: They 50 of them realize that if any of these rules change their party loses power forever.
Speaker 1: But I mean, there's still a human being.
Speaker 1: there's something that they care about right?
Speaker 1: Go and go and talk to them and it's like just you know figure out right, you know Do figure out.
Speaker 1: something's gotta be something you can do, right?
Speaker 1: It's like even someone like me right think about it the reverse direction right.
Speaker 1: let's say I was a senator.
Speaker 1: and They said Scott, you know, we want you to vote for.
Speaker 1: Yes guns guns good, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like.
Speaker 1: is there a way that they could get me to vote for guns?
Speaker 0: good But it's partisan.
Speaker 1: It would be really really hard to get me to vote for guns good But I'm not gonna lie and say it's impossible, but there's some way they could get me to do it.
Speaker 1: Right, so fucking figure it out.
Speaker 1: What you're there cleared all you there.
Speaker 1: I see all these people senators.
Speaker 1: They're just tweeting.
Speaker 1: It's like stop tweeting go talk to the other said they have.
Speaker 0: and so the thing is they have.
Speaker 1: figure out what you gotta do.
Speaker 0: And the answer has been so far.
Speaker 0: There is nothing that will convince any Republican senator to vote to make elections fair because if they did that Many of them would not win reelection.
Speaker 0: and if even and if any of them don't get reelection all of them lose power.
Speaker 0: So there's nothing you could do because you're literally asking them to vote to permanently remove themselves from power forever.
Speaker 1: Okay, fine.
Speaker 1: It's so Scott.
Speaker 1: I'm a senator right now and they say Scott senator Scott We want you to vote on a thing that will make you no longer a senator.
Speaker 1: It did.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: Well, what what?
Speaker 1: there must be something in it for me to compensate for the fact that I'm gonna lose now They're already rich.
Speaker 1: So yeah, it's like fucking work it out, right?
Speaker 1: There's got to be something, you know.
Speaker 0: so one fundamental thing that's going on in politics, I know you don't pay attention to like Senate procedure and all that kind of stuff, but What's mostly been happening now is?
Speaker 0: Democrats have been constantly trying to talk to them about this and their answer is always there is nothing.
Speaker 0: literally we do not care.
Speaker 1: No, there has to be something.
Speaker 1: There's something.
Speaker 1: there are human being.
Speaker 1: they have a life.
Speaker 1: There's something in their personal life.
Speaker 1: They must have desires goals feelings, right?
Speaker 1: You need to figure them out.
Speaker 0: send a PI after so Their desires and goals are.
Speaker 0: pass harmful legislation to hurt people that they perceive as their enemies.
Speaker 1: Okay, fine Here we'll agree to pass this harmful legislation that hurts your enemies as long as you vote.
Speaker 1: Yes on this voting one.
Speaker 0: No, because if they vote yes on the voting one It is guaranteed and they know that all the heart Try to fool them.
Speaker 1: right?
Speaker 1: there's still a human being.
Speaker 1: they're not geniuses right?
Speaker 1: you could try something right.
Speaker 1: work harder Right is your only job.
Speaker 0: even the ones who are retiring and not running for re-election Until are still refusing to even you might be able to fool.
Speaker 1: some of these people are so old.
Speaker 1: You might be able to fool them with the rabbit season duck season on the yay.
Speaker 1: Nay, right?
Speaker 0: It's like no because the party whip actually tells them here's what to vote and they just do it Right.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know, maybe you know, see if you can fool them.
Speaker 0: In fact, the one time Democrats did try to fool them once it was a few several years ago.
Speaker 1: They they there was a bill that they were all the last second, you know to invert all the language in the yes.
Speaker 0: No, they did something like that.
Speaker 0: This was crazy.
Speaker 0: so basically the Republicans had some bill.
Speaker 0: that was would have like Been so bad.
Speaker 0: that would have caused a problem for them, too.
Speaker 0: But they wanted to performatively vote for it.
Speaker 0: They could say the Democrats voted against it even knowing that if it passed it would destroy things.
Speaker 0: The Democrats all voted for it suddenly at the last second and it was about to pass and they had to scramble To change all their votes to no.
Speaker 0: So now you had a situation where the bad bill had no Republicans voting for it and a bunch of Democrats voting for it.
Speaker 0: But it didn't work in the end.
Speaker 0: It didn't actually pass because they try harder.
Speaker 0: Hey, you can't try harder because the guess what the rules of the Senate are controlled by the Senate.
Speaker 0: You need a vote of 50 people to change the rules.
Speaker 1: The point is right.
Speaker 1: the Republicans do all sorts of shady tricks, right and somehow those shady tricks work.
Speaker 1: do the same?
Speaker 0: Ah, no, I got there's the answer better at shady tricks than they.
Speaker 0: the answer that is simple They're only doing shady tricks to prevent things from being passed.
Speaker 0: They never do shady tricks to pass anything.
Speaker 0: They only do shady tricks to not let bills go forward.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: So do shady tricks to prevent any of their stuff from getting we do?
Speaker 0: you realize the Senate has done nothing Since the election because they can't.
Speaker 1: because of this There has to be.
Speaker 0: you know Senate has literally done nothing.
Speaker 0: no bill that has been Passed by the house is gonna get to the floor of the Senate.
Speaker 1: at least points at the very least Right, whether it's true that they're really trying every last trick in the whole book and the tricks just aren't working.
Speaker 1: It's it's just so difficult, right?
Speaker 1: At least make it look like you're trying right?
Speaker 1: They're not looking like they're trying every last dirty trick in the book, right?
Speaker 1: So at least make it look like you are so that we can have some more confidence in you that you are Being you know putting in the full effort, right?
Speaker 1: They're not making it look like they're trying?
Speaker 0: Well, but anyway, we've gone on for an hour and 20 minutes.
Speaker 0: So I think this was a good topic for a show.
Speaker 0: What we just did this was one of the longer gig nights in recent history.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna go eat food All right it.
Speaker 0: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and brand.
Speaker 1: Okay for the logos be sure to visit our website at front row crew.com for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 0: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 0: But unlike those other late shows it's actually recorded at night and the patreon patrons for this episode of geek night are Heidi McNichol Allen Joyce, Linky G dread Lily Tana break Chris Reimer Clinton Walden just like a dude guy.
Speaker 0: kashaya.
Speaker 0: 85 program threat.
Speaker 0: open speed undertake law adoption.
Speaker 0: Pierce absorb Rebecca Dunn.
Speaker 0: review med ball 34 powers.
Speaker 0: Ryan parent Sam Erickson Shervin von Horrell Taylor Braun.
Speaker 0: You hold the key to my heart and a whole bunch of people who do not want me to say their names.
Speaker 0: And now tonight I leave you with good evening.
Speaker 0: My name is crash.
Speaker 0: These are the boys.
Speaker 0: Yes This song is called.
Speaker 0: I am so sad.
Speaker 0: I am so very very sad.
Speaker 0: goes a little something like this Thank you.
Speaker 0: Not a race guys.
Speaker 0: All right, this next song goes into the guy who keeps yelling from the balcony.
Speaker 0: It's called we hate you.
Speaker 0: Please die Sweet love this one.