Speaker 0: It's Monday November 15th, 2021.
Speaker 0: I'm Rym.
Speaker 1: I'm Scott.
Speaker 0: And this is Geek Nights.
Speaker 0: Tonight, we are talking about heating, ventilation, and air conditioning in homes.
Speaker 0: That's a fascinating topic.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so we over here in New York We decided to actually go outside and go places where there were people and do stuff.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and we're gonna see if we face any consequences for that.
Speaker 0: With prudence and caution I like how you and your plan to go to that hockey game was very similar to our plan of all.
Speaker 0: right We're gonna go but we'll go scope it out and at any point We both reserve the right to call bail and we'll just bail immediately.
Speaker 1: Before we went to the hockey game, right?
Speaker 1: We bought tickets to this basically dance party Months and months and months ago and things were looking good and it was coming up and it was happening and we're like.
Speaker 1: well, should we go?
Speaker 1: because it was you know, one of the one of the Musicians, well, I guess not musician producer DJ, whatever, right?
Speaker 1: One of the people was someone that I was going to see years ago and they failed to come.
Speaker 1: I think it might have been for work visa reasons.
Speaker 1: They failed that other time.
Speaker 1: So I really wanted to see them and under normal circumstances I would have been like, oh, yeah I really want to go way bad, right?
Speaker 1: But obviously I didn't want us to go so bad I would die.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean we made we made a lot of tentative plans before the uptick happened.
Speaker 1: Yeah So we decided we're like, you know what?
Speaker 1: All right, you know, let's we'll go and we can leave.
Speaker 1: no one's keeping us there.
Speaker 1: Right, if we don't like the looks of things we can go we don't have to stay there.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and it's at a venue we'd been to before and we said, you know, we know that venue We could sort of stay in further in the back.
Speaker 1: We don't have to go in the crowd in the front No one's making us do that.
Speaker 1: So we went and they were very smart at the venue.
Speaker 1: They were basically, you know, you get in line at a concert place, right?
Speaker 1: And then at the front is security and then tickets and then inside right?
Speaker 1: Well, they actually did the vaccine checks At the back of the line.
Speaker 1: So as you got in the line, which wasn't even moving yet They were checking your ID and your vaccine thing.
Speaker 1: careful that and then they gave a wristband that not only had a color But was had the name of the venue printed on it.
Speaker 1: So there's no way anyone was gonna fake one of those, right?
Speaker 0: So, I guess you have to fake your you know Excelsior pass or whatever, yeah, which Not impossible, but I feel like that is actually a high bar for the kind of person who refuses to get the vaccine at this point.
Speaker 1: Yeah, anyway, but we went inside and we you know, we're like up.
Speaker 1: Should we leave?
Speaker 1: Should we stay?
Speaker 1: We just stayed the whole time because it was too good.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and Then we went to the hockey game yesterday, which you know.
Speaker 1: Similar situation and it's like well, you know, we similar.
Speaker 1: now we're good.
Speaker 1: now We're gonna stay inside and see what happens.
Speaker 0: Yep, the the next the the next fraud.
Speaker 0: We'd only did this once the whole quarantine and we did it like last week But we ate indoors once when the huntress was completely empty like there was no one there.
Speaker 0: Okay But we still have.
Speaker 1: he ate at the ramen place inside But it was the whole front of the place was completely open.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like that and we just happened to be Hunter says those giant the threshold Giant windows where basically if you're sitting by those windows It's not materially different from being on the other side of those windows, right?
Speaker 1: But yeah, here's here's the math on this situation Right.
Speaker 1: So in New York City, there's like over eight million people Right, and there are about a thousand cases a day right now in the city.
Speaker 1: So what's one thousand out of eight million?
Speaker 0: Well, that is a hundred out of eight hundred thousand.
Speaker 1: That is ten out of eighty thousand Right, so it's 0.01 to five for not it's not even one percent.
Speaker 1: It's 0.01 to five percent, right?
Speaker 1: So the capacity right of the concert venue was three hundred about three or four hundred, right?
Speaker 1: So even we say four hundred right, that means five.
Speaker 1: Uh No 0.05. so less than one person there had it.
Speaker 0: Well, I guess there's also that's like there's a big difference between going to an event with a number of people that lasts like one night Versus like going to a convention where 20,000 people shuffle in and out over the course of like multiple days
Speaker 1: Yeah, and Madison Square Garden.
Speaker 1: It's the capacity is like 20,000, right?
Speaker 1: Yep, so It's like that's point oh oh oh one times 20.
Speaker 1: So two people at Madison Square Garden Likely are sick today, right mathematically speaking.
Speaker 1: So it's like the you know in New York State wide the chart is starting to go up in a bad way.
Speaker 1: But if you look at the the maps, it's mostly outside the city that it's that's happening in the city.
Speaker 1: It's sort of holding flat and Which which me and these events like the ones we went to are happening.
Speaker 1: So there there may be spreading going on at these events But they're not super spreading at these.
Speaker 0: from what I've read most of the spread in New York City is localized to a small number of neighborhoods with a bunch of conflating factors and It's primarily among the unvaccinated and children going to school, right but mathematically speaking, right?
Speaker 1: You know if you if you randomly distribute the all those cases across all the people in New York Right, that means that of all the people who are at the cocky game last night two of them are gonna go tomorrow and have positive tests, so I think that's okay, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, we're vaccinated.
Speaker 1: We'll see.
Speaker 0: I mean, I'm still taking the prudent like cautious optimism and that I'm not.
Speaker 0: I'm still.
Speaker 0: we're gonna avoid like anything We don't care a lot about.
Speaker 0: obviously we can defer like I'm not gonna go to something I'm not that excited about.
Speaker 0: so we're doing a lot less like we're not gonna try.
Speaker 1: I think also, you know, it's like a hockey game, right?
Speaker 1: It's like yeah There's a lot of people there, but you're only in close contact with the people you're sitting near right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, whereas if you go to a convention you're walking around and you know for days Right walking around walking around walking around, you know in different areas different rooms Touching stuff.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know, even though even though kovat you don't get it from touching stuff.
Speaker 1: You can get other things from touching stuff.
Speaker 0: So yeah, it's a it's the cautious reopening.
Speaker 0: but at least the hockey game we went to was great because we just crushed him the high.
Speaker 0: the one game and the one game you Went to ended up being the the first shootout of the season.
Speaker 1: It was a long seven or eight rounds of shoot.
Speaker 0: I was a long shootout.
Speaker 0: That was a. that was a tense game to watch from home.
Speaker 0: so I can imagine what it was like in the garden.
Speaker 0: We could hear the crowd to the booze every time.
Speaker 1: Yeah, people, you know people have to boo PK Subban And it is true that by coincidence or not.
Speaker 1: He happens to be near other players.
Speaker 1: Well, they get injured.
Speaker 0: there were two other than there was the thing that happened of a couple weeks ago.
Speaker 0: There was a sleuthing it where he slew footed someone like straight up and he has a history of doing that.
Speaker 0: Specifically though the video in this case from home.
Speaker 0: It didn't look like it was intentional, but he just happened to be there.
Speaker 0: Yeah, he just did just happen.
Speaker 1: not a penalty to be near someone while they get hurt.
Speaker 0: It's like Isis slippery, but it was unfortunate that he had just slew footage someone like for real recently.
Speaker 1: Yeah Yeah, but it's like I don't you know, I don't hate PK Subban like other people do.
Speaker 1: Yeah, he seems cool You know, he's.
Speaker 1: he's outspoken dude as opposed, you know and an out there guy as opposed to one of those normal You know, but I guess business.
Speaker 0: Did they show a lot of replays of the the injury at the garden?
Speaker 1: We saw it.
Speaker 0: we saw a replay of it because on TV they kept showing it for the whole rest of the game.
Speaker 0: They kept cutting back to it and slow it.
Speaker 0: It's showing it in slow-mo new.
Speaker 1: Okay, we only saw it like, you know immediately after it happened.
Speaker 1: We saw it a couple times and that was it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that was a good OT.
Speaker 0: But anyway enough hockey talk.
Speaker 0: Let's get into a Monday.
Speaker 0: There's a lot of stuff We got to cover so briefly the Governments in the US is Incapable of dealing with like the telephone network and spam calls like they just can't.
Speaker 0: but New York State has been moving faster than a lot of the rest of the country.
Speaker 1: What can what can a state do about the phone network?
Speaker 1: I don't think the state had any power over that.
Speaker 1: I thought it's an FCC deal.
Speaker 0: Ah, it's.
Speaker 0: it's actually really complicated.
Speaker 0: So basically our new governor because we kicked out Cuomo Signed two New York State bills aimed at cracking down on robo calls Basically enabled by some things that the feds have done recently.
Speaker 0: There was that federal rule I think it's the acronyms funny yet stir and shaken.
Speaker 0: There's a new set of federal rules that give carriers like more ability to do things that they weren't allowed to do before like Not to get into all the details of these laws because you can just read them and I'm not an expert on this by any.
Speaker 0: But the best way to analogize it is.
Speaker 0: the reason email spam was destroyed is That people who sell email can basically do whatever the fuck they want.
Speaker 0: So a company like Google could just be like, you know what if you're?
Speaker 0: if we don't know who your email server is We're just gonna ignore emails you send to anyone on our network.
Speaker 0: What are you gonna do?
Speaker 0: sue us?
Speaker 1: Right telephones are different because of accessibility and you know, it's a utility.
Speaker 1: You can't deny phone service to somebody Because it's like it's almost.
Speaker 1: it's not a right but it's you know.
Speaker 0: So the first law that our governor is signed basically in codifies and enables New York State enforcement of that federal rule and the second legislation Actually gives the New York State Public Service Commission the authority to oversee compliance with this.
Speaker 0: so they can go after companies That robocall a New Yorker and they can go after a company that's in New York that is benefiting from robo calling.
Speaker 1: I know you could.
Speaker 1: they could definitely go after companies in New York that are doing robo calling.
Speaker 1: That's a hundred percent easy, but I someone who you know robo calls into New York from elsewhere.
Speaker 1: How could you know, I don't know if they could do anything about.
Speaker 0: it depends the federal.
Speaker 0: the federal actions seem to enable a lot of this.
Speaker 0: but The news here is
Speaker 1: not so much filtering phone calls at its borders
Speaker 0: No, but companies in New York with these bills and with what they enable will Effectively start to have a framework on when they should block things and when they shouldn't block things Yeah Instead of just leaving it entirely up to their discretion Which is kind of how the federal rules play out because the federal
Speaker 1: rules are never a place.
Speaker 1: that was New York was never a place where it has been profitable to run a robo call business.
Speaker 0: from now all these scams are run through American red states that have no regulations or in fact, I thought there was like a place in Utah where it happens.
Speaker 0: There's a few places.
Speaker 0: When I was running afoul of this pot at my previous company one of my early things that I did at my previous company is I set up our like Telephone network for the service team.
Speaker 0: I just did it myself because I still knew the phone network at the time.
Speaker 0: and Yeah, I bought a whole bunch of phone numbers through some shit-ass company in Texas that clearly also sells to scammers and spammers.
Speaker 0: But they were real cheap and they gave me a ton of phone numbers from all over the world that a hundred percent worked.
Speaker 0: But anyway, the the news.
Speaker 0: the reason I'm talking about this is that It is too late to save the phone number.
Speaker 0: in my estimation Everything that's happening now is Way too late.
Speaker 0: I think phone numbers are just dead.
Speaker 0: young people will not use them.
Speaker 0: I do not think the US federal government is capable of taking enough action to save the concept of a phone number Short of phone numbers that are only able to be used by an allow list of specific people in your contacts.
Speaker 0: I don't think young people will ever answer the phone again.
Speaker 0: I think that ship has sailed and it's fucked.
Speaker 1: You know, we could do is you could make basically right a second phone network.
Speaker 0: We could IP enabled you driven like right email like work.
Speaker 1: The current phone network is largely IP enabled, right?
Speaker 1: But you can basically make a new phone network and everyone has an account on it and their phone number is like an alias on Their account.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and then you create a gateway to the old phone network Right, and then you filter hardcore on that gateway and eventually deprecate it the way they deprecated.
Speaker 1: broadcast television Oh, oh, yeah.
Speaker 0: the the technical Solutions and the organizational solutions to this are easy and obvious.
Speaker 0: The problem is our laws and regulations will never even remotely get close to making that happen.
Speaker 0: Anyway, actually the listener points out that even in countries with more enlightened Governments, they can't solve this either.
Speaker 0: in France robocalls are just as bad like bones are just broken globally.
Speaker 1: Oh, oh, sir, your refrigerator warranty.
Speaker 0: We're gonna talk about France again next week on Thursday because there's the news I was saving.
Speaker 0: There is an official which that matters in French.
Speaker 0: French is a prescriptive language gender-neutral pronoun for the first time.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: Yeah All right, instead of eeler L. It's yell All right.
Speaker 1: I didn't know what any of the pronouns in French were.
Speaker 0: Yeah the problem is that doesn't solve a lot because adjectives have to be gendered to their what they're talking about and there's no Way to generically general gender neutralize those.
Speaker 0: so this is like a tiny step, but it's also a big step.
Speaker 0: But anyway, that's the news for next Thursday.
Speaker 0: But yeah, you can read about this if you want to see the details.
Speaker 0: But honestly do what everyone is doing in the rest of the world.
Speaker 0: block any phone number That's not in your contacts and just never look back.
Speaker 0: Just embrace it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean phones have that feature.
Speaker 1: I feel like that's all you need.
Speaker 1: right anyone else is either not gonna leave a voicemail or Okay, a spam leaves a voicemail once in a while.
Speaker 1: It doesn't happen that often.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so, uh, yeah, you got some news.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so Microsoft this is a bunch of articles today and at least two different sites talking about this Microsoft edge deflector thing.
Speaker 1: so basically What the?
Speaker 1: I tried to figure out what everyone is complaining about because they're like, oh my god It's gonna be.
Speaker 1: they're like they seemed really You know like it was a big deal that you wouldn't be able to change your default browser away from Microsoft edge.
Speaker 1: and I'm like.
Speaker 1: I'm using the newest Windows 11 stable and I've got Firefox and I set it to default browser the same normal way You always do.
Speaker 1: yeah, and it's sure as hell is my default browser.
Speaker 1: I've edge like I just on there.
Speaker 1: I've used edge Intentionally a couple times.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but it is never once opened without me Pressing and typing in edge and pressing enter and wanting to open it.
Speaker 1: I've never liked and I don't use ever Like.
Speaker 0: I have typed E-d and that's good enough.
Speaker 1: Yeah I Usually use that what I want to use like not private browsing but that you know, not Firefox.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so there is.
Speaker 1: it's rare, but it happens.
Speaker 1: But regardless I've never used any edge deflector anything.
Speaker 1: So I'm like what the hell are these people complaining about?
Speaker 1: Right?
Speaker 0: Yeah I was search results from the start menu.
Speaker 0: When did that right?
Speaker 1: So it turns out that the only place that this is an issue that I could find in Windows 11 is if you Open the start menu and type in a search a web search and click web So that you're searching the web instead of searching your start menu and you click it.
Speaker 1: What it'll do is it'll embed Bing results in your start menu.
Speaker 1: And if you click on those well That's actually clearly that little embedded Bing results in the start menu.
Speaker 1: is the edge browser embedded in the start menu.
Speaker 1: Yep And then you click on those.
Speaker 1: obviously it's gonna open edge because you just clicked on a link that was already in edge.
Speaker 1: It's an embedded edge.
Speaker 1: So Yeah, if I click a Firefox link, even if it's not my default browser It would still open in Firefox if I click on a Chrome link, even if Chrome's not my default browser opens a Chrome.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so you click an edge link, even though it's not edge isn't your default browser's gonna open an edge?
Speaker 1: So I don't see what the issue is there and also who the hell searches the web from there.
Speaker 0: That's that's the underlying like the fact that edge deflect exists and all this whole discourse.
Speaker 0: It took us both a minute to realize the fundamental problem.
Speaker 0: the fuck.
Speaker 0: if you're searching for a word Think of any word you might ever want to search for on earth.
Speaker 0: Why would you want to see results from your local environment and from the internet at the same time?
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 0: I think what I tell you tonight's into that thing.
Speaker 0: It's because I'm looking for like things called geek nights on my own fucking computer.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I wish I could just remove web search from the start menu.
Speaker 1: Why is it even there?
Speaker 1: If I'm typing something in the start menu, it's because I'm looking for an application to open.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm not looking for.
Speaker 1: I'm not looking for a website.
Speaker 1: I do an application.
Speaker 1: I'm going to run.
Speaker 0: I do look for folders that way but There aren't that many folders.
Speaker 1: I hope it was a little bit Explorer and or a terminal to do that.
Speaker 0: Anyway, well a handful of folders like the geek nights folder is pinned there just shows up.
Speaker 0: There was a suggestion.
Speaker 1: I was that there seemed to be some way that like Microsoft has some method to where Windows can force edge to open Rather than your default browser in certain instances.
Speaker 1: So I think this might be like, you know, maybe you're doing some special Installation of something.
Speaker 1: I don't know but I've never seen it happen.
Speaker 1: But apparently they were saying it can happen that in some cases, you know Microsoft can make edge open instead of your default browser when clicking on something besides just the start menu case and I don't see what the fucking problem is.
Speaker 1: This is not a problem.
Speaker 1: who gives a shit?
Speaker 1: Yep, like I this is not article or or worry-worthy.
Speaker 1: Why are you everyone worrying about this?
Speaker 0: Yeah Well, I'm trying to imagine the kind of person who wants to hit their start menu in their operating system and do a web search from there Specifically co-mingled with a search of their own computer.
Speaker 0: and It's tough because from the alternative perspective in a browser.
Speaker 0: There was an era where the URL I'm not saying we should do this, but In the URL bar at the top.
Speaker 0: The only thing that used to take was a fully formed URL of a resource.
Speaker 1: you wanted to have one character wrong and it wouldn't work.
Speaker 0: and If you wanted to search for something you typed in the URL of a search engine and then you type the search into that or You installed something that would do searches of web of like a Firefox Invented the or did Mozilla have it?
Speaker 1: first the special Mozilla first the mycroft.
Speaker 1: I think it's called the mycroft right that the top right the separate search box.
Speaker 1: I used to use that a lot I'd and it's funny how much to make you'd have to program Little extensions for it to add more sites to the searching which I did.
Speaker 0: Yep, but it's uh, it's funny How often I forget about those kinds of things that someone reminds me they existed.
Speaker 0: like it's easy to forget What Windows 3.1 or like Windows 95 or early Firefox actually was like until you look at it and you remember all this weird shit.
Speaker 0: That just doesn't make sense to a modern eye.
Speaker 0: So there was a transition where people Expected and like I do this now too if I'm searching for something on the internet I just type a bunch of words into that the one bar at the top of my browser and it just handles it.
Speaker 1: But you're not.
Speaker 1: you're not expecting to search your desktop file system when you type in that bar.
Speaker 0: true but I can see the slippery slope of like semantics where a Younger person would wonder if I type into the windows bar.
Speaker 0: Why doesn't you just search everything?
Speaker 0: I can see.
Speaker 1: Well, I think about it like an iOS or I assume Android but on iOS definitely, you know You do a little nudge downwards.
Speaker 1: you get that search box You type in searches up there and it searches like, you know the web and does like a Siri.
Speaker 1: It does like all these searches all at once and gives you one collective of results.
Speaker 1: But it's like whenever I do that.
Speaker 1: I'm always searching the name of an application that I know I already have installed.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I never using that search for anything else ever.
Speaker 0: I don't know better had that or not?
Speaker 0: Cuz what I had is I put I put the Google widget for a Google search at the top of my phone And you do that on iOS if you really want to.
Speaker 0: well, but that's the only thing I ever used.
Speaker 1: I never searched for the name of an app.
Speaker 1: If I want to search the web on my phone I open up the browser first and then I type in the search in that box.
Speaker 1: I don't search the web just like with the the the Phone the iOS global search the iOS global search just like the start menu.
Speaker 1: I'm searching for an app I have installed where the icon wasn't right in front of my face at that moment.
Speaker 0: So anyway, so in some other news, this is huge Huge news.
Speaker 0: We're gonna have to talk about this on a future episode.
Speaker 0: Maybe a Tuesday or Thursday But I'll just note it.
Speaker 0: So Unity has acquired the digital side of Weta Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: So Weta was basically like the big 3d, you know production house that you know Peter Jackson Lord of the Rings, right?
Speaker 1: They made all that stuff.
Speaker 1: So Unity is a game engine.
Speaker 1: That's a cross-platform game engine that is ridiculously popular.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and I think you know someone in our forum had the right call on this which is hey The Unreal Engine pretty much the direct competitor to unity.
Speaker 1: right the big two.
Speaker 1: The Unreal Engine is used for video games and movies.
Speaker 0: Yeah well but especially with the Mandalorian and the volume.
Speaker 0: that was the big transition.
Speaker 0: where that is like the big use case is revolutionizing film creation.
Speaker 0: right now is that combination of a real-time rendering engine like unity or like Like the Unreal Engine coupled with that physical technology of the volume.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean the the crossover between the Hollywood and game industries, right, you know I've always in the past maybe like five plus years ago.
Speaker 1: My gut was always telling me Hey all these triple-a video games you see them coming out.
Speaker 1: They're being made by people who couldn't get Hollywood jobs.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right.
Speaker 1: It's like some screenwriter who wanted to make a movie.
Speaker 1: their script got used for a video game instead, right?
Speaker 1: So, you know video games as a whole all entertainment software Doesn't have crossover with Hollywood, but the triple-a Fancy 3d big narrative games which are basically movies where you push buttons a couple times.
Speaker 1: All right, those and Hollywood have major crossover.
Speaker 1: That's only getting stronger.
Speaker 0: I explained to capital markets people Constantly, they don't understand.
Speaker 0: they think of games as a software company.
Speaker 0: Game companies are usually structured a lot more like movie studios and how they especially if you're building Your video game with an engine like you're using Unreal Engine.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you're buying most of the software, right?
Speaker 1: It's like yeah, you have to code stuff for sure, right?
Speaker 1: But you know, it's not like your ID where you're like, you know doom where your software company have to make a game engine.
Speaker 1: It's like you have the game engine, you know, most of the coding that you're doing is is you know specific to your content and not?
Speaker 1: General software stuff, right, you know, so, you know, there are plenty of programming involved.
Speaker 1: But it is not, you know, it's like this programming involved in making a movie, too.
Speaker 0: But this is huge now because you've got unreal which was already in place to be used for this like Modern production pipeline, which again I cannot use as new unity now has both also.
Speaker 0: Yeah because you need he didn't have the kind of render pipeline you would need for that kind of work and This basically closes that gap.
Speaker 0: their stock has Sky-rocketed.
Speaker 0: I'm not giving investment advice, but I'll say this when the announcement happened.
Speaker 0: I thought oh shit.
Speaker 0: I should buy their stock.
Speaker 0: I looked like it already skyrocketed.
Speaker 1: Oh too late Insider, you know insider trade needs to get it.
Speaker 0: So I decided well I'm not gonna jump on a fly like a high flying train because I I am More didn't it?
Speaker 0: I kept going every fucking day.
Speaker 0: It's going up.
Speaker 1: Well, the markets also a little bit up.
Speaker 1: No, this is this is like beat in the market by a lot.
Speaker 1: So my god, I didn't know.
Speaker 1: unity was public.
Speaker 0: I Think I forgot.
Speaker 0: I talked about that as news on geek nights Okay.
Speaker 0: Anyway, uh My gut feeling is that what happened there?
Speaker 0: is that?
Speaker 0: This was announced.
Speaker 0: so though like Wall Street thought Oh unity is important.
Speaker 0: now I've heard of Weta and the stock went up.
Speaker 0: but then day by day people who actually Understand the ramifications of this have explained it to people and it just keeps going up as a result.
Speaker 0: But yeah, I'm not giving investment advice.
Speaker 0: I'm not saying whether or not I'm going to buy it.
Speaker 0: I have not bought it yet again.
Speaker 0: I'm not giving investment advice at all Have to make that clear.
Speaker 1: but you definitely shouldn't take investment advice from rim because actually it peaked.
Speaker 1: Oh, is that today?
Speaker 1: It's gone down since it started going down today.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah a tiny bit.
Speaker 0: It is you all those days.
Speaker 0: You could have bought it on the second or third day and still made a lot of money.
Speaker 1: if you bought it like on the 10th Five days ago, right?
Speaker 1: You would be up.
Speaker 1: Yep, like What's 160 versus like?
Speaker 1: 200 right.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I guess I'll put it this way The thing does know about capital markets and stock price.
Speaker 0: is that by the time you?
Speaker 0: Without access to special information know about something to make a decision and you look at the price of a stock?
Speaker 0: That stock price was determined by All of that knowledge and the knowledge you don't have already.
Speaker 0: they what they say is everything you think you know is already Priced in to that value.
Speaker 1: That's right.
Speaker 1: That is correct.
Speaker 0: And if it's not a real stock like it's some fake cryptocurrency bullshit.
Speaker 0: that price is just fictitious anyway.
Speaker 0: But I digress don't buy NFTs.
Speaker 0: They're a scam.
Speaker 0: but anyway things Of the day.
Speaker 0: This is a fascinating Twitter thread.
Speaker 0: It's just really fun.
Speaker 0: Emily Velasco was at some sort of thrift store and One of the Twitter threads she's showing pictures of all this really old like Busted technology that's just for sale.
Speaker 0: They're like a credit card machine from the 90s like all sorts of weird nonsense.
Speaker 0: But one of the things that was there was a fish finder.
Speaker 0: What are those like sonar driven fish finding devices?
Speaker 0: Like?
Speaker 0: those are real.
Speaker 0: those aren't woo like.
Speaker 1: they're just radar or sonar in this case like sometimes both like they work if you're doing Deep-sea fishing where you can't see the fish, and it's like you know you might just be sitting there if you act.
Speaker 1: You know if a lot of people go fishing they don't actually want to catch fish.
Speaker 1: They just want to sit on a boat right, but if you want to catch fish if your actual fisherman's your job It's like you need to know.
Speaker 1: like are there fish in this area at least?
Speaker 1: or it's a fish finder?
Speaker 0: So that one of these things was there a fancy one.
Speaker 0: But Emily bought it because it looked like it had a full-on CRT in it.
Speaker 0: It was like a really expensive fancy one.
Speaker 0: Just really old.
Speaker 0: it in fact had one of those Hyper high quality orange phosphor CRT's.
Speaker 1: so the orange only?
Speaker 0: yeah orange only Maya.
Speaker 0: So my first laptop the one that I had the first laptop I ever used that I'd like directly controlled that was given to me by work was given to me by IBM.
Speaker 0: It was a 386 with an orange phosphor display.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it was age used a lot of terminals that are like you know green But the orange ones always had a better contrast.
Speaker 0: I didn't better Because they were more expensive way more expensive to make Orange.
Speaker 0: orange phosphor was like the good shit, so this thread outlines this person Going through effort to figure out how to send signals to it and try to just like render shit on it and like draw stuff On the screen that was designed to
Speaker 1: you know you don't want to use it as a fish finder a screens a screen Yeah Yeah.
Speaker 0: and it is just a really fun thread of how she got this thing to work and the kinds of chips and tools and like.
Speaker 0: But the saving grace like the way she was able to make all this work is that old technology?
Speaker 0: Like we talked about on a recent geek nights It's very well documented and the documentation was extremely specific.
Speaker 0: that Documentation plus an oscilloscope is all you need to drive this crazy proprietary display.
Speaker 1: Knowledge yep, not well knowledge skill, but knowing how to not get killed by the touching the CRT.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but assuming you have all that the documentation Was enough.
Speaker 0: without that documentation this would have been nothing a very difficult project if it ever would have been possible.
Speaker 1: Yep, all right, so I posted about this at the forum, but why not?
Speaker 1: I'll use this thing of the day also because I'm low on things of the day.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so Adele the singer the famous one for a second.
Speaker 0: I thought you were like Adele I thought you were gonna say computer, and then you pause.
Speaker 1: my brain said well The singer recalibrating she's got she's got a new album.
Speaker 1: It's a big deal.
Speaker 1: She's all over right now right selling all kinds of records making all kinds of money And she's way popular in South Korea where the kpop is Even though she's not Korean at all.
Speaker 1: And they posted a promotional image that just said all it said on.
Speaker 1: it was Adele.
Speaker 1: it had a picture of her And it said MBC MBC not NBC MBC like moo That that's one of like the big TV stations You know broadcasting companies in Korea.
Speaker 1: so from that image clearly she was gonna do some sort of television thing in Korea but The rumor spread that she was going to appear on show music core one of the you know kpop music shows.
Speaker 1: now I've been watching kpop music shows for like almost 10 years and Never have I seen a worldwide famous act appear on any of those shows ever not even one time Right never?
Speaker 1: that's like impossible right?
Speaker 1: you would never see like fucking Drake on there What no matter how big their song was in Korea?
Speaker 1: They might appear in like on Korean TV doing an interview or something But never on them actually performing on a music show not net can't happen Occasionally.
Speaker 1: they'll have like at the end of year special festival.
Speaker 1: They'll have like one Person they'll pay to come and there was a drama one time where they were gonna have Wiz Khalifa come and it fell apart.
Speaker 1: It's like you know so they can't even pull it off when they pay for it sometimes.
Speaker 1: So if that rumor was true that was gonna be just unbelievable news like like the biggest deal ever right Turns out.
Speaker 1: it was a rumor.
Speaker 1: It's not true.
Speaker 1: But because of that rumor you start asking some questions, and it's like well I've never seen anyone that famous on those music shows, but did it happen, and I missed it.
Speaker 1: You know what is it?
Speaker 1: Maybe what if it did happen?
Speaker 1: When did it happen?
Speaker 1: was it right?
Speaker 1: And you know it's turn.
Speaker 1: It's not like I've watched this.
Speaker 1: these shows are on.
Speaker 1: there's six different shows, right?
Speaker 1: They're on almost every single week unless they get canceled for some reason which happens occasionally.
Speaker 1: Right it's like every day every week of the year.
Speaker 1: It's like there's so many You're not gonna watch them all ever.
Speaker 1: And it turns out through research.
Speaker 1: Meaning reading the comments was my research.
Speaker 1: I Discovered that in 2009 before I knew any fucking thing about kpop at all Lady gaga appeared on M countdown yeah for real, and I was like wow that's pretty amazing.
Speaker 1: So there now you can watch that video from 2009.
Speaker 0: God 2009 was a long time ago lady gaga who was real young.
Speaker 1: in 2000 Specifically she was 12 years younger than she is.
Speaker 0: Right in the meta moment we are.
Speaker 0: Well, I am going to be live at PAX unplugged with a panel at 1 p.m.. On Friday.
Speaker 0: I won't be at the con otherwise I'm rolling into in the battle and rolling right out.
Speaker 0: the book club book is still the tale of Genji Definitely happening at the end of the year.
Speaker 0: We're both steamrolling through it lately.
Speaker 1: If we don't do well if we don't get that book up of a so it out by the end of this year.
Speaker 1: Then we'll just do it with wherever we're at.
Speaker 0: I'm doing your thing.
Speaker 0: I'm trying to take at least like one note about what interesting thing happened in each chapter or else I'm just not gonna forget everything.
Speaker 0: I wanted to say about this fucking guy Yep So I yeah stay tuned for that.
Speaker 0: that'll happen in December.
Speaker 1: tax East got announced for for real.
Speaker 1: It's gonna happen in late April yeah, and they said that they're gonna have vaccine requirement, which is good Yeah, and they're gonna have mask requirement Which is you know good and not good because if an event's gonna happen I'd rather them do masking.
Speaker 0: But at the same time I would rather just wait myself until I don't have to wear a mask and masks are not.
Speaker 1: you Have some weird hang-up of where you're like.
Speaker 1: oh a mask is too uncomfortable me like a baby right Whereas me.
Speaker 0: so you're going to faxes.
Speaker 1: I don't know yet We'll see right, but you know my my stance is still what I've said all along Which is that if it is safe to go to PAX East?
Speaker 1: then It should be say you know if it's - if it's not safe enough to go to PAX East without masks That is it safe enough to go to PAX East at all?
Speaker 1: question mark right.
Speaker 1: is it safe enough to go on the airplane?
Speaker 1: Without every passenger wearing a parachute?
Speaker 1: if it's not the plane might not be safe enough to fly.
Speaker 1: Let's just not even fly.
Speaker 1: so Well, we'll see what things are like in April.
Speaker 1: right it could be huge differences by then.
Speaker 1: right It's a long time from now.
Speaker 0: so yeah, I'll probably do the thing.
Speaker 0: We'll put in panels like usual and we'll play it by air.
Speaker 0: We have a lot of time before we have to make.
Speaker 1: the problem is if you put in a panel may accept it You can't bail.
Speaker 0: well, but I would just do it like you.
Speaker 0: remember I my last job I would go to Boston like every other week like just for a couple of meetings and back.
Speaker 0: so I could just sell it To Boston.
Speaker 0: do a panel or two and then a sell a home.
Speaker 1: Yeah, do whatever you can do.
Speaker 0: That's what I'm doing.
Speaker 1: it unplugged Yeah, but yeah, we got everyone's got to make their own decision.
Speaker 1: Yeah for themselves.
Speaker 0: the thing is the thing to bear in mind like just there will be a future Where cons are just like you can go to them again?
Speaker 0: It's just we don't know exactly when that'll be.
Speaker 0: we got to be cautious But I do look forward to a day when I'm out of packs playing games with some rando.
Speaker 1: the question is How much industry will show up to PAX East?
Speaker 0: Yeah, cuz they killed back south Good.
Speaker 0: Yep, justifiably.
Speaker 0: I'm boycotting that state like in every possible way at this point.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and we'll see and we'll see.
Speaker 1: you know also like you know I just went outside for the fucking first time at least where other people were.
Speaker 1: we'll see how that goes right.
Speaker 1: if I get sick This week guess what?
Speaker 0: Well, like I've been not gonna I have to go to work.
Speaker 0: I have to go to my physical office three days a week.
Speaker 0: Like that's the company policy I get to pick which days but up until now it hasn't been a big deal because I bike in both directions.
Speaker 0: It's almost too cold to bike to work.
Speaker 0: So now I have to decide am I comfortable riding the subway twice a day three times a week as opposed to subway?
Speaker 1: It's not an issue.
Speaker 1: I don't.
Speaker 1: I've been taking the subway all whatever I've.
Speaker 0: Partly cuz I get afraid of this.
Speaker 0: it's more than because I can city bike everywhere.
Speaker 0: I just avoid the subway.
Speaker 1: I've only read like if I could if I you know, if I it's like I'm not taking the subway, you know When there's an alternative, but I'm not.
Speaker 1: I'm not at this point.
Speaker 1: It's like the subway or the bus.
Speaker 1: It's like if you look at the numbers and other things.
Speaker 1: It's like there's not a lot of transmission going on in the buses and subways at all.
Speaker 0: Well, like earlier the one time we did a trip where we'd had to take a mass transit instead of just taking a private transport.
Speaker 0: Well, I was.
Speaker 0: it was still a more worrying time.
Speaker 0: We did the private room on the Amtrak because I wouldn't have been willing to sit in like a dense train car at that time But it's way different now than it was then.
Speaker 0: Also my calculus like for all of you But both of us our calculi are based heavily on the fact that we live in New York City.
Speaker 0: Much of the rest of America is not even close to that safe right now.
Speaker 0: Yep, like if I lived in most other places, I would be way more locked down than I am.
Speaker 1: Yeah, some countries and places, you know think doing worse better.
Speaker 0: Germany's getting pretty good weather report.
Speaker 0: Yeah So, all right, let's get into it.
Speaker 0: HVAC.
Speaker 0: we talked.
Speaker 0: we're not gonna talk about computer heating and cooling.
Speaker 0: we've done that before.
Speaker 0: We're not talking about server rooms.
Speaker 0: We did that.
Speaker 1: by that He means heating and cooling your computer not computers controlling the heating.
Speaker 0: Yes Yes, and we did a whole show in 2013 on cooling and like server rooms and data centers.
Speaker 0: Well, that's changed a lot.
Speaker 0: That's not what we're talking about today talking about homes houses and apartments like regular-ass heating and cooling.
Speaker 1: Well, I don't know too much about the subject But I do know how to discuss it in an entertaining fashion that is to talk about the original HVAC Which was sit around a fire.
Speaker 1: Yep, there was no there was no AC.
Speaker 1: Actually.
Speaker 1: It was just the H there.
Speaker 0: actually Did I mean I guess original original.
Speaker 0: you're talking 40 ish.
Speaker 0: that I guess the line we have to make is 40,000 years ago, maybe up to 80,000 of depending.
Speaker 0: is the difference between Just putting on some fur and making some fire?
Speaker 0: is that you're changing the environment Instead of putting something or doing so?
Speaker 1: we're only talking about changing the environment here in this exactly, right?
Speaker 1: So like going into a cave to cool down could be considered the original air conditioning But you didn't make that now cold, but right.
Speaker 0: there are very early civilizations that did things like Have a cave or a building that was constructed in such a way to have constant air flow in through low places and out through High places.
Speaker 0: that would do the V part of HVAC and often would also do half of what air conditioning does Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean you could also, you know, just building a roof could be.
Speaker 1: you know That's opaque could be considered cooling.
Speaker 0: I consider insulation to be a part of HVAC.
Speaker 0: Yeah But uh, yeah, I'm talking about modern times.
Speaker 0: to start instead of getting into a history lesson because I Don't know what comes next.
Speaker 1: as far as I'm concerned it went from, you know Sit around a fire like even I think in my medieval times.
Speaker 1: Like what's the heating?
Speaker 0: Oh Oh, you want to go down a rabbit hole.
Speaker 0: the technology of sitting around a fire?
Speaker 0: Advanced way more times than you realize.
Speaker 0: So here's one example is still sitting around a fire.
Speaker 0: No, so the big problem with fire like a fireplace especially an old fireplace or what people in the industry would call a naive Fireplace is that they don't actually radiate that much heat into your environment.
Speaker 0: Most of it escapes.
Speaker 0: The way you met the advancements in fire came around Getting the heat to linger and stay in the environment while getting the noxious results of combustion to leave the environment.
Speaker 0: That's where things like hearth stones came from.
Speaker 0: do you know what a hearth stone is?
Speaker 1: it's a card game.
Speaker 1: everyone knows that.
Speaker 0: so God damn it.
Speaker 0: The worst thing is I just typed it into Google to pull up the Wikipedia to make sure I don't say anything wrong.
Speaker 0: And of course, it's all the card game all the way down to multiple.
Speaker 0: God is still the card game.
Speaker 0: Hearthstone real fire.
Speaker 0: God damn it.
Speaker 0: still.
Speaker 0: You know The modern internet is good in some ways.
Speaker 0: it anyway hearth stones or things like them.
Speaker 0: what they would do.
Speaker 0: Sit in your fireplace Collect the heat like some of them.
Speaker 0: you put a big fucking piece of iron just in your fireplace And it gets hot and it turns red and it radiates the heat into the room.
Speaker 0: at campsites You could put big rocks in the fire.
Speaker 0: They get hot.
Speaker 0: you put them in.
Speaker 0: water heats the water.
Speaker 0: You put the water in your sleeping bag at night.
Speaker 0: it warms you.
Speaker 0: Technology around how to use fire to warm up a home or a dwelling has advanced in many more steps than you might realize.
Speaker 0: out there We're not I mean in this so we're not gonna cover that in detail.
Speaker 1: I mean the house I grew up in right.
Speaker 1: it came with this little you know It wasn't the kind of fireplace that you have in the you know, like and set in the wall the classic kind, right?
Speaker 1: It was like this met.
Speaker 1: It was the metal box kind that sort of set away from the wall So air can get all around it.
Speaker 1: Yeah And it's made of metal.
Speaker 1: and the house actually Kate does a shed out back that I that Collapsed.
Speaker 1: it had cold.
Speaker 1: you were I guess it was supposed to burn coal in there.
Speaker 1: We only ever burned wood in there.
Speaker 1: We never bought coal in there.
Speaker 1: Yeah, not that I remember even though there were just sacks of coal out back.
Speaker 0: I considered buying a house that was heated by a coal fired boiler back in 2009.
Speaker 1: oh I didn't.
Speaker 1: but yeah, but in the winter Occasionally right to offset just the cost of heating with the gas heat that the house came with We would put wood in there set it on fire and it would make the living room that it was in Really really nice and toasty and in a pleasant way.
Speaker 1: and there was this fan up near the top of the room That would then sort of blow air out of that one room into the rest of the house like this one little fan.
Speaker 1: So that way you could heat up sort of the whole house with you know Cuz it would blow right into like the staircase like in the perfect spot.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so the rest of the house got kind of war not way warm.
Speaker 1: It wasn't that great at evening out But kind of you know warmer as if you just lit this fire and as one Thing and then there was a big old chimney on the outside of the house.
Speaker 0: It did, you know exhausted through yep, my grandparents house that they built themselves.
Speaker 0: They designed it where it had two Fireplaces to provide like the ambient heat and save money and make it comfortable in the winter and then they had a regular old like electric furnace to fill in the gaps when it wasn't that cold when they want to make a fire.
Speaker 0: and the two fireplaces were actually very different designs and As a kid, I was fascinated with one in the living room because by the time I was a kid They were old.
Speaker 0: that house was huge.
Speaker 0: The living room was basically this unused Museum of Furniture.
Speaker 0: no one sat in.
Speaker 0: The Intellivision and the Atari were in there with a TV that no one used.
Speaker 0: It was connected to a dining room that also never got used except on like holidays where the family came over and as kids That fireplace just because it was the one they didn't use.
Speaker 0: We were obsessed with lighting fires in it and multiple times our grandparents our parents had to stop us as we had on our own Tried to start a fire in that thing.
Speaker 0: Yeah But they use the one in the family room all the time.
Speaker 0: and I gotta say just as a personal thing There's something about sitting in front of a fireplace on a cold day that no modern technology will replicate though I recognize that as a combination of nostalgia and novelty.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean it's like, you know It's like you could go into an air-conditioned, you know room.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right in when it's really hot out and suddenly you're all cooled out all over.
Speaker 1: But even if you're in the air-conditioned room Right the I got ice water that you're holding and drinking like is way cold.
Speaker 0: Well, it's the difference between a radiant heat versus ambient heat same reason why there are some heaters that will heat the room But like kerosene heaters those kinds of things a lot of like directed space heaters.
Speaker 0: They only heat you if they're pointed at you like the heat is coming from it and it doesn't go anywhere else.
Speaker 0: Like it doesn't heat the room.
Speaker 0: It just heats you right?
Speaker 1: So a fireplace is like, you know, it's like it's not a. it can heat the whole room But it's a lot more like the ice water where it's like it's real hot It's a fire right and you can get really close to it and it's like ah Next to your radiator you kind of can yep.
Speaker 0: Well like Like, you know I ski Obviously COVID kind of put a damper on that.
Speaker 0: but one of the most sublime feelings in the world is Skiing for half a day and then you're cold and you're tired and you're hungry and you go into that lodge on the top of Mountain and there's a fireplace that's bigger than you can imagine.
Speaker 0: that was built in like the early 60s and There's a gigantic fire and you sit next to it You take your boots off you put your feet up on that stone and you just hang out there for an hour.
Speaker 1: Yeah, as long as you don't have to breathe in any smoke fire is pretty nice.
Speaker 0: Fireplaces require maintenance and effort and there's a reason why Almost every fireplace the modern home is fake or there.
Speaker 0: at least they're not like a real Fireplace from olden times.
Speaker 0: They usually are just gas-powered the logs are usually fake.
Speaker 0: They're usually separated like much more cleanly from the environment and the fire department's much happier for it.
Speaker 0: Yep, cuz a lot of people who buy a house that's old, you know, my dad was a fireman My grandpa was a fireman.
Speaker 0: My great-grandpa was a fireman.
Speaker 0: I know a lot about fire safety.
Speaker 0: Fire places are not dangerous if they are properly when used properly.
Speaker 0: Most people who buy houses that have a real fireplace Don't know things like.
Speaker 0: you got to hire a chimney sweep.
Speaker 0: That's still a thing.
Speaker 0: Chimney sweeps are still a thing and without them you will die.
Speaker 0: Chris like things will build up in your fireplace that will kill your whole family.
Speaker 1: even if you have a fireplace and you haven't used it in like forever and you like You know you get you if you decide oh I want to use it now You got to get the chimney sweep first Even if you think it's empty up there.
Speaker 0: or you have to know About fireplaces.
Speaker 0: you have to know how to check a flue.
Speaker 0: You have to know what all those dampers do.
Speaker 0: What is a damper?
Speaker 0: when do you turn it?
Speaker 0: Why do you turn it?
Speaker 0: And also how do you structure the fire?
Speaker 0: Nobody knows how to make a goddamn fire in a fireplace anymore.
Speaker 0: You have to line the wood up the right way or it doesn't work that well or it's dangerous Yep, so when you are too much wood not enough wood.
Speaker 0: Oh, I was at a place was like a decade ago, but I was at a house and they had a fireplace That clearly it looked like it hadn't been used much But it had been used a few times.
Speaker 0: and next to it was all the shit you need for a fireplace Like the pincers and the poker and the rake and all that stuff.
Speaker 1: Yep Bellows are the most fun.
Speaker 0: I decided to start a fire in this fireplace because there's a place we were renting and guess what?
Speaker 0: all the stuff next to the fireplace was Decorative shit.
Speaker 0: It wasn't usable, but they had clearly been using it like it was real because they did not know the difference.
Speaker 0: But yeah, don't touch a fireplace if you don't know how to use a fireplace.
Speaker 0: but in my life, let's see I In terms of heat every house every place I've ever lived until I moved to New York State had an electric furnace and Forced air heating with vents a cold air return and a hot air send Filling the entire house and just a furnace.
Speaker 1: ever lived anywhere with electric heating?
Speaker 1: I know I've actually had electric heating ever.
Speaker 0: electric heating is increasing like in New York.
Speaker 0: They're like we're not.
Speaker 0: buildings aren't gonna have gas heat when they build new ones.
Speaker 1: Well, that's good for the environment, but I don't know if I've lived with electric heating.
Speaker 1: I've heard that it's simply expensive which makes sense, right?
Speaker 0: Never saw a radiator that was actually used until I moved to New York.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean that's not a thing.
Speaker 0: in most of the Midwest You have a central furnace with forced air heating and vents and filters and shit.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the places that I lived had either, you know had had boilers of some kind in the basement That were you know, heating up water.
Speaker 0: In fact, I'll legit I'll admit until I came to RIT Like literally until we moved into colony I Kind of thought that the radiator with the spitting and all that stuff was an old-timey thing.
Speaker 0: That literally did not exist anymore.
Speaker 1: Well, that's you know The place that was around.
Speaker 0: but I moved to RIT and that that radiant like shitty heating along our baseboards was there And that was the thing.
Speaker 1: Yeah, yeah at a baseboards or actual radiators right that were hooked up to some boiler in the basement.
Speaker 1: That was boiling water, right?
Speaker 1: We're heating it up a whole lot and piping it around the house and then you know The piping goes through some sort of radiator of some shape right and then it warms up the air near it You know with lots of surface area and then the hot air circulates around.
Speaker 0: Older houses were like that for a lot of reasons.
Speaker 0: that made a lot of sense and can still make a lot of sense because there are.
Speaker 0: there are big pros and cons of Circulating a liquid and having radiators versus centralized forced air versus Hybrid like window units like we have in most modern New York City apartments.
Speaker 0: like no one system is better or worse.
Speaker 0: They all have big big pros and cons like what you described.
Speaker 0: Well, there's a lot of benefits.
Speaker 0: that kind of system That's not that doesn't cover the V part of HVAC.
Speaker 0: It'll heat up your house, but it doesn't exchange the air in your house.
Speaker 1: Nope, not at all.
Speaker 0: and a problem that a lot of people run into is old houses that get retrofitted or like have additions added To them tend to have poor air circulation because they rely on that kind of heating and cooling But they don't have like like a cheap house in the Midwest in the 50s and 60s would have a system that heated But that same system circulated the air in the entire house constantly
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm, but
Speaker 0: the cons of that kind of system?
Speaker 0: you're cooking in the kitchen Guess what gets pulled into the cold air return in like the whole house smells like what you're cooking or Dustin.
Speaker 0: beauly positive.
Speaker 0: It could be a positive.
Speaker 0: It was often a negative.
Speaker 0: Garbage and Lynn like dust and dirt builds up in those vents and If you're imagining how they clean those kinds of events what you're imagining is wrong.
Speaker 0: It's so much worse than what you're imagining.
Speaker 0: It sucks shit Especially in a house built in the 70s.
Speaker 0: You put a vibrator in there like an industrial one and you shake it all out and you ruin your house And there's dust in the air for months.
Speaker 1: Why even clean it this uh?
Speaker 1: Why is the worst?
Speaker 0: why indeed we probably should not have bothered cleaning it?
Speaker 0: my mom Thought it was a good idea to clean it because of allergies and stuff But honestly leaving that shit in there would have been better for our collective allergies than trying Robot that can clean it.
Speaker 0: now, maybe Some systems will have centralized filtration, which is a cool thing or centralized humidification or dehumidification.
Speaker 0: but yeah that Nowadays in New York we deal with this fact that most New York apartments.
Speaker 0: You can't even control your own heat It's just on or not on.
Speaker 1: yeah Well, I didn't control my own heat at the previous apartment which had radiators right and it had in wall air conditioner.
Speaker 1: But at the new apartment we basically have hotel style P tax which are All the rage for new you know big building Construction because it's way cheaper for the person who makes the building and owns the building to do it that way.
Speaker 0: yep And they can meter you directly Right.
Speaker 1: so basically this is one unit in each room.
Speaker 1: They're all the same unit in the whole building and you can get it does heating and air conditioning.
Speaker 1: It's in the wall right and it uses gas if you want to heat and he's electricity if you want an air condition and It blows right in the room.
Speaker 1: you control all the different rooms separately or ball together.
Speaker 1: It's up to you.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and then which you gotta pay for all that?
Speaker 1: electricity or gas because they got in the basement.
Speaker 1: There's a meter for every apartment.
Speaker 0: It's so our building does not have a meter for gas.
Speaker 0: gas is just free in our building and so is water.
Speaker 0: Oh, we only pay for our electricity Mmm.
Speaker 1: Well we're paying for the gas.
Speaker 1: There's like a zillion meters in the basement one for every.
Speaker 1: I went in that room.
Speaker 0: It's scary week because we just have one giant central industrialized boiler that literally heats the entire Building and it takes them.
Speaker 0: I was talking to the guys downstairs.
Speaker 0: It actually takes them like a full day to bring it online every year when it's time to turn it on Mmm.
Speaker 1: It makes sense.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so I've learned more recently like in the past few years.
Speaker 1: It makes perfect sense when you think about it But I just hadn't thought about it my whole life.
Speaker 1: my whole life.
Speaker 1: My thoughts were like, you know, yeah, obviously, you know, we'd rather not use fossil fuels.
Speaker 1: That's bad, right?
Speaker 1: But you know, I didn't think about like direct harm of having a fossil fuel heated home.
Speaker 1: I was just like, oh, yeah gas stove is way better than electric stove Even though worse for the yeah, there was just that study showing how bad indoor air pollution is Especially in apartments that have gas cooking.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Well, that's like us, right?
Speaker 1: It's like, you know, if you have a gas stove and you you know Even with proper exhaust.
Speaker 1: a lot of places just don't have the proper exhaust.
Speaker 1: They don't have a hood that's actually blowing out, you know to the outside We don't.
Speaker 0: but it's actually not a problem.
Speaker 0: not that much of a problem because the way our buildings designs those P tech units.
Speaker 0: there's one in each of the three main zones of our apartment and They are also Ventilation systems that are designed to pull fresh air in to each room to replace the air some number of times per day.
Speaker 0: and The apartments are all positive pressure and the interior hallways are all negative pressure.
Speaker 0: So there's a constant flow of fresh air into the apartments into the hallways and then out of the building.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but basically, you know, there was this idea that's you know, you burn, you know wood.
Speaker 1: obviously all this smoke everywhere.
Speaker 1: You don't want to sit downwind of a campfire, right?
Speaker 1: No, you know you burn coal, obviously you can't even fuck it.
Speaker 1: Oh, that's a big problem.
Speaker 0: the Midwest all these people decided to save money on electricity.
Speaker 0: in places that have either Electric powered furnaces but are cold or places that don't have like municipal gas We have to buy propane or something or we're even worse fuel oil, which is a nightmare.
Speaker 0: I had a co-worker who had his basement flooded with that stuff an entire tankers worth once.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the house was a write-off.
Speaker 0: they had to leave they just had to move out of their home permanently.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it was a hazmat site.
Speaker 1: Yep Point is is that natural gas which is what's being piped to most houses for your stove and stuff.
Speaker 1: when you burn it You don't smell there's no smoke, you know smell burning.
Speaker 1: It feels like, you know, oh, I guess it's all being burned up, right?
Speaker 1: It's like it's totally this.
Speaker 1: not, you know poisoning me.
Speaker 1: It's like no it's horribly poisoning you.
Speaker 1: You know kids who live in houses with you know Gas being burned or like way more likely to have asthma and shit by a large factor, right?
Speaker 1: It's it's really not good for you.
Speaker 1: You're you're got.
Speaker 1: you're burning fossil fuels in your home and then breathing them.
Speaker 1: So on that way bad.
Speaker 0: in the suburbs in America the everything I just described before a lot of people got it into their heads to get wood stoves or Wood furnaces to supplement their heating so they could use like our renewable resource and Run it when it's really cold.
Speaker 0: So they don't have to use as much of their like their rest of their heating system Like the electric system is very expensive.
Speaker 0: the problem is Most of these wood stoves or wood furnaces or wood like all that that kind of technology.
Speaker 0: They're super polluting to the local air quality in their neighborhoods because they're often Poorly regulated and while there are extremely efficient Very low pollution wood pellet like furnaces.
Speaker 0: That is not what most people deploy.
Speaker 0: that is not what most people use.
Speaker 1: Nope, they got some cheapo one.
Speaker 1: Yep, probably set up incorrectly.
Speaker 0: So let's talk about a chimney.
Speaker 1: That's not clean.
Speaker 1: Yeah, before I conditioning so I mean when I was you know Our house was not the newest house that we I grew up in.
Speaker 1: Oh my house.
Speaker 0: I grew up in was built in like the 20s.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so it's like people and people I knew their houses weren't that new either.
Speaker 1: So I didn't really like.
Speaker 1: I knew like central air was on the new houses like in the 90s.
Speaker 1: But it wasn't until like the mid late 90s.
Speaker 0: I started seeing we Moved a lot like every four or five years we moved just we just moved to a different house.
Speaker 0: so by the time in middle school, we moved into a house that has central air and I Never lived in a house that didn't have central air until again RIT colony Dorms, etc.
Speaker 1: I don't think I've ever lived like.
Speaker 1: I've been to plenty houses with central air.
Speaker 1: I don't think I've lived as my main house in a ever with central air, but even more in my entire life I never lived anywhere that didn't have air conditioning until the dorms at RIT Even in those houses before the central air.
Speaker 0: the one house We lived in in Detroit had a giant hole in the wall wall.
Speaker 0: Like it wasn't a window air conditioning unit.
Speaker 0: There's just this giant fucking hole in the wall.
Speaker 0: that had a gigantic air conditioner like installed in it as part of the house and That air conditioning the entire downstairs.
Speaker 0: and then there was a window unit in our bedroom and our parents had another one of these like Giant wall units in their bedroom.
Speaker 1: We did not have the house did not have any air conditioning built into it whatsoever.
Speaker 1: So we bought window units But we only had one to start with and eventually we got like, you know a couple more.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right, but that was you know, that's all we had.
Speaker 1: It was just a few window units In college.
Speaker 1: We were mostly there in the winter.
Speaker 1: It's Rochester.
Speaker 1: We didn't need that much though that summer we lived there.
Speaker 0: I remember it was hot enough to work Scott We talked at length about how we could jury-rig some sort of cooling in that apartment.
Speaker 0: I don't remember You don't remember the dry ice conversation?
Speaker 1: No, not at all.
Speaker 0: we we talked a lot about I was too fucking hot and we would do anything to have air conditioning, but we didn't have any money.
Speaker 0: and The way our IT worked was we could have gotten.
Speaker 1: we could have bought weird windows.
Speaker 1: We couldn't put the normal ones in.
Speaker 0: we could have bought one and put it in the room.
Speaker 1: We have weird windows.
Speaker 1: They didn't go in.
Speaker 0: No, they would have gone in just fine.
Speaker 0: You get the one like what Alex had.
Speaker 1: I Thought oh the with that weird.
Speaker 1: No, I wasn't buying one of those.
Speaker 0: The problem was even if we bought one the way our IT worked is we would have had to register that we had an air Conditioner and our rent would have gone up by like a hundred bucks a month, which we couldn't afford.
Speaker 0: At least I couldn't afford.
Speaker 1: so anyway, the point is is that you know, I've been mostly living with window units You know and then or a place where there was a effectively a window unit This happened to be in a hole in the wall.
Speaker 1: That wasn't the window.
Speaker 0: Well, like now our P tech units are just also air conditioners.
Speaker 1: So yeah, it's just which is effectively a window unit.
Speaker 1: It just has its own special hole in the wall for itself.
Speaker 1: That's not the window.
Speaker 0: Yep, I think the key the thing to think realize about air conditioning is that
Speaker 1: it is
Speaker 0: weird that Americans in particular have historically treated heating as a necessity and Air-conditioning is just a luxury because that flattens the fact that there are a lot of places even in America where?
Speaker 0: Cooling an environment is just as important to human health as heating it.
Speaker 1: That's true.
Speaker 1: And but also I think it's just you know, this climate change right is a lot of America wasn't Hot.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right at least, you know.
Speaker 0: for that much I mean like I grew up in a place that was weird.
Speaker 0: Michigan is very hot in the summer and very humid in the summer, but also very cold in the winter.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but it's like it would only the amount of time of the year.
Speaker 1: if you even if you had the air conditioner that you Would use it would only be like a couple months.
Speaker 0: Those months with like an attic fan out of 12.
Speaker 1: out of 12 months You're gonna use the air conditioner for two or three.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right It's like it didn't.
Speaker 1: or even if you had central air, it's like you're gonna use it.
Speaker 1: You know not that you know, but now you're gonna be using it a lot more All right, whereas opposed you go to a country like say, you know, like Singapore.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like yeah Singapore like air conditioning.
Speaker 0: It could be hot enough and humid enough in Singapore during the hot season that Humans can't survive Outside for that long Like everyone knows.
Speaker 1: many.
Speaker 1: the mini units right those little ones the box that sits outside and just has pipes coming in right?
Speaker 1: Whatever those are cars.
Speaker 1: I took some great photos of those when I last time they're called mini something right those ones mini splits Mini split that's the one that's like that.
Speaker 1: Those are actually the best ones possible.
Speaker 1: the mini splits That's like.
Speaker 1: that's the ideal unless you have a big old house.
Speaker 0: Well, obviously there are alternative means of air conditioning.
Speaker 0: So for example in the projects and in a lot of older buildings that have old-school radiators in the summer You could run cold water through the radiators and air condition.
Speaker 0: You can cool and you can.
Speaker 1: you can do that.
Speaker 0: it's really effective.
Speaker 0: but The thing about air conditioning is that modern air conditioning and a lot of people forget this does two things it cools and It dehumidifies by the nature of how it works.
Speaker 0: that other option only cools.
Speaker 0: It does not dehumidify.
Speaker 0: There were.
Speaker 1: well, you'll get a lot of condensation on the radiator and hope it doesn't rust.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but that is not enough Dehumidification.
Speaker 1: No, it's not.
Speaker 0: and the fact that air conditioning dehumidifies is a big goddamn deal That a lot of people don't realize because they don't remember a world when Alternatives were used or they've never lived in a place where those alternatives are used like swamp cooling and all that other stuff Really effective at cooling depending on the local environment Not dehumidifying which is kind of a big deal.
Speaker 0: like Abe Lincoln when he was dying They used an early form of air conditioning to try to cool the room, but it didn't dehumidify.
Speaker 0: It was basically giant blocks of ice and fans That work.
Speaker 1: that's really good.
Speaker 0: It works.
Speaker 0: Okay, but it also can make the room in human.
Speaker 1: You can you can drive, you know, we have refrigerated trucks these days, right?
Speaker 1: If you just put a block of dry ice in a in a back of a truck with a fan on it and close the door You can store meat in there for a long ass time.
Speaker 0: It'll also kill anyone who tries to hang out in that room.
Speaker 1: Well, you don't hang out in there, but you can go in get the meat and get out.
Speaker 0: Yeah, depending I mean nowadays they just use active cooling.
Speaker 0: There's a you see those Cooler cars, but air conditioning.
Speaker 0: I Really really missed it.
Speaker 0: when I was at RIT Like that was the first time in my life I'd ever experienced like a day when it was like 90-something degrees and I couldn't just go inside somewhere.
Speaker 0: That was cool.
Speaker 1: I Basically like, you know, even no matter what heating and cooling system I have no matter how good it is or crappy It is I just generally For at least the past several years and try to you within what within the amount that I can control I try to minimize using it as much as possible.
Speaker 1: All right, it's just like I haven't turned the heat on yet.
Speaker 1: I probably might turn it on today.
Speaker 0: I I don't bother practicing that form of self-denial.
Speaker 0: I keep my environment comfortable within the bounds of what is reasonable.
Speaker 1: I'm comfortable.
Speaker 1: I'm not doing.
Speaker 1: it's like if I'm not comfortable.
Speaker 1: I turn it on.
Speaker 0: How are you like this?
Speaker 0: and yet when it's like 71 degrees?
Speaker 0: You're like, it's too cold.
Speaker 0: I can't bike.
Speaker 1: It is too cold Doesn't mean it's nice it's not too cold.
Speaker 1: I got to turn the heat on.
Speaker 0: but I'm saying if it's it like I Bike I'll bike to work.
Speaker 0: if it's like 50 degrees in shorts the t-shirt and be very comfortable.
Speaker 1: That's cold.
Speaker 0: But how do you have such a wide operating range sitting in your house?
Speaker 0: But if you're on a bike where you have a lot more control of your personal situation, you're suddenly like can't deal with anything.
Speaker 0: I'm just curious.
Speaker 1: Another thing is that you know The apartments that I happen to live in.
Speaker 1: this one in the previous one, they're they're so insulated They were so insulated and they have large south-facing windows.
Speaker 1: So the Sun comes in or I can put the curtains.
Speaker 0: and well I talked about this on the show before.
Speaker 0: but Remember like four or five years ago where our building like the boiler broke and we didn't have heat for like two weeks in the middle of the winter.
Speaker 0: it took More than four days for it to start getting chilly in our apartment from when the heater broke just because the building is so Insulated.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like a you know, I'm not cold right now in the apartment.
Speaker 0: We often in the fall will have to run the AC occasionally because it'll just get too hot in the building because the insulation Hmm.
Speaker 1: So just one one little side note here this the apartment I'm in now has two bathrooms and it came with right as a luxury item that we've never used even one time Heated floors in the bathroom.
Speaker 1: now you could imagine.
Speaker 1: Oh get out of the bathroom Get out of the shower.
Speaker 1: The floor is cold, right?
Speaker 1: I mean, I always imagine that being in hotels if
Speaker 0: I built a house like if I was rich and I had a house Like built from scratch that house would 100% have radiant floor heating
Speaker 1: whole house, but oh, baby Yeah, let me it could be good the rest of the house.
Speaker 1: But in the bathroom we have it and we've never used it and I've never come out of the shower and had cold floor.
Speaker 0: The floor under my feet here is Warm like actively warm because of the heat from the people living under us.
Speaker 0: because this building is so freakin insulated, right?
Speaker 1: It's like there's absolutely like it's it.
Speaker 1: they have the system to heat to special floor.
Speaker 0: Why it's New York.
Speaker 0: Your floors are all right heated.
Speaker 1: I've never needed it even once.
Speaker 1: and also one of them has like an error on the control Right and I asked the super.
Speaker 1: I was like, hey, I'm not using this but like do you want to fix this?
Speaker 1: He's like, no those things are a piece of shit.
Speaker 1: He's like, don't worry He won't charge you for it when you know, I feel like in an apartment.
Speaker 0: that is just a stupid idea All told and it's literally only there because they can put it as a checkbox.
Speaker 1: Yeah The other thing is I feel like if I did use it.
Speaker 1: if I did use it It's like how much?
Speaker 1: how much am I gonna pay for the electricity?
Speaker 1: It takes to heat the bathroom floor, right?
Speaker 0: It's like see those are good for a house where you want.
Speaker 0: You don't want cold stops and you just want like a nice radiant warmth in the whole house.
Speaker 1: I think it would make sense.
Speaker 1: If you had a big-ass luxury bathroom.
Speaker 0: Give me a second.
Speaker 0: There might be trouble in the other room One sec.
Speaker 0: What's up?
Speaker 1: Yeah Did the heating explode?
Speaker 0: Oh water in the ceiling really cut the rest of the show show.
Speaker 1: show up water in the ceiling.
Speaker 1: the classic All right.
Speaker 0: See you later.
Speaker 0: Bye This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at front row crew comm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 0: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 0: But unlike those other late shows it's actually recorded at night and the patreon patrons for this episode of geek nights Are handy.
Speaker 0: McNichol Island Joyce link each adrenaline the third of road.
Speaker 0: a bunch of people don't want me to say their names Chris Robert Clinton Walton Dex Finn just like a dude guy Chi 85 Rebecca done Ruby bad build 34 cowards Ryan parent Sam Erickson Shervin van whole Taylor Bron the Iron Front you hold the key to my heart and a bunch of people who actually do not want me to say Their names.
Speaker 0: I leave you only with a stinger that is appropriate to what just happens.
Speaker 0: Leave me alone.
Speaker 0: I see him son.