Speaker 0:
Speaker 1: It's Tuesday June 1st 2021.
Speaker 1: I'm rim Scott and this is geek nights tonight.
Speaker 1: We are reviewing the new Pokemon snap.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: It's on one hand It's weird that it's already June.
Speaker 1: I feel like time suddenly accelerated like I believe it was March and I thought wow We've spent.
Speaker 0: it was March.
Speaker 0: It was March in a long time and then it and then it was June 2021 the next day.
Speaker 1: I think I think what happened is that there was no May.
Speaker 1: May did not actually happen.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't know what's going on.
Speaker 1: It's like it's good times cuz it's summer and it's a good numbers are getting better at least in the u.s.
Speaker 0: Like we're doing okay, at least in New York.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but it's like at the same time.
Speaker 0: It's like Any play.
Speaker 0: I'm getting old.
Speaker 0: I need life to slow down.
Speaker 0: I want to live more.
Speaker 0: I don't want Stop speeding up.
Speaker 0: Go slow slow shit dad.
Speaker 0: Yep, but at the same time I don't need to be like in the in the arena retirement home tomorrow You know, I want to be there eventually so I could play a bunch of RPGs that haven't go to work.
Speaker 1: But I'll think of it this way.
Speaker 1: think back all of you the listener to the one listener on the live stream because I started It suddenly without any warning.
Speaker 1: Uh Think back to this moment when you're in the retirement home alone and you're 99 and think back to this exact moment.
Speaker 1: You just teleported from here to there Instantly.
Speaker 1: all that time just passed.
Speaker 1: That's my go-to taunt when I'm losing a board game As I watch this train game slip away from me pretty rapidly slip.
Speaker 0: It's it think it's gone past slip.
Speaker 0: This isn't.
Speaker 0: this isn't a slip away situation.
Speaker 1: This is more like the guy in the stands who got hit in the nuts by that home run that made the rounds earlier.
Speaker 0: You wouldn't you?
Speaker 0: may you spent all your you know, I won three in a row, right?
Speaker 0: And then you won what?
Speaker 0: three or four in a row, right?
Speaker 0: And now your load has your load has blown and I think I'm taking this one even though I didn't think I was gonna take it.
Speaker 0: I'm suddenly taking it.
Speaker 1: I think PD is what a priority deal.
Speaker 1: made you take it.
Speaker 1: Anyway, we're talking about a train game because we got some train game news.
Speaker 0: Whoa train news choo-choo.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so check this.
Speaker 1: there is an expansion an official one to 1846 the faint train game we played first the one that set us down this dark rail.
Speaker 0: Right
Speaker 1: now 1846
Speaker 0: is the one that we recommend people start with not because it's the simplest it actually has a few little bits that make it A little tricky compared to some of the simpler ones like 1889 or whatever But it is the most forgiving right and is the most one that one that makes a lot of sense.
Speaker 1: It makes a lot of sense when you lose the game ends pretty quick.
Speaker 0: You're not like stuck there and you can't if you go bankrupt, you know, it doesn't end the whole game, right?
Speaker 0: It's very forgiving to people new players.
Speaker 0: So that's the one we recommend you start with.
Speaker 0: and it just got.
Speaker 0: an upgrade to.
Speaker 0: new private corporations have been added to the game Which sort of helps one of the public corporations CEO, which was kind of meh And I guess it maybe could help you eerie even a little bit too because that one's also meh.
Speaker 1: I've definitely noticed eerie rarely gets a lot of like serious play except maybe you have to be.
Speaker 0: we don't play with enough players Often enough to even have eerie.
Speaker 0: you have a possibility being in the game true
Speaker 1: lately
Speaker 0: But you know, there's no reason to take eerie when New York is available
Speaker 1: true But if PRR and area are both not in the game, New York is extra powerful because it just basically doesn't have to worry about tokens
Speaker 0: Sure.
Speaker 0: I mean if there's not enough players in the game and not enough players in the game You don't have to worry about tokens as much just generally.
Speaker 1: But anyway with the up trend that a lot of people have noticed was that In like the center south of the board around Cincinnati There'd rarely be a lot of play except in the late-game like rush to get a route to st Louis because everyone has three.
Speaker 0: this three like super tiles the Cleveland tile the Detroit tile and the Cincinnati tile and the cleat.
Speaker 0: They could end Chicago like.
Speaker 0: well, Chicago is different, but there's this 3z tiles, right and The Cincinnati one didn't usually gets the least action because see you know That's right near it is weak and it has to bust through a bunch of mountains to get there, right?
Speaker 0: So they the new private corporations.
Speaker 0: One of them is Little Miami which adds the ability to like lay free tiles down in that area.
Speaker 0: And what's the other one?
Speaker 0: It's something else, right?
Speaker 1: Oh, well, I know is down there if you teleport.
Speaker 0: No, the other the other new private corporation.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So the brother the other private corporation Little Miami in boomtown.
Speaker 0: All right, boomtown.
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 0: What does it do?
Speaker 1: boomtown puts a $20 token in Cincinnati?
Speaker 1: And that company gets 20 bucks added to all of its routes.
Speaker 0: There you go.
Speaker 0: Almost yes, if both of those are or one or both of those are in the game.
Speaker 0: Suddenly now the area of the board that didn't get a lot of activity now gets is now equally hot compared to the other areas.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, and that can make a lot more dynamic play by giving you you know Putting basically all the different kinds of routes closer to the Pareto frontier.
Speaker 1: so yep, so it actually just seems to balance the game out a little bit and break the Somewhat stable meta or at least make it a little less locked into what's gonna get IPO to end Mmm.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but it's interesting that we it's available.
Speaker 1: I didn't know it was even coming.
Speaker 0: this news I didn't know it was coming either and suddenly was added to the train game website 18xx games.
Speaker 1: Well, I guess I would.
Speaker 1: I would suspect that there have been more games of 18xx games played on 18xx games.net That have ever been played physically.
Speaker 0: That's probably correct.
Speaker 1: I would bet on that as I personally I feel like 1846 and maybe 1889 are the most complex training games I would ever physically play like I would never ever in my life consider playing 1817 with physical pieces of paper.
Speaker 0: No a Chesapeake is very playable just because playable.
Speaker 1: you're right.
Speaker 0: CE is a very is really also the you know.
Speaker 1: But even then it would be hard because one of the problem You know, this is something that we didn't talk about as much when we reviewed these games early on.
Speaker 1: but I noticed this playing online.
Speaker 1: While it is public information how much money everyone has and how much money they make the fact that you would have to keep track of it on a piece of paper or ask people or Like look and count things in people's boards meant people didn't do it.
Speaker 1: So with the online version because all the numbers someone does it and wins.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but it's not worth it to do that It's just.
Speaker 1: it's such a pain.
Speaker 1: but online all the numbers are there.
Speaker 1: I can even click on a little spreadsheet and it shows me everyone's trajectory.
Speaker 1: Yep, like that's how I make decisions.
Speaker 1: I spend most of this game looking at the map and looking at the spreadsheet and occasionally looking at the entities tab Mm-hmm, and you can't get that in person.
Speaker 1: I think these games are not easily objectively better as digital games Even if you played them in person a hot seat on a tablet or something.
Speaker 0: Well, I mean imagine if you wanted it you could play a game.
Speaker 0: For example, you could play Master of Orion 2 completely tabletop without changing any rules whatsoever.
Speaker 0: It's a turn-based game, right?
Speaker 0: You know, there's no real-time element to it whatsoever But there are just so many numbers to deal with.
Speaker 0: it would be impossible.
Speaker 0: You wouldn't get through turn one, right?
Speaker 0: You know get to manage how much you know science is coming from every single colony and every single plan.
Speaker 0: Take your whole life to do so.
Speaker 0: There are some board games out there that have sort of.
Speaker 0: obviously they're nowhere near the complexity of Master of Orion 2 or a civilization.
Speaker 0: You know computer game in terms of all the.
Speaker 0: you know The the things going on but they push the limits of how many different numbers there are going on And so you can't really even if you can play them in person quite easily.
Speaker 0: You don't have all of the metrics available to everyone unless you really spend You know the time to calculate them or you just have a computer there.
Speaker 0: in which case why aren't you just playing on the computer?
Speaker 1: Yep, but that gets something.
Speaker 1: we talked about a lot on geek nights as especially in our panels around tabletop games and what it means to be a tabletop game and how they sort of enforce a certain Simplicity and elegance at least if they're designed well and Honestly, these 18xx games kind of make terrible pen and paper games in a computer-driven era Like they're.
Speaker 1: like the design is not informed by the usual constraints of tabletop.
Speaker 1: They're constrained by the.
Speaker 1: They're constrained more by the same things that constrain stuff like chainmail and Dungeons & Dragons.
Speaker 1: Like one of the components is a bunch up like a calculator and a bunch of pads of paper and pencils and stuff.
Speaker 1: But regardless I really like playing these games online.
Speaker 1: I feel like if we ever played one of the packs we would get out laptops and just sit there playing them on the laptop.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that sounds good.
Speaker 1: So on some other news, I really quickly.
Speaker 0: it would go by really quickly not having to like, you know Wait for anybody.
Speaker 1: I feel like we might do that when we're waiting in line for something or while we're waiting for someone else to take their.
Speaker 0: We could go to a pecs, right?
Speaker 0: We could start one and cuz since you can play it on your phone so easily?
Speaker 0: Yeah, basically be like while we're anytime you're waiting.
Speaker 0: It's like check to see if it's your turn and just keep it rolling to fill in all the pecs gaps.
Speaker 1: That's a good idea.
Speaker 1: and at pecs unplugged.
Speaker 1: We should do this.
Speaker 1: make it a thing Mmm, I'll make it a thing.
Speaker 1: So in some other news, uh, I have not played it yet.
Speaker 1: It just came out but we're gonna play it to review at some point soon.
Speaker 1: an airport for aliens currently run by dogs.
Speaker 1: It's apparently out.
Speaker 1: I forgot this game was coming.
Speaker 0: I've been I've been talking about this game for a long time.
Speaker 0: I've been so hype about this game and it is out now.
Speaker 0: and not only is it out but there was a patch so It's even better than it was when it was released.
Speaker 0: Not just some days ago, right?
Speaker 0: most.
Speaker 0: So yeah, it's basically I've played it.
Speaker 0: I haven't beat it yet, but it's a game.
Speaker 0: it's exactly what I thought it was gonna be.
Speaker 0: you are a person and You're you have a woken I guess in an airport and you have a spouse who is also in the airport clearly something you don't have a great memory of like the before times but somehow you're the last two humans in a universe in which there are only airports and horrifying things outside of the airports and Their airports are being run by dogs who are stock photos of dogs and The aliens if they ever existed don't exist now, or at least you don't see them.
Speaker 0: So you don't know what happened to them.
Speaker 0: And yeah, you go around Helping out dogs flying around meeting dogs Talking to your spouse, right?
Speaker 0: Who's doing some kind of research or something?
Speaker 1: And if you have not seen this game, like it's got a very like part of the reason we all get excited about it.
Speaker 1: You know, you look at a game.
Speaker 1: You're like that's an indie game.
Speaker 1: This game has got that feel all over like the dogs are literal stock photos of dogs.
Speaker 1: just right lain into the game The the aesthetic.
Speaker 0: it looks like the kind of game that you would just like.
Speaker 0: You know buy on itch IO that like some kids slap together, right?
Speaker 0: Who you know was managed to be able to use some 3d like map level generator.
Speaker 0: Right the kind of level like I'm not high school me would have made for quake one or something.
Speaker 0: Yeah You know, everything's a square but it's not like.
Speaker 0: it's not the.
Speaker 0: you know.
Speaker 0: The cause of it isn't?
Speaker 0: Oh some amateurs made this right?
Speaker 0: It's they did it that way on purpose, right?
Speaker 0: It's like if you have some master animator and they intentionally do stick figure on purpose sort of like.
Speaker 1: well It's the difference between the boom Coming into the shot because you are terrible at making films versus the boom came into the shot because you're trying to make a point About how this film is poorly made.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but it's like, you know, Don Hertz feels like my spoon is too big, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah It's just a little blob guy with a spoon.
Speaker 0: But yet that's like an oscar-winning Animation, I think it won't do that one, right?
Speaker 0: It's sort of uh, oh and the the humor is actually not too far off from that.
Speaker 0: it is it is very Humorous sort of game and it's it's great because a we don't see a lot of comedy games these days, right?
Speaker 0: I think a lot of comedy in general these days is you know Not funny?
Speaker 1: or Try to think of kind of games that were primarily funny to me like Hypnospace outlaw was close.
Speaker 0: This is by the same, right?
Speaker 1: But people are like some of these reviews up.
Speaker 1: multiple reviewers have said we haven't played it yet that it brought them to tears That it's there's a lot going on.
Speaker 0: Well, because it does have you know, like a like a meaningful message to it, right?
Speaker 0: It's like, you know in your life You've experienced at least some people have many people have experienced sort of like these transient Places right like airports, right?
Speaker 0: It's like you're in them.
Speaker 0: You're somehow familiar with them or at least part of them.
Speaker 1: Well, cuz any airport you go in the world, like if it's a major international airport They're all kind of the same.
Speaker 1: like your brain almost feels like they're all just directly connected.
Speaker 1: Like if you walk far enough at JFK, you'll end up in the Seattle Airport.
Speaker 1: somehow like your brain just can't quite parse directly intuitively that there's a plane in between them.
Speaker 0: because they're so sort of these feelings you have for places like that that you go to More than once but you don't really, you know, you're not like working there.
Speaker 0: I guess people who work in airports probably feel differently about.
Speaker 1: well think about difference on packs looks like having enforced much.
Speaker 0: But the point is you you have that combined with like this sort of long-distance relationship with your Spouse there, right and it's sort of you know.
Speaker 0: It's like even though the game is so ridiculous of these stock photo dogs handing you guns and and you know all this other nonsense.
Speaker 0: It's a cage dog locking you in a cage and all sorts of nonsense like that is going on.
Speaker 0: It's that thread that like main thread of the game is actually very you know Sentimental meaningful and sincere right?
Speaker 0: It's it, you know.
Speaker 0: in terms of you know Poking a particular feeling people have that I don't think any other game tries to poke that particular Feeling right?
Speaker 0: It's like it's like they.
Speaker 0: this is very specific feeling that you experience in certain circumstances in life.
Speaker 0: And this game was like we're gonna write a story that pokes that exact very precise area like Hokuto pokes Pokes that exact area As someone who's approaching 40 and who's oh, you know as we were saying before the show started Running out of time.
Speaker 1: I appreciate games and media in general that just poke one thing very well.
Speaker 0: So yeah, we're we'll talk about this little right give it a full episode when he beat it completely Yeah, and complete our proper Dex's.
Speaker 1: this is worth a full playthrough Yeah, so in some other news Nvidia has announced now that the 3080 T eyes are coming out for 1200.
Speaker 0: Well, so many Will be 1200 bucks Right, well so good I guess is that there's more cards.
Speaker 0: I guess right and also good.
Speaker 0: There's faster better cards.
Speaker 0: That's nice.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: They're going to my default with the Nerfing.
Speaker 1: that limits how useful they are for coins.
Speaker 0: I'm sure someone will see how that much that matters.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know the.
Speaker 0: I guess that's okay if it helps.
Speaker 0: They also have a higher MSRP, which is good and bad.
Speaker 0: It's bad because it makes them less accessible to people right which is not great.
Speaker 0: You know people actually want to play games aren't made.
Speaker 0: I'm not necessarily made of money So it's not that cool.
Speaker 1: But it might actually keep the price down Overall because the people who have money are buying that one and there's more supply of the cheaper ones that could Eventually be bought at their actual MSRP, but it's also less profitable to scalp, right?
Speaker 0: So if the supply can't be raised Does you know?
Speaker 0: then at least the price can be raised?
Speaker 0: So that way at least if they're gonna sell they're gonna sell to someone who wants them.
Speaker 0: They're not gonna sell to someone who just wants to resell it because there's no point.
Speaker 1: I mean frankly the price should be raised even with the collateral damage to gamers and professionals just to Cripple the coin industry.
Speaker 1: that is continuing to be a problem.
Speaker 0: Well, I mean all you'd be doing then is be taking it wouldn't?
Speaker 0: I don't?
Speaker 0: you wouldn't cripple the coin industry because coin people If at least if they were useful for coins, they would still buy them.
Speaker 0: Yeah But they were basically just transfer.
Speaker 0: It's just does.
Speaker 0: the money you spend for the price of the thing is effectively gonna be constant unless you get lucky.
Speaker 0: It's just.
Speaker 0: does the money you spend on the card go to Nvidia or does it go to some second third-party reseller, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah That's what the it's like.
Speaker 0: what portion of the money it costs to buy the card will go to Nvidia?
Speaker 0: or and the card makers like aces and gigabyte and whoever EVGA all them and Versus what percentage of the money you pay goes to just some guy who bought one and then evade it?
Speaker 1: But at least the other thing is these are the TI's.
Speaker 1: so these are the special cards that are usually only used by people who have a lot of money to waste or Professionals who are doing something serious with them.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I've never bought a TI.
Speaker 1: I've never needed a TI like my 1080 was fine.
Speaker 1: This thing is basically.
Speaker 1: the only real difference between the 3080 TI and the 3090 is that the 3090 is Three slots wide and uses a crazy shit ton of power Like you need a 750 watt power supply minimum to put a 3090.
Speaker 1: You can get comparable performance with a much more reasonable power profile and physical profile with the 3080 TI.
Speaker 1: That's kind of the big difference.
Speaker 1: I'm on a waiting list for both the 3080 and a 3090.
Speaker 1: I'll take whichever one I can get first.
Speaker 0: I'm on a waiting list for a 5080 or a 60.
Speaker 1: Not sure which one I mean, I only got a.
Speaker 0: My 1070 has not, you know found anything that causes it a problem.
Speaker 0: yet I mean I played do the newer doom right the internal one and the 1070 was just fine even with the 4k monitor.
Speaker 0: So I'm not gonna.
Speaker 0: I'm not really seeing a need for me to upgrade.
Speaker 0: it can still encode videos in Premiere.
Speaker 1: Well, we're our household is two professionals who need video Card stuff and between us we have a 1080 and a 770.
Speaker 0: Yes, you probably you need to replace the 770.
Speaker 1: We need at least one 3080 or 3090.
Speaker 0: My 1070 is gonna carry me for a long ass time and in the living room.
Speaker 0: I got a 1050 So that's gonna carry.
Speaker 1: for yeah, I'm still rocking out GTX 450 in the living room.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I was actually feeling you know when I bought that 1050 for the living room.
Speaker 0: It felt like sort of an unlike an exert of like a Excessive purchase because the I the integrated graphics and the HD PC were just fine You know for watching a YouTube or most 90% of what I was doing in there.
Speaker 0: But it was like I was occasionally and I still occasionally play a game on the HD PC That's a 3d game.
Speaker 0: And that's when that the IGP was suffering in the in the HD PC.
Speaker 0: So I'm like, alright I'll just get the cheapest like 1050.
Speaker 0: It's like that'll last me forever right and you know, it felt a little bit like to my.
Speaker 0: really wait, you know I don't do it that often right?
Speaker 0: It's like a mom.
Speaker 0: Oh, I could to go with the lower frame rates in the living room.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but the future-proofing ends up saving you so much money in the long run.
Speaker 1: It turned out to be a good good Bye, I've generally like now that I'm old enough to have had a lot of computers.
Speaker 1: the one thing I can say is that Every time I have spent what felt like too much money and future-proof something even if that harmed me in the short term It is always in retrospect been the right decision.
Speaker 1: Like I've never regretted Spending more than I needed to on a computer and I have 100% of the time regretted when I cheaped out on a component.
Speaker 1: It has always come back to bite me.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't think I've regret it.
Speaker 0: Like if there's a thing that I need, right?
Speaker 0: I don't think I've ever regretted an instance in which I bought the thing but bought like, you know an upgraded more expensive Better one of the thing, right?
Speaker 0: The only regrets are like bowling ball where you bought a thing and didn't use the thing enough, right?
Speaker 0: And therefore it was like an unused thing and then it didn't matter whether you bought the cheapo.
Speaker 0: I guess cheapo would have been okay because you barely spent any money on it.
Speaker 0: But it wouldn't matter if you bought like the medium or the high tier.
Speaker 0: Yeah, because you equally regret spending money on an unused thing.
Speaker 0: But if you buy like, you know about bicycle, right?
Speaker 0: It's like if you buy the medium Bicycle or the high tier bicycle or the doctor level the dentist level bicycle as the the they like to say in the biking community.
Speaker 0: As long as you're riding that bike a lot, I don't think you're gonna regret, you know any level.
Speaker 0: because if you buy a level too low Well, okay.
Speaker 0: well you know you bought a. It's eventually like it's gonna serve you well for a long time and eventually you'll upgrade it and get to the correct level of bicycle For you and if you get one that's too high it's like as long as you're riding it a lot you'll never Outgrow it because it's you know, even if even if it's too extreme for you.
Speaker 0: Yeah It's like you'll be fine with that for the rest of your life.
Speaker 1: So as long as I have the privilege of the money to afford it I'm gonna continue with what I've been doing my whole life.
Speaker 1: I'm always getting either the cheapest piece of crap or exactly what I want to need.
Speaker 1: I'm never gonna go into that middle of the road.
Speaker 0: I Ridiculously overpriced for no reason usually was like brand stuff.
Speaker 1: Yeah I mean, there's the same thing with flying like as much as like.
Speaker 1: oh, yeah business class is better than premium economy.
Speaker 1: I'm not fucking paying $10,000 to fly anyway.
Speaker 0: Yeah a good example.
Speaker 0: I always look at as is it in cameras as like the Leica cameras, right?
Speaker 0: It's like they're way fucking nice, right?
Speaker 0: I would if you wanted to give me one I would take a like an m6 or an m10.
Speaker 0: It's like yes, I want one, right?
Speaker 0: But you know a used old like an m6 is probably two or three thousand dollars You can buy and that's like a 35 millimeter film camera that just takes the same Film photos than any other like a. you know a $10 point-and-shoot or a disposable does right?
Speaker 0: You could just put lenses on it and the lenses cost a fortune.
Speaker 0: also, they're thousands and thousands of dollars to get a lens to go on that camera at least if it's a like a lens and You can just buy a much cheaper camera that takes the same photo and with for the amount of money it cost to get That camera because of its name brand and its fanciness you could get like a brand new ridiculous digital camera.
Speaker 0: Right, that's like, you know, there's 4k video and all this other, you know It's not that the price is too high for it to.
Speaker 0: it'd be like if you bought an Apple to GS and it cost $10,000 right?
Speaker 0: It's like but you bought it because it's an Apple to GS as this mystique, right?
Speaker 0: There's nothing else like it.
Speaker 1: it's that's why I made that distinction of not the best as much as The one.
Speaker 1: that is what I want and need like.
Speaker 1: if I cuz if I don't know what I want to need.
Speaker 1: I'm definitely not buying the expensive one Right.
Speaker 0: The point is is that it's the expensive one doesn't always line up with the.
Speaker 0: you know, the better the better one.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there are.
Speaker 0: there are things in the world that you can buy that are just overpriced because of brand right name recognition Or some other reason.
Speaker 0: that makes no sense And you could have regrets blowing the money on those Because you spent a bunch of money and got way less for your money.
Speaker 1: So in some other news, I feel like this is almost feels like news from I don't know 1997 but There was a giant ROM site.
Speaker 1: I mean I can't.
Speaker 1: I don't think I've been to this ROM site because I already have every ROM.
Speaker 0: Well, I think what.
Speaker 0: so I think it's like I used to go to ROM sites all the time back in the day but what happened is eventually we had bit torrent and when bit torrent came around and Obviously there weren't new old games not that many at least and the ones that are new you can get by other means there
Speaker 1: was This one torrent that was like every Atari NES NES gate.
Speaker 1: There was this one torrent that we all got.
Speaker 0: It's just I got a torrent.
Speaker 0: it had every NES game in it.
Speaker 0: I'm like, well, I don't need to go to ROM sites anymore.
Speaker 0: I have every NES game I have.
Speaker 0: I could make a ROM site if I wanted to And that that was the end of ROM sites, right?
Speaker 0: Why picking out individual ROMs?
Speaker 0: What's the point of that?
Speaker 1: So I did run into a situation remember when I was trying to get fightcade working which fightcade is an online service where you can be like I want to play a Genesis game or an SNES game with another human and It's designed for fighting game people to play fighting games remotely.
Speaker 0: You can imagine I heard about it from people in the fighting game community because they were using it big time during the pandemic.
Speaker 0: Yeah to play a lot of fighting games with each other, which is totally awesome.
Speaker 1: and it's cool like you go in and you just Join the room of the game you want to play and you can just like start a game with someone random and it just works.
Speaker 1: It's great.
Speaker 1: but the ROMs From that ancient ROM pack we have don't work.
Speaker 1: There's a slightly different format of ROM that everyone's been using.
Speaker 1: Interesting, so I had to go get that format and they are trivial to get even without this website.
Speaker 0: But is there some sort of convert?
Speaker 0: It feels like there could be some sort of converter where like you take an app you load a ROM in.
Speaker 1: I think you could just like move some files around like create a file of a certain kind Zip them up just the right way and it would work.
Speaker 1: I have not actually yet compared the full differences between the two to see if I could figure it out.
Speaker 0: It might not be too hard to make that app or to make just a mod for fightcade itself.
Speaker 0: Yeah automatically convert any ROM on low.
Speaker 1: I feel like this could just be a Python script that I run once.
Speaker 0: Yeah,
Speaker 1: but regardless The news here is that Nintendo went after this ROM site and they won
Speaker 0: Like they do and
Speaker 1: they've been awarded 2.1 million dollars in damages because the person running the ROM site Kind of tried to fight back and tried to like make an argument like pirates used to do in the 90s Like oh, it's not technically illegal to run this site.
Speaker 1: I didn't take okay.
Speaker 0: We'll see here.
Speaker 0: There were two problems here, right.
Speaker 0: problem.
Speaker 0: one is that this ROM site was actually not just Freely distributing ROMs or try, you know, anything like that.
Speaker 0: They were charging membership fees to people if you if you bought a membership you could basically download ROMs faster and unlimitedly and If you didn't buy a membership you could download ROMs slowly and shittily with some sort of bandwidth caps and limits.
Speaker 1: Also, most of the sites.
Speaker 0: that makes no sense, you know.
Speaker 0: First of all that makes no sense in a world where there's a torrent of all every ROM ever.
Speaker 1: Remember a lot of people are too young to know the ways of old pirates.
Speaker 0: true A lot of people have bandwidth limits.
Speaker 0: They might just need the super Metroid ROM and that's it, you know.
Speaker 0: Or they just want to put a link to the past randomizer only.
Speaker 0: they just need that one file.
Speaker 0: I don't need anything else.
Speaker 1: I found if you need just that one file You just type that file name into Google and you'll find it.
Speaker 0: Someone will DM it to you on discord.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that'll happen, too.
Speaker 0: But yeah, the discord server might ban you for asking.
Speaker 1: This site had movies and ebooks and this was just a full-on like sleazy pirate site, right?
Speaker 0: And then the second mistake the big mistake.
Speaker 0: The person decided to represent themselves in court and not get a lawyer.
Speaker 1: so there's a. there's a saying in the legal community that I encountered when I was a kid because For various reasons.
Speaker 1: I was aware of sovereign citizens when I was very young Girl up in Michigan until much later.
Speaker 1: Yeah sovereign citizens were.
Speaker 1: I encountered a few in my childhood like they were a thing and a Lawyer friend of the family who dealt with them said something that I see repeated often on the internet to this day Pro-c is Latin for bring popcorn Pro-c and it's process.
Speaker 0: I thought it's pretty after say yeah proceed.
Speaker 0: I don't know all the lawyers.
Speaker 1: I don't say I've heard both.
Speaker 0: If you see lawyers can't even agree on whether it's pleaded or pled guilty.
Speaker 1: So, uh Basically, if you do this, you don't have a lawyer.
Speaker 0: You just defend yourself in court and You can always be your own lawyer.
Speaker 0: You have the right to do that if you want.
Speaker 1: Uh, I I'm not giving legal advice.
Speaker 1: I'm not a lawyer.
Speaker 0: do not ever give you advice never do it.
Speaker 0: Do not never ever unless you and let even if you are a lawyer Right get a different lawyer to be your lawyer.
Speaker 0: I even I've seen like lawyers do that, right?
Speaker 0: I don't think I've ever.
Speaker 0: you know, it's very the kind of lawyer that you know.
Speaker 1: Well, usually when someone goes proceed they are a lawyer and usually this is a terrible decision because they're a bad lawyer.
Speaker 0: Yes, usually bad lawyers do that, right?
Speaker 0: Good lawyers get another lawyer to be their lawyer in court.
Speaker 0: They're not their own lawyer and there's a lot of raising never never be your own lawyer in court ever ever.
Speaker 0: It is it is always Almost always a bad idea.
Speaker 0: The only exception would be small claims court where I think you can't bring a lawyer.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right, but the other fascinating thing about this is this site was a massive piracy ring with a ton of crap on it But it got shut down by Nintendo.
Speaker 1: They only had that.
Speaker 1: There's a number here.
Speaker 1: There were 49 Nintendo ROMs on this site.
Speaker 0: Well, I cuz I mean most of.
Speaker 0: I mean there were probably the full NES library.
Speaker 0: But how many games in the NES library were Nintendo games right versus Capcom?
Speaker 1: Well, looks like these were mostly Nintendo switch Rob's.
Speaker 0: Oh Fancy.
Speaker 1: yeah, I'm looking at the sizing fire emblem.
Speaker 1: three houses Sid Meier's civilization six.
Speaker 1: Oh So, uh, yeah, but it was 49 games.
Speaker 1: I assumed they were all switch games.
Speaker 1: So they were to Nintendo thirty five thousand dollars for each game Saying that since he already shut the site down and was currently unemployed that figure was sufficient.
Speaker 0: Yeah, Nintendo asked for a bigger amount and they the guy was only making on the site from membership fees like 30k a year.
Speaker 1: It might have been 30k ever.
Speaker 0: Oh Okay, I can't.
Speaker 0: I just saw a 30k number.
Speaker 1: But yeah, 2.1 million Made between thirty thousand and thirty six thousand dollars.
Speaker 1: It appears that this was total in the history of the site.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so I don't understand, you know again this again, you know, don't do a crime if it's not a big enough payout To not have to keep doing crime.
Speaker 0: But also I think it shows yet again how the copyright system, you know is not Measuring the worth of things right in any sort of reasonable way.
Speaker 0: It's like the person didn't do two point one million dollars in damages, right?
Speaker 0: You know some of it's gonna just be punitive to be like.
Speaker 0: hey stop doing that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but oh they got another four hundred grand out of him for statutory trademark damages.
Speaker 0: Sure, right, but you know the most of the day, you know, did they do some damage?
Speaker 0: How many people right went to this ROM site and got ROMs and would have?
Speaker 0: Purchased a any of these games had that site not existed, right?
Speaker 1: Apparently thirty thousand dollars worth, you know, so But at the same time the fact that people I've all.
Speaker 1: I'm always amazed at the people who will pay for pirated things When often the pirate the thing you're paying for for the piracy site Doesn't really cost that much less than just buying the thing unless you're pirating a lot of things.
Speaker 1: Mmm, like a lot of people buy pirated manga.
Speaker 1: It's a host a whole thing.
Speaker 0: Now, you know, some people don't know and there's all kind of.
Speaker 0: there's all kinds of situations out there.
Speaker 1: So, uh in one last little bit we reviewed a game not too long ago March 9th 2021.
Speaker 1: So, I guess we reviewed that yesterday.
Speaker 1: the way my brain thinks Moonhunters.
Speaker 1: pretty cute game.
Speaker 1: We talked about it.
Speaker 1: It was pretty good.
Speaker 1: One of our complaints though was that the worlds you explore the actual levels where you're fighting we're very uninspired and kind of boring and slowed the game down to an unreasonable degree and
Speaker 0: The maps where you were doing the combat like yeah things when you ran into a person.
Speaker 0: it would be kind of interesting.
Speaker 0: Some of the little mini boss fights are kind of interesting But the map itself was pretty much just like this open sort of thing, you know.
Speaker 0: You just do like a depth-first search and you find everything.
Speaker 1: Yep, you know and there were it reminded me but I couldn't find a link to it then so I found it.
Speaker 1: Mammon machine wrote an article called nobody cares about it But it's the only thing that matters.
Speaker 1: pacing and level design and JRPGs back in Okay, and it breaks down like this article with some diagrams from some games that did this poorly.
Speaker 1: like All the beginner naive mistakes people make.
Speaker 1: designing levels for things like RPGs and Moonhunters is like a textbook example of how to make bad levels Mmm, like those levels are procedurally generated.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah Well, the problem is procedural generation is fine.
Speaker 1: But what was procedurally generated ended up being depth-first search.
Speaker 1: You know, what is not fun and almost any game depth-first
Speaker 0: search that
Speaker 1: is like that is almost guaranteed to make your game unfun and tedious
Speaker 0: Mmm,
Speaker 1: and this article just does a really good job of pointing out how bravely default Which made a lot of these same mistakes has some of the worst level design ever Mmm, so it's worth reading if you wanted to follow up to a review of moon chasers
Speaker 0: things Of the day,
Speaker 1: so I found this channel recently.
Speaker 1: It's just delightful.
Speaker 1: This is the really short video.
Speaker 1: They got a bunch of videos, but this is titled things in music that are the same but art If you've if you don't know anything about music, you won't understand this at all.
Speaker 1: If you know a lot about music, you will understand this video and appreciate it.
Speaker 1: but if you know a moderate amount about music like you got to the level where you can read music and you were like Why the fuck is there a double flat just to put a single flat and draw the different note?
Speaker 1: like all the weird stuff like when people talk about in augmented seconds as opposed to a minor third and like all the weird Technicalities and transposition and everything.
Speaker 1: this channel does a very good job of pointing out Exactly why all of that is funny.
Speaker 1: and I laughed out loud way too hard at this video.
Speaker 1: I'm not even gonna try to do it justice.
Speaker 1: It's a minute and 45 seconds long.
Speaker 1: just watch it and I promise if you know anything about music you will enjoy it.
Speaker 0: I Would always ask when I remember back in the middle school days, right?
Speaker 0: It's like, you know, you have it like.
Speaker 0: say you have the note a right then you got a sharp.
Speaker 0: Well, it's a little bit a little bit higher than a right between A to B. Yes between an A and a B, but a B flats between an A and a B.
Speaker 1: They're the same note.
Speaker 0: They're the same note.
Speaker 0: Why do you even have both?
Speaker 0: Why not?
Speaker 0: Just only have sharp.
Speaker 0: You will like this video a lot because the video saying that video is clearly that about that exact question.
Speaker 0: That's why I came up with it.
Speaker 1: Yep I Caught like this and they draw it the way Scott suggested And they basically their joke is something like but that'll only serve to get you.
Speaker 1: get you attacked by the people around you.
Speaker 0: Yep So yeah, so I don't like to reuse YouTube channels and things like that for thing of the day, but something extraordinary happened, right?
Speaker 0: So lock picking lawyer everyone's favorite YouTube channel The master of lock picking who doesn't do any lawyering on the channel other than to tell you don't pick locks You don't own.
Speaker 0: There was a another channel Completely unrelated to lock picking lawyer called stuff made here.
Speaker 0: I believe I think the guy's name is Shane maybe But he just makes he makes stuff.
Speaker 0: He's got a good YouTube channel.
Speaker 0: He's got like, you know, he's like seeing seeing stuff in his house, right?
Speaker 0: He's like, you know making stuff for real, right?
Speaker 0: His workshop and the idea that he came up with was that he wanted to make a lock.
Speaker 0: He's not a locksmith, but he's you know, making locks like, you know King Herb the derp No one on Tuesday geek nights, I'll get that no one on Tuesday.
Speaker 0: Nice to know that joke, but too bad.
Speaker 0: And his idea which is a genius idea, right?
Speaker 0: Now I want you to think about like you're trying to hack into a computer and you want to guess someone's password, right?
Speaker 0: Well, you type you have to type in the whole password and you either you know, if you're right or if you're wrong, right?
Speaker 0: You that's it.
Speaker 0: That's all you know, you don't know.
Speaker 0: you can't guess a password and it'll it doesn't.
Speaker 0: it's not like playing the game Mastermind where it's like, oh you got the first letter, right?
Speaker 0: You don't have the rest of them, right?
Speaker 0: It does not how it works.
Speaker 0: You're either right or wrong when you're picking a lock.
Speaker 0: Let's see you have like a six, you know, it doesn't matter which kind of lock it is.
Speaker 0: But let's say it's like a six pin tumbler lock, right?
Speaker 0: Well, you might not get all six pins But you might know all right.
Speaker 0: I got pin one at the right height.
Speaker 0: We're good with pin one.
Speaker 0: now I just get to get five more.
Speaker 0: right you can hack it When you're picking a lock.
Speaker 0: that's sort of how it works is you're you're guessing one part of the password at a time And if even if you've got, you know, if you got some parts, right and some parts wrong You know which parts you have right and you can narrow it down and break in very quickly.
Speaker 0: So the idea he had was to make a lock whereby the pins would only engage with the gate when you rotated it and So once it would once it was rotated you could no longer interact with the pins while they were over being tested by the gate.
Speaker 0: and there you couldn't do both things at the same time and Therefore you would have to guess the heights of all the pins correctly all at once and you wouldn't know which one.
Speaker 0: you would either Know if you're right or wrong, but you wouldn't know which ones were right or wrong.
Speaker 1: the way you are in a normal lock I want to say there's a kind of lock.
Speaker 1: I think it's traveling keyway.
Speaker 1: I don't know enough about locks.
Speaker 0: What do I know?
Speaker 1: but there's a kind of lock where you put a key in and you rotate the thing and the key Leaves.
Speaker 1: you don't have control over it anymore.
Speaker 1: The key itself goes deep into the lock and then tries to open itself or not.
Speaker 0: Anyway, the point is that He finally manufactured that lock to a sufficient degree.
Speaker 0: You can see there's a whole series of YouTube videos on the made stuff here channel about coming up with the idea for these locks Making them right and then finally sending off the original version and the upgraded version which is to core to lock cores.
Speaker 0: Yeah they interact with each other and Sending them to the lock picking lawyer and then the finale the the video that makes it so that we can now make it thing of the day.
Speaker 0: Lock picking lawyer received the locks and on Memorial Day open to both And then suggested improvements.
Speaker 0: and then I really wonder with those improvements I want to see if he can you know, if they're fully improved.
Speaker 0: Can he open them?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: We'll see about that now.
Speaker 0: the whole internet wants them to team up and Patent, you know the lock design and refine it and make a product right that we can then buy and put on our houses.
Speaker 0: So I think if you put this lock on your house people just bash your door in like this.
Speaker 1: Yeah Well, like a deviant.
Speaker 1: Ooh, along the other guy I follow who like is that's the kind of Infiltration lock stuff that I'm more interested in.
Speaker 1: they never pick locks and when he gives talks He talks all the time about oh, yeah, if I'm actually doing a job Picking a lock is like the 98th thing on my list of things.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna try Yep.
Speaker 0: So, yeah to his credit the maid stuff here guy because he sent a little a little tiny door along with the locks and I'm little tiny door.
Speaker 0: He Welded the hinge pins.
Speaker 0: I couldn't be popped out and the lock picking lawyer was like, oh I see you That's good because I absolutely would have tapped those.
Speaker 1: So in the meta moment We're mostly stuck inside but stay tuned for PAX East Online in July where there's a pretty good chance.
Speaker 1: You're gonna see between one and three all new panels because we only submitted either new stuff or One of them is the same title as an old panel, but it would be basically completely different content.
Speaker 0: Pax West may or may not happen.
Speaker 1: It has not been decided yet nor have we decided if we would go because we don't have enough information yet to decide that.
Speaker 0: I'm leaning heavily towards not go even if it happens, but Not only for safety reasons, but because there would not be enough time to prepare and plan for it.
Speaker 0: It's already June.
Speaker 0: I feel like it's too late to plan impacts West But the odds of packs unplugged happening are significantly greater.
Speaker 0: So that is interesting.
Speaker 0: So I'm not saying we're going to that but I'm saying the odds are Much higher that we will be at packs unplugged and I feel like well that packs unplugged will happen.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if that happens and we are there I feel like I'm gonna get there Early and do a lot of additional gaming around that packs.
Speaker 0: Yeah, maybe show up a whole day early and leave a whole day late.
Speaker 0: I don't fucking know.
Speaker 0: I got all kinds of days.
Speaker 1: All right, I got 30 vacation days.
Speaker 1: I got to use All right metamoment.
Speaker 0: the book club book is The tale of Genji.
Speaker 1: I paused only recently because I wanted to read a bunch of spider-man 2099.
Speaker 0: I read all the spider-man 20.
Speaker 0: Oh, I guess not.
Speaker 0: There's technically even more but I read all of the comic books of which the title is spider-man 2099.
Speaker 1: That's as far as I plan to go.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so I found out sadly that it ends.
Speaker 0: I didn't know this because I didn't finished it when I was a kid.
Speaker 0: Is that basically what happened?
Speaker 0: is they fired the editor because spider-man 29 was the only 2099 book.
Speaker 0: that was like selling well And the editor was editing the whole line.
Speaker 0: so they fired him and then the writers revolted basically and bailed.
Speaker 0: so Peter David's last issue is like two or three issues before the end and there's sort of a semi ending at that point And then there's a couple more issues and then another sort of end that's you know.
Speaker 0: And then that's like the end of the But then there's more.
Speaker 0: there's like a 2099 unlimited series that goes on after that and some stuff.
Speaker 1: I don't know whatever Yep, but it's warm out.
Speaker 1: I can read on the balcony.
Speaker 1: I can read at the park.
Speaker 0: I'm reading on the balcony for sure.
Speaker 0: I'm still I still think Except eat and read on the balcony.
Speaker 1: I'm confident in July.
Speaker 1: We'll do this book club book show.
Speaker 0: Maybe we'll see.
Speaker 1: It's not a slow read unless you like really obsess over it.
Speaker 0: No, it's a I can read a few chapters at a time.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean I blew through the count of Monte Cristo pretty quick back in the day.
Speaker 0: Otherwise, let's be once you get used to reading it.
Speaker 0: It reads faster.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but otherwise just stay tuned.
Speaker 1: follow us on the internet.
Speaker 1: We'll be doing things.
Speaker 1: we're doing more and more things as soon as discord stages.
Speaker 1: support video.
Speaker 1: You're gonna see us doing some live streams and some things in discord as well in the geek nights community discord.
Speaker 1: So stay tuned for all that.
Speaker 0: Also Panasonic announced a new camera.
Speaker 0: if we get it and it works then it is capable right on rims.
Speaker 0: Rims camcorder can live stream on its own with no additional equipment But it needs a wired ethernet connection to do so.
Speaker 0: the new Panasonic gh2 gh5 - that was announced can stream on Wi-Fi Directly to YouTube or twitch or even Facebook or anywhere.
Speaker 0: that's our CMP on its own with no additional hardware.
Speaker 0: You might want to use your phone as like a Wi-Fi hotspot to help it out, right?
Speaker 0: But it could just stream.
Speaker 0: I could just walk outside go to like the park turn it on and boom live stream.
Speaker 0: That's it with holding nothing else other than as long as it's Wi-Fi in the park, which there is in New York, right?
Speaker 0: So if we get that camera, you might want to follow us on our twitches.
Speaker 0: slash youtubes.
Speaker 0: cuz Spontaneous unannounced streams may happen.
Speaker 0: Yeah, cuz it'll be so easy to do.
Speaker 0: Why not?
Speaker 1: Ah, I just can't wait for that first packs, right?
Speaker 1: I'm back just dreams about nonsense.
Speaker 0: It could be anything.
Speaker 0: who knows what kinds of content.
Speaker 0: it'll be not even geek nights related.
Speaker 0: Just like hey check out the park Whatever.
Speaker 0: Let's have a good nice review this park.
Speaker 0: Relax in the park ten minutes stream Talk to me.
Speaker 1: That's our equivalent of lo-fi beats.
Speaker 1: just stream us lounging in the park.
Speaker 0: Yeah, New York New York low-vis low-vis beats.
Speaker 0: So you'll be.
Speaker 0: it'll be in 1080p.
Speaker 0: It won't be low-vis.
Speaker 1: and in the year 1999 a game called Pokemon snap was released.
Speaker 0: You did not have an end.
Speaker 0: Do you have an n64?
Speaker 1: No, I had never played.
Speaker 1: I did not play Pokemon snap during until at any point during its real run.
Speaker 1: I played it on an emulator way later.
Speaker 0: I Don't.
Speaker 0: I don't remember if like my brother my brother had the n64 by played it a bunch, right?
Speaker 0: I don't remember if he actually bought that game But I may.
Speaker 0: I think I may have played it like if not 1999 then like coming home from college at some point maybe played it in like.
Speaker 1: the thing is 2000 even though I was by the year 1999.
Speaker 1: I was like 100% PC gamer and I didn't really care about anything else except tabletop.
Speaker 0: I played.
Speaker 0: I was actually you know Most of my gaming.
Speaker 0: I keep forget, you know I keep forgetting this and then remember it's like.
Speaker 0: most of my gaming from like the late 90s through the mid 2000s was GBA DS gaming.
Speaker 1: Ah Yeah, I was.
Speaker 1: I even got the GBA late.
Speaker 1: I got when the platinum GBA came out is when I got one because my mom even you know When there was counter-strike and tribes - you know all that stuff.
Speaker 0: most of my gaming was GBA and then DS You know.
Speaker 1: and until the phone came along right pretty much once the before the n64 even came out I went full PC and never looked back And I didn't play console games again with any regularity until your game of cube.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so Pokemon snap was out But even at the time despite not playing it not having an n64 and not liking consoles.
Speaker 1: I was aware of Pokemon snap I appreciated it.
Speaker 1: I like I thought it was a brilliant idea and It was really surprising that There weren't any sequels like.
Speaker 1: it was the first Pokemon first-person shooter and they just never made another one.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the Sun I always talk about which is that?
Speaker 0: back in the early days of video games, right?
Speaker 0: There weren't so many genres right?
Speaker 0: Like I guess there was the Space Invaders genre of you know, little shoot-em-up Yeah, but it's like what genre is pac-man?
Speaker 0: what genre is Dig Dug?
Speaker 0: What genre is root beer tapper?
Speaker 1: Sorry games were like.
Speaker 1: the genres that they'd list were like sports games action games puzzle games.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like there wasn't really like.
Speaker 0: the genres may be based around the theme of the games But mechanically all those old classic games were like very very different from each other, right?
Speaker 0: You couldn't categorize the mechanically speaking the way that like you'll have today 20 different first-person shooters.
Speaker 0: They're all Visually and aesthetically completely different from each other.
Speaker 0: Yeah from cartoons to like serious warship But mechanically are all almost identical.
Speaker 0: right and not into the control schemes everything.
Speaker 0: Pokemon snap was sort of a rail shooter in a way, right but really was a Game in 1999.
Speaker 0: That was its own genre.
Speaker 0: the way that Dig Dug is its own genre, you know, it's like mechanically speaking.
Speaker 0: It's like you don't see that right.
Speaker 0: that what other what game has come out in the past you know.
Speaker 0: whenever that it you could say is its own genre.
Speaker 0: and then not only did it not sequel but No other games even like tried to copy it.
Speaker 0: yet I don't know if it was super popular but it was popular enough and it was really good and fun.
Speaker 0: and now finally in 2021 so 22 years later.
Speaker 0: Yeah They've made another one for the switch and oh my god It's pretty much.
Speaker 1: in fact, there was an article in the Seattle Times that had the best headline about this game Pokemon new Pokemon snap strikes.
Speaker 1: exactly one note.
Speaker 0: Yep, it does that well Yep, but it's like hey, there's.
Speaker 0: it's like if you released a Dig Dug in 2021.
Speaker 0: It's just you know, we're bomber.
Speaker 0: our man's his own genre, right, you know.
Speaker 1: But bar men keep getting sequels, yep, but Pokemon snap somehow didn't and I don't have a slide for it.
Speaker 1: But way back we did that panel egregiously unrealized potential where we talked about all the games that like no one ever remade.
Speaker 1: that would just probably make Ridiculous amounts of money.
Speaker 1: and we did talk about Pokemon snap a little bit but we didn't actually have a slide for it.
Speaker 1: it came up organically, but I Was surprised that it took this long.
Speaker 1: But the Nintendo switch is honestly the best possible form factor to bring this game back.
Speaker 1: No, other than VR, but VR is not accessible enough yet, right?
Speaker 0: So if you don't know anything about Pokemon snap It's a game where it's sort of a rail shooter.
Speaker 0: Like I said, right?
Speaker 0: You don't control your movement that much.
Speaker 0: You're always.
Speaker 0: you're on that.
Speaker 0: you're in this 3d world and you're always moving forward.
Speaker 0: in the original Pokemon snap I believe there's a button you could press to go forward faster, but you can never go backwards and you can never stop Unless like a Pokemon got in your way or something, which wasn't which is only in certain scenarios, right?
Speaker 0: And the current one I haven't unlocked I haven't beaten it.
Speaker 0: So I haven't gotten a move faster button yet.
Speaker 0: There may be one But you're on rails.
Speaker 0: You're just moving and you can't control where you move, but you're taking photos.
Speaker 0: You're you're a photographer.
Speaker 0: So while you're in this little bubble that just moves without beyond your control you can look around in 360 3d degrees, right Anywhere you want.
Speaker 0: you can just free.
Speaker 0: it's free.
Speaker 0: Look, you can just look wherever you like and you can take photos almost as you almost infinity photos.
Speaker 0: You do have a limit but you can just go for another ride if you run out of film and take photos again.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and you take photos of Pokemon this Pokemon fucking everywhere.
Speaker 0: They're just coming out your ears, right?
Speaker 0: You're in Pokemon land.
Speaker 0: It's Pokemon fucking everywhere.
Speaker 0: take photos of them.
Speaker 0: You know, you try to get good photos of them.
Speaker 0: You want them in the middle of the frame?
Speaker 0: You want them to get you want to get close to them?
Speaker 0: You don't want it to be like a speck on the her.
Speaker 1: I want to get all different kinds of star ratings Like catch them doing different stuff.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you want the you know, the Pokemon when it's using a special move when it's flying when it's sleeping, right?
Speaker 0: well, you know you want Pokemon in groups interacting with each other right and When you run down the track There's sort of like these.
Speaker 0: you know The Pokemon are gonna do the same thing basically every time you go down the track with the caveat
Speaker 1: that there's different like iterations of Each world where slightly different things will happen like you saw a lot of those as the game progresses
Speaker 0: But they you know the Pokemon are generally doing the same things You know in the same spots and you figure out how to manipulate the Pokemon, right?
Speaker 0: It's like well if I take a photo of this guy, for example in the original Pokemon snap I think it was.
Speaker 0: I don't remember the exact details But it's like you would take a picture of like a Magikarp and like several different spots and then when you got to the waterfall The Gyrodos would be there.
Speaker 0: But if you didn't take all those Magikarp photos on the way.
Speaker 0: if you missed one of them the Gyrodos wouldn't be there.
Speaker 1: This one has like the scanner and some of the things you scan will cause the environment to change a little bit around you.
Speaker 0: Yep, you have there's a scanner.
Speaker 1: There's the apples that you can throw at Pokemon and I love how the game goes out of its way to tell you that the Apples aren't actually apples.
Speaker 1: They're a soft light Non-harmful like special fruit that will not in any way hurt the Pokemon.
Speaker 1: but in game You're just talking apples at a Pikachu.
Speaker 0: Yeah, when you hit them they go out.
Speaker 0: they like bonk, right?
Speaker 0: They're not like, you know You see the Pokemon have been hit by it.
Speaker 1: I do enjoy that like I was throwing them at a big Pokemon and it just fucking ignored me.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there's these glowy balls that you get that are part of the lore of the game.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there's a whole story.
Speaker 1: You're trying to get the luminescent Pokemon But I mean it's Pokemon snap.
Speaker 1: the plot is about as exciting as you could expect.
Speaker 0: yeah, your research, but the thing is, you know part of the Universe of Pokemon right?
Speaker 0: is that there's so many different things you can do as a Pokemon trainer.
Speaker 0: right battling You know clothing.
Speaker 0: you're caring for your Pokemon breeding Pokemon, right?
Speaker 0: But the core is really studying Pokemon, right?
Speaker 0: It's like you're.
Speaker 0: it's always a professor right right from the beginning of Pokemon to first game.
Speaker 0: It's like Professor Oak is like we are here to study Pokemon, right?
Speaker 0: I want to learn about.
Speaker 1: none of that is really reflected in most Pokemon games.
Speaker 1: You're out fighting.
Speaker 0: No, I mean you are learning about Pokemon as you play.
Speaker 0: right.
Speaker 0: you're not doing research No, but you're in effect, right?
Speaker 0: It's like you.
Speaker 0: you got into the field.
Speaker 0: you see a Pokemon You've never seen before right?
Speaker 0: you learn what its types are right.
Speaker 0: It's like you as a player are Studying Pokemon when you play a Pokemon game, but in Pokemon snap It's more the your the activity that you're actually engaging Right your character in the game and you play regular Pokemon your character like red or whoever ash Whatever you want to call your Pokemon trainer.
Speaker 0: That's you isn't actively studying their catching battling right bicycling etc.
Speaker 0: in Pokemon snap you are actively Studying the Pokemon as your in-game activity by photographing them Observing them in their habitat like, you know a nature photographer Basically, yeah, which
Speaker 1: is extra interesting in terms of like hucking apples or pester balls or whatever that it's very much even real wildlife photography.
Speaker 1: You do things to get the animals to behave in a certain way to get the shot you want.
Speaker 0: That's yeah, it's how it is.
Speaker 0: Only you're not on rails, which is the most annoying part.
Speaker 0: It's like you can just walk around to do whatever.
Speaker 0: Yep, but I guess in terms of making this game too easy.
Speaker 1: The game is definitely designed to be playable by kids of all ages like it's very.
Speaker 1: it guides you very well and The things that are difficult don't like.
Speaker 1: if you don't get them doesn't quite prevent you from advancing.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you can definitely like even though I have been very there's like these Requests and I've got like 70 or 80 requests and I've only completed like seven of them.
Speaker 0: They're hard some of them, but it is not impeded my progress through the game.
Speaker 0: So if you suck at the game Or if you're just a child you will progress through the game and get to the end.
Speaker 0: But to be good at the game to complete requests to get all the different Pokemon and you know All the different things and bonus point get high score photos is quite challenging You know even for me, so maybe someone else out there thinks it's easy.
Speaker 0: Okay, great.
Speaker 0: It's easy for you.
Speaker 0: So I had a hard time.
Speaker 1: Yep Well, cuz it's partly a rail shooter like your your FPS thing skills actually do matter, but it's also a puzzle game.
Speaker 1: You're trying to figure out how to get the shot that you need.
Speaker 0: Yep And sometimes I know in the aiming sometimes, you know, it's like, okay I know to get this shot I have to like Throw an apple and get it to land like inside that Bidoof's dam which is a hole in the top like sort of playing Basketball.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like.
Speaker 0: you don't just aim at the top of the hole and press shoot, you know You have to arc it right and it's not easy.
Speaker 0: and the thing it keeps moving.
Speaker 0: you're constantly moving.
Speaker 0: So imagine like if you can't if you're in a car and you're not driving it You don't know what the driver is gonna do necessarily and you have to end as a basketball hoop that doesn't move.
Speaker 0: and you have infinite basketballs and you've got to get just One in there and then after you get it in there the Pokemon comes out and now you got to switch to the camera and Get a photo.
Speaker 0: the sooner you get it in the hole the sooner you get to take the photo you get more photo Opportunities for the better shot.
Speaker 0: if you get it in at the last second and the Pokemon comes out The car is already driving away.
Speaker 0: You get like this is far away shot.
Speaker 0: You got no zoom lens.
Speaker 0: It's a great but it's like.
Speaker 0: don't it.
Speaker 1: but don't underestimate the difficulty of this game because it seems like a simple concept.
Speaker 1: the game has significant challenge even for skilled gamers and also Every moat time like playing it.
Speaker 1: so far I start to get a little bored Like I go through one area too many times.
Speaker 1: Like the game is tuned very well and at the moment I feel any amount of hesitation to play again the games like oh, hey, by the way new area.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's night now there's a boss And even when there isn't a new area sometimes that it'd be like, okay, you know, you're at the the coral reef.
Speaker 0: great Well, you've got enough points in the coral reef.
Speaker 0: Guess what.
Speaker 0: coral reef is now updated to level two and you can choose whether to go through the coral reef.
Speaker 0: You know what.
Speaker 0: any location has levels now that it upgrades to when you do get enough good photos.
Speaker 0: So like you see any area starts at level one and it's like there's a few Pokemon around.
Speaker 0: Then it when you get enough good photos with a high enough total score in that area.
Speaker 0: it Unlocked that level.
Speaker 0: you can visit it at level two or level three or even higher levels.
Speaker 0: I think Depending on which area it is and when you visit an area at a higher level you see more, you know more Pokemon there You know, it starts off.
Speaker 0: There's like one bull.
Speaker 0: you come back again at level two.
Speaker 0: There's like a whole field of bulls.
Speaker 0: It's like all that You know.
Speaker 0: There's different stuff is happening and that keeps to the air as a way to keep the areas fresh even though you're revisiting the same Place over and over again, right?
Speaker 0: Imagine if you're playing counter-strike and it's like dust again.
Speaker 0: It's like nope upgraded dust Yeah, and then you play upgraded dust 20 times.
Speaker 0: It's like man.
Speaker 0: I'm bored of upgraded dust.
Speaker 0: Okay, we upgraded dust again.
Speaker 0: It's upgraded twice now.
Speaker 0: It's like whoa, it just keeps getting better.
Speaker 0: It's still dust but it's like now there's more crates.
Speaker 1: Yeah new bomb spot But I appreciate to how they kept the camera.
Speaker 1: like one Mistake a game like this could make is make the camera itself too complex.
Speaker 1: You're not fussing around with like Brightness and worrying about focal length.
Speaker 1: You can pretty much use a little bit.
Speaker 0: Come on didn't do that either exactly.
Speaker 1: But once you get the photos the game is a lot of quality of life stuff.
Speaker 1: one to make it quick Take till I get them all ranked like it has like the gates it puts around.
Speaker 1: what photos you can submit after a mission Are pretty good to keep you from sort of doing the unfun kind of min maxing that you could possibly do.
Speaker 1: You can only submit just like in the old game one image of each kind of Pokemon from that run.
Speaker 1: Yep so pick the best one from each one kind of like what I do with real photos in a pre kovat world and hopefully a Post-covid world where I sit in Lightroom and I say alright of all these pictures I took a Scott pick at his nose, which one is the one that I'm actually gonna like save and do something with.
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 0: But yeah.
Speaker 0: So the problem is is that you can sit there and you can by hand pick the best photo of each Pokemon to submit and get scored And that's kind of tedious.
Speaker 0: But if you want to win you kind of got to do it to get the best scores.
Speaker 1: Yep, but I kind of enjoy that like looking at the phone.
Speaker 1: I like looking at the four photos.
Speaker 1: I took it like some Pikachu and being like, that's the one that's gonna get me a new star.
Speaker 0: See, I'm just lazy and I'm like screw that I picked the auto option.
Speaker 0: The auto option is apparently not the way to win the game.
Speaker 0: The auto option is gonna.
Speaker 0: I don't know what its logic is But it does not always pick the best highest scoring photo of the ones you have chosen.
Speaker 0: It has some other criteria But it saves you a lot of time and you can go right back to taking photos and skip the sorting photos phase basically completely And it costs nothing to do.
Speaker 0: and it often does pick higher scoring photos Just not necessarily the best ones.
Speaker 0: So but it's there for you if that's how you want to play which is really nice.
Speaker 1: I also like how you choose like which four photos represent that Pokemon in your particular playthrough of the game.
Speaker 1: So if you hang out with someone else, they might have they'll have very different photos of that same Pokemon likely.
Speaker 0: Well, I think usually each Pokemon has like four different types of photos you can get up like like.
Speaker 0: they'll be like regular Pikachu.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I'm just coming over like often.
Speaker 1: It'll be like a regular one one where it's eating or sleeping or something one where it's doing some sort of Interaction with its environment and then one that's like hyper specific to that Pokemon.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like doing some major special attack, right?
Speaker 0: so it's like you have to get.
Speaker 0: each Pokemon has basically four photos you can get of it and then of The four photos you can get a higher point value for each of the four scenarios, right?
Speaker 0: so it's like you want to get four different photos of the Pokemon one for each category and You want to get in within each category?
Speaker 0: You want the best like the best sleeping Pikachu the best eating Pikachu the best electrifying Pikachu and the best normal Pikachu, right?
Speaker 0: So if you take like your electric one that can't count as your normal one, right?
Speaker 1: No matter how good it is It sucks when you take two really good photos of the same Pokemon in one run.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like oh, I got a great sleeping Pikachu and I get a great electric Pikachu.
Speaker 0: Which one do I submit?
Speaker 0: You know, I don't know how the auto chooses But if you're doing manually, it could be a tough choice.
Speaker 0: Yeah,
Speaker 1: and it seems to make it relatively easy by Nintendo Standards to touch up and share your photos just with people because while I'm playing this game to like play it for real I'm also taking photos of things that will not score high but are just hilarious to me.
Speaker 0: Yeah You can all.
Speaker 0: yeah, there's a lot of funny photos you can take with all the different situations the Pokemon in the way They interact with each other.
Speaker 0: It's like even though it's the same thing every time you go down that track basically unless you level it up Even you know, it's like if you go to the beach at level 3 It's always the same beach at the same level 3.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like unless you do something different It'll be exact same.
Speaker 0: things will happen Right in the exact Pokemon in the exact place at the exact times and the same thing.
Speaker 0: it's pre-programmed But it's somehow every time you go down that track different stuff happens.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you see you see something you didn't see before because the car is moving just fast enough to where you can get your photos.
Speaker 0: but if you're too slow you'll get a shittier photo or you might miss something or turns around a corner and you have to like.
Speaker 0: Sometimes you want to be looking behind you and you sort of learn by doing the same course over and over again.
Speaker 0: Okay, like okay.
Speaker 0: This is the spider.
Speaker 0: Pokemon is gonna be on the left.
Speaker 0: I'm ready for it.
Speaker 1: this time That bird's gonna swoop down right after that tree.
Speaker 0: So I guess the high level play in this game is really a memorization game of like knowing exactly What to do when to get the highest points.
Speaker 0: Yep But I'm not interested in that.
Speaker 1: Well, there's enough.
Speaker 1: like if you just play the game going for like normal scores and just try to play it the way it tells You to play it You'll just progress at a pretty natural steady comfortable pace.
Speaker 1: and so far I'm having a lot of fun with this game.
Speaker 0: You'll also discover, you know, the mysteries of the luma or whatever it is.
Speaker 0: as you're studying the Pokemon right and every each different is like these.
Speaker 0: each different area has like Or like is in a group, right?
Speaker 0: There's like several different islands.
Speaker 0: So like in each of the areas like the volcano area, I think is like, you know entry volcano In the actual lava.
Speaker 0: and then the third one is like, okay This is an area that's completely devoted to like this mega Pokemon.
Speaker 1: Yeah, these are like boss fights almost Yes, basically like a boss fight.
Speaker 0: But so you go in and you're driving around and there's only like really one Pokemon to take photos of.
Speaker 0: It's a magical Pokemon.
Speaker 0: you're trying to study and you have to sort of figure out its mysteries Right by throwing stuff and taking photos at the right times.
Speaker 1: and figuring out the mysteries is almost entirely Done by throwing stuff at these Pokemon.
Speaker 0: Well, you know, sometimes you got to figure out like this also the environment, right?
Speaker 0: It's not just the Pokemon But there's things to throw stuff at in the environment that could make stuff happen or that the Pokemon will then respond to And you can figure out their behaviors.
Speaker 0: And so it's kind of it's like a fun little nature nature ride.
Speaker 0: Yeah like You know like a safari almost right, you know, it's the original Pokemon at the Safari zone.
Speaker 0: And so when you go in those nature safaris at like, you know Disney World this kind of lay You know, it's.
Speaker 0: you're just seeing animals out there, right?
Speaker 0: You're not really.
Speaker 0: but imagine if you did that like a real person You know a real, you know zoologist or you know, whatever, you know out in the wild actually observing animals Right in your little Jeep where you drive around.
Speaker 0: That's what this is.
Speaker 0: So Yeah, I'm glad they made another one of these.
Speaker 0: it was long overdue.
Speaker 0: I think they can now wait a long while before making another one because this one will suffice for quite some time.
Speaker 1: Not only will it suffice but it's digital.
Speaker 1: It's on a switch.
Speaker 1: It's a modern world.
Speaker 1: They could easily add content to it like they do to the games like Animal Crossing.
Speaker 1: I don't think they need to but they could I bet they will just to keep people excited about it.
Speaker 1: It generates a lot of good social media.
Speaker 1: We'll see how this goes.
Speaker 0: It's not doesn't seem like the kind of game Nintendo will DLC but I do wish That Nintendo would make more games that are genres of their own the way Pokemon snap is.
Speaker 0: there aren't too many of these right, so Not that you know.
Speaker 0: there I have been other people who've made like.
Speaker 0: I've seen some indie games that are sort of in the the photo genre But not too many.
Speaker 1: I keep wanting to bring up Fatal Frame, but it's actually not it's.
Speaker 1: it's not even related to involve taking photographs.
Speaker 1: Yeah, apparently the most recent Fatal Frame was in 2014.
Speaker 1: Okay, I did not know they kept making those.
Speaker 0: I mean there was a spider-man game for Genesis.
Speaker 0: We had to take photos of all the guys.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, there was.
Speaker 0: You need photos of spider-man.
Speaker 1: But I think photography games even if they're if they're well made would either be too fiddly for a lot of people or Pokemon snaps magic is.
Speaker 1: it's not just that.
Speaker 1: it's like this simple puzzle slash photography slash first-person rail shooter game But it's also that it's the Pokemon intellectual property there.
Speaker 1: people love the Pokemon.
Speaker 1: if it was the exact same game But it was like just non-descript generic monsters.
Speaker 0: I don't think just animal real-world animals I think that would be even less popular.
Speaker 0: Yeah, probably.
Speaker 0: So Yeah, Pokemon snap.
Speaker 0: Oh, I think one last thing is that you know, obviously You know, we have created so many video games and video game.
Speaker 0: I guess infrastructure around, you know pointing guns at people Right and a camera is one of the few tools in the world that you point at things and push a button Activate right and it has sort of that same, you know, even talk.
Speaker 0: we even call it shooting, right?
Speaker 0: You know you go and you shoot photos.
Speaker 0: So it's that one of the few things we have as humans that has that sort of same.
Speaker 0: You know interactive language of point at a thing and activate it so that you can use You know a first-person shooting engine for a photography game, right?
Speaker 0: You're just replacing guns with cameras.
Speaker 0: What else can you replace guns, you know with that makes sense?
Speaker 0: Like we've had some firefighting games a little bit right, you know.
Speaker 1: Well in VR it gets interesting because I remember I was talking to some VR designers God in a time when I could go to conventions.
Speaker 1: But yeah, there was a complaint that a lot of VR like all the controllers for VR are very gun like and how they work Mm-hmm, but that is not because the games are all guns like.
Speaker 1: people make gun games.
Speaker 1: But most games on VR are not like you using a gun.
Speaker 1: It's that guns evolved to be the way they are because that is a fantastic UX for humans interacting with things generally Yep, especially anything that needs to be pointed at something.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know But you know you how?
Speaker 0: there are so many things that aren't guns that have pistol grips that you can get Right for them because that's just a way to hold a thing.
Speaker 0: That's really convenient.
Speaker 1: But I feel like a lot of interesting games that are not guns but are like in the adjacent orthogonally adjacent to things like Pokemon snap.
Speaker 1: They're arising primarily in VR right now because that's the kind of interaction that's easy to do But I think there's a lot of ground that's still left unexplored.
Speaker 1: Even just games about photography could be made that I think could eat.
Speaker 1: despite my people only care about this because it's Pokemon Complaint not complaint but observation.
Speaker 1: I think you can make games that do some of this stuff.
Speaker 1: That would be popular.
Speaker 1: I just don't think they get explored that much for a lot of reasons.
Speaker 0: It's just again.
Speaker 0: It's nice to have a game where you can get the mechanics of pointing and shooting right which is fun Just physically, but not have the metaphor of violence and murdering with guns.
Speaker 0: Which we want to you know I think is it's we have enough gun games.
Speaker 0: Do we really need any more?
Speaker 0: Really, you know portal.
Speaker 0: I guess kind of it was like okay It's a gun, but it makes portals doesn't kill.
Speaker 1: I'd say portal is very much an example of that.
Speaker 1: It's the first-person shooter where you're not shooting guns.
Speaker 0: sure it's still of it.
Speaker 0: It's still sort of.
Speaker 0: you know it's a little bit of a gun Just not completely.
Speaker 0: It's you know fires a projectile which a camera does not do.
Speaker 1: Now I just imagine counter-strike, but in the opening scroll It's just like these guns actually fire fluff bullets that look and sound and act like real bullets But are actually harmless and people just fall into a jealous sleep.
Speaker 0: so if you have a switch And you know you got to follow my policy of buy a game and download it only at the exact moment when you were going To start playing it right that way you don't buy a bunch of games and fill up your game library and never play all Games.
Speaker 0: yeah this policy has been working great for me.
Speaker 0: my steam library has basically been cleared out effectively.
Speaker 0: You know my sweet pre-order this game.
Speaker 1: one day I decided I want to play Pokemon snap And I immediately bought it.
Speaker 0: I waited until the moment where I said I'm gonna now play Pokemon snap And I bought it installed it and played at that moment.
Speaker 1: right all one two three well It took a little while to download, but then I saw I actually bought a physical copy because I imagine I might sell it or give it away at some point.
Speaker 0: But anyway I recommend you follow that policy.
Speaker 0: but also Yeah, if you have a switch and at any moment you're sitting there, and you're like man I'd like to play a single-player game right now, and I'm not any of the ones that are on my switch.
Speaker 0: I'm not too excited about.
Speaker 0: I recommend Pokemon snap.
Speaker 0: that is a good choice.
Speaker 1: if you liked the original Pokemon snap It's the same goddamn game, and if you've never played the original well.
Speaker 1: This is a unique experience You're not gonna.
Speaker 0: don't really need to play.
Speaker 0: I don't know you need to play the original like you can see it on YouTube.
Speaker 1: I think there's any reason to play the original.
Speaker 0: you can't mean it's still fun If you really want more, but the newer one is I think just better.
Speaker 0: Smoother.
Speaker 0: you know easier right, but you know the original.
Speaker 0: I think the value I guess of the original one would be It still holds up You know just not as good.
Speaker 0: But also the Pokemon in it are gonna be more of the earlier gen Pokemon in that first one.
Speaker 0: So it depending how old you are right your nostalgia level now.
Speaker 0: those Pokemon in that first one Which are mostly or maybe entirely gen 1 Pokemon if I'm not mistaken?
Speaker 0: Might appeal to you more than this one which has Pokemon across many generations.
Speaker 1: So I just learned something that I can't believe I didn't know Pokemon snap the original was not a Pokemon game.
Speaker 1: It was intended to be some other game to use some peripheral.
Speaker 0: I do remember this now.
Speaker 1: It's Jack and the Beanstalk thing.
Speaker 0: Yeah, okay.
Speaker 0: I think I remember this.
Speaker 1: it was developed at hell.
Speaker 1: There's a whole story here.
Speaker 1: I'm not just gonna read a Wikipedia to you But basically the game was like this Jack and the Beanstalk thing intended to use the 64 DD peripheral for the Nintendo 64 and Later the game freak.
Speaker 1: There's a whole story where they were like oh We need a Pokemon game and they came to some sort of deal.
Speaker 1: But that that Jack and the Beanstalk game was just a failure.
Speaker 1: it wasn't gonna come out.
Speaker 1: So they just decided to take that game turn it into a Pokemon spin-off, and that's what Pokemon snap became.
Speaker 0: Very nice, okay.
Speaker 0: I think also just worth noting there is I've seen oh, there's a quote from a water.
Speaker 1: Originally Pokemon snap for the Nintendo 64 wasn't a Pokemon game, but rather a normal game in which you took photos.
Speaker 1: But the motivation for playing the game wasn't clear.
Speaker 1: We wondered what players would enjoy taking pictures of and later we made a somewhat forced switch to making them take pictures of Pokemon.
Speaker 0: okay, but there is a heart.
Speaker 0: you can't find it, but There's like a hardware Pokemon snap arcade thing and I think it prints photos.
Speaker 0: I was never entirely sure.
Speaker 0: I've seen the device like in the wild.
Speaker 0: it looks like a little like kiosk of Pokemon snap.
Speaker 0: I don't know if you can like play Pokemon snap on it and print photos or put an n64 memory card in it or something.
Speaker 0: But there is some sort of Pokemon snap arcade ish hardware thing And you can probably google find a YouTube video of someone demoing it.
Speaker 0: that would explain it because I've only seen that it exists.
Speaker 0: I've never used it, and I don't know anything else about it, but if you're really into it It's worth probably worth investigating.
Speaker 1: yep, and I think they did something.
Speaker 1: they did some events.
Speaker 1: I don't know if you can still get this but some particular Line of mini printer.
Speaker 1: we had a thing with a special app that will just print your Pokemon Photos like.
Speaker 1: it's a Polaroid.
Speaker 0: that might have been related to the arcade device thing.
Speaker 1: Maybe yeah, it was part of a promotion.
Speaker 1: There's a whole thing here that I'm skimming but the reality is the game's just good.
Speaker 0: just play it Don't worry about all that other stuff Mm-hmm, and if you get good funny Pokemon photos right share them around.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know Photoshop.
Speaker 1: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 0: be sure to visit our website At front row crew comm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 1: remember geek nights is not one But four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 0: Geeknights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 1: But unlike those other late shows it's actually recorded at night and the patreon patrons for this episode of geek nights are Heidi McNichol Alan Joyce Linky G dread living Tenderberry Chris Reimer Clinton Walton just like a dude guy.
Speaker 1: Program thread open speed undertake law adoption.
Speaker 1: peers absorb.
Speaker 1: Rebecca Dunn.
Speaker 1: review mad bull 34 cowards Ryan Perrin Sam Erickson Shervin Von Hurl Taylor Braun.
Speaker 1: You hold the key to my heart at a bunch of people who do not want me to say their names.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's nice weather outside.
Speaker 1: We'll be doing a lot of stuff outside.
Speaker 1: You might see us record these upcoming packs online panels in person.
Speaker 1: So stay tuned for that.
Speaker 1: But for now I leave you with.