Speaker 1: It's Thursday, May 6th, 2021.
Speaker 1: I'm Rym.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott.
Speaker 1: And this is Geek Knives.
Speaker 1: Tonight we're talking about learning languages.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: Oh shit, do you have an opening bid?
Speaker 1: Uh... I guess I did.
Speaker 1: I got one.
Speaker 0: One second.
Speaker 0: Let me remember it.
Speaker 1: I had it.
Speaker 1: Right, you said you had one.
Speaker 1: You said it.
Speaker 1: Why was it?
Speaker 1: If you forgot it, I can start with something.
Speaker 1: I feel like I should leave this in the show this time.
Speaker 1: This fumbling.
Speaker 0: What the fuck was the opening bid?
Speaker 1: Can I talk about my rim light in more detail?
Speaker 1: No.
Speaker 1: I could set the rim light to make it look like there's just a fireworks show going on behind me.
Speaker 1: You got nothing?
Speaker 0: I forget my opening bid.
Speaker 1: That feels very, like, near the end of COVID lockdown feels.
Speaker 0: Oh, I thought of a different opening bid.
Speaker 1: Alright, I'm just assuming that's the first one that you originally thought of.
Speaker 0: It's not.
Speaker 0: It's definitely a different one.
Speaker 1: Alright, go for it.
Speaker 1: I stuck a marker in.
Speaker 0: Alright.
Speaker 1: Did you forget this one too?
Speaker 0: No.
Speaker 0: I'm just figuring out how to start it off contextually.
Speaker 0: So way back in the day...
Speaker 1: Wait, which day?
Speaker 1: There were a lot of days.
Speaker 1: There were the college days.
Speaker 0: It's actually a long time ago, but it feels like less of a long time ago, but it's actually quite long ago.
Speaker 0: There was a store in Manhattan called Broadway Panhandler.
Speaker 0: It was a store where you would buy kitchen stuff, right?
Speaker 0: Panhandler, get it, lol?
Speaker 0: And, you know, the chef's knife that I have in my kitchen, I bought at that store.
Speaker 0: That's how long I've had it.
Speaker 0: I was living in Beacon at the time.
Speaker 0: I just went down there, like, after work to buy, you know, kitchen stuff.
Speaker 0: That store has been closed a long time.
Speaker 0: But I would also go there to get my knife sharpened, you know?
Speaker 1: Yeah, like you do.
Speaker 0: There were knife experts there, and it cost, like, a few bucks.
Speaker 1: It cost a few bucks, and it's not hard to sharpen a knife, but it takes an amount of time, and it costs so little to just get someone else to do it.
Speaker 0: Sure.
Speaker 0: The last time I needed my knife sharpened... You know, basically, it's one of those things, like, I don't get it done as often as I should, especially in the COVID times, right?
Speaker 0: It was already needed to be sharpened, and then, you know... I brought one to the place that's right near RIM, the Saito Trading Company.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah!
Speaker 1: We're actually, we're planning to head down there and get a bunch of our knives sharpened, and also, there's a new knife we want.
Speaker 0: No, they did okay, you know, but it wasn't like, oh my god, the knife is, like, slicing paper, like, magically, right?
Speaker 0: So, I've always wanted to be able to sharpen a knife, you know, with the whetstone, like they do on YouTube, and, you know, they're, like, it becomes ridiculously sharp.
Speaker 0: But also, you know, it's like I'm so worried, like, oh, it takes such skill, it's like you're gonna, you know, mess up the knife or whatever.
Speaker 0: But, yeah, I just was, like, you know what, I'll just do it, right?
Speaker 0: I'll buy the, I'm watching YouTube videos, I bought the cheapest, well, not the cheapest, but, you know, a relatively inexpensive, highly rated one, you know, little whetstone set.
Speaker 0: I watched a bunch of YouTube videos, the instructions that came with the set even said to watch YouTube videos.
Speaker 1: That's the future!
Speaker 0: You know, and, you know, it turned out okay, knives are sharper, you know, but they're not, like, you know, ridiculously sharp like they are in the videos.
Speaker 0: So, I guess I have to practice more, but, you know, I'll try it again in some months from now, right?
Speaker 0: But I guess, do I recommend it?
Speaker 0: Eh, maybe.
Speaker 1: I mean, it's one of those things, like, when we shifted from using cartridge razors to safety razors, Well, that's a different situation entirely.
Speaker 1: Because shaving with those was both easier and it saved me, like, I stopped counting after it had saved me several thousand dollars.
Speaker 0: It's not, it's not only, it saves you a lot of money and it's better.
Speaker 0: This is not saving you that much money.
Speaker 1: And not better unless you get good at it.
Speaker 0: It's only better if you get really good at it.
Speaker 1: It's funny because we were literally having the same conversation, but because they're downstairs from us, the barrier to just, like, walking over there with a knife and being like, "Here's a $1.50, please sharpen
Speaker 1: this.".
Speaker 0: Yeah, pretty much.
Speaker 1: Like, I could just walk, I could walk down there in the middle of cooking if I needed to.
Speaker 0: I wouldn't do that.
Speaker 1: If I was desperate, my knife was just a, I don't know, just a steak.
Speaker 0: But yeah, you know, I think if you don't care about your knife, like, losing more material, you know, because I, you know, the whetstone sharpening, you're getting it A, sharper, and B, you're losing less knife material.
Speaker 0: But if you just use, like, the electric sharpeners or those other various kinds of sharpening devices that aren't whetstones, like, they'll still make your knife sharp, you'll just lose more material, and they won't be as sharp as, like, the perfect whetstone sharpening.
Speaker 0: But who, does that matter to you?
Speaker 1: Yeah, the thing I definitely always want to be able to do is hone correctly, because that'll at least keep a knife, like, working pretty well.
Speaker 0: If you hone every time you use it.
Speaker 0: But honing is completely unrelated.
Speaker 1: Exactly, but you gotta do both.
Speaker 1: You gotta sharpen them occasionally, and you also gotta hone them.
Speaker 0: Sometimes you don't need to hone.
Speaker 1: True, like, don't hone a serrated knife.
Speaker 0: Well, yeah, but usually it's the knives with softer steel need honing because the tip will, you know, bend around, right?
Speaker 0: But if a knife is made with really hard steel, and you don't need to hone it because the burr isn't, like, moving, it's so hard, it's not going anywhere.
Speaker 1: This, uh, weirdly gave me a specifically and strong memory.
Speaker 1: When I was in high school, me and Ken had to make a video about, uh, like, Macbeth.
Speaker 1: And, uh, we're gonna make this video.
Speaker 1: It's part of a class project.
Speaker 1: We needed swords to fight with, and we were, you know, we're both nerds who have real swords, and of course we're not gonna use our real swords, because they're, you know, they're "real" swords.
Speaker 1: And also, we'll just die.
Speaker 1: Like, that'll be a problem.
Speaker 1: So, we're not gonna choreograph something good.
Speaker 1: So, we went to a Home Depot, and we bought two bars of, like, cheap, mild steel, and just put hafts on 'em, and used those.
Speaker 1: Just, like, imagine a sword.
Speaker 1: that was not, it was just a piece of metal that was flat on all sides.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 1: That's the extent of that.
Speaker 1: I had that weird, long piece of metal with a hilt on it for some reason for years, and every now and then, I'd find it again, or someone would find it again and be like, "What the fuck is
Speaker 1: this?".
Speaker 1: That's the extent of my anecdote.
Speaker 1: So, let's get into the news.
Speaker 1: There's a bunch of stuff going on.
Speaker 1: Obviously, some things we're gonna save for, like, a Monday or a Tuesday episode of Geek Nights, but I do want to talk about this one.
Speaker 1: There's a situation going on with the COVID vaccines that you might have seen some talk about, but didn't really understand.
Speaker 1: Basically, the vaccines were made by private companies, even though that's a problem, so they have patents on these vaccines.
Speaker 1: So, no one else can make these vaccines without licensing that.
Speaker 0: Or getting sued.
Speaker 0: Or being in a country where that law can't touch them and just do it anyway.
Speaker 1: And a huge percentage of the world does not have ready access to the vaccine.
Speaker 1: Even countries like Germany and Europe don't have, like, full access yet.
Speaker 1: The U.S.
Speaker 1: is, for other reasons we've talked about, way ahead on deploying.
Speaker 0: They can't make their own.
Speaker 0: Private companies in those countries, if they make their own, might get sued for violating the intellectual property rights.
Speaker 0: So, they just have to buy some from us.
Speaker 0: The same way that so many countries just buy weapons from us.
Speaker 0: They're not making missiles.
Speaker 0: They buy our missiles and we sell them to them.
Speaker 1: So, it was a moderately big deal in that it was good, but I also want to make it clear that it's not nearly good enough.
Speaker 1: But it was good that the U.S.
Speaker 1: actually said, "We supported waiving the intellectual property rights at least until COVID is under
Speaker 1: control.".
Speaker 0: Like, little baby steps.
Speaker 0: By whose definition of "under control," right?
Speaker 0: But that's another...
Speaker 1: Yeah, but probably this would be a multi-year thing, like the way it was looking.
Speaker 0: It would still be good.
Speaker 1: The stock on the vaccine companies plummeted on that news.
Speaker 0: Well, okay, so it depends, right?
Speaker 0: A, yes, it did go down, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, I was going to talk about how then it went back up.
Speaker 0: Well, it's not even that it went back up.
Speaker 0: It's like, yeah, it went down.
Speaker 0: But if you zoom out on the graph to Pfizer over past five years, ten years, the amount it went down was basically insignificant.
Speaker 0: It did cause it to go down, but the amount it went down, not really making the Pfizer shareholders worry.
Speaker 1: But there were drops of like 12-13% for some of these companies.
Speaker 1: So, those stocks rebounded significantly after what happened now, where Germany has come out saying they do not support waiving these intellectual property rights.
Speaker 0: I guess Germany just hates themselves?
Speaker 1: Angela Merkel weighed in saying basically that it would create "severe complications" for the production of vaccines, which, that's ridiculous.
Speaker 1: The complication causing us to not have vaccines is that these companies are private in the first place.
Speaker 1: Capitalism should have nothing to do with basic medical technology.
Speaker 1: The fact that governments aren't funding this solely for the benefit of humanity is egregious and is arguably just straight up violence.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean, I've been saying the same thing for a while since I learned it from someone else, which is that, like, do you believe in democracy?
Speaker 0: If you don't, well then, don't worry about this conversation, right?
Speaker 0: But if you believe in democracy that people collectively should decide how our society operates, right?
Speaker 0: Then whatever mechanism you have for your democracy, A, should be actually democratic, not like what most countries have.
Speaker 0: Ours especially.
Speaker 1: Ours especially right now.
Speaker 0: Yes, especially.
Speaker 0: But B, that that democratically elected institution, whatever form it takes, must be the most powerful organization there is.
Speaker 0: There's no other organization of any form or shape or size in the society must be able to challenge the power of the democratically elected organization because otherwise you don't have democracy anymore, right?
Speaker 0: It's like we elected this government, even if you had the best elections that were so fairly and properly conducted, you elect this government that accurately represents the will of the people.
Speaker 0: If there's some private company that, like, not even necessarily is in total more powerful than the whole government, but has any sort of leverage against the government whatsoever, then that means that the will of the people is at least partially overrun or at odds with some other non-democratic power.
Speaker 1: Case in point.
Speaker 0: That means you don't have democracy.
Speaker 0: So therefore, any organization, including, say, a farmer's school company in this case, that has enough power to sort of, you know, change or move the government and, you know, compete with the will of the people cannot be allowed to exist if you believe in democracy.
Speaker 1: There is an incident that happened in the United States where literally a rich dude bailed out the US federal government.
Speaker 0: Like, that happened once.
Speaker 0: That also includes an individual person.
Speaker 0: If an individual person is so powerful that they can, you know, affect the government.
Speaker 1: Well, it's like in Blades in the Dark.
Speaker 1: There are factions.
Speaker 1: Like, there's a faction, like the Bluecoats or the Grinders that all have their different deals and they have different tiers.
Speaker 1: There's one faction that's just one fucking dude.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: And there's also things like it doesn't even have to be private organizations, right?
Speaker 0: The NYPD is strong enough.
Speaker 0: It's a public organization.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: But it is strong enough to basically oppose.
Speaker 0: It's not democratically elected directly.
Speaker 0: You know, they're like employees, yet they're powerful enough to influence the mayor more than the voters are.
Speaker 1: Can you imagine how radically different in a positive way New York City would be if we elected the cops?
Speaker 0: Sure.
Speaker 1: And took away their guns, of course.
Speaker 1: But if they were elected by the people of their boroughs.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: If you believe in democracy, there cannot be any organization of any kind that is more powerful in any way than the democratically elected organization.
Speaker 0: The end.
Speaker 1: So in some other news, YouTube's TikTok clone shorts, it's actually been around for a while, but it wasn't really available in the US, is out.
Speaker 1: You can do it.
Speaker 1: Scott made one already.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So there was YouTube short.
Speaker 0: Basically, you know, it's like TikTok.
Speaker 0: I'm actually kind of like.
Speaker 0: the thing with TikTok is the app itself.
Speaker 0: I'm not liking the user interface or anything and I don't like the owners of it.
Speaker 1: I don't like the sense, the nature of the censorship on that platform.
Speaker 0: Exactly.
Speaker 0: However, and I won't install it on any of my devices.
Speaker 1: Oh, I would not install TikTok on my phone.
Speaker 0: But I will visit the website.
Speaker 0: The website is, you know, I can just visit the website.
Speaker 1: Usually I watch TikToks that people have exported and put up on YouTube, to be honest.
Speaker 0: That is also the most of what I do as well.
Speaker 0: But I have visited the website a couple of times or seen embeds and such.
Speaker 0: But I do greatly enjoy the content on TikTok, the community of people who are making content there and the things they are making.
Speaker 0: There's really good stuff going on there.
Speaker 1: Well, just like Vine.
Speaker 1: Vine was like...
Speaker 0: TikTok is like Vine plus plus.
Speaker 0: It's like another level.
Speaker 1: Vine was such a creative explosion and a sea change.
Speaker 1: And also Vine was a place where black creators in particular really exploded and like made a movement of art.
Speaker 0: Sure.
Speaker 0: One of my favorite TikTok things I've seen actually is there's a guy who is a actual dermatologist.
Speaker 0: And he does, he has a TikTok where he basically does all kinds of different things.
Speaker 0: Like he'll watch people, you know, do skincare stuff.
Speaker 0: And he'll be like, "Right.
Speaker 0: Wrong.
Speaker 0: Don't do that.
Speaker 1: Do
Speaker 1: this.".
Speaker 0: And then he also will like, he'll do reactions to like people popping giant zits or scraping gross stuff off their face, which is always weird.
Speaker 0: I know we have some friends that enjoy that stuff a lot.
Speaker 0: For me, I sort of mix enjoy it.
Speaker 0: A part of me...
Speaker 1: I got the same feeling.
Speaker 1: It's like on one hand, I'm fascinated and I like to see strange, even terrifying things.
Speaker 1: But on the other hand, enjoy is not a word I would use to describe that feeling.
Speaker 0: Exactly.
Speaker 0: It's like eating a food.
Speaker 0: It's like sweet and sour.
Speaker 0: Well, I guess sweet and sour just tastes good.
Speaker 1: Well, you know, it's like when I got my vaccine, I had the side effects for a day.
Speaker 1: Like I wouldn't say I enjoyed it, but I appreciated how unique that experience was.
Speaker 0: Appreciate, but do not necessarily enjoy.
Speaker 0: I'm simultaneously feeling satisfaction, like the same satisfaction you get when you watch a power washing video while also feeling like gross.
Speaker 0: Like I just saw some gross.
Speaker 0: And it's like they mix that together at the same time.
Speaker 1: But part of it is I've definitely I've seen enough terrifying, gross, frightening things.
Speaker 0: You don't need to watch any well in real life to where.
Speaker 1: if it's not present in the room with me, it's very hard to push me over the line anyway.
Speaker 0: But yeah, I enjoy TikTok content.
Speaker 0: So I was excited at the prospect of YouTube shorts because I'm OK.
Speaker 0: I'm more OK with YouTube than TikTok as a thing.
Speaker 1: That more there is a load bearing word.
Speaker 1: I'm glad you stuck that in.
Speaker 0: It's a very low bearing more.
Speaker 0: And so YouTube shorts is basically just TikTok, except it makes a YouTube video when you're done.
Speaker 0: It's been out in India for a while.
Speaker 0: It's I think it's big there.
Speaker 1: Well, it's big there because TikTok is banned there.
Speaker 0: Oh, interesting.
Speaker 0: And then they were they brought it in like in beta to the US a little bit.
Speaker 0: But now it's.
Speaker 0: now it's everyone.
Speaker 0: It's still beta.
Speaker 0: But for everyone, I think you can now just make YouTube shorts.
Speaker 0: So in terms of watching, I still think TikTok has the ones to watch, but I'm not going to make TikTok because I'm not going to install the app.
Speaker 0: So I made a YouTube short.
Speaker 0: Let's see if I can come up with any more.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Young Rim, like I said in the forum, would have said on this show, I'm going to make one a week no matter how bad it is.
Speaker 1: Aged Wiser Rim is just going to say you might see me make a TikTok short at some point.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like I got to think of something that fits in 15 seconds.
Speaker 0: It's like it's not easy.
Speaker 1: Oh, so I actually went back because I knew TikTok was banned in India, but I didn't know the full story.
Speaker 1: It's because of that border clash between India and China.
Speaker 1: India banned a whole swath of basically any apps that were owned by certain Chinese companies.
Speaker 0: OK.
Speaker 1: That's what's going on there.
Speaker 0: And Google stepped in and beat Facebook to the race there to grab the dropped baton or whatever.
Speaker 1: I feel like if you're going to make YouTube shorts, like if the short videos are going to explode in a big way, like beyond what's happened with TikTok, focus on a niche that is underserved.
Speaker 1: I want to see indie RPG shorts.
Speaker 0: I do think that that is the.
Speaker 0: if you look at the people on TikTok who are successful is they find a niche and stick to it.
Speaker 0: And that's how they're able to make so much content is doing the same thing over and over.
Speaker 0: If you try to do variety, it's like like us, you run out of ideas.
Speaker 0: You need one idea that's popular and just keep doing it like the less sausage YouTube channel.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Hydraulic press YouTube channel.
Speaker 0: What can I?
Speaker 1: what can what do I do so frequently?
Speaker 0: Lawyer doesn't need new ideas.
Speaker 0: He just needs new locks.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I guess the best I could do is I could try to do something with my me failing at Overwatch.
Speaker 1: I'll figure something out.
Speaker 1: I'll make something.
Speaker 0: Exactly.
Speaker 1: Anyway, in some other news, Twitter actually has done a couple of things recently.
Speaker 1: They added a tip jar, which is there's.
Speaker 1: there's some stuff going on with that.
Speaker 1: We'll see how it plays.
Speaker 0: I mean, adding a tip jar on Twitter.
Speaker 0: It's like people are talking about it, but it's like you can already just put your coffee link, you know, coffee link or your your Patreon link in your profile.
Speaker 0: It's like what's what's now.
Speaker 0: it's like some people can get this tip jar like officially lit up in the Twitter interface.
Speaker 0: It's not very different.
Speaker 1: Pretty sure they're doing it this way because it's a trial balloon for even more features related to this down the road.
Speaker 0: Some people like their cash app IDs up there.
Speaker 1: Remember, Twitter was talking about having the option to have some of your tweets or an alternate channel that are subscriber only that cost them money.
Speaker 1: Like you have to pay to subscribe.
Speaker 0: That'd be OK.
Speaker 0: You know, you have a Patreon integration.
Speaker 1: I'd be 100 percent OK with that, because Twitter's biggest problem.
Speaker 0: You're going to see more tweets from me than other people see.
Speaker 1: Because Twitter's biggest problem is that it doesn't charge the users or the creators.
Speaker 1: It makes money with ads and bullshit.
Speaker 1: Come up with a better monetization model.
Speaker 1: I'm always in favor of models that involve having the people pay for the thing they use.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I am.
Speaker 0: But I read a thing today written by a guy who works for Google on ads and he's like, why I'm OK working on ads.
Speaker 0: And obviously I disagreed with most of it.
Speaker 0: But the one thing he said is like, look, you know, if you don't have ads, then a lot of this content is like has no way to pay for it.
Speaker 0: And it won't exist.
Speaker 0: And would you rather have, you know, look at how much of a problem it is that, you know, the real news is behind a paywall and no one sees it.
Speaker 0: And the fake news is just out there.
Speaker 1: But the problem there is not ads and no ads.
Speaker 1: The problem there is capitalism.
Speaker 1: You can't make money doing anything.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: If you didn't have the ads, the fake news wouldn't be there at all, which is, I think, good.
Speaker 0: But also no one would get the real news.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: But also the ads to a degree are just shifting who you're stealing the money from?
Speaker 1: because the advertisers are in many cases getting ripped off.
Speaker 1: Anyway, we've talked about that a lot.
Speaker 1: So this isn't like earth shattering news.
Speaker 1: Twitter did something else that I always.
Speaker 1: it amazed me why people were so mad about this for so long.
Speaker 1: Maybe just because I follow a lot of artists who were like oddly persnickety about it.
Speaker 1: Twitter had a cropping algorithm that would just crop images.
Speaker 1: If you post an image, it'll crop it.
Speaker 1: So it fits on your phone app, whatever you're looking at Twitter where you couldn't control the crop.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: But if you click out an image, you see the whole image anyway.
Speaker 0: Sure.
Speaker 1: If I see an image on Twitter, I'm going to click.
Speaker 0: The crop was sometimes unfortunate.
Speaker 1: Well, so the problem with the crop algorithm was that it tried to be too clever.
Speaker 1: It ended up doing some like very obviously racist things.
Speaker 0: It also did that, yes.
Speaker 1: And it did some unfortunate things.
Speaker 1: They probably could have gotten away with just having it always crop the top half of the image and just let people deal.
Speaker 1: That would probably work better.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 1: But apparently they got rid of it.
Speaker 1: But also I'm seeing a lot of people freaking out that they still see the cropping.
Speaker 1: And I think a lot of people...
Speaker 0: They only got rid of it on the mobile app.
Speaker 0: If you're using desktop app or tweet deck or something else, you're not going to see, you're going to still get in whatever cropping you've got based on whatever app you're using.
Speaker 0: Because, you know, I'm pretty sure the cropping is happening locally.
Speaker 0: And this is a great time to say if Twitter is, you know, an OK place to be.
Speaker 0: I'm on Twitter.
Speaker 0: I use Twitter a lot.
Speaker 0: Do not use the default Twitter website.
Speaker 0: Do not use the default Twitter app.
Speaker 0: Just uninstall that shit.
Speaker 0: Go and get some third party Twitter app.
Speaker 0: I mean, tweet deck is owned by Twitter, but it might as well be a third party app, at least still for now.
Speaker 0: Who knows?
Speaker 0: It might change.
Speaker 0: You know, on your iPhone, you can get Tweetbot.
Speaker 0: It's a very, very cheap subscription.
Speaker 0: It's like you're using Twitter that much.
Speaker 0: It's like this is cheaper than anything.
Speaker 0: It's so inexpensive.
Speaker 0: And if you get it, you will see only tweets from people you follow in reverse chronological order and no ads and no bullshit.
Speaker 0: And you can block and mute people.
Speaker 1: Well, you're going to see bullshit.
Speaker 1: It is Twitter.
Speaker 1: I mean, sure, sure.
Speaker 0: But the point is, do not use the official Twitter apps ever.
Speaker 0: The website, the real app, do not use them.
Speaker 0: They're garbage.
Speaker 0: All the bad things you hate about Twitter, a lot of it is because you're using those apps.
Speaker 0: Do not use them.
Speaker 0: Use the third party.
Speaker 1: In a minor news, I don't put a lot of stock in these things because they're a lot like the Academy Awards.
Speaker 1: The Michelin stars are arbitrary.
Speaker 1: They definitely have a European centric focus.
Speaker 1: There's a lot of problems with them.
Speaker 0: If you don't know, my feeling on them was if a place has them, it's probably really tasty frickin food, probably.
Speaker 1: But a place not having it does not mean it's not great food.
Speaker 0: Not at all.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: It's like but, you know, I'm not good.
Speaker 0: I'd ever.
Speaker 0: it was mostly a thing to like, you know, it ended up because it started as like, you know, literally a travel guide.
Speaker 0: Like you're traveling somewhere.
Speaker 0: There's no Google Maps, you know, will help you figure out which restaurants to go to.
Speaker 1: Remember traveling when there is no way to know the deal of any restaurant in advance.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: You know, like those placemats at the diner would tell you about all the places in town.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Hole to nowhere.
Speaker 1: Yellow pages.
Speaker 0: AAA would help you.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Travel agents, you know, they tell you what was going on in places.
Speaker 0: And that's why it existed.
Speaker 0: But it ended up becoming this thing where, you know, no one's using it as a travel guide anymore.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Instead, it became a target for restaurants to hit.
Speaker 0: You know, the what's the what's the principle called?
Speaker 0: Which I can think of a measure ceases to become a measure.
Speaker 0: It becomes a right.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I don't.
Speaker 1: I find whatever that is on the tip of my tongue.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: But also that.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So a restaurant will try to cater itself to the taste of the people who judge this to try to get on the list instead of necessarily catering to.
Speaker 1: I'm not saying what would be good, but what could be good, but does not cater to them.
Speaker 1: The same thing happened with wine.
Speaker 1: Wine over time.
Speaker 1: High end wine has catered to the kinds of people who are rich enough to afford high end wine and write about high end wine, thus causing a feedback loop that caused high end wine to get more like that.
Speaker 0: Superhero comics catered to the nerds who bought ten variant covers.
Speaker 1: But there's a paragraph in this article that points out one of the biggest reasons why I'm not a big fan of the Michelin stars.
Speaker 1: Quote, "With the exception of Jeju Noodle Bar, no ramen or ramyun spot has earned a star in the city, nor is any barbecue spot, pizzeria, food truck, taco stand, modern Vietnamese fare, or scores of other culinary styles New York is famous
Speaker 1: for.".
Speaker 0: Note, zero taco places.
Speaker 0: No.
Speaker 0: Well, well, well.
Speaker 1: With the exception of Casa Enrique, the city's starred Mexican restaurants are chic and expensive.
Speaker 1: This is why I'm bringing this up.
Speaker 1: Years and years and years ago when we lived here, a little tiny Mexican place opened up that was a spinoff of a French place, like same kitchen.
Speaker 1: They were cool.
Speaker 1: people called Casa Enrique, and it was just really good Mexican food, like really good Mexican food.
Speaker 1: And it was cheap.
Speaker 1: Like not cheap by like a real scale, but for New York scale, like for as good as this food was, it cost as much as like a normal restaurant in a normal non New York city place.
Speaker 0: Normal night out prices.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So it got a Michelin star years ago.
Speaker 0: Just one, not, not all three.
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 0: And there's also the half star, the bib gourmand half star.
Speaker 1: But Casa Enrique has maintained, they got the Michelin star again.
Speaker 1: They keep getting it.
Speaker 1: But the cool thing is they never raise their prices or change their menu.
Speaker 1: They just keep doing what they're doing.
Speaker 1: The only thing that changed is I haven't eaten there since, because I can't get in.
Speaker 1: There is like a multi-hour wait.
Speaker 1: They won't take reservations.
Speaker 1: A few weeks ago, they started doing delivery.
Speaker 0: Oh baby.
Speaker 1: I ordered some tacos, and not only did they do delivery, they deliver so fast, like 25 minutes your tacos arrive.
Speaker 1: And they're the same Michelin star Casa Enrique tacos.
Speaker 0: Now Casa Enrique is, I'd say, it's fantastic.
Speaker 0: I love to eat their delicious food, right?
Speaker 0: Great, great restaurant.
Speaker 1: It's not my favorite Mexican food, but it's one of my favorite Mexican restaurants.
Speaker 0: Exactly.
Speaker 0: I would, like I'm not even joking, right?
Speaker 0: Obviously the Cafe Maya in Fishkill, New York.
Speaker 1: Yucatan Mexican food.
Speaker 0: Oh my god.
Speaker 0: I would rather eat that.
Speaker 0: It's that dessert.
Speaker 0: If Casa Enrique is one star, then Cafe Maya is two star.
Speaker 0: And also in Manhattan, there's Tacos Numero Uno.
Speaker 1: Oh yeah.
Speaker 0: Tacos Numero Uno?
Speaker 0: I don't want to say, it's not a full restaurant.
Speaker 0: It's more of like a walk-in, grab-and-go kind of place.
Speaker 0: It's almost like a truck that's inside, but it's a little more than that, right?
Speaker 0: It's like, you know, but it's just like a takeout, quick-eaty place.
Speaker 0: But the taco there specifically, right, is better than like the taco basically anywhere.
Speaker 0: It's like, I don't know, I don't think you could make a taco better than the taco at Tacos Numero Uno.
Speaker 0: And I've heard Mexican people agree, right?
Speaker 0: And that has no Michelin stars that I'm aware of.
Speaker 0: It doesn't even have half stars, as far as I know.
Speaker 0: So there you go.
Speaker 0: But anyway, things of the day!
Speaker 1: So this is a Twitter thread, but it points out something that we've talked about before on Geek Nights, but this shows that this problem is more widespread and more current than you might think.
Speaker 1: Colorization APIs and colorization libraries, especially leveraging machine learning, are getting more and more popular lately.
Speaker 1: Ostensibly, they can take an old photo that's either black and white, or use one of those pre-full color processes where there's some color information that you can use.
Speaker 0: Well, because you can always remove the color information, make it black and white again, and then colorize it.
Speaker 0: Exactly.
Speaker 0: If necessary.
Speaker 0: But you can always just also use the existing weak, crappy, low-quality color information to help you make guesses about and move colors into a larger gamut.
Speaker 1: Coupled with having knowledge of the time and place the photo was taken, and maybe having other sources of data, there's a lot of ways to approach this problem.
Speaker 1: But it's important because, and we have a lot of studies to show this, black and white photos tend to make people feel like the past was further away and more alien and different than it really was and is.
Speaker 1: That's true.
Speaker 1: They're alienating.
Speaker 1: I remember when I was a kid, I saw a photo from World War II in color instead of in black and white, and it blew my kid mind because it just looked like a normal place with normal people doing, well, sadly, normal things.
Speaker 1: And it really made it real how, as many as things change, a lot of things don't change.
Speaker 1: But this also gets into the problem where a lot of Europeans, a lot of white supremacists have false ideas about the past.
Speaker 1: Like, they think that Roman buildings were white marble and austere.
Speaker 1: Like, no, they were painted with the most garish colors humans have ever conceived.
Speaker 0: And the paint wore out because it was shitty.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So the problem now is that these colorization libraries are getting very popular.
Speaker 1: So this person, this thing of the day, is they took some photos from 1909 and 1915.
Speaker 1: And they were color photos, accurate, good color photos, early color photos.
Speaker 1: They removed the color.
Speaker 1: Then they ran these through some of the most popular colorization libraries and machine learning networks that are out there, ones that a lot of historians use, where these photos get circulated widely using these APIs.
Speaker 1: And you showed the colors, like, what they look like.
Speaker 1: And they look like the old-timey color photos you expect.
Speaker 1: But then you look at the actual real photos and they look literally nothing like what that API did.
Speaker 1: Like, not even close.
Speaker 1: The real photos are so vibrant and the colors are so stark and the people look so different.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: And a lot, you know, that's the thing is, you know, as much as people have digital cameras these days, right?
Speaker 0: It's like, you know, and we talk about things like vinyl records being poopy, which is true.
Speaker 0: They're just garbage.
Speaker 1: They have way more noise than even, like, a CD.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Analog film, you know, depending on a lot of circumstances.
Speaker 0: But the quality of analog film is actually still, to this day, ridiculous resolution.
Speaker 0: You know, it's like not until, like, 4K even.
Speaker 0: It's like, even 1080p, it's like you're better off watching a, you know, 35mm film, as long as it's in good shape and your projector is good, than watching, you know, a 1080p, you know, boot ray.
Speaker 1: But, like, you look at the black and white...
Speaker 0: And even a 70mm film, it's like, get out, right?
Speaker 0: It's like...
Speaker 1: But, like, you look at this photo of these three village girls in black and white, and it just looks super old-timey and almost depressing.
Speaker 1: You look at what the API did, and it just looks really, like, sad and washed out and sort of still old-timey.
Speaker 1: The actual photo, they're wearing amazing dresses, and it is not a sad photo at all.
Speaker 1: So, be wary of the sources of colorized, I'm making quote motions, images from the past, if you don't know the process they used, because they often will be lying to you and setting subtle biases in how you interpret history.
Speaker 1: So, what do you got?
Speaker 0: I got something real fun.
Speaker 0: So, there was a movie in the 80s, movies like as old as we are, called Ninjas in the Dragon's Den, right?
Speaker 0: It's, you know, some old, one of those silly 80s martial arts movies, the kind of anime hell of a situation.
Speaker 1: Oh my god, those ninja costumes.
Speaker 0: Right, this is the most stereotyped ninja thing you'll ever see.
Speaker 0: And basically, at the beginning, the movie opens up with a three-minute sequence, and that's, like, where the credits play.
Speaker 0: Sort of like how a James Bond movie opens up with a credit thing, right?
Speaker 0: And it's this song, it's a great song, you'll love it.
Speaker 0: It's very of the period, and the three-minute sequence of the ninjas doing their ninja thing, it's like, do you even need to see the rest of this movie?
Speaker 0: I don't know, but this is a really fun way to spend three minutes with some ninjas, if you've never seen this movie or the opening to it.
Speaker 0: It is well worth your three minutes to have some fun 80s, you know, ninja action.
Speaker 1: I, uh, I remember seeing the movie, oh god, three ninjas in the theater, because I was one of those kids who was into ninjas.
Speaker 0: Did I see that in the theater or at home?
Speaker 0: I don't know which one I saw either.
Speaker 1: Not only did we see three ninjas in the theater, but we saw three ninjas kick back in the theater, I want to say.
Speaker 0: You know what I definitely 100% saw in the theater was, uh, what's the one with Chuck Norris and the kid?
Speaker 1: Oh, Sidekick!
Speaker 0: That one.
Speaker 0: That movie- I saw that in the theater.
Speaker 1: I, that movie messed with my kid brain.
Speaker 1: I wasn't sure if Chuck Norris was real or not.
Speaker 0: I don't remember anything about it other than that it was a movie with Chuck Norris and a kid.
Speaker 1: It was a kid who was bullied and he had this imaginary friend, Chuck Norris, who would, like, help him.
Speaker 0: But then he made that, like- I did not know that's what it was about.
Speaker 1: But then he, like- I've seen it.
Speaker 1: Chuck Norris ends up being real and, like, actually fights with him.
Speaker 1: Like, I don't, that is all I remember.
Speaker 0: Okay, I remember less than that.
Speaker 1: Also, Chuck Norris is a bad person in real life, just in case anyone doesn't know.
Speaker 0: Yes, Chuck Norris is bad.
Speaker 0: Very bad.
Speaker 1: But, uh, after we watched Three Ninjas, my brother and I put on the blindfold, or the, the headbands, 'cause the theater gave every kid who showed up a Three Ninjas headband.
Speaker 1: It was a long time ago.
Speaker 0: Whoa.
Speaker 1: And, uh, we put them over our eyes, like blindfolds, and ran blindly into the parking lot for training.
Speaker 1: And I ran straight into a parking sign.
Speaker 0: Good.
Speaker 1: I, uh, I had, it looked like someone had punched me in the face.
Speaker 1: So I come home from this movie, and my dad is just like, you're gonna have to explain what happened to you when your mom asks you, 'cause I am not involved in this situation.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that just reminds me of how sad I was as a kid, that on TV there would be commercials occasionally talking about, you know, special promotions like that, right?
Speaker 0: Yup.
Speaker 0: And how literally never was, not even one time, were any of those actually happening in a place near me that I went.
Speaker 1: Wow, they were like always near me for some reason.
Speaker 1: Like Lakeside bucket mall.
Speaker 0: It would be like, oh, go to, go to, go to this store.
Speaker 0: There's a special limit, you know, like, uh, cup or whatever.
Speaker 0: And I'd go to the store, and they wouldn't, like, no, we don't have that.
Speaker 0: You know, it'd be like, you know, oh, if you go see this movie on this day, you'll get a toy.
Speaker 0: Nope, no toys there.
Speaker 0: I think what was going on is- None of those things.
Speaker 1: We, like, we weren't rich.
Speaker 1: We lived, uh, we didn't live in the gray part, like the gray neighborhood.
Speaker 1: But, if we drove far enough, there was a fancy mall, fancy relative to the mall we would go to.
Speaker 0: There's a mall right next to my house.
Speaker 1: Yeah, for whatever reason, the fancy mall in the nice suburbs that we drive out to all the time instead of the crappy mall near us.
Speaker 1: Every single movie promotion was there.
Speaker 1: Like, every tchotchke you would possibly want would be there on opening night.
Speaker 0: The only ones we got occasionally were, like, the ones that would, like, come in in the newspaper.
Speaker 0: 'Cause we'd always buy newspapers.
Speaker 0: We'd get those kinds of things.
Speaker 0: I think there was one time there was, like, the thing was it was, like, a McDonald's vinyl record in the newspaper, I think I remember.
Speaker 0: I don't, I gotta look that up.
Speaker 1: Well, there was a, I mean, the McDonald's vinyl was part of that ad campaign where you had to memorize the song.
Speaker 0: I don't remember anything about it.
Speaker 0: Other than what I just said.
Speaker 1: Okay, interesting.
Speaker 1: I tried memorizing that song, and I would perform it on command for other adults because the adults all thought it was funny.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: And the contest was, if you got the vinyl, it had the real song, and then it had someone attempting to sing the song.
Speaker 1: And if the person attempting to sing the song and the vinyl you got succeeded, you won some cash prize.
Speaker 1: And, of course, nobody actually won that thing, but.
Speaker 0: I don't know why I remember this so specifically.
Speaker 0: There's an article here that says what happened to the winner of McDonald's 1 million Flexidisc contest.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't know, 'cause there were two contests.
Speaker 0: In 1989, a 13-year-old boy in Galax, Virginia thought he'd won.
Speaker 0: His family suddenly had money, but with it, more problems.
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 1: Interesting, yeah.
Speaker 1: More problems.
Speaker 0: Well.
Speaker 1: Otherwise, metamoment.
Speaker 1: We're still locked inside.
Speaker 1: Like, I just got my second shot less than a week ago.
Speaker 1: Stay tuned.
Speaker 0: I got mine maybe a week.
Speaker 0: I guess a week and a day ago, I guess?
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: Give me another week, and I'm not gonna change much in my life.
Speaker 1: Like, things are still not great out there.
Speaker 0: Well, you know, if it was warm, I would go outside more.
Speaker 1: I mean, if it's warm enough, I'm going outside more.
Speaker 0: It's a little cold.
Speaker 1: A little cold?
Speaker 1: This is like hiking weekend.
Speaker 0: And it's gonna rain for like a week.
Speaker 1: It's not gonna rain much on Sunday.
Speaker 0: It's cold.
Speaker 0: It's like 60.
Speaker 0: It's fine.
Speaker 0: It's cold.
Speaker 1: How did you get so old so fast?
Speaker 0: You know, the Earth, it kept going around the sun.
Speaker 0: It couldn't stop.
Speaker 1: So let's just get right into it, because I'm hungry.
Speaker 1: It's Thursday.
Speaker 0: It's the lounge.
Speaker 0: No metamoment action?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 1: All our stuff's on the internet.
Speaker 1: Our Discord's rocking.
Speaker 1: You should join it.
Speaker 0: The book club book is The Tale of Genji.
Speaker 1: The Tale of Genji?
Speaker 1: I'm reading it slowly.
Speaker 0: Genji is not a ninja.
Speaker 1: Yeah, let's just get into it.
Speaker 1: So, in America, you know, we're Americans.
Speaker 1: We're gonna talk about this from an English-speaking American perspective, because this is a country where white people born here don't really need to speak any other languages to get by, usually.
Speaker 0: Thanks to the imperialism of the UK primarily, but also the United States, English has imposed, much like the US dollar, English as a language has imposed its will upon the rest of the world, which is a privilege and benefit of us.
Speaker 0: that was not our fault, but we benefit from it greatly.
Speaker 1: Hey, at least we displace French as the lingua franca.
Speaker 0: That's sure.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's funny.
Speaker 0: The lingua franca is not English.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I never thought about that before.
Speaker 0: But yeah, I can go to most countries, and as long as I'm in heavily populated areas, especially, if I go to any airport, you know, things will be written in English.
Speaker 0: There'll be people who speak English around.
Speaker 0: You know, you can get through life, even if you travel frequently, with only English.
Speaker 1: Talk about my day job.
Speaker 1: I've spent a decade flying around the world doing business, like, everywhere, in places where very few people speak English, and I've made it out just fine with, like, let's see, some high school French, a little, I can read Turkish phonetically, and I know a few basic words that are useful for, like, ordering things, and I know a bunch of random Japanese nouns and verbs thanks to anime.
Speaker 1: Like, that's about the extent of it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean, I learned, you know, because I'm a Jew in Hebrew school, they taught us, it was really annoying to me that they would teach us to read Hebrew, right?
Speaker 0: So, I can, I guess I've forgotten some portion of it, because I haven't,
Speaker 1: well, like, how to read it phonetically, like, read it, like, you can look at the alphabet, and you can say the word out loud,
Speaker 0: perfectly, with perfect pronunciation, and someone says, "What does that word
Speaker 0: mean?".
Speaker 0: Like, I have no fucking idea.
Speaker 0: Yup.
Speaker 1: That was useful to me in Turkey, because I had to drive there, and I had to, like, do a lot of crap completely on my own.
Speaker 1: So, while I didn't know Turkish, I could say any word I could see perfectly, and that was super useful asking for directions.
Speaker 1: Like, that actually saved me many times.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: And then, for Spanish, so, in middle school, for all of middle school, they made us take a second language.
Speaker 0: You could choose Spanish, French, basically.
Speaker 1: That's something that came, like, while we were kids.
Speaker 1: Like, America wasn't big on learning other languages, generally, but there was a revolution where in the late '70s, early '80s, there started to be this idea that every kid in America should at least learn, while they're in, like, K-12 education, one other language, and some schools started to require it.
Speaker 0: So, the choices were Spanish and French.
Speaker 0: I chose Spanish.
Speaker 1: Oh, that's all you had?
Speaker 1: I went to a fancier school, I guess.
Speaker 0: Well, in high school, there were more choices.
Speaker 1: Yeah, our default choices, like the normal ones, were French, Spanish, German, and Italian.
Speaker 1: Those are, like, the four, but there was one Latin class, there was one Japanese class, and there was one Russian class.
Speaker 0: Yup, so yes, in high school, it was pretty much what you described, but in middle school, you had two choices.
Speaker 0: So, in middle school, I took three years of Spanish, right?
Speaker 0: And then, in high school, you know, they kept telling you, like, "Oh, man, you want to succeed in life?
Speaker 0: You want a college to accept you?
Speaker 0: You better take four years of foreign language, right?
Speaker 0: Otherwise, you know, your college just won't accept
Speaker 0: you.".
Speaker 1: I did not take the full four years.
Speaker 1: I stopped taking French my senior year.
Speaker 0: And then they said, "In order to graduate, you need two
Speaker 0: years.".
Speaker 0: And I was like, "Wait a minute, wait a minute.
Speaker 0: You're saying you give me the high school diploma with only two years, but, you know, you're really encouraging the four, but you've got all these other classes available in this school that I can take, computer classes, you know, all kinds of fun stuff, and I basically can choose to do those instead of
Speaker 0: these.".
Speaker 0: So I did the minimum two years of Spanish in high school, and as a result, my Spanish is actually, you know, it's like, there are some verbs I know how to conjugate, but I've, you know, forgotten some.
Speaker 0: And then, but it's like, I can read, like, even today, you know, that second year of high school was 1998, right?
Speaker 0: So it's been a long time since I studied any Spanish or spoke it at all, and I couldn't really hold a conversation if someone was, you know, with a fluent person who was speaking at their normal speed.
Speaker 0: But I can read, like, the signs on the subway that are in Spanish, like 80% of what's on the sign.
Speaker 0: You know, it's mostly vocabulary.
Speaker 0: Like, I don't know what that word means, you know, but I understand the sentence structure and enough words that I get the idea.
Speaker 0: So that's, you know, surprising.
Speaker 0: It was actually surprising to me that, like, I still know as much Spanish as I do, right?
Speaker 0: Considering how little effort I put into it, other than five years of classes that I had to take.
Speaker 1: I think what helps is that just living in a diverse city, we encounter Spanish a lot, so there's a lot of signs in Spanish.
Speaker 1: Like, you sort of just, like, you gotta know a lot of basic words if you're gonna live in New York and not just be that guy, so... But French, like, doesn't really come up in my life at all, 'cause I ended up picking French because in my school, the basic ones were offered at multiple times, so it was pretty easy to schedule.
Speaker 1: I wanted to take Japanese, 'cause I was a mega wee starting in elementary school.
Speaker 1: Japanese was during band, and I wasn't gonna give up music.
Speaker 1: So then I was like, "Oh, I'll do
Speaker 1: Russian.".
Speaker 1: Russian was during all the advanced math classes, so I couldn't do Russian.
Speaker 1: Basically, all the interesting languages I wanted to take were during a class.
Speaker 1: I wanted to take more, so I had to pick one of the default four.
Speaker 1: I picked French semi-randomly.
Speaker 1: I didn't have any particular rationale behind it, I just picked it.
Speaker 0: I picked Spanish just aesthetically, you know.
Speaker 0: And also the fact that I thought it would be more likely that I'd go to, like, you know, Mexico than it would be.
Speaker 1: I lived on the border of Canada, and we would go into Canada and head out toward Montreal.
Speaker 0: That's true, you were closer to Canada.
Speaker 0: I mean, I was also closer to Canada than I was to Mexico.
Speaker 1: But where I grew up, a lot of things in the grocery store would be in English and French instead of English and Spanish.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I wasn't that close.
Speaker 1: So I picked French, and it was an okay time, but I only took a few years of it.
Speaker 1: My senior year, I just bailed on it, 'cause I was done with high school.
Speaker 1: But then RIT was like, "Oh, it didn't take four years of language for the IT
Speaker 1: program.".
Speaker 1: I had to get a minimum number of language credits to get my degree.
Speaker 0: Oh, computer science did not have that.
Speaker 1: RIT had that.
Speaker 1: I had to take some language classes.
Speaker 1: You know what I did?
Speaker 1: I signed up for, like, intermediate French II.
Speaker 1: Like, I just picked French classes that looked like they were below what I could speak so they'd be easy, and tried to just basically take French again to get the credits.
Speaker 1: And it totally worked.
Speaker 1: I skipped the entirety of those French classes and passed all the exams.
Speaker 0: Sounds good.
Speaker 0: It worked out.
Speaker 1: I graduated.
Speaker 1: You can't take my diploma away.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So I put, you know, like with most things later in life, right, not just learning languages but other hobbies, right, it's like, you know, there are some where it's like, "I thought I would start 'em, but you didn't really," right?
Speaker 0: It's like, "I bought a
Speaker 0: harmonica.".
Speaker 0: No, right?
Speaker 0: It's like, I didn't practice.
Speaker 1: I kept practicing.
Speaker 1: I'm pretty good at that harmonica now.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's annoying.
Speaker 0: I didn't have the discipline to stick with it, right?
Speaker 0: So, like, I think I tried for, like, maybe, like, a week to, like, to read Japanese.
Speaker 0: You know, I could read the katakanas for, like, a little bit.
Speaker 1: Oh, remember, I learned Hangul, like, fully.
Speaker 1: Like, I could read Hangul phonetically, and I learned basic Korean.
Speaker 1: Can you read it now?
Speaker 1: No, I forgot it all, 'cause I never used it.
Speaker 1: This is way before K-pop.
Speaker 0: Right, so it's like, you know, my, I never put the effort in, I didn't have the discipline, and then it, so I failed a couple times, and I said, "All right, I give up,".
Speaker 0: and now it's like, "I should learn,".
Speaker 0: but it's like, "No, I already know I don't have the discipline, so why
Speaker 0: start?".
Speaker 1: So I had something change for me in that.
Speaker 1: part of the reason why I'd forget this stuff was that I just don't use it in my daily life unless I might go out of my way to use it, and I am not the kind of person who has a hammer and goes around looking for nails.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm, exactly, exactly.
Speaker 1: But I did, I decided, 'cause Emily's been doing Duolingo just to, like, pick up a lot of basic Spanish, and it's worked out really well.
Speaker 1: Like, read Spanish and understand it pretty well, like, it worked out.
Speaker 1: It was very low effort, and it provided that constant context, you know, just poke at it for ten minutes once a day.
Speaker 1: So I started doing it for French, and I learned something fascinating.
Speaker 1: I weirdly have a, like, extremely strong understanding of French grammar and structure and diction and pronunciation still.
Speaker 1: All I'd lost was the vocabulary.
Speaker 1: I didn't know any fucking words anymore at all.
Speaker 1: I remembered a lot of, like, verbs, but that was it.
Speaker 1: Like, nouns for anything were just gone from my brain.
Speaker 0: It's actually not, I haven't thought of that before, right?
Speaker 0: 'Cause, like, the languages that I think would be useful to me that I want to learn, right, are, like, you know, Japanese, Korean, right?
Speaker 0: You know, like, these languages where I can then access, you know, media, right, without subtitles.
Speaker 0: Well, like,
Speaker 1: I was even learning hiragana just 'cause that made it easy to be able to do things like read straight signs when we were traveling in Japan, and I knew it for a while, but then we didn't go back to Japan for a long time, and I literally forgot most of it because I don't need it in my daily life.
Speaker 0: Right, but it's like now, it's like thanks to literally just within this recording this podcast, it's like, you know, I already know enough Spanish to read signs on the subway.
Speaker 0: if I just put, I could probably, you know, become maybe even fluent in Spanish if I tried, right?
Speaker 0: You know, considering that I have, like, a head start of some amount, you know, maybe that would work out better if I did that instead of trying to learn something that not only, I don't, I know nothing and has a different alphabet.
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 1: Now, but the way I learn languages, 'cause I realize, like, doing Duolingo, like, it's very, like, immersion, like, it gives you a sentence and makes you translate it without telling you anything, but with, like, multiple choice, like, it does that kind of stuff.
Speaker 1: I'm not gonna, like, turn this into a Duolingo ad or anything.
Speaker 1: But I think I would not have liked that application at all if it weren't for the fact that I already know the, a good deal of how French works.
Speaker 1: So the only thing I'm learning is relearning the vocabulary and relearning stuff like which words are feminine and masculine and all that gendered nonsense.
Speaker 1: But, like, I don't, like, 'cause when I learn languages, I would, like, rather read about grammar for a year before I say even one sentence.
Speaker 1: Like, I like to learn structure and rules first before I start learning content.
Speaker 0: I mean, I don't really, you know, I don't know which way is the best way.
Speaker 1: Oh, I don't think that's the best way.
Speaker 1: I think that's just how I have engaged.
Speaker 0: No, I mean, for me, I don't know what the best way for me to learn is either, right?
Speaker 0: It's like, you know, it's like.
Speaker 0: how much, you know, I've consumed so much media in various languages with subtitles and I pick up words, you know, and I eventually learn what they mean, but I still can't speak or read those languages at all, right?
Speaker 0: Even though it's been many, many years of consuming piles and piles of media for some of them, right?
Speaker 1: That's kind of why I'm doing this app thing 'cause it just, it forces me to see the language and engage with it a tiny bit every single day.
Speaker 0: It seems like it's working.
Speaker 0: I did pirate those Rosetta apps way back in the beacon days.
Speaker 0: They were not great.
Speaker 1: I also pirated them.
Speaker 0: They did not work.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I wouldn't pay for them.
Speaker 0: They charged so much money for those, but yeah, they didn't really work for me at all and I wasn't able to stick with those either.
Speaker 0: I didn't have the discipline, so it didn't work.
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 1: So, I'm gonna keep this up and see if I have rudimentary French again by the time we go to France 'cause I actually haven't been to Paris in, God, it's been a long time now and I wanna actually go there on a vacation instead of for work.
Speaker 0: Maybe, yeah, maybe I should try the, you know, it's like to become fluent in Spanish from where I am should be theoretically less work than from nothing in some other language, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: And although I'm not interested in Spanish media, you know, it's like maybe, like there are plenty of Spanish-speaking people all around here.
Speaker 1: It's just generally useful, especially in a cosmopolitan city.
Speaker 0: It would be actually very useful if I could just actually engage in a conversation.
Speaker 1: What's funny though is so, you know, I used to spend a lot of time in Turkey to the point that I was like earnestly trying to learn Turkish.
Speaker 1: Like I was studying the language, I had a bunch of grammar books, I would like try to use it when I was there, but literally every single person I used any Turkish words with, like I'm not even exaggerating, 100% of the people, if they spoke English at all, they would tell me, they would literally just be like, "Why are you speaking Turkish?
Speaker 1: Don't learn our language.
Speaker 1: No one else on earth speaks it.
Speaker 1: There's no point.
Speaker 1: You're wasting your
Speaker 1: time.".
Speaker 1: They were like oddly insistent, like, "No, don't bother.
Speaker 1: Like this language, I love my language, but no one speaks it outside of Turkey.
Speaker 1: Unless you move here, you will never use it in your
Speaker 1: life.".
Speaker 1: And they were like specifically earnestly insistent about that.
Speaker 1: It's also a neat language.
Speaker 0: Their perspective was like, you know, that, you know, their perspective is like, man, you know, learning English for them, right?
Speaker 1: Like opens up the world.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: It opens up doors for them, right?
Speaker 0: Whereas knowing only Turkish, they sort of feel trapped.
Speaker 0: So it's sort of like, why would you want to learn Turkish?
Speaker 0: It's like being able to access this tiny, it's like this little tiny box that, you know, even from their perspective of being Turkish people, right?
Speaker 0: You know, but other people are like, yes, please learn our, you know, we want people to learn our language.
Speaker 0: We want to spread our culture and share with you, right?
Speaker 0: It's just different attitudes and different places.
Speaker 1: So yeah, we'll see.
Speaker 1: I'm going to give this like a year and see how far my French gets along and decide what to do from there.
Speaker 1: I was vaguely thinking if I wanted to learn a language more deeply, I was honestly thinking about German.
Speaker 1: Because in terms of places I might end up, long term.
Speaker 0: The board game business?
Speaker 1: Well, not so much the board, like the board games would be a bonus, but more in terms of like what country generally is closer to like the political ideals I have as a structure.
Speaker 0: When you learn Dutch then?
Speaker 1: Ah, yeah, that would work too.
Speaker 1: Finnish?
Speaker 0: Say something like that?
Speaker 1: German seems like it would be generally useful.
Speaker 1: Also, I do, in the course of my work, I encounter a lot of German speaking people.
Speaker 1: I also have a bunch of engineering teams in Frankfurt right now.
Speaker 1: So I would actually like have an excuse to use that language because I do enter.
Speaker 1: There are people I would like to interact with more who do not have like, they're not fluent in English, they're fluent in German.
Speaker 1: They interact with me in English because I'm the product manager, but like I don't speak German.
Speaker 1: So I would earnestly like to be able to engage with them more directly.
Speaker 1: But that would be a much, just using a language, like planning to use the language for that purpose is a much bigger commitment than learning French for like a trip I'm going to take to France.
Speaker 0: Yeah, at my work they actually, there were so many frequent requests coming, you know, they were like at the front desk or at other places in the company, right?
Speaker 0: They'd like get a contract from like a French songwriter or something and they'd, they'd send a message out, like broadcast like, "Is there anyone in the office who speaks, who's fluent in
Speaker 0: X?".
Speaker 0: It happened frequently enough.
Speaker 0: They created a company-wide directory.
Speaker 0: So you could find the people who are fluent in X. We
Speaker 1: have a similar directory and you can also, in all of our internal systems, if your name has a spelling that uses characters, diacritics or anything that would be different in different contexts, you can actually input your name for all those different contexts and it'll show up appropriately depending on what language is being used.
Speaker 0: That's good.
Speaker 1: It's really neat.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but it's like, you know, if anyone out there is, you know, I definitely, you know, believe that even if you are, have the benefit of, you know, already knowing English because you were born in a place that speaks English or, you know, that learning another language is very valuable.
Speaker 0: You know, don't, don't do as I do.
Speaker 0: Do as I say.
Speaker 0: Don't do as I don't does, right?
Speaker 0: You know, learning more languages is, you know, just awesome.
Speaker 0: It helps you and it's, you know, it, I would, if someone who knows more than one language, I have respect for them, right?
Speaker 0: It's like, you know, you can, you know, it's just, uh, it's just all around positive.
Speaker 0: You know, it would be nice if the whole world spoke one language and everyone could communicate easily.
Speaker 0: Uh, but that also is, you know, language also affects how people think.
Speaker 0: So that would make people all think the same way as well.
Speaker 0: And that's not.
Speaker 1: Ah, so that's something I think about a lot.
Speaker 0: And it would also, it also do, you know, erase a lot of cultures, which is even less great.
Speaker 1: Well, so are you familiar with the Sapir-Whorf hypothesis?
Speaker 0: No, but I'm pretty sure I can guess what it is.
Speaker 1: Uh, it's the idea that the set of languages you speak best and use the most in your own head materially affect your worldview and cognition and how you approach and interact with things.
Speaker 0: I believe it.
Speaker 1: And there's a lot of debate on how strong it is and how much, like, there's some, there's evidence for it.
Speaker 1: There's weak evidence against it.
Speaker 1: There's, it's a whole, but the culture books, those sci-fi books are based on it.
Speaker 1: A big part of the culture is the idea that the machines make up a new language and over time get all humans to speak it.
Speaker 1: But that language is subtly designed to reduce aggression and increase curiosity and things like that.
Speaker 1: That is like a fascinating field we are in no way competent to speak to beyond maybe the next couple minutes.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: An observation I have made, you know, especially in our forum, but just around the internet as well, are people who will argue about something, whatever the something is, and they'll make some semantic argument, right?
Speaker 0: And then they'll be like, aha, these words mean X, therefore this thing about reality.
Speaker 0: And it's like, I think people have a heart.
Speaker 0: I'm always intentionally forcing myself to sort of separate and be like, you know, the way the world works.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Has nothing to do with the words that we've invented.
Speaker 0: We, you know, even things like, you know, we say we talk about like physics and chemistry, like these two separate things, you know, conceptually, it's like, you know, in order to understand them, we need that framework.
Speaker 0: But it's like, there's no actual separation.
Speaker 0: The universe is the universe.
Speaker 0: Atoms are atoms.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: You know, why are you thinking about those things separately?
Speaker 1: It's like, it's like, well, that's why I'm such a big fan.
Speaker 1: And we do this in our talks all the time of.
Speaker 1: if we're going to make a like very focused or semantic based argument, we'll at least set the agree on the definitions of the things we're going to use for the debate in advance and agree that those definitions are not universal.
Speaker 1: They're just for the purpose of this particular thought experiment.
Speaker 0: But if you speak a different language, you have different words available to you.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Maybe that maybe the some theoretical language has a word for something and that word encompasses some parts of physics and some parts of chemistry.
Speaker 0: But it's still anyone who speaks that language would clearly understand that word, whatever it is, its own thing.
Speaker 0: It's like they could teach a class in school on that thing.
Speaker 1: That's one of the reasons why Latin is used for a lot of like scientific terms, because since it's not a like actively spoken language, it's not going to evolve significantly.
Speaker 1: So its meaning will remain relatively constant and untouched by culture or at least less touched by culture because it's still touched by the culture of the person who chose a particular Latin word or Latin sounding word.
Speaker 1: But another idea in that space is some languages have concepts like when you use a noun or a verb like verbs, verbs that imply something happened have varying degrees of how much truth there is to it.
Speaker 1: Like there are languages that if I say I went to the store, I could use a different word than went.
Speaker 1: That means I went to the store.
Speaker 1: I am saying 100 percent.
Speaker 1: this is literal truth versus I went to the store.
Speaker 1: But I'm not like.
Speaker 1: I'm not saying this as a literal truth.
Speaker 1: English has nothing like that.
Speaker 0: And then you got languages with gendered pronouns.
Speaker 1: I'm so like not jazzed about it.
Speaker 1: I forgot how much I hate the gendering in French.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: There's so much stuff like that going on, you know, all all the different aspects.
Speaker 0: And the way they are thinking.
Speaker 1: That's the word I'll use for computer.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And, you know, I think that learning more languages and, you know, getting those, you know, especially if you can go above two languages, you can start to sort of erase those sort of controls on your brain to some extent, maybe, you know, but just it's a good thing.
Speaker 0: So you're not.
Speaker 0: And also, from what I've read, I'm not 100 percent sure on this, but I've read it in several places that the idea that like, oh, kids can just pick up languages and it's hard for adults.
Speaker 0: I've read that that's actually just a myth.
Speaker 1: It's yeah.
Speaker 1: If you're immersed, you start to pick it up like that's going to happen.
Speaker 0: It's you don't.
Speaker 0: if you it doesn't matter if you have enough life.
Speaker 0: Don't worry.
Speaker 0: I mean, if you're so old, you don't have that much life left to live.
Speaker 0: Maybe, you know, I guess.
Speaker 1: Do you want to spend your baby to do a little lessons a day instead of one?
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Or faster.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: But, you know, even at my age, it's like hopefully I have enough life left to live.
Speaker 0: learning on the language.
Speaker 0: It could still be valuable to you.
Speaker 0: Don't write it off just because you didn't start early.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: See you next week.
Speaker 1: This has been Geek Nights with Rim and Scott.
Speaker 1: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at FrontRowCrew.com for show notes, discussion news and more.
Speaker 1: Remember, Geek Nights is not one, but four different shows.
Speaker 1: Sci-Tech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 0: Geek Nights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 0: Geek Nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 0: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.
Speaker 1: And the Patreon patrons for this particular episode of Geek Nights are And a bunch of people who do not want me to say their names.
Speaker 1: We talked a little bit about the harmonicas that we both bought and Scott decided to not learn.
Speaker 1: and I decided to learn.
Speaker 1: So I just pulled mine out and I'm just going to play my harmonica really briefly.
Speaker 1: And that's all you're going to get at the end of this episode.