Speaker 0: It's Thursday, January 28th, 2021.
Speaker 0: I'm rim.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott.
Speaker 0: And this is geek nights.
Speaker 0: Tonight.
Speaker 0: We talk about our unfinished business.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: Oh, shit.
Speaker 0: We have any opening bits?
Speaker 0: I got nobody.
Speaker 0: that is kind of vaguely relevant.
Speaker 0: So, uh, I'll admit that and Scott's doing this, too.
Speaker 0: So it's not just like me.
Speaker 0: We are watching the sports that are happening during covid.
Speaker 0: And I have a little bit of an ethical conundrum there, because on one hand, they should not be doing sports yet.
Speaker 0: Like it's too soon.
Speaker 1: If I was in charge, if I was in charge, I would have been like, you know, I guess the Super Val is in two weeks or a week and a couple of days.
Speaker 1: You know, I would have.
Speaker 1: I would have been like, no sport.
Speaker 1: You cannot have these sports at all.
Speaker 1: The Super Bowl is going to have people at it in Florida.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I didn't realize until like a week ago that there's going to be people in that arena.
Speaker 0: It's not going to be just closed.
Speaker 0: What arena?
Speaker 1: It's a stadium.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: But there was no, there was a. there was games last week, like in Kansas City.
Speaker 1: They had people, you know, way too many people.
Speaker 0: So even worse.
Speaker 0: Well, I guess that's one thing.
Speaker 0: But if I don't watch, nothing changes like me choosing to watch or not watch.
Speaker 0: There's no I don't have a trolley lever.
Speaker 0: I'm pulling.
Speaker 0: It's like, do you watch the trolley hit the people or not?
Speaker 1: I mean, it's the same old comic where it's like, ah, you criticize society, but you also partake in it.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: And it's like, you know, now that I have that comic to so sort of succinctly sum up, you know, participating in evil capitalism and whatnot, it's like, you know, yeah, I'm not like spending money to watch hockey.
Speaker 1: I'm right.
Speaker 1: It's like I'm not pirating a stream.
Speaker 1: I'm not buying any hockey stuff.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: I mean, they're just holding our ticket money.
Speaker 1: We're not spending any more ticket.
Speaker 0: And like, I wouldn't go even if we could go in any capacity.
Speaker 1: If they suddenly said, hey, you know, you can go now.
Speaker 1: I'd be like, no.
Speaker 1: So I do that.
Speaker 0: But the best part is, at least like where I landed is I'm going to keep watching these sports, but I'm going to pirate them and I'm not going to like social media, like celebrate the fact that these sports are happening.
Speaker 0: But I am going to watch that Rangers game after Record Geek Nights.
Speaker 1: We'll see.
Speaker 1: Just lose again.
Speaker 1: It's fine.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: You know, the Rangers, they're back to their pattern of, oh, they should have won that game, but they lost.
Speaker 0: It's like, no, you just lost it.
Speaker 0: Like you were playing good enough to win does not mean you won.
Speaker 1: Also, you know, the best players on our team are not showing up.
Speaker 0: Chasturkin's doing the best he can with the D that is presented to him, at least.
Speaker 1: The D is actually, you know, used to be.
Speaker 1: our weakness is now strengthened.
Speaker 1: It's just the offense that we had.
Speaker 1: We have those players still, but those players are not performing at their high level.
Speaker 1: And everyone's like, you know, blaming the coach.
Speaker 1: And it's like, what?
Speaker 1: You change the coach?
Speaker 1: You think they're just going to win tomorrow?
Speaker 1: It's like this, you know, it's like, come on.
Speaker 1: And two, everyone's blaming things like, oh, there was no training camp.
Speaker 1: There was no this, no that.
Speaker 1: It's like the other teams didn't have training camp either.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: Like, what do you like?
Speaker 0: Crieder is slower regardless of any other factor.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like the players we have that were good players that we paid a lot the most money to are not playing as well as they played last year.
Speaker 1: It's on them.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: So there is a ton of news.
Speaker 0: We're not going to talk more about that GameStop thing because it's doing way too fast.
Speaker 1: The GameStop thing is the biggest news.
Speaker 1: That's like the freshest news.
Speaker 0: It's like actually a new thing that hasn't happened and is not like the political axis of like the actual crisis in America.
Speaker 0: Like it was something orthogonal to that.
Speaker 0: That just happens.
Speaker 1: It intersects with so many things.
Speaker 1: It's like, you know, basically you can summarize like our times with that story so that we could talk about it probably for like a whole week, just nonstop to cover all the aspects.
Speaker 0: I mean, we've been talking about it nonstop in our like Discord DMs forever.
Speaker 1: The whole Internet is.
Speaker 1: But I think what we'll do is for Geek Nights, since we already talked about it way too much, we'll wait until it's done, done.
Speaker 1: And then we'll talk about it one more time.
Speaker 0: You know what that is?
Speaker 0: We're bringing back the Jack Thompson rule.
Speaker 0: We can't talk about Jack Thompson again unless he does something crazier than the last thing he did.
Speaker 1: But I know certain websites that have like a lockpicking lawyer rule.
Speaker 1: It's like they can't post another lockpicking lawyer video until he does something more ridiculous than the previous time they posted his video.
Speaker 0: I think Sausage Man has that there with, all right, you're going to beat water?
Speaker 0: You're going to beat nothing?
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like we already posted sausage.
Speaker 1: We're good.
Speaker 1: You can check out all the sausages now on your own.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: But actually, the guy who does historical food just did a really good one.
Speaker 0: that was like surprisingly good about a guy who died due to lobster, but in a really sad and funny way.
Speaker 0: Anyway.
Speaker 1: But it was by the claw or the magnet.
Speaker 0: This was in the Louis XIV era.
Speaker 0: But the one thing I will say about this whole GameStop thing is that the details of it are interesting, but they're not the message to take away.
Speaker 0: Short selling is not the thing to focus on.
Speaker 0: There is only one thing to focus on.
Speaker 0: This is the question you should ask yourself and think about in this whole realm.
Speaker 0: What should the stock market do for society?
Speaker 1: Well, should it exist?
Speaker 0: Well, if the idea of a stock market is going to exist at all, one, what purpose does it serve for society?
Speaker 0: Two, is it serving that purpose well?
Speaker 0: And three, what do we need to do to make it serve that purpose well?
Speaker 0: That is the only conversation that matters.
Speaker 0: Everything else is just political hobbyism.
Speaker 0: You're enjoying the spectacle.
Speaker 0: You're not doing anything.
Speaker 1: I am enjoying the spectacle.
Speaker 1: You're right.
Speaker 0: When it hit 420.69, I will not pretend that I didn't laugh out loud a lot.
Speaker 1: I thought that was a Photoshop.
Speaker 0: I think that really happened.
Speaker 1: I'll check.
Speaker 0: It got above that, so there must have been a point where the tick was that for a brief moment, though it could be wrong because the spread was actually weirdly wide.
Speaker 0: But anyway, we're not going to talk about that.
Speaker 0: Here's some news.
Speaker 1: Oh, it must have at one point because the highest peak was 468.49, so it did hit it for like probably a fraction of a second, some moment in time like yesterday.
Speaker 0: So you might remember Otacon.
Speaker 0: It was the second to last anime convention we still went to.
Speaker 1: We went to it seven or eight times.
Speaker 1: We went to it from 2002, three, four, five, six, seven, eight.
Speaker 1: We went to it eight times, 2002 through 2009.
Speaker 0: It was a big moment.
Speaker 0: There was a time when we had done so many panels at Otacons that like Otacon was more panels we had done than literally every other con we'd ever been to in our lives combined.
Speaker 1: We were going to it earlier than other cons.
Speaker 0: We were doing like five or six panels at a given Otacon sometimes.
Speaker 1: We were doing panels there before we did Geek Nights even.
Speaker 1: 2002. 2002,
Speaker 1: three, four.
Speaker 1: Geek Nights didn't start until 2005.
Speaker 1: We didn't start going to PAX until 2008 and PAX was like, "Hey, do one
Speaker 1: panel.".
Speaker 0: Otacon was like, "Can you do
Speaker 0: eight?".
Speaker 1: We submitted all kinds of stuff.
Speaker 1: I never remember what all those panels were.
Speaker 1: I have a list.
Speaker 1: We did an Advance Wars panel there.
Speaker 0: While we're talking, I'll pull up the list.
Speaker 0: Anyway, Otacon is in a little bit of trouble and I don't think they're going to survive this.
Speaker 1: I don't have any inside information.
Speaker 1: I just have the general knowledge we have from being a United States fan convention, somewhat experts, sort of.
Speaker 0: Also, we're in that sphere like we used to perform there.
Speaker 0: We were technically staffed there for a brief period.
Speaker 1: But I haven't talked to anyone from Otacon in how many years?
Speaker 1: I don't know what the hell is going on there specifically.
Speaker 0: We stopped going.
Speaker 1: We moved to a new building.
Speaker 1: I've never even seen that new building.
Speaker 0: When I imagine Otacon, in fact, when I was talking about it, I keep wanting to say Baltimore.
Speaker 0: It hasn't been in Baltimore for a long time.
Speaker 1: Obviously, they didn't have Otacon last year.
Speaker 1: If they sold any tickets, I don't even know.
Speaker 1: if they did, they had to refund them probably.
Speaker 1: I know it's a nonprofit organization, so the only thing that could cost them money if they're not having the convention would be taxes.
Speaker 1: You don't have low taxes.
Speaker 0: Salaries for the few employees you have that are permanent employees of the company.
Speaker 1: Any permanent employees or any sort of contracts you might have to outside people that you have to pay.
Speaker 1: Maybe they have a Google Suite account for the Otacon email.
Speaker 1: They have to pay that bill.
Speaker 1: Maybe they have a website that's being hosted to pay that bill.
Speaker 1: There's bills you have to pay just for having a company to exist even if you're not doing any fucking business.
Speaker 1: Even if they might be relatively small.
Speaker 1: So, the thing is, those kinds of bills, if you don't do any business, you just chill, especially if you're nonprofit, you don't need profits, and you don't have employees with salaries, or at least not a lot of them, is kind of small.
Speaker 1: You can just wait it out.
Speaker 1: But Otacon is saying, "Oh,
Speaker 1: no.".
Speaker 1: This is publicly, they've said this.
Speaker 1: "Oh, no.
Speaker 1: They started to work on 2021 Otacon.
Speaker 1: It might not happen.
Speaker 1: I think it's unlikely to happen in my personal
Speaker 1: opinion.".
Speaker 1: And they need, they're publicly expressing that they fear that if Otacon 2021 doesn't happen, then never, Otacon might just never happen again.
Speaker 1: They just admitted that.
Speaker 1: Which signals to me, there must be some expense that they need the money for they can't avoid.
Speaker 1: And the most likely thing is something you've mentioned on our show before, which is, if you have a contract with the convention center, and you can't get out of it by canceling, unless...
Speaker 0: And the government doesn't give you cover.
Speaker 1: Right, there is some sort of cover, like you've been forced to cancel by an act of outside forces beyond your control, right?
Speaker 1: And I think I've told the story about the laser light show when I was in first grade, where...
Speaker 0: That's like a Geek Nights trope at this point, that story.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I know, right?
Speaker 1: The school, elementary school, hired someone to come in and put on a laser light show for the kids.
Speaker 1: And in the contract, they signed with this person.
Speaker 1: They said that they would provide a room that was incredibly dark, right?
Speaker 1: Or a certain amount of darkness so that the show would look good.
Speaker 1: They could not make, they put like black construction paper over the windows in the gymnasium.
Speaker 1: And it was not dark enough, so the person came in, looked at the room, left, and the school still had to pay them.
Speaker 1: And somehow I understood that in first grade.
Speaker 1: And I think my guess is that's the situation Otacon is in, that unless the government of some D.C.
Speaker 1: or federal government or someone, mayor of
Speaker 1: D.C.,
Speaker 1: forces them to not hold Otacon 2021 and they simply choose not to hold it, or hold it but no one shows up, or they can't get enough staff or they just can't hold it, then they will still have to pay the convention center for the weekend and not have that money.
Speaker 1: And therefore, that will be the end of Otacon.
Speaker 1: It will be bankrupt.
Speaker 1: And they're asking for donations.
Speaker 0: Actually, there's a quote here of exactly what they said was, "We use the proceeds from each year to plan the next Otacon and make sure we survive until
Speaker 0: then.".
Speaker 0: So without the income from Otacon 2020 and the early pre-registrations we would normally see at this time of year, we're in a very precarious position.
Speaker 0: Put it simply, in the next few months we will have to make the decision to continue planning for Otacon 2021 or potentially close our doors forever.
Speaker 0: So yeah, it really sounds like if they do not run Otacon 2021 physically, they're gone.
Speaker 0: And they're asking for donations.
Speaker 0: I question the value of donating to them in the sense that if they can't survive without 2021 happening, I can't imagine fans would donate enough money to undo that "can't survive" statement.
Speaker 1: It is a crowded con.
Speaker 1: There are a lot of people who support it, but that number has been going down to my knowledge.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they didn't hit the caps they used to.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think the last time I looked, which has been actually a few years, let's take a look here, they have it on their website there.
Speaker 0: Yup, I remember when we went.
Speaker 0: it was like 26,000 uniques?
Speaker 0: Something like that?
Speaker 1: Here we go, event statistics.
Speaker 1: 2019, the unique memberships were 28 for 30.
Speaker 1: So yeah, it's down, it's peak, we're like in the 30s.
Speaker 1: So 28 is actually up.
Speaker 1: 2017 was low, it was like 24, 894.
Speaker 1: And in fact, when we went in 2009, it was 26.
Speaker 1: So it's up from where we were.
Speaker 1: So it's not too bad, they only had, you know, they actually had a bunch of big ups and downs.
Speaker 1: Like negative 20% in 2015, right?
Speaker 1: Up almost 10% in 2016, down 15% in 2017.
Speaker 0: It's funny, if you showed me those numbers for taxes, I could probably speculate on exactly what was happening year by year, but I just don't know.
Speaker 1: Wild fluctuations here.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't know what caused the ups and downs of the different years, but there you have it.
Speaker 0: The other thing that worries me, there was a statement added that the staff remained "hopeful" alongside the rollout of the vaccines.
Speaker 0: And they're exploring with "partners in DC to explore options to safely gather later this
Speaker 0: year.".
Speaker 0: That really worries me.
Speaker 0: that they're banking on being able to run in person, or not at all specifically.
Speaker 1: I mean, you know, sometimes, it's like for us, whenever I'm thinking about anything, I always calculate the value of one human life to be infinity.
Speaker 1: So it's like, if I had some business that I'd worked my whole life for, I guess I can't say that because I haven't had one.
Speaker 1: But it's like, I would just let it all go away to save one person's life.
Speaker 1: Well, here's the thing.
Speaker 1: At least in principle, but I haven't done that.
Speaker 1: So other people who have big things that they've worked for and built up, right?
Speaker 1: It's like, I guess Geek Nights, I couldn't save someone's life by sacrificing Geek Nights.
Speaker 1: If you've built something over a long time, you can end up valuing it more than other things, and it could change your judgement.
Speaker 0: Nerd cons are different because the thing is the convention happening and the people.
Speaker 0: But the appetite for nerd conventions is nearly limitless.
Speaker 0: And if, say Otacon went bankrupt, and the people who ran Otacon in a year or two, like when COVID, when we're post-COVID era, they spit up a new con called something else, and everyone just knows, "Oh yeah, this is just what replaced
Speaker 0: Otacon.".
Speaker 0: I think the same people would just show up.
Speaker 1: I don't even know what, even if they go bankrupt, it's like, okay, and you have all the exact same people just form a brand new nonprofit that does the exact same thing.
Speaker 1: You could even call it like,
Speaker 1: "Tutacon.".
Speaker 0: You could even crowdsource pre-orders for the first one to get that before money that we always talk about.
Speaker 1: Right, and then it's like, what are they actually losing?
Speaker 0: They might lose the trademarks, and they couldn't call it Otacon.
Speaker 0: They'd lose the professional relationships they have.
Speaker 0: But the people who foster those relationships in nerd conventions...
Speaker 1: Would they, right?
Speaker 1: As long as they have the same people on staff, what relationships do they lose?
Speaker 1: You just call up someone and you go, "Yeah, our old company had to go bankrupt because of the COVID.
Speaker 1: You know how life
Speaker 1: is.".
Speaker 1: "It's still me.
Speaker 0: Here's my new email address.
Speaker 0: @Otacon.".
Speaker 0: Yeah, @Ootacon.
Speaker 0: Otacon with a C.
Speaker 1: Right, .org, whatever.
Speaker 0: Otacon.
Speaker 0: They actually finally make it Otacon.
Speaker 1: Metal Gear.
Speaker 1: Anyway.
Speaker 0: But basically, I think it's like any nerd convention, there's two things going on here.
Speaker 0: One, the whole point of having a nonprofit or an LLC or whatever it is you structured is that you are not the con.
Speaker 0: You can just let the con fail.
Speaker 0: Just everyone resigns.
Speaker 0: The con's gone, and start a new one later.
Speaker 0: And the creditors gotta sort out what to do with the assets or any money owed or anything.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like why don't they just take whatever they've got, stop doing anything, and just call up a bankruptcy lawyer.
Speaker 1: Give them your remaining monies to help you sort this out and just be like, "Listen, we just want to be able to have this convention
Speaker 1: again.".
Speaker 1: "We don't even give a shit if we lose all these
Speaker 1: assets.".
Speaker 1: "We just figure it out for
Speaker 1: us.".
Speaker 0: There's also an opportunity.
Speaker 0: I'm not gonna say this applies to Otacon, but it is my opinion that this applies to a lot of nerd conventions.
Speaker 0: Over time, because of the way nerd conventions get founded, especially older ones, they tend to accrue people who might be full of some drama, or some people who might be actually making the con worse or holding it back, and it's often very hard to dislodge them.
Speaker 0: A convention just going bankrupt and the people who are dedicated enough to do the work to make a new con out of the ashes after COVID might be able to shed some of that dead weight and shed some of the old ideas of how to run cons, structure themselves better, and actually make a better convention.
Speaker 1: That is a good strategy, but it requires a strong marketing team or PR team to make sure that the people know.
Speaker 1: The people who don't know anything about your drama know that your con, the new one, is the real one.
Speaker 0: Here's how I think that's easy.
Speaker 1: There have been a lot of forks in the past.
Speaker 1: One that I know in the bicycling world is there's this famous bike ride called the Ragbri, which is basically you bike across Iowa.
Speaker 1: My friend did it, I would not do it because I don't want to go to fucking Iowa.
Speaker 1: But it was a famous, famous ride, it had drama, and I believe, I haven't read too much about it since it happened, but that it basically forked, and there were like now two different rides and battles sort of like over which one's the real one, which one's run by the not shitty people.
Speaker 0: But I think nerd cons, that gets sorted out real quick, and also it's easy because every time there's a new nerd con, it hits its cav immediately because people are so desperate for conventions, even pre-Covid.
Speaker 0: Like brand new cons, a big part of why they often failed was that a brand new con would have 10,000 people show up, even if they didn't advertise.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so that's a big news there.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there's a whole, that's a big one.
Speaker 1: The latest con drama.
Speaker 1: Just one more news, right?
Speaker 1: So I was real excited, you know, we talked about sports in the opening bit a little bit, but you know, women's hockey has been growing over the years, I've been following it since, you know, I guess it was in college, right?
Speaker 1: But more so when they started the NWHL a few years ago, and this year they decided that what they were going to do with the NWHL was to make a little bubble in Lake Placid, a great place, I've been there, where the Olympics were.
Speaker 1: Rambi would probably like it, the skiing.
Speaker 0: I've been to Lake Placid many times.
Speaker 1: Oh, okay.
Speaker 1: And basically they said, yeah, we'll just bubble all the women's hockey players here for two weeks, play a whole shit ton of hockey, give out the Isabel Cup and go home all safe-like, right?
Speaker 1: So I'm like, oh, okay, you know, it's on Twitch, all the games are on Twitch, and the final games were going to be on NBCSN, which is going to die, that's a news for another time.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so I was watching it on Twitch, right?
Speaker 1: You know, having a good time.
Speaker 1: And then of course, drama, right?
Speaker 1: So what drama has happened?
Speaker 1: There is so much drama.
Speaker 1: So first of all, there's the existing pre-drama of women's hockey in that there is an organization that is not a labor union, but is sort of close to it, kind of.
Speaker 1: It's the PWHPA, the Pro Women's Hockey Player Association, I think.
Speaker 0: Something like that.
Speaker 1: And it's basically some of the best, actually, women's hockey players in the US and Canada.
Speaker 1: And they're basically like, yeah, NWHL is BS, we're just going to do our own thing over here, right?
Speaker 1: So that's a thing.
Speaker 1: And then you've got this other organization, right?
Speaker 1: You may have heard of it, it's called Barstool Sports.
Speaker 1: And I try not to write its full name on the internet, because the trolls might see you, so usually I'll type "bar" and then the poop emoji.
Speaker 0: Well, it'll be real blunt.
Speaker 0: Barstool Sports is like the dog shit tier of sports journalism.
Speaker 0: Like, they're absolute dog shit.
Speaker 1: Barstool Sports is a racist and misogynist organization that puts out awful content.
Speaker 1: There's like whole Twitter accounts dedicated to showing you the people that work there, saying the n-word.
Speaker 1: There's just an awful place with awful people, awful culture, awful fans.
Speaker 1: It's bad.
Speaker 1: But it's somehow gained, right?
Speaker 1: It's basically sort of replaced that old sports talk radio, which still exists to some extent.
Speaker 1: Those people who would listen to the radio in their car, right?
Speaker 1: And I think COVID helped them out even more.
Speaker 1: They didn't need help, they're already big before COVID, but have moved to listening to sports talk podcasts instead, right?
Speaker 1: And Barstool became the place that had a whole bunch of podcasts for all the major sports with all sorts of toxically masculine racist people, you know, doing sort of morning show talk radio type culture.
Speaker 1: You're calling in and complaining about the coach or whatever, right?
Speaker 1: Like there is in sports, all those kinds of problems.
Speaker 1: And what you have is you have some people in sports, right?
Speaker 1: Like I've even seen like Henrik Lundqvist being interviewed on like a Barstool podcast one time, right?
Speaker 1: It's like, I don't even know if he knows.
Speaker 1: It's like, what's going on there?
Speaker 1: I didn't listen to it, but I saw he was on there and I was disappointed.
Speaker 1: So I don't know what he said.
Speaker 1: If he came back at them or who knows?
Speaker 1: If they even said anything bad on that show, right?
Speaker 1: It's not like.
Speaker 1: every episode they put out contains, you know, racism, but the whole organization itself is inherently bad.
Speaker 0: Yeah, which is almost worse because a lot of like generic sports fans don't see the bad side of Barstool and then they get weird when people criticize Barstool.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I mean, it would make sense, right?
Speaker 1: It's like if you've, you know, I'm sure there's probably, you know, they have so many shows, I don't even know all the shows.
Speaker 1: I'm sure that some of those shows, the hosts are probably not bad.
Speaker 1: They're just working there on their show at the organization, right?
Speaker 1: And then if you only listen to that show, you wouldn't know that the network itself is bad.
Speaker 1: And the network also, you know, they're doing that sort of cover thing, right?
Speaker 1: Where they have some sort of charity they have.
Speaker 1: It's like Barstool charity of some kind, right?
Speaker 1: Just sort of make themselves look good.
Speaker 0: A lot of the Dirtbag Left podcasts do that similar thing.
Speaker 0: Like they'll donate to trans rights causes, but are actively anti-trans and what they actually say and do.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: Stuff like that.
Speaker 1: So anyway, that exists over there.
Speaker 1: So what happened is in the NWHL, there is an amazing player on the Newark Riveters, our team, right?
Speaker 1: Soroya Tinker, who is a black person, you know, and she was like, post things on Twitter, right?
Speaker 1: So on her Twitter account, I follow her on Twitter.
Speaker 1: So it was like, she was like, she posted a photo of like, you know, her and some of the teammates kneeling during the national anthem.
Speaker 1: And she was like, I know that even the teammates who were standing, we all support each other.
Speaker 1: It was like, oh, how great is this team?
Speaker 1: How nice, right?
Speaker 1: Yay.
Speaker 1: Women's hockey, right?
Speaker 1: And then, right, apparently like some NWHL people like appeared on some Barstool podcast and she called them shit out.
Speaker 0: Correctly called them out.
Speaker 1: And then Barstool's coming, right?
Speaker 1: Posting like the CEO of Barstool, who is a woman, but that doesn't make it impossible for them to be misogynist or racist.
Speaker 1: Post like a video on Twitter, right?
Speaker 1: Like calling basically for targeted harassment of, you know, people, right?
Speaker 1: In the NWHL and others, right?
Speaker 1: And basically huge ass drama going on, right?
Speaker 1: Within the team, right?
Speaker 1: You know, and with external to the league and it just basically put a dark cloud over what was starting out as basically the nicest sport that was happening.
Speaker 1: This little two week bubble now had a dark cloud over it.
Speaker 1: And you know what?
Speaker 1: You didn't think it could get worse.
Speaker 1: The cloud got darker.
Speaker 1: The Riveters, that same team, our team, the team from the New York area.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: Pulled out.
Speaker 1: They pulled, someone got COVID or something.
Speaker 1: They didn't, I don't know.
Speaker 0: All we know, they pulled out due to quote health and safety concerns pretty suddenly.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: They just suddenly came back to the bench, like after a period ended and then they were out.
Speaker 1: It's like the team, it's like someone must have had a positive COVID test or something.
Speaker 1: So the whole team just got up and left the bubble and they're going to continue playing with the remaining five teams.
Speaker 1: Uh, so yeah, super like.
Speaker 1: now it's pitch black and there's so many dark clouds going on.
Speaker 0: But all I'll say is whatever reason they have, I respect that because they get to choose if they feel safe playing or not.
Speaker 1: Obviously.
Speaker 1: I'm not the one to stop playing.
Speaker 1: But it's still, it's just disappointing.
Speaker 1: that like, you know, you, it's like, you know, there's a little engine that could come on women's hockey, you can do it.
Speaker 1: And it's just hitting like so many, not, you know, it's already enough to go over the hurdles of just, you know, the sexism inherent in society to climb over and especially within sports to climb over that.
Speaker 1: And some of the hurdles that they're facing are that.
Speaker 1: But then there's additional roadblocks in the way as well.
Speaker 1: And it's just like, ah, it's so disappointing.
Speaker 1: What can I do?
Speaker 0: It sucks because I remember like I was Emily and I were at the first time the Isabel Cup was awarded.
Speaker 0: And it was just this feeling of like, yeah, women's hockey might be having its moment.
Speaker 0: And it's just, it keeps like not being able to lift off because of all these problems that the players have almost no control over at all.
Speaker 0: They're basically fighting like capitalism and like the institutional sexism of sports.
Speaker 0: And now COVID, like everything is just conspiring to keep them from rising up to where they really brightly deserve.
Speaker 0: This hockey is great.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: And you can't even get like, you know, they can't even like reach WNBA level.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: It's like WNBA.
Speaker 1: It's like, you know, they exist.
Speaker 1: They've been playing for a super long time.
Speaker 1: It's like, you know, it's legit.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: But it seems like somehow they have less problems than women's hockey, which is trying to make a professional league many years later than the WNBA did it.
Speaker 1: So, yeah.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: So before we get to the things today, I did dig up the recurring panels we used to do at Otacon are the Anime Club Summit.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we know that one.
Speaker 0: The Podcasters Roundtable.
Speaker 0: Remember that?
Speaker 0: Oh, OK.
Speaker 1: I guess I don't remember any one of doing those, but I guess we did.
Speaker 0: There's pictures of us and Dave and Joel.
Speaker 1: I'm sure there are.
Speaker 0: Cover Your Bases, Anime You Should See, Know Your Creators, Comics for the Manga Reader.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 1: I remember that one.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Beyond Dungeons and Dragons.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: We did do that at Otacon.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: We were like, should we call it Beyond Besom?
Speaker 0: And even they were like, nobody knows what Besom is.
Speaker 0: OK.
Speaker 1: We did the Advanced Wars one once.
Speaker 0: Advanced Wars, which I will never forget.
Speaker 0: That was a formative moment when I realized the like weird amount of authority that people will give a white person who's on a stage without knowing anything about them.
Speaker 0: When the audience clearly thought we made Advanced Wars.
Speaker 0: And despite us telling them we did not and being very clear that we were just two nerds with a podcast, the questions they asked us were the questions that a nerd would ask like Nintendo about a game.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like, how would we know?
Speaker 1: It's like the only reason we know anything.
Speaker 1: You know, I keep reiterating this.
Speaker 1: I guess people listen to geek days know this already, but it's like the only reason I look like.
Speaker 1: I know what all this stuff is because I read it on the Internet.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: If you're watching the live stream, you can see me looking shit up live to say on geek nights.
Speaker 1: For the most part, I can not.
Speaker 1: I'm not perfect.
Speaker 1: No one is.
Speaker 1: For the most part, I can tell what's real and what's not.
Speaker 1: I know how to go to Snopes or whatever.
Speaker 1: And then I learned that I read a lot of Internet constantly.
Speaker 1: So I know things because of that.
Speaker 1: I don't actually have inside knowledge or anything.
Speaker 1: But if I encounter someone who's never read any Internet, it's like, you know, you can sound like, you know, there's so much stuff to them, right?
Speaker 1: Because they don't know those things, not because they're unintelligent, just because they haven't gone through this constant work of plugging their brain into the Internet and constantly informing themselves about everything.
Speaker 0: Always the time, including a lot of really stupid crap.
Speaker 0: But anyway, things of the day.
Speaker 0: So this is, you know, I ski like skiing is actually one of my primary hobbies.
Speaker 0: Scott does not ski.
Speaker 0: That's fine.
Speaker 0: But I ski.
Speaker 0: Emily skis.
Speaker 0: But if you've never skied and you watch a movie that involves skiing, they usually show like the fancy gondola, people like skiing down a really well-groomed slope.
Speaker 0: And then they show people well-dressed, hanging out in fancy looking lodges, sipping cocktails and drinking beers.
Speaker 0: And like they imply this level of elegance to like what it's actually like to ski.
Speaker 0: So what this video is, it's an old video I just found randomly called "Shit Skiers Say" from like 2012.
Speaker 0: This is what skiing is actually like.
Speaker 0: The lodges look like shit.
Speaker 0: They all look like they were built in the 70s because most of them were.
Speaker 0: It's just this like farce of people like walking awkwardly and ill-fitting boots and tripping down stairs trying to carry beverages, eating the worst food you can imagine in like high school cafeteria looking like tables for like 30 bucks a plate, covered in mucus, trying to get GoPros to work and they're not working.
Speaker 0: Like skiing is just this mucus covered, uncomfortable mess.
Speaker 0: But it's also super fun.
Speaker 0: So I'm using this as my thing of the day just to let you see like the reality of skiing that people who ski a lot don't often tell non-skiers about.
Speaker 0: Like they don't want to tell you like, yeah, I'm literally just my face is covered in mucus the entire time.
Speaker 0: It is disgusting.
Speaker 1: When you mentioned that, you know, skiing in movies, I always think of James Bond skiing, right?
Speaker 1: And like, you know...
Speaker 0: Yeah, I know exactly where you are.
Speaker 0: The end of Inception on the snowmobiles, like that kind of skiing.
Speaker 1: Right, but I was saying like James Bond skiing always looked like some sort of, you know, he'd always probably be getting chased by someone trying to kill him.
Speaker 1: But it was always like a luxurious like place.
Speaker 1: There was not a lot of people there, right?
Speaker 1: It would like be just him, you know, and like a few other people.
Speaker 0: Some places do look luxurious, but the people are all dressed like shit, are dirty and smelly and like it's...
Speaker 1: If I could go James Bond skiing and like, I guess James Bond was usually skiing in like the Alps or something.
Speaker 1: But if I could do that, I probably still wouldn't, but I would be more likely to.
Speaker 1: It would increase the percentage chance of skiing.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so my thing of the day.
Speaker 1: So this thing of the day, there's this guy, Bruce Wang, the Chinese cowboy question mark.
Speaker 1: I don't know Bruce's story because he hasn't told it or I haven't watched every video on his channel.
Speaker 1: But he is a person apparently of Chinese descent and someone who had to learn English, right?
Speaker 1: English is not Bruce's first language.
Speaker 1: But if you watch Bruce's video, he is extremely fluent in English, way more than you would expect of someone where English is their second language.
Speaker 1: And he is fluent in English with a southern accent, which is, you know, unusual for someone like me who lives in the northern part of the United States to encounter someone where English is their second language.
Speaker 1: And I don't, you know, usually when someone English is their second language, their accent comes from the place that they're from.
Speaker 1: I guess it's true even if, you know, English is your first language.
Speaker 1: If I learn French, I'm going to speak French.
Speaker 0: You sound like an American speaking French.
Speaker 1: I'm going to have a New York French accent, right?
Speaker 0: But couple that too with the whole.
Speaker 0: like the media accent, like the quote neutral, I'm making big finger quotes, American accent, like that Midwestern thing is what most people think of it here in popular media, especially outside of America.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: But I know, for example, you know, pretty much every other language on earth has accents, right?
Speaker 1: But it would be akin to me learning Japanese and speaking with like the Osaka dialect.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: So that alone is, you know, you don't encounter it very often.
Speaker 1: So it's very cool.
Speaker 1: But Bruce's videos, what he has a thesis and his thesis is like, hey, actually the nature of, you know, he's like, hey, listen, a lot of people who learn English as their second language have pronunciation issues.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Which is true for anyone who learns anything.
Speaker 1: That's fair.
Speaker 0: Have you seen English?
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: It's like you have pronunciation issues no matter what you learn is your second language.
Speaker 1: English in particular.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 1: But Bruce's thesis is that if you try to learn with the Southern accent, that it actually makes life easier in a lot of ways.
Speaker 1: And I guess he doesn't have a study to show this, but he himself is living proof.
Speaker 1: because if you didn't see his face or have him tell you he was Chinese, if you just talk to him on the phone, you would think you were talking to a cowboy who was just born in Texas or wherever he is.
Speaker 1: So, yeah, making really awesome videos down there, Bruce.
Speaker 1: Keep it up.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: In the meta moment, we'll talk about the book club book in the main bit.
Speaker 0: Otherwise, we got nothing.
Speaker 0: We're actually writing a few new panels, like getting ready for like a round of online conventions because we're pretty much assuming there really aren't going to be conventions this year physically.
Speaker 0: So that's something that is not going to be in the second half of the show because whenever we get a panel submitted and it's accepted, there's a hard deadline and nothing gets us to finish.
Speaker 0: something like consequences of not finishing that thing.
Speaker 0: We might do it at the last minute.
Speaker 0: We have definitely put panels together and slides at Akan the day we then presented that panel.
Speaker 0: That has happened, but we didn't.
Speaker 0: Otherwise, we're still stuck inside.
Speaker 1: I don't know what's going on.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Just comment.
Speaker 1: If you're listening to this and you don't know who we are, whatever site it is that you like to use on the Internet, YouTube, Twitch, Twitter, Instagram, I don't really post there.
Speaker 0: I guess we have a Facebook.
Speaker 1: The Facebook page still exists.
Speaker 0: We got the Patreon.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you can find us on the Internet wherever you like to use Internet, whatever service that is, we're probably there.
Speaker 1: Our podcast is available on Spotify, iTunes, Google Play, you know, all the places Amazon podcast.
Speaker 1: If anyone in the world uses that, I can't imagine anyone does.
Speaker 1: We're there.
Speaker 1: We are in those places.
Speaker 1: You can come and find more of our content in those places.
Speaker 1: Do it if you really want to.
Speaker 1: We got a Discord server.
Speaker 1: We have a website with a forum on it.
Speaker 1: You can email us.
Speaker 1: My DMs are open.
Speaker 0: My DMs are actually, I realize, not open.
Speaker 0: But you can email us.
Speaker 0: Like geeknights@ferbrokrug.com just works.
Speaker 0: Scott's usually the one to respond, but I do see those emails.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: OK, so that's us.
Speaker 1: Let's go to the main bit.
Speaker 1: So we talk a lot on Geek Nights about shit talking.
Speaker 1: So what shit talking is, is when you say you're going to do something.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: So usually some sort of grandiose plan or project of some kind.
Speaker 1: And then you don't do jack shit.
Speaker 1: You don't do nothing.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: But unfinished business is different.
Speaker 1: Unfinished business is something you're actually doing.
Speaker 1: But you're having maybe a hard time finishing or you're definitely you're absolutely going to do it.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: It's not a shit talk.
Speaker 1: You say you're going to and then you're not.
Speaker 1: It's like, no, you are going to do it.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: You have like some sort of proof that you're going to do it, but you just you just can't get it done.
Speaker 1: Or you haven't started it yet.
Speaker 0: Did it.
Speaker 0: Got it pretty far.
Speaker 0: But there's something you cannot like.
Speaker 0: There's a piece that's missing that you have not been able to actually do.
Speaker 0: It's not like you shit talk and never do anything.
Speaker 0: You can't finish it.
Speaker 1: You just you've gone over the starting line.
Speaker 1: Shit talking.
Speaker 1: If you've gone over the starting line.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: You have gone a long way past shit talking.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: You are already better than most of us.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: But if you haven't gotten to the finish line.
Speaker 1: Then you're unfinished business.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: I guess if you go long enough, if you cross the starting line and wait long enough without doing anything, it might become shit talking again.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Some of those might apply here.
Speaker 0: I got a wide variety of things.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: So, you know, my original idea for this show was to talk about because on my shelf, I have a lot of books that I bought and haven't read yet.
Speaker 1: And I was like, oh, we can just talk about all these books we haven't read, including the book club book that which we're definitely going to do.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Just haven't gotten over the finish line.
Speaker 1: We got over the starting line.
Speaker 1: And rim was saying how basically other than the book club book, there is no you don't you don't buy books or like I buy.
Speaker 0: I want to read a book.
Speaker 0: I just buy it and start reading it like straight away.
Speaker 0: But I've been reading almost entirely nonfiction during covid, as we've talked about on the show before.
Speaker 0: I like to read fiction when I travel and on commutes and subways and poop at work.
Speaker 0: But when I'm home, I tend to focus on other things naturally.
Speaker 0: And I have to actively fight that if I want to read fiction at home during covid.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: I should probably.
Speaker 1: I'm going to guess I'm going to start that policy right now, because that's my already.
Speaker 1: my policy for video games is I only buy a video game if I'm going to literally install it and play it that second.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 0: Like this example of me and a friend of ours, we're talking about a book that it's a book that talks about say there's a difference between being informed about politics and actually being an effective activist.
Speaker 0: And it's about a series of essays around like, what's the difference between like, are you a hobbyist or are you an activist?
Speaker 0: And if you find out you're a hobbyist, how do you make the leap for real specifically?
Speaker 1: Usually involves spending a lot of time doing something else.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: The problem is a big part of it is like, oh, yeah, none of this shit applies to New York because machine politics are.
Speaker 0: But anyway, that's also.
Speaker 0: New York is like its own world.
Speaker 0: But yeah, my policy for a lot of stuff like video games, everything is I have been very like.
Speaker 0: I buy the thing the moment I am about to start interacting with the thing.
Speaker 1: It's a good strategy, I think, for everything I'm going to I'm going to stick to it.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: The only thing that can catch you right is the subscription services.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: It's like I have Netflix.
Speaker 1: It's not like when I'm going to go to watch Netflix, subscribe, watch, unsubscribe.
Speaker 1: That's a pain in the ass.
Speaker 0: And, you know, the most common thing to watch on Netflix is just scroll through the things you could watch until it's too late and then don't watch anything.
Speaker 1: That's exactly right.
Speaker 0: So I want to go all the way all the way back to a thing like we can jump around like recent things, old things.
Speaker 0: But the oldest thing that's a gig night's thing.
Speaker 0: that was unfinished business that I was thinking about when Scott proposed the show idea was.
Speaker 0: You might have noticed for a long time that the gig night's URL is a front row crew dot com, and it's the front row crew forum.
Speaker 0: When we started gig nights, we actually put some work into making it such that our Web site and all our stuff would support multiple shows.
Speaker 1: That's true.
Speaker 0: Our plan and we started this, we got some guest hosts on the show in those early days, was to have other people we trusted do other shows under the front row crew brand.
Speaker 0: Gig nights was just going to be one of them.
Speaker 0: We went down that road to the point that if you look at the old archive, especially like 2007, 2008, 2009, there's a bunch of episodes that are not hosted by us.
Speaker 0: Just on the feed, like two other people host gig nights using our format.
Speaker 0: And we just fucking gave up on that around 2012, I want to say.
Speaker 1: Well, I think, you know, it's well, it's because we for gig nights, we instituted the Penny Arcade rule.
Speaker 1: You know, we goes in at that time, right.
Speaker 1: We looked at Penny Arcade, right.
Speaker 1: As sort of like the model for two white dudes creating a media on their own independently on the Internet and becoming successful at it.
Speaker 1: And there's the strategy that they had.
Speaker 1: that we latched onto was and also we looked, I guess we were looking at the South Park guys, even though they're probably even worse role models of it's just like they had a schedule.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Penny Arcade schedule was Monday, Wednesday, Friday.
Speaker 1: South Park schedule was X times a year for their season.
Speaker 1: They just did it.
Speaker 0: No matter what.
Speaker 1: No matter what.
Speaker 1: They put something out, you know, even if it was at the last second or crappy.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: So you said, OK, here's our gig night schedule.
Speaker 1: We're going to stick to it.
Speaker 1: But other people did not have that sort of thing.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Where it's like they were like, here's our schedule.
Speaker 1: We're going to, you know, churn out episodes like a machine.
Speaker 1: And so, yeah, you couldn't really be added to the network if you weren't also going to be a machine of producing content.
Speaker 1: And if you were, why would you want to join us?
Speaker 1: You could just do it yourself.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: We got to this point to where we had the infrastructure, but no one was willing to put in that level of effort.
Speaker 0: That we knew and everyone is willing to put that level of effort in with everything that we would endorse.
Speaker 0: Exactly.
Speaker 0: Lots of people would put in the effort that we would not endorse.
Speaker 0: Sure.
Speaker 0: I'm sure they're out there.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: And also, what do we have to offer them?
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: It's like we you know, it's like if you're big, then, you know, you can offer people your platform.
Speaker 0: But there was a brief time like.
Speaker 0: it's interesting because there's this confluence of like especially around 2008, 2009, when there was like this podcasting bubble that then just burst and then like that's come and gone over time.
Speaker 0: But there was this weird moment when relative to all the English podcasts in the world, we were not like huge or popular.
Speaker 0: Do not read into this at all.
Speaker 0: But as a percentage of the total podcasting audience, we were a lot bigger than we are now because the platforms and podcasting are so much bigger.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I think that our pie slice size is sort of shrunk slightly over time.
Speaker 1: But the size of the pie is so big now compared to then that our percentage of the pie is way, way, way smaller.
Speaker 0: But at that time, we were like I like because I did a lot of the previous stuff.
Speaker 0: We were approached by some radio stations to do consulting.
Speaker 0: But it was kind of a pain in the ass.
Speaker 0: And we kind of just stopped talking to them after a few emails and a couple of meetings.
Speaker 1: We were on Japanese radio one time.
Speaker 0: We were.
Speaker 0: We were on Tokyo FM.
Speaker 0: We even signed the wall as guests in there.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Anyway, but we like there was this time like we were folks like that era.
Speaker 0: I started to take us toward Forman LLC, monetize and try to like make real money with this.
Speaker 0: I had an idea of could we pivot to doing this full time someday?
Speaker 0: And I kind of just gave up on that completely because I realized that this was like I was doing active effort toward this.
Speaker 0: This was a project.
Speaker 0: This was something I wanted to do.
Speaker 0: Every way to do it would either have compromised on what we liked about geek nights or compromised on our own ethics and morals.
Speaker 0: Or we realized we're not paying enough money to live the life we would want to live.
Speaker 0: And it's not that we should talk.
Speaker 0: We did all that work.
Speaker 0: And then we just said, no, we just won't monetize like fuck it.
Speaker 1: So the major, I guess, geek nights related thing that I have unfinished that I'm still slowly working on, like I worked on it the other day.
Speaker 1: It's not shit talk, you know, is basically updating our websites.
Speaker 1: So what we did is we had in the early days, we used like a WordPress.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: And then I said there were the plugins and things available at the time for WordPress did not let us do what we wanted to do.
Speaker 1: So we went through some iterations and eventually I just made a website and we got someone to make us those logos.
Speaker 1: We got Brando K to make us logos.
Speaker 0: Kat Lee for website Brando K with the logos.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: We got, you know, our friend Kat Lee to design the website that you see now.
Speaker 0: And you might notice that website is a certain.
Speaker 0: It's not a je ne sais quoi.
Speaker 0: I know exactly what it is.
Speaker 0: It is Web 2.0 is what our website looks like.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's anyway.
Speaker 1: So, yeah, it hasn't been updated, basically.
Speaker 1: You know, it works.
Speaker 1: The software that runs it is super out of date and, you know, whatever.
Speaker 1: But I guess the job done, the code isn't broken.
Speaker 1: I have to occasionally, you know, fix a thing here or there.
Speaker 1: But it's pretty.
Speaker 1: it's pretty rare, actually.
Speaker 0: And about half the time there's a problem is because I fucked something up, not because the website broke.
Speaker 0: I uploaded away because he's stupid.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean, it should be able to resist your fuck.
Speaker 0: Well, you did fix that.
Speaker 0: It can't upload away file anymore.
Speaker 1: That's true.
Speaker 1: At least not something that ends in WAV.
Speaker 1: You could rename your MP3 to WAV.
Speaker 0: If I name my MP3 WAV, there is a much deeper problem.
Speaker 1: You know, you rename your WAV to dot MP3 and then upload it.
Speaker 1: It would work.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: But then there's a much more fundamental problem that we need to address.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so the thing is for the new website, what I've had to do is we already got a new graphic design.
Speaker 1: I went through with that.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: So we've got new business cards.
Speaker 1: We've got new logos.
Speaker 1: I updated all our graphic design and all our other platforms.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Except for our website.
Speaker 1: But to update the actual website.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: First, I got to update all the backend bits.
Speaker 1: So I could just sort of do it, you know, the sort of "meh" way.
Speaker 1: Just sort of do it.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Like I did it the first time.
Speaker 1: But the problem is I'm trying to build up something that's going to like carry us even further.
Speaker 1: This one's already lasted like how long?
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Some ridiculous number of years.
Speaker 0: It has to last this long.
Speaker 0: It's like building a computer.
Speaker 0: I build a computer every eight years and just hold on to it.
Speaker 1: So I'm like fully setting up everything so perfectly.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: With automated deployments and all this stuff.
Speaker 1: Because if I can set that up, then if that is all working, then it's sort of once I get past like this one.
Speaker 1: It's like it's so slow, this beginning part.
Speaker 1: Once all of that foundation is laid, then it will take off like a rocket ship.
Speaker 1: It's like, oh, well, I can just edit code.
Speaker 1: And as soon as I push, it automatically deploys and updates the website instantly.
Speaker 1: And it's like if I have that set up to be so perfect with the CI/CD that we've talked about on Geek Nights before.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: And if I have all those things, then I'll be able to like, you know, develop the website itself crazy fast.
Speaker 1: And make changes to it, you know, without even, you know, right now to make changes to the website.
Speaker 1: I got like SSH in and mess around and deal with bullshit because it's so old and cranky.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: I'll be able to just, you know, oh, we want to change something on the website.
Speaker 1: One, two, three.
Speaker 1: Edit code.
Speaker 1: Push one button.
Speaker 1: It's changed.
Speaker 1: Done.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: It'll be so great.
Speaker 1: But we're still slowly getting towards that point.
Speaker 1: And then again, I just want to say, if anyone knows anyone who has the skills of website designing.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: We already have graphic design, you know, logos, aesthetic, but we need website design specifically and also HTML, JavaScript skills to turn that design into a reality.
Speaker 1: We have money.
Speaker 1: And once I get past that hurdle, we're going to need someone to do that because otherwise the website will just be black text on a white background because I don't have those skills.
Speaker 0: You do not want to see what we're going to put together in CSS by ourselves.
Speaker 1: I mean, I could do it if we want to go for a different aesthetic, like, you know, GeoCities aesthetic.
Speaker 0: Hypnospace.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Hypnospace aesthetic.
Speaker 1: I could just do it myself, but we don't want that.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: So hit us up if you want money or know someone who wants money who can deliver.
Speaker 1: Professional level, though.
Speaker 1: We're not looking for, you know, live journal level.
Speaker 1: We're looking for like pro tier.
Speaker 0: So this came up the other day because we're going to pay pro money.
Speaker 0: We were I was looking at in an unrelated conversation, I was looking at like, what are people watching?
Speaker 0: because my YouTube channel actually get like.
Speaker 0: there is a lot of views on my YouTube channel.
Speaker 0: Like there's a constant churn.
Speaker 0: But weirdly, most of the views on any given day, unless except during like convention season where we make new panels and upload them, like only a few hundred people really watch these live streams either at the time we do it or like after the fact.
Speaker 0: Most people are really on our channel for like the video essays and the panels, but the videos that consistently get the most views now are those utenna videos, also the most comments.
Speaker 0: And as you notice, like people keep bugging us about it.
Speaker 0: We haven't made more.
Speaker 0: We've talked about in the past why we haven't made a lot more.
Speaker 0: But the reason I bring it up in the unfinished business is that I actually have like about a third completed a new episode of that.
Speaker 0: The only reason we have not continued and actually made the videos is that it's only fun to make them when Scott and I sit on the couch and record it together.
Speaker 0: Making panel content or really any video content that involves both of us remotely kind of sucks as to do like.
Speaker 0: it's not as fun.
Speaker 0: This is fun doing the live stream because this is like the only time I talked to Scott, like I miss this, but doing like a panel, it's just imagine everything we do to do a panel at a con, but way less fun and way harder.
Speaker 0: Like I got to tear my living room apart and set up all these fucking lights.
Speaker 0: And the only reason we have not uploaded a new video is that I don't want to do it unless Scott and I can sit on a couch together to record that main bit.
Speaker 0: And that sucks, but like that is literally the only reason we have not uploaded one.
Speaker 0: I've done 100% of the pre-production for the next episode.
Speaker 0: Along those lines, the thing I didn't even shit talk about, but I hinted at, remember way back I made that Five Nights at Freddy's video?
Speaker 0: It's like scarily popular, but it's the only video essay I've ever uploaded.
Speaker 0: I've like half written five or six more of those.
Speaker 0: Like they're like, I wrote a script.
Speaker 0: I have a teleprompter time script, like partially complete.
Speaker 0: I have slides.
Speaker 0: I have like everything I need to do them.
Speaker 0: I just haven't done them.
Speaker 0: And again, it's just because during COVID, I don't like to have to tear apart my living room and set up a video studio and I'm maybe I'm just too prideful and I'm unwilling to do it shittily, like just sit down at the computer and do it like this.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: But meanwhile, you look at someone like Sausage Guy, he's just slapping together YouTube videos.
Speaker 1: He's already got a YouTube thing on his wall.
Speaker 1: We don't have that.
Speaker 0: That's why I bring that up as like a personal struggle.
Speaker 1: He's making like one minute videos, just slapping down a sausage with probably his phone camera, who knows what.
Speaker 1: It's like we're sitting here, like, you know, trying to make everything, you know, so, so perfect.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: And that's something we've struggled with for our entire lives, I think.
Speaker 1: And yeah, it's like I hold this like a certain standard I have of production quality.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: And it's like in other areas, I've been able to overcome that.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: So, for example, recently, you know, I got the the bike to nowhere trainer thing.
Speaker 1: I guess mid mid last year and I used it a bunch.
Speaker 1: Then I didn't use it a bunch.
Speaker 1: Then I've used it off and on.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: The past few weeks, I've been using it a bunch again.
Speaker 1: And, you know, I kept like at first I was just riding.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: And streaming it on Twitch.
Speaker 1: Then I sort of was doing the in the in game training programs.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: And streaming that also.
Speaker 1: But then when that ended, it's like there wasn't another in game streaming program that looked good.
Speaker 1: And I started watching those videos from that Dylan guy who was my thing of the day and learning about how to make your own bike training program and all this stuff.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: And even though that made me want to do it more, it ended up making me do it less because now I was like, well, I can't ride until I get this training program just right and figure this shit out.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: So I'm kind of thinking I'm going to shit my talk myself a little.
Speaker 0: I think what I'm going to do to break this like hurdle is I'm going to you know what else you talk.
Speaker 0: I'm going to bring back the rims rants.
Speaker 0: I used to do that Friday nights, but I'm going to force myself to do it every week, no matter what.
Speaker 0: And if I'm unwilling to set up the real camera and make it look good.
Speaker 0: Well, fuck you.
Speaker 0: You got to use the shitty webcam like.
Speaker 0: that's the problem.
Speaker 1: Just do just do just do it.
Speaker 1: You can force yourself to make a shitty one to be like it's phone camera.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: That's it.
Speaker 1: Exactly.
Speaker 0: Like I'll just I'll just stand in the shower just like all this thing.
Speaker 1: My phone camera is actually my phone camera is actually way good now because I got a new iPhone.
Speaker 0: I mean, I'm going to force myself to do that every other week.
Speaker 0: The Friday episode of Geek Night starting next Friday.
Speaker 1: So what I ended up doing that's been getting me to bike, you know, more again is a I'm doing it in the morning before work because like doing it after work.
Speaker 1: It's like it sort of eats time out of my day.
Speaker 1: If I do it before work, it's like I didn't lose time.
Speaker 1: What was I doing with that time?
Speaker 1: Nothing.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: And the other thing is that now I'm basically I basically just lowered the bar instead of you know, I had this like training program set up like do X watts for X minutes.
Speaker 1: Now all I do and I and for like X amount of time.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: It's like a spike for an hour.
Speaker 1: I basically said, you know what?
Speaker 1: Fuck it.
Speaker 1: I'm just going to turn on this thing and pick random route.
Speaker 1: I don't care where where I ride or if it's a hill or not or whatever.
Speaker 1: And I'm just going to bike for 30 minutes only and just by lowering it and not caring so much.
Speaker 1: I'm doing it more, which is way better than if I hold myself to some high bar and then don't do it at all.
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: It's vastly superior.
Speaker 1: Just do this.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: And it works.
Speaker 1: It's like I feel, you know, healthier, I guess.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 0: So remember way back.
Speaker 0: We can wrap up after a couple more because the Rangers game started.
Speaker 0: But way back we had this idea that we weirdly put way more effort into than I expected us to.
Speaker 0: That whole president of the Internet thing.
Speaker 0: Remember that?
Speaker 0: I found what I think.
Speaker 0: I found the metadata.
Speaker 0: Like I have a database of where I've stored data that I have in complete cold storage.
Speaker 0: Like it's not accessible.
Speaker 0: I think I have.
Speaker 1: I think a lot of that was stopped by.
Speaker 1: what happened in the real world made that no longer a good idea.
Speaker 0: That's exactly what I was going to bring up with the idea.
Speaker 0: We had an idea because we've gone on for a while.
Speaker 0: Get in all the details.
Speaker 0: We had this idea and we wanted to make like a video series and do a thing with this idea.
Speaker 0: But the real world happened in such a way.
Speaker 0: Not that like, oh, that idea is bad.
Speaker 0: It's that in the real world, if other if that actually happens, it looks way like it is not a good thing for society.
Speaker 1: No.
Speaker 0: Like it is a bad thing.
Speaker 0: that is dangerous.
Speaker 0: Sometimes the reason you don't finish something is not that like you weren't trying hard.
Speaker 0: It's that the world changed.
Speaker 0: Like say you get really, really, really good at, I don't know, making funny animations and uploading them to your website, like a collegehuber.com.
Speaker 0: Say you make a fun little website and then the world changes and you can't monetize that anymore.
Speaker 0: And you're just gone.
Speaker 0: There's nothing you could have done to prevent that if the world just changes around you.
Speaker 0: because like what you were doing does not apply to a later world.
Speaker 0: I was just thinking about that with that whole president of the internet because what a good idea that was a bad idea that ever was.
Speaker 1: Very bad idea.
Speaker 0: I also have a sort of a success story in that I was very into music.
Speaker 0: Like I would like compose stuff and play my trumpet and everything and I kind of stopped doing it for like more than a decade.
Speaker 0: But I always told myself I'd start it up again and then stop it.
Speaker 0: Start it up again and stop it.
Speaker 0: Like oh I should start composing again.
Speaker 0: Start learning some software then I don't do it.
Speaker 0: I did force myself during COVID to actually just start practicing my trumpet again and the way I was able to do it was I stopped having a goal of to be able to do X. Like it was no longer get good enough at my trumpet to like go do a gig thing or to make a video or start composing music again to upload something to Geek Nights.
Speaker 0: Like hey I made a song.
Speaker 0: I literally just started doing it to do it and enjoy it intrinsically with no goal at all.
Speaker 0: And I've been playing my trumpet consistently since March and I'm actually getting close to as good as I used to be again.
Speaker 0: And it feels real good and you're never going to see videos of it because I'm not doing it for you.
Speaker 0: I'm doing it only for me.
Speaker 1: Mmm.
Speaker 1: I think the only other thing I could think of right that is...
Speaker 0: Oh I have like 50 things on this list of projects that have stalled out in my life that I really care about.
Speaker 1: That's a lot.
Speaker 1: Oh no.
Speaker 0: One of them involves a brand that I'm just not going to bring up because I don't want to even invoke the drama of that brand.
Speaker 0: But that's the thing that we have paused waiting for things to cool down and see if it's a thing we want to do or not.
Speaker 1: Oh okay.
Speaker 1: But yeah the only other one that I can think of is there was a... You know I do a lot of photography action right?
Speaker 1: I got all these cameras.
Speaker 0: I'm looking up at my GX1 and the zoom lens that are sitting right there.
Speaker 1: I got a whole pile of cameras up there right?
Speaker 1: And I never planned to do it professionally.
Speaker 1: I have no interest in that right?
Speaker 1: It's not a fun job or anything.
Speaker 1: I just like doing it.
Speaker 1: But the thing is when you're a photographer it's like you try to find like what is your style, what's your angle, what's your thing right?
Speaker 1: You know you could be maybe someone who shoots owls or something.
Speaker 1: There are people who do that.
Speaker 1: All they do is photograph owls.
Speaker 1: Like they're the owl photographer.
Speaker 1: There's a guy.
Speaker 1: He's the squirrel photographer.
Speaker 1: All he does is photograph squirrels right?
Speaker 1: That's his thing.
Speaker 0: You know what?
Speaker 0: Now I'm just having flashbacks to when we went to Australia and you kept making fun of me.
Speaker 0: Because I kept documenting every time I found a utility door that was labeled with what's in there in Melbourne.
Speaker 1: But anyway so I was trying to like well what's my thing right?
Speaker 1: What can I do?
Speaker 1: So I thought about like you know what do I like to look at right?
Speaker 1: And that's what I should probably photograph.
Speaker 1: So I thought you know that's my favorite things to look at.
Speaker 1: is you know when I'm biking around the city right?
Speaker 1: I like to look at people having fun you know around the city.
Speaker 1: You know because you don't see it's the part of the city you don't see if you know you're not biking around.
Speaker 1: If you're in a car or if you don't live here right?
Speaker 1: You don't see like you know a birthday party in the park right?
Speaker 0: Oh that is that is literally my favorite part of running those half marathons.
Speaker 0: The one thing I can kind of do during COVID.
Speaker 0: Because you get to Randall's Island and you'll see like a family by themselves in a field just having a little birthday party.
Speaker 1: One time I biked to the secret beach and there was I don't I forget what like what their culture was.
Speaker 1: But basically they were having a celebration for a new a new baby right?
Speaker 1: And it involved drinking a beverage that I had not heard of.
Speaker 1: that was very alcoholic obviously right?
Speaker 1: And maybe I don't know if it was like you know Christian or Catholic or baptism in any way.
Speaker 1: But they still wanted to put the baby in the water or something right?
Speaker 1: So that's why they were at the secret beach having a good time.
Speaker 1: And they of course had the table full of all the catering trays full of delicious food right?
Speaker 1: So I'm just sitting there biking eating my you know ice cream whatever I was eating right?
Speaker 1: And these people made friends with me.
Speaker 1: they're like hey you know we're celebrating the baby you want to drink our beverage?
Speaker 1: And I'm like no sorry I would drink your beverage if it didn't have poison in it though you know.
Speaker 1: Hey you know having a good time talking about stuff right?
Speaker 1: The problem is is that a lot of those things right?
Speaker 1: If you just go around photographing that kind of stuff right?
Speaker 1: There's like children there right?
Speaker 1: Or you know there's problems you know with some of those things right?
Speaker 1: Oh let me go.
Speaker 1: there's a beautiful children's birthday party in the park let random strangers start photographing it.
Speaker 1: No let's not do that right?
Speaker 1: But the one thing I saw in parks that I could photograph was amateur sports right?
Speaker 1: There's people playing all kinds of sports in the park right?
Speaker 1: You get your cricket out in Queens you know and you see a lot of sports that like you know are not normal right?
Speaker 1: You see stuff like.
Speaker 1: there's people who play like hockey on fixies on a basketball court in Brooklyn.
Speaker 0: I've seen that happen.
Speaker 0: There's a roller hockey rink that has some like serious like amateur play at 96th street.
Speaker 1: Oh that one I was talking about the one in Brooklyn Bridge Park where I went.
Speaker 0: Oh yeah I know that one too but 96th street is where like I've stopped and actually watched them play sometimes on my runs.
Speaker 0: Because they're going hard when they're playing hockey.
Speaker 1: I'll have to check that one out.
Speaker 1: you know there's tennis right?
Speaker 1: There's all kinds of stuff and the people who are playing these sports are usually adults right?
Speaker 1: You know little league games are happening in closed places right?
Speaker 1: Not just in public parks where someone reserves.
Speaker 1: you know the park right?
Speaker 1: So I was like hey every single time I went to talk to people hey can I photograph your game?
Speaker 1: They were like please do send us the photos.
Speaker 1: oh my god here's my content.
Speaker 1: you know the whole thing.
Speaker 1: I have business cards right so they could find the photos after I upload them.
Speaker 1: I set up the whole thing.
Speaker 1: I did it several times for like a few years.
Speaker 1: I would go on the weekend.
Speaker 1: I'd bike around until I found a sport.
Speaker 1: I would photograph the hell out of it.
Speaker 1: I would you know curate, edit, upload.
Speaker 1: There's a website full of them.
Speaker 1: I had an Instagram account.
Speaker 1: I still have it.
Speaker 1: I didn't used to have it right?
Speaker 1: The Facebook page is gone because Facebook turns off your Facebook page if you don't update it enough.
Speaker 1: But I was just trying to be on every platform right?
Speaker 1: And I did that a whole bunch.
Speaker 1: It wasn't a shit talk.
Speaker 1: I did it like many many times.
Speaker 1: you know quite a few.
Speaker 1: But then I just stopped doing it because I wasn't you know biking to see sports.
Speaker 1: And you know I didn't have the time or I was you know ended up doing other things.
Speaker 1: Even though it would still I would still like.
Speaker 1: it was like a whole summer went by.
Speaker 1: Where like every like Saturday I'd wake up.
Speaker 1: I'd be like let's go biking.
Speaker 1: And instead and I'd be like oh I should go I should go do sports photos right?
Speaker 1: But instead of doing that I would just bike really far upstate instead.
Speaker 1: And obviously if you do that you're not seeing any city sports when you do that right?
Speaker 1: I'm leaving the city taking the train home or something like that.
Speaker 1: So I just haven't done it in so long.
Speaker 1: But I basically wanted to just.
Speaker 1: my idea was just keep doing it until at least someone notices.
Speaker 1: Even if I was even if I was doing a shitty job I don't think I was doing that great.
Speaker 1: But you know people thought I was doing great.
Speaker 1: At least the people who were in the photos occasionally thought it was great.
Speaker 1: So you know.
Speaker 1: and then it's like now you got a pandemic that stopped the whole thing right?
Speaker 1: Even harder than it was already stopped.
Speaker 0: That's something to bear in mind too.
Speaker 0: Part of it like.
Speaker 0: I think you need to internalize this message if you're feeling doubt about not creating stuff.
Speaker 1: But let's not fool ourselves.
Speaker 1: I stopped.
Speaker 1: The last one I did was several years ago not you know March 2020.
Speaker 0: But for everything you think like oh I have this unfinished business this thing that I just got to get going again.
Speaker 0: There's a lot of reasons why you might have gotten that thing going again recently.
Speaker 0: And that's pretty normal.
Speaker 0: Like for everything you see us do there's like 10 things that we just gave up on or failed at.
Speaker 0: Or are still like trying to get going but can't quite get it off the ground.
Speaker 0: Don't think that just because we do geek nights constantly that we succeed at everything we do.
Speaker 1: Yeah I definitely.
Speaker 1: if I could retire for real I could do that like twice a week and still have plenty of time right?
Speaker 0: Oh my god.
Speaker 0: if I could retire for real I would do geek nights.
Speaker 0: I would make content creation and a bunch of stuff like this my full-time job.
Speaker 0: But I can't.
Speaker 0: I gotta pay bills.
Speaker 1: Right and like.
Speaker 1: this wasn't shit like for example right that time that I went out to that roller hockey rink.
Speaker 1: It's like I buy.
Speaker 1: I was biking around without cameras.
Speaker 1: I saw the roller hockey rink.
Speaker 1: I talked to the people there.
Speaker 1: I asked them when they were playing.
Speaker 1: they said they were playing they that like the league is there on like Wednesday nights or something like that.
Speaker 1: And I went over like I was going there after work.
Speaker 1: I brought everything to work.
Speaker 1: I went there after like it was a job after work or you know I was really doing it.
Speaker 1: Not not even close to shit talk but I just haven't done it in a long ass time.
Speaker 1: Alright so unfinished business.
Speaker 0: And I think that's enough because I haven't even checked the score of the Rangers game.
Speaker 0: so.
Speaker 1: It's 0-0 but stupid Lou Mew is in the box again of course.
Speaker 0: Of course when Tony Deal will be in there next it will be a 5 on 3.
Speaker 1: Looks like they're killing it off.
Speaker 1: alright we'll see.
Speaker 0: So yeah don't fault yourself for having unfinished business.
Speaker 0: everyone has unfinished business.
Speaker 0: Don't force yourself to finish business.
Speaker 0: that's not satisfying unless you have a good reason to.
Speaker 1: Avoid shit talk avoid bowling ball but don't feel bad about an unfinished business.
Speaker 0: Yeah because if you started something and put effort into it that is more than like most people are ever able to do about anything.
Speaker 0: Like that is a good step.
Speaker 0: This has been Geek Nights with Rim and Scott.
Speaker 0: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at FrontRowCrew.com for show notes, discussion news and more.
Speaker 0: Remember Geek Nights is not one but four different shows.
Speaker 0: Sci-Tech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: Geek Nights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: Geek Nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 1: But unlike those other late shows it's actually recorded at night.
Speaker 0: And the Patreon Patreons for this particular episode of Geek Nights are Alan Joyce, Heidi McNichol, and Keegee.
Speaker 0: Graham Finch, you hold the key to my heart now.
Speaker 0: Go through the last year or so of podcasts and make room.
Speaker 0: St.
Speaker 0: Clinton, Walton, Repton, New Zealand, Ryan Perrin, Review, Mad Bull, 34, Cowards, Dread, Lily Tenebrae, just like a dude guy.
Speaker 0: Chris Reimer, Finn, Shervin Von Horl, and a bunch of people who do not want me to say their names.
Speaker 0: Yeah looks like the NWHL game for everything we talked about.
Speaker 0: The dark bad luck cloud hanging over it.
Speaker 0: Looks like now the game was cancelled because of additional COVID issues.
Speaker 0: So yeah, we'll see how long any sports continue in the US.
Speaker 0: But for now, I leave you with... Oh boy!
Speaker 0: Seven!
Speaker 0: Say, did you ever kill a giant?
Speaker 1: Seven!
Speaker 1: I killed seven giants with one blow!
Speaker 1: Seven with one blow!
Speaker 1: How many?
Speaker 1: Six!
Speaker 1: Seven!
Speaker 1: With one blow?
Speaker 1: Jiminy Cricket!
Speaker 0: Who?
Speaker 0: The tailor!
Speaker 0: Do you mean it?
Speaker 0: Seven!
Speaker 0: With one blow?
Speaker 0: No!
Speaker 0: Yes!
Speaker 0: Seven with one blow!
Speaker 0: Seven!
Speaker 1: Did you kill seven at one blow?
Speaker 0: Uh, yes your honor.
Speaker 0: And how?