Speaker 0:
Speaker 1: It's Wednesday, December 29th, 2021.
Speaker 1: I'm Rym.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott.
Speaker 1: And this is Geek Nights.
Speaker 1: Tonight, in the last episode of 2021, we will be reviewing the French animated feature, The Summit of the Gods.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: So, uh, I've ended up for various reasons watching a lot of British game shows on YouTube, Taskmaster in particular, and also...
Speaker 0: That's all you got going on.
Speaker 1: But also a bunch of skiing videos, and, uh, also a bunch of true crime videos.
Speaker 1: And it was interesting to see how people using our TV, and us using our TV, like our IP address, even if YouTube is not logged in, what YouTube thinks the people who tend to be in this house watching YouTube on the HDPC or from this IP address like to watch.
Speaker 0: Well, if you're logged in, it will, you know...
Speaker 1: If you're not logged in, it also definitely does that.
Speaker 0: If you're not logged in, absolutely, right?
Speaker 0: But if you're logged in, it will only check things that were viewed by that user that's logged in.
Speaker 1: It is fascinating.
Speaker 0: I don't get recommendations for things that other people in the house watch, but as soon as you log out, suddenly you see all kinds of stuff.
Speaker 1: It is just fascinating to see what YouTube recommends when the HDPC is not logged in versus when I'm logged in.
Speaker 1: But at the same time, sometimes I'll see something interesting when I'm not logged in, and then I go to like it, like,
Speaker 1: "Ah.".
Speaker 1: But then I have to log in to like it, and then it starts polluting my YouTube recommendation engine.
Speaker 1: That was the most exciting thing I have to talk about since the last time we did a show.
Speaker 1: Everything that happened the previous week just disappeared from my brain.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I know.
Speaker 0: I definitely had some opening bits, and I said before the last show, like, "Hey, we got a pile of opening bits because we haven't done a show in a
Speaker 0: while.".
Speaker 0: But as soon as we do the show, we'll use like one of those bits, and all the other ones will disappear from our minds.
Speaker 1: It's like a write-many-read-once heap.
Speaker 1: You put things in the heap, but if you ever read what's on top of the heap, like to say it on heap nights, the heap gets emptied instantly.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you get one random item, and then it's it.
Speaker 0: Is there a game to be made with that mechanic?
Speaker 1: So thanks to Google Photos, and it's like, "Hey, remember when you did
Speaker 1: this?".
Speaker 1: So we did do something.
Speaker 1: So over the weekend, we wanted to go hiking, but because of all the holiday travel, we did not want to leave the city because we did not have to deal with coming back into the city with a million million people traveling.
Speaker 1: So for the first time in my life, we did an urban hike, as in, we just started walking.
Speaker 1: We walked up to Astoria over the RFK around Randall's Island, and we walked from the top of 125th Street down to Central Park and just kept going.
Speaker 1: We went like, I forget how many miles we went, but we used to spend all day just walking through New York.
Speaker 0: I mean, I've done the, not as like an intentional thing, like I'm going to walk, but I've been like, "I will go to that place.
Speaker 0: I will walk to get there and have walked far as a
Speaker 0: result.".
Speaker 1: Yep, done that, but that was the furthest I've ever walked in one go in New York.
Speaker 0: I guess usually the circumstances where I did that were usually the weather's good, I'm in this place now, the next place I have to go is all the way over there, and I don't have to be at that place for a significant amount of time.
Speaker 0: If I take the train, I'm going to be sitting around there waiting.
Speaker 0: I will walk there instead.
Speaker 1: Where I usually do that walk was either to MSG from like my work in ancient times when we would go to hockey games together, or walking to Astoria-Kaufman from home was like the other one.
Speaker 0: Before there was a city bike, yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah, now there's a city bike, that kind of changed everything.
Speaker 1: So, the walk was good, but it made me realize something.
Speaker 1: I have not been in the interior of Central Park in like six years.
Speaker 0: I think I biked through it this year.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I biked through it a bunch, but biking through Central Park, you bike around the big loop that mostly skirts the edge of the park.
Speaker 1: All that interior stuff, like all those little paths, I basically haven't been in those things in forever, because even pre-Covid.
Speaker 0: Oh, it depends which you're talking about, like the ramble or whatever?
Speaker 1: Yeah, the ramble, the walking, no bikes allowed path around the reservoir, like all those interior places, all those pavilions, the castle, like all that stuff.
Speaker 0: The zoo?
Speaker 0: You go to the awful zoo?
Speaker 1: Yeah, we didn't go into the zoo because of Covid, but we walked top to bottom of the park in the interior.
Speaker 1: And it got to the point where I had to look on Google Maps to remember where certain landmarks were in the park, because I just didn't remember anymore.
Speaker 0: No, I know where they are.
Speaker 1: You know, what street is Belvedere Castle at?
Speaker 1: Is that north or south of the reservoir?
Speaker 0: I don't know what street it is, but I could walk there if I was standing in the park.
Speaker 1: Is the ramble north or south of the reservoir?
Speaker 0: I don't know where they are relatively, but I know if I'm standing at a spot that I could walk to any individual thing by looking around at like the buildings in the distance.
Speaker 1: Oh yeah, yeah, but you pivoted pretty quick from "I still know where everything is" to not being able to answer even the most.
Speaker 0: You're asking like, because it's like, it's like, okay, if I see, you know, if I see X buildings in the distance, then I know that it's between those buildings and I walk in that direction.
Speaker 0: And then you want me to find another thing?
Speaker 0: It's like, well, I'm not, I never found that thing relative to the second thing.
Speaker 1: But the reservoir is the largest and most obvious landmark.
Speaker 1: that is the most walked past in the park.
Speaker 0: There's a lot of water going on.
Speaker 0: Anyway.
Speaker 1: Anyway, you got any news on this Wednesday?
Speaker 0: What was my news?
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: So Urasawa, Naoki Urasawa, one of the best living manga creators who made many famous mangas that you hopefully have read.
Speaker 0: Asadora, his great new manga.
Speaker 0: that is very obviously a manga that he made because it follows all of his typical storytelling tropes.
Speaker 0: All of his, you know, signature moves are on display in that manga.
Speaker 0: So if you like that, you should read it.
Speaker 0: But anyway, he has decided to release all or most, I guess not all, but the vast majority of the manga he's ever created in a digital format so that you can read it all.
Speaker 0: However, it's not in English yet.
Speaker 0: It's Japanese.
Speaker 0: So he's made a website and he made a YouTube video where he announced this on his own channel.
Speaker 0: And basically, yeah, crap ton of his manga, even going all the way back to like Yawara and stuff is available in Japanese.
Speaker 0: More is coming.
Speaker 0: He still seems to be hesitant about the manga of his I want to read most, which is Billy Bat, which is not on the list and is still not available in English.
Speaker 0: Maybe there is a pirated one trans cancellation out there somewhere.
Speaker 1: Monster was not on the first list, but it's coming in February.
Speaker 0: Monster's coming.
Speaker 0: But yeah, hopefully he can get on the English bandwagon with this.
Speaker 1: Honestly, just the way business tends to go over there, I kind of give that a 50/50 shot.
Speaker 1: I could see this easily being a Japanese exclusive forever.
Speaker 0: Somewhat unique, different case.
Speaker 0: But it is a thing where like, hey, all the Japanese media, right, mostly anime and manga, but also movies and other things, right?
Speaker 0: They're always having distributors and publishers and in between companies, right?
Speaker 0: And even when they sort of do it themselves, it's a Bandai visual situation when they do that, right?
Speaker 0: It's like, but here we have a situation where I guess he's, is he going through Shueisha or whatever his publisher is?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: You know, Viz publishes his manga in the US, so I guess Viz would have to be involved.
Speaker 1: He has a website for this now, and this is all only available in specific Japanese ebook stores.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: But still, it's like, hey, he's basically sort of going direct-ish.
Speaker 0: And I'm waiting to see, because you see a lot of comic creators are effectively sort of going direct to the world with Webtoon, right?
Speaker 0: Because you get your comic on Webtoon, that's effectively like a worldwide distro, right?
Speaker 0: Because you can get Webtoon in almost any country, and it's usually, there's translations of things, right?
Speaker 0: Even us not speaking certain languages, we can get foreign Webtoons, right?
Speaker 0: We can read them.
Speaker 0: They're in English, they've got subtitles or translations or whatever, some of them, a lot of them.
Speaker 0: So I'm waiting.
Speaker 0: It's like, hey, is there going to be a big-time manga creator who's going to be like, you know what, I'm just going to, you know, not like webcomic, but like actually ebook published to the world in all the languages.
Speaker 1: Basically a modern webcomic.
Speaker 1: I mean, I feel like that day is coming.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 0: And it's like, but do the English comic people, right?
Speaker 0: People in like the United States, you know, it's like, are they even doing that?
Speaker 0: You know, you can go to your Comixology and on Amazon or whatever and get all kinds of, you know, digital comics, you know, even mangas that are translated.
Speaker 0: But those are all from US distributors.
Speaker 0: It's like, are any of them, right?
Speaker 0: Like, is there anyone out there who makes an ebook in every language and just puts it out there for the whole world, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, direct creators pretty much know.
Speaker 0: Usually it's prose and not graphic novels doing that.
Speaker 1: And the people in the US are on the avant-garde of that, like the ones who are doing a big English direct publishing of their own works online and with, maybe they partner with a publisher for the physical version.
Speaker 1: They tend to publish only in English and really only go after the domestic market.
Speaker 0: I understand.
Speaker 0: You don't see too many ebooks for sale that are graphic novels that aren't through a publisher, distributor or something, right?
Speaker 0: The direct, like Kindle Direct is almost always just 100% prose.
Speaker 1: The funny thing is now would be a good time to do that because increasingly a lot of people have high resolution tablets or phones.
Speaker 0: A lot of people are just reading, you know, I stopped, I think this is actually, I guess, sort of an opening bit.
Speaker 0: So since April of 2006, every single month I've ordered pre-ordered comic books from DCBService.com, which is still a great business.
Speaker 0: There's no complaint with them whatsoever.
Speaker 0: And you basically, the way it works, I've talked about this a long time ago, you put in a pre-order out of, you know, the catalog of everything a comic book store can buy.
Speaker 0: And you pre-order two months in advance, you get a ridiculous discount and then starting two months after your first order, you just get boxes in the mail every month full of comics.
Speaker 0: And that's how I filled up all these shelves over a zillion, you know, 15 years, something like that, right?
Speaker 1: As me, I'm just trying to get rid of as much paper in my house as I can.
Speaker 0: Well, I'm also getting rid of, but you know, the point is, is there's some things, for example, I got 21, 22 volumes of One Punch Man over here, right?
Speaker 0: And I was digging it, and then over time I stopped digging it as much because it sort of fell into a quagmire plot-wise, right?
Speaker 0: And now it's like, I'm sort of satisfied.
Speaker 0: I've had enough One Punch Man and/or I can just read the rest digitally.
Speaker 0: I don't feel like.
Speaker 0: even if I, you know, the level that I enjoy One Punch Man, which of the early volumes is a great deal, I don't really feel the need to own the volumes, right?
Speaker 0: Like, some of these I gotta own, right?
Speaker 0: Especially ones that aren't gonna be available.
Speaker 1: I mean, there's a reason I'm not getting rid of that barely-held-together sanctuary or eagle that I got back there.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Or, you know, some of these books are legendary, right?
Speaker 0: But some of them, it's like, okay, you know, I'm not gonna read this again in my life, right?
Speaker 0: I'm only gonna live this one time, so I don't need them anymore.
Speaker 0: And also, it's like, like Rim was starting to explain, the reading experience of the digital comics has improved a significant deal.
Speaker 0: I'm reading Chainsaw Man entirely digitally.
Speaker 0: I've never owned a volume of Chainsaw Man, and I never will.
Speaker 0: Right?
Speaker 0: I'm enjoying it a lot.
Speaker 0: It's great.
Speaker 0: We did an episode on it.
Speaker 0: But, I'm only just reading it digitally.
Speaker 0: That's it.
Speaker 0: Yup.
Speaker 0: So, because of, and also, a lot of things I was reading, right?
Speaker 0: So, for example, City over there, right?
Speaker 0: I feel like I'm gonna keep City.
Speaker 0: I own it.
Speaker 0: I'll probably read it again before in my life, so I'm not gonna get rid of it.
Speaker 0: But, it's one volume left.
Speaker 0: That's over.
Speaker 0: It's done.
Speaker 0: It's like there's no more to buy.
Speaker 0: So, as things ended, I'm ordering less.
Speaker 0: So, actually, I didn't, for the first time in 15, 16 years, I didn't put in an order at all.
Speaker 0: There was nothing to order in the whole order form that I wanted.
Speaker 0: that was worth ordering.
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 1: I mean, I'll admit my comic reading has dried up to near zero, partly just during the pandemic, because most of the time I'm reading comics is traveling.
Speaker 1: I'll like burn through a whole series on like a work trip.
Speaker 0: I'm reading more, 'cause I finally have time to catch up on all these ones that I bought and didn't read yet.
Speaker 0: But, I'm buying less, because, you know, things, it's just less, the quantity of things that are coming out that I don't already own.
Speaker 0: 'Cause, you know, 'cause when I started buying, there was this decades of backlog of things I hadn't- Kinda like when we first started watching anime, there was a decades deep backlog of top tier anime.
Speaker 0: And by the time that I caught up on that backlog, there was a second backlog, right?
Speaker 0: But after a few waves, you know, the waveform, the amplitude gets down, right?
Speaker 0: I mean, look at games!
Speaker 1: I am just now working on finishing the campaign in Radio Commander.
Speaker 1: A game that I bought so many years ago, I struggle to say what year I bought it.
Speaker 0: Well, games take a lot longer to play, so the rate at which they come out versus the rate at which you can play them, it's like you can't catch up.
Speaker 0: But comics, it's like, I have a stack down there, I have every volume of Full Metal Alchemist, right?
Speaker 0: I'm gonna read it all and get rid of it.
Speaker 0: Probably to book off or something.
Speaker 0: Or maybe to Second Dibs, who knows, right?
Speaker 0: But, to read all those volumes, which I haven't done yet, I've read some of them, is not gonna take very long at all.
Speaker 0: It's like twenty-something volumes, that'll take me what, like a couple days, right?
Speaker 0: Way less time than Telegenji.
Speaker 1: Well, that was a matter partly of willpower.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So, yeah, Urasawa's going digital, which is kind of a big deal.
Speaker 1: Yeah, curious to see where it goes.
Speaker 1: I never actually finished Twentieth Century, boys.
Speaker 0: It's got an ending.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Monster is still, I think...
Speaker 0: Monster is much better.
Speaker 1: Yeah, Monster hit multiple points along the way where I thought, alright, it seems like this is wrapping.
Speaker 1: Oh, there it goes.
Speaker 1: So I got a couple of quick little geek bites.
Speaker 1: So I did watch with Emily just recently, because it just came out on streaming.
Speaker 1: Disney's latest animated feature, Encanto.
Speaker 0: I didn't even know this existed, so you said something.
Speaker 0: It is absolutely fantastic.
Speaker 1: I will say, and it pains me to say this, it is materially better than Raya.
Speaker 1: And I really liked Raya, but this is just a better film.
Speaker 1: Like, hands down.
Speaker 1: It's tighter, it's a musical, like a full-on stage musical, basically.
Speaker 1: To the point that they choreographed physical act singers and dancers doing these scenes like it was a stage play as reference for the animation.
Speaker 1: The songs are great, the characters are great.
Speaker 1: And all I can say is, I highly recommend you watch it.
Speaker 1: We'll review it at some point, whenever Scott sees it.
Speaker 1: I'll just leave it at that.
Speaker 1: I love the shit out of this movie.
Speaker 1: I kind of want to watch it again.
Speaker 1: It's just a spectacle.
Speaker 0: It's going to take a while for me to get back to the Disney+, right?
Speaker 0: We're currently getting close to canceling Netflix, and then, you know, going to be all HBO Max for a while.
Speaker 0: Yep, the trouble is... Because Disney+ will come next in the queue.
Speaker 1: We finished Lupin, and I thought, "Maybe we can cancel Netflix, watch all the other stuff, and pick Netflix back up once Dragon Prince comes back, and Arcane season 2 comes
Speaker 1: back.".
Speaker 1: But we just started watching Centaurworld last night, and I gotta geek-bite that show, because...
Speaker 0: I heard that it's kind of wild.
Speaker 1: It's both exactly what I expected, and nothing like I expected at the same time.
Speaker 1: It is... interesting.
Speaker 1: The way I will describe it, having watched a bunch of season 1, is that half of it is take Adventure Time, but just do the weird Pendleton Ward stuff.
Speaker 1: But instead of going weird and navel-gazing, just go absolutely nuts.
Speaker 1: But then, frame it with a 100% dead serious, animated in a completely different style for real fantasy drama.
Speaker 1: That is very gritty and real.
Speaker 1: And the dichotomy between those two stories, and where they seem to eventually be on a course for intersection, that is the story.
Speaker 1: It's abstract and weird, and it's also extremely musical.
Speaker 1: There's a song, like, every few minutes in the show.
Speaker 0: Oh, okay.
Speaker 0: It's not like Adventure Time, where it's like, song once in a while.
Speaker 1: It is like, songs move the plot, and songs might literally be happening for real as magic in the show itself.
Speaker 1: It's also very high concept, in that it almost seems to be going for this angle where the Centaurworld, with this ridiculous nonsense, it's like a magical world cut off from the rest of reality, where people are basically gods, but also don't face any conflict anymore, and might have turned themselves stupid?
Speaker 1: It's hard to say.
Speaker 1: I haven't seen enough to know where this is really going yet.
Speaker 0: Oh good, they've cancelled the rest of the kids' hockey.
Speaker 0: Good.
Speaker 1: Oh yeah, I've seen- They shouldn't have started, but okay.
Speaker 1: A whole bunch of minor leagues across a lot of sports have cancelled in the last 24 hours.
Speaker 1: A whole bunch of high school stuff got shut down in the last 48 hours too, sports-wise.
Speaker 0: Good.
Speaker 1: So yeah, I highly recommend watching at least one episode of Centaurworld.
Speaker 1: That is enough to know if you're willing to see more or not, just one episode.
Speaker 1: Because you will see both sides of that, like, the dichotomy in that one episode, and those two threads continue in every episode I've seen so far.
Speaker 1: But anyway, things of the day!
Speaker 1: So I don't know much about this show yet.
Speaker 1: I've found a place where I can watch the first episode of it.
Speaker 1: I gotta figure out where to watch it for real.
Speaker 1: I'm sure there's a fan community with English subtitles, kind of like with a lot of Korean dramas where we can see this.
Speaker 1: But I'll link to this tweet that got me excited.
Speaker 1: It's just a clip from this show that's very popular in China that seems to be running right now.
Speaker 1: And the way it seems to go down, this show is just 24, like the American show 24, but set during the Tang Dynasty in China.
Speaker 1: And it looks absolutely bonkers, and I am absolutely going to watch.
Speaker 0: There's a lot of ones like that.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: Kind of like when we saw the trailer for Kung Fu Hustle with the axis, and we were like, "Whatever the fuck that is, we have to watch it as soon as
Speaker 1: possible.".
Speaker 1: It scratched that itch in a way that nothing has scratched in a while.
Speaker 1: Like, here's some Kung Fu-looking historical drama nonsense.
Speaker 1: I'm definitely going to watch an episode of this soon.
Speaker 1: And I'll let you know.
Speaker 0: That's something that I've always talked about, is how you look in the US, right?
Speaker 0: Look at US television.
Speaker 0: There's big shows, legendary shows, especially in the sitcom department, right?
Speaker 0: You get your Seinfelds and your Friendses and your Cheerses, right?
Speaker 0: Like these mega Dallases, these big, big shows.
Speaker 1: See, the finale of M*A*S*H was like a mass cultural event in the United States.
Speaker 0: At the time, right?
Speaker 0: But at any given time, it's like, let's see, NBC sitcoms right now.
Speaker 1: Like, what's the big show?
Speaker 0: Right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like, okay, so you got like, what's it?
Speaker 0: Mr.
Speaker 0: Mayor, I don't even know what the heck that is.
Speaker 0: I have no idea what that is.
Speaker 0: Young Rock, I guess it's The Rock, right?
Speaker 0: It's like, you know, there are these shows.
Speaker 0: You know, let's see, CBS sitcoms.
Speaker 0: There are shows that are like, they're on, you know, broadcast TV.
Speaker 0: They're like big, you know, they're in this country.
Speaker 0: But like anyone in any country doesn't know what the hell these are, right?
Speaker 0: Unless they become, you know, big enough to be like, say like The Office, where like you start getting adaptations in other countries and stuff, right?
Speaker 0: But they can still have some large-ish significance, right?
Speaker 0: Some, you know, and then other countries have shows of that level, right?
Speaker 0: Every country does, right?
Speaker 0: But you basically can't see any of them, right?
Speaker 0: Outside of the countries that they are from.
Speaker 0: You know, it's like they're unique to that place only.
Speaker 0: Those are never getting translated, exported, whatever, right?
Speaker 1: And even when that happens, people outside of that market often don't understand.
Speaker 1: Like, explaining to people outside of Europe or who are deep into comics how big the Disney ducks are in the entire world, except the US.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: You know, this is something like a, I don't know, like a Saved by the Bell tier of show, right?
Speaker 0: It's like, there are Saved by the Bell tier things all around the world, you know?
Speaker 0: There's a Chinese one, an Indian one, you know, one from Uganda.
Speaker 0: There's every country, you know, Russian ones, right?
Speaker 0: Brazilian ones, everywhere, they got them.
Speaker 0: And you just, you're never going to see them unless you live in that country.
Speaker 1: Thanks a lot, now my brain, like this ridiculous, memetic, Pavlovian response, the entire theme song of Saved by the Bell is literally stuck in my head now.
Speaker 1: It's all right because I'm Saved by the Bell.
Speaker 1: Anyway, what do you got?
Speaker 0: What?
Speaker 0: Oh, my thing of the day.
Speaker 0: So, this thing has gotten really popular over the past, I guess, maybe week or two.
Speaker 0: I don't know, but it's just this website with this little word game and it updates with a new word every day.
Speaker 0: I don't know how long it's existed for, but the reason it's gotten popular is they have a very clever social media sharing mechanism.
Speaker 0: And so, the way the game works is you get a word, you know, I think it's a six letter word every day, five letter word.
Speaker 0: And you just guess what word it is.
Speaker 0: You just type in five letters and it will tell you of the five letters you typed in, right, which I think have to be a word.
Speaker 0: I don't think you can just type in five random letters.
Speaker 0: You can't just be like R-S-T-L-A, right?
Speaker 0: It'll tell you if a letter is gray, that means that letter is not in the correct word.
Speaker 0: If a letter is green, that is a letter that is in the word and is in the correct position.
Speaker 0: And if it's yellow, that letter is in the word, but it's in a different position.
Speaker 0: And so, you just keep guessing and you try to guess, you know, in...
Speaker 1: Yeah, it will not let you type in a word that is not a word.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So, I've got, you know, I tried it yesterday and today.
Speaker 0: And yesterday, I think it took me three guesses and today it took me like two guesses.
Speaker 0: You know, I did pretty good, but I forgot to share it.
Speaker 0: And sharing is the important part because after you get the answer, if you click share, let's say you tweet, right?
Speaker 0: Let's say you tweet your answer out.
Speaker 0: It'll tell you, everyone else, your score, but in your tweet, it uses like emojis and Unicode to make a little grid of squares.
Speaker 0: that shows how, you know, your solving process.
Speaker 0: Like, oh, my first guess, it was all yellow and my second guess, it was all green.
Speaker 0: somehow, if that was possible, right?
Speaker 0: But no one knows what word you guessed.
Speaker 0: They just know that you can just see how well you did just by looking at that colored grid of blocks.
Speaker 1: I'm trying for the first time right now and it's real fun.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but you can only play it once a day because they only change the word once a day.
Speaker 0: So, it's like if you play it on your phone and get it right, you can just go to your computer and just type in the right answer and get it in one shot, but who cares?
Speaker 0: It's like a big deal, right?
Speaker 0: That's not the point.
Speaker 0: And it's just a website.
Speaker 0: You go to it and you play it.
Speaker 0: It's the same word for everybody every day.
Speaker 0: So, don't let anyone tell you what the word is.
Speaker 1: It's got a good UX too in that I like how the keyboard updates to remind you what letters you've used or not so you can just focus on the puzzle itself.
Speaker 0: Also, I realize there's a hard mode.
Speaker 0: Hard mode means that all revealed letters must be used on subsequent guesses.
Speaker 0: And unbeknownst to me, and on my first day, I was just playing hard mode.
Speaker 0: I was forcing the hard mode rules on myself because I thought that was the best strategy.
Speaker 0: But apparently, I guess a pro or a move might be to guess two unrelated words that don't share any letters first and then you'll have enough to work with and just nail it on the third one with more consistency.
Speaker 0: But I was imposing the hard rule restriction on myself naturally.
Speaker 0: So, I feel like I'll just enable it from now on.
Speaker 1: In the meta moment, the Geek Night's Book Club book, Taylor Genji.
Speaker 1: I propose we do it at the end of January, but it's up to you at this point.
Speaker 1: I'm going to steamroll through.
Speaker 0: I'm hoping we're going to get through it somehow.
Speaker 0: We're going to make it happen.
Speaker 1: I slowed down a little because now when I read a chapter, I'm then going and reading a short summary of that chapter from one of those literary guides just to make sure I didn't miss anything super obvious and to remember who the characters were.
Speaker 1: I don't know if it's actually slowing me down though because I kind of read the chapter faster now that I'm doing this because I know I have this safety net at the end of the chapter.
Speaker 1: So, we'll see.
Speaker 1: That might be a technique.
Speaker 1: if any of you are slowing down.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I'm actually working on the Geek Night's website more than I'm reading the book, which may be a problem.
Speaker 0: But that's also not a problem.
Speaker 1: I'm working idly on a panel that I'm just going to do online as me because definitely not going to MagFest.
Speaker 1: If it was not obvious, we will not be at MagFest, which is coming up pretty soon.
Speaker 0: The PAX East isn't looking likely unless some kind of great thing happens.
Speaker 0: Which is possible.
Speaker 0: I hope it's possible, but very unlikely.
Speaker 0: I wouldn't bet a penny.
Speaker 1: But MagFest is happening basically a week right in the danger zone of the spike that's going to be caused by the holidays.
Speaker 0: I'm not going anywhere near that MagFest.
Speaker 0: Nope.
Speaker 1: In fact...
Speaker 0: Zero percent.
Speaker 0: Negative 1,000% chance.
Speaker 1: A few weeks ago, I was willing to go to PAX Unplugged for three hours to do a panel wearing a mask the whole time, even on stage.
Speaker 1: If PAX Unplugged had been the weekend of MagFest, as opposed to then, I would have bailed.
Speaker 1: For the first time in my life, I would have called the PAX and said, "Sorry, we can't
Speaker 1: perform.".
Speaker 1: But that panel is on YouTube.
Speaker 1: If you want to see it, despite the mask, the audio sounds just fine.
Speaker 1: One thing I will share, because it's the meta moment, this was the hardest audio engineering exercise I have ever done with one exception on a panel.
Speaker 1: It is really hard to record someone who's wearing a mask and giving a talk.
Speaker 1: Good lord.
Speaker 1: But I did it, so watch this video if for nothing else than to appreciate how fucking good of a job I did.
Speaker 0: You could have dubbed it.
Speaker 1: You know what?
Speaker 1: I could have, because YouTube subtitles...
Speaker 0: You could have just given it again when you got home.
Speaker 1: I could have ADR'd it.
Speaker 1: The problem is, I did not script this panel.
Speaker 1: Because when you and I do a lecture together, we tend to script a lot more in terms of what we're going to say on each slide.
Speaker 1: When I do talks by myself, I tend to riff a lot more and often go off in strange tangents based on how the audience is reacting.
Speaker 0: But you need more tangents because you got less time.
Speaker 0: You got more time to fill in.
Speaker 1: Exactly.
Speaker 1: But also, I need clever ways to get the audience to laugh, to react enough to give me a break, to like, take a sip of water, collect my thoughts, take a breath.
Speaker 1: Usually I say something controversial that you'll react to or hand the baton to you, so I have like 30 seconds to do that.
Speaker 1: It is more than twice as hard to do a one-hour lecture by yourself than to do it with a partner, is all I'm saying.
Speaker 0: Yeah, 30 minutes versus an hour, yeah.
Speaker 0: Even if we don't split the time 50/50, it's still...
Speaker 1: Yep, still just having that relief to take a break is a big deal.
Speaker 1: Or, Scott will say a point that I forgot to get to and vice versa.
Speaker 1: All that kind of dynamic happens too.
Speaker 1: Anyway, it's on YouTube.
Speaker 1: You can just watch it.
Speaker 1: I feel like this panel is basically complete, so I don't think we need to run it again anytime soon.
Speaker 0: Maybe when I finish all this website book stuff, we'll get back to, you know, lecturing, paneling, something along those lines.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: Oh, actually, a little bird told me that Zenkai Con, which I'm not going to physically, very likely, considering the circumstances, but they're gonna have an online panel track despite having a physical con.
Speaker 0: Will anyone come to it, though?
Speaker 1: A lot of people.
Speaker 1: Not enough for anyone to make money off of this, but there is a significant contingent of people, and there's some data to back this up.
Speaker 1: Not enough for big companies or big cons to care, but definitely enough for small cons to care, who want to go to cons for various reasons, often due to disability or lack of money, can't go to cons, and they will voraciously consume online video content of panels.
Speaker 0: So my question to the listener is this, right?
Speaker 0: Let's say I did a panel, and then it's like, I could just put it on YouTube right away, but would, if you went to an online convention and they just showed a video that was already on YouTube, would that feel like cheapen it, or would you not care?
Speaker 1: Oh, but no, the main reason they're doing this is to also stream those panels on their YouTube channel during the con.
Speaker 0: Right, but it's like, or do I have, the question is really, do I have to sort of withhold the content so that the convention gets an exclusive first, or do I not have to do that?
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't know, PAX wasn't super clear on that, I just uploaded to the panel a couple weeks after PAX, just as a courtesy.
Speaker 0: Right, but it's like, do I have to do that?
Speaker 0: It's like people who are attending the online con are very unlikely to have been to my YouTube channel on their own.
Speaker 0: True.
Speaker 0: So, it's like, and regardless, it's like, so could I do a thing where it's like, I just record panels, should I just upload them all to YouTube and then tell conventions, yeah, you want some content, check out my YouTube channel, pick any video, show it, right?
Speaker 0: Or, do I have to stock up, send them to conventions, and then once all the conventions are done, then put it on the YouTube channel?
Speaker 1: So, I can't announce anything yet, because nothing has been done, but I have been talking to someone who works with a large convention, and we have an ongoing conversation now about interest in using the Geek Nights back catalogue of lectures we've given.
Speaker 0: Creative Commons license, go wild, it's all yours.
Speaker 0: Creative Commons, I can't stop you, even if I wanted to, I can't stop you, too late, past me already didn't stop you.
Speaker 0: So, I can't stop past me either, past me is already gone down that road.
Speaker 1: The other thing that I guess I'll ask the listener while we're on the stack, then we'll get into the main bit, because this movie was great, but I feel like if we, if Scott and I just record a panel on our own, like if we just do it not for a convention, because there's some topics we've wanted to do a panel on, but the con situation's still in flux, because of COVID, I feel like it's more fun.
Speaker 1: for me at least, I don't know about you, Scott, I've enjoyed when we've given a panel to a con, and then being able to just sit in the chat and react to people who are watching it live for the first time in a group, so I kind of want to use the YouTube Premiere capability.
Speaker 1: if we record a panel that's not for a con, so that it airs for the first time at like 8pm Eastern on Saturday.
Speaker 0: We could do that, we could try that one time, make a YouTube Premiere.
Speaker 1: Because I think it would be fun to be able to hang out in the chat without having to be on stage, because there's a lot of reasons we don't take questions on stage.
Speaker 0: If we just had video and screen sharing, we'd be set.
Speaker 1: There's no way that is not in the Discord hopper, that has to be like- What's taking so long?
Speaker 0: What's taking so long?
Speaker 0: Right?
Speaker 0: It shouldn't be that hard with what they've already got.
Speaker 1: Discord, need a product manager, hire me, I'll make it done, I'll make it happen.
Speaker 0: Alright, anyway, let's get into the review, because Emily saw this movie- Let me give you some background, let me give you some background info here.
Speaker 1: Oh, because I have some background background info, Emily saw this movie some time ago because of an Academy screening that she was- I got more, even farther background info on this, going back to like, you know, 15 years ago.
Speaker 1: This was one of those screenings where I couldn't even go, like I couldn't even ride on her coattails to go to this one, that's how locked down it was.
Speaker 1: So, she comes back and she's like, "This movie's amazing, you've got to see it, oh wait, you
Speaker 1: can't.".
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: So, back in mid-2000s, when Geek Nights was early, I guess later 2000s, we were going to mocha festivals, and mocha festivals were still in, like, you know, the armory, or even the puck building, right?
Speaker 0: One of the booths that I always saw.
Speaker 0: there was a publisher, Fanfare, slash, I'm going to pronounce this wrong, I'm sorry, Ponemon?
Speaker 0: I guess it's French, right?
Speaker 0: And they publish many, you know, they're really, at least in the
Speaker 0: U.S.,
Speaker 0: it's a very small publisher in the
Speaker 0: sorry, importing, you know, various works, translating them and whatnot, right?
Speaker 0: Like, really boutique graphic novel selection here, right?
Speaker 0: And one of the things that they did is they had, I believe they still have, like, the U.S.
Speaker 0: exclusive license for distributing the works of Jiro Taniguchi, right?
Speaker 0: If it's a Jiro Taniguchi manga in the
Speaker 0: U.S.,
Speaker 0: they publish it.
Speaker 0: And I had a, you know, very "I recognize your face" relationship with the guy who would always work at that booth.
Speaker 1: That is, I can't remember the names of half the game publishers I talked to at PAX's or whatever, but I remember exactly what they look like when they're standing behind their own booths.
Speaker 0: Yep, and so one of the works that I noticed at that booth, I think one of the last, you know, was Summit of the Gods, right?
Speaker 0: Which is, I believe, it's five or six volumes in total.
Speaker 0: I don't know if all of them are out, but I knew, that's how I knew it existed.
Speaker 0: I knew that this was a manga about mountain climbing from Jiro Taniguchi that was available in whole or in part in English.
Speaker 0: And that it was, like, you know, legendary and great, and I hadn't read it, and I still haven't read it.
Speaker 0: But I have read other Jiro Taniguchi works.
Speaker 0: So, Jiro Taniguchi, I think, passed away, like, a few years ago.
Speaker 0: It might have been news on this show.
Speaker 0: But if you don't know, Jiro Taniguchi is this manga/gekiga creator who is in, sort of, this unique space on his own.
Speaker 0: And that, first of all, it seems to me, like, the impression that I've always gotten is that France loves him way more than Japan does.
Speaker 0: That's just, like, this impression that I've gotten because his works just seem to be huge in France.
Speaker 1: Also, like, another one of his comics was adapted into a live-action Belgian movie.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: In fact, the most recent book of his that I bought and own is The Guardians of the Louvre.
Speaker 0: There's a series of graphic novels.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, you were talking about that.
Speaker 0: Right, there's a whole series that the Louvre commissioned, right, from various graphic novel creators around the world to each draw, to each create an individual comic that involved the Louvre.
Speaker 0: You know, so I got one from the JoJo creator, right?
Speaker 0: Urasawa's got one, right?
Speaker 0: I got the Jiro Taniguchi one.
Speaker 0: And so what Jiro Taniguchi does is, sort of, unique in the manga space, at least in terms of mangas that are accessible to the US market, is that his works generally don't involve sci-fi, fantasy, magic, anything unrealistic at all, right?
Speaker 0: They're almost always some sort of, you know, human drama.
Speaker 0: that is, you know, I don't say, not adult porn adult, but adult and, like, children would be bored out of their minds.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, the movie we just watched, a child would just be like, "This is just old people on a
Speaker 1: mountain.".
Speaker 0: It's like, here's some people doing a thing, right?
Speaker 0: It's about human emotions and things that can actually happen, could have actually happened, or did actually happen.
Speaker 0: And they're generally all, like, amazing, and it's the artistic style of his that the movie captured very well, even though it wasn't perfect, we'll get to that, artistic-wise, we'll get to that in a second.
Speaker 0: But when you look at his character designs, right, they're sort of in that space where it's, like, you can tell that it was, you know, a manga creator who drew those people, right?
Speaker 0: But it's not, like, triangle chin Evangelion Naruto, right?
Speaker 0: It's much, you know, and I think that it's much closer to, you know, in this in-between space, right, between, of more, like, a realistic human depiction, but still a simplified manga depiction.
Speaker 1: But much like the creator- I mean, you could say the same thing about some of Urasawa's work, like- Sure.
Speaker 0: But Urasawa has, like, that sort of, like, style that's particular to him.
Speaker 0: You can just tell that's an Urasawa face.
Speaker 0: Especially his little eyebrow he'd always draw.
Speaker 0: Anyway.
Speaker 0: But the backgrounds, much like in Death Note, are, like, just these incredible backgrounds, right?
Speaker 0: That just, like, someone spent way too much time drawing because they had nothing better to do, right?
Speaker 1: No, you're right on the France thing, too, because he actually was knighted as a Chevalier of the order of art and, like, some big order.
Speaker 1: He's a knight.
Speaker 0: Rym's checking out Wikipedia, probably.
Speaker 1: You realize I stream my desktop while we're doing Geek Nights, so people can see exactly what I'm looking at.
Speaker 0: Oh, so everyone can see that you're looking at the Wikipedia?
Speaker 0: Okay, yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah, all right.
Speaker 0: But, yeah, so that's who Jiro Tanaguchi is, sadly passed away a few years ago.
Speaker 0: Legendary, legendary manga creator.
Speaker 0: If you see Jiro Tanaguchi's name on a manga, it's probably good.
Speaker 0: You should probably just read it.
Speaker 0: So, this movie is an animated 90-minute adaptation of the manga, Summon of the Gods, and it came out very recently, and it's on Netflix, I believe, exclusively in the US.
Speaker 1: Yep, and it only recently appeared on Netflix, like, just, like, you can watch this now, and we couldn't have said that.
Speaker 1: I don't know when it actually hit.
Speaker 1: Let's see.
Speaker 0: And it's only 90 minutes long-ish, right?
Speaker 0: It's not one of those mega-log movies.
Speaker 0: You can just watch this one real quick.
Speaker 1: Oh, longer than I thought.
Speaker 1: It hit on November 30th.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and it's actually, you know, you might think, "Oh, this is an anime
Speaker 0: movie.".
Speaker 0: No, it's a French movie.
Speaker 0: It was made by French studio, right?
Speaker 0: The original language is French.
Speaker 0: Don't watch Japanese with English subtitles.
Speaker 0: Watch French with English subtitles.
Speaker 0: It's in France.
Speaker 0: It's in French, even though this is something really interesting that I'm gonna give a lot of credit for, right, is that if this had been made, right, by an English, a US Hollywood animation studio, say Disney, right, they would have made it an American mountain climber, right, speaking English.
Speaker 0: These, a French studio made a movie based on a Japanese manga, and it was a Japanese mount, just like the original manga.
Speaker 0: They didn't change it.
Speaker 0: It was a Japanese mountain climber who was from Japan, right?
Speaker 0: They lived in Japan.
Speaker 0: The original dub language is French just because French voice actors were the original voice cast, but they didn't make it a French story or anything.
Speaker 0: They kept it as it was.
Speaker 0: It's a story about a Japanese people, right, who do mountain climbing.
Speaker 0: So, that's A-plus France, not euro-washing, right, at all.
Speaker 1: And obviously, this is a review.
Speaker 1: We won't spoil anything, material, because I highly recommend you watch this movie.
Speaker 1: This movie is phenomenal.
Speaker 1: I very much enjoyed it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, even spoiling, it's like, even if I told you the whole plot just straight up, it's like, there's nothing in the plot.
Speaker 0: It's not about surprises, right?
Speaker 0: It's like, you basically know as soon as you know what it's about, what's gonna happen, right?
Speaker 0: It's just so obvious.
Speaker 0: It's like, you don't make one of these stories about a mountain climber, right?
Speaker 1: It was Chekhov's "What would you do if your friend was hanging from the
Speaker 1: night?".
Speaker 0: Chekhov's Mountain, and the mountain is on the cover, right?
Speaker 0: It's like, come on people.
Speaker 0: It's not about that, right?
Speaker 0: So, basically, the plot structure is sort of this cliché of, it's about a person, but we don't see that person.
Speaker 0: Instead, we see a journalist who's investigating that person, and you get flashbacks as the journalist discovers more information about the person.
Speaker 0: And I said, while I was watching it, I said to myself, "Yeah, that's a
Speaker 0: cliché.".
Speaker 0: And the other half of my brain said, "Oh, it's a cliché?
Speaker 0: Alright, tell me one thing that has that same
Speaker 0: structure.".
Speaker 0: And the other half of my brain went, "Uh...".
Speaker 0: And then it finally said, "Oh, Citizen
Speaker 0: Kane.".
Speaker 1: Citizen Kane is the same structure, right?
Speaker 1: You're like orbiting around looking for something recent and forgetting the giant planet.
Speaker 1: that's just right there.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Citizen Kane is, you know, it's a journalist who's trying to investigate what the hell was up with Rosebud or whatever, right?
Speaker 0: And it flashbacks to show you Citizen Kane's life.
Speaker 0: So, the first half of the movie is basically that.
Speaker 0: The journalist investigating the dude, and then the second half of the movie, I don't know if it's the half, maybe final third, right?
Speaker 0: Is sort of separate in that it's sort of a different act in which, okay, you found the dude or whatever, right?
Speaker 0: And now, mountain climbing.
Speaker 0: And then that's, I guess, the climax of the movie.
Speaker 1: It's a very thoughtful ending that wraps up all of the themes.
Speaker 1: Every theme that is presented in the movie is wrapped up very neatly and very provocatively.
Speaker 1: Just the way it ends and how it ends.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean, you know, the core point of the movie is real, and I guess presumably the manga that I still probably should read, but haven't, is pretty much like, "Why the hell would you go mountain
Speaker 0: climbing?".
Speaker 1: Yeah, well, it's a little more nuanced than that because without spoiling things, look what happens to this character.
Speaker 1: On one hand, the mountain climber character, not the journalist.
Speaker 1: The mountain climber is clearly driven and definitely has that sort of, "Everyone around me is not as good as me.
Speaker 1: Even if they're my friends, I could do better by myself.
Speaker 1: No one is on my level to climb with
Speaker 1: me.".
Speaker 1: Simultaneously, he's, you know, thinking back to Master Keaton, and I'm not a master versus a professional.
Speaker 1: He's basically a professional here in that he is seeking the absolute extremes of skill to the point that he can really only rely on himself.
Speaker 1: And simultaneously, due to the tragic incident that occurs when he breaks the sort of rule he's made for himself.
Speaker 0: Many tragic incidents.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but one in particular sets the stage for him to be very internally justified in climbing by himself.
Speaker 1: Like, he almost recognizes that, one, no one is on my level, and two, anyone who tries to be on my level, I am putting them at extreme risk to the point that for the safety of others, I climb by myself.
Speaker 0: Alright, but basically it takes that question of why would you go mountain climbing, but applies it then, you know, to just all of, you know, human life, right?
Speaker 0: Like, why would anyone do anything like mountain climbing?
Speaker 0: Why would you be driven to do anything, period?
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: Right?
Speaker 0: And you just, mountain climbing is just used as a lens to examine your own goals and your own drives, you know, through it.
Speaker 0: And also, ask yourself that same question.
Speaker 1: What is mountain climbing?
Speaker 0: What would make you do 2000 podcasts?
Speaker 1: But it's a spectrum too, because look at, in the very beginning, there's that, you know, the gang of friends are all mountain climbers together, and he's complaining like, oh, like they always turn back, they start late, they turn back, like they don't succeed at most of their climbs.
Speaker 1: But they're also mountain climbers, they're also like super skilled, but they're enjoying themselves, and they're not after the same thing he's after, even though they're doing the exact same activity.
Speaker 1: Which is a topic we talk about on Geek Nights a lot.
Speaker 0: People who have the same hobby, the same interest, but enjoy it for different reasons and different ways, and don't get along as a result.
Speaker 0: Actually don't have much in common, even though you think they might, because they're both mountain climbers.
Speaker 0: But actually, no, there couldn't be more different.
Speaker 1: But it's also framed in this, because, you know, there's the other guy he's competing with who dies, because a lot of mountain climbers die trying to do this stuff.
Speaker 1: The sort of meta framing, because this is not set in modern day, is that...
Speaker 0: No, this is set, it's set in like, I think the late 90s, because you can tell by the laptop the journalist has, still has a three and a half inch floppy hole on it.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: All film cameras, like cell phones.
Speaker 0: And digital cameras came around like 2000, it was early 2000s, he probably would have moved up to a digital camera, like 2003 or something.
Speaker 0: So it's got to be late 90s, based on the technology shown.
Speaker 1: But also based on the backdrop of what is happening in mountain climbing.
Speaker 1: Because there is the simpler story of why do people do, like.
Speaker 1: that's a very common trope in this kind of story.
Speaker 1: But there's a broader point around the sort of increasing search for the extreme to do something new or different or push a boundary specifically.
Speaker 1: Because it talks a lot about how at first it was, can you climb something?
Speaker 1: And then people started climbing things.
Speaker 1: And then it started to edge into, oh, climb increasingly dangerous things.
Speaker 1: And then, all right, let's climb things we've already climbed, but make it artificially dangerous.
Speaker 1: I'll do it without oxygen.
Speaker 1: I'll do it without support.
Speaker 1: I'll do it blind.
Speaker 1: Like there's this race among the professionals of increasing risk and increasing danger that they're putting onto themselves because of the goal that they're seeking, which is arguably unattainable.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: I guess you can go to Mars and climb Olympus Mons instead, right?
Speaker 0: Yup.
Speaker 0: That'll get you.
Speaker 1: But you can almost see that this is arguably a toxic aspect.
Speaker 1: Of things like mountain biking, mountain climbing, skiing, extreme sports, in that there is a culture of pushing those limits to the extreme.
Speaker 1: When for many people, like all the people who failed to summit in the very beginning and gave up when the storm came through, like reasonable people, they're still enjoying the sport.
Speaker 1: They're still supreme experts, but they got to the point where they can do the extreme quadruple black dangerous nonsense, but they choose not to.
Speaker 1: They use that skill to do something slightly less dangerous and have more fun doing it.
Speaker 0: So yeah, so this movie, right, it's interesting because it still has some of the aspects of like an initial D, right?
Speaker 0: Like a lower brow sports manga, right?
Speaker 0: Because it gets really whoever did the research on this, right?
Speaker 0: It's so technically correct with regards to the every little detail about the methods.
Speaker 0: And, you know, when they're actually climbing the mountains, like, you know, it's like not even you.
Speaker 0: I don't know that much about mountain climbing, but you don't have to know that much to see that what they're doing is.
Speaker 0: that's the way it's done.
Speaker 1: Like they're doing that, like laying the leads and the safety ropes, like accurately the tying.
Speaker 0: Someone drew them tying knots the correct way.
Speaker 1: Or the accident with the kid.
Speaker 1: When that happens, you can see behind him the exact thing that causes the incident.
Speaker 1: The rope is like slightly curled around this tiny little piece of rock that's sticking up.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: So yeah, so that's a good, you know, you can learn, I guess, you know, if this encourages you to do mountain climbing, I would hope that you would stick to low level.
Speaker 1: Or level up.
Speaker 1: Start at your local indoor climbing gym.
Speaker 1: Because the one thing that was bothering me and that I wasn't sure how this movie was going to end was the idea that he's going to do the climb he does in the end of the movie without oxygen.
Speaker 1: And of course the journalist is going to follow him, but there is no way that journalist is capable of doing what he's about to do.
Speaker 1: So the whole time you're like the tension for the audience is, you know, there's no way he can make it.
Speaker 1: So how is this possibly going to end?
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: So that is something I think that this particular story brings attention to that not many other stories I've seen do.
Speaker 0: The only other ones I think that come close are stories I've seen about like war photography where it's like if you're a photographer, it's like, yeah, you can get a big zoom lens.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: To shoot, you know, animals or whatever from far away.
Speaker 0: But for the most part, if you're a professional photographer, certain subject matter requires you to not just be a photographer, but to also be something else.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: It's like you can't be a mountain climbing photographer if you're not a mountain climber.
Speaker 0: You can't be a skydiving photographer if you're not also a great skydiver.
Speaker 1: All those photos we have of like big sea battles in World War Two, people in planes were flying through a dogfight, like taking those photos.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: It's like, you know, some aerial photography.
Speaker 0: these days, you can get someone else to fly the helicopter.
Speaker 1: Drones have changed that to a significant degree.
Speaker 1: Like you can have a drone just follow you.
Speaker 0: Well, you still need to be a drone pilot, which takes some skill.
Speaker 1: Oh, there are completely automated there.
Speaker 1: So there's a cool set.
Speaker 1: There's a drone.
Speaker 0: There are automated ones, but there's a drone I want.
Speaker 1: But it is illegal to use pretty much anywhere I will ever ski.
Speaker 0: People just do it anyway.
Speaker 1: No.
Speaker 1: At ski mountains, you get shot down.
Speaker 0: Oh, not at ski.
Speaker 0: In the city, people just do it anyway, even though it's illegal.
Speaker 1: These are drones that you put up and they will just follow you on a program automatically without you doing anything, beginning to end.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: But, you know, it's not.
Speaker 0: sometimes you want to get a fancy shot and the automatic shot is not, you know, just like autofocuses might not get the shot you want.
Speaker 1: And the movie really makes a point of highlighting that, but it doesn't at any point address up until the final scene, wait, so how is this going to work when he follows this guy?
Speaker 1: But it really points out that Mallory carrying that camera to prove that they did it.
Speaker 1: Even the Sherpa is like, he needs you.
Speaker 1: Otherwise, there won't be any proof that he did it, which I think is very subtle because the Sherpa knows exactly how this whole situation is going to go down.
Speaker 0: So there's, it, it, it serves three purposes, right?
Speaker 0: So one, it, it gives you some focus on like, yeah, the photographers and journalists of the world who are covering subject matter that requires themselves to be there are not getting the credit of the, of their subjects.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Even though they're pretty much right there next to them.
Speaker 0: A lot of the time in some cases, right.
Speaker 0: Mountain climbing in particular, uh, be right.
Speaker 0: It gives you a way you can now see how amazing the one person is because they've put a very expert person next to them to give you that contrast, right?
Speaker 0: If they just show you a person climbing by themselves as someone without knowledge of climbing, you can't really tell how great they're doing.
Speaker 0: But I love someone next to them and you can see how much better they are than the other person.
Speaker 0: And now you can understand what's going on.
Speaker 1: I love how beautifully that is portrayed because that final act is basically the journalist.
Speaker 1: You don't see the professional climbing.
Speaker 1: You see the journalist climbing and he's following the tracks and there's a lot of environmental storytelling along the way.
Speaker 1: Like he gets to that ravine and you didn't see the professional do it.
Speaker 1: You see the journalists like figure out and like plan to do it himself.
Speaker 1: And the tension is you don't actually know exactly how the professional did it.
Speaker 1: The professional is already like miles ahead on the trail.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: Well, in fact, the first part of the movie is also the journalist following the person, right?
Speaker 1: But you see there he's taking a parallel.
Speaker 0: Once he finds him, he physically follows him afterwards.
Speaker 0: So, yeah, it's, you know, this movie, I think, you know, it doesn't make me want to do mountain climbing, although I recognize how amazing it would feel to be like at the top of a mountain and then to think I got all the way the fuck up here with nothing but my
Speaker 1: own
Speaker 0: body and some sticks.
Speaker 1: If you want to try mountain climbing without like...
Speaker 0: No, I have no idea.
Speaker 0: I have no interest in that.
Speaker 1: I have summited gothics like it.
Speaker 1: That is achievable by someone like you.
Speaker 0: But you know what it did make me want to do?
Speaker 0: What?
Speaker 0: It makes me want to go on like a plane to the bottom of the mountain.
Speaker 0: I don't want to go up the mountain.
Speaker 0: I just want to go to the bottom of the mountain.
Speaker 1: You can do glacier hiking to see those vistas without having to go up.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: I could just like fly to where Mount Everest is and just like stay at Camp One, you know, like not climb anywhere.
Speaker 0: Camp Zero, whatever.
Speaker 0: Just stay at the airport.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: You know, see, you know, I could take this stuff there.
Speaker 0: You know, see people.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: See the people are climbing, you know, look up at a sky.
Speaker 1: It's not on that scale.
Speaker 1: I've summited six of the high peaks in the Adirondacks and that is it is quite an experience to get up onto like the actual top top summit and look around you and see what it looks like from such a high vantage point.
Speaker 0: I'll go.
Speaker 0: I'll go up any mountain that can be climbed via bicycle.
Speaker 1: You could bike up Gothic if you're insane.
Speaker 0: Does it have a road?
Speaker 1: No.
Speaker 1: Mountain bike.
Speaker 0: That doesn't count, does it?
Speaker 1: You could bike up Whiteface.
Speaker 1: Whiteface has a road to the top.
Speaker 1: It's in the Adirondacks.
Speaker 0: How high is it?
Speaker 0: Very high.
Speaker 1: It's one of the high peaks in the Adirondacks.
Speaker 0: How many feet?
Speaker 1: Let me pull it up right now.
Speaker 1: Whiteface.
Speaker 1: Because that was the most boring mountain I've ever climbed up there, to be honest.
Speaker 1: Whiteface, how tall are you?
Speaker 1: About a mile.
Speaker 0: Oh, OK.
Speaker 1: The top elevation is about 5,000 feet.
Speaker 0: That's fine.
Speaker 1: The prominence of it over the land is about 3,000 feet.
Speaker 1: It's a relatively easy hike to the top.
Speaker 0: If there's a road, I could bike up that.
Speaker 0: There is a road.
Speaker 1: I don't know if people bike it.
Speaker 0: I just go slow.
Speaker 0: I go weeka weeka weeka.
Speaker 1: Biking up Whiteface.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 1: It seems like it's a thing people do.
Speaker 1: Cycling Whiteface Mountain.
Speaker 1: High.
Speaker 1: It's not even.
Speaker 1: You'll do a 3,500 foot elevation gain.
Speaker 1: Eight miles.
Speaker 1: Average gradient 8.4%.
Speaker 1: It's not that bad, actually.
Speaker 0: I'll go weeka weeka weeka.
Speaker 1: That's such a long route, though.
Speaker 1: When I climbed this thing, I basically just went straight up that steep side there.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the road probably goes like a spiral or a back and forth.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the road goes like way up and around this really easy gradient compared to what I climbed.
Speaker 1: Anyway.
Speaker 1: So, two other things that I noted about this movie that I really liked.
Speaker 1: Because I have very few complaints about it.
Speaker 1: Just one observation of something they messed up.
Speaker 0: Oh, I'll get to my complaint with the words.
Speaker 1: The complaint, and when Emily saw it, the first thing she said, and it was so obvious when you see the movie, is all the characters emote like French people and not like Japanese people.
Speaker 1: There's a lot of hand gesticulation and the way people are talking.
Speaker 1: It really stands out.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: True.
Speaker 1: But what I like is that the movie did not make a judgment or a moral pronouncement about whether or not people should do the various things that are shown in the movie.
Speaker 1: It's very much a, "We're just exploring why people do this and we're showing what they do without
Speaker 1: judgment.".
Speaker 0: Show it how it is and then that's it.
Speaker 1: It wasn't like.
Speaker 1: the end of the movie was, "See?
Speaker 1: That's what
Speaker 1: happens.".
Speaker 1: It was more like, "Let's explore why this
Speaker 1: And I also like that, just like you talked about the photographers, like that aspect, it also really shows off subtly.
Speaker 1: The other thing about big mountain climbing, like Everest is a big example, the white people who make a big deal about climbing it get a lot of support from Sherpas who have been climbing around on that mountain for a long, long time.
Speaker 1: Sherpas are hauling all their gear up for them.
Speaker 1: The Sherpa in the movie has extreme knowledge, it's almost like he has foresight about how this is going to go down as a result.
Speaker 0: I do think that, from what I've read about Everest specifically, I was also sort of disappointed.
Speaker 0: the movie was about Everest because it's so overplayed, but it's fine.
Speaker 1: It was less overplayed then.
Speaker 1: That was like the beginning of the era of it becoming a tourist destination, basically.
Speaker 0: Well, but not when the manga was written.
Speaker 0: But regardless, from what I've read about Everest is that when you go to it now, it's almost like tourist attraction, right?
Speaker 0: And it's like this manga doesn't show that aspect of it, but partially they get away with it because he's climbing the other side, the not tourist side.
Speaker 0: So it's like, "Okay, I guess it's okay not to show the tourists because they're not in the spot where the tourists
Speaker 0: are.".
Speaker 0: But anyway, so the thing that bothered me is that, art-wise, the character designs seem to be taken straight from the manga, really excellent.
Speaker 0: Obviously everything was computer animated, you can just tell, but still pretty good.
Speaker 0: It's not something to complain about.
Speaker 0: It's not like they did it in a bad, offensive way.
Speaker 0: And the backgrounds were always usually incredible, just to look at, which is kind of important.
Speaker 1: The soundscape was extremely good, too.
Speaker 1: It really set the mood with all those establishing shots.
Speaker 1: Tidy character, giant mountain in the background.
Speaker 0: And in scenes where things were animated, they were animated well, but the one thing that was noticeable is how much they cut back on, which is something that happens a lot in anime in general since the times of Astro Boy, obviously.
Speaker 0: But for a 90 minute movie, there are a lot of times you could just tell they cut way back on the number of drawings in parts where it didn't count.
Speaker 0: A lot.
Speaker 0: There was a scene of a crowd of people on a street and they were just sort of two framing up and down.
Speaker 0: It was like a little guy in the corner running one time.
Speaker 0: It looked like a little flip book.
Speaker 0: A lot of the inconsequential aspects were basically not moving.
Speaker 0: There were some scenes I saw where they took advantage of the computer.
Speaker 0: There was a montage where half of the montage was still frames.
Speaker 0: And in the computer, they moved around the digital light source in a clever way.
Speaker 0: I think there was a guy, he was standing over a highway holding a glass bottle.
Speaker 1: Oh, that was a really good scene, I thought.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 0: So the cars were going underneath and they were shining through the bottle, which is a really cool effect.
Speaker 0: But what was actually being animated was he was just sitting completely still and they were just moving the digital light on his face every time a headlight went past.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And it's like that's a really big effect for a very cheap technique wise.
Speaker 0: So it's really good economy of animation.
Speaker 1: Well, it was also a very striking scene that you could visualize.
Speaker 1: You could see that happening.
Speaker 1: That's the kind of scene you could see in real life of someone standing there and every car goes by and they're like, you see their face for just a second.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: So that's an example of being economical with animation, but still getting a big effect.
Speaker 0: But a lot of other scenes that weren't, you know, that if it wasn't like the signature action of like, you know, the main part of the scene, background characters, any stuff like that was economically animated.
Speaker 0: Perhaps too much for when I when I watch a movie, when it's only 90 minutes, I guess I have a higher expectation.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: To not see that sort of, you know, lower budget kind of stuff going on.
Speaker 0: The other thing you won't see, like I haven't still haven't seen Belle, but I guarantee you.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: That like just some background person is going to just be animated fantastically based on the handful of reviews I've skimmed about Belle.
Speaker 1: People are like, I cannot believe that it is as good as people are implying.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: But I guess, yeah, that's my only.
Speaker 0: the only art complaint is just, you know, animation in the corners.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 1: Like if you take one thing away from the movie, like I like how very subtly but directly it shows that the photographer and Habu are both doing the exact same thing.
Speaker 1: There is no difference between like what they're doing other than extremity.
Speaker 1: Like he's trying to like why is he trying to figure out if Mallory hit the top of Everest first or not?
Speaker 1: Like why does he care?
Speaker 1: Even his boss doesn't care that much.
Speaker 0: Mm hmm.
Speaker 0: Well, the boss didn't care until he thought there might be money in it.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Then he cared enough to send it.
Speaker 0: But even then, but, you know, the boss is just like, hey, people want to see you take great photos.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: People want to see the photos.
Speaker 0: Go take some.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: It's like he's like, you know, I also the boss didn't have a wrong attitude.
Speaker 0: I like the boss.
Speaker 1: I've never experienced altitude sickness.
Speaker 1: The closest I've gotten is in Park City, Utah.
Speaker 0: Oh, that was a good.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there was an abstracted an abstract art scene of like trying to convey what it feels like to have the altitude sickness.
Speaker 0: That was a really that was like the highlight scene animation wise, I think, because it's almost like you hear about like a blackout or a white out.
Speaker 1: The closest I've ever experienced to that is like you could call it a red out almost, but it is like this.
Speaker 1: Your eyes are just like it's almost like your eyes are closed and you're looking through your own eyelids, like if you're oxygen deprived to that point.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I have no intention of ever being in a situation where that could happen.
Speaker 1: I mean, that it's kind of from what I've read about altitude sickness, it's not even a matter of skill.
Speaker 1: It's a matter of genetic luck.
Speaker 1: How, how much it affects you.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: But I'm just not going anywhere high up.
Speaker 0: Period.
Speaker 1: Whether I have the genetic problem, you never want to get to the top of Mount Fuji.
Speaker 0: No, it's a new volcano.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: It's fine.
Speaker 1: I can go off like dangerous and call it all the time.
Speaker 1: Actually, we're planning to climb it when we go back to Japan.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: I was literally researching routes last week before we decided to watch Summit of the Gods.
Speaker 0: Well, don't fall.
Speaker 1: I don't think I will.
Speaker 0: But yeah, I haven't read it.
Speaker 0: I'm sure falling off of Mount Fuji was a regular occurrence.
Speaker 0: I know I'd read stories about it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there was just an almost fatal fall, apparently, that YouTube kept recommending to me, probably because I was Googling Mount Fuji a bunch.
Speaker 0: Well, I guess, you know, that's you're not going up there.
Speaker 0: I'll take that.
Speaker 0: Is there a cable car?
Speaker 0: I'll take the cable car.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there's a bunch of old.
Speaker 0: Can I bike up Mount Fuji?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 0: Is there a road?
Speaker 1: There's a bunch of old people.
Speaker 1: ways to get up there, though.
Speaker 0: That's that definitely seems like too tall for a road, a biking.
Speaker 1: Well, hey, if you once covid dies down, one thing I am planning to do just with our friend group is head out, get a cabin up in the Adirondacks because I want to go climb more high peaks.
Speaker 1: Like I've been up there in a long time and a bunch of our friends like hiking so I can plot a hike for like the people who don't want to climb mountains.
Speaker 1: Me and Emily and like maybe Scojo and a few other people are going to go climb a few mountains.
Speaker 1: You could just come on that trip and bike up Whiteface while we're climbing it.
Speaker 0: Is that the only one that has a road, though?
Speaker 1: That's the only one I know of that has a road.
Speaker 0: I only bike on roads.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so you you bike up Whiteface and back down.
Speaker 0: Any other any other roads out there?
Speaker 1: Well, a few roads, a few of us.
Speaker 1: Let's see.
Speaker 1: Last time I was there, I climbed Whiteface and some other mountain.
Speaker 1: And the time before that, we did the two Wolf's Jaws and Gothics and a mountain I don't remember the name of.
Speaker 0: Yeah, not interested in going up the mountain.
Speaker 1: Put it on your bike and we'll do something else.
Speaker 1: But anyway, this movie is just on Netflix.
Speaker 1: Like if you have Netflix, it's only 90 minutes long.
Speaker 1: It's beautifully animated for the most part.
Speaker 1: It's well worth watching.
Speaker 0: You know, you just spent probably close to that long listening to this Geek Nights episode.
Speaker 0: What's wrong with you?
Speaker 1: Just go watch the movie right now.
Speaker 1: We literally both watched it right before we did this show.
Speaker 1: This has been Geek Nights with Rim and Scott.
Speaker 1: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design, and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at FrontRowCrew.com for show notes, discussion news and more.
Speaker 1: Remember, Geek Nights is not one, but four different shows.
Speaker 1: Sci-Tech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays, and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 0: Geek Nights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 0: Geek Nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 0: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.
Speaker 1: And the Patreon patrons for this episode of Geek Nights are Heidi McNichol, Ellen Seitzel, Gigi, Dread Lily, Tenebrae, and a bunch of people who really don't want me to say their names.
Speaker 1: Chris Sadad, Chris Reimer, Clinton Walton, Dex, Finn, Chi 85, Rebecca Dunn, Remi Bill, Mad Bill, 34 Cowards, Sam Erickson, Sherman Mount Horrell, Taylor Brown, Yul, The Cheat of My Heart, and a bunch of people who do not want me to say the handles that they have put into Patreon.
Speaker 1: Uh, yeah.
Speaker 1: We just watched the movie right before we did the show.
Speaker 1: I think you'll enjoy it.
Speaker 1: You should watch it too.
Speaker 1: And right now, I'll just leave you with...