Speaker 0: It's Tuesday, September 14th, 2021.
Speaker 0: I'm rim.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott and this is geek nights tonight.
Speaker 0: We are reviewing oath Chronicles of Empire and exile.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: so, uh, I Uninstalled Pokemon unite because it's a pay-to-win piece of shit game.
Speaker 0: Just like
Speaker 1: I understand that a long time
Speaker 0: I played it a bunch because the thing about that game that bothers me is Like we don't tend to review games that are bad on geek nights much anymore like we rarely do that because they're just not even worth engaging with.
Speaker 0: like who cares?
Speaker 0: but Pokemon unite Its actual core game is super fun Like I really enjoy playing it like.
Speaker 0: that is an interesting take on a MOBA that I really want to see explored more But they literally ruined it with all that pay-to-win.
Speaker 0: So I uninstalled it.
Speaker 0: However, when I uninstalled it it meant that I looked at for a brief moment the full library of games I bought on my switch instead of just the ones that play like.
Speaker 1: I do think that's an issue with the switch interface.
Speaker 1: Is that you know?
Speaker 1: They put your apps in a straight line and you can go to the end and push the button like show all and you got Grid on the DS.
Speaker 1: It's like yeah, you couldn't see everything on one page if you had too many things.
Speaker 1: But you could make folders and it would.
Speaker 1: you know You could and it was like a great.
Speaker 1: you could I guess you could set it differently, right?
Speaker 1: You could choose how to lay them out.
Speaker 1: But on the DS I had the grid was like the default on my DS at least and I could.
Speaker 1: you could see everything.
Speaker 1: So you wouldn't like forget like, oh right that game.
Speaker 1: It's like it's staring you right in the face.
Speaker 1: Whereas a good example is like Like Sonic Mania I bought that right by digital.
Speaker 0: Oh, I remembered I owned that too.
Speaker 0: I forgot I owned that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's not bad.
Speaker 1: I could I could have played it more than I did.
Speaker 1: I probably will play it again, but it's like it's not on the strip when I turn my switch on.
Speaker 1: So I don't think to go to it because there's usually something on the strip that I've played.
Speaker 1: recently cuz
Speaker 0: I'm busy I'm an adult and with video games out of sight out of mind Like I got I have so many options for gaming that if I'm presented with a list of options I'll probably be more than happy to play one of the things I currently am looking at.
Speaker 1: Yeah, steam does a better job.
Speaker 1: what you know, you have a more screen real estate Obviously, you can also make all those rules like.
Speaker 0: I have different filters.
Speaker 0: that'll like filter down to games I play regularly or games I have actually installed.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm excited actually because the new iOS comes out Monday, right?
Speaker 1: So yeah days for now and they added this feature Called like focuses and the idea of the feature is that you'll be like, okay I want you tell your you know, iPhone or iPad.
Speaker 1: Hey, I want to focus on Art right now or I want to focus on you know You know whatever right now, right?
Speaker 1: You can figure each focus and it's most of the focus settings are around notifications because it would be like Okay If you're focusing on that we only want to give you notifications for these things right now and mute or hide Notifications for these other things.
Speaker 1: like you might have a notification for some news thing, but if you're currently in art focus mode okay, we'll turn it off for now and when you go back to Normal mode or going about my day mode.
Speaker 1: We'll let that notification come through right that sort of thing.
Speaker 1: However, the what I really want that feature for is that it lets you customize The like your home pages.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right and your widgets and everything Per focus.
Speaker 1: It's like if you choose your art focus, you'll just instead of like having to go to your art folder.
Speaker 1: It's like your whole home page will just be your art apps, right?
Speaker 0: That what you described being used for.
Speaker 0: I would definitely have a convention focus like what do I do exactly?
Speaker 1: so That same feature could be good on a thing.
Speaker 1: You know a video game system like a switch or steam, right?
Speaker 1: So imagine steam, you know, you open up steam and you say hey steam I'm.
Speaker 1: it's.
Speaker 1: it's Sunday and it's rainy Right.
Speaker 1: Show me the long single-player games.
Speaker 1: I'm sitting here all day by myself Or you could be like it's steam.
Speaker 1: It's Six o'clock seven o'clock.
Speaker 1: I finished dinner on a weeknight and my friends are here.
Speaker 1: Show me the three to four player co-op multiplayer games, right?
Speaker 1: like a you know, if you can if the thing your library wouldn't filter by Genre or the game you played recently or just some tags, right but actually based on your situation Right.
Speaker 1: show you the correct set of things to choose from So that the iOS when you have to configure it by hand Which I'm gonna probably spend a lot of time doing especially on my iPad.
Speaker 0: Yeah It's tricky though because that feels a lot like The organization of files and all these other things like like tried to get away that doll point libraries were supposed to eliminate that.
Speaker 0: Yep like the way I used to handle photos is I would like in flicker like in ancient times and then Lightroom like old Lightroom in ancient times like tag the people in all my photos so I could Like manually curate all this data.
Speaker 0: like what are these little?
Speaker 0: increasingly I can rely on heuristics machine learning and other ways to filter my data and It's almost that the effort I put into curating that old data ended up being worthless.
Speaker 0: So I find that I increasingly am unwilling to curate current data.
Speaker 0: if I can foresee a future Where that curation will be replaced by something?
Speaker 1: Yeah, the problem is is that the current automatic stuff like it's good.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but it won't tell me like show me all my sports easily like this way.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's not but it's not good enough.
Speaker 1: like doing it by hand is still better.
Speaker 1: So you're always finding issues if you rely on some automated thing.
Speaker 1: But to do it by hand to get the better result is so much work.
Speaker 1: It's not worth it.
Speaker 1: It's like we're suffers.
Speaker 1: We're settling for a crappy result because it's too much Manual work to get a better result, right?
Speaker 1: So the automatic crappy result ends up winning.
Speaker 1: It's like.
Speaker 1: but if I really just give me the automatic good result, let's go.
Speaker 1: It's taking so long.
Speaker 0: Yep I feel like there's a big sector there that could be explored but that's more of a Monday topic.
Speaker 1: But anyway, I'm just so.
Speaker 0: because of this I happen to clay see Everything installed on my switch.
Speaker 0: I saw that Sonic game, which looked pretty good.
Speaker 0: That's the kind of game I'd play like on the train.
Speaker 0: I'm just sitting there and I saw west of loathing which I had literally never played.
Speaker 0: even a second.
Speaker 1: had that I have it on Steam.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so I started playing it.
Speaker 0: I'm not gonna do a full review.
Speaker 0: All I'll say is that I've been playing it a lot lately.
Speaker 0: if I get a beat it real soon That game is funny as shit that game.
Speaker 1: So I played it when it came.
Speaker 1: I played it when it came out and I didn't beat it.
Speaker 1: But I basically played it and played it and played it and got really far and I got there a certain point and then I stopped.
Speaker 1: I wasn't sure how close I was to the ending but I was pretty deep and I was having plenty of fun with it.
Speaker 1: I think I may have talked about it at when I could go figure out Figure out when the game came out and then look at Tuesday geek nights around that time.
Speaker 1: You might see me talking about it and that'll be better than me talking about it.
Speaker 1: Now years later who has forgotten almost everything?
Speaker 0: But I guess the high level of what I would actually say is that one.
Speaker 0: it just like it's stylistically really well put together - it's actually a pretty real game.
Speaker 0: the puzzles ain't trivial like they're clever puzzles kind of like the original kingdom of loathing.
Speaker 0: three the soundtrack fucking slaps.
Speaker 0: and four the writing like the way characters engage with each other.
Speaker 0: and like what the plot is is this mix of It's funny and weird, but it also takes itself seriously in so far as a game like this
Speaker 1: can and
Speaker 0: I don't know like Choices you make in this game actually do feel like they have consequences in a way that a lot of more real role-playing games They really don't feel like they do anything like.
Speaker 1: yeah I mean if you spend your effort working on that part of the game and not on you know fancy graphics Then guess what you can.
Speaker 1: But I also do want to mention though that like wasn't it revealed one of the loathing.
Speaker 1: the guy who made Kingdom of loathing is like a piece of shit.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I remember something like that, but I remember the details of which dude it was or what the deal was.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so I don't know if that person will get money if you buy west of loathing now.
Speaker 1: So I don't want to you know for that reason.
Speaker 1: I don't want to tell you to go buy it But I will say as a game.
Speaker 0: I am deeply and thoroughly enjoying it, and I am gonna finish it soon.
Speaker 0: I just killed that fucking necromancer.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I already own it So maybe I will go back to it, and I'd have to start over, but it you know it shouldn't take that long to Alright, so the other game.
Speaker 0: I've been playing and I can't really say much about it yet is aliens fireteam elite Which is the you took.
Speaker 1: you took the bullet because I looked at that game And I said man that looks like a fun game for us to play together, but it's 40 bucks.
Speaker 1: Rim has money.
Speaker 1: you go test it out tentatively.
Speaker 0: It's co-op only which I do appreciate.
Speaker 0: it's 3-player co-op specifically which happens to solve a problem that me and Scott have where there are exactly three of us who are pretty much Always down to play a game Only to figure out more genres of game that are good for three player co-op besides.
Speaker 1: shoot stuff with your friends Yeah,
Speaker 0: but if I had to describe it on a really high level take Left for dead and a lot of the things that left for dead did especially left for dead to Cross it with hell divers if anybody remembers that game that we reviewed.
Speaker 1: Yeah, yes, that's basically shoot.
Speaker 1: shoot things with your friends robotron.
Speaker 1: There's a million games that are just like it's base.
Speaker 0: It's sort of a first-person shooter, but like head-clicking doesn't matter.
Speaker 0: What matters a lot more is you're playing a real fucking story game?
Speaker 0: Just co-op like.
Speaker 0: it's a full-on aliens game with all the proper nouns you'd expect and the game is basically You're the Marines sent in to do a mission and of course shit goes sideways and you'll like make your way Solve puzzles go along and then you'll get cornered somewhere and you'll play out the scene from aliens Where the turret mo is slowly running down to zero.
Speaker 0: you'll play that scene out over and over again But the scene is so different and so stressful every time that it's pretty fun But I don't know if it's $40 fun yet.
Speaker 0: I got a poke at it more to make it a true.
Speaker 0: It is definitely $15 fun.
Speaker 0: If this game was $15, I'd say buy it immediately.
Speaker 0: I don't know about 40.
Speaker 0: I'm debating if 20 is the line.
Speaker 0: So stay tuned, but I'm gonna play it some more.
Speaker 0: the other cool thing it does if you don't have a third person or even a second person if You go into the matchmaking to find people to play with eventually.
Speaker 0: It'll just be like fuck it.
Speaker 0: Here's an AI.
Speaker 1: He'll be good enough Yeah, so in similar news, right?
Speaker 1: I got the Wario where game for 50 bucks.
Speaker 1: you know, I'm testing that one out and You know, if you like if you're a Wario where person like you like a Wario where you know single-player it's like Yeah, you should get this game.
Speaker 1: But should you $50 get this game?
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: It's like, you know breath of the wild is 50 60 bucks.
Speaker 1: It's like woof.
Speaker 1: It's tough to save $50 for Wario, even if it's a good Wario.
Speaker 1: But I haven't played any of the multiplayer modes yet At least not ones that didn't have a single-player option.
Speaker 1: but just Examining them.
Speaker 1: there is some potential there for some good party times.
Speaker 1: I just don't know if they'll be.
Speaker 1: It's like, you know, we had Wario where that was endless fun party times the GameCube one, right?
Speaker 1: And we had Wario where that was no fun party times that we won This one might.
Speaker 1: my guess is that it's gonna be in the middle where it's like fun party times that run out like you get Bored of it, but you'll it's good until you get bored of it.
Speaker 1: So we'll see if it's 50 bucks.
Speaker 1: good, but um, you know Wario, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, and it's got the good Wario style.
Speaker 1: You never get tired of Wario style.
Speaker 1: No It's really
Speaker 0: the only the only thing I ever get disappointed about with Wario games that they've so far Still not counting this one, which I have not touched yet They haven't made Wario games that are even close to as good at multiplayer as the Wario where on the GameCube.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well, I mean, you know, we'll.
Speaker 1: we'll probably talk more about it after we play all the multiplayer in a party situation.
Speaker 1: But you know just early, you know early thoughts on the Wario game that you know is out now.
Speaker 1: Yeah and Metroid whatever it comes out like a month from now, so Save your money for that one.
Speaker 0: Yeah So you got any gaming news on this fine Tuesday?
Speaker 1: Do I have a gaming news?
Speaker 1: Well, it's sort of a gaming news and that you know much.
Speaker 1: like we just talked about the West a loathing guy Whoever that is who I heard was bad.
Speaker 1: There were other gaming people who were revealed to be bad.
Speaker 1: So there's a company you may have heard of called broken token and what they sell are basically like these little wooden Insert replacements to go in your board game boxes.
Speaker 1: It's like there's a board game you buy and everyone knows that.
Speaker 1: the the plastic inserts that come in board games to help you organize the Game.
Speaker 1: first of all, you know, let's talk about those just I was about.
Speaker 0: I was about to say there's a whole there.
Speaker 0: We could do a whole fucking show on that concept.
Speaker 1: But the point is they suck right.
Speaker 1: companies put them in there to like.
Speaker 1: they don't tell you how you're supposed to Organize the game in the thing, right?
Speaker 1: You just sort of guess and figure it out.
Speaker 1: It takes up a lot of air in the box Because they want to have a big box.
Speaker 1: I guess it like makes the box bigger for no reason.
Speaker 1: if you took the insert out and just threw it in the trash You could put the whole game in a smaller box.
Speaker 1: It's just wasting space you If you get an expansion for the game well now you can't fit it fucking in there because The inserts taken up all the space and the insert wasn't made with the expansions in mind.
Speaker 1: Alright, so those things to begin with suck.
Speaker 1: So the broken token was a company that's like, alright You wanna you don't want to rebox your game like in a completely new box You don't just want to put everything in baggies and toss it in the box because you're a fancy gamer person Who's gonna sleeve everything and spend a lot of money or whatever?
Speaker 0: So we'll sell you this wooden organizing thing, but these wooden organizers They echo like old board games had these things in like there was an error where they had really good things at them.
Speaker 0: But they only work if you'd never carry that fucking box anywhere ever.
Speaker 0: if that box anyway But the horizontal in your closet and you bring it out just to play the game and you put it straight back into the closet Keeping it horizontal the entire time.
Speaker 1: Well, the idea is you spent you give them money and they make it.
Speaker 1: they make things custom to particular games and then you know.
Speaker 1: So you would organize your stuff in this wooden thing.
Speaker 1: So apparently the person who ran that company the CEO Was a really bad person.
Speaker 0: Accusations not sexual abuse and harassment like.
Speaker 0: yeah now this is so.
Speaker 1: I never bought any of their products.
Speaker 1: But now I definitely won't buy any of their products and the person has been forced to step down.
Speaker 1: But they still own the company.
Speaker 1: So So don't.
Speaker 1: I would say don't buy.
Speaker 1: I would encourage you not to buy any broken token organizing things.
Speaker 1: I would encourage you to stop caring so much about how.
Speaker 1: you know pristine a piece of cardboard is Right.
Speaker 1: The game is.
Speaker 1: you can still play the game.
Speaker 1: Oh the game is in mint condition.
Speaker 0: Well, you know, you know what I look for specifically How quickly can I set the game up and tear the game down?
Speaker 0: That is my primary interaction with these.
Speaker 1: I'm perfectly happy with a box full of baggies.
Speaker 0: Now the listener also points out that part of the shift is that there was that era In the late 90s early 2000s for some games came with really overwrought like trays in them.
Speaker 0: But today the primary reason those trays exist is bad Which was a fair point is just to ship the game to you once and they assume you're gonna do something different once it arrives Like doesn't matter.
Speaker 1: after some some companies do but some don't.
Speaker 1: you know the inserts are all fancy and like you clearly they made that.
Speaker 0: Well They point out that some games Work with a company like gamer trays or one of those other companies that makes that kind of stuff to have a good solution in the box already.
Speaker 0: Yeah, anyway I'm still a fan of lots of little baggies because usually that is the quickest way to organize the things in a way That's good for setting the game up quickly.
Speaker 1: Yep, just put everything in baggies throw it all the inside.
Speaker 0: Yep, broken token is basically completely fucked by this.
Speaker 0: 13 employees were laid off.
Speaker 0: They're probably all their partners.
Speaker 0: quit Companies basically done and frankly sorry, but that's good news.
Speaker 0: You can't let people like this exist in this industry at all.
Speaker 1: But the problem is is the one shitty when the shitty person is a CEO?
Speaker 1: which CEO is usually the shitty person, right?
Speaker 1: It's like.
Speaker 0: well, I hope that so.
Speaker 1: this is a topic I was kind of saving for a Thursday, but I agree with that route, but the other the people who were laid off It's like they didn't.
Speaker 1: they weren't, you know bad people right, but now they lost their jobs.
Speaker 0: This is a lot of people are using the old phrase one rotten apple spoils the bunch.
Speaker 0: really weird and wrong lately.
Speaker 0: So I got to set the record straight because this is another one of those situations.
Speaker 0: What that aphorism means is that if there's even one bad apple all the apples are fucked.
Speaker 0: You got to get rid of that Apple as soon as possible no matter what or all the apples are gone.
Speaker 0: That is what that means.
Speaker 0: It doesn't mean Oh only a few of the apples are bad.
Speaker 0: looking at you people who are trying to support the police right now.
Speaker 0: But same thing here.
Speaker 0: they let this Apple persist and now all the apples got fucked.
Speaker 1: hmm anyway And similar news right a company that I didn't know existed.
Speaker 1: The CEO was a piece of shit.
Speaker 0: this company tripwire that made some video games Scott and I don't like they're not necessarily bad games.
Speaker 0: It's not the kind of games we play.
Speaker 1: What games does tripwire make?
Speaker 1: I don't even freaking know right?
Speaker 0: I remember I looked it up.
Speaker 1: It was a big deal like killing floor.
Speaker 0: was that red orchestra that kind of stuff.
Speaker 0: Okay, so killing floor That's like an FPS that I have is the only one I could think of off the top of my head.
Speaker 1: So I'm looking through I guess like a game that I own Because I got it in so free in some bundle and I've never played it and it's just I fit it always my thoughts on It having never played it.
Speaker 1: or that's an FPS that some small number of people still keep playing But isn't really big and popular But is like subsisting couldn't have said it better myself just has some fans for some reason and is sort of over there somewhere.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean, I Don't know what that is I've been a fan of heard of it like that before.
Speaker 0: like.
Speaker 0: I'm one of the 40 weirdos who were really into this game More than 40 in this case, but yeah the CEO of tripwire they did something bad - but they did.
Speaker 0: is they basically tweeted being in support of the egregious and undemocratic ban on abortion that was just passed in the American state of Texas, which to be very clear that is a straight-up like Incorrect opinion to have like.
Speaker 0: I fully support you not being allowed to be in the game industry if you believe that Mmm, and it's not even just that he has this horrific belief.
Speaker 0: He expressed this belief from his public Twitter account that reflects directly on the company itself and all of its employees.
Speaker 0: I think the employees even issued a statement saying fuck that guy.
Speaker 1: Yep, so they got rid of that guy and there's a new guy.
Speaker 1: but then so the the new guy came in.
Speaker 1: However, I mean not that I was playing or buying any of their games except by accident But the new guy.
Speaker 1: well, I guess apparently Possibly not.
Speaker 1: who knows what their position is on the abortion thing?
Speaker 1: But I think someone was like, you know, I think somebody tweeted.
Speaker 1: I don't know that you might want to investigate this To make sure that it's true.
Speaker 1: I'm not standing by this but I saw a tweet that Suggested that the new guy who came in Changed his like Twitter photo or profile or something.
Speaker 0: I saw that.
Speaker 1: I saw that Because and he took it because he was like a gun dude, right?
Speaker 1: So gun dude has a high.
Speaker 1: not it doesn't mean necessarily Right, but high correlation with not good, dude.
Speaker 1: We don't know if they've fixed their problem But I'm probably and I never.
Speaker 1: I wasn't buying anything from them to begin with so I don't know the need to change.
Speaker 0: This gets it more into a fundamental like this.
Speaker 0: This edges back into this conversation people are having as they discover that Nabisco is a horrible company that mistreats workers But they want to buy Pokemon Oreos and cross that picket line.
Speaker 0: There's obviously in capitalism.
Speaker 0: There's no such thing as that.
Speaker 0: the ethical consumption like that is true But a lot of people like to use that as an excuse to keep doing their bullshit.
Speaker 0: There's because of the current extreme assault on abortion rights in America.
Speaker 0: It is pretty much unethical to do business with a company that doesn't support abortion rights Or at least does not actively oppose abortion, right?
Speaker 1: Well, what's you know, the the big picture right is that you know corporate America, right?
Speaker 1: Because they've been allowed to have influence in government via giving money to elected officials.
Speaker 1: right now effectively in many ways, you know is either a monopolies that are more powerful than the government right or Controls some aspect of the government via money.
Speaker 1: So now it's like we find ourselves appealing to companies via capitalism.
Speaker 1: Right with you know, our energy.
Speaker 1: that should just simply be energy in you know spent in a democratic You know public fashion, right?
Speaker 1: We now have to go to these companies rather than just going to the elected people.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right with our with our voices.
Speaker 1: So We'd like to change that so that's not the case which we're still trying to do.
Speaker 1: But while that's the state of things.
Speaker 1: it's like, you know, if you're mad about some technology policy, it's like being mad at Apple Google Microsoft is probably gonna get you just as far as you know complaining to your senator about or whatever.
Speaker 1: So you got a complaint to all of them?
Speaker 0: Yep, but also it's directly harmful to the people who could get pregnant And the people who love care about or know those people who might work for this company.
Speaker 0: I mean, we've already seen a bunch of other companies Literally giving employees money if they need to get the fuck out of Texas like that's gonna continue.
Speaker 0: So Torn banner.
Speaker 0: They actually I see torn banners use a statement about this.
Speaker 0: We do not share the opinion expressed in a recent tweet by the president of tripwire publisher of chivalry - this perspective is not shared by our team nor is it reflected in the games we create.
Speaker 0: a Statement stands in opposition to what we believe about women's rights and you saw this across the industry of pretty much every non shitty company That interfaces with tripwire issued a statement like this basically immediately.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so the other thing we're seeing lately, which is good is we're seeing companies that are.
Speaker 1: you know All companies are shitty right because capitalism.
Speaker 1: but we're seeing companies with you know less shitty Leadership right is.
Speaker 1: what they're doing is when they discover that they are doing business with someone shitty, right?
Speaker 1: They're cutting them off.
Speaker 1: they're being like, you know, I've seen people who had like Licensing deals to make a game right and then the the person who was making the game Revealed themselves milkshake duck and then the company that sold that, you know licensed the IP to them was like, you know What you can't make that game by?
Speaker 1: Too bad.
Speaker 1: We're not letting you make that game anymore because you suck.
Speaker 1: We don't want to.
Speaker 1: you know, and it's just like, you know, that's that hurts way more than you know.
Speaker 1: A bunch of fans refusing to buy the game.
Speaker 1: There's always those bad fans who will buy it who might be enough in existence to you know get them and wall profits.
Speaker 0: all of these kinds of things do clearly reek of either rainbow capitalism or progressive capitalism like Brands will often do things like this just for profit motives.
Speaker 0: But there's an important aspect to that one it does deny resources in the long term to shitty people and At least Keep those resources from growing those shitty people.
Speaker 0: even if it doesn't go to good people like at least it's almost like stopping the bleeding But - it might go to it might go it might go to a different shitty person.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like at least but it still it over time disincentivizes like you can almost see having a piece-of-shit person in your company in a position of leadership as a Corporate risk.
Speaker 1: and as soon as people look at look at blizzard still.
Speaker 0: Yeah blizzards being sued by Shareholders because they failed to disclose their shitty sexist culture.
Speaker 0: and they're arguing the shareholders that the stock dropped and the Company is materially harmed by the fact that shitty people work there and the company hid that from them.
Speaker 0: the sit Like the shareholders are saying they should have been informed that shitty sexist people work at blizzard.
Speaker 0: Mmm, that's a big deal and I can't say much more about that because of my day job.
Speaker 0: So I'm not giving you investment advice I'm not a registered investment advisor.
Speaker 1: So The other thing that how do I become a registered investment advisor?
Speaker 0: take a test next time you want to be a registered investment advisor.
Speaker 0: It's not that hard.
Speaker 0: I Didn't.
Speaker 1: that's why I was thinking it probably isn't that hard.
Speaker 0: No, it's not that hard.
Speaker 0: You just say you have to learn a lot of proper nouns But it's not as complicated as you think.
Speaker 0: it basically boils down to Basic ethics plus a basic understanding of capital markets and like how finance works.
Speaker 1: Did I make money doing this?
Speaker 0: Yes, registered investment advisor is literally a career And your advice doesn't even have to be fucking good.
Speaker 1: Yes, and I'm saying is like I could I could just be like index funds the end Next person.
Speaker 1: just tell us anything to every single person.
Speaker 0: All I'm gonna say is you would really think how the wealth management industry works is funny.
Speaker 0: That's kind of how it goes.
Speaker 0: But I digress so.
Speaker 0: but the important thing to internalize.
Speaker 0: If you're depressed about the state of the world and you see this rainbow capitalism or progressive tinge capitalism as just being a cynical cash grab even if you're right and it is 100% a cynical cash grab it means the people with money and resources think that the winning side is the correct side.
Speaker 0: They're saying we will make more money selling to gay people or more money selling to Good people than we will Continuing to hold on to evil people.
Speaker 0: that doesn't mean they're doing the right thing for the right reasons.
Speaker 0: It means you're starting to win a little bit Mm-hmm as a point that just is worth talking about because people often lose that.
Speaker 0: but also don't do business with shitty companies if you Can't avoid it.
Speaker 0: Don't buy the Pokemon Oreos until Nabisco ends the strike by giving their workers rights.
Speaker 0: Yep, so in some other news along these lines Twitch is Starting to do something about another kind of shitty person.
Speaker 1: Well, we talked about this story already.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'm not gonna recap the whole thing to TL DL.
Speaker 0: There are bots that are actively aggressively and at extreme scale harassing primarily black and LGBT streamers on Twitch like on a scale that is Right and the bots are run by, you know, obviously a small number of people Small number of people causing a large amount of damage.
Speaker 0: twitch For all the other things going on.
Speaker 0: They're doing one thing that I think is good and I want to see more of this They are suing two Individuals for coordinating this harassment and harassing people.
Speaker 1: so we figured out who two of the people are and they're like You know not just banning them from twitch, right?
Speaker 1: They're going.
Speaker 1: they're like saying Okay, we're gonna come after you and actually sue you the human being.
Speaker 1: we figured out who you were.
Speaker 1: you're running these botnets.
Speaker 1: Here we come.
Speaker 1: Right?
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I hope you're ready to you know.
Speaker 1: face a lawsuit Yep for get a lawyer because remember some shitty edgelord 4chan troll.
Speaker 0: They don't care about getting banned.
Speaker 0: They're behind seven proxies and have their botnet.
Speaker 1: They'll just make another.
Speaker 1: they're making bots all the time.
Speaker 1: They can make another account too.
Speaker 0: Yep, but if suddenly their mom or Most likely they're actually in their 30s now and they themselves get a lawsuit Legal consequences, that is a very different conversation.
Speaker 1: This is this is why I keep saying I want to make a platform Where you it's like the same way that like a sports league finds players for misbehaving.
Speaker 1: I want to make a some sort of you know, computing platform where if you fuck around Right, we find you we just take your money.
Speaker 1: It's like oh you you set a slur while you were playing that video game.
Speaker 1: You just lost 100 bucks.
Speaker 1: right go say slur again.
Speaker 1: See what happens, right?
Speaker 1: I'm not even gonna ban you.
Speaker 1: give me another hundred bucks instead.
Speaker 1: Yep, it think that could eat.
Speaker 1: There's a way to make that work.
Speaker 0: somehow There was an early simpler internet where generally things that happen on the internet stayed on the internet and you could treat it as a Different world.
Speaker 0: we have long past that point.
Speaker 0: so if harm is coming to people via the internet then Finding out and consequences has to come back to those same people via the legal system.
Speaker 0: So this is Italy.
Speaker 1: really interesting to see how this plays out but it's all for not if the raids and stuff don't stop happening and twitch doesn't become a safe place for streamers of all kinds and This doesn't mean anything, right?
Speaker 1: So, you know, it's like this is nice But it doesn't you know, show me that it's actually solving the root problem.
Speaker 1: It's like, okay There's bad people and you took their money.
Speaker 1: But is it any better to be on twitch?
Speaker 1: No, it's still a shitty place.
Speaker 1: Well, you didn't do anything.
Speaker 0: Yeah, because the other side of this is while this is good There are and we talked about in the show.
Speaker 0: I'm not gonna die because we got to do the main bit but we've talked about this before.
Speaker 0: there are like 15 Objective-specific easy to implement things.
Speaker 0: twitch could have done that they refused to do and I think they're still culpable for not stopping this.
Speaker 0: They could have stopped this I think.
Speaker 1: see I'd like to see and here's this is the right.
Speaker 1: So if they if the people who were the victims of harassment had money They should sue twitch and be like you could have implemented all these basic measures and you didn't right.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I was harassed because you didn't do anything about it.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: All you did was no sue the two of the people you thought did it but you didn't do anything to stop it.
Speaker 1: You could have stopped it and you didn't right.
Speaker 1: Yep, just like if an arsonist burns your house down, but your house was also You know made poorly.
Speaker 1: it was very flammable.
Speaker 1: You could sue the person who made the house to probably right same kind of thing Not just arsonist but anyway things Of the day.
Speaker 0: So this is just a really tiny thing.
Speaker 0: This article is So short, but I laughed out loud.
Speaker 0: I think it's really funny and I just want to share it with you.
Speaker 0: It is titled email addresses.
Speaker 0: it would be really annoying to give out over the phone and These are email addresses like well, we're on a podcast.
Speaker 1: So you can't really give them out.
Speaker 0: Okay, like Mike underscore 2004 at yahoo.com or 1/1 the first just the number the second spelled out at hotmail.com Or so you.
Speaker 1: obviously you can't.
Speaker 1: this is not working because you're over the phone effectively speed up.
Speaker 1: Hey, you're gonna have to click on this.
Speaker 1: That's a thing of the day.
Speaker 1: Yeah See the email addresses and then you'll understand.
Speaker 0: I like it because there have been a couple of games like that bomb game the VR game where you're trying to diffuse the bomb That take advantage of this type of wordplay to make it very difficult to explain to the person in VR What the fuck they're supposed to do.
Speaker 0: You're like cut the blue wire and they cut the blue wire the one labeled blue and it's that the one called the blue wire That is red like that kind of situation.
Speaker 0: But I had this tickled my fancy what do you got?
Speaker 1: So I didn't know until somewhat recently that in the game of badminton Right the shuttlecocks the like the right there's you know, the ones we used when you were a kid.
Speaker 1: You bought them in like a pack just like about tennis balls and they were pretty much plastic.
Speaker 1: Right, some of them were slightly fancier, but they were still plastic.
Speaker 1: Apparently the in or in the competition serious badminton You have to get real ones made with like real feathers Like it's like some specific thing like a left side of a goose.
Speaker 1: I don't even know what the hell it is.
Speaker 1: It is it because they're all the same way or so?
Speaker 1: I forget?
Speaker 1: I read it somewhere but there is there.
Speaker 1: apparently, you know There's the one place.
Speaker 0: I didn't Google to see if anyone's ever said that before?
Speaker 1: It's it's something like that.
Speaker 1: But anyway Someone posted this on Twitter this video and it shows people in a village in India where there used to be several.
Speaker 0: So the phrase the left side of a goose returns exactly one Google result in the entire world and it is shuttlecock online dot page dot TL Something like that.
Speaker 0: Yeah I've never said I have not seen a search that returned a single result in like seven years.
Speaker 0: This is amazing.
Speaker 1: Yeah, bad men show Yeah feathers of light there, yeah, so They also ducks, right?
Speaker 1: But anyway, so this place the video here shows this place in India where they're making Shuttle cocks by hand from basically duck feathers that came from a nearby, you know duck slaughterhouse.
Speaker 1: So it's like they just buy the feathers by the you know in big bundles right for cheap.
Speaker 1: And it's there used to be a lot of places that did this and this is the only place still doing it by hand Because they're not only and they're not only making not fake ones.
Speaker 1: They're real feathered ones, but they're also doing it by hand.
Speaker 1: There's like almost no machines involved because you could just dump the feathers into a machine that makes them also right instead of doing it by hand, so It's pretty fascinating to see some you know, some handy work like this.
Speaker 1: but also Apparently I was not aware of this but it makes perfect sense.
Speaker 1: These shuttlecocks fly completely differently from the ones you would buy You're.
Speaker 1: it's not like tennis where like you buy some yellow balls and like yeah, that's what they're using to play tennis, right?
Speaker 1: You're not.
Speaker 1: it's like if you stay are at home Playing badminton with the plastic ones from the store and then you want to go and play real badminton.
Speaker 1: You're gonna be way off right because they're gonna for the real badminton uses the real feather ones only.
Speaker 1: But real badminton is thinking about changing up the.
Speaker 1: you know, the official rule probably should Right, but you got to get one that flies Correct or otherwise is basically different sport because it's so dramatically different Like it would be like the difference between like duck pin bowling and regular bowling.
Speaker 0: so one could one could argue that if Hockey pucks required immense animal suffering to create that maybe if we change the way hockey pucks work, that would be fine.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean there are some articles I've seen that are like yeah, there's places that are plucking live You know animals to get the feathers and that's fucked up.
Speaker 1: Don't be doing that.
Speaker 1: But it seems like this place.
Speaker 1: they weren't doing that.
Speaker 1: at least the video doesn't say they were.
Speaker 1: who knows what the reality is?
Speaker 1: But it's like yeah, if you're killing a duck anyway to make duck meat you might as well use the feathers.
Speaker 0: Yeah, absolutely use they.
Speaker 0: use all of the left side of the goose.
Speaker 0: Yeah in the meta moment the duck bones to make Halloween decor The geek nice book club book Taylor Genji powering through it still gonna do the show in the next month or so, I think The next month and at this the end October 2022.
Speaker 0: I think in October we can do this show.
Speaker 0: I'm still sitting my eyes on October.
Speaker 1: We'll see.
Speaker 0: You know, just power through it.
Speaker 0: My if I just don't.
Speaker 0: if you're not sure who someone is you'll figure it out later.
Speaker 0: I I still.
Speaker 0: I only remember chapters by who was Genji having sex with or trying to have sex within that chapter?
Speaker 1: And if I think the last couple chapters I read he wasn't having trying to have sex with anybody.
Speaker 0: No, that does happen occasionally That does.
Speaker 0: there are some chapters where he did not actually try to have sex with anyone But then there are chapters where he makes up for that.
Speaker 0: Anyway, anyway, uh I Don't have anything else.
Speaker 0: There's no conventions coming up like magfest was announced, but that's too far in the future.
Speaker 1: Who knows if we're going to that?
Speaker 0: Yep, not going to pack some packs.
Speaker 1: Unplugged has not had any announcements.
Speaker 1: We presume it's probably gonna happen.
Speaker 1: We don't know anything.
Speaker 1: So yeah Who knows what's gonna be going on there?
Speaker 0: Even if peck south meets all of our requirements I'm really not willing to do business in Texas.
Speaker 0: So I ain't go to peck south.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah, Connecticut just happened.
Speaker 1: People were there.
Speaker 1: I know yeah, but they said it was way less crowded than usual.
Speaker 1: Obviously, we weren't there Yep, which good.
Speaker 0: I do want to go back to Connecticut, but not during a global pandemic.
Speaker 0: It's not worth risking my life Yep, who knows?
Speaker 0: so otherwise just follow us on the internet.
Speaker 0: There's a lively live stream with a surprising amount of chatter right now And we'll just get into the main bit.
Speaker 0: We played a game a game called oath chronicles of empire in exile.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so the people who brought you root the same designer Cole Worley, I think that's how you pronounce his last name.
Speaker 1: Sorry Cole and The artist everyone loves is it?
Speaker 1: Kyle Ferren?
Speaker 1: is the name of the artist that everybody loves?
Speaker 0: who does the art Cal Ferren?
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 0: I was right Kyle for yeah, like the holy trinity of amazing game art, right?
Speaker 1: It was basically like hey this this team brought you root this amazing mega hit game.
Speaker 1: Let's make another game called oath.
Speaker 1: So what is oath?
Speaker 1: Oath is nothing like root really although you can see some similarities right because you know same designer and
Speaker 0: I saw someone said it best as it's almost like if you took root and Zoomed way out both physically and in terms of time and to
Speaker 1: the point I don't know.
Speaker 1: I think you're zooming it to pay your zooming out in terms of time But you're zooming in like you're just one person one character or one person.
Speaker 1: You've got like your entourage And yeah, but you're still one dude right whereas in route you're like a kingdom all right, yeah.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so what's oath?
Speaker 1: the idea in oath is that there is this sort of Kingdom, right?
Speaker 1: It has a main area.
Speaker 1: It has you know, sort of a suburban villages area and then it's got a faraway hinterlands area, right.
Speaker 1: And over time, you know the kingdoms shit happens, right?
Speaker 1: There's a Chancellor who rules they sometimes they continued and they keep ruling Sometimes and they build things up and you know, the kingdom waxes and wanes over, you know and things happen.
Speaker 1: And when you sit down to play oath, you are playing one chapter in the story of the kingdom, right you start out basically with the status quo of the kingdom as it was right the Chancellor and the stuff that they were Controlling is already set.
Speaker 1: So if the Chancellor ended it's a legacy game, right?
Speaker 1: So the Chancellor ended the last game in a strong position.
Speaker 1: They're gonna start the game in a big strong position Yeah, and if they if they right and then me if it may be You know and the thing is whoever won that may might not have been the chant the person the Chancellor that started last time one last time but whoever You know, let's say one of the other Non Chancellor players won the game last time.
Speaker 1: Well, at least story wise the Chancellor of the current game is whoever won the last game, right?
Speaker 1: It might have been some exile or a citizen or who knows what right?
Speaker 1: So you said you set up the game according to how the last game ended and then you play out another chapter.
Speaker 1: And what happens is you have the the Chancellor.
Speaker 1: they start out with all the stuff.
Speaker 1: there may be Characters who are citizens.
Speaker 1: their citizens are on the Chancellor's side.
Speaker 1: they use the Chancellor's units.
Speaker 1: They don't have their own units, but their goal is to a get the Chancellor to win But be six become the successor to the Chancellor.
Speaker 1: So they become the new Chancellor even though the team Chancellor won and then everyone else is an exile.
Speaker 1: Who is basically trying to overthrow in some manner?
Speaker 1: and You know, basically you're just this individual and you travel.
Speaker 1: it's every.
Speaker 1: the thing about this game I love the most is that every action you do in the game?
Speaker 1: right speaks narratively.
Speaker 1: The mechanics and the narrative just like, you know merge completely the game.
Speaker 1: We're just not a role-playing game, but you could make it one kinda.
Speaker 0: Yep, like in the game We just played because of what was happening on the board.
Speaker 0: my army like my pop by base of power consisted of a bunch of Geriatrics living in a tent city and that's just that's what my army consisted of.
Speaker 0: That's how things shook down.
Speaker 0: What are they after?
Speaker 0: what are their motivations?
Speaker 0: You can infer that pretty heavily from the events that happen in the game itself.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like every single act.
Speaker 1: So there's a bunch of.
Speaker 1: I'm not gonna talk about all the rules.
Speaker 1: It'll take forever.
Speaker 1: read them yourself.
Speaker 1: They're free online But a simple action in the game would be like muster right which lets you add dudes add war bands to your little entourage.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so you're at.
Speaker 1: you are physically your pawn which represents you the character, right?
Speaker 1: You you you're at a location.
Speaker 1: Maybe you're in the hinterlands and in the hinterlands is a forest right.
Speaker 1: and in the forest There's some cards next to the forest.
Speaker 1: the cards have denizens Right people who live in that forest and some some locations.
Speaker 1: like we had a we had like what was it?
Speaker 1: a sunken city?
Speaker 1: Yeah, it has a maximum space for zero.
Speaker 1: No one can live there as zero.
Speaker 1: You're not allowed to have denizens there.
Speaker 0: There's a pile of nonsense there a bunch of relics, right?
Speaker 1: But like a pleasant veil might have three spots for denizens or something.
Speaker 1: So you go there into some denizens and you see and one of the denizens is the old people the elders, right?
Speaker 1: They're living there.
Speaker 1: So you want to muster.
Speaker 1: so you do.
Speaker 1: is you take favor Right and you give the favor to the elders and then you add two war bands To your board and it's like that tells a little.
Speaker 1: you just did one action in the game But it tells this story of.
Speaker 1: I did a favor for the old people and some old people joined my army.
Speaker 0: Yeah, or the old people told me secrets or something right you trade with the old people.
Speaker 1: I'll do.
Speaker 1: hey old people I'll do you a favor if you tell me a secret.
Speaker 1: or hey old people I'll tell you secrets if you do me a favor.
Speaker 1: or You know all kind.
Speaker 1: everything you do in the game is something along those lines that tells a little mini story and those little mini Stories add up into the big big story and then the game ends, right?
Speaker 1: And you figure out who is gonna be.
Speaker 1: you know, who is who is ruling the kingdom next time right?
Speaker 1: versus this time?
Speaker 1: And there's all sorts of fun things to interact with right?
Speaker 1: You've got The denizens, right?
Speaker 1: You got some cards.
Speaker 1: You got some cards that are your advisors, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, you're busy denizens that walk around with you everywhere.
Speaker 1: They're just only working with you not with anyone else.
Speaker 0: There's all these relics and a fun thing another game.
Speaker 1: You know, it's amazing magic items.
Speaker 1: You can get.
Speaker 0: there's a game We'll talk about another time.
Speaker 0: We'll review called fortress the freedman freeze game that does something similar in that We haven't seen the deck.
Speaker 0: So like I'll go somewhere and see an art of relic and that relic just the way the game is constructed and the way you play Each round.
Speaker 0: maybe no other human has ever seen at this table before so I know there's people currently playing Haven't looked up all the card spoilers.
Speaker 0: Yeah, which I'm avoiding.
Speaker 0: so like yeah, it was interesting too.
Speaker 0: I saw a relic.
Speaker 0: I was like, oh, okay that seems like a reasonable thing for a game to do.
Speaker 0: and then I saw another relic and That relic seems so powerful and weird that it gave me pause to consider.
Speaker 0: What the fuck other relics might I run into?
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like yeah because every time when you finish a game you remove you.
Speaker 1: basically you start the game with a deck.
Speaker 1: They give you and but there's a bunch more cards in the box.
Speaker 1: when you finish a game Whoever one is gonna make some decisions right relating to the what's had the state of the board and They're basically gonna remove some cards from the deck and add more car add six cards to the deck.
Speaker 1: So you're constantly cycling out and in cards, right?
Speaker 1: And so the next time you play you're gonna see some stuff you're familiar with.
Speaker 1: but you know the kingdom change over time.
Speaker 1: The kingdom is changing right.
Speaker 1: some people who used to live here don't live here anymore.
Speaker 1: Some new people showed up some people, you know, but most of it is Basically the same at least as of last game but compared to ten games ago.
Speaker 1: It's completely different, right?
Speaker 1: It's been so long since then, you know, there's no one alive from ten games.
Speaker 1: It's been so long.
Speaker 1: So you're telling this long story.
Speaker 1: the addition I got I don't know if the non.
Speaker 1: Okay, I didn't like pay extra for extra Kickstarter biz.
Speaker 1: I just kick-started at the level of give me the game But it came with metal favor tokens, oh they feel so nice special rosin secret book tokens And also this little leathery book to write your Chronicle in right because it's people are making art in those Chronicle books.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so I'm like the Chronicle book.
Speaker 1: It's like you have one page per game that you write down what the hell happened and then you build this Chronicle Right of what happened in the kingdom over time.
Speaker 1: You keep playing this game over and over.
Speaker 0: Yep, like I guess I'm just flipping through a board game geek this one person they posted there.
Speaker 0: They had one page where I guess the Fox people Became the chance like exile.
Speaker 0: Yeah, yep, like they won.
Speaker 0: so they didn't write any words.
Speaker 0: They just drew a picture of an evil looking Fox with like some shadowy flame and it just says shrouded rebellion.
Speaker 0: They didn't write anything else.
Speaker 0: So whatever the fuck happened in that game I feel like the foxes got up to some bad news business and won the game.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm Yeah But yeah, it's just.
Speaker 1: I don't know how else to describe the game.
Speaker 1: It's oh, so I guess let the rules a little bit a little bit rules, right?
Speaker 1: So it's an action point game.
Speaker 1: you on your turn right you go.
Speaker 1: This is I think the only negative about the game.
Speaker 1: Is that much like root?
Speaker 1: It is still a game where you don't do much when it's not your turn.
Speaker 1: Yep, so on your turn you do a whole bunch of stuff and then it's the next person's turn.
Speaker 1: So if you're playing with a lot of players I think you know, it lets you go from two to six.
Speaker 1: you play two you need an AI player.
Speaker 1: I don't think that that's great.
Speaker 1: Five and six I think is too many because you're it takes so long and the players who have the last turn order at a bit Of a disadvantage because the game starts four turns worth of stuff happens.
Speaker 1: then they get their first turn.
Speaker 1: It's like oh my god, right?
Speaker 1: And there's too much waiting and it takes too long.
Speaker 0: I think three or four players is ideal though if everyone is fully fluent in the mechanics I think the game would move literally twice as fast as our early the game.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know the game is actually not a slow game.
Speaker 1: if everyone knows how to play.
Speaker 1: It's the first time you play.
Speaker 1: you're gonna need to spend a lot of time rule learning and card reading And probably the second time and if you don't play with the same exact people again You're gonna still spend time card reading and rule learning and some exceptions to the rules are gonna get you.
Speaker 1: But if you're playing with people who got good at the game you can under two hours easily, right?
Speaker 1: And there's a lot of variance in that as well depending on how the game ends.
Speaker 1: But you on your turn you have this supply meter and you just spend action points to do Actions, there's a whole list of actions
Speaker 0: stuff like travel out to the hinterlands or recruit some armies or go get this relic or fucking Attack someone
Speaker 1: and some actions are free like put some denizens out, you know Go, you know, I guess not.
Speaker 1: it's not for you to go exploring and look for some cards, you know to get more cards But it's a thing you can do all right.
Speaker 1: battling obviously is an action all kinds of actions you do you spend your points But if you run out of supplies Right narrative again, you're spending some things you want to do.
Speaker 1: cost supplies moving around cost supplies You're traveling.
Speaker 1: right.
Speaker 1: obviously that cost supplies the farther you travel the more supplies it costs.
Speaker 1: But just telling someone who's hanging out with you, right like one of your advisors to like Hey, you should you should build you should stay here.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna leave.
Speaker 1: that doesn't cost any supplies, right?
Speaker 1: You're just saying hey stay here giving someone an order.
Speaker 1: It takes two seconds, right and you go around doing these things You know telling you a little story on your turn and then you say you're done and then you refresh your supply.
Speaker 1: You refresh your supply according to how bigger.
Speaker 1: if your army is real big you have less supplies.
Speaker 1: It's harder to move around and you got to feed all these frickin soldiers or whatever.
Speaker 1: if your army is real small Then you got more supplies.
Speaker 1: You can do more stuff, right?
Speaker 1: You're not hanging around with a big crowd again.
Speaker 1: Narratives that make sense with the mechanic, right?
Speaker 1: So you just do this and there's every game.
Speaker 1: There's gonna be this victory condition the oath and whoever is currently leading is gonna have the oathkeeper banner.
Speaker 1: the Chancellor always starts with it because they're always in the strong position at the start of the game and They just have it because they're.
Speaker 1: you know They're no matter what.
Speaker 1: at the start of the game The board will be in such a state that the chant the starting Chancellor is Meeting the victory condition more than anyone else no matter what.
Speaker 1: but as soon as the game goes on someone else Right could take that away from them.
Speaker 1: It's possible.
Speaker 1: And if they do and they hold on to that oath if they keep that oath long enough and you think oh well How are they gonna do this?
Speaker 1: Right?
Speaker 1: Well, the Chancellor just naturally loses power as the game goes on.
Speaker 1: It's just structured in that way.
Speaker 1: So if the game goes on too long the Chancellor is gonna get weak.
Speaker 1: The Chancellor can get strength by getting people to become citizens and join their team if they weren't citizens at the start.
Speaker 1: But if a non citizen holds that oath for too long I think two laps around the table then they win right because the Chancellor lost the their oath.
Speaker 1: Another way to win.
Speaker 1: if somebody is not the Chancellor They're in exile there's visions and if they they have a vision.
Speaker 1: right I had a vision of an empire.
Speaker 1: Right and you fulfill the vision somehow Right.
Speaker 0: Well, they're gonna be nine small mushrooms in a row.
Speaker 0: this I so decree Right you have.
Speaker 1: if you have if you're in exile and you have a vision and you bring it about It's like that's such a tremendous thing.
Speaker 1: Right?
Speaker 1: You're a visionary figure in the society And it came true.
Speaker 1: well then you beat that's it you win.
Speaker 1: But just to make a vision happen It's like you have to play the vision So everyone sees it on your turn and then it has to go all the way around the board and at the start of your Turn the vision has to be fulfilled still and that's difficult to do because everyone sees it and tries to mess it up sort of Like dune where it's like I'm winning on my turn.
Speaker 1: who's gonna stop me Becomes.
Speaker 0: one or more players will win if the game gets back around to them and the game becomes Really like not to get into the details of the mechanics because again It would just take too much time and it would also be too hard to explain without visual aids.
Speaker 0: but what I would say is the way you are engaging with the game is.
Speaker 0: You were trying to prevent the person who is currently winning from actually winning when it gets around to them while posturing To be ready to be the person who will win after they have failed.
Speaker 1: Yep, and the last thing is if the Chancellor just holds on to the oath, right?
Speaker 1: They mate they stay strong They remain the oathkeeper.
Speaker 1: then Of halfway through the game the game can only ever be eight rounds.
Speaker 1: long After the fifth round, I think they get to roll a d6.
Speaker 0: They do.
Speaker 1: they do If it comes up on a six exactly they win.
Speaker 1: but if they get it if they get to go another round Let's say they make it to the sixth round and there's still the oathkeeper.
Speaker 1: now They win on like a five or a six and basically the odds of them winning keep Increasing.
Speaker 1: if they're managed to hold on to the oath Right as the game nears the eighth round if they're holding on to it at the eighth round They just win.
Speaker 1: if not, there's like a list of things that happen.
Speaker 0: So the but the fun part about the fight.
Speaker 0: It really gives this feeling of like you've got to take your shot or they're like they're just too powerful.
Speaker 1: And then the final thing is if the Chancellor does win But one of these citizens has met the successor goal.
Speaker 1: They win instead of the Chancellor.
Speaker 1: So it's like the Chancellor wants to win.
Speaker 1: But it's like if someone else has that's on your team is meeting this successor goal.
Speaker 1: It's like you have to find some way to like bring them down without hurting the team because otherwise you don't win.
Speaker 0: Yeah Like all the outcasts to a degree of the exiles have to sort of work together at least like.
Speaker 0: I wouldn't antagonize a fellow exile Early in the game necessarily unless I had some reason to like a vision in my hand that I need to set myself up for Later, so the game ends up simulating this feeling of court intrigue.
Speaker 1: pretty well Mmm, and I guess the last the last thing is that you know nothing in the game.
Speaker 1: It's like you know is like you think.
Speaker 1: oh the Chancellor is like special.
Speaker 1: It's like they're a little special, but really it's unlike root.
Speaker 1: It's very symmetrical.
Speaker 1: everyone does the same things on their turn the same actions the same supply thing.
Speaker 1: basically.
Speaker 1: For example the Chancellor has this like scepter like this royal scepter thing.
Speaker 1: It's a relic.
Speaker 1: It's just a relic like any other relic.
Speaker 0: just steal it.
Speaker 1: You could just steal it and if you have the scepter you have control of the royal you know Reliquary and you can.
Speaker 1: you know.
Speaker 1: you can make people into citizens.
Speaker 1: You can grant them citizenship because you're holding the scepter or you can exile people who are citizens And it's like the Chancellor starts with it, but anyone else can come and fucking imagine take it Chancellor.
Speaker 0: He gives joy joy Shabbat ooh citizenship, and then I steal the scepter and exile Joe Joe Joe Shabbat ooh.
Speaker 0: How fun is that right?
Speaker 1: It's hard to do, but you can do it.
Speaker 1: You know you can all cut.
Speaker 1: all these things are possible like they're.
Speaker 1: nothing in the game is like special in any kind of ways that you interact with all the things in ways that make sense narratively within the context of the actions And I guess really get really creative with your solutions.
Speaker 0: Situations I would call out on a high level without getting too deep into the details are that one?
Speaker 0: The the economy of the game is interesting in that it is a closed economy like if you do things Favor goes out onto the board and favor only comes back from that same board and some things you do Just destroy favor like you could shrink the actual full economy of the game in the course of the game.
Speaker 0: Another commodity the secrets those books.
Speaker 0: They're a resource that you can just use over and over and over again.
Speaker 0: They're like a recharging resource, but you can also burn them to almost supercharge yourself.
Speaker 0: But as I learned if you burn all your books You're not a great position in the mid game right.
Speaker 1: well, you can also just get more books.
Speaker 1: right.
Speaker 1: There's like a. there's an infinite supply of books But they're very difficult to get so that meanwhile the favors are easier to get but they're.
Speaker 0: they're literally a zero-sum game.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the favors are in this sort of closed economy But not only are there a limited number of them, but based on this suits on the different cards We're not gonna get into that, but yeah, basically there's different piles of favor.
Speaker 1: So maybe there's a huge pile of favor on like the hearth bank.
Speaker 1: So you can doing hearth things like you can go get favors from hearth peoples.
Speaker 1: But maybe the discord bank could be empty.
Speaker 1: maybe someone emptied it on purpose.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like you know if you're if you're playing a big discord game you have discord advisors and stuff.
Speaker 1: It's like why you want to get some favor.
Speaker 1: It's like well You can't.
Speaker 1: the discord.
Speaker 1: people have no favors to give.
Speaker 1: they've already given all their favors.
Speaker 1: You know they don't.
Speaker 1: they're too busy or they're spent right.
Speaker 1: and that's what it's again narratively Representing.
Speaker 1: like.
Speaker 1: yeah, you kept going to ask favors from the old people.
Speaker 1: They don't have any more favors to do.
Speaker 1: give anymore.
Speaker 1: Right people kept giving favors to the to the order.
Speaker 1: you know clan It's like.
Speaker 1: so now you can go and ask the order clan for favors because they're doing great.
Speaker 1: They got plenty of time to help you out.
Speaker 1: join your army.
Speaker 0: Whatever you want them to do Mmm, so I guess the other interesting mechanic is the way combat works.
Speaker 0: is the dice have a whole thing going on.
Speaker 0: But basically if I'm attacking Scott I List out all the things Scott has that I want to attack and it turns into one big pool And I either win it all or I win nothing.
Speaker 0: so you can literally go big or go home with this game.
Speaker 0: And that's a really there's a lot of nuance and detail to that.
Speaker 1: You can attack people you can attack their relics.
Speaker 0: I could be like I'm just gonna see the banners that you didn't even talk about.
Speaker 0: the banners Yeah like.
Speaker 0: I might say I'm just gonna take that relic from you.
Speaker 0: or I might say I'm gonna knock you out of these four places and I'm stealing your favor, and I'm taking that relic.
Speaker 0: and then you're like well.
Speaker 0: I have a giant army I'm the Chancellor.
Speaker 0: what the fuck do you have?
Speaker 1: Yeah, there's all kinds of stuff you get really creative with what you're gonna Do.
Speaker 1: yeah, and then basically the attacker you know the defender rolls dice and sets the bar.
Speaker 1: It's like this is how high you have to jump if you want to win.
Speaker 1: then the attacker jumps And if the attacker doesn't meet the bar or exceed it they can kill their own guys To jump higher or just accept the loss.
Speaker 1: yep So that's how the combat works.
Speaker 1: and then yeah like rim said the attacker either wins in which case they take all the things that They were attacking or they lose and they just lose half their dudes.
Speaker 0: Yeah in the attack, so I guess Should you buy it or not is an interesting question because I would say if you're in the Fert play it once Maybe before you buy it just to make sure the mechanics jive with you.
Speaker 0: You can play it on TTS.
Speaker 1: You can read the rules online.
Speaker 1: the PDF is just on their website.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there's no official tabletop simulator like scripted version.
Speaker 0: You can just open And play but try it out.
Speaker 1: I don't know how I don't know how you preserve the legacy aspect.
Speaker 1: There might be a way.
Speaker 1: there probably is a way But you're probably just gonna you know.
Speaker 1: use it to test and play the first game with the starting setup.
Speaker 0: Internalize that your first game especially if it's a teaching game will take about twice as long as a game once everyone knows the deal Like literally about 20 as long.
Speaker 1: also accept the fact that you're gonna get.
Speaker 1: there's a. there are some fiddly rules.
Speaker 1: the biggest rule We keep getting wrong is the protection.
Speaker 1: This will make no sense to anyone, but you can only Reclaim reclaim this.
Speaker 1: the banner of the darkest secret.
Speaker 1: if The person who has it is at a site Where one of the advisors at the site at least does not match one of the denizens at the site Does not match the suit of any of the person's advisors It's like there has to.
Speaker 1: they have to be in a place where someone lives who is not friendly with them.
Speaker 1: right narratively It makes sense.
Speaker 1: it's like yeah, you want to steal the banner of the darkest secret from someone.
Speaker 1: They have to be standing in a place Where there are unfriendly peoples that you can convince to help you steal the banner if they're standing among friends or standing among No one who's there to steal it.
Speaker 1: right, but it's a really hard rule to remember and parse when you read the English of it.
Speaker 0: So when you're teaching this game spend a lot of time on all the proper nouns and defining them.
Speaker 0: It'll save you a lot of grief, but if you if you like it like you feel like you can engage with it I'd also say only buy it if you are confident.
Speaker 0: You will get it to the table a bunch of times not necessarily with the same people.
Speaker 0: But this game does not shine unless you play it many times.
Speaker 1: Yep, I mean some people out there.
Speaker 1: I know are like I'm gonna play it only with this one group and that's it.
Speaker 0: That's a real fun way to go.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's a fun way to go.
Speaker 1: my I'm like, alright I'm gonna be the one who I'm playing it with whoever is gonna play it, right?
Speaker 1: I don't need the same people to be in the same seat all the time.
Speaker 0: It's like we met with.
Speaker 0: we met with the person who was the Chancellor in the game before the game We played and we could tell the story like.
Speaker 0: hey Scott the steward of your empire kept it together.
Speaker 0: He's still Chancellor.
Speaker 1: yeah, it's like.
Speaker 1: so like because I Narratively right if the red exile wins in game one in game two The Chancellor at the start of game two there might be a different red exile in game two.
Speaker 1: But the Chancellor in game one is that same person who was the red exile in the previous game.
Speaker 1: because they want right?
Speaker 1: Yeah So you can.
Speaker 1: you can carry it forward that way.
Speaker 1: if you keep playing with the same human beings like you can really be the character But you don't have to right.
Speaker 1: It's like it doesn't matter.
Speaker 1: It works out.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so try it out before you buy it and Really like if you like it commit to it.
Speaker 0: or you probably don't want to buy it because Playing one iteration of this game without interacting with that longer-term like hey, what kind of stories did we create?
Speaker 0: It's fun, but it's not like That.
Speaker 0: much fun without like engaging with all these other long-term mechanics.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if you just keep playing like the starting setup over and over like you're gonna get real bored.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's not.
Speaker 1: it's not that fancy right.
Speaker 1: at least it.
Speaker 1: you know it is fancy.
Speaker 1: I guess we had a lot of fun with it.
Speaker 1: But if you did it over and over again like you're seeing the same cards Yeah, you don't have any like ruins and other edifices that can end up on the board.
Speaker 1: There's these other all these other things going on when you play several times More powerful relics coming out.
Speaker 1: You know different sites like we had you know like I said that sunken city.
Speaker 1: Let's Lincoln City was Narratively.
Speaker 1: we went there, and we dug up had three relics.
Speaker 1: It's like a place full of relics.
Speaker 1: so we traveled there And we all you know competed it almost like an Indiana Jones kind of dig up all the relics there.
Speaker 1: Right and it's like that thing won't be in your first game ever.
Speaker 1: It's not possible.
Speaker 1: It's not in the starting setup and You know to experience that you're gonna have to play.
Speaker 0: you know a few games, so I'd say it's a pretty elegant ambitious and Fairly unique game like this is almost.
Speaker 0: there have been legacy games before But this is the first one that I think is doing something really interesting and novel and I think games like this Will start to come based on people's experiences with this game.
Speaker 0: I think there'll be another game like oath in the coming three or four years that will be clips it But there's nothing like this out there right now Other than oath and I do want to play it more.
Speaker 0: I did enjoy it thoroughly.
Speaker 0: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 1: be sure to visit our website at front row.
Speaker 1: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 0: remember geek nights is not one But four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows It's actually recorded at night and the patreon patrons for this episode of geek nights are Heidi McNichol I'll address the kids you generally.
Speaker 0: senator by Chris Reimer Clinton Walton Dex Finn.
Speaker 0: just like a dude guy I could shy 85 Rebecca Dunn review metal three four cowards Ryan parents and Eric center about all Taylor Braun Under cam pro law at Oh Pierce Wright seed ab threat open.
Speaker 0: You will the key to my heart and a bunch of people who do not want me to say their names.
Speaker 0: So now tonight after having reviewed oath Which I will play again and maybe we'll talk about after we've played several games of it in a row a little bit of follow-up conversation but tonight I simply leave you with.
Speaker 0: Did you check the toilets on the right?
Speaker 0: did you check the toilets on the right?
Speaker 0: did you check the toilets on the left?
Speaker 0: Did you check the toilets on the right?
Speaker 0: did you check the toilets on the right?
Speaker 0: did you check the toilets on the left?
Speaker 1: Did you check the toilets on the left?
Speaker 1: Okay, okay you win Ribbit ribbit on totally lost toilet with me of me already sold In the rain or in the snow.
Speaker 1: I got the funky flow, but no I really got to go In the rain open the snow.
Speaker 0: you got the funky flow, but now you really gotta go.
Speaker 1: The toilet over there will bring you up, so give up.
Speaker 1: I got no time to spare.
Speaker 0: The toilet over there will bring you luck so give up.
Speaker 1: I got no time to spin in the rain up in the snow.
Speaker 1: I got the funky flow, but now I really got to go in the rail from the snow.
Speaker 0: You got the funky flow, but now you really gotta go the toilet over there.