Speaker 1: It's Wednesday September 8th 2021.
Speaker 1: I'm rim.
Speaker 1: I'm Scott and this is geek nights tonight.
Speaker 1: We are talking about the Superman.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: Well who designed it?
Speaker 0: who does not?
Speaker 0: who designed these fucking knees?
Speaker 0: what garbage yeah?
Speaker 1: Hey, if you're talking about the knees I have some concerns around the upper and lower back while we're at it.
Speaker 0: Why are we standing?
Speaker 0: if we just didn't stand up straight we'd be all right Yeah, but standing up straight does have some benefits.
Speaker 0: Reaching high shit.
Speaker 0: all right you can just reach.
Speaker 0: stand up straight when you got to reach high shit, then go back down.
Speaker 0: Yeah, why you got to stay up there?
Speaker 1: So years ago I was having a problem with my left knee Biking which had been a problem that occurred off and on my entire life.
Speaker 1: like it would come and go.
Speaker 0: and yeah lots of people Have biking knee problems, and we usually say either gear too high gear too low seat too high seat too low right always something like that Back.
Speaker 1: I did originally fix that problem by going to a bike shop and sitting down with an expert who sized my bike to the right height and Watch me pedal and then fucked with it, and then like and he was like okay You probably won't have any knee problems again.
Speaker 1: And if you do then raise it up a half a centimeter or down a half a centimeter and see if it goes away Like from this and it disappeared like no knee problems, but then I started biking a lot And Especially last summer over COVID like I started biking centuries like pretty regularly.
Speaker 1: That's a hundred miles if you're not like bike people just call it a century for Reasons you can imagine like.
Speaker 1: it's a nice way to say it.
Speaker 0: But a lot of people a lot of people try to be like a bike to metric century.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I Biked a Gregorian century anyway, so uh my knee problems came and went.
Speaker 1: but eventually I got to a point where I was having a slightly different knee problem.
Speaker 1: and Physical therapists, there's two different ways to go with that particular knee problem.
Speaker 1: It's the problem where like the front inner part of your knee or the top of the patella hurts and basically they either say You've got to put less pressure on your down strokes or in running do shorter strides because it's caused primarily by Stressing that upper part of the patella like the pressure of striking the ground or pushing hard with the pedal.
Speaker 1: so Mm-hmm, but it can also be caused if your muscles are imbalanced and that is often the case with people who cycle But don't do any other sports or people who run but don't do any other sports.
Speaker 1: basically anyone who does One very narrow type of sport is at risk for these kinds of knee issues.
Speaker 1: if you do that sport a lot because you'll over Develop the specific muscles that do those things and the rest of your muscles are weak.
Speaker 1: So eventually those muscles get too strong and start pulling.
Speaker 0: I don't understand how that happens cuz I'm pretty sure it's like.
Speaker 0: doesn't cycling use Every single leg.
Speaker 0: Oh, no, not even what other leg muscle is there.
Speaker 1: so I Solved this problem and I did talk to doctors like this was advice.
Speaker 1: But this advice and I got I cannot stress this enough does not apply to you or any random person Unless you talk to a doctor because this is only a concern for people who have extremely overdeveloped muscles, but basically Instead of slowing down or changing my biking because my form was good.
Speaker 1: I started running a lot more and Weight training a lot more I ramped up all the other leg Exercises I do and that actually made all my knee problems go away a hundred percent of them just gone.
Speaker 1: My knees just feel great all the time.
Speaker 1: so what happened to me when we did our century last weekend is The knee problem came back a little bit and I looked at my Strava history and I realized something I Was running the same amount I'd been running but I was actually biking a lot more than I had been previously.
Speaker 1: So it's not just bike a lot but also do some running.
Speaker 1: It's if I bike more I have to increase the other exercises by a proportionate amount or the problem will come back.
Speaker 1: so the experiment I did was Increasing my running while taking a break from biking and then starting the biking again.
Speaker 1: And so far it seems like increasing the running has made all problems go away.
Speaker 0: So I don't have any knee pains, but what I do have is this has been this way for Many years is you know, I'll wake up in the morning, right?
Speaker 0: I'll start biking.
Speaker 0: It's like when I first start biking like the immediate start like I'm rolling and rolling like less than a block distance Like my kneecaps will be like, oh we're doing something and they'll go like click click and they're like snap into place And then that's it.
Speaker 0: It's like if you know if I wake up and I didn't do anything Or even if like, you know, even if I start biking a little later than the early morning, right?
Speaker 0: It's like the start of biking.
Speaker 0: But you know, it's like my leg is like not in bike mode and then it like you can feel my knees are like what?
Speaker 0: Click There's a noticeable Clicking of some kind and then they're like, okay, you can bike forever.
Speaker 0: now, we're done.
Speaker 0: It's like there's some sort of mode shift or gear change in the knee zone.
Speaker 1: So it is Likely, but again, I would recommend you talk to a physical therapist or your doctor at some point.
Speaker 0: that doesn't hurt.
Speaker 0: It's not from.
Speaker 1: It could be causing a minor cartilage damage or joint damage before it clicks and It could potentially be prevented entirely if you cross-trained a little though I know you probably don't want to cross-train a little Hmm.
Speaker 0: I did find I think we talked about this last time right.
Speaker 0: the one exercise other than biking That's actually fun is jump rope.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah jump also swimming, but swimming is a lot harder Oh my.
Speaker 1: so the other thing I noticed was I Just because between went we went to the shore for that private beach house And I also went to that lake house for a family thing.
Speaker 1: So I had two weeks of swimming almost every day.
Speaker 1: Oh Did that put me in like preternaturally a book like good shape?
Speaker 0: I but not if it's not like lap swimming.
Speaker 0: It's just you know hanging out in the water.
Speaker 1: No, I was swimming.
Speaker 1: you weren't hanging out with me in the water.
Speaker 1: I was swimming back and forth in the waves.
Speaker 1: Like I was doing laughs in the water.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but I was.
Speaker 1: But I actually lost three pounds on that Wildwood trip.
Speaker 1: Hmm, and I think it was solely from all that swimming.
Speaker 0: Anyway Got some anime something's hard to do you gotta.
Speaker 1: oh, yes.
Speaker 1: So the thing is I'll run 13 miles.
Speaker 1: No problem I'll bike a hundred miles and just be a little sore at the end swimming like 40 yards.
Speaker 0: I'm fucking done I well not that I'm talking about.
Speaker 0: you have to have money to swim.
Speaker 1: It's it's hard, but even if you have money swimming is just so much harder than any other exercise I do Like.
Speaker 1: as much.
Speaker 1: as athletic as I am I cannot swim that far effectively without being completely exhausted.
Speaker 0: I mean Olympic people don't swim that far either.
Speaker 0: No, it's like hundred meter five foot, you know, how many meters right?
Speaker 0: It's not.
Speaker 0: it's not like I swim 60 miles like I'm biking 60.
Speaker 0: Yeah What's the long.
Speaker 0: I don't know what the what's the longest swimming event in the Olympics in the Olympics?
Speaker 1: I don't know, but I had a boss who would swim the English Channel for fun like every now and then.
Speaker 0: yeah They do it slowly.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, super slow.
Speaker 1: Like he was really into like ocean swimming.
Speaker 0: marathon Swimming is only ten kilometers in open water.
Speaker 1: Okay, that ten swimming ten kilometers terrifies me.
Speaker 1: running ten kilometers I wouldn't even break a sweat.
Speaker 0: That's what I'm saying.
Speaker 0: Is that people in general even you know endurance long-distance swimming people don't swim that far.
Speaker 1: In fact, it takes me about 40 40 ish minutes to run ten kilometers.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we're not.
Speaker 0: I mean that they would be like, you know How long is the fish walking race, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah It's like two inches and then you can who can flop right.
Speaker 0: flop flop flop flop flop and then yeah.
Speaker 1: So in some animation anime news, I'll start with a geek bite on that Harley Quinn show Which I'm gonna say is fantastic, but with some caveats, it's not for everyone.
Speaker 0: Which what is it on?
Speaker 1: Uh So I I must admit that I don't know because I am watching it on my NAS.
Speaker 1: Okay, and I click buttons and it appears on my NAS.
Speaker 1: Oh, it's on HBO max.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 0: Oh, I have HBO max now.
Speaker 1: Oh, uh, so it looks like it was somewhere else but is officially moved to HBO max permanently.
Speaker 1: So I'm gonna can't?
Speaker 0: I'm gonna cancel Netflix soon ish.
Speaker 0: But HBO max right now has the most stuff that I want to see and I want to watch the wizard city.
Speaker 0: So I just got it.
Speaker 0: You know Instead of canceling and then signing up I signed up and then I'll cancel like in a week.
Speaker 1: HBO max is honestly killing it in terms of getting the catalog of stuff that at least me and Scott Personally want to watch at least at this moment.
Speaker 0: I'm sure I'll burn.
Speaker 0: The
Speaker 1: problem is the cycle is Netflix has a bunch of stuff that I already finished and the further seasons of those things are not out yet Mmm, but Harley Quinn, I think you might actually like honestly like I think you might enjoy it What I would say having watched a whole bunch of it I've loved the entire first season which I won't spoil anything, but the difference between Harley Quinn then considered compared to say like betas as a superhero supervillain DC Universe show is That Harley Quinn surprised me at a lot of points by just killing a major character Making a radical change to the DC Universe just doing something nutso and then the next episode.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's the universe.
Speaker 1: now It's just not so like Superman's gone, you know, it's some non Canon cartoons.
Speaker 0: they can just do it.
Speaker 1: That's what makes it good.
Speaker 1: The fact that this show doesn't give a shit about the Canon of the rest of DC is Actually, the only thing that made me like it.
Speaker 0: I think like that is though, you know, there's like, you know There's like 10 bajillion DC and Marvel things just like that.
Speaker 0: They do that all the time.
Speaker 0: Alternate that table steaks.
Speaker 1: what I like about this one is that it's it's learned.
Speaker 1: The show seems to have learned and informed itself from other Superhero or superhero adjacent things that were popular or that did well or that at least tickled my personal fancy.
Speaker 1: I'm confident that the people who write this show are Extreme fans of the venture brothers because they seem to have used it as their style guide.
Speaker 0: You didn't even bother to look up who they were.
Speaker 1: Oh, no, I'm just talking about it from a perspective of What the show is like and whether or not you will like it.
Speaker 1: are you the listener will like it because I want to a Review later.
Speaker 1: I'll do it with Emily if you don't ever watch it, but Basically, it's from the perspective of the villains like it's Harley Quinn.
Speaker 1: It's her show.
Speaker 1: She's the main character, but it's set as they're kind of just millennial dipshits doing their thing.
Speaker 1: But they are still just super villains.
Speaker 1: and all the super villains are there in the universe.
Speaker 1: Like Lex Luthor is there Superman's just there.
Speaker 1: Batman shows up all the time.
Speaker 1: I'm not gonna say it's a deconstruction because that is a term that a lot of weaves are Really misusing lately to the point that I almost don't want to use it for a while and hope they forget about it.
Speaker 1: But what it is is it it is making fun of the DC Universe more so than earnestly exploring the DC Universe.
Speaker 1: Yet by making fun of the DC Universe It is a more earnest exploration of these characters than most DC things have ever been in my opinion Caveat I don't like that many DC things.
Speaker 1: So take that with a grain of salt if you're a DC fan.
Speaker 0: I Look up the people who made this show and there isn't too much interesting things about them and nothing they have credits for is interesting.
Speaker 1: So it does have an all-star voice acting cast and I will say that.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah the voice actors I know I can see who they are, but I'm not like.
Speaker 0: I was like.
Speaker 1: There was like.
Speaker 1: there was a character the first episode I was like.
Speaker 1: that is that Jason fucking Alexander.
Speaker 1: It was it was him it is and the funniest thing is it's basically him playing himself But it's him playing himself as in it's George Costanza as this character effectively.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the person who wrote it is is Justin Halpern Patrick Schumacher and Dean Laurie.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but it's like.
Speaker 0: I look I click on Justin Halpern on Wikipedia and it's like, okay Who is Justin Halpern?
Speaker 0: a full-time writer for Maxim magazine online?
Speaker 0: It's like.
Speaker 1: well see that's why.
Speaker 0: so it's like show this show the way it's Completed the book shit My dad says the way it's like.
Speaker 0: and also a TV show named shit.
Speaker 0: My dad says it's like his second book.
Speaker 0: I suck at girls like who the hell is this guy?
Speaker 0: Why do I?
Speaker 1: so?
Speaker 1: the way that she was put together is that it's probably a lot more like The Simpsons in that the team is what made it and it's very hard to point at any one person who is responsible for Like the show being good or bad or whatever.
Speaker 1: Like there's a writer's room.
Speaker 1: There's a bunch of editors.
Speaker 1: I think the editors have a lot.
Speaker 0: It seems like it seemed if you look at the Wikipedia It's pretty much this guy and his two and his his friends his two friends wrote did.
Speaker 1: most of the are pretty much Responsible for the show, but there's a team of four editors who as far as I can tell have a heavy influence on the show.
Speaker 1: But basically the voice acting is top-notch.
Speaker 1: The show is extremely funny.
Speaker 1: It is true to the villains and it takes it does a lot and it really Breaks the rest of the DC Universe and it is a serial plot that just advances Like.
Speaker 1: I really don't want to spoil anything other than there's a point where the bad guys win and then Gotham's just fucked.
Speaker 1: Here's what Gotham's like if Batman's gone and Superman's gone and guess what?
Speaker 1: It sucks.
Speaker 1: Hey, I find this show funny enough to where I'm basically watching it as fast as I can.
Speaker 1: I really look forward to watching the third season.
Speaker 1: I've only watched the first two seasons so far and If you enjoy the venture brothers and you're worried that you won't get a lot more of it This is not as funny or good as the venture brothers But it is very much along the same lines Just not as polished as the venture brothers like.
Speaker 1: it's almost the same kind of story just using DC intellectual property instead of a homegrown intellectual property and the editing and the writing is just not as Polished as the venture brothers.
Speaker 1: So you need more venture brothers.
Speaker 1: This is your show.
Speaker 1: if you don't like the DC Universe this might be your DC show to watch and I really enjoy it.
Speaker 1: It is also full disclosure Extremely violence and the violence is juxtaposed by the fact that no one in the show Canonically cares at all about that violence.
Speaker 0: hmm Also, it's an HBO.
Speaker 0: So it has to either be violent or sexy or both.
Speaker 0: Right?
Speaker 0: Yep, or it has to be Which usually involves violent sex in both.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but HBO do.
Speaker 1: it's also they like.
Speaker 1: King Shark is not a character I ever expected to have anything interesting going on with and yet he's one of the best characters in this show.
Speaker 0: Well, that's the Suicide Squad.
Speaker 0: Yeah the shark.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So in some other news There's more Lupin coming.
Speaker 1: I think we might have mentioned this briefly at some point.
Speaker 0: They seem to now be in this groove, you know where they're regular, you know It's like there was a few Lupin TV series and then there was a long break where there was just you know And specials here and there and then you know, there was the Fujiko Mina whatever but seems like you know recently ish And I had didn't look it up.
Speaker 0: I don't know exactly what year.
Speaker 0: it's probably longer ago than my memory tells me We should go.
Speaker 1: Mina came out when we were living in Beacon.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right, but it's like it seems like you know in the past few years which again I'm not gonna try to guess what year because I'm probably gonna guess wrong and it's probably longer ago than I think.
Speaker 0: but they came out with Lupin series.
Speaker 0: Four five, I think.
Speaker 0: four and I think there's a gap between three and four was like very large in years wise.
Speaker 0: But since four, I think it's like four five six is the new one six, I think or seven.
Speaker 1: Yeah, Lupin the third part six six.
Speaker 0: so I think it's like four or five six, they're like boom boom boom and I haven't seen them but all the indications are that they're all you know High-level well, very good Lupin pretty much of them.
Speaker 0: every once I just have to figure out where they are So I can watch them.
Speaker 1: I probably will starting with would you go Mina?
Speaker 1: pretty much every Lupin thing that's come out since then has been a top-tier Lupin and a top-tier just animated thing.
Speaker 1: to be honest.
Speaker 0: It feels like there was some sort of turning point where like the loop someone was looking at the Lupin status quo and they're like Okay, Lupin is just sort of in this rut of doing his thing over and over right?
Speaker 0: Let's we got a choice.
Speaker 0: We can either put a kid put a sock in it be like, all right That's enough or we can you know Give it another go and it seems like they gave it another go and it's working out and they're just.
Speaker 0: you know We're right like you're a Lupin fan Fueled the Lupin and it's still going at full speed.
Speaker 1: But the other thing interesting now I just got clear because I see him credited as a writer but also as a guest writer like it's not and maybe as a producer role, but Mamoru she is.
Speaker 1: this is attached to Lupin the third part six in this article.
Speaker 1: He is credited as a writer.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think he's working on it to some extent.
Speaker 1: Yep, but okay.
Speaker 1: He is a guest writer.
Speaker 1: It looks like there's some other guest writers.
Speaker 1: So like there's a mystery novelist who's popular?
Speaker 0: Taku Ashibi there might be one episode per person.
Speaker 1: kind of deal might be something like that, which honestly Intrigues me.
Speaker 1: that's exciting.
Speaker 0: do a little do a little upon anthology series in season six here.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there's a note in this anime news network article that oh, she was at some point in the past involved in a Unnamed Lupin the third film.
Speaker 1: that never like it never got made.
Speaker 1: It just got canned for some reason.
Speaker 1: and The thing I'm most excited about is if oh, she's doing anything.
Speaker 1: in my personal opinion everything oh, she is interacted with this animated has been good and everything goes Well.
Speaker 1: At least has been interesting to me.
Speaker 1: anything he's been associated with that has been live-action has been a fart noise generally, I Don't know what he's done.
Speaker 1: recently I kind of ignored him for several.
Speaker 0: Oh, she is not.
Speaker 0: Oh, she is interesting in that he is not someone who's like You know putting out solid gold every season out.
Speaker 0: that is not the hand of Midas, right?
Speaker 0: The Midas touch where it's like everything he produces amazing.
Speaker 0: He has this touch where everything he produces is Mamoru.
Speaker 0: She's yeah I think you can tell that he made it
Speaker 1: That I thought
Speaker 0: even if he makes something that's a stinker right which is not infrequent You watch it and if you like the Mamoru Oh, she flavor It's sort of like Okay, this isn't great, but I can still taste the Mamoru.
Speaker 0: Oh, she spice.
Speaker 0: How often can you taste that?
Speaker 0: I like that spice.
Speaker 0: up to a point Yeah, but you took that spice and just slapped it on a sad piece of chicken breast or whatever.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like the thing he was like, I don't know.
Speaker 1: the stuff He was best at were old animated shows in my opinion.
Speaker 0: But again, he does.
Speaker 0: I think he he has this thing where he just doesn't want to.
Speaker 1: You know, you look at someone like you like if guy Richie was like, you know, what?
Speaker 1: I don't really like making heist movies.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna make a right.
Speaker 1: I'm all rom-coms.
Speaker 0: You see certain people.
Speaker 0: they have a thing that they're good at and it's like they just keep doing that thing and people are like Hey, you're so one-note and it's like I'm really good at playing that note.
Speaker 0: It's making me money.
Speaker 0: What's the problem?
Speaker 0: and you look at Mamoru.
Speaker 0: Oh, she and it's like ghost in the shell Pat LeBourg.
Speaker 0: It's like whoa, just make like a hunt.
Speaker 0: make make more of those until the end of time, please.
Speaker 0: and he's like nah That's I'm tired of that.
Speaker 0: It's like no just make ten more Pat LeBourg's please.
Speaker 0: That's all the kind of anime.
Speaker 0: I want to see.
Speaker 0: Oh, I promise if you make more I won't watch any other anime, so I'll just watch only those.
Speaker 0: No, I wasn't do it.
Speaker 0: He goes and make some other nonsense.
Speaker 1: Yeah So basically your takeaway is if you haven't been watching Lupin stuff since before the the Fujiko mean a show me Help me figure out where we can watch.
Speaker 0: Yeah My thing is a funimation.
Speaker 1: Maybe I mean the last Lupin thing We both watched and reviewed on geek nights was the 3d CG one, which was also fantastic.
Speaker 0: Yeah, pretty good that was.
Speaker 1: that was a. that was an upper-tier Lupin Irrespective of how it was made or anything else around it and I did enjoy that.
Speaker 1: it got it aged into Lupin lore a little bit, but it didn't take it too far Lupin.
Speaker 0: the third part for English dub is on Prime.
Speaker 0: I don't know if there's a sub though.
Speaker 1: Nah And in some other news the of the final with a big asterisk next to it.
Speaker 1: adventure time or at least the final Adventure time distant lands wizard city did come out.
Speaker 0: there might be more distant lands, but this is the final.
Speaker 0: I'd already announced.
Speaker 1: distant lands Yeah, and there's that Fiona and cake thing come.
Speaker 1: I'm pretty sure as I posited way back that they might just trickle out adventure time content forever As well, I mean as long as people still watch it and care about it.
Speaker 0: Yes They'll still keep making it to some extent.
Speaker 0: But yeah, I watch the wizard city.
Speaker 0: I'm not gonna say anything about the wizard city, except something happens in it that made me Specifically very won't upset other people necessarily, but it made me specifically very very upset and unhappy.
Speaker 0: But then do not miss the post credit scene.
Speaker 0: There is a very brief We're talking seconds long, right?
Speaker 0: Just a few seconds.
Speaker 0: post credit scene.
Speaker 0: essential post credit scene redeemed Redeemed all and erased all unhappiness.
Speaker 1: So that's like the opposite of the alien 9. post credit scene.
Speaker 0: Do not miss the post credit scene.
Speaker 0: It is Maybe even the best part of the wizard city.
Speaker 1: I'm just glad that they in the show like in the universe of adventure time Tried to do everything they could to let peppermint butler become what he was before the thing happened.
Speaker 1: Mmm, I like that just as a character note on the over.
Speaker 0: watch it.
Speaker 1: No, I didn't watch it yet.
Speaker 1: Okay?
Speaker 0: Well, you should watch it before you say things like that.
Speaker 1: Ah, I mean sending him to wizard school.
Speaker 1: That's just.
Speaker 1: that's as good as you're gonna do in terms of you should.
Speaker 0: you should watch it before you say things like.
Speaker 0: that Is all I'm saying.
Speaker 0: cuz you're way off.
Speaker 0: I was I was thinking the same thing you were thinking when I read the description, but the nature of peppermint butler's Status is not what you were thinking.
Speaker 0: It is which is I I thought the same as you based on the how he ended up the last time we saw him.
Speaker 0: But our thinking was wrong or at least they made our thinking wrong With what they have done in wizard city.
Speaker 1: So interesting that imply anyway.
Speaker 1: Well, we'll review it fully probably after we review those Evangelion movies now that they're all out.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: I saw them all.
Speaker 1: Yep, all I've seen all of them pretty.
Speaker 0: maybe I'll watch them all again.
Speaker 1: I I have an urge to watch the original show again.
Speaker 1: That's one of them the shows I've seen the most times of any anime show.
Speaker 0: Well, you should.
Speaker 0: I would recommend if you're gonna do that nothing wrong with doing that.
Speaker 0: I might do that too, but The Movies the rebuild movies, right?
Speaker 0: Regardless of how good that even if they whether you think they stink or whether you think they're better than the TV show doesn't matter.
Speaker 0: In my opinion one interesting feature of them is that by their existence they original TV show is better Because these rebuild things just I just are there.
Speaker 0: so you should watch them first Because then when you if you go back and watch the TV show again It will just be better than it was the last time you saw it.
Speaker 1: Thing is that that original event I still remember the first time I saw the original Evangelion and I stand by it being one of the best animated things ever made.
Speaker 0: Well, it'll be even better if you watch the rebuild movies Even if you hate them.
Speaker 0: even if you hate the rebuild movies if you just watch them and then go back to the TV show the TV show will be better than otherwise be.
Speaker 1: So in one little brief news We knew from Ken and from basically what anyone who has seen this movie has said so far That Bell Mamoru hosted his latest stuff.
Speaker 1: Opus is gonna be fantastic.
Speaker 1: But we have yet another piece of evidence gonna be.
Speaker 0: it's out.
Speaker 1: So it is is yes, but we have not seen it yet.
Speaker 1: No, it's not clear when or how we'll see it since I don't think we're going to theaters anytime soon.
Speaker 0: It's gonna be in theaters here soon.
Speaker 0: I think tickets went on sale maybe today even To go see it at the Walter Reed theater, which is where we last saw Satoshi khan in person over by Lincoln Center.
Speaker 0: but Yeah, I'm not gonna go to some movie theater and risk my life for a movie no matter how good the movie is.
Speaker 0: I'm not gonna die to see it.
Speaker 0: Literally.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right only metaphorically am I dying to see it?
Speaker 1: So so it's been.
Speaker 0: we're gonna have to wait until it is safe to see it in a theater or at home.
Speaker 1: So it's been in Japanese theaters for eight weeks now and yep in its eighth week.
Speaker 1: It is still the number two movie.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean, it's not like.
Speaker 0: I don't know what movies have come along to try to unseat it.
Speaker 0: But you know still being the number two movie after eight weeks is pretty, you know significant.
Speaker 1: that's not common Generally granted.
Speaker 1: I don't know a lot about how Jeff like To see if it's getting up there, you know in terms of like your name levels of Because last I looked at stats for American theaters generally American.
Speaker 1: in America movies Disappear after a couple weeks like even if they're great.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think I think your name is basically the current like bar.
Speaker 0: right for an anime movie in Japan.
Speaker 0: that you're the high bar.
Speaker 0: I don't you see how close it gets to that bar to judge.
Speaker 0: You know how well it's doing.
Speaker 0: spirited away was the previous bar, but your name broke it.
Speaker 1: So yeah, but I am Very excited to see that movie.
Speaker 0: However, and whenever I see it, but not gonna and also, you know not having seen Belle Obviously, but having seen your name and knowing what I know about Belle I think I will.
Speaker 0: my guess is that I will like Belle more than your name Regardless of whether Belle beats it out at the box office at some point in the future.
Speaker 1: So some other little news.
Speaker 1: Keiichi Ararai has What a new manga coming, right?
Speaker 0: so Keiichi Ararai is the person who brought us Nichijou and Helvetica standard and the two mangas that come.
Speaker 0: yeah those two mangas combined made the Nichijou TV show and Then we did an episode on the manga city, which I'm still reading and I only ever read the first volume.
Speaker 1: I should borrow that from you and read the rest.
Speaker 0: city is almost done.
Speaker 0: I think it is done, but there's 13 volumes.
Speaker 0: I have 11 of them.
Speaker 0: So I'm waiting for two more maybe.
Speaker 0: And that's the end of city like it's gonna end.
Speaker 0: end.
Speaker 0: And they put out a mysterious announcement, which is not so mysterious.
Speaker 0: It's clearly the new manga that is being started by Keiichi Ararai coming very soon But we know nothing about it.
Speaker 0: Other than that.
Speaker 0: Yes, they're making a new manga.
Speaker 0: So I'm gonna be all over that.
Speaker 0: So hey Your eyeballs on the comic order form for the remaining volumes of city in English and the first volume of whatever the hell's coming Next
Speaker 1: kind of figure out where I can watch Nichijou cuz it hasn't been on crunchyroll for a long time and I can't actually
Speaker 0: find animation Pirate Bay.
Speaker 1: I just googled.
Speaker 1: Where can I watch Nichijou?
Speaker 1: legally?
Speaker 1: and Crunchyroll is still the top result despite the fact that it has been on crunchyroll for years.
Speaker 0: Streaming is what I'm gonna type in Nichijou my ordinary life watch on crunchyroll.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's not there.
Speaker 1: obvious might be on Funimation.
Speaker 0: where to watch Nichijou?
Speaker 1: It's on Funimation.
Speaker 1: I found it there.
Speaker 1: Okay, you gotta pay for the premium Funimation to watch it.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: There we go.
Speaker 1: But anyway things Of the day.
Speaker 1: so, uh, this is a very short Twitter video but it is just someone used a deep fake algorithm to Replace an actor in the famous movie pretty woman with Willem Dafoe instead.
Speaker 1: It's not the character you expected to be and or maybe it is I mean I assume if you if you know me then you a hundred percent assume that this is replacing Julia Roberts and not Richard Gere like.
Speaker 1: But this movie not worth watching in a modern era.
Speaker 1: a lot of problems in it.
Speaker 1: I would say I haven't seen it since I was in like high school.
Speaker 0: I never saw it.
Speaker 0: I just but you couldn't not know.
Speaker 1: it existed in 1990 when I was a little kid like in the 90s.
Speaker 1: the one thing I took away from this movie was why is George Costanza in it?
Speaker 0: because I didn't even know he was in it.
Speaker 0: Cuz I never saw.
Speaker 1: I only ever saw the poster and I knew the song Alexander in anything except Seinfeld and duck man up to that point.
Speaker 0: Yeah, pretty much but You know, it's like I. you couldn't escape knowing that the movie existed, but I never saw it Not even I think even parts of it.
Speaker 0: So I can't even tell you one scene.
Speaker 0: But this I assume the two I assume the two famous people kiss the end.
Speaker 1: Replacing an actor with another actor via deep fakes is a what I would consider a fully approved use case for deep fake technology.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean we see you know This is the.
Speaker 0: I'm sure it's been done before.
Speaker 0: but this is the first time that I've actually heard of Verified instance of someone going through and doing the whole fucking movie, right?
Speaker 1: It's like usually Actually do the entire movie.
Speaker 1: They did a bunch of scenes together.
Speaker 0: Okay, well the whole movie would probably Honestly, this is enough because I was gonna say I was like, oh someone did the whole movie why that's sort of unnecessary.
Speaker 0: No one's actually gonna watch that.
Speaker 0: you can get your point across with just a few scenes Right, I guess.
Speaker 0: Okay, they did just to do a few.
Speaker 1: see I feel like if they did the whole movie I might watch it, but that's me.
Speaker 1: Yeah, why I'm MV.
Speaker 0: Did they do you think the voice also?
Speaker 1: No, it's just really Roberts voice which actually works and makes it funnier.
Speaker 0: It could work, but it would also be funnier to to do the voice.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think it would be equally funny but differently funny if it was also Willem Dafoe's voice.
Speaker 1: Mmm, somebody got.
Speaker 0: So, yeah, you know everyone these days, you know, even though I guess it's it's already out of style.
Speaker 0: Right given the rate at which you know fashion and music trendiness moves.
Speaker 0: You know, we love that vaporwave type style and that vaporwave type style is usually embodied in 90s computer interfaces.
Speaker 0: Yeah and VHS and cassette tapes right and the art style they're upon.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so here's a website that I didn't know about.
Speaker 0: I don't know how old it is.
Speaker 0: It could be really old and I just didn't discover it till recently or maybe this possible.
Speaker 0: This is a thing of the day so long ago.
Speaker 0: I don't remember but it's tape deck org and all it is is a website that collects JPEGs of blank cassette tapes Of all brands, you know makes models so that you can peruse them Right and you can search by brand running time the material of the tape and color.
Speaker 0: Alright, and you can.
Speaker 0: maybe there was a particular kind of tape that you had.
Speaker 0: I learned from this that the blank cassette tapes that I had were Sony HF 90s with the yellow red orange Stripe on the sticker that were clear and see-through.
Speaker 0: And also I learned that the most stylish possible cassette tape is the Memorex DBS.
Speaker 0: So and you can just go in.
Speaker 0: you know cassette tapes are not like rare even blank ones.
Speaker 0: You can just go on eBay and buy some you know cassette tapes if you want.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's far from complete.
Speaker 1: There's a lot of things missing from this still like Obviously because there's a lot of different cassettes out there.
Speaker 0: There's a lot but if you have some you can submit them.
Speaker 0: If there's any that you didn't you know don't have any sure.
Speaker 1: I got rid of every cassette tape I ever owned.
Speaker 0: I don't think I have any left anywhere.
Speaker 0: Not least not here, but if you For some reason want to be nostalgic and use cassette tapes There are still some record labels producing them in limited quantities for new releases and things like that.
Speaker 1: You can also just make your own.
Speaker 1: just record whatever you want.
Speaker 1: on to cassettes.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you can buy some blank ones on eBay.
Speaker 0: I looked on eBay for the Memorex DBS ones that look better.
Speaker 0: the cooler the high the good styling ones Yeah, and there was like it was like three pack completely sealed 12 bucks.
Speaker 1: They're like whatever plus late-stage like the like once you got the the fancy metal tapes like the good tapes at the end of the run of cassettes.
Speaker 1: they are So much better than even the best possible vinyl, and yeah, they're about CD quality.
Speaker 0: actually yeah They're not they're not bad But you know based on how I don't know if they denature over time.
Speaker 0: even if they're blank or anything they definitely do.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the only thing I want to warn people of is that if you're gonna get a kiss you got to get a cassette player.
Speaker 0: You got to make sure your heads on the cassette player are clean.
Speaker 0: all right that everything's all you that you're.
Speaker 0: you know everything's well Lubricated so it spins at the right speed of the motor and everything.
Speaker 1: you also have to make sure your cassette deck supports the specific Formulation of the tape you're using.
Speaker 0: there's different types of cassettes And the most important thing if you're gonna get into cassette tape usage for some nostalgic reason Doby and our noise reduction is an essential feature.
Speaker 0: you need to make sure Right that all you have all those ducks in a row regarding noise reduction or else it just gonna sell garbage.
Speaker 1: It's a little more complicated.
Speaker 1: you had the tape has a particular kind of noise reduction And then the deck has a way to use that noise reduction if those are not.
Speaker 0: What I'm saying though is a lot.
Speaker 0: if you go out and try to buy like a tape deck these days a lot of them just like don't have the Dolby noise reduction.
Speaker 0: that is the most common and standard noise reduction and Everything's gonna sound like ass.
Speaker 0: you want to buy.
Speaker 0: maybe buy an old one.
Speaker 0: If you can't like buy like a really high quality one That's old like the same thing I do for cameras.
Speaker 0: right we're like I buy.
Speaker 0: You know the most like what camera was an absolute fucking professional using in 1990. it's like yeah, it's a really old film camera, but guess what it was top of the line then.
Speaker 0: so it's still really good I'm gonna link to.
Speaker 0: I'll put a third thing of the day in there instead of buying a Shitty cassette deck made in the year 2021 going by like the ultra rich person hi-fi cassette deck from 1990 when Pretty Woman was in movie theaters, and that'll be way better.
Speaker 1: So I'll link to a third thing of the day that might be relevant if this peaked your fancy.
Speaker 1: It's a techmoan video.
Speaker 1: I don't use them as in the day because I've used them much in the past but this is about a half hour long and it will tell you the full deal on all the different kinds of tapes and the Dolby and everything.
Speaker 1: and if you watch this video You will know More than you need to know about tapes and you will be able to do whatever you want to do with tapes with no problems.
Speaker 0: This video is much like much like vinyl.
Speaker 0: don't go down the tape road because you think it's gonna sound better because it's not.
Speaker 0: It's just for fun.
Speaker 0: That's the reason to go down the tape road and also the aesthetics of the tape are cool.
Speaker 1: So all right.
Speaker 1: so in the meta moment the geeks book club book is the tale of Genji.
Speaker 1: I have not read.
Speaker 1: I read some yesterday Oh, I didn't read any in the last week, but I did read a bunch up until the previous geek nights Mmm.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: It's the first novel read it the first novel ever in the history of humans.
Speaker 1: So, uh, it's pretty good.
Speaker 1: I said this a bunch of times.
Speaker 1: I'll just say it one more time if you're reading it with us We're gonna finish it in the next month or two because we're actually reading it now.
Speaker 1: but do not like try to get too precious about knowing exactly what happened and Exactly who everyone is and when we actually have an episode on this.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna say so much stuff That's like, you know, oh that is gonna be so many realizations and wrongnesses.
Speaker 0: It's gonna be like, yeah.
Speaker 1: Oh my god I I usually frame things by like Who is what kind of person was Genji trying to have sex with in that chapter?
Speaker 1: And that is how I remember like what that chapter was.
Speaker 0: Oh that person from that chapter.
Speaker 0: was that person from a different show?
Speaker 1: I lose track.
Speaker 0: I'm pretty sure the say I booked the book now calls them something different.
Speaker 1: that I'm pretty sure.
Speaker 1: I Am thinking that the same person is multiple people in a few of these instances.
Speaker 0: Or yeah, or there's you know, yeah, but vice versa.
Speaker 1: It's pretty good.
Speaker 1: I picked the next book club book.
Speaker 1: It'll probably be a pretty quick read.
Speaker 1: I'm pretty excited to read it.
Speaker 0: I am excited to make up when we are eventually done with this to make up for the debacle Which is partially pandemic induced debacle of taking several years to read one book.
Speaker 0: I am going.
Speaker 0: I've already decided.
Speaker 0: For the foreseeable future all Selected books will be of the nature that will end quickly Right the kind that you know will want to read and won't be that long and such.
Speaker 0: so yep Otherwise our let me one book in three years But then we'll.
Speaker 0: basically what I'll do is I'll we'll read so many books so fast until the book rate Evens out again.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so Otherwise our most recent packs panel Atari game design is just on YouTube.
Speaker 1: You can just watch it.
Speaker 1: packs West happened this past weekend.
Speaker 1: We were not there, but as the listener pointed out in the last stream I at least have been to since 2008 every packs that Gabe has also been to.
Speaker 1: Okay, cuz he stopped going to the packs Australia's and he also didn't go to this one and he's done As a measuring stick for anything.
Speaker 1: Measuring stick for that one very specific metric.
Speaker 1: Beyond that check out our forum our live stream.
Speaker 1: There's a chat there.
Speaker 1: There's all this different stuff.
Speaker 1: just type geek nights into the internet, and you'll find all our crap and I'll get right into it with soups.
Speaker 1: So full disclosure I'm not a big fan of really DC anything like.
Speaker 1: I like Batman and Batman adjacent things And I appreciate Superman.
Speaker 1: I've seen a bunch of Superman things much like Superman like spider-man is one of those characters that just Everyone like in America, everyone knows Superman's deal, even if they have never read a comic book in their life Just like everyone knows spider-man's deal.
Speaker 0: I Think the thing with Superman is that the actual story of Superman, right?
Speaker 0: It's a story of Immigration, right?
Speaker 0: It's a story of you know, even though he's a white dude, right?
Speaker 0: He's like an alien.
Speaker 0: come to earth, right?
Speaker 0: It's a story of you know You know like a guy who's you know, so powerful, right?
Speaker 0: It's like but yet is good, right?
Speaker 0: You get this are like this, you know benevolent God situation going on right?
Speaker 0: It's like there's so many angles You know.
Speaker 0: you could talk about them for like a hundred years, right?
Speaker 0: You could talk about the people, you know, Simon Schuster made Superman right.
Speaker 0: all this stuff going on.
Speaker 0: But The actual most that I have read or watched Actual Superman media right end up not actually going down those roads.
Speaker 1: Yep, that is my main complaint with Superman is that most Superman stories don't tell the stories.
Speaker 1: I am interested in about an Individual very powerful person who wants to do good in a cruel and evil world.
Speaker 0: Right, it's like, you know you see, you know, some of them do right, you know some of them do but it's like when I was a kid the Superman that I actually I think probably still to this day the Superman that I have consumed the most is That Lois and Clark Superman TV show because we my family watched that.
Speaker 0: it was on like 8 o'clock Like I forget what day.
Speaker 1: Oh my god.
Speaker 1: We watched that too.
Speaker 1: I liked it.
Speaker 0: Okay Yeah, I mean, I remember it being okay, but it was pretty much just.
Speaker 0: You know 90s TV level, you know Sikkami kind of show right?
Speaker 0: It didn't dart.
Speaker 0: It didn't dig deep on any plots, right?
Speaker 0: It was like, oh no, there's some danger.
Speaker 1: He fights it Which to be fair like a lot of Batman media like even B test which I love was also like that.
Speaker 1: it just had a lot of style and occasional very brilliant episodes and like Did more but it didn't really interrogate the Batman in the way that I like.
Speaker 1: the Batman interrogated, right?
Speaker 0: But eat that's true.
Speaker 0: But you know while the Batman has much to interrogate Superman has way more to interrogate.
Speaker 1: Yeah, anybody see I am a living God among humans.
Speaker 1: I hide my identity, but I'm still just one, dude I can't just fix the world.
Speaker 0: this journalism aspect that goes on in Superman, right only so often gets explored.
Speaker 0: You know just so much going on there.
Speaker 0: but when it does get explored right when there is a Take on Superman right that actually goes down those roads.
Speaker 0: It's like it's like so good, right?
Speaker 0: I mean we already.
Speaker 0: we've already did an episode super long ago about you know, Frank Miller's got his issues.
Speaker 0: But in the Dark Knight Returns, it's like there's like even though Superman is like this shiny You know sun is shining good guy.
Speaker 0: It's like there's like this absolute terror, right?
Speaker 0: It's almost like a Lovecraftian terror Like if Superman is coming because it's like it's like God is coming like you're gonna get Moses gonna see the fucking burning bush Yeah, holy shit.
Speaker 0: And then it's just like, you know There's something going on and it's like you see how you see like a blur and like the bad guys are gone Right.
Speaker 0: It's like the end.
Speaker 0: It's like he just took care of it like that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there's none of that.
Speaker 1: Plays with that.
Speaker 1: there's a couple episode.
Speaker 1: We're like super.
Speaker 1: if Superman shows up It's just over like whatever was happening is over when Superman shows up.
Speaker 0: That's how it's supposed to be.
Speaker 0: There are too many.
Speaker 0: you watch most Superman stuff like the old the super old public domain Superman cartoons and it's like, you know I guess that was when he couldn't even fly this way.
Speaker 0: He could only jump and stuff really high.
Speaker 0: but he just you know He's punching out like bank robbers and mad scientists like it's like one punch to Superman and their head explodes, bro.
Speaker 0: It's like they never flies to the moon or some shit.
Speaker 0: It's like it doesn't beat up dudes like spider-man does Right, it's it's led, you know Saitama level here right when you get involved with yeah You can't be punching other human beings.
Speaker 0: They'll just indeed build their good.
Speaker 0: They'll be ribs all over the place.
Speaker 0: Yeah Rib tips or whatever.
Speaker 1: the other super that I actually saw way more of is the old black and white TV show because it was On late at night.
Speaker 0: I never watched that.
Speaker 1: I watched a lot of that show and the only episode I have specific memories of because they were they were almost all almost every one of that old show like the episodes were just here's a very particular very zoomed in tiny problem that Superman is trying to solve.
Speaker 1: and the one I remember is some dude committed some crime and He locked himself in an extremely like thick safe until the statute of limitations would run out and Superman couldn't get in.
Speaker 0: so man can get in.
Speaker 0: so that's no.
Speaker 1: so the plot was Superman couldn't get in.
Speaker 1: it was too much for even Superman to get in.
Speaker 1: so he learned some technique to Change the atoms in his own body.
Speaker 1: Thanks to his superpowers in the Sun to walk through walls.
Speaker 1: So he starts walking through the wall of this giant safe to get in to arrest this dude.
Speaker 1: and The dude psychs him out by being like yeah, but what if you don't Rematerialize?
Speaker 1: is this is real dangerous what you're doing.
Speaker 1: So Superman gives up and Superman then solves this problem with his.
Speaker 1: in that show massive intellect.
Speaker 0: wouldn't.
Speaker 0: wouldn't the guy Suffocate in the safe.
Speaker 1: Oh, he had a way to get air There.
Speaker 1: was they like they?
Speaker 1: this was this very much make just pump gas in there.
Speaker 1: Uh Superman wasn't evil enough to do something like that.
Speaker 1: In the end they just fucked.
Speaker 1: they made the clock inside the safe move a little faster.
Speaker 1: So he came out five minutes before the 20 years was up and then Superman just arrested him.
Speaker 0: That's oh my god.
Speaker 0: That's ridiculous.
Speaker 1: That's what that show was like.
Speaker 0: That's awful.
Speaker 0: In some ways it's clear.
Speaker 0: in some ways it's clever right but in other ways it's like, you know That's the.
Speaker 0: you got Superman right there.
Speaker 0: Don't need to miss the app you have and you what.
Speaker 0: Superman has nothing to do with that.
Speaker 0: if you saw it's an Indiana Jones Situation.
Speaker 0: we're like.
Speaker 0: he contributed nothing to the solution.
Speaker 0: He came up with the idea See, I guess maybe there were.
Speaker 1: there was another one where I remember he had to use this.
Speaker 1: He had to use his heat vision to save the day but he was still Clark Kent.
Speaker 1: so he couldn't do it because it would melt his glasses.
Speaker 1: every would know.
Speaker 1: and In the end his he almost solved everything with a clever idea.
Speaker 1: The clever idea was he removed the lenses from his frames to be able to do the thing without melting them though for the one Time he needed to do it the end.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: Yeah That's the other right.
Speaker 0: So that's I think that's also, you know, where some of the corniness comes from right?
Speaker 0: It's like you have this good aspect of.
Speaker 0: you know, he was raised by humans Right and you had is that connection to humanity right parents even though they're not his real parents his biological parents.
Speaker 0: They're his real parents not biological right his biological parents and from whatever alien.
Speaker 0: Yeah, Krypton, whatever, right?
Speaker 0: So you have the adoption story, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, you get a found family story around that like the connections he makes cuz he doesn't have any biological family left anywhere in the Universe.
Speaker 0: and I don't know.
Speaker 0: Clark Kent was the original secret identity, but it effectively set the the template for everyone else's secret identity who came later.
Speaker 0: It was modeled after the Superman secret identity.
Speaker 0: So and but the thing is that actual no matter how good an interpretation of Superman you're watching The secret identity part if it's in play because sometimes it's not in play if you're watching super friends It's like he's just always Superman.
Speaker 1: He doesn't or just no can't in that Can't off on his own and then separately.
Speaker 1: just he's in the Justice League base Just talking to people sometimes like he's just right.
Speaker 1: He's just one of the x-men effectively Yeah, it's like.
Speaker 0: why do you even need the super friends if Superman is there?
Speaker 0: Why do you still have any of these twins?
Speaker 0: What are they contribute?
Speaker 0: The flash.
Speaker 0: what's what's the point of the flash?
Speaker 0: Superman can go fast and He's like the Superman is the flash plus more things.
Speaker 0: Why do you why is the flash should just retire?
Speaker 1: I guess because of all those aspects like the wholesome nature like he grew up in a humble Family and he learned to connect with humans, but also he's a living God on this earth.
Speaker 1: But his powers are very limited within the bounds of like what other superheroes can do in the expanded DC Universe.
Speaker 1: I like the stories where Superman is the only super thing Mmm, like or like like.
Speaker 1: imagine.
Speaker 1: Superman versus famine is a way more interesting story than Superman versus I don't know doomsday.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well, I mean you think the number one Superman villain is Lex Luthor right who I don't know.
Speaker 0: I'll guess over time.
Speaker 0: You know if you read certain comics has superpowers, but at least nominally Lex lit the basic.
Speaker 0: Lex Luthor is Justin is just you know, Ellen Musk right?
Speaker 0: Ellen Musk is literally Lex Luthor.
Speaker 0: It's a rich dude who's up to no good.
Speaker 0: Yeah, just want you know, it's just evil, you know and runs a business.
Speaker 0: So it's really, you know Superman versus you know industry and capitalism, right?
Speaker 0: That's the.
Speaker 0: and metaphorically the story there is really good But the way it plays off it's like if there was a Superman and those an Ellen Musk.
Speaker 0: Superman could just The end.
Speaker 0: right.
Speaker 0: why it's like.
Speaker 0: But it's like, you know, it took a while before the you know, Lex Luthor found out about kryptonite.
Speaker 0: somehow Superman could just taken care of it at any time before that the end.
Speaker 0: Why did why did this happen?
Speaker 0: Makes no sense.
Speaker 0: It's just silly.
Speaker 0: so it was like this.
Speaker 0: these metaphors Right because of the structure of the story and the personality and whatnot.
Speaker 0: The the good metaphors and the good stories told the Superman can't escape those sort of corny Ham-fisted plot holes and various things when they try to keep the story down to earth, right?
Speaker 0: and So depending on which Superman you read a lot of times It's like, you know, it's.
Speaker 0: it's hard to digest as someone with it with a brain from the year 2020.
Speaker 1: There is well one of the later Superman cartoons one of the more recent ones there is that they do do a really good take on Lex Luthor and they cuz like.
Speaker 1: the long roundabout story is basically that Lex Luthor is so Fucked up in evil and Ellen Muskie that he cannot.
Speaker 1: his main thing Is that he thinks Superman is an evil threat and always.
Speaker 0: that's always been true Similar to JJ and Jamison, y'all spider-man only.
Speaker 0: but JJ isn't actually evil He's just sort of like, you know.
Speaker 1: But that show resolves that like.
Speaker 1: the big plot of that show is eventually something happens and Lex Luthor Gets Superman's powers for a little while and I think there's been some comics where you know, Luther gets magic or other.
Speaker 1: I mean, I'm pretty sure but I don't cry.
Speaker 0: sometimes he swears like sometimes he wears like some sort of you know mech suit.
Speaker 0: He's almost like an Iron Man situation, which is also very Ellen Muskie thing.
Speaker 1: I don't like Batman I don't know which Superman thing.
Speaker 0: I don't know
Speaker 1: Because I've never read Superman comics
Speaker 0: but it's gonna be some, you know There's gonna be some listener who knows the real deal is gonna be like, oh my god, you're so wrong about this but I'll
Speaker 1: link to it because there's really good scene where Lex Luthor like sees everything and realizes that Superman was actually earnestly a good guy.
Speaker 0: Hmm well there is you know, that's another good angle to put on Superman.
Speaker 0: that is not often put is Even though he's a good guy right if you believe in Democracy and you believe in you know human self-determination.
Speaker 0: Right Mistakes right.
Speaker 0: even if Superman exists Right even for him to do good is Still tyrannical, right?
Speaker 0: It's like there is no.
Speaker 0: It's like even if you have a government and you vote for a president and everyone's there's an army and the army obeys the president's Orders, it's like even a Superman is just chilling at home in Kansas.
Speaker 0: Everyone is effectively, you know in principle obeying Superman's orders.
Speaker 0: Right, because if you weren't obeying his orders, he could just take the army and throw into the Sun.
Speaker 0: So the fact that he doesn't do that or he hasn't done that means you are obeying him Even if he hasn't even opened his mouth, right just in principle.
Speaker 0: the fact that he right so by his existence.
Speaker 0: It's like there is no democracy There is no freedom.
Speaker 0: as long as he's just there as if he's standing there doing nothing You all your freedom is in principle lost.
Speaker 0: So if you believe in freedom, even if you trust Superman is a good person, you know.
Speaker 0: If you believe in freedom as a principle because you're a libertarian or something You therefore must advocate for his destruction or exile or something to keep him in check.
Speaker 0: You're not the government like like the president has to have kryptonite or something.
Speaker 1: Well, I see that if you are not some libertarian dipshit and you actually believe in a bork nuanced concept of freedom Then freedom from becomes equally important as to freedom to write and freedom from Lex Luthor Or freedom from poverty.
Speaker 1: the Superman would be Morally justified in taking extreme actions to end poverty because unlike any human there is no consequence He could suffer and no risk He would have to take.
Speaker 1: the risk would be to all the people around him or him making a poor decision But he's not risking anything himself.
Speaker 0: Yeah there.
Speaker 0: Well, I haven't read or heard of a Superman story where he does anything like that.
Speaker 0: It's like he's from a farm.
Speaker 0: It's like he could.
Speaker 0: Superman could fly into space go to a planet where no one lives.
Speaker 0: That is it like arable Plant enough food for like everyone forever and personally deliver it and end all.
Speaker 0: and you know He could and you could see like, you know what?
Speaker 0: We don't need any more shipping boats or airplanes.
Speaker 0: I'm going to personally ship everything.
Speaker 0: It'll take me five minutes every morning.
Speaker 0: Right to ship all goods on earth with no climate change consequences.
Speaker 0: No fossil fuels or anything, right?
Speaker 0: Everyone who needs anything shipped just put an order in the supercomputer and I'll do it tomorrow.
Speaker 0: every you know at 9 a.m.
Speaker 0: Whatever right, but he never does anything fucking like that.
Speaker 0: All right, maybe someone wrote that story, but I haven't seen it.
Speaker 0: But that's a far cry from the original Superman who could just jump really high and punch really hard Sure, but yeah, I guess I guess the flying Superman has to come into play for that.
Speaker 0: The original Superman didn't fly.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well, there's there's a. the thing is the.
Speaker 1: how powerful Superman is is a wide varies a lot.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it literally ranges from I can jump high and punch things - I'm a literal living God composed primarily of energy.
Speaker 0: at this point Well, I think you know at some points it's like in different stories different universes.
Speaker 0: His power is different and also within a single universe his power will wax and wane over course of events, right?
Speaker 0: And it's also, you know the connect, you know, they'll always have some sort of explanation, right?
Speaker 0: It's like oh, he's got to be near the Sun.
Speaker 0: So he'll go to some other planet.
Speaker 0: He'll be weaker.
Speaker 0: They're different.
Speaker 1: so I guess he just has to be near any yellow Sun.
Speaker 1: There's a lot of them out there right.
Speaker 0: and then kryptonite which is just really corny.
Speaker 0: It's like he's near a particular rock.
Speaker 0: Therefore.
Speaker 0: He's weak.
Speaker 0: It's like what it's.
Speaker 0: you know, I'm sure they explained how the kryptonite works at some point, but I don't care.
Speaker 0: It's really, you know, I guess kryptonite became a coined term which in and of itself means like, you know a weakness.
Speaker 0: It's like you could be like, oh, that's my kryptonite and that's really my Contribution.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's a good contribution to the lexicon of the English language, but as a plot device, it's like really it's like you just needed something Something gives like you couldn't think of anything else, you know, and it's stuck, right?
Speaker 0: It's still we're stuck with as Superman's.
Speaker 1: now the other kind of story I enjoy quite a bit is when they Superman is basically just a modern-day Herakles too powerful for his own good.
Speaker 1: and Even if he does if he does the right thing or the wrong thing The consequences of anything he does are just bigger than what a normal person would do.
Speaker 1: yet He is not powerful enough to always do the right thing or make a big change so that die like this if you haven't read all the stories of Herakles or Hercules?
Speaker 1: if you're If you don't know what you're talking about He fucks up a lot and it's more a tragic story than a hero story.
Speaker 0: Well, yes, there's a lot of Superman story.
Speaker 0: I think it's just.
Speaker 0: that's just not Superman, but it's all.
Speaker 0: the superheroes have this sort of same story But Superman more so because his power level is greater.
Speaker 0: All right, and you know, he came earlier in that it's like, okay, you're Superman.
Speaker 0: Someone's falling off a building the old classic right.
Speaker 0: Superman's gonna catch him.
Speaker 0: if Superman doesn't catch him then Isn't that equivalent?
Speaker 0: Superman could have caught him at basically no cost Because you're Superman.
Speaker 0: if Superman lets him at the ground or is too busy or whatever That's equivalent to Superman throwing them off the building, right?
Speaker 0: It's like you make.
Speaker 0: you made that happen effectively.
Speaker 0: You could have stopped it and chose not to that edges into your trolley.
Speaker 0: Your power is.
Speaker 0: your power is so high.
Speaker 0: you were responsible for catching them and didn't right.
Speaker 0: you killed, you know It's like and that moral, you know, Superman being a good person would feel right responsible for that You know and other superheroes would probably have the same thing When you have more so much more power, but
Speaker 1: if you want to explore that idea, that's literally just the trolley problem You're better off just watching The Good Place than a Superman story,
Speaker 0: right?
Speaker 0: But Superman, you know, so old Relative to the other superheroes, right?
Speaker 0: You got to remember.
Speaker 0: it's like there were the history of comics.
Speaker 0: It's like comics were romance stories horror stories, mostly Westerns, right some sci-fi stuff.
Speaker 0: and then you get here Stuff Yeah, then you had you know, the comics code coming in and being like no no No, all this stuff is too inappropriate for the children's right?
Speaker 0: We can't be having that, you know cracking down in the comics and then it's like yeah There were superhero stories around but Superman action comics number one.
Speaker 0: It's like when that come came out, right?
Speaker 0: That's like okay.
Speaker 0: We got something.
Speaker 0: it obeys the comics code It's appropriate for the children and it's a smash hit right, you know?
Speaker 0: Because we don't have our you know Westerns and whatnot anymore which are not appropriate for the kids or at least not like.
Speaker 0: we use not the Westerns like we used to Have and that started.
Speaker 0: all the other superheroes stuff came after that right?
Speaker 0: There's no Superman.
Speaker 0: Spider-man wasn't until the 60s.
Speaker 0: Yeah way after Superman Batman was years later - everyone came after super one was what 1938.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like it's old shit.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's pre World War two.
Speaker 0: Yep Really old.
Speaker 0: Yeah, Captain America was coming to punch Nazis.
Speaker 0: It's like Superman.
Speaker 0: there weren't even Nazis when there was a Superman.
Speaker 0: Yeah He was.
Speaker 0: he was doing his super biz before then just fighting mad scientists and whatnot.
Speaker 1: Yeah, whatever, you know and I won't uh, I won't belabor this point But one of my favorite portrayals of Superman still is in the Frank Miller Batman dark.
Speaker 0: We talked about that already But we did.
Speaker 1: the episode we did on that comic is worth listening to if you're interested in this conversation because we talked about Superman a lot in that episode because Superman despite how few appearances he has in that comic is Like is such an overbearing presence when he appears on the page.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so the last thing is so, you know, not everyone, you know You can like tell a Superman story legally because you got to have the license He's still owned even though certain things are so old the public domain like the old cartoons.
Speaker 0: You can't just go making a Superman comic on your own and sell it for money, right?
Speaker 0: But a lot of you know, the Superman's powers flying strength, you know laser eyeball, right freeze breath Those all became like the template for other superheroes because you just gave him the same powers or almost the same powers, right?
Speaker 0: It's like oh, you know, you got a bunch of heroes flying around together right punching real hard or a super strength, whatever.
Speaker 0: So what you have seen is even if Superman himself doesn't officially Tell the kinds of stories that I would like to see from Superman at least often enough You do see a lot of times other people writing superhero stories with a superhero.
Speaker 0: That is Effectively fucking Superman.
Speaker 0: right they fly they punch hard.
Speaker 0: They're basically invincible.
Speaker 0: They just have a big like are on their chest maybe Yeah, or something like that and they just tell a story that could have been a Superman story.
Speaker 0: But isn't?
Speaker 0: it's in some other person
Speaker 1: that is actually the legacy of Superman that I am the most Invested in the people who take the long shadow of Superman and tell the story of a Superman themselves Not the canonical Superman, you
Speaker 0: know, I mean people do that with Superman to miniseries alternate universes and whatnot.
Speaker 0: But one one that comes to mind that I like a lot which isn't the greatest But I have it and I've read it all is there was a series called rising stars and in it There's a bunch of superheroes.
Speaker 0: But one of them is Superman.
Speaker 0: ish, right?
Speaker 0: It's sort of Superman Captain America ish type of character and spoilers for rising stars.
Speaker 0: He goes around the whole world and just takes Like all the nuclear weapons on earth from every country just yoinks him and throws him and gets rid of him.
Speaker 0: It's just like fuck.
Speaker 0: That's it.
Speaker 0: I forced nuclear dearmament.
Speaker 0: right deal with it.
Speaker 0: Um, what are you gonna?
Speaker 0: just stop me?
Speaker 0: You know, I can't stop me with the nuke.
Speaker 0: I'm effectively scary and he just fucking does it and it's like.
Speaker 0: that's the shit I love to see.
Speaker 0: right that sort of stuff that you know.
Speaker 0: Superman Occasionally does stuff like that but not often enough.
Speaker 1: Harley Quinn actually does it there.
Speaker 1: Superman take is interesting too because when he shows up he not only is all-powerful But he also like doesn't show up when he should.
Speaker 0: and well, that's that's what Saitama does.
Speaker 1: Yeah But he's very much portrayed as I like, you know, you could be doing a lot more buddy.
Speaker 0: Listen, well, I think the other well, it depends on which DC, you know, if you're going DC Universe stuff, right?
Speaker 0: It's like a lot of times Superman is dealing with even bigger problems in outer space.
Speaker 0: Hmm, right?
Speaker 0: It's like yeah There's people falling off buildings.
Speaker 0: There's a there's a mad scientist doing a crime or you know, see the you know Something like that, but it's like bro Asteroid is gonna like hit the earth.
Speaker 0: Superman is you know, he can't just do that instantly.
Speaker 0: Okay, it takes him at least a little time to go fly out there push the asteroid right onto some different orbit.
Speaker 1: I guess so It's.
Speaker 1: I've never really read or engaged with much Superman not doing like very mundane earth stuff.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like if you read, you know, a lot of that like crisis infinite earths Like he's just doing outer space dealing with all kinds of outer space like time shit, right?
Speaker 0: Making sure the fabric of the universe doesn't fall apart right, you know dealing with that sort of god-tier, you know threats Right cuz who else is gonna do it?
Speaker 0: Batman is not dealing with that shit Even though they end up in DC finding some way for him to help with that kind of stuff.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I feel like there's a lot of DC Universe stuff is predicated on the concept of how do we cram Batman in here?
Speaker 1: So this will sell Sometimes.
Speaker 0: but you know, it's like.
Speaker 0: yeah The flash just runs fast, even though sometimes they find a way that for the flash to help with it, too.
Speaker 0: But yeah, I know what other DC, you know, I guess there's like plastic man I was like, you know, we're Harley Quinn.
Speaker 0: Harley Quinn isn't gonna stop the space-time riff from ending the unit.
Speaker 1: Oh in fact Spoilers Gotham gets fucking destroyed at the end of the first season.
Speaker 1: Let's just like
Speaker 0: if one of the you know
Speaker 1: Cool now I get to hang out in a wrecked city fuck y'all, right
Speaker 0: If there's some DC villain going around not like the Joker but like Darkseid or some nonsense like yeah Only Superman's gonna be on the level to do anything about that.
Speaker 1: Yeah So I'm gonna read a lot because the other thing about Superman's personality is all that the attributes we have talked about Really did come later.
Speaker 1: in the earliest days Superman was quote rough and aggressive.
Speaker 1: He often used excessive force and terror against criminals and on occasions Yeah, he was just.
Speaker 0: it was like a you know, like a mean Dick Tracy kind of like you.
Speaker 1: look at the early concept designs And he's this kind of just jolly looking dude.
Speaker 0: Yeah, he just was really strong.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and no one.
Speaker 1: he was bulletproof and the comics code actually forced the change in his personality.
Speaker 1: hmm So you only had a couple years of mean killing Superman and then he turned into the boy the Blue Wonder Boy Scout.
Speaker 0: I mean you only had a little while of gun Batman.
Speaker 0: Yeah And it was just a detective.
Speaker 0: and then and then all the way in the future Batman's got a kryptonite gun But no regular yeah, then the the censors turned him into corny old Adam West Batman.
Speaker 0: Yeah, because the cod the Silver Age Batman is a lot like that.
Speaker 0: Adam West TV show.
Speaker 0: all corny, right?
Speaker 0: It's all this, you know wacky and whatever you see like those really silly like memes made with up like, you know Cutouts from a Batman comic.
Speaker 0: that's what it's from Silver Age Batman for sure.
Speaker 1: I appreciate this moment where uh Harley Quinn literally challenges Batman or father Superman to a fight and in response is just he laughs slightly and then he leaves.
Speaker 0: Mmm, and you know Silver Age Superman comics, right?
Speaker 0: We're sort of like equally silly.
Speaker 0: you ever see those ones where it's like You know, like what's it called?
Speaker 0: This where it's like, oh, you know, it comes it there's like all those comedic ones that come.
Speaker 0: I can't find any of them on the internet right now.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I Read a lot of those Because they're corny.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's why you just see them as memes on you know, the internet, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah here Oh, like, you know, here we go Superman.
Speaker 0: How can here we go Superman?
Speaker 0: it from July number 218 it cost 15 cents right and on the comic you've got a shocked Superman.
Speaker 0: You've got a woman who says who's pointing at a little superboy who's flying and the woman says how can you deny?
Speaker 0: I'm your wife Superman.
Speaker 0: You signed our marriage certificate and there's your super son.
Speaker 0: Why did you leave us see daddy me fly just like you?
Speaker 0: Featuring Superman's secret past right?
Speaker 0: It's like that's Silver Age biz right there.
Speaker 0: That is not.
Speaker 1: Well, what do you get into like crypto?
Speaker 0: All that stuff that is all Silver Age stuff that you know, that's what happens when you're an old superhero No matter what you are No matter what your story is.
Speaker 0: Any superhero that was around in those days went through those that corny storytelling trend of the Silver Age.
Speaker 0: It's like this dude's a god and you're threatening him with like, you know some daytime talk show Who's the who's the baby daddy shit?
Speaker 0: It's like what.
Speaker 0: but on another why does he even care?
Speaker 1: You can argue that that is a lot like like look at old Greek gods again.
Speaker 1: It's just a ridiculous talk show drama nonsense baby mama drama constantly Mm-hmm, and the gods care a lot about this for some reason Yep, so maybe Superman cared a lot about it in that era.
Speaker 1: I think we don't have to worry about the the poison pill of Trying to make a canonically consistent Superman because trying to make can it's not possible.
Speaker 1: trying to make cannons out of any Large thing is just an exercise in like nerd futility.
Speaker 0: So, yeah, yeah, you know I do like the it's you know Because of those core features of the story that are good You know to explore and it's like you could explore them endlessly.
Speaker 0: Right this you meant.
Speaker 0: it it's possible to keep Superman like around and relevant even to this day.
Speaker 0: But I you know, I think it's simply the company that owns it.
Speaker 0: Right not wanting to like, you know go down those roads because they're too, you know serious and heavy biz.
Speaker 0: To go down those roads is why?
Speaker 0: You know, you don't see you know, the like DC movies killing it the way the Marvel movies are killing it.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm You know cuz Marvel has always.
Speaker 0: you know, there are the godlike figures in Marvel are all in outer space pretty much You don't have to write and they're usually a threat.
Speaker 0: They're not usually your main hero.
Speaker 1: Your main heroes are always people in New York who just live there And for a lot of reasons, they kind of just keep the x-men off to the side.
Speaker 0: But even the x-men are just you know, they're mutants but they're they're still human they're now.
Speaker 1: they're not God.
Speaker 1: Cyclops could be taken out by a bullet if someone was careful Right.
Speaker 0: I mean almost every.
Speaker 0: if Superman came to the Marvel Universe It's like who.
Speaker 0: anyone who lives on earth is pretty much not gonna fuck with them, right?
Speaker 0: Is there any Marvel?
Speaker 0: I would are some but not any major not any major ones.
Speaker 0: You know, we're taking out any of the psychic characters Maybe but you know Thor level right is a Thor level character That's true.
Speaker 0: But you know what keeps Thor right from being Superman in the Marvel Universe is that you know There's other gods in Asgard right?
Speaker 0: It's like Odin's there.
Speaker 0: It's like.
Speaker 0: it's not like Thor is the number one dude, right Superman is.
Speaker 0: that is the top dog right in the DC Universe.
Speaker 0: There's.
Speaker 0: no it's not like there's some other.
Speaker 0: there are but there aren't.
Speaker 0: effectively there's not like name one Name someone who's more who's more important some decent only if you're someone who's not a DC Comics nerd name one.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's a better way to put it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but yeah name one name one that someone on the street knows who they are.
Speaker 1: I think the important thing to just take away from Superman is just that There's so much media that you don't need to think about like oh I like Superman or I don't like Superman or just Superman is a kind of story.
Speaker 1: It's almost like a modern folklore that is so pervasive in the end in our storytelling today that the echoes of Superman are in All this other media and the echoes of Superman in just how we talk about things.
Speaker 1: Like you said using the word kryptonite That is the most fascinating thing about Superman far more.
Speaker 1: So than most of the stories told about him specifically.
Speaker 0: Yeah, even somebody who's like, you know Never in their whole life watched or read or any Superman thing ever Right, even some kid right who's just just in elementary school will know what you mean if you say something something's kryptonite.
Speaker 0: Yeah So Everyone sees the S in that shape thing, you know It's might as well be a coke.
Speaker 1: there are exactly two cool S's and everyone in America has seen both of them.
Speaker 1: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott.
Speaker 1: special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and brand Ok for the logos.
Speaker 0: be sure to visit our website at front row.
Speaker 0: crew comm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 1: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 1: But unlike those other late shows it's actually recorded at night and the patreon patrons for this Episode of geek nights are Heidi McNichol Allen Joyce link eg dread Lily Tenebrae Chris Reimer Clinton Walton decks.
Speaker 1: Then just like a dude guy who shy AI 85 Rebecca Dunn review mad bull 34 cowards Ryan parents Sam Erickson Shervin von Horrell Taylor Braun under program law edo pours ab threat open seed, right?
Speaker 1: Fuck you, you hold the key to my heart and a bunch of people who do not want me to say their names.
Speaker 1: We missed the show on Monday because it was a holiday.
Speaker 1: We always skip holidays and we continue to skip holidays, but we're at our regular business.
Speaker 1: But for now, I leave you with.
Speaker 0: Okay, Nimbus only drinks the good shit.
Speaker 0: mr.
Speaker 0: Nimbus you making fun of me.
Speaker 0: Nimbus is an ice-cold dick killer.
Speaker 1: Is that mr.
Speaker 1: Nimbus?
Speaker 0: Nimbus, he's mr.
Speaker 0: Nimbus, I am mr.
Speaker 0: Get in worthy of Nimbus.
Speaker 1: Mr.
Speaker 0: Nimbus has land dwellers.
Speaker 0: Do not keep Nimbus waiting.
Speaker 0: I fucked Nimbus wouldn't need anything.
Speaker 1: does Nimbus need anything?
Speaker 0: dare Assassinate Nimbus.
Speaker 0: I am mr.
Speaker 0: Nimbus Nimbus.
Speaker 0: That's I got the shell shit.
Speaker 0: Okay, Nimbus son of a bitch Betray Nimbus he controls the police getting cold feet.
Speaker 1: No Please don't tell rich.
Speaker 0: He wouldn't understand.
Speaker 0: Yes, he would.
Speaker 1: Hey, I finished it.
Speaker 1: What's the prize?