Speaker 1: It's Wednesday, November 3rd, 2021.
Speaker 1: I'm rim.
Speaker 1: I'm Scott and this is geek nice.
Speaker 1: tonight We are talking about the manga jujutsu kaisen.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: So, uh in my continued exciting life of biking to and from work on city bikes as it's gotten colder so far There are no more city bikes than there were before like they run out at the same rate now that they did a month ago Despite the fact that it was 48 degrees when I didn't mean to work.
Speaker 0: Well 48 Fahrenheit.
Speaker 0: It's not that cool.
Speaker 1: You know, I mean it's cold for me, but I mean in the grand scheme It's not that I was a little chilly cuz I don't wear a coat Like I was just wearing my normal like work clothes.
Speaker 1: I think I gotta get a biking coat out at this point.
Speaker 0: if you look at Number historical city bike numbers.
Speaker 0: It's like they go down when it's cold, but they don't go down that much.
Speaker 1: Well, in fact, did we use this as the thing of the day to we just talk about it?
Speaker 1: I think we just talked about it.
Speaker 1: Anyway, there's a. there's a video that got into a lot of research and the conclusion of this research across multiple studies was that The weather in a place has zero impact on the rate of people commuting to work via bike Using bikes in summer winter different seasons or anything.
Speaker 1: the sole Correlation between people biking or not biking is if the place is more car friendly or more bike friendly full stop.
Speaker 1: So in like parts of London people bike everywhere even in the snow because there's bike lanes and then in place I mean, it's just no one bikes because Canada doesn't support bikes for shit.
Speaker 0: I mean, it's just it's just a matter of you know Attitude, right?
Speaker 0: It's like, you know, you look at you know people in Netherlands.
Speaker 0: It's like, you know, oh, it's raining.
Speaker 0: I'll put on a big piece of plastic and I'll go bike right.
Speaker 1: so that European umbrella I use the weird one that I imported that I like and I talk about a lot.
Speaker 1: get this it actually has.
Speaker 1: I never bought This because this is a product aimed at Europeans.
Speaker 1: It is a mount so you can stick it on the front of your bike and because it's so aerodynamic You can bike up to 20 miles an hour without it having a problem.
Speaker 0: And if you also have a necessary when you could just buy, you know, the cloak thingy.
Speaker 0: That depends this.
Speaker 1: I say I saw videos of it And if you're the kind of person who's biking around a city in Europe where you're biking real slow on a real slow bike Like the same kind of bike you'd have like a coffee cup holder on And you have fenders and all that stuff.
Speaker 1: It looks like it works really well.
Speaker 0: The brand.
Speaker 0: Oh, that's right.
Speaker 0: That's the brand.
Speaker 0: so if you're looking for if you want to bike in the rain and not get wet and you're not like Biking fast.
Speaker 0: Yes bike.
Speaker 1: Yeah, biking fast.
Speaker 1: Just embrace wetness at that point Right.
Speaker 0: the.
Speaker 0: the brand that I have heard good things about is clever hood.
Speaker 0: So I've seen them around and they look pretty cool.
Speaker 0: actually You know, I should.
Speaker 1: I should think I should actually maybe think about getting something cuz I now that now that there's really no reason To have an unlimited metro card anymore in New York.
Speaker 1: I just pay every time I ride the subway.
Speaker 1: You don't ride it that often.
Speaker 1: So maybe I'll just like double down on biking even more than I do now.
Speaker 0: Yeah, somebody I remember though that reminds me I can't find it's it's one of those things where it's like one tweet.
Speaker 0: it would be impossible to find again because Twitter search is so awful, right, but Somebody tweeted and they showed like an American children's school book.
Speaker 0: That was like, oh it's raining, you know Let's not go outside Right.
Speaker 1: Oh, it's you know, let's you know, but it's such an attitude That has bothered me my whole life that people will just like Avoid getting wet unless they have a good reason not to like.
Speaker 1: if you're wearing fancy clothes Yeah, like you want to avoid getting wet, but if I'm walking to work and it suddenly pours who cares?
Speaker 0: I'll just be wet like fine, but that but they.
Speaker 0: the.
Speaker 0: the children's book from you know The in Northern Europe was like Oh biking in the rain an adventure Like a different attitude.
Speaker 1: I just imagined the one from Eastern Europe is like goblins will eat you.
Speaker 1: So anyway, I Once again have a minor city bike adventure.
Speaker 1: So I got a city bike in the middle of the day to go pick up my new glasses Bike over get the glasses bike back and there happened to be one e-bike.
Speaker 1: So I took it because it cost like 80 cents to use.
Speaker 0: that thing was a bat was the battery did.
Speaker 1: nope Totally fine.
Speaker 1: It was so.
Speaker 1: if you use those e-bikes often enough in New York The thing is about a third of them just don't work and you have to put them right back in the dock because you can't Bike that thing it weighs.
Speaker 0: I've never even tried to take the e-bike I don't know.
Speaker 1: real they're real good when they work but about a third of them just don't work and you just have to Pay extra.
Speaker 1: yeah, it's like four cents a minute and the first ten minutes are free or something.
Speaker 1: It's like almost nothing.
Speaker 1: It's zero cents a minute if I take the regular one and use my leg Yep, but if I don't want to get sweaty and I'm trying to get to work, it's so cheap.
Speaker 0: It's cheaper than the subway and faster than the other way, you know Another way to not get sweaty is don't pedal so hard.
Speaker 1: Oh, no.
Speaker 1: No, it's never gonna happen.
Speaker 1: Just chill plus if I pedal slow enough to not work up a sweat.
Speaker 1: The seven train is faster than a city bike, but an e-bike or my real body in a hurry I'm always in her.
Speaker 1: I always Lee.
Speaker 1: I if I need to be at work in 15 minutes.
Speaker 1: I leave with 13 minutes.
Speaker 0: I'm just enjoying going on my bike.
Speaker 1: I all I buy.
Speaker 0: why would I be in a hurry when I could bike more?
Speaker 1: No, I'll just I'll be in a hurry.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so I get on this thing.
Speaker 1: it's working fine.
Speaker 1: I'm biking like to the optic like the optics place in Kips Bay and I'm using only the front brake because really you only need A front brake on a bike.
Speaker 1: It's the better brake.
Speaker 1: We've talked about this before people who don't know how to use bike brakes.
Speaker 1: When I was turning a corner onto like Second Avenue I used work.
Speaker 1: No, I used the rear brake because I was turning and I just wanted to slow down because there's a bunch of traffic and shit.
Speaker 1: the rear brake screeched.
Speaker 1: now That happens like even a nice bike will like screech if it's a little wet or something.
Speaker 1: It was so loud the cars around me all like stopped.
Speaker 1: suddenly Everyone on the street like stopped and turned to look.
Speaker 1: a cop like started looking around like what's going on.
Speaker 1: It was so loud that it stopped traffic and people on Second Avenue.
Speaker 1: All right, and I was like what the fuck and I'm like, I just like I yell like sorry This city bike sucks shit and everyone starts laughing.
Speaker 1: and then I bike further and just to test I try it again.
Speaker 1: It's even louder.
Speaker 1: Okay, it hurt my ears.
Speaker 1: my ears were literally ringing.
Speaker 1: So I parked it and I reported it broken and I was like.
Speaker 1: it is dangerously loud if you use the rear brake.
Speaker 1: I don't know how this even happened.
Speaker 1: That's my story.
Speaker 1: that's the most exciting thing that's happened to me since Tuesday when I realized the next morning the episode didn't actually post.
Speaker 1: No It's on patreon, but it's still not on the Ignites website until Scott fixes it.
Speaker 0: Well, I guess I had to do something like that, yep No rush because it's it's the patreon.
Speaker 1: people all got it and no one complained yet.
Speaker 1: So Great, but yeah, there's some news.
Speaker 1: I think the biggest news.
Speaker 1: there's a lot of news We could talk about.
Speaker 1: I'm not even gonna say anything more about that cowboy bebop live-action.
Speaker 1: Well, we'll see it and then we'll just review it at this point.
Speaker 1: but in comic world The workers of image comics announced on November 1st two days ago that they have unionized.
Speaker 1: That is a big goddamn deal.
Speaker 0: So does that?
Speaker 0: so all the different comic publishers?
Speaker 0: right have different ways that they manage the Creators of the comics the writers artists colors inkers.
Speaker 0: Yeah and such right With like, you know in terms of like you make one-off deals you do contracts you do They're permanent, you know exclusive employees And some of them do this in combination.
Speaker 1: There's the way labor organizes like practically and theoretically is really complex and a lot of people especially tech bros Don't really appreciate the complexity of this space
Speaker 0: And I sort of forget all the different ways the different comic companies do it and they all have histories of good and or bad.
Speaker 0: Yeah, what's going on there, right?
Speaker 0: And Some of them, you know wax and wane, right?
Speaker 0: you'll see some like a company being really popular with creators and then doing someone dirty and then becoming really unpopular with creators and like Creators, you know artists writers know to stay away from that company Cuz.
Speaker 1: then you get the companies like the Tokyo pop era and like the obvious exactly.
Speaker 0: I wanted to stay away from right but you cannot you can usually tell because you look at the company and you can see Over time right?
Speaker 0: It's like oh in the in this year to this year Look at all those books that company published from all these great creators.
Speaker 0: and then why do they publish now like nothing?
Speaker 0: It's because they've done someone, you know They did something dirty and everyone left and knew to stay away from even case in point in the video game world.
Speaker 1: We'll talk about this next Tuesday.
Speaker 1: show Blizzard, you know We talked about them a bunch all the sexual harassment and nonsense that happens there as happens in every triple-a studio.
Speaker 1: But not only did they fire a ton of people which was the right thing to do But all the people who didn't seem to be bad and we're just good game designers have also quit during all of this.
Speaker 1: now a Bunch of their games are delayed and like.
Speaker 1: it's not clear if they'll even be able to keep making good games at this point.
Speaker 0: We'll see.
Speaker 0: But anyway, so this image union, right?
Speaker 0: I'm not sure if it includes Everyone right because usually the writers of an image comic aren't gonna be an employee of image comics, right?
Speaker 0: But the editors at image comics might be
Speaker 1: yeah, and I haven't read every people
Speaker 0: working on printing and Marketing and also, you know a lot they do have a lot of employees that are permanent full-time, you know, or even part-time Employees of image comics directly, but most of the people who are writing and drawing the books.
Speaker 0: I don't believe are Employees.
Speaker 0: Oh, here's what I can know if they are part of the year's.
Speaker 1: what I can say now about what this union is?
Speaker 1: It is what is a larger union than normal.
Speaker 1: It is called the comic book workers United.
Speaker 1: But I'll actually read the statement they gave quote for years comics publishing have watched our professional efforts support creators and delight readers.
Speaker 1: Sadly, we have also watched the same labor be taken for granted at best and exploited at worse.
Speaker 1: Keeping our heads above water was the new normal before the pandemic and since it's on set We've been expected to take on even larger workloads with fewer resources.
Speaker 0: That's everybody.
Speaker 0: That's not just comic.
Speaker 1: That is literally.
Speaker 1: I mean I all laborers eyes it aside if any of you are a Product manager like literally like my level of seniority We're hiring like I'm hiring people to work next to me as a peer.
Speaker 1: We're hiring engineers.
Speaker 1: We're hiring fucking everything right now, and we can't fill these positions.
Speaker 0: There's definitely, you know the same amount of work to be done in businesses that haven't failed and less people doing that work.
Speaker 1: So, yeah, it's a thing Yeah everywhere and it also talks about how contract employees are particularly vulnerable and exploited in the comics industry Specifically extremely.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah, almost everyone in the comic industry is on some kind of contract deal.
Speaker 0: There's very few full-time employees situations only like, you know editors-in-chief and that sort of thing, you know.
Speaker 1: Yep, so I'll link to their official statement and a gizmodo article that goes into a lot of details But I say I encourage you to just read about this and understand exactly what this union is doing especially if you work in this industry because this is the time to Like work in solidarity with another group that is already Unionized to either make a bigger union or make a union structured.
Speaker 1: Similarly, there's like this is the moment if you work in this industry.
Speaker 0: Now the only thing about this particular case here of comic book industry in the United States Think might be an issue is that you look at these other unions we've been seeing right Yahtzee.
Speaker 0: It's like they're working on movies that have huge budgets and make a fortune.
Speaker 1: Comics don't really make that much money.
Speaker 0: right and fair, you know video game people, right?
Speaker 0: It's like there is you know blizzard or whatever right or any of these places there is.
Speaker 0: there are people at the top Right who are fucking loaded and this high, you know margins Somebody's ranking in the bank and the Union is just gonna you know Hopefully be able to take some of that money out from the top and distribute it down.
Speaker 1: but there are industries where there is not enough money and The entire industry disappears, I don't know if image comics can sustain not Exploiting the labor.
Speaker 0: Yep, while also having the same quantity and quality of work and Also not jacking up the price of comic books to ridiculous heights that almost no one would buy them though arguably the sort of a Catch-22.
Speaker 0: the price is like this product can only exist at an affordable price even forgetting inflation even without the Exploitation.
Speaker 1: Well, there's a few things.
Speaker 0: Well image comics just go like just go under like what's gonna happen?
Speaker 1: on one hand entertainment is Extremely cheap compared to the cost of creating entertainment Global.
Speaker 0: and is the problem with just comics?
Speaker 0: fundamentally and video games?
Speaker 0: you create movies Right, but but the difference is that if you create a video game, it creates an enormous amount of labor.
Speaker 0: It sells at a low price.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but it sell.
Speaker 0: if you you got a hundred years of selling this thing You sell so many copies.
Speaker 0: it sells forever It doesn't go away and you can also do gambling and other nonsense to bring in more money.
Speaker 0: with a comic book, you know to create even just a normal floppy 30 page color comic book is a Very large effort.
Speaker 0: it could take, you know, the artist all fucking months and people are willing to pay one a couple bucks for it.
Speaker 1: They read it in five minutes.
Speaker 1: They write away.
Speaker 0: They pay three dollars for it, right?
Speaker 0: As soon as it's a week old It's not worth the three bucks anymore.
Speaker 0: and it's like unless it was a seek some significant Incredible comic, you know, it's like, okay, maybe it'll sell again in trades digitally a little bit or
Speaker 1: like an option for a movie but even then that not a lot of money goes to the creators of Those comics when that happens
Speaker 0: and the quantity of them that's available is so high.
Speaker 0: So even really fucking good ones are just like, you know lost to time.
Speaker 0: basically, and even if one's a hit the market size the pie of Comic book readers in the United States who read, you know comic books that are made by people in English Originally, yeah is not that large to begin with.
Speaker 0: so even some comic book that gets a large portion of that pie for a week It's like, you know, this.
Speaker 0: was there even enough revenue to pay the creators alone for getting all the other people involved?
Speaker 0: You know a decent wage for the month.
Speaker 1: so yep, so like We should be feel like a cop like a video game should cost Hundreds of dollars if we actually took into account inflation and labor and everything else comics in the same way.
Speaker 1: So we're gonna be in a situation.
Speaker 0: just do the simple math, right?
Speaker 0: It's like you want someone to make 70k a year median income.
Speaker 0: Yeah divide that by 12.
Speaker 0: Let me get my calculator.
Speaker 0: Yeah All right.
Speaker 1: Well you do that.
Speaker 1: what I'll say is what connect?
Speaker 1: what's gonna?
Speaker 0: okay?
Speaker 0: So you need to make for the one person.
Speaker 0: you need to get about six thousand dollars, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, so a month.
Speaker 0: so you've got how many people working on the comic book?
Speaker 0: you at least have writer artist color or letter.
Speaker 0: That's for $18,000.
Speaker 0: right for just those four people We're not talking about you know, the people at the print shop the people right because they're working on multiple books.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know editor, I guess.
Speaker 0: so six people right?
Speaker 1: What about all the material costs printing?
Speaker 0: Yeah Exactly exactly Right, but so they're talking.
Speaker 0: Oh great now.
Speaker 1: So Amazon takes a cut.
Speaker 1: that doesn't help.
Speaker 0: yep, you need to sell tens of thousands of copies of your comic book and Give all of the revenue all of it to the creators to be able to make that.
Speaker 0: and now you still got the comic book Shops taking a cut.
Speaker 0: You've got the distributors taking a cut.
Speaker 0: You got the distributor giving out discounts.
Speaker 0: You've got the bosses at the comic company taking a cut, you know You might have licensing deals.
Speaker 0: like you know My Little Pony comic Transformers comic this licensing to fees to pay right for whatever the deal was Right.
Speaker 0: all this money's taken out of the three dollars.
Speaker 0: They're charging or whatever.
Speaker 0: but
Speaker 1: all of this combined me on this book is that if we truly want a labor movement that forces living wages for things a lot of things a lot of industries are literally going to go under and that is just Because those industries could not exist safely fairly or equitably under our current economic system.
Speaker 0: So and if you you know, and even if you start you manage to kick-start the cycle of higher wages higher prices, right?
Speaker 0: So, okay people are getting paid more.
Speaker 0: You know things cost more but hopefully the only things that cost more are things like comic books and not things like food.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if you can get wages up keep the food price normal and you know It's okay.
Speaker 0: if the prices of luxury goods go up because the higher wage is everyone can live.
Speaker 0: Well, because the necessities are a good price.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and then yeah luxury goods are expensive there, you know, they're luxury goods.
Speaker 1: Well case in part, we always talk to Australia as an example.
Speaker 1: They have a very high minimum wage.
Speaker 1: Everything's really expensive except food unless that food is imported.
Speaker 1: so people have a pretty high average quality of life and Also, they can still afford things but they can't afford like Imported luxury IP goods like a my little pony backpack will cost them like a hundred bucks.
Speaker 1: So they can't buy as much crap like that, but food costs about what it costs here just in Australian dollars.
Speaker 1: So it ends up being much better for the average person, right?
Speaker 0: But I think that's the situation in which you know, you have to get even if you get to that situation.
Speaker 0: Right, you know, there isn't an Australian comic books.
Speaker 0: There are Australian comic creators for sure Yeah, but there isn't an Australian comics publishing industry.
Speaker 0: That's big but like a machine the way the Japanese or French.
Speaker 1: if the Japanese European and American comics industries contracted massively due to a labor movement that would open up the global stage for More global comic production with less competition from these heavily subsidized by human misery companies.
Speaker 0: There I think it just makes.
Speaker 0: I think it just makes life better for the people who are making purely digital comics because all You you've so many you only have the craters to make money, right?
Speaker 0: You don't have to worry about all those other people there, you know, yeah
Speaker 1: but in the short term Irrespective of the like broader meta consequences of organizing like that you as a worker should absolutely organize because whatever happens later Has to start with us Actually putting pressure on these companies and putting pressure on our broken capitalist system.
Speaker 0: Yeah, even if you destroy if you know, it's like if you're at a job where you're being exploited.
Speaker 0: Right, your choices are continued to be exploited.
Speaker 0: make a union and maybe you can not be exploited and keep your job Which would be I guess the best situation.
Speaker 0: Yeah, or You start the union and you destroy your company.
Speaker 0: It's like well at that point.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right Being exploited at this point go get a non exploit II job someplace else I guess.
Speaker 0: But you know, it's like some people could see that as worse than being exploited because now you have nothing.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but
Speaker 0: that worse right
Speaker 1: also means that if like this is what leads up to critical moments in like labor policies large enough strikes force government or private equity action That's the whole point of direct action like a general strike is the Surest way to force a government to make drastic changes, even if the people in that government do not want to make those changes.
Speaker 1: Yeah But it's very hard to get a general strike because if not everyone is on board if the strike is not big enough the people Who scab come out on top in the end or they replace the people who are trying to fight for better wages.
Speaker 1: Wages actually drop even lower more workers are exploited more and the individuals who tried to organize are just left out of the economy forever.
Speaker 0: I mean you also might just end up causing yourself a lot of pain and misery for nothing.
Speaker 0: Right, if you look in New York strikes don't work.
Speaker 0: The cabbies are on a hunger strike down there to try to get the medallion loans Fits up right.
Speaker 1: normal people who are still down there not eating because the government doesn't care and people who?
Speaker 1: Use cars a lot also don't care because they all just use uber or something.
Speaker 1: Nor they even know that this is happening because they don't read the news or like talk to people.
Speaker 0: So Anyway, and some other like if I don't understand like, you know, how cold is the mayor right?
Speaker 0: if I was mayor?
Speaker 0: I'd be like, please don't die.
Speaker 0: Let's I'm gonna fix this right now.
Speaker 0: Yeah Well, New York mayors do not have a history of - I would have I would have fixed it long before they got the head Number.
Speaker 1: step one ban uber in New York City full stop.
Speaker 1: number two In New York City full stop.
Speaker 0: Step three cancel all medallion debt period just like student loan debt.
Speaker 1: fully nationalize the taxis and make them part of the NTA Mmm, something like that.
Speaker 1: Anyway, it's calm.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's communism here on gig nights tonight.
Speaker 1: But one other little news.
Speaker 1: a Gretsuko did get picked up.
Speaker 1: They have announced that there is a fourth season coming.
Speaker 0: I only ever watched season one.
Speaker 0: I don't know what's even going on that they could.
Speaker 1: so what I will say is the show Definitely got better and better and better as it went on.
Speaker 1: season two was far superior to season one.
Speaker 1: season three Okay, it goes more serious it the issues that it kind like in season one.
Speaker 1: It really like danced around these babies first like workplace and sexism issues.
Speaker 1: season two was like nope Look that look at that guy right there.
Speaker 1: That's a problem.
Speaker 1: Season three like she's got a stalker and like shit goes down Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: The show is getting more and more real as it goes on and it's not the best show.
Speaker 1: Like it's not.
Speaker 1: I'm not like heavily looking forward to this.
Speaker 1: But if season four were out right now I would probably watch an episode tonight because I've run out of all the shows I'm watching right now Speaking of shows that if you know that I might watch again and that you should watch A revolutionary girl Utena shoujo kakame Utena is now
Speaker 0: on
Speaker 1: crunchyroll
Speaker 0: Alright, so I mean this show hasn't really been hard to watch.
Speaker 1: It was on YouTube legally.
Speaker 0: It was on yeah, like it was on YouTube legally for quite a period of time.
Speaker 1: I've got three different DVD box sets of this fucking show.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but if for some reason you still haven't seen it or you want to watch it again It's gone crunchyroll as of today.
Speaker 0: supposedly I didn't actually go check But they say it is.
Speaker 1: and before you ask no We are not continuing the Utena analysis show even though it is one super fun to do and two Super popular.
Speaker 1: the problem is I have been threatened with lawsuits and had problems So many times that we're basically never gonna make anime content on YouTube ever again.
Speaker 0: Let's just make some you know, some non YouTube Right.
Speaker 0: Well, we'll get video.
Speaker 1: It's not even worth the effort.
Speaker 0: Maybe I'll I could set it up.
Speaker 0: We'll see.
Speaker 1: you can set it up.
Speaker 1: You could do it.
Speaker 1: I've seen that people have been getting anime takedowns on Twitch and other platforms, too.
Speaker 0: I'm talking about like put videos mp4s in an s3 bucket, right and then use up, you know?
Speaker 1: Oh, you want to continue our anime reviews.
Speaker 0: bootleg style right an HTML 5 video tag, right embed it in the web page.
Speaker 1: Try to get a partnership where we sponsor the blab and the blab hosts it for us.
Speaker 0: Just get a CDN You know or we could put them on.
Speaker 0: Like what if you put it on?
Speaker 0: one of those people are using the the porn sites to host things.
Speaker 1: The other thing we could do is if we do it that way we could also get it on YouTube Via burner accounts and as they get sued, we just put up more burner accounts.
Speaker 0: Maybe that's what we should do like make a you know Go there's a guy teaching like calculus on one of the porn sites.
Speaker 1: I think yeah, we could make it it all.
Speaker 1: Straight-up only fans kind of thing where we'll do the Utena show for you If you're like in there.
Speaker 1: the other way we could do it, you know, it doesn't get copyright only fans and you pay The other place.
Speaker 0: we could actually do this if we made them unlisted but then put them to patreon only would yeah But unless it still gets flagged.
Speaker 1: I had unlisted videos flagged and give me strikes.
Speaker 1: Okay Another way to go would be to host them Directly like we did but hide them and the only place that link exists is via Patreon and patreon actually has some deals with some streaming platforms that don't seem to have any sort of.
Speaker 0: We can make it.
Speaker 0: we can put that.
Speaker 0: you can put them in like free patreon post that anyone could see.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you click this link and it goes just goes to a video file on a CDN.
Speaker 0: Well, I'll load it and watch it in VLC.
Speaker 1: yep, because I have a lot more legal avenues to protect us.
Speaker 1: if patreon gets a DMCA then if like YouTube does because YouTube I pay all patreon has is a link.
Speaker 0: They don't have the video that the DMCA would have to go to.
Speaker 0: who's hosting the video?
Speaker 1: It should be like Amazon Web Service nine proxies If there's no way something like that would get to the point in the court where the lawyer is literally like.
Speaker 1: so this bootleg video That was linked to from a site that you control but you claim you have nothing to do with Clearly shows two individuals who look exactly like you Know.
Speaker 0: we would say let's watch the video.
Speaker 0: Is this look like a bootleg of the anime utenna?
Speaker 0: The problem is reviewing at Cisco and Ebert style.
Speaker 0: What is not fair use about this?
Speaker 1: So the problem is because of the way fair use is.
Speaker 1: even if you have absolutely Sacrosanct fair use the courts often will just rule against you.
Speaker 1: Anyway, and you have no fucking recourse the courts.
Speaker 0: That's alright We'll get.
Speaker 0: we'll get causes an affirmative defense We'll get a lawyer who's had a fair use case victories before and you know, yeah anyway things Of the day.
Speaker 1: so check this out.
Speaker 1: I found this YouTube channel and it's just this dude Steve Wallace and what he seems to do is Try to camp in Places.
Speaker 1: you're not allowed to camp in novel ways.
Speaker 1: so like find a rich suburb just camp like in the street like in a u-haul in that suburb and Goes through all the techniques to like not die survive not get caught by the cops Not have a weird neighbor like come out with a gun and bother you.
Speaker 1: He does things like camp inside of a culvert Camp behind a police station and not get noticed by the cops.
Speaker 1: camp on the side of the freeway.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna link to one that was pretty fun.
Speaker 1: It's a little long.
Speaker 1: It's like a half hour u-haul stealth camping in a 30 negative 35 degree weather day in a u-haul.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I watched part of it and I got worried when he was using a full of fuel burning heat.
Speaker 1: He covers that right away.
Speaker 0: He's like I got a carbon monoxide detector and I got a vent open and I'm like that's still probably not great But I guess you didn't die.
Speaker 1: He's also got a low oxygen shut off and a couple other things going on.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: That's true.
Speaker 1: It's just a real fun kind of thing.
Speaker 1: It's it's very adjacent to the urban exploration stuff.
Speaker 1: I like to do and This kind of thing looks real fun.
Speaker 1: I would love to see some people like do this at nerd Conventions with the caveat that you've got to have a way to shower or I do not condone you doing this.
Speaker 0: So there's a my thing of the day.
Speaker 0: there's a thing that happens very often in this world where a book will have a very You know books in particular that just so many of them Will have you know such a small amount of interest and a small print run.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and never be printed again.
Speaker 0: but that book might be actually quite significant or important perhaps to a niche or even a larger group of people and If the book has never been scanned and put on the internet or is not like in enough libraries.
Speaker 0: it could be a very inaccessible book right.
Speaker 0: so such that people know it exists and You know new people come around and are born into the world who are interested in the topic of that book and just can't get It right.
Speaker 0: It's like cannot be gotten And but they know about the book and it's very frustrating.
Speaker 0: So this is one of those situations.
Speaker 0: There is a book called cartoon modern and it's basically a book all about basically mid 20th century, you know cartoon art.
Speaker 1: Oh my god.
Speaker 1: I love this UPA kind of style, right?
Speaker 1: Often in the style.
Speaker 0: if you don't know what UPA style means Just click on my thing of the day and as soon as you see the images you'll be like, oh that aesthetic.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like the best fucking aesthetic ever that one, right?
Speaker 1: You know, oh just type you and just type UPA style into Google Images and a Cornucopia will open for you.
Speaker 0: Yep, pretty much.
Speaker 0: You'll know exactly, you know, what's being talked about here.
Speaker 0: So This is basically like the ultimate like, you know, sort of Holy Grail ask book about UPA style animation And the creator of that book Said on the internet, right?
Speaker 0: Man it's a shame that book isn't out there.
Speaker 0: I wish someone would just scan it and put it online.
Speaker 0: So if you go to this thing of the day this article written about the book they just scan that fucker in as best they could and you could just click and download a 319 megabyte PDF and get the damn book good as as it should be.
Speaker 0: so Get this book before I Mean, I got the PDF.
Speaker 0: you can always get it from me, but you can still download it from this link.
Speaker 1: I downloaded this within three seconds of Scott posting this link to me.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you can get the CBZ also.
Speaker 0: So also read the art.
Speaker 0: read the article that goes into great detail about.
Speaker 0: you know, what the deal is.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, I'm gonna be reading the articles there.
Speaker 1: But after I look at all those beautiful image, I it's hard to express how much I love that style of animation in particular.
Speaker 0: That's the style.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 1: Yeah In the meta moment the geek night's book club book tale again G I've resumed reading it because it only took me like a half hour to read it the first volume of this manga we're gonna talk about.
Speaker 1: and Much as Scott mentioned last time the geek nights newsletter has a micro site.
Speaker 1: You can like go subscribe to it.
Speaker 1: It's on our website.
Speaker 1: We're working on our website redesign.
Speaker 1: We have someone we found someone to work with us who we are paying to make our website better.
Speaker 1: Our last packs panel is on our website.
Speaker 1: Atari game design from paxis online 2021 At least I not likely is like a 0.1% chance.
Speaker 1: Scott will be there too.
Speaker 1: I will be at packs unplugged on Friday between 1 p.m.
Speaker 1: And 2 p.m.
Speaker 1: Doing a panel which is a Updated rewrite of a panel.
Speaker 1: We did a draft version of years ago at magfest called rare game mechanics But I'm rewriting it based on like how that went the first time and focusing entirely on tabletop.
Speaker 1: I'm literally gonna roll into the con do this panel and Immediately go back home.
Speaker 1: It's up to you if you want to go to the con But I will tell you right now You do not need to go to packs unplugged to see this panel because of course, I'm gonna bring all the fucking equipment.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna record it.
Speaker 1: It's gonna be on YouTube that weekend like by Sunday.
Speaker 0: Yeah, all right, so yeah, I guess that that's what you want to do.
Speaker 0: go ahead.
Speaker 1: it's like it's like an hour.
Speaker 1: It's just not a long drive.
Speaker 1: I'll just drive there do it and drive back.
Speaker 1: Otherwise, it's pretty much all we got.
Speaker 1: let's get ready to this main bit cuz I'm already getting a little hungry here.
Speaker 1: So, uh, this is this.
Speaker 1: apparently this manga and anime are popular.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so what I did is I went and I was like, you know, hey Let's do an episode on something that you know.
Speaker 0: Usually it's like something that I was into and then I tell rim to watch or read it or vice versa, right?
Speaker 0: I'm like, let's go find.
Speaker 0: You know the popular thing these days that neither of us care about and we'll probably never read or watch otherwise.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and go go check it out and see what the deal is With judge anime by its cover.
Speaker 1: to ignore anything that doesn't isn't obviously good for you because the internet will tell you later.
Speaker 1: So occasionally we have to make sure that we haven't missed something that like we're just everyone's talking about and we're ignoring.
Speaker 0: So I went to Amazon and I clicked on the.
Speaker 0: they have a page bestsellers in manga comics graphic novels And I guess right now jiu-jitsu cousin only has one entry in the top.
Speaker 0: Oh, no has two entries in the top 20 number nine and number 17 But at the time that I checked it had several like four or five volumes were up there in the top 20.
Speaker 1: Oh and as of October 2021 as of last month jiu-jitsu kaisen.
Speaker 1: the manga has over five fifty five million copies in circulation and The prequel to it jiu-jitsu kaisen zero.
Speaker 1: Combined with the the regular run make it one of the best-selling manga of all time.
Speaker 0: Right, so I don't know if it's at the my hero academia one piece level.
Speaker 0: I don't know if it's it my.
Speaker 1: I think I have the list.
Speaker 1: I'm looking it up right now.
Speaker 0: I think it's a little bit behind chainsaw man a little bit but not much, you know It's basically one of the big shonen mangas these days, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah been around for a while.
Speaker 0: Actually.
Speaker 1: It's not that new It's not in the top 20, but it's in the top 50.
Speaker 1: Oh, you know what?
Speaker 1: You know what?
Speaker 1: The next most popular manga is Initial D.
Speaker 0: No Okay, it's a. it's above Ranma 1/2 and below initial D, but you're looking at like an all-time list.
Speaker 0: Yeah, this is an all-time list list.
Speaker 0: I'm talking about like the now list.
Speaker 0: Yep Regardless jiu-jitsu kaisen I all I knew was that yes I recognize that name.
Speaker 0: that is the name of a shonen anime manga that I have never watched or read and know nothing about other than that, it's a popular shonen and I said, well, it seems to be really popular.
Speaker 0: It's been around for a while.
Speaker 0: It's not super new but not super old and I could just get the first volume digitally and read it.
Speaker 0: and Why not it?
Speaker 0: what shouldn't take long a shonen manga doesn't take long to read it all and then we could do an episode on it.
Speaker 0: So that's what we did.
Speaker 0: We read the first volume of jiu-jitsu kaisen and I can tell you that it is indeed a shonen manga.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's uh the end.
Speaker 1: it is so shonen manga that I could you could almost like predict exactly like when they go to meet the the principal of the magic school Who's gonna like determine if the guy gets to go into the magic school?
Speaker 1: as soon as I saw him I was like that's gonna be the guy who seems weird and flippant and not that powerful But actually is a big deal and there's gonna be like a big turnabout right there And they're gonna let him into the school.
Speaker 1: You can predict everything that's gonna happen Not the specific details of how fight unless this is a first shonen manga or that you've ever what read.
Speaker 0: there is an anime.
Speaker 0: I didn't watch that though.
Speaker 0: I assume it's just the same thing.
Speaker 1: Yep I assume so too but reading it all it made me want to do is stop reading it and go read more chainsaw man.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so I think that's the thing, you know If you're talking about recent shonen mangas that are popular that we personally have read
Speaker 1: Anything that makes this stand out to me at all
Speaker 0: Those are those are the only two that we have experience with that are new and popular at shonen's.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and chainsaw man has some uniqueness to it, right?
Speaker 0: You know, it's not just you know.
Speaker 1: executing on the formula chainsaw man leaves mysteries early on unresolved that I'm interested in.
Speaker 1: it also goes a lot harder moves a lot faster and every time I think it's gonna follow a shonen trope it Like jumps miles past that what would I would expect to be an entire arc?
Speaker 0: Well, it also just you know, just visually chainsaw man the aesthetic right this dude with two fucking chainsaws coming out.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I know his face, right?
Speaker 0: It's like, you know, you look at jiu-jitsu kaisen.
Speaker 0: It's very well drawn.
Speaker 0: The art is actually quite incredible.
Speaker 1: the faces jump around like there are really funny faces in the background often.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think probably the thing that sells it the most is the art, you know, it really reminds, you know.
Speaker 0: Especially the backgrounds, you know are so, you know, beautiful architecturally.
Speaker 0: the way like the backgrounds and death note are yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah But like nothing like is cool.
Speaker 0: It's like, okay, that's a anime monster.
Speaker 0: It's not particularly cool or memorable or awesome in it.
Speaker 0: It's just oh they're using some powers.
Speaker 1: Okay, their powers are strength and oh, look the protagonist is weirdly powerful and no one can explain why.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so just short plot summary of volume one.
Speaker 0: there's a character who's clearly the protagonist the good guy.
Speaker 0: He's super strong for no reason.
Speaker 0: He's in school.
Speaker 0: There's school shit going on, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, but it's not a Transported to another world scenario.
Speaker 0: It's the second thing where it's like.
Speaker 0: actually there's stuff going on in the real world But only some people see it and know about it.
Speaker 0: So even though we're not gonna physically transport you to a different world You're going to sort of enter this under society where this other stuff is happening.
Speaker 1: You you haka show did that to a degree?
Speaker 0: I'm a card cap to Sakura.
Speaker 0: There's this whole world.
Speaker 0: go Sailor Moon.
Speaker 0: Sailor Moon fucking war is whole world, right?
Speaker 0: Meanwhile, you know of earth people do an earth shit.
Speaker 0: But meanwhile, there's this galactic battle happening and the normal earth people don't know about it.
Speaker 0: Right, it's you know The sailors are in this other world where they have to battle while still being in the normal earth world.
Speaker 0: at the same time Same same old trope here There's a world of like these curses some excited demonic thing going on curse with a capital C.
Speaker 1: They're like Evangelion angel monster type things but most of them are really weak and there's a whole thing with them.
Speaker 0: That's not only some.
Speaker 0: people can see and detect them and fight them and they're bad.
Speaker 1: They're caused by Human, hope and human fear and traumatic events and all this generic stuff.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: They hang out near bad places, right?
Speaker 0: And there's this one mega demon.
Speaker 0: I guess this is this real similar.
Speaker 1: There's a Vecna.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's really similar to chainsaw man.
Speaker 0: Actually where they're collecting the pieces of the gun.
Speaker 1: That was soon.
Speaker 1: They were like he ate the finger and then they're like, oh, yeah, so there's a bunch more of these fingers.
Speaker 1: We got to collect them all.
Speaker 1: that's clearly the plot.
Speaker 0: Yeah, just like, you know, I guess at least there's less fingers than there are crystal shards and a new yasha But there's more than there are one pieces in one piece where there's only there's only one.
Speaker 1: there's one piece One piece.
Speaker 0: this is like I don't know what.
Speaker 0: how many pieces do they say there were?
Speaker 0: I have four hands.
Speaker 1: Yes four arms.
Speaker 0: So there's 20 fingers.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: So there's 20 fingers.
Speaker 1: This kid has to physically eat and their Vecna looking fingers.
Speaker 1: They're just like these mummified Horrible little jerkies.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they belong to some old evil dude.
Speaker 0: So he's gonna get all the fingers and then he's got to somehow contain the evil dude within himself by will Or become the evil dude.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the evil dude takes over his body.
Speaker 0: He's already super strong.
Speaker 0: So that would be kind of bad If that happened, I'm sure it will.
Speaker 1: But yeah, yada yada yada He ends up being inducted into the magic ninja warrior school.
Speaker 1: That is just a normal high school, but everyone there is doing the same kind of thing.
Speaker 1: He's doing.
Speaker 0: Yep, it's right now.
Speaker 0: How did?
Speaker 0: the question is?
Speaker 0: Why is this such a ridiculously popular shonen manga among the shonen mangas?
Speaker 0: And the only things I can say is either a something must happen in a future volume that shakes it up, right?
Speaker 0: I don't know if there is such a thing because I haven't read past volume 1 but nothing in volume 1 suggests that's coming But I I'm open to that possibility.
Speaker 0: Clearly there's a twist where they write they started out following the formula and they said this isn't working Right.
Speaker 0: Let's do something off the wall.
Speaker 0: And that's what made jiu-jitsu kaisen a big deal.
Speaker 0: and if that's the case and you know, it's the case Please tell me in which volume that occurs because if it's volume 2 I might read it Maybe but if it's 3 or higher no chance, I'm back.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's not happening Or it just follows the shonen formula and that's still a successful thing that you can do these days.
Speaker 1: the end Wikipedia now looking at like so far everything I've skimmed over giant long arcs does not imply that there is Anything different that's gonna happen from the kind of things we already read.
Speaker 1: It's you know, I describe it.
Speaker 1: Take the feel of Naruto And cross it with the feel of chainsaw man.
Speaker 1: set it in modern-day Japan and make everything less extreme.
Speaker 0: hmm, so I do want to say the the right the crater right gig a Akutami, which might be a pen name or mate might not be this creator.
Speaker 0: It says in the book here They published a few short works before starting jiu-jitsu kaisen which again and shown and jump in 2018.
Speaker 0: So this is this person's like first big real deal ongoing manga That they've ever made right.
Speaker 0: so for them to get such a big hit off the bat?
Speaker 0: basically Right.
Speaker 0: The only things they did before this were little short short deals.
Speaker 0: You know, it's like.
Speaker 0: well that's actually you know, it's seeing the art.
Speaker 0: I guess that that might you know be a contributing factor.
Speaker 0: But Yeah, I don't know I Guess if you really like the shonen formula.
Speaker 0: see I like the shonen formula, but only when there's an extra spice on it, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, you get Jojo's gives you an extra spice of style, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah fist of the North Star gives you an extra spice of exploding heads chainsaw man extra spice of chainsaws.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's got.
Speaker 1: it's got the music right.
Speaker 0: one punch man Started off with some special spice but lately it's been going, you know The only thing it has left really nowadays that they're sort of gotten away.
Speaker 0: I might stop reading it even even though that might sound horrifying Because they've really gotten away from the whole Saitama one punch man thing.
Speaker 0: it's not about all the other characters just doing shown in battle stuff and Those.
Speaker 0: the only thing that really has merit is the fact that all the characters are really well designed Interesting, you know fun characters right like poor you pretty prisoner and stuff, right?
Speaker 0: But I've seen enough of very pretty prisoner.
Speaker 0: is you know, he's not as funny.
Speaker 0: just showing him to me again And again, it doesn't stay funny.
Speaker 0: So I don't know how long one punch man can hold out.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but it's just.
Speaker 1: it's hard this.
Speaker 0: this doesn't even hold out past volume.
Speaker 1: what I do have a theory I've always thought about that.
Speaker 1: There's this ebb and flow of shonen where in general any random person who starts reading manga anywhere in the world If they've never encountered shown in before they often get into it like everyone gets into one Like it's a real.
Speaker 0: it is a really good formula and you know the deal.
Speaker 1: like you don't know what's coming.
Speaker 1: You just see it's like long power creep long arcs.
Speaker 1: you get into these characters.
Speaker 1: I see why people get pulled in.
Speaker 1: but then I thought then I see the second shown in manga the third one in the fourth One.
Speaker 1: I see they're all the same.
Speaker 1: I think every time a shonen manga comes out the crucial factor is How big is the previous big one still?
Speaker 1: and Will new people getting inducted into the world of shonen?
Speaker 1: Read the one that's already big or is there a lull and they read a different one and at my end then Whichever one is new that is the best or just there at the right time becomes the next big one.
Speaker 0: mmm, I mean To its credit while this is just you know, a standard shonen formula.
Speaker 0: It is well executed.
Speaker 0: It's like they are going quickly.
Speaker 0: It has there's nothing.
Speaker 0: there's nothing like bad about this.
Speaker 0: It's not like oh, there's this heart It's really poorly.
Speaker 1: Dialogues pretty good.
Speaker 1: The characters are all really different and really funny.
Speaker 1: The girl when the girl and the dumbass protagonist are both just petting the spirit dog instead of dealing with the crap.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like there is nothing bad about this shonen manga.
Speaker 0: It's just so.
Speaker 0: I've you know, because I'm old I've seen this a thousand times and there's nothing Special to recommend it Over any of the other options.
Speaker 1: in the same I'd almost say I wouldn't recommend reading it.
Speaker 1: if you if you've never had shown and you think you might like shonen Read either one piece or Naruto and see if you like that.
Speaker 1: and if you do But you want or you wanted something a little more hardcore or weird.
Speaker 0: I think if you want to me if you if you've never read a show them before you should stick to this the special ones That I mentioned right the ones that have something, you know extra going on, right?
Speaker 0: You don't want to read the boring everyday ones.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well I guess if you like chainsaw man and Naruto and just want more of that kind of stuff This might be like the best possible manga for you.
Speaker 0: Yeah I mean there.
Speaker 0: I guess there are people out there who just will eat up this formula no matter how many times it's Regurgitated and you could do worse than this one.
Speaker 1: This is one of the better ones by far.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there's a lot of garbage shonens out there that are poorly drawn.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: that the plot doesn't make sense like bleach is way worse than this thing.
Speaker 1: Oh my god
Speaker 0: Right, so
Speaker 1: and at least this doesn't do the thing that I'm still mad at you you hawkish you for because that show persisted longer than most shonen do on being more about the school and more fun and Then it turned into shonen and I almost didn't realize it at first.
Speaker 1: and I'm still mad at Naruto for giving up on Awesome ninja school hijinks and turning into a shonen fighting show.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: if Naruto had just been ninja school over the years and then ninja school at the college years Might have kept reading and watching that.
Speaker 0: but yeah Yeah, I do feel you know, it's only based on volume one.
Speaker 0: So I guess you can't really you know Get a get a good feel for the pacing based on that.
Speaker 0: because you have all.
Speaker 0: the introductory part does move pretty quick right, but it's not a sequence of Fights right even when they start fighting monsters.
Speaker 0: It doesn't feel like this is going to become.
Speaker 0: You know the the the timing of it is gonna be like oh every chapter They're have to fight a monster like a tournament kind of deal.
Speaker 0: It feels like it's gonna you know, follow that sort of back and forth pattern where you know Here's the part where every you know, they're talking and working on things and then like the first fight They really have is with it.
Speaker 1: Actually one of the most dangerous possible things and it kind of leads to that
Speaker 0: Right, so chainsaw man has that same structure right what you think is a more modern structure of okay Here's the downtime where all these characters talk and sort out their deal and whatever and then the thing happens And now they go into finally a nothing in the fighting chapters where there's an encounter.
Speaker 0: It's almost like an RPG.
Speaker 0: It's initial walking and talking in town.
Speaker 0: Did that the encounters?
Speaker 1: To an extreme degree initially is mostly talking in school stuff and then every several episodes They'll be the fight Not the race.
Speaker 1: Yeah, which always there's an episode that leads up to the race There's an episode that ends at the start of the race and then there's an episode that is the race.
Speaker 1: So it's three up three or two six episodes and out of the fun stuff and then three episodes of the race.
Speaker 0: right the opposite of that would be like Something like your pedal.
Speaker 0: your pedal is like, you know school school school and then race.
Speaker 0: There's a one race and that one race goes on for fucking ever.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it just doesn't.
Speaker 0: it's like just chapters And they break that race down.
Speaker 0: So it's like, you know, you would get like one chapter for like a whole months of school, right?
Speaker 0: And then you'll get one chapter for like just it's the start of the race.
Speaker 1: Well, it's like Ophery.
Speaker 1: that would literally be like here is every single pitch and every single at-bat for an entire Nine innings of baseball and then and then the same number of pages will be dedicated to like all of the school that happens between that.
Speaker 1: So, uh, yeah this was I'm gonna spend a while.
Speaker 1: It was almost kind of like when we started playing quake one deathmatch again recently and it's such a like bog standard Simplistic like no respawn invincibility like simple game.
Speaker 1: and yet it was almost refreshing how simple it was.
Speaker 1: I did have a feeling of how refreshing this was when I was reading it and it was just like yep.
Speaker 1: It's shown in ten pages still shown in.
Speaker 1: Oh, look, it just kept shown inning.
Speaker 1: It was oddly refreshing but not to the point that I want to read more of it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I guess it's like, you know, it's like a you know, it's like a just a normal old burger, right?
Speaker 0: It's like.
Speaker 0: well, I'm not like a fancy burger at the Baroness not Fancy one where I'm gonna recommend it and be like.
Speaker 0: you gotta eat this burger.
Speaker 0: It was something else but it wasn't a McDonald's burger that I would say poison don't know.
Speaker 0: It's like if you're hungry, this will satisfy but there's no particular reason to seek it out nor avoid it.
Speaker 1: It's like a Shake Shack burger.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like there.
Speaker 0: it is available tasty.
Speaker 0: Okay, you know If you got time and you really want to read a manga Just as a guy said it's a thing.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so I guess we'll end on really quick because with this show is a little shorter because there's not that much to say about This thing.
Speaker 1: the listener actually has a question that we could both try to answer really quickly.
Speaker 1: Okay, if we could pick a Western novel to Western being a very vague category to get an anime adaptation.
Speaker 1: What would we choose?
Speaker 0: Okay, so but I'm gonna change your Western.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna replace Western.
Speaker 0: lately.
Speaker 0: I've learned a cool thing.
Speaker 0: We're gonna replace the term Western.
Speaker 0: Yes Golf playing nation, I like golf playing nations a lot, right?
Speaker 0: So that does actually include Japan I guess but not that's fine.
Speaker 0: But yeah, but basically the golf the places on earth where golf is played are the wealthy places right, so and mostly, you know, Scotland UK you at right.
Speaker 0: so What most people would consider West yeah overlaps heavily with the places where golf is.
Speaker 1: I think a mine is actually really easy.
Speaker 1: I would pick any culture series book and my rationale is They're so weird that Animation is probably the only way to do it effectively.
Speaker 0: It's not a bad choice.
Speaker 1: Also.
Speaker 1: I just why would I watch the shit out of that?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I you know not having a lot of time to think about it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I went off the cuff.
Speaker 0: I'm sure I'm missing if I had more time to think about this.
Speaker 0: I could probably give a fucking terrific answer.
Speaker 0: I'll probably come up with a terrific answer very soon.
Speaker 1: Probably like 10 seconds after I hit stop stream, right?
Speaker 0: But obviously any Neal Stephenson book is gonna be on.
Speaker 1: Oh diamond age the anime, right?
Speaker 0: It's just.
Speaker 0: you could even just do it's like you.
Speaker 0: can you go wrong?
Speaker 0: Really?
Speaker 0: It's gonna work.
Speaker 1: snow crash would just do it like ghost in the shell.
Speaker 1: Just go all y'all.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's what I'm saying.
Speaker 0: Just gets to.
Speaker 0: you know, you get production IG.
Speaker 0: obviously no one else, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think I want diamond age over snow crash because diamond I do too.
Speaker 0: But I'm what I'm saying is that snow crash couldn't go wrong.
Speaker 1: No kind of like with the culture series.
Speaker 1: doesn't matter which one.
Speaker 1: just pick any of them.
Speaker 0: Just pick any one of them.
Speaker 1: It'll be fine even though even like, you know This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and brand Okay for the logos.
Speaker 0: be sure to visit our website at front row.
Speaker 0: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 1: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 0: But unlike those other late shows it's actually recorded at night
Speaker 1: and the patreon patrons from this episode of geek nights are Heidi McNichol Alan Joyce link eg dread lily tenebrae and a bunch of people who don't want me to say their names Chris Reimer Clinton Walton Dex Finn just like a dude guy show you high.
Speaker 1: 85.
Speaker 1: Rebecca Dunn.
Speaker 1: review mad bull.
Speaker 1: 34 cowards.
Speaker 1: Ryan Perrin Sam Erickson Shervin von Horrell Taylor Braun the Iron Front.
Speaker 1: you hold the key to my heart Mon a bunch of people who actually do not want me to say the names of their page.
Speaker 1: You're at accounts on this show at the end.
Speaker 1: at this time We have used enough words there to where you cannot possibly make that your name on patreon.
Speaker 1: It's getting colder.
Speaker 1: I'll see how long I can keep biking to work.
Speaker 1: Hopefully I'll continue to have city bike anecdotes for you for a while to come but for now I leave you With.
Speaker 0: oh, this is bad.
Speaker 0: This is really bad.
Speaker 1: You're working your slave and you steal just enough for a sweet lick of that shiny brass ring.
Speaker 1: Don't I get a lick doesn't kill.
Speaker 1: get a lick.