Speaker 0: It's Wednesday, January 20th, 2021.
Speaker 0: I'm Rem.
Speaker 1: I'm Scott.
Speaker 0: And this is Geek Nights.
Speaker 0: Tonight we are talking about the Chainsaw Man.
Speaker 1: I don't think it's the Chainsaw Man.
Speaker 0: It's just Chainsaw Man.
Speaker 1: It's just Chainsaw Man.
Speaker 0: But it's a... But there is only one Chainsaw Man, as far as I can tell.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: So it is Definite Article Chainsaw Man.
Speaker 0: It's about the Chainsaw Man, not just a Chainsaw Man.
Speaker 1: The title of the book is just Chainsaw Man.
Speaker 0: But are we talking about the book or the character?
Speaker 1: The book.
Speaker 1: That's true.
Speaker 0: So there is real news, and we're not going to dwell on this because... Read a book, read the news.
Speaker 0: But you didn't notice.
Speaker 0: the actual inauguration happened.
Speaker 0: There wasn't some magic nonsense storm.
Speaker 0: Joe Biden is actually president.
Speaker 0: That happened.
Speaker 0: Now we can start to make changes.
Speaker 0: The thing I want to point out to you, my news is, if you didn't watch the inauguration, I'm not saying you had to, but go watch...
Speaker 1: It's kind of boring.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Go watch the speech that the poet gave Amanda Gorman during the inauguration.
Speaker 0: It is phenomenal.
Speaker 1: I would say two things.
Speaker 1: One is that we made it past four years of not good times.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: A lot of people did not.
Speaker 0: Do not roll into 2021 with the "I Survived 2020" t-shirt, because a lot of people you're going to encounter know people who didn't survive.
Speaker 1: Or maybe you know people who didn't survive.
Speaker 0: It's also going to kind of get worse before it gets better.
Speaker 0: Like COVID's not getting better.
Speaker 1: I can't find the tweet because Twitter search is garbage, but someone definitely tweeted in 2016, "People are going to die because of
Speaker 1: this."
Speaker 1: And they were right.
Speaker 1: Whoever that person was, they should be in charge.
Speaker 1: The other thing is, on the one hand... I'm going to put this in terms like a nerd can understand.
Speaker 1: On the one hand, it's like, yeah.
Speaker 1: The executor superstar destroyer crashed into the Death Star, and the Death Star blew up, and the emperor didn't actually die.
Speaker 1: Whatever.
Speaker 1: He's not in power anymore.
Speaker 1: But there's still a dozen other super star destroyers around the galaxy still.
Speaker 1: So on the one hand, the empire is still out there.
Speaker 1: But on the other hand, you can still sing yub nub right now.
Speaker 0: Yup, that's a point I've been trying to make on Twitter and other places.
Speaker 0: Like, yeah, we got a lot of work to do, but it is totally okay to celebrate this victory.
Speaker 1: You can sing a yub nub, but just don't forget that that was only one super star destroyer, and there was a lot more than that.
Speaker 1: I guess if you've only watched the movies, you wouldn't be nerdy enough to know that.
Speaker 1: There were so many of those.
Speaker 1: That was only one.
Speaker 1: So yeah.
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 0: So in some animation news, I got a little bit of a geek bite.
Speaker 0: I talked a while ago about Hilda, which is a phenomenal... I used that word too many times already today, but it is a fantastic top-tier A+ animated series that's on Netflix based on some graphic novels.
Speaker 0: Season two of it dropped, and we just finished it, me and Emily.
Speaker 0: And I'm not going to go too deep into a geek bite because I don't want to spoil things.
Speaker 0: You should just watch this.
Speaker 0: Everyone should watch it.
Speaker 0: I can't think of a single human.
Speaker 0: What's it even about?
Speaker 1: I know what it looks like.
Speaker 1: I've seen it.
Speaker 1: I just don't know what it's about.
Speaker 0: It's about a...
Speaker 1: You're only Hilda, right?
Speaker 0: So Hilda is a series.
Speaker 0: It's about a pseudo-Scandinavian, maybe Swedish, pleasant town called Trollberg.
Speaker 1: Is it sort of like Heidi of the Alps, only 2020?
Speaker 0: A little bit, but it's more like... So imagine a world where there's a lot of fantastical stuff just there, but it's totally normal to everyone.
Speaker 0: Like, why is it called Trollberg?
Speaker 0: Because there's fucking trolls outside the walls that turn to stone every day.
Speaker 0: But it's just like normal life.
Speaker 0: And Hilda goes off on adventures in this setting, and it's just sort of fun.
Speaker 0: Like, kid has adventures and deals with dark forces and usually comes out okay in the end.
Speaker 0: But with the twist that it's better than the average children's show that does this kind of thing, because the peril she gets into is a lot more perilous than you might expect.
Speaker 0: Like, it gets way more serious and dangerous than a lot of children's media tends to, even though that level of danger is what kids actually want, if you ask them and not their parents.
Speaker 0: So Hilda season two, what I'm going to say about it is that it's just as good as season one.
Speaker 0: Like, the show just continues to be utterly fantastic.
Speaker 0: But the last episode looked like it was going to just be like a good season finale and end, and I could think, "Well, now I'll just wait for season
Speaker 0: three.".
Speaker 0: Something happened I didn't expect.
Speaker 0: The last episode of season two fades out, and then it fades back in and shows you something and it shows you the terrible secret of space.
Speaker 0: It shows you the kind of thing that you'd see at the end of a VHS tape of an anime where you can't see the next season for a year.
Speaker 0: This is an Escaflode level cliffhanger.
Speaker 1: What was that anime?
Speaker 1: that was a very short one, only maybe it was an OAV.
Speaker 0: Oh, Combustible Campus Gardress?
Speaker 1: No, not that one.
Speaker 1: And it was just like these... I think I remember there were robots and they had alien hats of some kind or something.
Speaker 0: Alien 9.
Speaker 1: I don't know if it was Alien 9 either, but it might have been.
Speaker 1: But there was stuff in the... Basically, when the credits played at the end of the last episode, ridiculous stuff happened behind it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that was Alien 9.
Speaker 0: It was like, "Oh, all those characters died.
Speaker 0: Wait, what?
Speaker 0: What?".
Speaker 0: Yeah, it was Alien 9.
Speaker 0: That's what we were thinking of.
Speaker 1: Let me Google it.
Speaker 1: Yup, that was it for sure.
Speaker 0: Alien 9 weirdly is in my... It has a lot of brain space for me.
Speaker 0: for some reason still, even though I read one volume of the manga and it didn't make sense.
Speaker 1: Literally, what I just said is all that I know about it, other than recognizing it and knowing crazy stuff happens during the credits.
Speaker 1: That's all I got.
Speaker 0: So, yeah, the end of Season 2 of Hilda, which it'll be a while before there's a Season 3 because the comics have to catch up to where they can even make another season, is quite a cliffhanger and I still haven't quite processed it.
Speaker 0: So, watch Hilda.
Speaker 0: It is utterly amazing.
Speaker 0: But if you are not good with dealing with spoilers, watch all the way up to the second to last episode of Season 2 and then just wait.
Speaker 0: Because if you watched that last episode, it's a spoiler that I was shocked by.
Speaker 0: It's a good spoiler.
Speaker 0: It's a good... Whatever's gonna happen in Season 3 is gonna be like S-rank, I think, because of this.
Speaker 0: But now I really want to know what the deal is with that thing that I saw.
Speaker 1: It's a terrible secret of space.
Speaker 0: Yup.
Speaker 0: And Season 2 spent the entire time.
Speaker 0: Season 1 didn't seem like it was going anywhere other than Hilda's way more powerful than she should be.
Speaker 0: But Season 2 sort of has this thread of things aren't necessarily what they appear or maybe the government is bad.
Speaker 0: We should look into that, but...
Speaker 1: Oh, you don't say.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So, yeah.
Speaker 1: You don't say.
Speaker 0: Watch Hilda.
Speaker 0: I cannot stress this enough.
Speaker 0: This is one of those shows where I would universally recommend it to anyone, regardless of what else they might like.
Speaker 1: So, something else I'd recommend to anyone regardless of what else they might like.
Speaker 0: I do agree with that.
Speaker 1: But maybe not really, because there are some people for whom it wouldn't fly.
Speaker 0: People are at least over the age of 18 in America.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there is a webcomic named Ogloff.
Speaker 1: We've talked about it on the show before.
Speaker 1: It is excellent, and it is rated X-lent, for sure.
Speaker 1: And recently, they had a Kickstarter to kickstart printing the physical Volume 3 compilation of the Ogloff comics, which... The Ogloff website is actually somewhat painful to navigate, and they don't post their comics on other places because of the X rating parts, obviously, right?
Speaker 1: So, they'll sometimes post a comic that has extra pages, and you have to click a different link to go to see those.
Speaker 1: If you just click Next, Next, Next, you'll skip over different strips because of the way the website is.
Speaker 1: And it's hard to keep up with it.
Speaker 1: They do come out rather consistently, so if you don't stay on top of it, you'll miss some.
Speaker 0: I don't think I have ever failed to read an Ogloff within a day of it coming out for years.
Speaker 1: I thought that, too, but then I read these compilations, and there were several strips I'd never seen before in my life.
Speaker 1: And then, also, you hover over your mouse, and there's funny alt text on a lot of the strips as well.
Speaker 1: And those sometimes are funny.
Speaker 1: Not usually, but sometimes.
Speaker 0: What was the first webcomic to do that?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: That's a great question.
Speaker 0: Because I feel like even the early Penny arcades had the alt text.
Speaker 1: It is a misuse of alt text, which is meant for accessibility and reasons, but whatever.
Speaker 1: Not honestly, but kind of, you know.
Speaker 1: Anyway.
Speaker 1: But, yeah, they printed, they put this Kickstarter out, and they said, "You know what?
Speaker 1: I'll kick it at the level that gets me all three volumes, and then I can read through all of it again.
Speaker 1: Even though I've read most of it from the beginning, I'm sure there'll be parts I didn't remember, or maybe I was correct, strips I'd never seen.
Speaker 1: I somehow missed them.
Speaker 1: And I'll catch myself up, right?
Speaker 1: Make sure I don't miss anything.
Speaker 1: And then I'll just keep reading it like I do, and then get volume four one day to, you know, do the same thing.
Speaker 1: Catch up and fill in the
Speaker 1: blanks.".
Speaker 1: So, yeah, first of all, these printed volumes are a really great way to read Ogloff.
Speaker 1: Much better than the kind of eh website.
Speaker 1: However, the alt text are printed at, like, the side and the top of the page, right?
Speaker 1: And this sort of happened to me also with the Adventure Time comic, where they would put, like, a funny, tiny line of text, like, outside the panels, like, at the bottom of the page.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 0: I missed those at first.
Speaker 0: Like, I just didn't pay attention to them.
Speaker 1: As sort of like a commentary on the page, right?
Speaker 1: And while those often contained awesome content that I was happy to get, it's sort of like you're reading these panels, and then you stop to read this line of text, and it totally messes up the pacing, and sort of, like, hurts my head a little bit, right?
Speaker 1: Not, you know, like, it's hard to read words.
Speaker 1: But it's just sort of like, if I was reading only panels, I could, like, blitz through the whole thing, right?
Speaker 1: And just take them all in.
Speaker 1: But, like, it's like I'm in panel reading mode.
Speaker 1: Like, it's almost like having a car going 100 miles an hour, and then you hit the brakes and stop at a red light, and then you go to 100 miles an hour to read the next strip, and then you stop at a red light.
Speaker 0: I've always felt like, especially if it's a commentary thing, like, you should read the whole comic, and then whenever you read it again is when you look at that commentary.
Speaker 1: Maybe, but the thing is, all those alt text only make any sense in the context of you just read this comic, now read this alt text.
Speaker 0: No, I mean, you read the comic again, but that, like, the second time through is when you also stop and read all those bits.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 1: This is as opposed to, say, something that does it, I think, much better, which is, like, Watchmen, where you read the whole comic, and then there's some non-comic part that you read separately, right?
Speaker 0: I feel like we had to admonish a lot of people for not reading those, like, bits between the drawn parts of Watchmen.
Speaker 1: There are a lot of nerds who just don't read those at all, which is, I think, that's way bad.
Speaker 1: But it's like, in Watchmen, you're only hitting, you're going from 100 miles an hour to stop once, right?
Speaker 1: You get that feeling one time, and then you read the text, right?
Speaker 1: Here, it's like, you're reading two rows of panels, and then you're stopping, and it's sort of like, ow, ow, ow, over and over again.
Speaker 1: And I think maybe, you know, I might have been happier just not reading those alt texts, because, like I said, only some of them were actually kind of funny.
Speaker 1: The comics are all great, right?
Speaker 1: It's like, the comics are all, like, A+.
Speaker 1: But the alt texts are just sort of like, they weren't that necessary.
Speaker 1: I could have just read all the, you know, if I'd read it again, I would just skip all of them and read the panels only.
Speaker 0: Yeah, because one thing about Ogloff is they're not, like, particularly funny like they are on some comics.
Speaker 1: That's true, yeah.
Speaker 1: Anyway.
Speaker 1: But yeah, if you are, you know, talking about, like, web comics, right, and quality level, like, Ogloff is actually, you know, of the web comics I've read in my life, which is quite a few, I think it's pretty high ranking in terms of, right?
Speaker 0: It's current level of funniness compared to every other web comic I read.
Speaker 0: I think it's the funniest web comic I read right now.
Speaker 1: It might be, like, a top ten all-time web comic period, right?
Speaker 1: Oh, easily.
Speaker 1: But it's just sort of, like, under-represented in terms of, you know, its popularity.
Speaker 1: I don't know how popular it actually is, but in terms of its, you know, how much praise it gets, I think it's lessened, and because of its X-rated nature, it's like.
Speaker 1: they're not, like, you know, tweeting out and stuff, right?
Speaker 1: Even on their Patreon, it's like, yeah, they only put other stuff on Patreon.
Speaker 1: They don't put, you know, certain things on there, right?
Speaker 1: Even though Patreon has had a history of being full of porn.
Speaker 1: I guess they can start an OnlyFans.
Speaker 1: If there was an Ogloff OnlyFans, I would make an OnlyFans account.
Speaker 0: I think I might, too.
Speaker 0: It is a shame that it's hard to, like, make a space for adult content that isn't just gross, like, just generic content of any kind that happens to also include these sexual and mature themes.
Speaker 0: That is not necessarily pornographic.
Speaker 1: Yeah, Ogloff isn't regular old porn.
Speaker 1: It's not, like, Fritz the Cat kind of situation.
Speaker 1: It's not a anime porn game on Steam situation.
Speaker 0: It's just like there'll be a joke that's about D&D, but that joke may involve a penis, because penises are funny.
Speaker 1: It's funny comic that would be in the Playboy magazine without the rest of the Playboy magazine.
Speaker 1: It's like just tear that comics page out of the Playboy magazine and have it on its own situation.
Speaker 1: And also it's better than anything that's ever in a Playboy magazine.
Speaker 1: And yeah, that's what Ogloff's all about.
Speaker 1: So you missed the Kickstarter, but you can still buy the books on Topatico, and I'm sure there'll be a Kickstarter for Volume 4 someday.
Speaker 0: At some point I should get those books, but I've been reading it online for so long.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm pretty sure we've talked about Ogloff on the show before, but reminder, Ogloff exists.
Speaker 0: Pretty sure we straight up reviewed it at one point.
Speaker 1: We may have.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we've definitely done webcomic shows.
Speaker 1: So I'm sure we've talked about it on those.
Speaker 0: But anyway, things of the day.
Speaker 0: What do you got?
Speaker 1: So a long time ago I did a thing of the day where it was like an old Groucho Marx TV show, I think, and someone was on the show and they were trying to figure out who this person was or what had happened to them, and it was like, "Oh yeah, this person was like a child who was in Ford's Theatre when Lincoln was assassinated, and the person lived to be on
Speaker 1: television."
Speaker 1: To sort of show you how, and it gives you a new perspective on how time has passed.
Speaker 1: And I sort of saw that occurring again, because it was MLK Day, and people love on MLK Day to, correctly, I love it too, to post color photos of Martin Luther King to show you how fucking recent that was.
Speaker 1: It's like, yeah, if he hadn't been shot, he could still be alive, right?
Speaker 1: It's like Betty White is alive and she's older than he was, right?
Speaker 1: That sort of thing.
Speaker 1: And yet that same phenomena came again with a YouTube video I saw linked, and this YouTube video is from 1958.
Speaker 1: I guess '50s TV is like the perfect time for this sort of thing, because in the '50s there were still people alive from the 1800s, yet television existed, right?
Speaker 1: And if any of them appeared on television, that sort of bridges that sort of time gap, right, and messes with you.
Speaker 1: But yeah, here you have the author of Brave New World, Aldous Huxley, being interviewed by Mike Wallace for 28 minutes on CBS, right?
Speaker 1: And the things I want to say about this are A, Aldous Huxley was right about a lot of things and wrong about a lot of things.
Speaker 1: It's not some perfect genius person, either was Orwell, and I think the truth is some combination of the two, right?
Speaker 1: Number two, notice the way the interview is conducted.
Speaker 1: It's like Mike Wallace asks a question, Aldous Huxley gives an answer.
Speaker 1: Question, answer, no one's yelling over each other, right?
Speaker 1: The questions are actually like they're talking with some amount of depth.
Speaker 1: It's more like what you get in a podcast in 2020 than what you get on television.
Speaker 0: I gotta say, in general, 50s and 60s interviews are some of my favorite content compared to later interview styles.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and I think, you know, in the first set of questioning in this interview, he asks him about like, you know, hey, what's like hurting freedom in the United-- what are threats to freedom in the U.S.
Speaker 1: and the world that you believe exist?
Speaker 1: And I think he somewhat wrongly talks about overpopulation, right?
Speaker 1: But then, somewhat correctly, mostly correctly, talks about, you know, technological threats to freedom, which we have seen being very right.
Speaker 1: So this is worth 28 minutes of your time, I guess, right?
Speaker 0: I'm definitely going to watch this like right after we do the show.
Speaker 1: But also, I want to say, if anyone knows, right, because the YouTube algorithm has been actually quite bad at recommending more of these to me, even though I've watched all the ones I've confined, I think you sort of have to know they exist.
Speaker 0: Did you watch the Salvador Dali one?
Speaker 1: Yeah, I've seen Dali, yes.
Speaker 1: But yeah, if anyone knows any more like super old TV interview with person you think, you know, who you would think wouldn't have been on TV, right, you know, kind of thing, let me know.
Speaker 1: I can make more things for the day or just enjoy watching them.
Speaker 1: Maybe we should make a YouTube playlist, you know, something.
Speaker 1: I've been a fan of the YouTube playlist lately.
Speaker 0: I find that that helps me tune my own algorithm, and also it lets me like bucket types of content that I want to share with other people instead of just going to my own likes.
Speaker 1: Right, also archive.org, right, good venue for this sort of thing.
Speaker 1: The other thing I want to point out is that I did go through the effort to confirm that this was real and not some sort of deep faked thing.
Speaker 1: If it was a deep fake thing, god damn you did a great job of posting stuff all over the internet to make me believe it was not a deep fake thing.
Speaker 1: But the second thing I want to say is we should make a deep fake thing along these lines.
Speaker 1: If we can make it as good as this black and white, we don't even need color, we can make a black and white low res video, right, and voice act it.
Speaker 1: Or use some sort of AI on like samples of Mike Wallace's voice to get one half of it.
Speaker 1: And all we need is audio of someone else's voice, so we can find like a person who didn't live long enough for TV, but has a lot of radio, and get their voice, right, use AI to then type text and have it speak like them.
Speaker 0: You know the worst thing is though, hold on, we could get them to then promote gig nights from the 50s.
Speaker 1: We could do that, I was going to say, they'd be dead, we can't get them to do anything.
Speaker 0: Just drag that corpse out of the earth and get it to sell some products.
Speaker 1: But I'm saying, let's make deep fakes of old public domain people, right.
Speaker 0: I think our code of ethics would be we'd only ever make them say true and righteous things.
Speaker 1: Obviously it would be, who knows what we're going to make it say, but the point is, we would not be evil, right, we would put the hint there, right, we wouldn't actually try to deep fake it, we would be like, yeah, this is fake y'all.
Speaker 1: You know what the bigger danger to us is, you and me specifically, is-- It would be fake, it would be obviously fake in the way that War of the Worlds is fake, talking about old radio.
Speaker 0: Yeah, yeah.
Speaker 0: Now I'm thinking more that we've been podcasting longer than almost anyone has been podcasting.
Speaker 1: Oh, you want to deep fake Scott Rim?
Speaker 0: I think it would be, with the data set that exists, it would be pretty trivial to train one of those deep fake audio algorithms to get both of our voices perfectly.
Speaker 1: I think that is correct, anyone could do that with our Creative Commons licensed MP3s that are freely available on the internet.
Speaker 0: I welcome you to do this, just as long as you never make me or Scott say Nazi shit.
Speaker 1: Please do this, so that way-- Plausible deniability.
Speaker 1: If Rim decides he wants to bail, I can make a podcast and just type what he's saying, or vice versa.
Speaker 0: If Scott decides to bail, the problem, what if we both bailed and the AI just starts making geek nights forever, it's just like, I was biking to work today, were ya?
Speaker 0: I just shaved with my safety razor.
Speaker 1: Also, I could, for example, go to a-- you could go to a convention, I could just type what I was going to say, and then the deep fake me on the video screen can just do my part, I don't have to go there.
Speaker 1: Lots of good stuff, anyway.
Speaker 0: I just miss going to conventions.
Speaker 0: So anyway, my thing of the day, there is an old, there's an 80s manga.
Speaker 0: that was also an 80s anime that I doubt any of you have seen called Genga Nagaraboshigan.
Speaker 0: I've never heard of it.
Speaker 0: It's about dogs.
Speaker 0: It's about a bunch of dogs.
Speaker 1: Is it like What's Michael, which is about cats?
Speaker 0: Uh, so it's about a bunch of dogs who go off to fight this really powerful bear, but it's like-- It's nothing like What's Michael.
Speaker 0: But it's like a war movie, like a war story, but it's just dogs.
Speaker 1: Oh, like the penguin one, the penguin war one.
Speaker 0: Yeah, except they are just dogs.
Speaker 0: Like, there is no-- they're dogs dogging.
Speaker 1: Okay, okay, I think I may have.
Speaker 1: actually, now that you've described it, I may have seen some images of it.
Speaker 0: You've probably seen images of it, but you've probably never read it or seen even one second of the information.
Speaker 0: I never had either.
Speaker 0: So our friend Judith pointed me, because this is up Judith's alley, like dogs doing this kind of thing, like that's a-- You know, like there's weird manga that only I'm into.
Speaker 0: This is a Judith thing.
Speaker 0: And Judith pointed me at this YouTube video, and this YouTube video is a condensed version of the musical stage show that was put on very recently.
Speaker 0: that is an adaptation of this manga.
Speaker 1: Is it like cats only dogs?
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: And plus war?
Speaker 0: It is a bunch of hot guys dressed up as like basically dog furries doing this musical, and this video is ten minutes of like choice bits from it with subtitles.
Speaker 0: I approve.
Speaker 1: I approve strongly.
Speaker 0: This is fucking amazing.
Speaker 0: The look.
Speaker 1: That's right.
Speaker 0: You've got to see it to believe it, and the thing that I want to point out to you to pay attention to are, look at how hot these guys are, and two, look at the bear.
Speaker 0: The bear is basically a Fist of the North Star villain singing his song-- Is it Zangief?
Speaker 1: Street Fighter?
Speaker 0: No, he's a little more refined than Zangief.
Speaker 0: He's more like hot, massive guy.
Speaker 0: Gaston?
Speaker 0: Yeah, with big like bear paw hand glove things, and he just appears like above the stage singing this song about how fucking great it is to be a murderous bear, and how no one will ever kill him.
Speaker 1: So Gaston from 3D and the Beast.
Speaker 1: That was right the second time.
Speaker 0: I don't know if you need to watch the entire musical for real, but watch this video at least.
Speaker 0: And if you enjoy this video, it's probably worth your while to see the actual musical, but I don't know if it's worth your while to watch this 80s anime.
Speaker 1: I do wonder if in the post-pandemic United States, right, if there is a greater, you know, hunger for, you know, theater, concerts, those sorts of things, right?
Speaker 0: I think there will be.
Speaker 0: I feel like I'm gonna go kind of crazy once I can go outside again, like going to theaters.
Speaker 1: It's hard to do anything on Broadway because Broadway is owned by a very few small number of people who only let certain things on their stages, right?
Speaker 1: It's a very controlled platform, but, you know, I wonder if community theater instead of, you know, most community theaters, they just sort of put on all the old plays, right?
Speaker 1: You know, existing famous plays is what they put on, right?
Speaker 1: Would there be some sort of, you know, market, because it seems like in Japan, you see a lot of, "Oh yeah, we put on this, this is like a stage show for a fucking yoga pedal," right?
Speaker 1: It's like, you know, all kinds of stuff has like these, they put stuff on stage that normally wouldn't be.
Speaker 1: It's like, how come no one in the U.S.
Speaker 1: is like, and I don't even watch these things, right, but like, you know, what are the popular TV shows in the
Speaker 1: U.S.,
Speaker 1: right?
Speaker 1: Why isn't there like The Wire on stage, Sopranos on stage, Breaking Bad on stage, Game of Thrones on stage?
Speaker 0: Like you don't cover the whole show, you just do like this.
Speaker 1: You could just make like a, you know, two hour show, two and a half hour, you know, whatever, just, you know, take whatever popular fucking thing is on TV, you know.
Speaker 1: They tried Spider-Man, that didn't work.
Speaker 1: Avengers might work.
Speaker 0: It turned out that dark, all right.
Speaker 1: But that would be on Broadway, Disney owns Broadway theaters, right?
Speaker 0: I think part of it might be licensing issues.
Speaker 1: I feel like I worry that more- No, but I'm saying the people that make those TV shows should just do it themselves.
Speaker 1: Don't license it to some, you know, whatever, right?
Speaker 1: You know, make it, do it yourself, make it happen.
Speaker 0: I, my best guess is that they just don't think there'd be enough return for them.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: If I was a producer at a TV show, I would be like, all right, our TV show ended its run.
Speaker 1: Let's try to get it on stages in places just to make more money and see what happens.
Speaker 1: And if it worked to any extent, everyone else would do the same thing and that would start a whole thing.
Speaker 0: You know, like a cross media thing where like every year or two, you just got to make one thing to rekindle interest in your whole like IP back catalog of whatever that thing is.
Speaker 0: Like Adventure Time, they're just releasing this HBO thing every now and then.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: But go big.
Speaker 0: If there was an Adventure Time musical stage play, I would go see that.
Speaker 1: I'd see that shit.
Speaker 1: Opening night, let's go.
Speaker 1: I don't care how crappy that is.
Speaker 1: Let's see it from there.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: In the meta moment, I have not read any more Tale of Hanzo yet because I read- I'm going to read it real, I'm feeling a reading mood lately.
Speaker 0: Well, I'm starting to feel it too, partly because I can't go outside anymore.
Speaker 1: The only thing between me and that book is volume three of Ogloff.
Speaker 0: Well, I did pre-order Chainsaw Man, volume three, but that does not take long to read.
Speaker 1: Oh, I read the digital edition.
Speaker 1: I didn't read the paper one.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 0: I pre-ordered the digital version, meaning it'll just appear in my Comixology.
Speaker 1: Oh, okay.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So, yeah.
Speaker 0: Otherwise, you may recall a while ago, we appeared, quote, finger quotes, at MagWest for the first time because it was online and we did a panel that was a- So, we didn't have time to like write a new talk.
Speaker 0: So, we took that old like hour long play dirty to win and we tried to do it as condensed and like fast as possible.
Speaker 0: I almost think this version is better and that it's more usable and practical.
Speaker 0: if you just want to win because it's literally just do this, do this, do this, do this, trust us.
Speaker 0: So, but they're like, there's no chatter.
Speaker 0: We didn't do anecdotes.
Speaker 0: It was really hard to put this together because we are used to talking.
Speaker 0: Like we've spent so long doing panels that my brain, when I start talking to people, just says like there's this intrinsic timer of you've got 58 minutes and I just everything ends in exactly 58 minutes for me no matter what.
Speaker 0: It was really hard to make this panel happen, but we did it and now it's on our YouTube channel and you can just watch it.
Speaker 0: If you didn't see it live, add MagWest.
Speaker 1: I guess you should also mention MagFest as having like a huge drama.
Speaker 0: I was trying to not mention it because I don't want to get involved in nerd convention drama.
Speaker 1: Well, I think that's what I want to say, right?
Speaker 1: Is like.
Speaker 1: people are aware there's a huge MagFest drama and they might come looking to us since we have appeared at MagFest so many times.
Speaker 0: I've been, I've been added in threads about this on Twitter by three different people trying to get me to comment on it.
Speaker 0: Someone posted in our forum trying to get us to comment on it.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: So the thing is, is like, it's such a drama and I'm not like, even though we appear at MagFest, you know, have gone to it so many years in a row.
Speaker 1: Like I don't know these people.
Speaker 1: I don't know the staff.
Speaker 1: I don't.
Speaker 0: And it's like, you know, I know on the staff, I know, like I know the people that like I work with to set up our gig.
Speaker 1: The people in the person in the majors department and the person in the panels department.
Speaker 1: That's it.
Speaker 0: We are hired guns.
Speaker 0: We are brought in.
Speaker 1: And we have a friend, we have one friend who is on staff who hasn't told us anything.
Speaker 1: So it's like, there's a drama there.
Speaker 1: The drama is so deep and it's not some simple drama that I can just like make heads or tails of easily and be like, yes, no.
Speaker 1: It's like a complex twisted drama.
Speaker 1: And there's all these documents and stuff.
Speaker 1: And it's like, I don't have time for that.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: I can't figure this out.
Speaker 1: So I'm basically not touching that drama with a thousand foot pole.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: It's like, it's got nothing to do with me.
Speaker 1: It's got nothing to do with Geek Nights.
Speaker 1: We'll wait until that drama ends when the drama has ended, because it still hasn't ended.
Speaker 1: It's like ongoing continuous drama.
Speaker 1: When it ends, then we'll go and we'll see what the right thing to do is.
Speaker 1: Until then, I got nothing to do with it.
Speaker 1: Magfest isn't happening, so I don't have to decide whether to stop attending to continue attending.
Speaker 1: There's no Magfest anything happening.
Speaker 1: So I'm just going to continue in the meantime, not going to the non-existent Magfest until such a time.
Speaker 1: If Magfest returns and the drama has been sorted out and we can figure out the drama is, you know, whatever the answer is to it, then we'll say something.
Speaker 1: Until then, don't come looking to us for answers on Magfest drama.
Speaker 1: Go to people who are way more involved in Magfest than we are.
Speaker 0: I will say that Google Drive, you refused to read.
Speaker 0: I did read everything in that thing.
Speaker 0: And I still have no fucking comment, no opinion.
Speaker 0: I could not make head or tails of it.
Speaker 1: I got nothing to say about that.
Speaker 1: No comment.
Speaker 0: The only convention drama I'll be involved in is when I am running a convention, and I haven't run a convention in a while.
Speaker 0: So, Chainsaw Man.
Speaker 1: So I heard about Chainsaw Man from the Twitters, obviously, other people, right?
Speaker 1: And it sounded like, you know, a Shonen manga with some ridiculousness, sort of like in the One Punch Man zone.
Speaker 1: It has a man in the title, right?
Speaker 0: It's in Shonen Jump, and you'd always see this picture that was like, "A dude with chainsaws coming out of
Speaker 0: him.".
Speaker 1: Right, a dude with a chainsaw coming out of his face.
Speaker 1: You're like, "That is the anime/manga style that I am all
Speaker 1: about.".
Speaker 1: A dude with a chainsaw coming out of his face called Chainsaw Man.
Speaker 1: That's amazing.
Speaker 1: I think that's all I need to know to know that this is A+.
Speaker 1: But, I read a summary, and the summary had my opinion lowered.
Speaker 1: Quite substantially, in fact.
Speaker 1: Because the summary I read talked quite a bit about how this main character, Chainsaw Man, like, his goal was to touch boobs.
Speaker 0: Yup, now judge anime by its cover, that is like, that is a red flag, 100 feet tall.
Speaker 1: That is a crimson flag at the top of the flagpole, seen halfway around the world.
Speaker 0: Like start singing the Soviet national anthem.
Speaker 1: I was like, "That makes me think Chainsaw Man is not gonna be good, actually.
Speaker 1: I should just enjoy the fact that there is a person with a chainsaw coming out of their
Speaker 1: face.".
Speaker 1: But then, you know, there was so much tweeting, I said, "Okay, I will read, Chainsaw Man is available for cheap in digital form, I will read it digitally, I will not waste bookshelf space on it, let's see what the deal
Speaker 1: is.".
Speaker 1: So, indeed, it was not lying.
Speaker 1: Chainsaw Man is a man who wants to touch boobs.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but somehow that is not the problem that I expected it to be.
Speaker 1: They dedicated way more ink to that plotline in the summary than there actually is in the story.
Speaker 1: Spoilers, I guess, he actually touches the boobs quite early on, and that stops mattering.
Speaker 1: Yup, and also- And it's not in the sort of, you know, perverted anime kind of way.
Speaker 0: It kind of is, but it's not intrinsically bad in the way that I would say it is fucking intrinsically bad when that comes up in most anime.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and actually the lesson that he learns almost immediately is like, yeah, just touching some random person's boobs who consensually lets you touch them.
Speaker 1: isn't that exciting, right?
Speaker 1: It's like touching boobs with someone that you're, you know, in love with and in to be with is what you're really after.
Speaker 0: So it got bugged me.
Speaker 0: It was like, "Alright, read Chainsaw Man.
Speaker 0: It's actually good.
Speaker 0: We'll do a show on
Speaker 0: it.".
Speaker 0: And I think what you told, because you told me more to try to sell me on it to actually get me to read it, because when neither one of us, if either one of us recommends something to the other one, like it never gets consumed unless there's like the right tickle.
Speaker 1: The right tickle was, "We're doing a Wednesday show on this.
Speaker 0: You better read
Speaker 0: it.".
Speaker 0: No, the tickle you gave me was- It's cheap and digitally available.
Speaker 0: You said something to the effect of, "Wait till you find out the deal with the Gun Man, like Gun Demon as opposed to Chainsaw
Speaker 0: Man.".
Speaker 1: That's right.
Speaker 0: And when I got to that point, I went from thinking this is good to thinking this is like legit good.
Speaker 0: Like that was a moment, once I learned the deal with the Gun Demon, I'm down for whatever the hell happens in the rest of this manga.
Speaker 1: But- Yeah.
Speaker 1: So the story is, plot summary, right?
Speaker 1: It's a world of humans, much like our world of humans in Japan, right?
Speaker 1: I guess, right?
Speaker 1: Because it's a manga.
Speaker 1: And there are demon/devils, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: And they are a lot like how, you know, sort of like a polytheistic culture will have like God of this, God of that, God of this.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: There's a demon of like a devil of like everything.
Speaker 1: There's a demon or devil for everything, right?
Speaker 1: Demon or devil of swimming pools, demon or devil of television, demon or devil of, you know, forks, whatever it is.
Speaker 1: And of course, it's a demon/devil of chainsaws.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: It's just one of the things.
Speaker 1: And I guess how powerful a devil is depends.
Speaker 1: It's a lot like RIM's Forgotten Realms, right?
Speaker 1: How many people believe in the God, the God gets stronger, right?
Speaker 0: So- I'm amazed that you remember that much about the theology of Forgotten Realms.
Speaker 1: You've gone on about it.
Speaker 1: How long for how many years?
Speaker 0: To be fair, that is in fact true.
Speaker 1: So, you know, if people, you know, something like television would be a very powerful demon indeed, right?
Speaker 1: But chainsaw, I mean, it's powerful because it's a fucking chainsaw.
Speaker 1: But how many, how much, how much do chainsaws take up the mindshare of human society?
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Not a very powerful large demon.
Speaker 0: when it comes- At the same time, if you encounter a chainsaw directly, you're probably afraid of it if you're not a master of chainsaws.
Speaker 1: Indeed you are.
Speaker 1: So, what happens is this poor, sad kid encounters the chainsaw demon and somehow merges with it, which is, I guess, sort of like the plot, right?
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: To become the chainsaw man.
Speaker 1: Fucking literal chainsaws just coming out of his arms in space.
Speaker 0: There's a pull cord in his chest.
Speaker 0: If he pulls it, he transforms into the chainsaw man in a bloody missile.
Speaker 0: Like, it's just horrific and amazing.
Speaker 1: And he's actually quite powerful and ends up, right, that there are these demon devil hunters that are sort of part of the police, right?
Speaker 1: And they go around stopping demons and devils, but they also have sort of demon devil people on their team to help them, right, fight demons and devils.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: And they sort of keep them under control, right?
Speaker 1: So he becomes sort of like, you know, a tool of the police, right?
Speaker 1: They sort of have him on a metaphorical leash, right, and use him to fight other demons and devils.
Speaker 1: And then you get into the, right, the sort of structure of the manga, right?
Speaker 1: It's like, oh, there's going to be a demon or devil causing trouble.
Speaker 1: The police, along with chainsaw men, go out to deal with it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the AD police go and can't deal with it, and then they call in the special government squad.
Speaker 1: Exactly.
Speaker 1: And they do this over and over again, and each one they encounter is a different one.
Speaker 1: that provides a different challenge to them.
Speaker 1: And it's not always just some combat challenge.
Speaker 1: It's, you know, really interesting kind of things happen with different kinds of devils doing weird shit in almost a Junji Ito-esque kind of way.
Speaker 0: That's a good way to put it.
Speaker 0: They are very non-human.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there's a lot of weird shit with each devil they got to deal with.
Speaker 1: And then along the way, character development happens for all of the characters, the main ones being, of course, chainsaw men and the other members of this police group.
Speaker 1: And then, of course, they're building up to the head boss, which is the gun devil, right?
Speaker 1: Because guns are such a thing for humans.
Speaker 1: The gun devil is just, like, ridiculously strong.
Speaker 0: It makes a big point.
Speaker 0: Like, there's a mass shooting in the US, the gun devil spawns and starts fucking murdering, like, everybody when it appears all over the world.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: So there's also the societal message about gun control, which is a big deal coming from Japan, where guns are heavily restricted versus the rest of the world.
Speaker 0: Now, normally, this is the kind of setup that would just be like a kind of boring shounen fighting show, or fighting manga, but as Scott pointed out, the fights aren't fights always.
Speaker 1: No, not at all.
Speaker 0: And they tend to be pretty quick, or if they're long, it's because, like, real plot stuff is happening.
Speaker 1: Yeah, some of the longer ones sort of get into an almost Death Note-y situation, like, "What did we do about this devil?
Speaker 1: What's he doing?
Speaker 1: Why did we go up the stairs and we're still on the
Speaker 1: floor?".
Speaker 0: Yeah, the bit in the hotel, that's what I was thinking of, where the little blobby guy goes by and they're like, "Well, killing that devil didn't do anything.
Speaker 0: Hmm.".
Speaker 1: Yeah, let's solve the riddle of this devil, right?
Speaker 1: So it's like, not every devil is the same kind of challenge.
Speaker 1: It's almost like a video game where it's like, well, this is a puzzle part, and now this is a combat part, and now this is a, you know, different kind of... Like, it's a different genre, almost, for each devil, of how they get, you know, how the conflict is shaped.
Speaker 1: So, the other thing is that artistically, right, you know, it's very good, you know, shounen manga artwork, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: But, whenever the Chainsaw Man fucking cuts the shit out of some devil, there's like an incredible Blade of the Immortal, like, two-page splash image, and these are just like, fucking incredible.
Speaker 1: Um, and it, you end up, I ended up staring at those for, like, a long-ass time, whenever they happen.
Speaker 1: Well, you turn the page, and you're just like, "Ooh, Chainsaw
Speaker 1: Man!".
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like, the Chainsaw Man just fucking, like, when he chainsaws, it's like, "Oh,
Speaker 1: baby!".
Speaker 1: Uh, um, so yeah, it's like, those are just really fantastic, and they have you wanting the Chainsaw Man to chainsaw somebody just to see another one, and the artist, I'm sure, is like, "Please, writer, don't, let's go longer without having the
Speaker 1: chance.".
Speaker 1: "We don't have to draw another one of those, it took me, like, a
Speaker 1: week.".
Speaker 0: The other thing about it, though, that I cannot stress enough, is that it's very funny, and it's funny in a lot of different ways.
Speaker 0: Like, it's not, like, a lot of comics and manga will have, like, very simple jokes, or, like, the same joke happens over, this is just funny in, like, surprising, random ways.
Speaker 0: But there's, like, the two things that stand out to me very early, that I laughed out loud, was in the very beginning, when you, when he fights, like, his first devil, and the way the devil talks to him is like a shitbag, 13-year-old internet edgelord.
Speaker 0: And the second part that made me laugh out loud, and made me decide that I love this comic, is specifically when the one cop who doesn't like him is, like, beating him up, like, "Yeah, you can't be one of us, like, just go run
Speaker 0: away.".
Speaker 0: And then you turn the page, and he just starts wailing on that guy's dick.
Speaker 0: He knees him in the nuts, and then starts kicking him in the nuts over and over and over again, and it's this whole bit about how the crotch, when I fight guys, I only aim for the crotch, and you get multiple pages of this.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's sort of, uh, it's sort of the same vein of humor as, like, One Punch Man, but more mature, definitely like an older audience a little bit, right?
Speaker 1: It may be kind of the same, you know, but it definitely, you know, I guess, eh, it just feels, it has a, I don't know, a different target, it's not exactly the same, there's something else about it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well, it's kind of like- It's less, I guess it's less cartoony, slapsticky, I don't know.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like, it's weird, it's a little slapsticky sometimes, but it's always in this, like, kind of brutal, violent way, but it always sends back on how, like, the main character is kind of a, like, dirtbag piece of shit, but you also kind of can't blame him for being that way, considering how he grew up, and you see him trying to improve himself bit by bit, but always from this starting point of being this kind of dirtbag piece of shit.
Speaker 1: He is, alright, but it's, like, he also is very introspective, and, like, you know, you'll see the main Chainsaw Man, like, thinking about, like, ah, you know, what, what should I do?
Speaker 1: Hmm, right?
Speaker 1: He's actually, like, thinking about his own life, and, like, what are the right and wrong things to do?
Speaker 0: Like, he has this really dumb goal, like, I want to touch a boob, like, cause, like, that's the kind of person he is, but the whole time he's thinking, like, oh, what does this mean?
Speaker 0: Why do I want this?
Speaker 0: And, I don't know, it's very interesting to read, like, his inner monologue in the context of the story, but then outwardly, his interaction with other characters will just be hilarious.
Speaker 0: I also like the main girl, the cop who, like, runs the whole division.
Speaker 0: There's something up with her.
Speaker 1: He's definitely, like, that mysterious, um, reminds me of in Eccentric Family, the, the girl.
Speaker 1: that's the bad one.
Speaker 0: Oh, Benten?
Speaker 1: Who's really, yes, reminds me of Benten.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Kind of character, a lot.
Speaker 0: Kind of mysterious, like, tells people what they need to know, but clearly is omitting something.
Speaker 1: Yeah, also in, in Patlabor, there's the, I forget her name, but there's the one that's used in a meme all the time, where, like, she shows up at the airport, and it's, like, business or pleasure, and she's, like, combat.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: That character in Patlabor is very similar to that one in Chainsaw Man, also.
Speaker 1: Same kind of character.
Speaker 0: So, yeah, as long as you're down for some, uh, ultra violence from a living chainsaw.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if you, like, if you're the kind of person who, you know, likes, takes those ridiculous ideas that are in manga and anime every so often, right?
Speaker 1: Guy who punches someone and they explode, you know, sniper who always hits someone in one shot, guy who punches, can beat anyone with one punch, you know, any of those sort of ridiculous ones, Chainsaw Man is the latest in that line.
Speaker 1: You know, a death note, right?
Speaker 1: There's always some ridiculous thing.
Speaker 1: This is the latest in that line of ridiculous premise shown in mangas, um, but, and it's a good one.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'm gonna, I'm gonna keep, I've read two volumes of the manga.
Speaker 0: You can just get it on, like, Amazon or Comixology or whatever.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I would recommend getting digital editions or if you really want paper editions.
Speaker 0: The first three chapters are just free to read on Viz, so you can actually read a good chunk of it.
Speaker 1: There you go.
Speaker 0: To decide if this is your bag or not.
Speaker 1: That sounds like a great idea.
Speaker 0: And you'll get well past the nut shot that I was talking about.
Speaker 1: Yep, and you will definitely see the Chainsaw Man chainsawing in those first three chapters, for sure.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know, but the, the, the, the proto-chainsaw demon or devil actually reminds- It's really cute, I want, you want, like, a toy.
Speaker 0: I do want a little lot of plushie of that, but also kind of reminds me of, uh, it's hard to say anything about this without spoiling it, The Thing in Decadence.
Speaker 0: The little pet in Decadence.
Speaker 0: Being very vague there for a reason, if you haven't seen Decadence, watch it.
Speaker 0: We reviewed it not too long ago.
Speaker 1: It's definitely, you know, got that great combination of cute but also powerful and evil.
Speaker 0: Yep, but is it really evil?
Speaker 0: Because it does the right thing.
Speaker 0: It's just a cute little guy.
Speaker 1: Kinda.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Sorta.
Speaker 1: I mean, it is a devil.
Speaker 1: I mean, that's probably going to be a, you know, a plot point at some point.
Speaker 0: I get the impression that devils, like, they're not necessarily bad.
Speaker 0: Like, there's definitely an undercurrent of they're not all necessarily bad and they're all- The gun devil is bad.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but they're driven by- I don't think there's any question about it, you know.
Speaker 1: Like,
Speaker 0: the, the girl devil that he meets that they kind of partner together, you see, like, you get his inner monologue, but you don't really get these other characters' inner monologue, but you can sort of infer from the way he is that if you look at those other characters, if you understand what they're trying to achieve and what they care about, even the weird things.
Speaker 0: they do seem to actually make a lot of sense and they're almost trying to do the right thing.
Speaker 0: They just have, like, weird views on morality because there's this undercurrent of the world is a late capitalist hellhole.
Speaker 0: Like, the only reason he's even in this, like, the main character even is the way he is, is because the mafia is going to murder him unless he kills devils for them because of late capitalism.
Speaker 1: That part also reminded me of, like, you know, Kaiji or whatever.
Speaker 0: Yeah, exactly.
Speaker 1: So it's sort of like, you know, I've mentioned so many different other mangas, right, and I guess it's sort of like a mixed salad, right, of these, like, components and characters that I've seen all before, but, like, such a wide variety of them all together, right, in a new formulation, right, that it feels completely fresh.
Speaker 1: You know, even though I can relate it, I'm relating it to all these other things, at no point when I was reading it did it feel like, "Ah, this is just X redone," right?
Speaker 1: It never felt, it felt like a completely new kind of deal except for the fact that it was a shounen manga with a ridiculous premise.
Speaker 0: Yep, and the last thing I'll say, because we can wrap this up, is it does not drag at all.
Speaker 0: It moves pretty quick.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 1: All the fights, like I said, are pretty much just like, "I'm gonna chainsaw you, chainsaw, chainsaw, chainsaw," something, and then the two-plate splash where he, you know, chainsaws something like that, and that's it, right?
Speaker 1: It's not like, you know, Naruto, "I'm gonna use my wah-wah-wah technique.
Speaker 1: Oh, no, I better use my
Speaker 1: wah-wah-wah.".
Speaker 1: None of that.
Speaker 1: That does not happen here.
Speaker 1: The fights are real quick when they happen at all.
Speaker 0: This has been Geek Nights with Rim and Scott.
Speaker 0: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design, and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at FrontRowCrew.com for show notes, discussion news, and more.
Speaker 0: Remember, Geek Nights is not one, but four different shows.
Speaker 0: Sci-Tech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays, and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: Geek Nights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: Geek Nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 1: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.
Speaker 0: And the Patreon Patrons for this episode of Geek Nights are Alan Joyce, Heidi McNichol, and Eiji Graham-Fitz, you hold the key to my heart.
Speaker 0: Now go through the last year or so of podcasts and make Rim sing.
Speaker 0: Clinton Walton, Ren from New Zealand, Ryan Perrin, Review, MadBull34, Cowards, Dread, Lily, Tenebrae, JustLikeADudeGuy, Chris Reimer, Finn, Shervin, Ron Hall, and a bunch of people who do not want me to say their name.
Speaker 0: Celebrate what happened today, and you can start the work on what we gotta do for the next phase of making things better tomorrow.
Speaker 0: But tonight, like honestly, just like breathe a sigh of relief.
Speaker 0: And now, I leave you with something that has nothing to do with that.
Speaker 1: I said it.
Speaker 1: Wait!
Speaker 1: We have more excellent advice!
Speaker 1: Filthy opaque intruders.
Speaker 1: Wait, I was being haughty.
Speaker 1: Well, we're not.
Speaker 0: Last voice, smack a pair of trash water harpies into our perfect civilization.
Speaker 1: Shorts!
Speaker 1: Take 'em back to the tower, you guys.
Speaker 1: This could be any run-of-the-mill cave hack.
Speaker 0: Why should we believe you even?
Speaker 0: Of course, this day is subtle.
Speaker 0: Is this what passes through music and cotton candy land or whatever?
Speaker 0: You've gotten warped, princess.
Speaker 0: First glass boy, then the fakie Marceline.
Speaker 1: Now you're putting faith in a princess even more helpless than you, okay?
Speaker 1: It's just as we predicted.
Speaker 1: Oh, shut up!
Speaker 1: This is the last place the feast will happen.
Speaker 1: Yeah, get in that death hole.
Speaker 0: So what now?
Speaker 0: Yes!
Speaker 0: We can trap them both in there forever!
Speaker 0: Shutting down the barrier?
Speaker 1: Um, it's not advisable, majesty.
Speaker 1: What a tragic turn.
Speaker 0: I am so sad to tell you that your reign is over.
Speaker 0: No, no, no!
Speaker 0: Everyone stop taking your clothes off!