Speaker 0: It's Tuesday, November 23rd, 2021.
Speaker 0: I'm Rym.
Speaker 1: I'm Scott.
Speaker 0: And this is Geek Nights Tonight.
Speaker 0: It is the Geek Nights Holiday Gaming Gift Guide 2021.
Speaker 1: Let's do this!
Speaker 0: See, I almost got straight up hit by a car walking home from the subway today.
Speaker 1: I mean, that happens all the time.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so walking across Queens... the light was red.
Speaker 0: Walking across the pedestrian area, across Creston Street, right at the base of the bridge, and a gigantic truck, like just a regular truck full of bros, just a giant one, is barreling down the bike lane at very high speed.
Speaker 0: One biker literally like jumped out of the way with his bike and like fell over.
Speaker 0: Another guy jumped into the road, traffic stopped, horns are screeching, and the guy just barrels down the bike lane, runs the red light, and drives off over the Queensboro Bridge.
Speaker 0: Literally had to jump out of the way or get hit by him.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's normal.
Speaker 0: Yep, I got video and everything.
Speaker 0: I did call the cops and they didn't seem to give a shit.
Speaker 0: No, they didn't care.
Speaker 1: It probably is a cop off duty.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I actually got very clear photos of the faces of the guys because they were forced... After they barreled ahead through the red light, they stopped in the intersection for a second because there was a car like blocking their way onto the bridge, and I right over got a picture of their face.
Speaker 1: People were saying, I didn't see any evidence, obviously, that a lot of the fart cars are cops.
Speaker 0: I wouldn't doubt it.
Speaker 1: I believe it.
Speaker 1: It could be, you know, judging by how little they do to, you know, stop the problem.
Speaker 0: Yep, I mean, I did have that experience where I got to sit and listen to a bunch of fart car guys talking about their fart cars.
Speaker 1: Well, the thing, you know, I pointed out, you know, during the marathon, right, the cops went out and they towed mass towing.
Speaker 1: They towed every single car that was parked along the marathon route, right?
Speaker 1: Overnight.
Speaker 1: Tons and tons of cars, right?
Speaker 1: Just towed them all.
Speaker 1: It's like, well, if you can do that, then you could just go through like the whole neighborhood and tow every fart car.
Speaker 0: Yeah, because if you have video and audio, you could have records of which cars are the fart cars that are undisputable and then just go find them.
Speaker 1: But you could just look at a car and tell if it's a fart car.
Speaker 1: You get under it with a flashlight.
Speaker 1: You're like, "Oh, no cat, tow
Speaker 1: it.".
Speaker 0: Oh, my God.
Speaker 0: So a few days ago, Emily and I were on Citi Bikes looking at apartments over in Vernon Jackson, which, spoilers, while they're very expensive, they're not really nicer than the apartment we're in now in a lot of ways.
Speaker 1: No, I mean, you know, when I looked at apartments two to three years ago, I guess, I don't know, when did I move here?
Speaker 1: I don't remember.
Speaker 1: But yeah, there were fancy apartments we looked at that were kind of, they were fancy, but they were new, but they were kind of small and meh.
Speaker 0: Yup, the bedrooms in all those fancy Vernon Jackson buildings are way smaller than what we got right now in this place, paying thousands of dollars less.
Speaker 1: It's quite like two bedroom, but it's actually two tiny bedrooms that are actually one bedroom.
Speaker 1: They just put a wall in between.
Speaker 1: You're actually getting less square footage.
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 1: You know, it's hard to find places that actually have square footage unless you pay for three bedroom or, you know, one bedroom.
Speaker 1: It's like basically the same as the two bedroom, only that wall's missing, so you get more space.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So anyway, yeah, all that aside, let's get right into this because we probably got a lot to say in this show.
Speaker 0: And we can start with the Nintendo Game & Watch, which might be a hot gift.
Speaker 1: Oh yeah.
Speaker 1: So I got the Mario one, right?
Speaker 1: And now I got the, here's the Zelda one I got.
Speaker 0: Oh yeah, look at that.
Speaker 1: So the Zelda one is, I mostly got this, like why would I get this, right?
Speaker 1: To play Zelda that I've played a million times, right?
Speaker 1: It's like, what, 50 bucks?
Speaker 1: Why would you do this?
Speaker 1: So the reason I got this is because it makes a really nice desk clock, right?
Speaker 1: You put it on the desk and I had the Mario one, but the Mario one, you know, first of all, you get a little tired of it.
Speaker 1: It's the same Mario one over and over, right?
Speaker 1: Switch it up.
Speaker 1: The Zelda one compared to the Mario one is vastly superior.
Speaker 1: Number one, you can run the clock and disable the auto sleep.
Speaker 1: So you don't need to have it plugged in.
Speaker 1: The Mario one had no auto, the auto sleep was just locked in.
Speaker 1: You couldn't change it.
Speaker 1: So if you wanted it to run as a clock all the time, you had to keep it plugged into USB-C all the time or else it would turn off.
Speaker 1: The Zelda one, you can tell it, don't turn off and yeah, you're going to have to charge it, obviously, because the battery doesn't last that long, it lasts hours.
Speaker 1: But if you just do it continuously, but you can just use it as a clock on your desk without having it plugged in all the time.
Speaker 1: So that's nice.
Speaker 1: Number two, it's got a lot more going on than the Mario one.
Speaker 1: This one's got Zelda one, Zelda two and Link's Awakening, complete original games.
Speaker 1: It plays much nicer, the screen is much nicer, you know, everything about it is nicer than the Mario one.
Speaker 1: It has a better Game & Watch game, which is the vermin game, right, the one with the two hammers, right, and you move left and right.
Speaker 1: Only they put Link's head on the guy instead of Mr.
Speaker 1: Game & Watch.
Speaker 1: It's got a little countdown timer you can use if you need one, I guess, for some reason.
Speaker 1: So would I buy this as a gaming device to play the games, right?
Speaker 1: Probably not, but you got to think about it.
Speaker 1: If you don't already have some sort of portable gaming device, like a Game Boy Advance or a DS or something, this is smaller.
Speaker 1: And it's three, like these are to S tier games, right?
Speaker 1: All the games are, well, the second one, Rymn likes it.
Speaker 0: I think Zelda two is good and important, but it is not as good as Link's Awakening.
Speaker 1: The other two games are S tier regardless, but this is better than playing the games on your phone.
Speaker 0: Oh wait, you can play the English or the Japanese versions, so that means Zelda two is the harder version with the different leveling up?
Speaker 1: Yeah, I bet to check the music.
Speaker 0: There are big differences between those versions.
Speaker 1: Right, but yeah, you know, if you want to play some Zelda one on the go, like this is smaller than a GBA or a DS or even an SP kinda, right?
Speaker 1: So it's way smaller than a Game Boy Pocket.
Speaker 1: So it's not a bad choice actually for playing the games.
Speaker 1: So yeah, 50 bucks, I guess, you know, still that's a little bit steep.
Speaker 0: You know what it makes actually, it makes a good gift for a gamer who's around our age.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean, it's, you know, it's a lot of novelty, a lot of, you know, some amount of collector's item, shelf display item factors going into it, but it's just way better than the Mario one.
Speaker 1: And I hope that on like the 35th anniversary of like, you know, Metroid or they make a Metroid one or a...
Speaker 0: Ooh, a Metroid one could be real good.
Speaker 1: Kirby one, give me a Kirby one, you know, hook me up.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so in some news, I think this was announced today, so we don't have a lot to go on except the press release.
Speaker 0: basically.
Speaker 0: Epic Games has acquired harmonics.
Speaker 0: You may remember harmonics from the era that was shorter than people realize of buying plastic instruments.
Speaker 1: Right, so if you don't know the whole story, you can read it online, but the summary is that Guitar Hero is made by harmonics, but then I think after Guitar Hero 2 or 3, I forget exactly when it was taken away from them because they didn't like, they were developers, they weren't the publisher, they didn't own the rights, whatever.
Speaker 1: And another company kept going with Guitar Hero, so they went and did Rock Band.
Speaker 1: And then they also did, they basically started a game company that only made rhythm music games of various types, right, after Rock Band.
Speaker 1: They had the DJ one, the card, the card thing.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that card thing, I remember that card thing.
Speaker 1: And they were actually, they were a big deal at PAX East because they were a Boston-based, you know, game developer.
Speaker 1: There weren't too many.
Speaker 1: They were probably the biggest Boston-based game developer there was in terms of the success of their games.
Speaker 1: But music games have gone out of style.
Speaker 1: They didn't really, you know, get any more hits after a while.
Speaker 1: And so they got acquired by Epic who makes Fortnite and has the Epic store.
Speaker 1: And now all those people are going to presumably be working on Fortnite.
Speaker 1: Presumably on some music thing for Fortnite.
Speaker 0: They've officially announced, they did a little FAQ already.
Speaker 0: So one, what does this mean for Rock Band DLC?
Speaker 0: Nothing.
Speaker 0: All those plans continue.
Speaker 0: What about Fuser events?
Speaker 0: No change.
Speaker 0: I don't even know what those are.
Speaker 0: Does this mean more Rock Band?
Speaker 1: Fuser is the DJ game.
Speaker 0: Oh, that's it.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: Anyway.
Speaker 0: Does this mean more Rock Band instruments will be made?
Speaker 0: Nope.
Speaker 0: What about servers for insert harmonics game?
Speaker 0: Will those be taken offline?
Speaker 0: Nope.
Speaker 0: And the last one, what will the harmonics team work on?
Speaker 0: Quote, our team will work with Epic to create musical journeys and gameplay for Fortnite.
Speaker 0: That's it.
Speaker 0: They're definitely going to make music stuff inside of Fortnite, which is, there's probably a topic here for like a full Geek Nights or a panel at some point.
Speaker 0: But Fortnite, much like Minecraft and other big games that have a lot going on, younger kids increasingly will play almost degraded forms of other bigger dedicated games within these games.
Speaker 0: Like it's a thing.
Speaker 1: That's basically what's, that's basically the model, which I think is partially Minecraft's fault, right?
Speaker 1: Or Gary's mod, I think was the first, not, maybe not the first, but it was a big deal.
Speaker 0: But Fortnite really pushed it too.
Speaker 0: Like kids will play hide and seek in Fortnite or role play in Fortnite.
Speaker 1: Kids will play capture the flag and VR chat.
Speaker 1: AOL chat room had that going on, but yeah, it's like rather than make more games, you know, they've, they've just create this, you know, play room platform, like Minecraft or Roblox or any of those.
Speaker 1: And that's, that's the big hit these days is get kids into your, into your play room platform.
Speaker 1: And now when they buy microtransaction hats, they have the hats no matter what game they're playing in Fortnite world.
Speaker 1: And it's way cheaper than developing a bunch of different games.
Speaker 0: You have a built-in audience.
Speaker 1: And it's way cheaper and it's what has a longer staying power than say making an Overwatch.
Speaker 1: And then if people get tired of Overwatch, it's like, well, it only plays Overwatch.
Speaker 1: It doesn't do anything else.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: It's like, you know, it's the way that mods can keep counter-strike alive or whatever.
Speaker 1: Cause it's like, okay, I'm bored playing regular counter-strike.
Speaker 1: Well, here's here.
Speaker 1: We're going to play.
Speaker 1: Wow.
Speaker 1: We're going to play zombies in counter-strike, right?
Speaker 1: They're just been taking that idea so long.
Speaker 0: The people who were playing that level up role play heavy world of Warcraft mod in counter-strike.
Speaker 0: Like that was the peak of.
Speaker 1: people play all sorts of different things in world of Warcraft.
Speaker 1: But I think that's the model of today is create a game that is also a games platform, which, you know, and so it can last long.
Speaker 1: People can just fully invest themselves in that one thing and put their money into it.
Speaker 1: Your developers can keep working on the one thing, but then that person, the people who play your thing don't need other things.
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 1: They're good.
Speaker 0: Another part of it is that those spaces are almost primarily social spaces as opposed to dedicated games in terms of how kids tend to interact with them.
Speaker 0: So these are starting to be a lot like what the early social networks that tried to be like interactive spaces all failed to be.
Speaker 1: It came around like second life, right?
Speaker 1: It's like, no one was going to go to second life cause it was just second life.
Speaker 1: It's like, well, you're here to play counter-strike, but we'll add some second life.
Speaker 1: You're already, you're already here.
Speaker 1: You know, but you're not going to make a special trip to install this second life thing.
Speaker 1: Just to do some concert, but it's like, I already played Fortnite.
Speaker 1: Well, there's a concert in the Fortnite you already have.
Speaker 1: Oh, all right.
Speaker 0: I highly doubt they will at any point start making plastic instruments again, though.
Speaker 1: Plastic instruments are done.
Speaker 1: I think the, as much as I'm the, you know, the exact opposite on the VR spectrum, right?
Speaker 1: I think the future of pretend to be in a rock band, pretend to be.
Speaker 0: It's gotta be VR.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Pretend to be a dancer, right?
Speaker 1: Any of those are all going to be VR, AR type things going forward.
Speaker 0: Actually, MR.
Speaker 1: The specialized plastic thing is gone.
Speaker 0: The ridiculous killer app would be, you have the ridiculous plastic, but it doesn't fucking do anything.
Speaker 0: It's just like an inert, unintelligent drum set that just sits there.
Speaker 0: Like it's just pads on poles.
Speaker 0: But when you sit down in front of it and put on a VR helmet, you still hit the pads.
Speaker 0: But everything is tracked by the VR stuff.
Speaker 0: And it's just a mixed reality experience where you're literally on stage playing with the band, with all the nonsense.
Speaker 1: Like that is where you could do actually, that would actually probably make, uh, enough money to sustain the lives of a few developers.
Speaker 1: If you could make it, you could make it today.
Speaker 1: You could make a VR software where you just, you don't forget all the stuff you just said, right?
Speaker 1: Just you get any two stick like objects.
Speaker 1: Doesn't matter what the hell they are, right?
Speaker 1: Just two sticks.
Speaker 1: You can be six from the yard.
Speaker 0: Something in front of you to hit.
Speaker 0: It could be a table, right?
Speaker 1: You don't even need something to hit.
Speaker 1: You just need two.
Speaker 1: You just need two sticks.
Speaker 1: And then there's a cameras in the VR helmet.
Speaker 1: They see the sticks, you swing the sticks.
Speaker 0: Scott, that already exists.
Speaker 0: There's like 20 games like that.
Speaker 0: They're all pretty good.
Speaker 0: There are.
Speaker 1: Oh, okay.
Speaker 1: And the camera sees the sticks and then it just makes drum noises at the right moments.
Speaker 1: And now you can play the drums in the air.
Speaker 0: There's a million things like that already.
Speaker 0: The killer app here would be not making the better game.
Speaker 0: It would be making the immersive experience using that VR as an MR as opposed to an AR.
Speaker 0: Anyway, there's a lot going on here and we'll, we'll see.
Speaker 0: But yeah, don't, too many nerds.
Speaker 1: Maybe what you could do, maybe what you could do, right?
Speaker 1: Is go to like a big concert, right?
Speaker 1: Say a Metallica concert.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: And you know, the piece of shit drummer, right?
Speaker 1: Lar, whatever his name is, Lars.
Speaker 1: Oh yeah.
Speaker 0: You record, you have to replace it, right?
Speaker 1: You put, you put a helmet, you put a head cam on him, right?
Speaker 1: Or three 60 head cam on his head during the concert.
Speaker 1: And now anyone can pretend to be him.
Speaker 1: You subtract out all the drum sounds from the mix and you subtract out the video of his arms.
Speaker 1: And now you look around and like, you know, you're, uh, you are him, right?
Speaker 1: You're on stage playing with drums with Metallica.
Speaker 1: You can play whatever drum you want.
Speaker 0: A big aspect of people playing rock band was just the experience of listening to the song while doing the thing.
Speaker 0: And this would be just that on another level.
Speaker 0: And the technology is actually there now for that kind of experience where it wasn't even a couple of years ago.
Speaker 1: So that, you know, that's not, that's not a bad, uh, it's not a bad experience.
Speaker 1: I would do that.
Speaker 1: I mean, I wouldn't buy a whole VR set to do that, but I would enjoy doing that.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I've had some great VR experiences, but that alone would not be enough for me to buy VR if I did not already have VR.
Speaker 0: But if that existed today, I would buy it immediately and play it.
Speaker 1: That said, that would be a fun thing.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 0: One last little news, cause we're probably, we're very unlikely to do a show on Thursday cause you know, Thanksgiving holiday, but a wire cutter, which I don't use.
Speaker 0: Like I don't do wire Friday shopping or wire.
Speaker 1: So if you go online and you want to know the best X, you can't trust reviews on Amazon or anything anymore too much.
Speaker 1: And you consumer reports, sometimes you can figure out what they recommend, but they're usually behind a paywall.
Speaker 1: You don't want to pay for that.
Speaker 1: And you know, other ones like America's test kitchen also kind of a paywall situation.
Speaker 1: It's not always easy to find, right?
Speaker 1: Like reliable reviews, even though we have a whole fucking internet full of, you know, unless you have like a specialized Reddit or something like headphone Reddit, you could find headphones.
Speaker 0: Oh yeah.
Speaker 0: Like I can go to Sweetwater and get reviews of like professional audio equipment, but guess what?
Speaker 0: That does not exist.
Speaker 0: for like regular old stuff, right?
Speaker 1: If you want to know, for example, in my situation, best humidifier, there's not a lot of options.
Speaker 1: Well, yeah.
Speaker 0: Also the answer is there are no good humidifiers.
Speaker 1: There are, is true.
Speaker 1: It's I'm trying one out and I'm going to find, if it sucks, I'm going to return it.
Speaker 1: So I expect it to not be perfect.
Speaker 1: The, um, so wire cutter is a division at the New York times that does real product reviews for real and posts on their website for free.
Speaker 1: Uh, the rankings, like I want to know the best, you know, bedsheets here they are right.
Speaker 1: Ranking best one, you know, other good one.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: And it, you know, they're actual real recommendations.
Speaker 1: They're not just like Garbo top 10 lists, uh, like most sites are.
Speaker 1: Uh, but all the links on their website are affiliate links, which means if you go to wire cutter and they say, this is the best bicycle and you click buy, then you get taken to a different website to buy the bicycle.
Speaker 1: Cause it's not like New York times sells bicycles.
Speaker 1: And then if you end up buying it, the New York times gets money.
Speaker 0: Now I'll admit, even when I choose to buy something based on research, I did on a thing like wire cutter.
Speaker 0: Like that can happen when I'm doing research, uh, I always strip or, uh, any affiliate links or go to an independent site or buy directly from the manufacturer.
Speaker 1: Anyway, I agree up until now I've used wire cutter many times to get recommendations.
Speaker 1: I don't always go with the recommendation, but whether I do or not.
Speaker 1: I re I realized that those are affiliate links.
Speaker 1: And if I see, and I decide I want the product, I will then separately open up a website of a store and type in the product model number into the product.
Speaker 0: I go DTC for everything.
Speaker 0: I go direct to consent.
Speaker 0: I go to manufacturer and buy it directly.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 1: If they say the Scott brand, whatever is the best I'll go to scottbrand.com and buy the thing right there.
Speaker 0: If, if, if it's not before any of you say that, how can a wire cutter make money?
Speaker 0: That is not our problem.
Speaker 1: That's not my problem.
Speaker 1: Fuck them.
Speaker 1: But the point is they're mistreating the workers at wire cutter who were doing reviews, doing real reviews is hard, like time intensive work.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: We only review a video game like once every month or so on geek nights.
Speaker 0: It takes a lot of effort to be able to review one.
Speaker 1: We're not doing it properly with journalistic integrity.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: So it's not our job.
Speaker 1: So it's like, imagine having to review, you know, and actually figure out which a humidifier is the best.
Speaker 1: You got to get all these fucking different humidifiers.
Speaker 1: You got to see how they all work, test them all out.
Speaker 1: You know, it's like, measure them all, do all kinds of, you know, really like get to know each one of them very well to figure out which one, you know, what's good or bad about each one, you know, pick the best one, you know, and then write, do actual writing, um, about it.
Speaker 1: It's like, that's hard work.
Speaker 1: So though people who work at wire cutter on strike, they're like, fuck the New York times.
Speaker 1: They're not treating us well.
Speaker 1: We're doing all this hard work.
Speaker 0: They announced the strike today at 10 58 AM.
Speaker 1: So what are the striking?
Speaker 1: And they said, what they want you to do is not use wire cutter, which means even if you do use wire cutter, make sure you block all ads and don't use the affiliate links.
Speaker 1: And that way you can just, you know, mooching off of it is basically the same thing, right?
Speaker 1: Cause what they need to see or just don't go to the website, then you're really safe.
Speaker 1: You won't go across the picket line that way for sure.
Speaker 0: But the key is we got to make sure that the New York times sees that they make almost no money from their affiliate links this year.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: Or a lot less.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Hopefully a lot less.
Speaker 0: So that's why I get the word out about.
Speaker 0: the other
Speaker 1: thing is that, you know, even if the,
Speaker 0: uh,
Speaker 1: cause if, if the affiliate link strike doesn't, uh, influence the times enough to, to, to strike a better deal, what they're going to probably have to do is whole keep striking for long enough that, and hope there's no scabs and that the reviews get out of date.
Speaker 1: Cause once the reviews are out of date, then the whole thing is done.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: But as long as the reviews are still timely, they're asking for so little too.
Speaker 0: Uh, I imagine though, if there were scabs, they're being paid so little that you do a shitty job and ruin the reputation of wire cutter.
Speaker 1: And thus you, you'd be like, well, fuck this.
Speaker 1: I don't need, this isn't helpful anymore.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: As soon as you become no better than an Amazon review, you're just done.
Speaker 1: I do want to disclose that, uh, you know, for, for example, a geek nights book club and some other things, right?
Speaker 1: I have an Amazon affiliate account.
Speaker 1: You just basically click to get one.
Speaker 1: I just had it forever.
Speaker 1: And so, uh, when I linked to those things, I use the affiliate link cause it's like, well, if someone clicks this, I get free money instead of Jeff Bezos getting free money.
Speaker 0: I still urge you to strip those out.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: But also I think we're going to just get rid of those.
Speaker 1: Cause why?
Speaker 1: Basically don't make any money on them.
Speaker 1: So why?
Speaker 0: I think we make more money from like the YouTube ads that you should be blocking.
Speaker 1: I think what we're going to do, actually look into these stats.
Speaker 0: Almost all our YouTube ad money is actually YouTube.
Speaker 0: I almost said YouTube red.
Speaker 0: It's almost it's YouTube premium money.
Speaker 0: If people are paying for the real YouTube.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: But yeah, I think what I'm going to do is, you know, coming up soon with the new website, we're going to be just, I'll just close the affiliate account and we'll get rid of all those links and you know, probably not link to him.
Speaker 1: I'll go to through the book clubs and I'll link to like some other site for the books, The original publisher or a different bookstore or something.
Speaker 0: Problem is any book I buy, I'm still buying an Amazon ebook.
Speaker 1: You can read on my Amazon to buy the book from wherever you're going to buy.
Speaker 1: That's up to you.
Speaker 1: But you know, on the website, we don't gotta be, be doing that.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: We can link to like goodreads or something.
Speaker 1: That's owned by Amazon.
Speaker 0: Crap.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: They'll figure something out to link to there.
Speaker 0: There used to be more websites.
Speaker 0: I say that a lot.
Speaker 1: Goodreads is highly integrated with the Kindle.
Speaker 0: I say that a lot, but there used to be more websites.
Speaker 0: And the fact that there aren't enough websites is a big problem right now.
Speaker 0: But anyway, things of the day.
Speaker 0: So I played doom and doom 2, like when they came out, I got those shareware disks.
Speaker 0: I was all in on doom.
Speaker 0: And doom 2 was notable in that one.
Speaker 0: It, it had multiple double barreled shotgun shotgun.
Speaker 0: It was a fantastic goddamn game.
Speaker 0: It was better than, and different from doom 1 without just replacing doom 1.
Speaker 0: They're both worth playing cyber demons.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: There's a lot going on there, but, uh, doom 2 had four different versions.
Speaker 0: Like they updated it.
Speaker 0: Remember this was before most people had access to the internet.
Speaker 1: You couldn't just, you bought, when you bought doom 2, that was the version you got.
Speaker 1: And you weren't, if there were patches, you weren't getting them easily.
Speaker 0: Uh, only would go and get these patches.
Speaker 0: You had to like know what to do.
Speaker 1: But I mean the same thing existed, you know, look at people talk about like, Oh, you know, if you play a link to the past randomizer, you need, you know, link to the past 1.0 Japanese version because all the American versions had patches and there were even patches beyond that.
Speaker 1: Now they tested those games so thoroughly before release that no casual player would really ever encounter almost any of those glitches.
Speaker 1: Um, but there were still lots of them.
Speaker 0: Not like.
Speaker 0: there's the Pokemon game that sets out now, one of the recent ones, and people have discovered multiple permanent game ending soft locks in it.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: But it's like, nobody's gonna, you know, missing.
Speaker 1: no, it's like, you need a guide to find missing.
Speaker 1: no in the original Pokemon, right?
Speaker 1: You're not getting any glitches as a casual with the amount of testing they do, but they still patches.
Speaker 1: And your point is you could never upgrade because you got a cartridge.
Speaker 1: You couldn't upgrade your cartridge and tend to didn't take the old one back and send you a new one.
Speaker 0: Total aside as a kid playing Final Fantasy 4 as Final Fantasy 2, the US edition on a cartridge that we bought like near when it came out, I accidentally did some sort of glitch and got two items, a summon and one of special items in my inventory from a random encounter.
Speaker 0: And none of my friends believe me.
Speaker 0: And I like took photos of the TV to prove that I had them.
Speaker 0: I had like the imp summon and the bomb some, all this weird shit that I found.
Speaker 1: Anyway, one time I was playing a mega man too.
Speaker 1: I was fighting bubble man and accidentally there was some kind of glitch.
Speaker 1: and you know, cause you go into a boss room in a mega man and you know, the little boss door opens like tick, tick, tick, tick, tick, and then it closes and you can't go back.
Speaker 1: You can only, it's a one way door.
Speaker 1: One time I was fighting both men and somehow by X, I don't know what I did.
Speaker 1: The door opened up in reverse and I left the room.
Speaker 1: And then I came back in and it was a fucked up glitch room.
Speaker 1: Oh yeah.
Speaker 1: And I could, I could never replicate it.
Speaker 1: And I've never seen anyone on the internet replicate it.
Speaker 1: It was just a random glitch.
Speaker 1: Might've been, who knows what, but the boss door opened backwards.
Speaker 1: You can believe me or not.
Speaker 1: I was a kid.
Speaker 0: So Doom 2 had four versions, version 1.666, 1.7, 1.8, and 1.9.
Speaker 0: I was, and this was over the course of like between 1994 and 1995.
Speaker 1: There's no way for me to know which version I played.
Speaker 0: I intimately knew these versions because I was deep into the modding community of Doom 2 back in the day.
Speaker 0: Like I was playing with dehacked and wadded and windu and all that crap.
Speaker 0: I made all sorts of weird mods and teleporter guns and me and Ken and a bunch of our friends were like deep into that.
Speaker 0: And there were a lot of important, like.
Speaker 0: you had to know which version you were targeting and you needed older versions for certain kinds of weird hacks you wanted to do.
Speaker 0: What I did not know somehow until I saw this video a couple of weeks ago is that there were a lot of differences in specific parts of the maps in these versions.
Speaker 0: All the differences I knew about were in the engine, in enemy behavior, in like the way some triggers worked.
Speaker 0: But there were differences in the maps and this video explained a weird mystery as a kid where I had this memory of a secret door being in a spot and I remember very specifically like going to find it because I wanted to do something with it for a mod and I couldn't find it.
Speaker 0: And it was fucking me up to the point that as a high schooler I literally thought I had dreamed about this secret door and just like assumed it was real.
Speaker 0: Nope, it was only in like version 1.8, which I didn't bother playing because that was like the worthless version.
Speaker 0: So yeah, there you go.
Speaker 0: This video is fascinating.
Speaker 0: It's like 13 minutes long.
Speaker 1: I did watch this video before you even brought it up today.
Speaker 1: I watched it like maybe a while ago and they pointed out a lot of the map changes were like just straight up design improvements.
Speaker 1: They're just better.
Speaker 0: Like move an enemy slightly to the left or fix the pegging of a texture so it actually lines up with the rest of the level, that kind of stuff.
Speaker 1: So speaking of old PC games, right, people often think of Quake as the first like actually 3D FPS because Doom was mostly 3D, but not really.
Speaker 0: Doom was a 2D game that had a third dimension implemented via interesting mechanisms.
Speaker 0: Most people call it.
Speaker 1: the first actual, for real, 3D game was Descent.
Speaker 1: And Descent was a game.
Speaker 1: that was the first game that I played on DOS where I got nauseous the first time I played it.
Speaker 1: Then I got used to it.
Speaker 0: Descent was so fucking good.
Speaker 1: But so there have been some more recent games made by like the people who originally made Descent to try to bring back, you know, the old times, but not so successful because a game where you can move around like that is like not an accessible game, really.
Speaker 1: It's understandable why it's not popular now, but you can get Descent 1 to Descent 2 on GOG.
Speaker 1: And I was in a mood to play some Descent.
Speaker 1: So I went and I downloaded GOG because I own them on there already.
Speaker 1: I tried to run them and they run, but they ran really kind of meh.
Speaker 1: And I tried to mess with the DOSBox configs to make them less meh.
Speaker 1: And then I discovered, oh, wait, there's a thing called.
Speaker 1: what the hell is it called?
Speaker 1: DXX Rebirth.
Speaker 1: Yeah, DXX Rebirth.
Speaker 1: It's basically just like ZDoom, which is an engine that you load Doom wads into it.
Speaker 1: It's way better than regular the Doom game, right?
Speaker 1: At least for the current day.
Speaker 1: DXX Rebirth.
Speaker 1: If you have legit copies already of Descent 1 and 2, you copy some files over from your, you download the games in GOG, you copy some files over, and then you run DXX Rebirth.
Speaker 1: And now you can play Descent 1, Descent 2 only.
Speaker 1: Everything's modern.
Speaker 1: I'm running it at 4K resolution.
Speaker 1: My GPU is helping out.
Speaker 1: It's not everything's all pixely all the time.
Speaker 0: There's a lot of Doom mods that did a similar thing to the point.
Speaker 1: I can use my mouse wheel for the controls, you know, all kinds of good stuff.
Speaker 0: Back then, if you were lucky, your mouse had three buttons.
Speaker 0: Scroll wheels were not really a thing yet.
Speaker 1: No.
Speaker 1: So, yeah, if you want to play Descent, DXX Rebirth is definitely the best way to play.
Speaker 1: And also, I highly recommend playing Descent.
Speaker 1: Pretty much any game that says Descent on it is a good game.
Speaker 0: I feel like I got some time off, too.
Speaker 0: I could play this because I was thinking about after you mentioned it, I was thinking about playing Descent again, because I literally have not played that since the era I was running DOS.
Speaker 1: Descent is really like, you know, you think about like FPSs, but like basically.
Speaker 1: imagine Quake, but, you know, where your mouse looks, right?
Speaker 1: Your WASD moves.
Speaker 1: And but in Quake, the problem is this gravity.
Speaker 1: So up is like jump, but it's only a little bit up and down is like crouch.
Speaker 1: It's only a little bit down.
Speaker 1: Descent is the same exact thing.
Speaker 1: Only it's zero gravity.
Speaker 1: So jump.
Speaker 1: It's like you don't move up and down.
Speaker 1: You just stay put and you press jump.
Speaker 1: You go up and when you let go of jump, you just stop wherever you are.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: You know, and you crouch, you go down and you let go.
Speaker 0: And this is not like flying.
Speaker 0: I don't know, a Star Wars squadron ship through a building like it.
Speaker 0: No, you got to play it.
Speaker 0: There are not many games that control this way.
Speaker 0: And it is.
Speaker 0: it is neat.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's it's.
Speaker 1: it's not too different from any other FPS, right?
Speaker 1: You should set up your controls exactly the same as the way you play quake.
Speaker 1: Just remember that jump is not jump.
Speaker 1: It's up and crouch is not crouch.
Speaker 1: It's down.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: And you'll be very if you set your controls up like that.
Speaker 1: Oh, and I guess you also have to use a, you know, Q and E for roll for roll, right?
Speaker 1: Because, you know, you can't roll in quake, but you can roll in descent.
Speaker 1: So because you're a ship, you're not a.
Speaker 0: I actually played it with a joystick.
Speaker 1: That's also a good way to do it.
Speaker 1: Perfectly valid.
Speaker 0: I had a flight stick pro plugged into my sound card.
Speaker 1: But yeah, it's.
Speaker 1: it's like and you know, you think, oh, instead of being free, you know, the other difference between descent and say X wing is that, yeah, it's your fraud.
Speaker 1: You're flying freely in space, but you're trapped in a maze like you are in Doom or Wolfenstein.
Speaker 1: You're not just out in the nowhere.
Speaker 1: If you want, if you want that experience, play descent free space, which is a different game.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: In the moment, the geek does book club book, Taylor Genji.
Speaker 0: We'll do that show shortly after the new year with steamrolling through.
Speaker 1: Uh, I read some.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I read some too.
Speaker 0: I read.
Speaker 0: So I was, I had to go to work today and, uh, at a poop that was about long enough to finish a chapter I was on.
Speaker 0: So, uh, we'll keep going.
Speaker 0: This is Genji story.
Speaker 0: Knowing what I know, I'm probably going to stop at the points where it is debated whether or not it's the same author onward.
Speaker 0: It's a spoiler.
Speaker 1: You're going to cut short.
Speaker 1: I'm going to keep reading anything that is a chapter.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: My question to you is Genji still alive?
Speaker 1: Uh, yeah.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 0: You know, I plan to stop reading.
Speaker 1: I know.
Speaker 1: I know he bites it because I saw it at the museum.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: I plan to stop reading when Genji is no longer alive unless I feel compelled or I finish in like the next week and a half or two.
Speaker 0: I'll just keep going until we do the show.
Speaker 0: But anyway, otherwise, while I will be live, probably very likely without Scott at Pax Unplugged on Friday at 1pm in the Crab God Theater with a rebuild of a panel.
Speaker 0: We did a pilot version of once called Rare Game Mechanics.
Speaker 0: If you're not already going to Pax Unplugged, you do not need to go to see this panel because I plan to come home, edit it together and put it on YouTube before Pax Unplugged ends that weekend.
Speaker 1: You know what?
Speaker 1: That's Friday, December 10th, not this Friday.
Speaker 1: Oh yeah.
Speaker 0: December 10th, not this Friday.
Speaker 0: There's some con this Friday, but not what we're going to know.
Speaker 0: Otherwise, yeah, let's get right into the gift guide.
Speaker 0: I don't have anything else.
Speaker 1: So yeah, a lot of websites out there as we discussed, affiliate links, right?
Speaker 1: There's a lot of websites out there that, you know, either a are just SEO spam where they put together a website, they go on Amazon, they find like the 10 best X, right?
Speaker 1: Or they put together some gift guide for X and they just take a bunch of affiliate links that they know that have good Amazon reviews and look like they didn't put any research in to figure out what's actually best.
Speaker 1: They just got a site to show up on your Google search result and hoping that you click those links.
Speaker 1: So they make free money.
Speaker 1: There's also a lot of journalistic outfits, like real journalistic outfits, even nerdy ones where in the holiday season, they'll post articles to their website that are like holiday buying guide for X, right?
Speaker 1: And it's like you're already reading their website and so you're the target audience and now they can post a list of things for you to buy.
Speaker 1: that are all affiliate links and they make some money.
Speaker 1: But that's not really like actually helping you choose to help, you know, find things to buy.
Speaker 1: It might, maybe, but yeah, there was a lot of effort put towards those.
Speaker 0: It is very easy to get money looking at a list like that because you know what those, uses those lists.
Speaker 0: People who are trying to buy a gift for someone they don't know that well or for whom they are not willing to put in that much effort and they're just they're trying to fulfill the unit of.
Speaker 0: I have given a gift and this is a really easy way to abdicate that responsibility.
Speaker 0: Oh, I know he's into gaming.
Speaker 0: I'll buy him the what's the top game Metroid.
Speaker 0: That's the game that came out on the Nintendo.
Speaker 0: He has a Nintendo, right?
Speaker 0: You buy that gift.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so I'm like, hey, what if we do, right?
Speaker 1: It's a holiday season now, right?
Speaker 1: We can do sort of a no personal capitalist interest, but also no capitalist interest whatsoever.
Speaker 1: Gift buying guide, right?
Speaker 1: It's, you know, it's like, so I guess today is Tuesday, so we'll do the gaming one.
Speaker 1: So there is a person that you need want or need to get a gift of some kind or give a gift to for holiday times.
Speaker 1: And you know that this person is a video game and or tabletop game enjoyer of sorts, right?
Speaker 1: What gift should you get this person now?
Speaker 0: Of course, we can give a lot of suggestions and such, but remember, you actually have to know about them.
Speaker 1: saving my best suggestion for last.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, I got some.
Speaker 0: I got some radical ones because games are a minefield for buying gifts, because if you look at video games, a lot of people, if they want a video game, they just buy that video game.
Speaker 0: A lot of people have access to a lot of video games they haven't even played yet.
Speaker 0: And in fact, often being bought a video game can be social pressure by someone who likes that video game to try to get the person who's receiving the gift to play that video game with them.
Speaker 1: It's also, you know, in terms of giving gifts, I still feel like giving digital gifts is, you know, kind of meh.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like that's.
Speaker 0: I've thought about that a lot.
Speaker 0: Like there's on one hand, people who give me steam gifts before, like, hey, here's a free game.
Speaker 0: But that's usually incidental as opposed to like, it's your birthday.
Speaker 0: I bought you Half-Life 4 or whatever.
Speaker 0: It's more like I had a bunch of gift codes.
Speaker 0: Here's one.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so, you know, I don't really most games are digital, so I don't really like buying a game.
Speaker 1: Also, if there's a game someone wants, they probably got it.
Speaker 1: So you if someone's a Smash Brothers fan, you can't really get them.
Speaker 1: Smash Brothers.
Speaker 1: You can't get them a switch.
Speaker 1: They've got it right.
Speaker 1: You need to get something else outside of that that zone.
Speaker 0: You got to separate between.
Speaker 0: is this a gift for a person or this is this a gift for a child who does not have control over their own finances and cannot get?
Speaker 1: children are easier to buy gifts or because, yeah, even if they're a child with rich parents or something, they're well off.
Speaker 1: There's children don't have the ability to purchase things for themselves.
Speaker 1: So there's probably things that they want that their parents haven't bought them yet that they probably made some sort of gift list of.
Speaker 0: These are the things I want.
Speaker 0: I want Smash Brothers.
Speaker 1: Or you just know what that kid likes.
Speaker 1: And the kid probably doesn't also read the news.
Speaker 1: So they probably don't even know that like a new thing is that exists.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 1: But in terms of like the Pokemon Diamond Pearl remakes just came out.
Speaker 1: Rim was talking about the soft locks.
Speaker 1: It's like there's probably Pokemon fan kids who don't even know that those are out.
Speaker 0: But for kids who don't control their own finances or for gamers who have
Speaker 1: money or
Speaker 0: buy the things they want, if you're going to get a gift that is a game in a digital world, the best possible way to do that is to figure out what ecosystem that person primarily plays games and get them some sort of gift card in that ecosystem.
Speaker 0: that is effectively cash.
Speaker 0: Nothing makes a kid's day more than having 40 dollars in like Roblox or whatever ecosystem they give a shit about.
Speaker 1: If there's a if there's a Roblox kid, giving them Robux is going to make them thrilled.
Speaker 1: But you have to consider for yourself how you feel about giving money to an immoral system.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: But similarly, it would be a Roblox kid is going to be super happy to get a pile of Roblox.
Speaker 1: Let me tell you.
Speaker 0: But a non Roblox, a Roblox kid who owns the Nintendo Switch, Nintendo dollars, Nintendo coins are extremely valuable to those kids.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Also, you know, someone's got an iPhone.
Speaker 1: You can't go wrong with some Apple dollars.
Speaker 1: It's like, so I get their kid.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: So you want to go through video game enjoyers first or tabletop enjoyers first?
Speaker 1: It doesn't matter.
Speaker 1: So my first idea, and this is something I got for myself recently, but I think could be good for anybody really, is that almost any video game player has controllers.
Speaker 1: Now, they already got controllers.
Speaker 1: If there was a fancy controller, they needed like a fighting game person or something.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: It's like they already got that.
Speaker 0: Sometimes the hotasses are hard to get and expensive.
Speaker 0: So that is the kind of something that is a niche gift, but a controller that is actually hard to get that you somehow are able to get with your connections and resources.
Speaker 0: Absolutely fantastic gift.
Speaker 0: But that's a situational thing.
Speaker 0: That's rare.
Speaker 1: I think that's true.
Speaker 1: Just in general.
Speaker 1: It's like, yeah, if you have a bunch of money and you want to get some 3080, it's like or any sort of expensive, rare thing.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: It's like, you know, they want to get it.
Speaker 0: I can't even get a fucking 3080 kid.
Speaker 1: But the point is, if there's something that's obviously rare out of stock, you know, hard to find, that's something that you can get for someone who even has money because they probably didn't get it for themselves already.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: That's that's easy one.
Speaker 1: But my idea was you could go and I recently changed the shells on my joy cons to be green.
Speaker 1: So you could get somebody's controllers and customize them, put different shells on them, or you could go get a controller.
Speaker 1: Don't give someone the shells unless, you know, they're a big DIY person.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: You're going to have to do it for them and give them a controller that's already customized and has their aesthetic.
Speaker 1: They would be into that, I think.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 0: That that's a good gift.
Speaker 0: Another with gaming.
Speaker 0: It's tough.
Speaker 0: A lot of people want to be live streamers, but don't quite know how to do it.
Speaker 0: And if you know, the person's kind of doing it, but like has not invested at all.
Speaker 0: Buying any amount of the technology or things that a professional would know to own, but some kid wouldn't know to own like a ring light or a desk mounted stand for a light or one really nice microphone.
Speaker 1: Like even if they're not going to be good at streaming or use it a lot.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: They'll be happy to have it if they're trying and having these, you know, dreams of grandeur that they give up on a two months.
Speaker 1: That's all right.
Speaker 1: They'll have a gift.
Speaker 1: They'll be happy for two months.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: They'll thank you.
Speaker 0: Or even if they don't.
Speaker 0: Those kinds of things tend to just make it more pleasant to be online in social spaces in general, like being in a discord video call or zoom in with the friends or whatever.
Speaker 0: Those are just super generically useful.
Speaker 0: And a lot of people don't know like the good things that exist in that space.
Speaker 0: Like a lot of people have no idea that a ring light is like fantastic for a webcam and they wonder why they look like shit online.
Speaker 0: It's the kind of gift that some in general, the best kind of gift you can get someone is something that they didn't know they wanted, but you figured out they would use or would want if they knew it existed.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: So also along the custom lines, right?
Speaker 1: You know, I recently upgraded my GBA big time.
Speaker 0: Oh yeah.
Speaker 1: If you go and get, you know, an old, you know, GBA, people probably aren't thinking of that, right?
Speaker 1: But go get an old GBA, upgrade it with the new screen, right?
Speaker 1: And the, and the USB-C charging battery, just like I did.
Speaker 1: Get a flash cart, load the flash cart with all the ROMs, do everything for them.
Speaker 1: And if you give that to some gamer as a gift, even if they weren't thinking about it, even if, you know, it's like anyone who plays video games is going to be happy to have one.
Speaker 0: And if, and there's almost no danger.
Speaker 0: This person already has that because people who have those things and use them will never fucking shut up about them.
Speaker 1: It's like, oh yes, they already have, they already, you would know if someone was the kind of person who took a Game Boy Advance and swapped this display on it.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: Cause they've got it with them.
Speaker 0: They show it to you when there is no context for that.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: So we're talking cool ideas.
Speaker 0: One, especially for online spaces.
Speaker 0: If you know someone like hangs out in VR chat or does a lot of social media, buying someone a commission slot with an artist who makes avatars or things like that, that is the kind of gift that no one thinks about finding a good commission artist to make you like an avatar or
Speaker 1: commission an artist to make an art for them or obviously be an artist and make an art for someone.
Speaker 1: That's a gift for not just Tuesday, but any day.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 0: But if you're not an artist and you can't make it yourself, then either commissioning someone to make it for them, or especially if it's something like a social media avatar, finding an artist that's in the style they like, or that, you know, they like and buying them the commission slot, but letting them work with the artist on the details way safer.
Speaker 0: And that is the kind of gift that no one thinks to give.
Speaker 1: Mm hmm.
Speaker 1: And no, that branches out into like, you know, other categories.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: So like in the tabletop zone, you might think, oh, okay.
Speaker 1: Dice tray.
Speaker 1: Wait, fancy dice tray.
Speaker 1: Wait, no.
Speaker 1: Commission artist who makes custom dice trays.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: That's like just take it to another level there.
Speaker 0: Same thing with mouse pads.
Speaker 0: Fancy new mouse pad.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: You got the art that the kid is really into.
Speaker 0: Like their Roblox is right there fighting the other Roblox.
Speaker 1: Mm hmm.
Speaker 1: It's like, oh, buy someone some dice.
Speaker 1: No, buy someone a slot with the person who makes handmade dice and they can get their own custom dice to their desires from the dice artisan.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 1: You got to go next level, right?
Speaker 1: If you just give someone some dice, it's like, okay, I got dice.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I always like getting more dice because they're nerd.
Speaker 1: But yeah, but it's like, I got nerds who want dice.
Speaker 0: You know what they want to do more than anything.
Speaker 1: Someone got me, even someone like me, who's not using dice too much these days.
Speaker 1: If you got me the commission slot with the dice artisan, I'd be like, oh, that's great.
Speaker 1: Oh yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: But if you're getting someone just dice that can be bought commercially, that's kind of a fail because anyone who cares about dice, they want more than anything when they're at a gaming store or a convention to buy more dice.
Speaker 0: They're barely holding themselves back.
Speaker 0: So you will get them dice that they don't need and deny them the pleasure of buying those dice from the place.
Speaker 0: But the commission dice, that's a big one.
Speaker 1: And if they're a tabletop person in general, right?
Speaker 1: If you don't, you could either go, if you're going for some standard item that they already have, like dice, you need to level it up to like fancy or commission level, right?
Speaker 1: But you could give them some weird items.
Speaker 1: Like here, I went to Game Crafter and I got you a ton of fucking meeples and sticks and right.
Speaker 1: It's like, yeah, even if someone's not looking to design games, tabletop nerds love to have game bits.
Speaker 1: They just like them.
Speaker 1: You can't go wrong.
Speaker 1: I mean, here's a sack of meeples for like every game, you know, just a hundred thousand meeples.
Speaker 0: I have an enjoyer of just sack of meeples to do something with.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you got the cow meeple, the meat meeple, the wheat meeple, you know, have fun.
Speaker 1: Good times.
Speaker 0: Along those lines, we're talking about tabletop in particular.
Speaker 0: RPGs are interesting and tough because RPG people tend to buy every goddamn RPG they even remotely thought was interesting.
Speaker 0: Or they just play D&D or Pathfinder, which is basically just D&D.
Speaker 0: That's a tough space to get gifts in directly unless they're in the miniature zone, right?
Speaker 1: It's like that is the miniatures.
Speaker 1: People are actually probably the easiest because, yes, they will just be happy to get more miniatures.
Speaker 1: like some dude has a 40K army or he does D&D with minis.
Speaker 1: It's like, here, I got you 20 skeletons or I got you 20 space marines.
Speaker 1: They're just like, yes, they're just like, here's some paint.
Speaker 1: It's blue.
Speaker 1: It's like, yes, it's like they're thrilled, right?
Speaker 1: That's just not cheap.
Speaker 1: There's doubles.
Speaker 1: Doesn't matter.
Speaker 1: I already got that one.
Speaker 1: Just get them anything.
Speaker 1: That's as long as it's in the right game that or the stuff that they do.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: It's all good.
Speaker 1: Just minis are the easiest in the universe.
Speaker 1: Here's some fake bushes.
Speaker 0: Woo.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: But a way to go on generic gifts, especially with a lot of people's stuff to play RPGs online.
Speaker 0: And I've seen directly from some conversations with coworkers recently that there are many people who struggled to find people to roleplay with during the pandemic, when a lot of people got driven online, suddenly had a bunch of people to play with because they were online.
Speaker 0: A lot of people still struggle with actually making online games work well.
Speaker 0: So depending on the person, paying for a year for them to have an account like a real one on a thing like Roll20 could be a really good gift.
Speaker 0: if you know the person's playing games online.
Speaker 1: Maybe you're getting you're getting close to my ultimate gift idea, but you're not quite there yet.
Speaker 0: Or just like I talked about with the streaming equipment, a lot of people are playing games online might not like in a discord or something might not have the things to facilitate that experience and make it easier.
Speaker 0: One of those webcam stands that points down at a die rolling pit could go a long way for someone who's playing games online ad hoc.
Speaker 1: Hmm.
Speaker 1: So, yeah, back to the equipment ideas, right?
Speaker 1: You know, most gamers are probably not using regular playing cards too often, but you got to have one in the house somewhere.
Speaker 1: When I was I was recently buying a lot of playing cards for some purposes, you would be shocked.
Speaker 1: I mean, maybe probably not when you think about it, but just a sheer amount of different playing card decks that are out there with different art on them of high and low qualities.
Speaker 1: It's like if you get someone everyone needs a deck of playing cards, if you get a gamer, you can probably get a Mario deck of playing cards, a Star Wars, whatever it is.
Speaker 1: Fancy deck of playing cards is like that's the stocking stuffer.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: You just said right along those lines, if you know a big tabletop person who doesn't have a set of actually nice clay poker chips, those are so nice, so useful.
Speaker 0: I love my poker chips.
Speaker 0: That giant, like heavy suitcase that I've been stopped.
Speaker 0: Ninety percent of the times I've flown with those things, I've been stopped by the TSA.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: So next item I got here, someone might enjoy a game, say, maybe they're Animal Crossing person or Zelda person.
Speaker 1: There do exist various like.
Speaker 1: the easiest example are like the big strategy guide books or like that Zelda history book they have or Mega Man art book.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: There's always going to be lots and lots of like small, not huge print run, you know, coffee table book kind of stuff, but just meta media that is published or produced about the game that they're into.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 1: Whether it's strategy guys, art books, you know, documentaries, you know, anything like that, anything in the meta zone.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: That has been created and sold.
Speaker 1: Those are usually sold as gifts.
Speaker 1: That's what they're there for.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: So getting any one of those, if you know which game the person is into, is probably easy.
Speaker 1: if you know they don't have that thing already.
Speaker 1: Likewise, we talked about getting some of the expensive, hard to get thing, but there's also the rare unknown thing is usually this applies to, you know, because it's video games, usually Japanese merch.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Now you pay attention to merch that is being produced in another country.
Speaker 1: Go to like HLJ.com or something, or Big Bad Toy Store, or any of those websites where they're importing Japanese merchandise.
Speaker 1: I'm sure it's more expensive these days and harder to get, but there is a lot of merchandise produced in other countries that someone who isn't very internetty and isn't very well connected is not going to even know it exists.
Speaker 0: And the less internetty someone is, the lower that bar is.
Speaker 0: That Zelda Game & Watch, for a huge percentage of gamers in America, even if they would like that thing, they don't know it exists because they just don't pay attention.
Speaker 1: And it's on the shelves at their local Target and they don't know it exists.
Speaker 1: So if you get something, if you import like, you know, the Gengar backpack for some kid from Japan, it's like, holy shit, where'd you get that from?
Speaker 1: Oh, the other side of the world, right?
Speaker 1: It's like, no way are you going to miss as long as you get the right intellectual property.
Speaker 1: Bring the rare import.
Speaker 0: So situationally, this is either a gift for an older nerd who's starting to try to collect retro gaming stuff or a young gamer who doesn't have a lot of games or the sheer novelty of this would get them.
Speaker 0: If you've got like an old NES or an Atari 2600 laying around, not the modding situation like Scott talked about, where you like get the custom GBA mod with the chip and give it with the card and give it to them.
Speaker 0: But like kid, here's an NES.
Speaker 0: The cables are plugged into a modern TV and 50 cartridges.
Speaker 1: Well, you can also get, I think a good idea is, you know, how I mentioned the upgraded GBA.
Speaker 1: There are various, you know, sort of unofficial console devices that you can get.
Speaker 1: You can get like one of those handheld Raspberry Pi things or, you know, a console Raspberry Pi style device.
Speaker 0: Those things are pretty good.
Speaker 0: They're definitely a dubious legality, but who cares?
Speaker 1: Well, there's two different styles, right?
Speaker 1: There's the style that's full of emulators because, you know, if they're not an HDPC person, if they got an Apple TV, just get them a device and, you know, load it up with all the ROMs that they can plug into their TV that has some controllers attached to it.
Speaker 1: Or they have ones that, yeah, it's not an actual NES, but you can put an NES cartridge in or a Genesis cartridge or a Super Nintendo cartridge and it plays.
Speaker 1: Maybe it also plays ROMs, right?
Speaker 1: It's just, there's a lot of these, you know, sort of, uh, unofficial console devices out there that you can get.
Speaker 1: And a non-HTPC person can get a lot of benefit out of one of those.
Speaker 1: And, you know, coming from my perspective, I'm like always telling people, get an HDPC.
Speaker 1: You can play every video game ever.
Speaker 1: Get a, you play every video game ever and people don't do it.
Speaker 0: You, uh, you gave me a really good segue because one of the things that's near the bottom of my list was for, for someone who is not an HTPC person, fucking get them a tiny HTPC already set up and install it in their house.
Speaker 0: And they will, they will never look back.
Speaker 1: Or just get the gaming, you know, just, just the gaming part of it as a, as a little device, right?
Speaker 1: Just so they, it's like, look, I set it up for you.
Speaker 1: I got you this gift.
Speaker 1: You now have every emulatable video game ever on a little SD card and they all play on your TV.
Speaker 1: And now you can see what I was raving about all this time.
Speaker 0: Yup.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: The HDPC was more for my Monday list.
Speaker 0: It was literally just get one of those people, the tiniest possible HDPC.
Speaker 0: And it's got like Chrome and steam and windows installed on it.
Speaker 1: Tiniest computer with like eight or 16 gigs of Ram, a CPU.
Speaker 1: You don't need any GPU in there, right?
Speaker 1: Just, and then plug it and get it plugged into their TV with some kind of remote control keyboard thing.
Speaker 0: Get them that one, like Logitech integrated keyboard and touch pad that everyone uses cause it's cheap and it just works.
Speaker 1: And they still make it.
Speaker 1: And it was on sale recently.
Speaker 1: I don't know if it still is.
Speaker 0: I changed the batteries every like year and a half give or take.
Speaker 1: So I'm down.
Speaker 1: I'm down to my two ultimate gift ideas.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: Cause I, our commission is pretty ultimate.
Speaker 1: So our commission was pretty ultimate.
Speaker 0: I can't, that was, what's your pen ultimate?
Speaker 1: The pen ultimate is not.
Speaker 1: everybody is like us who in a safe time can just go to fucking conventions all the time.
Speaker 1: Oh, if you just, you know, it's cost money.
Speaker 1: It does.
Speaker 1: You take someone, you just take them and right.
Speaker 1: It's like, guess what?
Speaker 1: Bitches are going to fax, right?
Speaker 1: They never been.
Speaker 1: Or guess what?
Speaker 1: Bitches are going to Essen.
Speaker 1: We're going to Tokyo game show.
Speaker 1: Where are we going?
Speaker 1: Take them, get the tickets, get the flight, get the hotel, get it all.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: It's like, we're going to Disney world.
Speaker 1: kids only not.
Speaker 0: That is one hell of a good gift idea.
Speaker 1: Just take them to the con.
Speaker 1: We're going to go see those two geek nights.
Speaker 1: Nerds
Speaker 0: that is a gift that requires effort because especially someone who's never been to a con before, just buying them, like getting them in and then like they're on their own by not cut it, but being willing to actually go with them and make it a thing and like show them around.
Speaker 0: Not only is that fun for them, but I mean, I like doing that.
Speaker 0: Whenever we have a PACS newbie who comes with us to a PACS, that is a good time.
Speaker 0: It's Scott.
Speaker 0: I were dragging them around like, Oh, we're going to the omega-thon finale.
Speaker 0: You don't even know what that is.
Speaker 0: Do you?
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 0: Hopefully it's not a bad game.
Speaker 1: So the ultimate gift idea, the thing that all gamer, all gamer actually wants, right.
Speaker 1: Is won't even cost you any fucking money.
Speaker 0: I know.
Speaker 0: I'm going to type in no, in my little notepad, uh, exactly what I think you're about to say.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: Let me see what you're let me tell you.
Speaker 1: Oh, in your notepad.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 0: So I just said what I'm doing, what I typed was I will play the game that you want to play with you a certain number of times.
Speaker 1: That's exactly right.
Speaker 1: The thing that all gamer wants.
Speaker 0: I'll play your fucking train game that you've been bothering me about for 10 years.
Speaker 0: Look, I will play with you.
Speaker 1: The ultimate gift is peak gaming experience.
Speaker 1: We are going to, I rented out the place that has the battle tech VR fucking day.
Speaker 1: We're bringing 10 people there.
Speaker 0: Or you want to do laser tag or airsoft for doing it once.
Speaker 0: Here it is.
Speaker 1: I rented out the back of the game store and we're going to play that the 10 hour samurai swords taught in pyramid.
Speaker 1: It's happening.
Speaker 0: You always wanted to play that crazy LARP that your one friend kickstarted.
Speaker 0: Well, guess what?
Speaker 0: I arranged there are 12 of us.
Speaker 0: I will run it on this day.
Speaker 0: You're playing inheritance.
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 1: It's ha I, I, I already figured out your calendar, right?
Speaker 1: It's everything is set.
Speaker 1: This is happening.
Speaker 1: The, the amazing game experience is going down guaranteed, right?
Speaker 1: Some long ass high effort thing is actually going to happen for real.
Speaker 0: Presenting that as an, a coupon slash IOU slash we will do.
Speaker 0: this is a great gift.
Speaker 1: Now it's got, you got, if you just give the coupon that says like one peak gaming experience or like I will Twilight Imperium with you, that's not enough.
Speaker 0: You know, it's got to be one peak.
Speaker 0: You have to get all the committed.
Speaker 1: You had to get the other people to were playing committed and there you have to do all the effort, right?
Speaker 1: You're not spending a lot of money on this, right?
Speaker 1: But the quality of the gift is so high.
Speaker 1: You just have to do all the arranging so that happens, right?
Speaker 1: You can't just be like, Oh, I promise we'll do this.
Speaker 1: No, it has to.
Speaker 0: We all promise.
Speaker 0: We'll play a game like that all the time.
Speaker 0: It doesn't happen that often.
Speaker 1: Exactly.
Speaker 1: You have to make it.
Speaker 1: You have to, you have to personally wrangle all the cats to make it happen.
Speaker 0: Yup.
Speaker 0: And that is a great gift.
Speaker 0: If you have a lot of time and care about your friend, but don't got a lot of money.
Speaker 1: Hmm.
Speaker 1: It's also a great gift because presumably you are playing in that experience.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: I mean, it's a self gift.
Speaker 1: Also, it might just make sure you don't pick the game that you like and the friend doesn't like.
Speaker 1: you have to choose the game that the, and the experience that the person you're gifting the, this too is wants the most.
Speaker 0: They cannot be the bowling ball that Homer gave to Marge.
Speaker 1: Exactly.
Speaker 0: But it could be the bowling ball that Marge gives to Homer.
Speaker 0: You could agree to arrange the game that you don't fucking like.
Speaker 0: That is, that is a gift.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: Like always wants to play that no one else wants to play.
Speaker 1: Be like, okay, we're going to play the thing.
Speaker 1: You want, you want to play that no one else ever wanted to play.
Speaker 1: We're going to all, you know, it has to be sincere, right?
Speaker 1: You have to all put in your effort to make it, you know, a good play experience.
Speaker 1: You can't just sort of go through the motions and be like, okay, we played it.
Speaker 0: It's kind of all I can think is you and me and a bunch of our show up at a certain unnamed individual's door after like post COVID.
Speaker 0: And we show up and we just say, Hey, you want to play shake geek?
Speaker 1: We're going to play all shaky golf fucking day.
Speaker 1: Let's go.
Speaker 0: But yeah, see how different a gift buying guide on how to get a good gift is from.
Speaker 0: here is a list of things that I'm going to get $10.
Speaker 1: If you buy for even if we use affiliate links, the vast majority of those aren't getting us any fucking money, even if you clicked them.
Speaker 1: What, what affiliate link could I put up for, uh, uh, uh, get someone the ultimate game experience that they've been craving.
Speaker 0: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and brand.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: For the logos.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at front row crew.com for show notes, discussion, news, and more.
Speaker 0: Remember geek nights is not one, but four different shows.
Speaker 0: Tech Mondays, gaming Tuesdays, anime comic Wednesdays, and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a creative commons attribution.
Speaker 1: 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 1: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.
Speaker 0: And the patron patrons for this Tuesday episode of geek nights are Heidi McNichol, Alan Joyce, and Gigi, and a bunch of people who don't want me to say their names.
Speaker 0: Chris Reimer, Clinton Walton, Dex Finn.
Speaker 0: Just like a dude guy.
Speaker 0: I 85 or Becca Dunn review.
Speaker 0: Mad bull, 34 cowards, Ryan Perrin, Sam Erickson, Shervin von Horrell, Taylor Braun, the iron front.
Speaker 0: You hold the key to my heart and a whole bunch of people who actually do not want me to say their names.
Speaker 0: So, uh, yeah, we hope that gift guide is a useful, uh, don't actually buy me a 30 80.
Speaker 0: I will get one eventually, but yeah, if you buy me one, I wouldn't complain, but don't actually do it.
Speaker 0: But anyway, I leave you right now with.
Speaker 0: Welcome to Lee Carvalho's putting challenge.
Speaker 0: I am Carvalho.
Speaker 0: Now choose a club.
Speaker 1: You have chosen a three wood.
Speaker 1: May I suggest a putter?
Speaker 0: Three wood.
Speaker 0: Now enter the force of your swing.
Speaker 0: I suggest feather touch.
Speaker 0: You have entered power drive.
Speaker 0: Now push seven, eight, seven to swing.
Speaker 0: Ball is in parking lot.
Speaker 0: Would you like to play again?
Speaker 1: You have selected.
Speaker 1: No.